<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:56:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The parts of Myanmar the military junta doesn't want you to see</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/inside-myanmar-during-military-junta-sham-election-voting/106190364</link><description>Myanmar's military is holding its first elections since overthrowing a democratically elected government in 2021. But as it aims to portray a sense of normality, signs of the junta's menacing presence are everywhere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">948d3c6bb8238924022179a27bbdcb98</guid></item><item><title>Mid North Coast brumby program rehomes 160 wild horses across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/brumby-rehoming-program-gives-wild-horses-second-chance/106085286</link><description>About a third of the brumby population on the NSW Mid North Coast has been rehomed through a program designed to give wild horses a second chance as pets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ece383d3daeacd448a3de2d057214f0</guid></item><item><title>Naomi Osaka loses United Cup match to Maria Sakkari ahead of Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/united-cup-naomi-osaka-maria-sakkari-australian-open/106196062</link><description>Just over two weeks from the season-opening major, former world number one Naomi Osaka reveals she is not at full health after contracting a viral illness over the Christmas period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">512763bd96b8fdd1d3013fa3d2190ff2</guid></item><item><title>Tesla loses title of bestselling EV company to BYD as sales drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/tesla-loses-title-bestselling-ev-to-byd/106196066</link><description>Tesla sales have declined for the second consecutive year, with Chinese rival BYD surpassing it as the world's largest electric vehicle maker.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c10f01312156bde84a15adaabb610cff</guid></item><item><title>Police hunt for offenders after shooting in Melbourne's inner north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/fitzroy-shooting-police-crime/106196082</link><description>Police are searching for offenders, who are believed to have driven past in a silver SUV and fired shots at a young man, before fleeing the scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">558108aa6fbd3604a2fedf660c062bb4</guid></item><item><title>Barbecue explosion prompts safety warning after Qld beautician's burns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/mums-bbq-warning-after-explosion-on-christmas-eve/106195412</link><description>Rachel Dear has a serious warning for anyone using a gas barbecue after she suffered significant face and body burns while cooking on Christmas Eve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb1ca2b13267460bbd659d5184771082</guid></item><item><title>Coffee pods generate thousands of tonnes of waste in Australia. Here's what is being done about it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/qld-australia-coffee-pod-waste-upcycled-schemes-recycling/106149492</link><description>Between 10 and 20 per cent of the 3 million coffee pods Australians consume daily are actually recycled. Here's what's being done to change that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e00615d7dff72de8460ca30c668e1baa</guid></item><item><title>Photographs of Men in Love exhibition reveals public glimpses of forbidden love</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/photographs-of-men-in-love-exhibition-same-sex-couples-canberra/106164254</link><description>What started as a chance discovery of an old photo at a Dallas antique store has spawned a collection of more than 4,000 images of male couples, more than 100 of which are now on display in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">342bd9008f4a6040aef96519ae23b8f6</guid></item><item><title>WA's Pilbara region shares a human and shorebird FIFO population</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/migratory-shorebirds-land-in-the-pilbara-for-summer/106039306</link><description>Dozens of shorebird species flock to northern WA for summer during their global migration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ff35fe466eef14512e81d2afaf6106e</guid></item><item><title>Middle Percy Island is a 'haven' for sailors, displaying scores of memorabilia from bygone days</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/percy-island-attracts-yachties-from-across-world/105385704</link><description>Middle Percy Island is a rare gem where boaties can come ashore and wander through thousands of mementos left by travellers from across the globe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1746a1ce94f0eacb5cef7b4153c7f3b5</guid></item><item><title>Former Darwin councillor's ex-partner speaks out after guilty domestic violence verdict</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/ex-partner-darwin-councillor-speaks-out-after-guilty-dv-verdict/106170776</link><description>Former Darwin councillor Paul Arnold was found guilty of domestic violence after a years-long court battle, with his ex-partner refusing to be scared into silence. She said the case was "stressful and deeply humiliating", but facing her abuser had been empowering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4c243120a1fef30a2f8354e4ef212a0</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police riot squad to carry long-arm firearms at Sydney Ashes series following Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/nsw-police-riot-squad-carry-long-arm-firearms-sydney-ashes-/106196098</link><description>Officers will carry long-arm firearms as part of a bolstered police presence at the Ashes series in Sydney in the wake of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6877b2907f2f985901c51db094f90f7d</guid></item><item><title>Premium beef producers expect to be the main casualty of China's new 55 per cent tariff</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/wagyu-angus-casualty-of-china-tariffs-on-australian-beef/106194112</link><description>Australian cattle farmers producing wagyu and Angus beef are likely to be among the hardest hit by China's 55 per cent tariff on exports exceeding a 205,000-tonne quota.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">228dfb545460ba76f36dbd3ab6992df6</guid></item><item><title>Two separate echidna puggles unearthed during home renovations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/two-separate-echidna-puggles-unearthed-during-home-renovations/106159590</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bee84e046009ae0bde6da898d0d96438</guid></item><item><title>Wildlife carers warn people to watch out for puggle burrows this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/watch-out-for-puggle-burrows/106123746</link><description>With female echidnas seemingly creating burrows in random places at this time of the year, wildlife carers warn to keep an eye out for what might be disturbed while doing holiday work on your property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b008ff0393e48ce7d75c57dbd80231e6</guid></item><item><title>Local government inspector Tony Brown granted new powers to probe WA councils and 'improve accountability'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/wa-perth-local-government-inspector-powers/106172240</link><description>The new role of Western Australia local government inspector Tony Brown includes the ability to send in monitors — as well as legal and financial experts — to stamp out any early signs of trouble.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">348a4d2e5cc41b88eb40686a673c393e</guid></item><item><title>Driver arrested for allegedly speeding at 209km/h on Southern Expressway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/p-plater-arrested-for-alleged-street-racing-at-209kmh/106196234</link><description>Police say two 19-year-old drivers will face court for street racing along Adelaide's Southern Expressway, with one of the P-platers allegedly detected speeding at 209km/h.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b4af35eb1673cc59d51314fb6ffcc48</guid></item><item><title>Australia coy about Cameron Green's role in final Ashes Test against England at SCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/fifth-ashes-test-australia-england-steve-smith-cameron-green/106196310</link><description>Steve Smith launches an impassioned defence of the out-of-form Cameron Green, but cannot guarantee the all-rounder's place in Australia's XI for the final Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44e672e99bdcb5e120088bfc68bef9ed</guid></item><item><title>Hunt for escaped red-whiskered bulbul that has SA's fruitgrowers worried</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/authorities-hunting-escaped-invasive-bird-threatening-fruit-crop/106192434</link><description>The sighting of a single red-whiskered bulbul in the wild might not seem like a big deal, but this invasive pest could put crops and the environment at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a966eb6406a57993be641fd862019d7</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with hit-and-run death of woman on Darwin's Bagot Road, one week after incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/nt-police-charge-man-hit-and-run-death-indigenous-woman-darwin/106196270</link><description>Police arrest a 61-year-old man after a seven-day investigation involving CCTV, crime scene analysis, forensic examination and witness enquiries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d1b49b76fa056ebc89a2d587c85f317</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police investigating woman's death at Goulburn home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/police-investigating-womans-death-in-goulburn/106196478</link><description>NSW Police launch an investigation after an unidentified woman was found dead in a home in Goulburn on Saturday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5adbd3ecf7e382f730e10a80618394a7</guid></item><item><title>Fight breaks out after crash on Monash Freeway in Melbourne's south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/monash-freeway-crash-fight-narre-warren-police/106196610</link><description>Police are investigating an altercation potentially involving edged weapons after a collision on the Monash Freeway in Melbourne's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9465fcb7ffb6741e7ff20ab5071d8f6a</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios prepared to go through Australian Open qualifying if wildcard spot eludes him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/kyrgios-prepared-to-go-through-aus-open-qualifying/106196636</link><description>Nick Kyrgios describes himself as a "chaotic mess, but an entertainer" as he prepares to return in Brisbane and awaits a call on his Australian Open status.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2122f15620e50b8bead13b9bfd9b350</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan residents capture successive explosions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/venezuela-residents-capture-successive-explosions/106196778</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">609617ce9ba4e56884382b45c8d1d20c</guid></item><item><title>Nicolás Maduro was 'captured' by the US military. This is who he is</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/who-is-nicolas-maduro-explained/106196820</link><description>The 63-year-old Venezuelan president was "captured" in a "large-scale strike". Here is what is known about the man set to stand trial on criminal charges in the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cc9c5f7831714d7c7d694a482d152e2</guid></item><item><title>Trump says US 'will run' Venezuela as Maduro arrives in New York after capture during raid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/venezuela-trump-says-maduro-on-way-to-new-york/106197080</link><description>Deposed Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro is now in New York after he was captured in an early-morning US raid on the nation. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be4394dd4dad737718f96cd59d5c48e4</guid></item><item><title>For its 250th birthday, America is being America</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/on-its-250th-birthday-america-is-being-america/106193418</link><description>It is entirely fitting that the US is so splintered on its semiquincentennial. Division, for the lion's share of its history, has been its default.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be15980d4e27f638fbdc28e784e3d4d9</guid></item><item><title>Butter, margarine or nut spreads. Which is best for your home?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/butter-margarine-nut-spreads-which-is-best/106010740</link><description>You might have a personal preference for which spread you use at home, but experts say there are health considerations for which one you use.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffd9f40f3868b38eeed0e32478084049</guid></item><item><title>Australian exporters still grappling with 'the wild west' eight months after 'liberation day'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/australian-brands-still-dealing-with-trump-tariffs-more-in-2026/106194486</link><description>From de minimis to beef tariffs, Aussie exporters are preparing for another "wild" year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9246f57d955ff69454a3be3212a7d4f7</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan's first woman to summit K2 sparks new wave of female climbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/pakistan-women-hikers-summit-k2-sparks-new-wave-female-climbers/106032678</link><description>Pakistani women are hiking some of the world's tallest mountains and glacier trails, claiming a space that has long been out of reach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f79cc4bf811ab7235c60a6f796067699</guid></item><item><title>Blak romance surges as First Nations authors rewrite love stories with 'choc-lit'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/blak-romance-choc-lit-magabala-first-nations-love-stories/106164166</link><description>An anthology of love stories written by First Nations people is in the works with stories of blak love, joy, and connection capitalising on the fastest growing literary genre in the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df9b7659d4d072a526b05734c5f9c4cb</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says US will run Venezuela for now after Nicolás Maduro's capture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/venezuelan-president-nicolas-maduro-captured-by-us/106197206</link><description>The US will temporarily run Venezuela after American forces captured the country's president and first lady in an extraordinary military strike, US President Donald Trump says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6071f5efeb5d6d77093a6c135f8f37a4</guid></item><item><title>Tourists stranded, dozens of roads closed as rain continues in flooded outback Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/tourists-stranded-dozens-of-roads-closed-by-queensland-flooding/106196556</link><description>Tourists are stranded in towns dotted across north-west Queensland as rain continues to keep major rivers in flood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4063b5ce47cbef605b6e0562bf95ada7</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur unfazed by United Cup loss to Casper Ruud in Australian Open build-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/united-cup-tennis-alex-de-minaur-casper-ruud-australian-open/106197302</link><description>Alex de Minaur is not concerned about his Australian Open preparations, believing he can "flip that switch" after recording his first career defeat to Casper Ruud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0897fbd111d1c554413b28e57ba54b5b</guid></item><item><title>Calls for universal vision screening tests for all SA preschool children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/calls-for-universal-preschool-vision-testing-in-sa/106190758</link><description>A group of researchers is calling on the South Australian government to implement a universal vision screening program for all children attending preschools or day care centres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44abe98801d7c95d0cc2201b06217444</guid></item><item><title>Tumbarumba Rodeo celebrates 80 years of bulls, broncos, thrills and spills</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/tumbaumba-rodeo-turns-80/106194110</link><description>As the Tumbarumba Rodeo celebrates its 80th year, the Rial family have held on for the longest ride of them all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b960525b255ab23d980624f3a76c4aeb</guid></item><item><title>How Louis Braille’s musical notation system remains relevant 200 years after its invention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/louis-braille-music-200/106176564</link><description>In the 1820s, Louis Braille devised a raised-dot system of letters, numbers and musical notation. 200 years later, it’s still opening the music world for blind musicians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e97e8f94552d14784e346f2986eed9e1</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested at Sydney airport after alleged sexual assault in Melbourne laneway on New Year's Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/sexual-assault-investigation-melbourne-coors-lane-new-years-day/106197360</link><description>A 22-year-old French man has been arrested at Sydney International Airport following an alleged sexual assault in Melbourne's CBD in the early hours of New Year's Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1e42251cf2ef235b74a4ea4c82ac818</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane man aiming to be fastest person from sea level to Mount Everest summit in memory of late mother</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/world-record-mental-health-oliver-foran-everest/106166224</link><description>Oliver Foran struggled with his mental health after losing his mother to cancer. Now, he is training to set a world record while raising money and awareness for youth mental health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68a58cbf6598c7f23302ee42fb7f336e</guid></item><item><title>Scientists, landowners working on Tasmania's Bruny Island to help forty-spotted pardalote species</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/forty-spotted-pardalote-bruny-island-endangered-species/106176110</link><description>Donning a helmet and a well-equipped harness, Dr Fernanda Alves looks like she is set to take on an extreme sport. Instead, she is climbing trees to check nesting boxes for a tiny and very rare bird.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7065e03d105853f2e0eb6a85285754a5</guid></item><item><title>Former North Melbourne AFL player Phoenix Spicer dies aged 23</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/afl-former-north-melbourne-player-phoenix-spicer-dies/106197350</link><description>Phoenix Spicer, who played 12 AFL matches for North Melbourne, has died at the age of 23.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfa0dfdd5a10b7ce680fca27b175557a</guid></item><item><title>How artificial intelligence is being used across the ACT to provide vital services</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/how-act-government-is-using-ai-across-services/106137618</link><description>Artificial intelligence is a controversial subject, but as the debate rages it is already being used by ACT government departments, doctors and the people running firefighting operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10d58a3640f58092e04e8f0b3594fff5</guid></item><item><title>Top End dams overflow as parks come to life in the wake of Cyclone Fina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/fogg-dam-darwin-river-cyclone-fina-monsoon/106194820</link><description>The Northern Territory's Top End has been transformed into a lush green paradise by a cyclone and a monsoon that have brought an unusually heavy start to the annual wet season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bbc1a06303d5df7cdf15ccf7111d910</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2026: Bad light halts England's charge as Harry Brook and Joe Root dominate spinless Aussie attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/live-updates-ashes-australia-vs-england-fifth-test-day-one/106197464</link><description>The top two men's Test batters in the world make hay against a spinless Australian attack, only to be stopped by the weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d9e95b3c067548eb7455d61911bd1a7</guid></item><item><title>Sports stars call for federal royal commission into antisemitism and Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/sport-stars-call-for-federal-royal-commission/106197406</link><description>Ian Thorpe, Jess Fox and Lleyton Hewitt are among more than 60 Australian sports stars joining public calls for a Commonwealth royal commission into the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfe61c6f50adb040dbfdacd8e9523102</guid></item><item><title>Captured Maduro touches down in New York</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/captured-maduro-touches-down-in-new-york-/106197506</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbdeb06a0ee170385f9595f1fdfb7e36</guid></item><item><title>Collector with 50 pinball machines in his shed hopes to create a playable museum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/western-australia-pinball-collector-greg-sharpe-bally-williams/106190702</link><description>This shed in Western Australia is filled wall-to-wall with collectable pinball machines, all in working order. Greg Sharp hopes to one day share it as a playable pinball museum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">551adce7b764201eb76b53d9fbddfb07</guid></item><item><title>People celebrate Maduro’s capture around the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/people-celebrate-maduro-s-capture-around-the-world-/106197528</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5e56aca1a7518d9b280843b572c2751</guid></item><item><title>Some world leaders view Venezuelan strikes with 'deep concern', others 'salute' US action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/how-world-leaders-reacted-to-venezuelan-strikes/106197592</link><description>The US mission to capture deposed Venezuelan president Nicolás Maduro and his wife prompts celebration and condemnation across the globe. Here's how key world leaders have reacted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">279fcf720691af2b125e7bc3ad5eb256</guid></item><item><title>US makes 'bold' grab for oil as financial markets brace for price change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/us-intervention-in-venezuela-impact-on-oil-prices-unclear/106197522</link><description>Oil futures do not trade until Monday, Australian time, and financial market participants are divided over whether there will be a spike or correction in the price of oil in Asian trade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cddf5973a667bf5403f659045cd625dd</guid></item><item><title>The Venezuela strike sets a new low for the world order — even by Donald Trump's standards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/venezuela-operation-us-blatant-disregard-international-law/106197628</link><description>Even in a world that has grown used to a cavalier attitude to international law from Donald Trump, the move stuns leaders across the globe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51723f26a2ed373c59c19ed134c851e4</guid></item><item><title>Death in custody investigation launched after fatal crash on SA rural highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/highway-fatal-crash-treated-as-death-in-custody/106197538</link><description>Police launch a death in custody investigation, after a 33-year-old man was killed in a crash in an allegedly stolen car that was road-spiked on South Australia's Eyre Highway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e7160a86849d3d52922b1ce5327b915</guid></item><item><title>Evonne Goolagong Cawley's life story immortalised in screen drama</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/evonne-goolagong-cawley-tennis-lila-mcguire/106121294</link><description>Lila McGuire on the pressure and joy of playing former world number one and winner of seven grand slam singles titles, tennis legend Evonne Goolagong Cawley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17b39dbac2a0c60bd0858768f09e02d7</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan diaspora divided over US capturing of leader Maduro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/venezuelan-diaspora-divided-over-us-capturing-of-leader-maduro/106197588</link><description>Venezuelan migrants across Latin America and other parts of the world cheered in the streets, supporting the US mission to capture Venezuela's deposed president, Nicolás Maduro.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bb59c27e88d19c330d4a4cf93d035c4</guid></item><item><title>Convoy believed to carry Maduro arrives at DEA complex</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/convoy-believed-to-carry-maduro-arrives-at-dea-complex/106197822</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbf90a15e8e69976d1581129272c1b9c</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Venezuelan diaspora gathers after US captures president Nicolás Maduro in military strike</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/venezuela-australian-reaction-after-us-military-strike-maduro/106197558</link><description>Australia's small but tight-knit community of Venezuelan-born residents is gathering to discuss the unfolding situation in their home country after the US captured Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af4bf140de0b9a9dd93ed13301415cd0</guid></item><item><title>Deposed Nicolás Maduro inside New York law enforcement offices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/deposed-nicol%C3%A1s-maduro-inside-new-york-law-enforcement-offices/106197952</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d502c57a26e57e60c600e9f5fb4a9de2</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelans race to stock up on essential goods after Maduro's capture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/venezuelans-race-to-stock-up-on-essential-goods/106198102</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e5500561dd2a6cb53683ff2abef77a4</guid></item><item><title>SCG pays tribute to Bondi heroes, weather frustrates and Australia goes spinless — quick hits from day one of fifth Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/ashes-fifth-test-at-scg-day-one-quick-hits/106197510</link><description>Australia opts not to pick a spinner for another Test, breaking a streak of 138 years at the SCG, which rises as one to honour the heroes of the Bondi terror attack. Here are the quick hits from the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb302c1928946d6230d618f585d1ea1b</guid></item><item><title>Weary Australia eyes Ashes finish line at the SCG as England senses opportunity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/ashes-fifth-test-day-one-weary-australia-eyes-ashes-finish-line/106197850</link><description>Only the rain could slow England's progress on day one in Sydney, as a weary Australia reflected its coach's claims the series really ended in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0673d5a9a75261e6fada5da482bd264</guid></item><item><title>Australian cricket great Damien Martyn awakes from induced coma after falling ill with meningitis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/australian-cricket-great-damien-martyn-awakes-from-coma/106198212</link><description>Former Australian Test batsman Damien Martyn is awake and talking after being in an induced coma for several days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c44eb726bb83ef6540bbd5a1ffa2f384</guid></item><item><title>Thanasi Kokkinakis tears up and Nick Kyrgios chills out as Special Ks return at Brisbane International</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/nick-kyrgios-thanasi-kokkinakis-special-ks/106198254</link><description>Thanasi Kokkinakis said he didn't think he'd be able to return to tennis after a 2025 blighted by injury. Instead he's made a winning return alongside doubles partner and all-round showman Nick Kyrgios.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7aef09a3f488ce63cc4a9cf1fddbcb21</guid></item><item><title>Venezuela updates: Maduro arrives at Manhattan court, Trump doubles down on oil plans for Venezuela - as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/venezuela-maduro-in-custody-blog-january-5/106198380</link><description>Deposed Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro and his wife have been transferred to a New York courthouse as Donald Trump doubles down on oil plans for Venezuela — as it happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dfd5b587b46b480d65b9556a0e4fc6b</guid></item><item><title>Death toll rises in Iran as anti-government protests spread</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/iran-protests-spread-death-toll-rises/106198320</link><description>At least 16 people have been killed in a week of demonstrations fuelled by the rising cost of living.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95d5d3870c71498c6f6b04fccea8017d</guid></item><item><title>Cookbook Club Naarm is bringing strangers together over food</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/cookbook-supper-club-community-events-cooking-books-chef-potluck/106092308</link><description>Each month, strangers and friends meet to share dishes from a chosen cookbook. But Cookbook Club Naarm is more than a foodie feast, it's a reminder of food's power to bring us together.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7003e991adab8bd16875eb0360f89db3</guid></item><item><title>Inflation, tariffs, EVs: What the ABC's business experts are watching in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/economy-markets-predictions-2026-business-experts/106156688</link><description>What are you watching in 2026 when it comes to the economy or markets? That's the question we put to the ABC's experts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8e64e8827c29ee9a51c9b365ad229e5</guid></item><item><title>Repeated brain injuries linked to memory changes in intimate partner violence survivors, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/brain-injury-concussion-strangulation-partner-violence-study/106159980</link><description>An Australian-first study finds evidence of previously undetected, long-term cognitive changes in women more than six months after they experienced repeated concussions and strangulation during intimate partner violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3515faea792fbbea3ef26d94212d5fbf</guid></item><item><title>Value of Australian dollar now dependent on interest rates, commodities prices and geopolitics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/australian-dollar-now-dependent-on-interest-rates-commodities/106186480</link><description>The value of Australia's currency could move significantly up or down depending on the direction of interest rates. But the global economic backdrop will also be crucial in determining its direction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7e2086e93d1eeda3b7369847e469d66</guid></item><item><title>Were the US actions in Venezuela legal under international law?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/were-the-us-actions-in-venezuela-legal-under-international-law/106198134</link><description>International law is created by all states, not just the powerful few. This makes international community reactions to breaches particularly important.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a0e863241ad26e5cd8c8ea505ef6198</guid></item><item><title>National donor conception register would prevent 'potential trauma', advocate says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/national-donor-conception-register-for-key-information-call/106188336</link><description>Hundreds of people have accessed South Australia's Donor Conception Register in its first year, lifting decades of secrecy surrounding anonymous donations — an outcome that has prompted calls from a leading advocate for similar moves at national level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ccef3ff92f6b64b2e7e9c03e5e15da5</guid></item><item><title>Nicolás Maduro's allies maintain power in Venezuela, rejecting US claims they will 'comply'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/nicolas-maduro-allies-take-power-in-venezuela/106198570</link><description>The Trump administration insists Venezuela's leaders will now comply with American demands after the extraordinary capture of president Nicolás Maduro — but his allies are resisting US pressure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83250884e03b7c92ee18975a7269611d</guid></item><item><title>Daria Kasatkina defeated at Brisbane International as Ajla Tomljanović reaches second round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/brisbane-international-tennis-daria-kasatkina-ajla-tomljanovic/106198664</link><description>Daria Kasatkina admits she held back tears and dealt with severe nerves during an agonising three-set loss at the Brisbane International.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a32d0120141242f52a751aac1eeffec</guid></item><item><title>Emergency departments ill-suited for mental health crises, advocates say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/patient-traumatising-hospital-care-act-crisis/106157462</link><description>A 24-year-old NSW border resident says dismissive treatment in hospitals, long waits for care and limited access to services have pushed her away from support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f1c951190641b270ccdeaceac77ed09</guid></item><item><title>This sacred 'forbidden island' in Japan is World Heritage listed and completely off limits to women</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/okinoshima-island-world-heritage-listed-gender-ban/106017014</link><description>Boasting thousands of years of history and a World Heritage listing, Okinoshima is Japan's very own treasure island. It's also completely off limits to women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6008aa4cf4f81cb4dd85f39230b6299</guid></item><item><title>Australia urged to back spinners after Todd Murphy's omission from fifth Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/ashes-scg-test-australia-critcises-for-leaving-out-spinner/106198718</link><description>Leg spinner Mitchell Swepson wants Australian cricket officials and curators to buck the growing trend of producing pitches that heavily favour seam bowlers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94e68ac134662be379513200ede43cac</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelans march in Caracas to oppose Maduro's capture.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/venezuelans-march-in-caracas-to-oppose-maduro-capture/106198748</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dd0da9fbce5906065ad8e4f58fa4553</guid></item><item><title>Motorcyclist killed in crash that forced closure of lanes on South Eastern Freeway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/motorbike-crash-at-crafers-west-on-south-eastern-freeway/106198698</link><description>A 25-year-old motorcyclist has died in a crash that forced the closure of city-bound lanes on Adelaide's South Eastern Freeway this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">590e21b6ca29b9a31bdbf77803c64112</guid></item><item><title>Rufous scrub-bird DNA project aims to safeguard ancient and elusive songbird</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/dna-project-to-save-rufous-scrub-bird/106191878</link><description>The Rufous scrub-bird is one of the world's oldest surviving species of songbird, but scientists believe fewer than 2,000 of the birds remain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9303e143d26a1ac223b41d18d2f75fda</guid></item><item><title>Higher rate of eviction for community housing residents in WA as decision-making process questioned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/higher-rate-of-eviction-for-community-housing-residents-in-wa/103417084</link><description>Community housing is seen as a way for the government to tackle the housing crisis, but between limited options and court orders, some people are falling through the cracks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f09ccbcce50039859f8104c5fcbe1f78</guid></item><item><title>What is developmental delay and how can you to tell if your child has one?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/how-to-tell-if-your-child-has-a-developmental-delay/105888348</link><description>Developmental delay will be a big part of the new NDIS alternative for some kids. But what does the phrase mean and how can you tell if your child has one?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c55d7c08342830d440475646461211de</guid></item><item><title>Is sustainable forestry certification protecting Australia's bushland?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/sustainable-timber-certification-concerns/105904122</link><description>Questions are being raised about sustainable timber certification in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d5dcc7b9702ebd2eb291f96d40e8434</guid></item><item><title>Country league president reported to AFL integrity unit over alleged 'gender weirdness' comments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/kyneton-womens-fc-report-league-president-to-afl-integrity-unit/106190264</link><description>A country football league president has been reported to the AFL Integrity Unit over alleged comments about a club's "grooming and gender weirdness" after it was involved in blocking the club from entering a neighbouring competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ceb9c73f6adf9f57f90bb1caae08180</guid></item><item><title>Oil prices fall after US strikes on Venezuela, ASX flat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/asx-markets-business-live-news-jan05-2026/106198892</link><description>Australian shares have ended the session unchanged on Monday, while oil prices fall in a choppy trade following the US strike on Venezuela that sparked concerns about oversupply.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f288e3c976105486c93bd0feca2bfa3</guid></item><item><title>Ditching Sydney for a wheat header, French farmer travels 17,000km to pick up where dad left off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/french-farmer-travel-to-australia-brittany/106192804</link><description>When 22-year-old Tanguy Bodiguel's friends said they were travelling to Australia, he left them in Sydney to work on a farm with sentimental value.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cf0435bf977df35b5865638e1562af7</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2026 live updates: Australia 2-166, Travis Head 91* after Stokes-Labuschagne clash on day two of fifth Test at SCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/ashes-cricket-scg-test-day-two-live-blog/106199006</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne falls two runs short of a Test half-century, nicking off to Ben Stokes immediately after clashing with the England captain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc60eeb2c778ab5b08f78ec8147d9340</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic exits Professional Tennis Players Association ahead of Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/novak-djokovic-exits-professional-tennis-players-association/106199048</link><description>Novak Djokovic is stepping away from the Professional Tennis Players Association citing concerns over transparency and governance within the organisation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">970d55f22cdf9cf67d04dfab8333e33e</guid></item><item><title>This toad busting group is determined to take back Magnetic Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/magnetic-island-cane-toad-busters/106136446</link><description>On a tropical Queensland island, 'toad busters' have decided the cane toad's spread across northern Australia should not be a lost cause.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8dc5263c05317f292acb302d1806c9f</guid></item><item><title>South-East Asian powers offer strong criticism of US operation in Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/asian-powers-express-grave-concern-over-us-venezuela-operation/106198804</link><description>Indonesia, Singapore and Malaysia express "grave concern" over the US capture of Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24e70a3542fee7391f5108367731680e</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Liberal Party deputy leader Sam Groth will exit politics at next election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/sam-groth-victorian-liberal-party-deputy-leader-exit-politics/106199004</link><description>Sam Groth, the deputy leader of the Victorian Liberal Party, has announced he will not contest the upcoming state election in November, saying he made his decision after realising that some recent negative public pressure had come from within his own party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f5b5f8c41cda77210cad523d0a9e51b</guid></item><item><title>Tributes flow for founding father of Australian beef industry, Sir Graham McCamley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/australian-beef-industry-mourns-loss-of-sir-graham-mccamley-93/106198876</link><description>From building one of Queensland's most respected cattle empires and championing the Brahman breed, Sir Graham's lifelong dedication to agriculture and his community was truly remarkable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53678aa9f26c57b78d0c160062c6859c</guid></item><item><title>Critics Choice Awards 2026 winners: One Battle After Another wins best picture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/critics-choice-awards-2026-winners-list/106199058</link><description>Now in their 31st year, the Critics Choice Awards are historically known to be the most accurate predictor of the Academy Award nominations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8952945cea491eff7e8aa4654529ec63</guid></item><item><title>Eels sign Brian Kelly as potential replacement for Zac Lomax ahead of 2026 NRL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/nrl-parramatta-eels-brian-kelly-zac-lomax/106199350</link><description>In the wake of Zac Lomax's sudden departure, Parramatta makes a move in the player market as it looks to lifts its fortunes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac27c637175a2fbeca89c1866fa2c76</guid></item><item><title>Jacob Elordi and Sarah Snook win at Critics Choice Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/critics-choice-awards-2026-key-moments/106199154</link><description>Australian actress Sarah Snook takes out Best Actress in a Limited Series or Movie Made for Television with All Her Fault while Australian Jacob Elordi takes out Best Supporting Actor for Frankenstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8693e491b3fd4de2f6d37b7e51d742e6</guid></item><item><title>Measles alert as Adelaide and Sydney airports among possible exposure sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/measles-case-travelled-from-adelaide-to-sydney-on-qantas-flight/106198812</link><description>SA and NSW health authorities have issued alerts about a potential measles exposure risk, after a person with the disease recently caught a flight from Adelaide to Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">871c233d42ef3773ef479cf4dcf379c7</guid></item><item><title>Trump's Venezuela move assumes his base will support his foreign interventions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/donald-trump-venezuela-foreign-policy-honduras/106199368</link><description>Donald Trump has long defied political gravity but whether his followers in Congress and the MAGA movement will follow him into a new colonialism is a big gamble.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fa61fc0754b3cf4b15eaf2e43ea3549</guid></item><item><title>NSW residents urged to check if they are owed share of $300m in unclaimed cash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/about-300-million-in-unclaimed-money-in-nsw/106199820</link><description>Almost $300 million in refunds, dividends and cheques remain unclaimed by households and businesses across New South Wales, with locals urged to take action to secure the money they are owed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7337b84bfbea19ae477d4850fbbd042f</guid></item><item><title>What's Going on in Venezuela?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/what-s-going-on-in-venezuela-/106199950</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0798e3f8fb2d3bd2b2e21a497df3929e</guid></item><item><title>Joe Root best since Donald Bradman says Darren Lehmann after second Ashes century on Australian soil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/joe-root-second-century-scg-don-bradman/106199570</link><description>Joe Root is hailed as the greatest cricket player since Don Bradman after adding a second century to his tally this Ashes tour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a3694ac0d0eba32578e8d3615060f54</guid></item><item><title>Emergency departments ill-suited for mental health crises, advocates say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/act-emergency-departments-ill-suited-mental-health-crises/106200130</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb03edf77794382a8abaf4029cb90a38</guid></item><item><title>Autopsy unable to determine cause of Tennant Creek woman's death in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/nt-tennant-creek-watch-house-death-in-custody-post-mortem-result/106199844</link><description>Police say the cause of a woman's death in a Northern Territory police watch house last month remains "undetermined" following a post-mortem examination conducted on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1fb0594a4e3a0f4ef5d5114e677138e</guid></item><item><title>All 40 victims of Crans-Montana bar fire identified amid outpouring of grief</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/all-victims-of-swiss-bar-fire-identified-police-say/106200304</link><description>Swiss police say more than half of the 40 people killed after a fire broke out at a bar in the Crans-Montana resort were teenagers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be79554e24e09bfc8a188718c2ecb50d</guid></item><item><title>Trump ramps up rhetoric on Colombia, Cuba and Mexico after Venezuela raid.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/rhetoric-trump-venezuela/106200620</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c091f82677be41778140424f59c9d8dc</guid></item><item><title>Langi Kal Kal prison escapee threatens farm worker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/prison-escapee-attacks-farm-worker-langi-kal-kal/106199880</link><description>A farm worker says he was threatened by a man who escaped from Langi Kal Kal prison near Ballarat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22a240d35a388433f5b60959e32c27ab</guid></item><item><title>Why did a Venezuelan rally go ahead in Sydney despite protest restrictions?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/nsw-explainer-protest-ban-bondi-as-venezuelans-rally-in-sydney/106199170</link><description>New laws restricting protests were recently passed in NSW, yet close to 300 people took to the streets of Sydney after the US attack on Venezuela.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abd16d859e4adf561fa9fedbb64772ac</guid></item><item><title>Moderate chance of cyclone hitting Far North Queensland coast by the weekend, weather bureau forecasts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/far-north-queensland-cyclone-forecast/106199464</link><description>The chance of a tropical low off the Far North Queensland coast developing into a cyclone is increasing from low to moderate by the weekend, according to the weather bureau.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb93f7f8d3e6c70af69b17d4c25e36b5</guid></item><item><title>Key points to understand US attacks on Venezuela and capture of President Maduro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/what-happened-us-strikes-venezuela-maduro-captured-what-next/106198900</link><description>These are the key points to get up to speed with what we know about the US strikes on Venezuela and the current state of play after its president was ousted and removed from the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8831a0d03d39f3b5a7c9e57fd010b6ca</guid></item><item><title>Victims withholding information after three Hobart shootings in a week, Tasmania Police says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/hobart-three-shootings-police-victims-withholding-information/106198946</link><description>Three shootings have occurred in northern Hobart in the space of a week, with police saying two appear to be related.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6547af8b9c7d035da4d8d77424d0f4d2</guid></item><item><title>Denmark tells Trump to back off over 'threats' against Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/denmark-rejects-us-trump-threats-greenland/106199700</link><description>The leaders of Denmark and Greenland have urged US President Donald Trump to stop threatening to take over Greenland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90f98d74a11dbe632e6e2a20575310b9</guid></item><item><title>Small aircraft crashes at airport in Adelaide's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/small-aircraft-crashes-at-airport-in-adelaide-s-north/106201012</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09b85a9721ddc253f7442a89b4ba7b0d</guid></item><item><title>Pasta, slow-cooker recipes and tray bakes: Our top 10 recipes from 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/your-favourite-recipes-of-2025/106091718</link><description>Easy weeknight meals were your favourite (again), with tray bakes, soups and noodles amongst the most loved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8de5c8d7977a031014b35aa3f1495f1</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro held in New York prison described as 'hell on earth'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/nicol%C3%A1s-maduro-in-the-new-york-metropolitan-detention-center/106199184</link><description>The facility where detained Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro has been taken is a notorious New York jail that has held a string of high-profile and celebrity criminals, from drug cartel leaders to hip-hop stars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">784a697b58d4fb284175a75608400421</guid></item><item><title>Senior Queensland doctor cleared of allegations after 14-month suspension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/chief-medical-officer-reinstated-mackay-charles-pain/106200692</link><description>Mackay's chief medical officer, Charles Pain, returns to work after an external investigation cleared him of allegations of poor clinical governance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85b480f0b3f7daeb998b973f37ba8781</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne prises farcical wicket, Cam Green's agony continues, Travis Head sparkles — quick hits from day two of SCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/ashes-scg-test-quick-hits-day-two/106199122</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne picks up a farcical wicket, Cam Green can't catch a break and Joe Root enters rare air. Here are the quick hits from the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63d637764db6fed8ea8267c149c9b46d</guid></item><item><title>Energy company ENGIE promised pensioner refund then sent debt collectors after him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/engie-energy-makes-mistake-sends-debt-collectors-after-pensioner/106132388</link><description>Australia's energy prices continue to soar as questions continue to be raised about the actions of providers, including by this pensioner who was overcharged and then had debt collectors chasing him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f33b84b38f7a914084ecd3e5659b2fe6</guid></item><item><title>Travis Head and Joe Root bring batting class to bowlers' Ashes on a fiery second day of SCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/batting-class-prevails-for-head-and-root-ashes-scg-day-two/106200104</link><description>In what has been a bowlers' series, the class of Joe Root and Travis Head again shone on day two in Sydney, where it often took something silly for a wicket to fall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c0d5da305e3e8babfb546559bd6132d</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/gold-and-silver-jump-after-us-attacks-venezuela-oil-down-slightl/106201488</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6baf356d650d49c9ff9bf950dca45c81</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Police employee faces court over alleged antisemitic online posts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/police-service-employee-faces-court-over-alleged-hate-crimes/106201402</link><description>Muamer Nukic, a 50-year-old Queensland Police Service employee and described as a "self-proclaimed anti-Zionist" was granted bail in the Brisbane Magistrate Court on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52a4aaba462836bd8b3c7c152be81a0f</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump claimed Venezuela stole US oil assets but the issue is more complicated than that</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/why-venezuelan-oil-is-not-stolen-from-the-united-states/106200804</link><description>US President Donald Trump has said Venezuela stole United States oil assets. Experts say the truth is much more complex than that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1185033f9bae9e894518bb6079f6eeb6</guid></item><item><title>Former Labor politicians urge Albanese to call federal royal commission into antisemitism and Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/former-labor-politicians-plead-albanese-royal-commission-bondi/106201744</link><description>A group of former Labor MPs, senators and party officials have signed an open letter asking Anthony Albanese to call a national royal commission into the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26a868908b51731a34c2d0c946047074</guid></item><item><title>Manchester United sacks head coach Ruben Amorim after turbulent tenure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/manchester-united-sacks-coach-ruben-amorim/106201814</link><description>It comes less than a day after the club drew one-all with Leeds United and a testy post-match press conference in which Amorim questioned his own role and the club's management.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a2476a5bca8dd0da1f9c213592433da</guid></item><item><title>A Paris court finds 10 people guilty of cyberbullying France's first lady Brigitte Macron</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/10-charged-for-cyberbullying-brigitte-macron/106201796</link><description>Several defendants told the court their comments were intended as humour or satire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5382845bf3ac9a036f487b1f6faa3210</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann launches High Court appeal in latest defamation fight, alleging findings 'compromised'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/bruce-lehrmann-launches-high-court-appeal/106201754</link><description>Former Liberal staffer Bruce Lehrmann takes his appeal to the High Court against the findings that he, on the balance of probabilities, raped Brittany Higgins in 2019.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">446e771832ca4322175a527c2b872641</guid></item><item><title>Ousted Venezuelan leader Nicolás Maduro and wife Cilia Flores plead not guilty in New York court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/venezuelan-leader-nicol%C3%A1s-maduro-appears-in-new-york-court/106201846</link><description>Nicolás Maduro and Cilia Flores, who were captured in Caracas at the weekend, face multiple drugs and weapons charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">893a666a98bd976fe476ea782d0fed9e</guid></item><item><title>How this new Melbourne suburb is dodging baking heat in summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/clyde-tree-canopy-requirement-casey-council/106174988</link><description>Thousands of young trees dot the streets and front gardens of this outer Melbourne suburb as part of a neighbourhood-wide push to create more shade and curb the urban heat island effect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">416a36938699bfbb40f85c53e408d39c</guid></item><item><title>Nancy Kerrigan assault a soap-operatic story that overshadowed the 1994 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/nancy-kerrigan-assault-tonya-harding-1994/106184912</link><description>The genteel and sequined world of figure skating had its dark side exposed in a drama worthy of a soap opera in 1994, as Nancy Kerrigan was the victim of a dastardly plot to eliminate her from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1979bdf82e7b75b4e83dc1710e143ef</guid></item><item><title>How much do you know about the meat pie? Test yourself (or treat yourself)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/dr-karl-how-things-works-pie-quiz/106086912</link><description>From pastry processing to mass-cooking meat — test your knowledge on the humble meat pie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7992118d27286ee078a2f7a57c588df</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's 'bold' oil grab in South America appears to be a major chess move</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/venezuela-oil-donald-trump-power-grab/106200092</link><description>In a world awash with oil, US President Donald Trump's takeover of Venezuela seems to be more about power than production.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c448111ae1ca3e26a21c7187e2bfbb4b</guid></item><item><title>'Most significant' heatwave in six years brings temperatures above 45C</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/australia-heatwave-most-significant-in-six-years/106200088</link><description>The "most significant" heatwave south-eastern Australia has seen in six years is likely to trigger an extreme fire danger alongside searing hot temperatures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62b8cc56863c610fcfcc3d2abaf4eee4</guid></item><item><title>UN chief António Guterres warns of wider instability following US operation in Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/un-security-council-meets-to-discuss-us-attack-on-venezuela/106201850</link><description>The warning by the UN chief comes during an emergency session of the United Nations Security Council, just blocks from where Nicolás Maduro and his wife Cilia Flores are facing a Manhattan judge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4231245359710a0d66c24b6639109fa</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's bioluminescence unrelated to salmon farm nutrients, scientist says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/algal-bloom-concerns-near-tasmanian-salmon-farms/106199152</link><description>Scientists say a bioluminescent algae causes the red tides at the centre of recent environmentalist concerns — but that's not to say the magnificent display is totally harmless to marine life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e53ddd06679985fe547fe80d6ac07c62</guid></item><item><title>What to expect from Reserve Bank and interest rates in 2026 with rate hikes on the table</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/what-to-expect-from-rba-interest-rates-in-2026-hikes-on-table/106200132</link><description>Mortgage borrowers and savers may have used the new year as an excuse to get their financial affairs in order, but things may be set to change within a matter of months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">750d17a1fe3aa50c384088d78725fa3d</guid></item><item><title>Child abuse campaigners want reforms to Centrelink, insurance repayments from compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/child-abuse-survivor-compensation-repayments/106186294</link><description>When survivors of child sexual abuse receive compensation, many may have to repay Centrelink, Medicare and private health insurance amounts relating to their abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">445284820f8256e62fd89879c511bb41</guid></item><item><title>Walk while you work: Are the extra steps using an under-desk treadmill worth the cost?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/is-a-desk-treadmill-worth-the-cost/106195036</link><description>Many people know what it feels like to sit at a computer all day, then sit on the living room couch all night. Would a desk treadmill help?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffcf1a90a47f29dce8bb12e93387795c</guid></item><item><title>Woolwich Marina expansion rejected but locals worry about future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/local-groups-stop-woolwich-marina-expansion-but-fear-isnt-over/106194942</link><description>Local groups that helped save heritage-listed Kelly's Bush Park from being impacted by a marina expansion proposal are calling on the NSW government to do more to protect the foreshore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ef73f7409172d89acff9defaf0a59bc</guid></item><item><title>Venezuela updates: Venezuelan opposition demands release of all political prisoners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/venezuela-maduro-in-court-new-york-live-blog-january-6/106201828</link><description>Nicolás Maduro and his wife face court in New York after being captured by US forces as House Democrats leader Hakeem Jeffries accuses US President Donald Trump of lying to the American people about the reason for the attack — as it happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38c7711ad0e476096b4dbf0305c9525e</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Emerson Jones wins through at Brisbane International as Kimberly Birrell and Olivia Gadecki advance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/brisbane-international-emerson-jones-kimberly-birrell/106202016</link><description>At 17, Emerson Jones shows why she is one of the brightest prospects in Australian tennis, as she wins through to the second round in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">800c2bb4f3ed164cde54cbd1807eaea6</guid></item><item><title>Prime minister announces $38 million for flood-affected communities across north-west Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/northwest-queensland-flooding-continues-as-low-approaches-coast/106201374</link><description>A number of communities remain on flood watch, while a traveller is in hospital after walking through knee-deep mud after he became bogged in outback Queensland on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b23fad379a4df846e138e9df38237487</guid></item><item><title>The country town program ensuring age gaps are no barrier to friendship in Bungendore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/act-country-town-bungendore-is-bridging-the-generation-gap/106150492</link><description>In a country town near Canberra, a program run by an aged care provider and the local high school is seeing positive results in breaking down barriers between younger and older community members.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4c1c677e77b5ad78ff4a3e88f44e28c</guid></item><item><title>Concern over SA's algal bloom pushing visitors to other SA tourist towns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/algae-bloom-fears-boost-sa-tourism-towns/106198724</link><description>An algal bloom that has been ravaging parts of SA's coast for months is pushing visitors to head to other parts of the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">216d8b9fda4186d0057389dee189df90</guid></item><item><title>Mother of 13yo who fell pregnant in state care says system 'ruining lives'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/13-year-old-pregnant-sexual-assaults-state-residential-care/105980432</link><description>Child safety experts say the case of a 13-year-old girl who became pregnant while in state care highlights the dangers of the residential system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4012124523dbc441aaf538ab50f821f</guid></item><item><title>Banyule locals question whether North East Link caused sinkhole at Heidelberg football oval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/banyule-locals-blame-north-east-link-for-sinkhole-at-oval/106201992</link><description>A sinkhole has opened up in Banyule Flats Reserve, close to where a North East Link tunnel boring machine is operating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc8ae93b6811ee31f0339b6cd21c4c76</guid></item><item><title>ASX runs out of steam despite Wall Street rally, BlueScope shares surge — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-tuesday-6-january/106202082</link><description>Australian shares retreat into into the red, while steel producer BlueScope gains 20 per cent on a takeover tilt. Follow the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7809e826a0344b5bddac05840738c1c8</guid></item><item><title>Coco Gauff loses singles but US makes United Cup quarterfinals with win over Spain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/united-cup-us-coco-gauff-taylor-fritz/106202112</link><description>The US secures a United Cup quarterfinal berth after Coco Gauff makes up for a shock singles loss by helping win the deciding mixed doubles rubber.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4f0ace718e668a337e3e9da17513cb6</guid></item><item><title>Delcy Rodríguez officially sworn in as Venezuela’s interim president.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/delcy-rodriguez-sworn-in-as-venezuela-s-interim-president-/106202118</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46012b67cd5c9df4fa1ab5cd325ecb28</guid></item><item><title>Convicted scammer Patricia McIntyre allegedly targeting victims in new pet and house-sitting con</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/patricia-mcintyre-alleged-pet-and-house-sitting-scam/106189894</link><description>Dozens of people from multiple states have come forward after allegedly falling victim to a new pet and house-sitting scam orchestrated by career con artist Patricia McIntyre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea2688ee74d484d6e17d4604eb7e9b06</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's other goal in the Venezuela strike was to get China out of Latin America</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/us-venezuela-strike-to-get-china-out-of-latin-america/106201438</link><description>Venezuela has spent years getting cosier with China. Now Donald Trump is sending a clear warning to Beijing — get out of his backyard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfdc10ffe823e9f14d299014d36b82fe</guid></item><item><title>Before Venezuela there was Panama and the first US capture of a Latin American leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/panama-and-the-us-capture-of-manuel-noriega/106199932</link><description>Thirty-six years to the day before this week's capture of Nicolás Maduro the United States's invasion of Panama led to the capture of its de facto ruler General Manuel Noriega.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36f6098c33c7542886efa28300790ad0</guid></item><item><title>As Victoria's grassland dries with warmer weather, the CFA warns of increased fire risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/victoria-bushfire-risk-high-despite-rain/106096142</link><description>Grassland in Victoria has dried significantly since September, including in the north-west of the state and in outer Melbourne, putting firefighters on edge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56648e0798244c53feb8995a6632532a</guid></item><item><title>Yarloop locals mark decade since bushfire destroyed 160 homes and killed two people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/yarloop-bushfire-10-year-anniversary-marked/106155544</link><description>Ten years after a bushfire took just seven minutes to tear through Yarloop, residents say community spirit and support from neighbouring towns helped get them through the tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7088a5388f230abfd0c35a9b80b27d3</guid></item><item><title>Council criticised for removing 'illegally planted' trees from sensitive sand dunes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/council-criticised-for-removing-illegal-trees-from-dunes/106174826</link><description>A Queensland council is being criticised for uprooting unauthorised saplings from sand dunes amid a long-running vegetation battle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f71c6b7a0767545c69d6fe4ce8e7d3d3</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic withdraws from Australian Open lead-up event at Adelaide International</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/australian-open-novak-djokovic-out-of-adelaide-international/106202328</link><description>With the Australian Open on the horizon, Novak Djokovic does not feel he is well enough prepared to contest next week's Adelaide International.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1bf5f795fc9797030df50d8ec0a5d3a</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2026: Steve Smith fires Australia to dominant position on day three of fifth Test at SCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/ashes-live-scg-test-day-three-australia-england/106202206</link><description>Australia leads England by 134 first-innings runs after a dominant day three at the SCG, punctuated by centuries to Travis Head and Steve Smith.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e17568c8efb295c226cff3da05c270b</guid></item><item><title>Site selection delayed for desalination plant Lower Great Southern needs 'to survive'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/plans-pushed-back-for-desalination-site-the-lower-great-southern/106189738</link><description>Plans for a desalination plant in Western Australia's Great Southern are delayed as the clock ticks to secure a critical water source.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69d1703d9bcf7f663d90b817178ed0ae</guid></item><item><title>Top Trump adviser refuses to rule out military action to take over Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/trump-move-on-greenland-would-mean-end-of-nato-danish-leader/106202286</link><description>Stephen Miller, Mr Trump's chief of staff for policy, said the Trump administration believed Greenland should become an American territory in order for the US to "protect and defend NATO".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22c6960cd900eb92db5bc309f548541a</guid></item><item><title>Destructive Los Angeles-like fires possible for Australia's capital cities, report warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/bushfire-risk-australia-climate-council-report/106199356</link><description>Australia's capital cities are increasingly at risk of being affected by a major fire like the one that ravaged Los Angeles last year, according to a new climate report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90f6425c4896291e2a117d20625d65cf</guid></item><item><title>Scenic Rim Council red tape on camping pushes farmer to consider selling up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/scenic-rim-farmer-considers-selling-up-due-to-camping-red-tape/106138010</link><description>A Scenic Rim farmer says the costs of getting a council permit to host campers are so high he may have to sell his property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cca44102320cd231cdc9cad3bb669b2</guid></item><item><title>Dragons sign Keaon Koloamatangi from Rabbitohs on massive five-year NRL deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/nrl-keaon-koloamatangi-signs-with-dragons-from-rabbitohs/106202500</link><description>Dragons supporters will have to wait until 2027 to see Keaon Koloamatangi wearing the Red V, but the club describes his signing as the "biggest" in their recent history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed9ce3b0406bc0a0762d38d5e4b6f92</guid></item><item><title>Woman who lost home in Koolewong bushfire reunited with cat seriously injured in blaze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/koolewong-cat-sassy-injured-in-nsw-bushfires-on-road-to-recovery/106202244</link><description>Sassy the cat was almost killed when a bushfire razed a Koolewong home on NSW's Central Coast. Now, the lucky pet has been reunited with her family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">655f04089e2ac7fcb3a3b0f3e05c923e</guid></item><item><title>US cuts number of vaccines recommended for children including flu, hepatitis A and B</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/us-changes-vaccine-advice-for-children/106202478</link><description>The US government takes the unprecedented step of cutting the number of vaccines it recommends for every child, a move long sought by Health Secretary Robert F Kennedy Jr. But medical groups say it undermines protections against diseases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d878d401a8589bb4ad51f1bb7e74fa83</guid></item><item><title>Future of historic Paringa Bridge uncertain as it nears 100-year anniversary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/paringa-bridge-future-uncertain-river-murray/106197800</link><description>South Australia's only vertical-lift bridge has been unable to rise for more than a week due to a mechanical malfunction, affecting holiday-makers and locals alike.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2374dc8a311dc3a7c38dab862a46ed90</guid></item><item><title>Three NFL teams sack coaches on league's traditional Black Monday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/three-nfl-teams-sack-coaches-browns-raiders-cardinals/106202876</link><description>For struggling NFL teams, the end of the regular season triggers an annual exercise in bloodletting known around the league as Black Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edaad378af111f690b8894efe6821b89</guid></item><item><title>Former Queensland senator Ron 'Bozzie' Boswell dies aged 85</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/former-queensland-senator-ron-boswell-nationals/100104534</link><description>Known as "Bozzie" to his mates and colleagues, Mr Boswell's political career spanned three decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6ba7206268efa5b012eaf2bd0f93624</guid></item><item><title>Man charged in connection to alleged Hanukkah car arson in Melbourne's south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/hanukkah-car-alleged-arson-arrest-st-kilda-east/106203066</link><description>A man is charged after an alleged arson attack on a vehicle with a Hanukkah decoration on Christmas morning in Melbourne's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">452095e39da6542d075c9c43a35624de</guid></item><item><title>Police appeal for information on 2012 disappearance of Kalgoorlie-Boulder man Charlie Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/charlie-park-disappearance-wa-police-appeal-for-information/106201662</link><description>Fourteen years after Charlie Park disappeared in regional WA, detectives have reopened the case and are calling for information from the community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ef16feed52527efc5e1fb50da63a0ed</guid></item><item><title>BlueScope Steel weighing up $13 billion takeover by Kerry Stokes's SGH and US partner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/bluescope-13-billion-takeover-bid-by-stokes-sgh-us-steelmaker/106202730</link><description>Kerry Stokes-controlled firm SGH has launched a $13.2 billion takeover bid for BlueScope Steel, in partnership with a US steelmaker.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9cd553dbb824a883ccd91d871eba7e6</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal mother of five identified after death in NT police watch house</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/nt-indigenous-woman-identified-death-in-custody-tennant-creek/106201448</link><description>A Sydney-based law firm says it is representing the family of a 44-year-old Aboriginal woman who died in custody at the Tennant Creek police watch house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acd19c10c7c229b3ecd8e6257a7c199b</guid></item><item><title>Denmark and Greenland PMs condemn Trump's territorial ambitions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/denmark-and-greenland-pms-condemn-trump-s-territorial-ambitions/106203154</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5513a4fb1df7d2930c5e6aa5ff3eb34f</guid></item><item><title>EU, Britain join condemnation of sexual deepfake images created with Grok AI</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/eu-britain-join-condemnation-of-grok-ai-sexual-images/106203054</link><description>A digital undressing spree on Elon Musk's social media site has prompted investigations from countries including France, India and Malaysia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f654a8e793018da7efcde345435c3c43</guid></item><item><title>South Australian MP Nick McBride will contest state election after assault charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/mp-nick-mcbride-home-detention-bail-decision-/106201364</link><description>South Australian independent MP Nick McBride says he will run for re-election, as he remains on home detention after spending 10 days behind bars for an alleged assault against his wife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99cc8ee41c421db2557998824483a304</guid></item><item><title>Who is Cilia Flores? The woman by Nicolás Maduro's side until Donald Trump threw them in detention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/nicolas-maduros-wife-cilia-flores-never-far-from-power-/106199366</link><description>Her husband Nicolás Maduro calls her Venezuela's "first combatant" because she is not just a spouse, but a fellow fighter in the Chavism movement and a political player in her own right.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">516521070bcce88d706dbeb440dfaea2</guid></item><item><title>NSW Liberal leader Kellie Sloane announces new shadow cabinet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/nsw-kelly-sloane-liberal-party-shadow-cabinet/106202696</link><description>The opposition leader says she does not consider the gender breakdown of her shadow ministry, which has 16 men and 10 women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4176766c46085151e2556aa3ac80b248</guid></item><item><title>Venezuela left as 'potential powder keg' after Maduro capture, experts say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/what-could-happen-in-venezuela-next-after-maduro-capture/106199800</link><description>The US capture of Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro has left the country with an uncertain future, sparked concern among regional neighbours and could embolden other countries in territorial disputes, some experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cdac61e2198b0888c01d59c64824bde</guid></item><item><title>Madison Keys, Aryna Sabalenka kick off Australian summer of tennis with wins at Brisbane International</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/brisbane-international-madison-keys/106203350</link><description>Defending Australian Open champion Madison Keys and last year's runner up Aryna Sabalenka both got their Australian summer off to winning starts with straight-sets victories at the Brisbane International.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a7a6bd704fac9f604729a9fa583f543</guid></item><item><title>Actor Mickey Rourke turns to crowdfunding to avoid eviction from LA rental</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/mickey-rourke-crowd-funding-to-avoid-eviction/106203308</link><description>The actor, who faced accusations of homophobia and inappropriate behaviour on set last year, could now lose his home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3c2ee270a5a454027aaf7c1bcd5bc4a</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese doesn't rule out calling royal commission into Bondi terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/anthony-albanese-doesnt-rule-out-royal-commission-bondi-attack/106203368</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese does not rule out calling a royal commission into the Bondi Beach terrorist attack, but says his immediate priority is the review of intelligence and security agencies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28656b90ee40aa91243855a4aec8d59f</guid></item><item><title>Here's how sinkholes can form underground long before anyone realises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/sinkhole-explainer-environment-erosion-soil/106202498</link><description>The sudden collapse of a sinkhole in Melbourne's north-east left residents shocked on Tuesday. Here's an explanation of how and why they form.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b240d0d648a4f0432199dbb426a7fbb</guid></item><item><title>Public library visitor numbers return to pre-COVID levels as cost-of-living crisis bites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/public-libraries-australia-visitors-up-cost-of-living-crisis/106152152</link><description>Public libraries in Australia are experimenting with inventive ways to attract new members — but a lack of funding means they must do more with less.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e273b68565ad26ab3ff69f3d903723a</guid></item><item><title>After Venezuela, Donald Trump's other threats ring alarms around the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/after-venezuela-donald-trumps-other-threats/106203334</link><description>Donald Trump is talking about where US forces might venture next. But one of his cabinet secretaries could provide the clearest clues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">250a454241e20cae5504c394f87e089d</guid></item><item><title>Disappearance of outback woman declared major crime by SA Police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/trisha-graf-disappearance-major-crime/106203084</link><description>Investigators hold "grave fears" for Trisha Graf's wellbeing, after she was last seen in the early hours of December 12.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53ac6c7f04c6416e1c39097e6243a106</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police commissioner extends restrictions on Sydney protests for another fortnight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/nsw-police-protest-restrictions-decision-mal-lanyon/106203890</link><description>The NSW police commissioner will extend temporary protest restrictions across Sydney for another two weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0745c4340b305515c7295e0f60908cc</guid></item><item><title>WA Police raid Bunbury tobacconist after suspected firebomb of different vape store</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/police-raid-tobacco-shop-bunbury-after-vape-store-incident/106199506</link><description>Police seize vapes and cigarettes from the South West WA store days after two different shops were destroyed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74b2a96d2b8637c8c416829ecffeb71c</guid></item><item><title>Ben Austin died in a cricketing tragedy. His parents Jace and Tracey blame no-one as they speak out for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/ben-austins-tragic-death-parents-jace-and-tracey-speak-out/106203078</link><description>Ben Austin died in late October after a being struck by a cricket ball. For the first time his parents speak exclusively about the incident and their belief no-one is to blame for the tragic accident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f56edd19cac4ec08635e690f74444c07</guid></item><item><title>Some NSW farmers say 10 guns are not enough ahead of planned restrictions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/some-nsw-farmers-say-10-guns-are-not-enough-firearms-cap/106203318</link><description>New gun laws in NSW will limit farmers to 10 guns but the industry says this is not enough, and the change could see "a whole lot more firearms and ammunition" moving between farms in vehicles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f530343703d6e087769daf3a394e93af</guid></item><item><title>Sam Groth to relinquish deputy Liberal leadership at February party room meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/sam-groth-to-step-down-deputy-liberal-leader-february/106204434</link><description>The outgoing MP will vacate the deputy leadership role in February, clearing the way for a refreshed leadership team to carry the opposition to this year's election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dc93df5e6ebe8534501516dabb634d1</guid></item><item><title>Bondi terror attack royal commission pressure trumps Albanese's beliefs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/bondi-terror-attack-royal-commission-anthony-albanese/106202808</link><description>Whether or not Anthony Albanese believes a federal royal commission is necessary, or even the best use of resources, is now politically irrelevant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fd413938019ae14f86ed8d2268fdb30</guid></item><item><title>Teen faces court over Baldivis convenience store arson linked to illegal tobacco trade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/teen-charged-arson-attack-baldivis-convenience-store/106204496</link><description>A boy who allegedly set fire to a Baldivis convenience store may be facing threats from organised crime figures, Perth Children's Court hears.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef902b7ab40b6d39d9ea83f52d1c0efa</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith treats Sydney to a Smudge Day, in all its weird and wonderful glory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/ashes-fifth-test-day-three-steve-smiths-smudge-day/106203528</link><description>Steve Smith was at his bizarre best on day three in Sydney, grinding England into the dust with his scintillating strokeplay and trademark oddness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">323f9319839ca877e27543eeb68bc9df</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith plays his greatest hits as Will Jacks drops sitter and Ben Stokes burns reviews— quick hits from day three of the SCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/ashes-quick-hits-day-three-scg-test/106202476</link><description>Steve Smith plays all his greatest hits en-route to a century as England suffers in the field on all fronts. Here are your quick hits from day three.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b94f234b7a07d22d230ae94a78f3a7d2</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/tuesday-finance-with-david-chau/106204516</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af844bcc6a4cee1825a23893cb37c003</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios out of Brisbane International as reality of multiple surgeries hits home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/nick-kyrgios-out-brisbane-international/106204148</link><description>Nick Kyrgios limped out of the Brisbane International at the first hurdle as the 30-year-old's ailing body lets him down once again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">def25752ecb77df1a086f86ca64f48de</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Jenna the second system to lash Cocos Keeling Islands in less than two weeks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/cocos-tropical-cyclone-jenna-keeling-islands-indian-ocean/106203486</link><description>Residents of the islands clean up following heavy rain and winds brought by Tropical Cyclone Jenna, less than two weeks another system battered the region on Christmas day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd6ee8f687d014634b9cb4ac57cf1730</guid></item><item><title>Human remains found in search for snorkeller missing off WA's Ledge Point</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/human-remains-found-in-search-for-snorkeller-missing-wa/106204822</link><description>Police confirm human remains have been found washed ashore north of Perth, believed to be those of a 32-year-old man missing since New Year's Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">115d2e3da7e9c4da7c8cc4508e5df6e4</guid></item><item><title>The tragic death of young cricketer, Ben Austin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/the-tragic-death-of-young-cricketer-ben-austin/106204520</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9c63ee090c555390c147aaa8b6f089c</guid></item><item><title>What are Nicolás Maduro and Cilia Flores alleged to have done?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/drug-trafficking-allegations-against-nicolas-maduro/106202616</link><description>The US has justified the seizure of deposed Venezuelan leader Nicolás Maduro and wife Cilia Flores by arguing they had breached US domestic law. So what exactly have they been accused of doing?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">941caf9bf09b2b36e2322b47582fc864</guid></item><item><title>Stuart Clark denies confrontation with Cricket Australia chief Todd Greenberg over controversial comments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/cricket-stuart-clark-todd-greenberg-controversial-comments/106205010</link><description>Stuart Clark opens up on his conversation with Cricket Australia chief Todd Greenberg after his stinging criticism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73e49b8eeecfd23e60b4e690b997ae88</guid></item><item><title>National freight routes affected after train partially derails in South Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/national-freight-routes-affected-train-derails-south-australia/106205122</link><description>Several train wagons have derailed in South Australia, affecting key freight services connecting the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b50b43777a15a670b76909a8d5c9a8cf</guid></item><item><title>Australia's spot booked at United Cup quarter finals after De Minaur's high-pressure double act</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/de-minaur-dazzles-to-restore-australias-cup-hopes/106205120</link><description>Twin wins from world No.6 Alex de Minaur have dragged Australia off the canvas and into the United Cup quarter-finals with a do-or-die victory over Czechia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34a9d1647547c2c1fe6030a93748a2c7</guid></item><item><title>US set to back Ukraine defence coalition if peace deal made with Russia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/coalition-of-the-willing-paris-ceasefire-defence-coalition-us/106205340</link><description>A draft statement outlines what Ukraine's allies could commit to if Russia attacks its neighbour again in the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b290e391153bf910a66318327fd97287</guid></item><item><title>Fire safety inspections lapsed for years at Swiss bar where 40 died in New Year's blaze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/fire-safety-inspections-lapsed-for-years-at-swiss-bar/106205302</link><description>Swiss authorities admitted that fire safety inspections hadn't been carried out since 2019 at Crans-Montana bar where 40 people died on New Year's Eve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">203c64a84bd26fbac5e8e795ee2f8b36</guid></item><item><title>European leaders rally behind Greenland amid threats of a Trump take-over</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/european-leaders-back-greenland-after-trump-threats/106205394</link><description>The US president and his officials are continuing to push for an American take over of the Danish territory, saying the island is needed for national security.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ec6b2a38e5d7036a528511a65d3cf0c</guid></item></channel></rss>