<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 08:57:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Oscars to stream exclusively on YouTube from 2029, academy says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/oscars-to-stream-exclusively-on-youtube-from-2029/106156210</link><description>In a seismic shift for one of television's marquee events, the Academy Awards will depart US broadcaster ABC and begin streaming on YouTube, beginning in 2029.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b2a3bea8d3ea1606da38930c85634bc</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill arts community left in the lurch following funding cuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/broken-hill-arts-community-left-in-lurch-following-arts-cuts/106126872</link><description>Malyangapa Baaka Wiimpatja artist Leroy Johnson says the axing of an arts grant, which he is the last recipient of, has left the Broken Hill arts community feeling unsupported.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b3a6fee31b695634ba5cca51ecf993a</guid></item><item><title>Outback Farm stars finish first barley harvest at Central Australian farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/outback-farm-stars-barley-harvesting-at-athelle/105910900</link><description>Amid the red dirt, termite mounds and buffel grass, the first barley harvest is finished at Central Australia's Athelle Outback Hideaway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4efdcac86120cd9033a291516f7e54b</guid></item><item><title>Crime in Victoria continues to rise, driven by an increase in thefts and family violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/vic-crime-stats-victoria-machete-ban/106156470</link><description>The latest statistics show crime in Victoria is at its highest level since the Crime Statistics Agency started keeping records 20 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b90625f57a38f252951ec3fadc26a80</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Ben Stokes cramps, DRS woes continue as Pat Cummins, Nathan Lyon claim wickets on dominant day two at Adelaide Oval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/adelaide-ashes-test-day-two-live-updates/106156540</link><description>Ben Stokes has dragged his battered, cramping body to the close on day two of the third Ashes Test, with the tourists chances of victory hanging by a thread.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a7a17505140fd3d4d2be613d8f7ef43</guid></item><item><title>NT Police doubles reward for information on missing mother-of-two Angie Fuller to $500k</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/nt-police-angie-fuller-missing-person-reward-increase/106155860</link><description>NT Police has doubled its reward for information related to the disappearance of Angie Fuller, almost three years after her suspected murder in outback Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94a3c02c77d24d73932b9d0604eaac42</guid></item><item><title>Woodside chief executive Meg O'Neill resigns in move to BP</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/meg-oneill-resigns-as-woodside-ceo-to-join-bp/106156568</link><description>The chief executive of Perth-based oil and gas producer Woodside, Meg O'Neill, resigns from the company effective immediately in order to take up the same role at BP.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db976d0815d4331ccd3cfeda4efde02d</guid></item><item><title>Coalition 'flabbergasted' by Labor's response to calls for Bondi royal commission into antisemitism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/labor-brushes-aside-calls-for-antisemitism-inquiry/106156446</link><description>The opposition criticises the government for brushing aside calls for a royal commission into antisemitism as pressure mounts on Prime Minister Anthony Albanese to act in the wake of the deadly terror attack on Sydney's Jewish community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8428a4bb199dae7c9f208b323a41741f</guid></item><item><title>Albanese announces tougher hate speech laws in wake of Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/albanese-announces-tougher-hate-speech-laws-after-bondi-terror/106157020</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has announced sweeping reforms to crack down on antisemitism in the wake of the deadly terror attack on Sydney's Jewish community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb1481dd3d507d8f207dcaf53fabf32a</guid></item><item><title>Two years out from FIFA's equal prize goal, the men's tournament's pool will be six times that of the women's</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/fifa-world-cup-prizemoney-six-times-more-for-men-tournament/106156952</link><description>FIFA has announced a record prize money pool for the 2026 men's World Cup, but the figures are dwarfed by the riches on offer for the biggest club competitions, and fly in the face of the deadline for parity with the women's tournament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f61b5b4739119d707026638fb1a5d04</guid></item><item><title>Netwealth strikes ASIC deal to compensate First Guardian investors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/netwealth-strikes-asic-deal-to-compensate-first-guardian-losses/106156744</link><description>Financial services company Netwealth has agreed to pay more than $100 million to more than 1,000 clients who invested in the failed First Guardian super fund through its platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ead504871a8071956e3651af1208fbd1</guid></item><item><title>The best films of 2025: From gory horror to sugar-rush animation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/best-films-of-2025/106143092</link><description>From Australian-made gore to sugar-rush animation, here are the films that had our critics seated and watching this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad1b57ad13abb1e0cf26196589f6c8d2</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Alex Carey's DRS controversy leaves experts questioning use of 'Snicko' technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/ashes-drs-real-time-snicko-alex-carey-adelaide-test/106156654</link><description>The use of "Snicko" in the Ashes is questioned after yet another DRS controversy in the third Ashes Test frustrates England and helps Alex Carey to a Test century.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b03ebceb2f178654fa59208f1e08226</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr scores the winner as Chelsea makes it through to Women's Champions League quarterfinals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/sam-kerr-scores-the-winner-for-chelsea-in-womens-cl/106158026</link><description>Sam Kerr heads in the winner as Chelsea secures a spot in the Women's Champions League quarterfinals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a30653c9718b291a83ae7e7ee3b67482</guid></item><item><title>X payments incentivised misinformation in wake of Bondi shooting, expert says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/expert-says-x-incentivising-misinformation-bondi-shooting/106152144</link><description>US social media platform X incentivised the spread of inflammatory misinformation in the wake of the Bondi Beach shootings, a digital media expert has said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8751dbc55d2a8c36b53eedab5e615bb7</guid></item><item><title>New large-scale battery approval laws in Queensland draw mixed reaction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/what-new-large-scale-battery-approval-laws-mean-for-queensland/106156666</link><description>There have been big changes in the way battery energy storage systems are assessed in Queensland. Some rural communities applaud the shift, while industry groups say it risks investment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d3dfb5f04d211200e82d3945eb0d400</guid></item><item><title>Humbled Albanese shifts gear as Jewish community's anger builds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/anthony-albanese-antisemitism-press-conference-bondi/106158612</link><description>This was a humbled prime minister. Showing contrition, some regret, and an acknowledgement more could have been done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a35623b9f1fa29f6533d76df8584ecf</guid></item><item><title>Optus slapped with 21 recommendations following Triple Zero outage linked to two deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/optus-releases-triple-zero-report-david-taylor-analysis/106158108</link><description>Kerry Schott's report into the Triple Zero outage debacle increases pressure on Optus to implement 21 recommendations, some of them "urgent", and highlights numerous errors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd3859e8c3a83ab01d4c2b17790f44cc</guid></item><item><title>South Coast WA towns brace for booming angler numbers as West Coast fishery closes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/south-coast-angler-surge-ahead-of-fishery-closure/106152490</link><description>South Coast towns are calling for more funding to cope with a surge of recreational fishers as the region prepares to shut down recreational and commercial fishing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28e4f25d18ee7f34d1982808059f3a94</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous community mourns Stolen Generation mission site destroyed by fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/mogumber-mission-stolen-generation-site-damaged-fire/106150974</link><description>Parts of WA's Indigenous community are in mourning, while others have mixed feelings, after a former mission where members of the Stolen Generation were institutionalised was partly destroyed in a bushfire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8a6abceac33c462c6755e73bde195cb</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters put out 'ferocious' 30m tall blaze at Forster oyster business</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/police-investigate-fire-at-forster-oyster-business-christmas/106157276</link><description>A NSW oyster grower is left reeling after tens of thousands of dollars' worth of equipment went up in flames just a week away from Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e2d415f3e52b07daeafcbf18770471b</guid></item><item><title>NT government's tourism permit for Lorella Springs Wilderness Park 'in excess of its powers', federal court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/nt-lorella-springs-tourism-permit-under-review-federal-court/106158346</link><description>The future of an isolated tourism hotspot home to stunning waterfalls and ancient rock art is uncertain following a Federal Court hearing in Darwin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6b5cf83771d56ecc607988f963b9ceb</guid></item><item><title>US approves largest ever multi-billion-dollar arms package for Taiwan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/us-approves-largest-ever-weapons-spending-for-taiwan/106158962</link><description>The United States has approved its largest ever weapons package for Taiwan which is under increasing military pressure from China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0afaf9f65ad62333010998a4d0e9d52e</guid></item><item><title>'Children aren't born antisemitic': Education review aims to make Jewish students safer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/antisemitism-education-taskforce-review-david-gonski/106158642</link><description>The focus will turn from the threats outside the gate to those some critics say are embedded within education from a lack of Holocaust education to the harassment of Jewish students at universities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c28629c71488122314f4634803c7887</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Government details 'value capture' mechanisms to fund Suburban Rail Loop east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/victorian-government-suburban-rail-loop-value-capture/106158982</link><description>The Victorian government turns to developer contributions and car park levies as it tries to raise more than $10 billion in funding for the first stage of the Suburban Rail Loop.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42bd9034870f97187799cd6e0f36c8e0</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: DRS madness in Adelaide Test as Jamie Smith survives, then gets out after shambolic reviews</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/drs-madness-jamie-smith-adelaide-ashes-test/106159504</link><description>A series of strange decisions by umpires further erodes any trust in the DRS process as day two at the Adelaide Oval devolves into "shambles" and "chaos".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e5c2a27ce8a53f03b7f1460dfb9e536</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Day predicted to be scorcher in Perth with top of 39 degrees predicted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/christmas-day-perth-weather-city-to-swelter/106159466</link><description>With only seven more sleeps until the big day, Western Australia looks like being the hottest capital city in the nation this Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdfe5017133ef9d9e011c289172be07c</guid></item><item><title>How to handle awkward comments and conversations this Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/handling-awkward-comments-and-conversations-this-christmas/106089872</link><description>While your Instagram feed says the holidays are about joy and love, for many people Christmas is a time of managing tricky family members, inappropriate comments and probing questions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bc0df96a730c250545430b3882f82d8</guid></item><item><title>Lucky few Zone RV customers rejoice after receiving caravans from collapsed manufacturer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/some-zone-rv-customers-collect-caravans-despite-collapse/106151986</link><description>People who fully paid before the company collapsed can receive their vans if they pay an extra fee, while the majority of customers remain in limbo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d252b499c53d44089413bc79dd642917</guid></item><item><title>Snicko's issues, Archer argues with Stokes and catching controversy — quick hits from day two of the third Ashes Test at Adelaide Oval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/ashes-adelaide-oval-quick-hits-day-two-archer-stokes-snicko/106156806</link><description>Ben Stokes and Jofra Archer share a robust conversation, Snicko is decried as "the worst ever" and another catching controversy. Here are the quick hits from day two of the third Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcb3884c4d515195fd8c242745419262</guid></item><item><title>Snicko circus distracts in Adelaide as Australia sends England sliding towards Ashes oblivion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/snicko-circus-distracts-england-slides-ashes-adelaide-day-two/106158348</link><description>The circus comes to town in Adelaide with technological madness marring a second day which, more importantly, saw England wilt again and Australia tighten its grip on the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc1ead655fe8dfe21518a7f410576c3b</guid></item><item><title>Tropical disease melioidosis rebranded 'melio' after record-breaking year for soil-borne bacteria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/tropical-disease-melioidosis-rebranded-melio-/106157064</link><description>Cases of melioidosis in Cairns have set records this year, and authorities are uncertain why. But one survivor has joined a campaign to start a conversation about safety as the rains return in the north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">955ddfc1328853d6e419c39ac0beb7a2</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106159216</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b41ae5d6f0b8341cc9c3d373f494549</guid></item><item><title>Queensland mother accused of staging drowning death of four-year-old son committed to stand trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/tara-maree-richardson-committed-for-trial-son-found-in-pool/106160022</link><description>Tara Maree Richardson is charged with the 2021 murder of Tarrin O'Sullivan, with prosecutors alleging the boy was killed before being placed into the water at Munbura, south of Mackay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63f73f18022f7712ab91d97a46c19be3</guid></item><item><title>Inquest hears nothing could have been done in 'rare, tragic' baby's death at Atherton Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/inquest-into-death-of-newborn-at-atherton-hospital/106159620</link><description>An inquest has been examining the death of a newborn at Atherton Hospital and whether the care the mother and baby received were in any way responsible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05ad532b556233f4f62ffa25201f4db8</guid></item><item><title>Australian man Lamar Ahchee sentenced to 12 years in prison for role in Bali cocaine-smuggling plot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/lamar-achchee-sentenced-12-years-in-jail-cocaine-smuggling/106160268</link><description>An Australian man is sentenced to 12 years in a Bali prison for his role in trafficking cocaine into the country in Lindt chocolate wrappers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a17afa13de67b8c5f7cad4c9dc04de23</guid></item><item><title>Security experts say hate speech crackdown may 'constrict' preachers promoting violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/hate-speech-crackdown-welcome-as-labor-warned-laws-must-be-used/106155900</link><description>Experts say the federal government must actually use new laws being finalised this summer to crack down on hate speech and so-called "hate preachers" in the wake of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34fb8c1b3b2094c7d69a7a13a1c1ae7c</guid></item><item><title>Signs the algal bloom that's devastated our beaches could be diminishing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/is-the-worst-of-the-algal-bloom-over/106159452</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1b419093c29c764b432dd2523f021ad</guid></item><item><title>One week on, how well is the social media ban working?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/one-week-on-how-is-the-social-media-ban-working-/106159430</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8a342aceb66026ad31db8aa3d9278f6</guid></item><item><title>Yoshua Bengio explains why AI could become a threat to humanity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/yoshua-bengio-explains-why-ai-could-become-a-threat-to-humanity-/106159442</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">111e26eb49a84be3db245ba5adfc2025</guid></item><item><title>Police called to Mordialloc again after reports of assaults near pier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/victoria-police-mordialloc-pier-assault-young-people/106160536</link><description>Police have again been called to the Melbourne bayside suburb of Mordialloc, a day after reports of a brawl involving more than 100 teenagers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">391289b209db692692dc509e8c89a1ff</guid></item><item><title>Extra $42.6 million for mental health support after Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/extra-funds-for-mental-health-support-after-bondi-terror-attack/106160596</link><description>A temporary mental health centre will be set up in Bondi offering free walk-in services to help Australians grieving and traumatised by the deadly terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40e9bb859fa1f6720f1100846a5ca6b3</guid></item><item><title>French doctor jailed for poisoning 30 patients, including children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/french-court-jails-dr-death-30-patients-poisoned/106160720</link><description>Frederic Pechier's youngest victim, a four-year-old, survived two cardiac arrests during routine tonsil surgery in 2016.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b83fabf3e6844b123c26ef92e0adb2cd</guid></item><item><title>Trump Media group buys fusion power company for $9bn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/truth-social-buys-fusion-power-company/106161116</link><description>The US president's company also operates a number of cryptocurrency-related financial products and owns social media platform Truth Social.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a68041fb7d16b0605b364fcc3e33179</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: An adventurous koala, a chaotic Lionel Messi tour and a Trump blockade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/abc-weekly-news-quiz-dec-19/106157746</link><description>Another week, another quiz. Are you ready to test yourself?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9c2b8256d5eb4e0e1b7d8c5c5bd3839</guid></item><item><title>Tougher hate speech laws used four times before government vowed to rework them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/hate-speech-laws-used-four-times-since-february/106148170</link><description>Strenthened federal hate speech laws that the government held up as evidence it acted on antisemitism have been used four times since February, with it now conceding they do not go far enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4ebc3e8e2d3a8d267cda8a13f76b434</guid></item><item><title>ASIO's 'grim reality' as it picks over Bondi intelligence gaps</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/asio-grim-reality-bondi-intelligence-gaps/106153836</link><description>As Australia's intelligence agencies look back over how the Bondi attackers were missed, a "grim reality" of their jobs confronts the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10a47d9964fcd5dba6fd8c4df5da74e7</guid></item><item><title>Patients allege rape, beatings and staff cover-ups at Brisbane mental hospital in damning report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/qld-wolston-park-report-mental-health/106158032</link><description>Wolston Park closed in 2001, but, for decades, it has been at the centre of disturbing allegations of abuse and chemical restraint. Now, patients' stories have been published alongside a report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10b1ff649c9c9da6f5dc381095630a39</guid></item><item><title>Former police officer claims he warned of Bondi terror attack a decade ago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/nsw-former-police-officer-bondi-beach-terror-warning/106157580</link><description>Steve Buttel says he told his bosses "it was only a matter of time" before there would be a terror attack on Bondi's Jewish community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1caf77ec257e39df34d086c49436dcdb</guid></item><item><title>AHPRA puts practice conditions on neurosurgeon Greg Malham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/ahpra-practice-conditions-neurosurgeon-greg-malham/106158256</link><description>Doctor Greg Malham, who was terminated from a Melbourne private hospital following an ABC investigation into his behaviour, will have to undertake mentoring sessions to continue practising.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c43912e422e890a6413eb57a100b1320</guid></item><item><title>Indonesian influencers glamorise life and earnings in Australia but the reality falls short</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/whv-social-media-influencers-create-high-hopes-for-indonesians-/106122868</link><description>Influencers push a false promise of easy money and a better life in Australia with a Work and Holiday Visa, inspiring young Indonesians to take extreme measures to chase an almost unrealisable dream.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec98971920736558ada3e4ae9293985c</guid></item><item><title>Achievements and regrets: Peter Malinauskas and Ashton Hurn reflect on 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/peter-malinauskas-ashton-hurn-reflect-on-2025/106158048</link><description>As the political year winds up, Premier Peter Malinauskas and Liberal leader Ashton Hurn have much to contemplate over their Christmas lunch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea89d871ff67dbac4920d1bee448622a</guid></item><item><title>More photos released on eve of Jeffrey Epstein files deadline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/democrats-release-photos-on-eve-of-epstein-files-deadline/106161190</link><description>US Democrats continue their drip-feed of material from sex predator Jeffrey Epstein’s estate, releasing more photos on the eve of a deadline for the full publication of the Epstein files.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f701626a063a1abada89e59606e5e33</guid></item><item><title>PM flags 'national day of mourning' for terror attack — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/bondi-beach-shooting-terrorist-attack-live-blog-december-19/106160710</link><description>Anthony Albanese says he will confirm a "national day of mourning" for the Bondi attack in the new year, and has declared Sunday, December 21 as a day of reflection to honour the victims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfeb98deb2a8d2cd40979ccd353b17f0</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese is forced into policy catch-up after Bondi atrocity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/anthony-albanese-jewish-community-bondi/106156698</link><description>In an extraordinary personal censure, Australia's Jewish community effectively denied Anthony Albanese the role of being the nation's chief public mourner in this week of national tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab47ad73169cf157b1c7d055826871f9</guid></item><item><title>Russell Crowe on the reappraisal of Master and Commander and its masculinity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/russell-crowe-on-master-and-commander-reappraisal/106156486</link><description>Master and Commander flopped in 2003 but is now hailed as a masterpiece. Discover why this epic is earning renewed respect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66a4d3a14b4e26b7aa93f7ae112ab387</guid></item><item><title>ANZ to pay $250m penalty, ASX finishes slightly up — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/asx-markets-business-live-news-dec19-2025/106161298</link><description>The Federal Court has increased penalties to be paid by ANZ to $250 million, while the ASX closed slightly higher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a7fddbda2c27e3e1cb2d0ae17c336c0</guid></item><item><title>Queensland now third least-affordable state as even remote property prices rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/queensland-third-least-affordable-state-as-prices-keep-rising/106104852</link><description>The Ballini family made the move to regional Queensland where they are are paying half the mortgage they were in the south-east, but that's rapidly changing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36859b6ab934b6858364ddc5f972bfa8</guid></item><item><title>Queensland police investigating Nazi symbol and offensive words graffitied on Brisbane mosque</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/queensland-police-investigating-mosque-graffiti/106161260</link><description>Offensive words were also written on the Brisbane mosque, along with the swastika. WARNING: The following story contains an image of a Nazi symbol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4780fb654b418f545d7210716de14539</guid></item><item><title>Why a $2.5 billion surplus has created a migraine for the WA government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/wa-mid-year-budget-review-rita-saffioti/106158160</link><description>For most other governments, a $2.5 billion surplus would be news to shout from the rooftops — but in WA's case, it's a headache with little prospect of relief.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc29bb536e7d4b8d3d929920f53f6881</guid></item><item><title>NT Firearms Council pushes back on gun control debate after Bondi shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/nt-gun-law-changes-bondi-shooting-massacre-firearms-council/106157036</link><description>The Northern Territory Firearms Council is against limiting the number of weapons a person can own, as New South Wales parliament is set to discuss gun reforms in the wake of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63fa17090a47f44ad8e8e6197d85909c</guid></item><item><title>How the world reacted to the Bondi massacre, from the Middle East to Manila</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/how-world-reacted-to-bondi-massacre/106151664</link><description>The shock waves from Sunday's deadly terror attack at Bondi Beach have reverberated around the world from the Middle East to Moscow and Manila.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4258572528ca29c20001adca2704e9a7</guid></item><item><title>Prince William and Princess Catherine release 2025 Christmas card</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/prince-and-princess-of-wales-release-christmas-card-2025/106161436</link><description>The Prince and Princess of Wales have released a new family portrait to coincide with their annual Christmas card.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f6e483127b66aa726ea6e7f1466d32</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Travis Head scores century, Alex Carey a half-ton as Australia bat England out of third Ashes Test at Adelaide Oval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/ashes-adelaide-test-day-three-live-blog/106161670</link><description>Travis Head scores his fourth century in a row at Adelaide Oval, and Alex Carey scores a half-ton as Australia's lead passes 350 on another dominant Ashes day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c227938b347eba082c77baa574cdfc1</guid></item><item><title>House lost near Benalla as Victoria prepares for high fire danger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/house-lost-in-grassfire-near-benalla/106161500</link><description>One house and six sheds have been lost in a fire started by farm machinery at Goomalibee, near north-east Victorian town Benalla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b483fcb3d8f0d707c6bd020919a53865</guid></item><item><title>King Edward Memorial Hospital baby death review finds multiple failures in care provided to mother in labour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/king-edward-memorial-hospital-tommy-starkie-baby-death-review/106159992</link><description>A review into the death of newborn baby Tommy Starkie reveals multiple failures in the care provided to his mother during her labour at Perth's King Edward Maternity Hospital earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cab5ceddf88a744761075768b1ae515d</guid></item><item><title>Life on Adria Downs, one of Australia's most remote cattle stations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/life-on-one-of-australia-s-most-remote-cattle-stations/106155078</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d7fbcf81c588959cd0e9c828a30dba9</guid></item><item><title>Life on Adria Downs, one of Australia's most remote cattle stations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/life-on-remote-cattle-station-adria-downs-edge-of-simpson-desert/106113634</link><description>The idea of life out on the edge of the desert has pulled in young people from across the country and overseas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30aecf0298469be8c670668321a4088e</guid></item><item><title>Polly the pony spreads Christmas cheer in Sale aged care home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/polly-pony-sale-aged-care-home/106123742</link><description>A Welsh Shetland cross pony is spreading festive cheer — and stirring memories — during visits to an aged care home in eastern Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68763151c972423b282b7963af875a56</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government to continue pause on puberty blockers for new adolescent trans patients in public system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/qld-puberty-blockers-pause-trans-teenagers-to-continue/106161908</link><description>The Queensland government says it made the decision after considering a 530-page independent review into the evidence surrounding the treatments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9649e5db226eb3adc70c227e0d23c9c</guid></item><item><title>How to turn feelings of helplessness into support after the Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/showing-support-after-the-bondi-terror-attack/106144732</link><description>While you might be feeling a sense of helplessness after the attack at Bondi Beach, there are ways to convert those feelings into small acts of support and kindness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b80a9f2b4e6404531d9fddd5a3b2b165</guid></item><item><title>Prime minister announces 'largest' gun buyback scheme since Howard era</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/prime-minister-announces-national-gun-buyback-scheme/106162002</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has announced a national gun buyback scheme, days after a deadly terror attack on a Hanukkah celebration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c11240861c3ceb5d58dbe19f71f7daf5</guid></item><item><title>In pictures: Thousands honour Bondi victims in emotional paddle-out tribute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/bondi-terror-attack-paddle-out-in-pictures/106161604</link><description>Thousands of locals packed the Bondi beachfront for an emotional paddle-out in honour of the victims of Sunday's terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80b6bdcff0b11b7f238ce68b0cd09872</guid></item><item><title>Australian Cricketers Association calls for Snicko overhaul following Adelaide blunder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/cricket-union-snicko-adelaide-faulty/106162676</link><description>Australian Cricketers Association boss Paul Marsh has called for an investigation into Snicko, saying careers are being affected by the technology's lack of precision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ceaf99f984f811d439fa9a9313c4257</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder of his 88-year-old mother in Fern Bay, Newcastle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/man-charged-with-murder-of-his-88-year-old-mother-fern-bay-/106161282</link><description>Police say Thomas Andrew Tapley was his mother's carer and it is a tragic set of circumstances for the family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a26ea786a2b42912d0801203e8d85da4</guid></item><item><title>Long-running NT alcohol study recommends changes to costs and trading hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/alcohol-study-nt-reform-bottle-shop-costs-trading-hours-bdr/106153030</link><description>A major study into alcohol policy in the NT has recommended tightening bottle shop trading hours, raising the minimum price of alcohol and reforming the approach to individual liquor bans in the territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faf1e114544e966fb307519ec8b869d5</guid></item><item><title>Dimboola woman who told undercover police she gouged elderly man's eyes found not guilty of murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/murder-trial-jodie-hill-dimboola-supreme-court-wimmera/106135010</link><description>Jodie Hill wept as a Supreme Court jury found her not guilty of murder and manslaughter, follow a week of deliberations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c27523dda1ba63361998149b80edd8b3</guid></item><item><title>Nearly 500 small businesses seek assistance in dispute with digital platforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/meta-suspends-small-business-socials-account/106153840</link><description>The Small Business and Family Enterprise Ombudsman says he's seen a rise in small businesses disputes with digital platforms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">575c09b02f562780d30082f1c2ecee19</guid></item><item><title>Suspect in Brown University fatal shooting found dead in New Hampshire storage facility, officials say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/brown-university-shooting-suspect-found-dead/106163330</link><description>The suspect in last week's mass shooting at Brown University has been found dead from a self-inflicted gunshot wound, officials say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03aa8aee1e67b02a79262a38e836b4ad</guid></item><item><title>The PM has announced the 'largest' gun buyback since the Port Arthur massacre. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/australia-gun-buyback-2025-explained/106162936</link><description>Days after the Bondi terror attack, the federal government has announced a new national buyback scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af3bacfe919750a3d4e08d84c6c0e8a1</guid></item><item><title>Man resembling Bondi gunman Naveed Akram caught on Philippines CCTV in mid-November</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/hotel-staff-id-bondi-shooter-naveed-akram-in-davao/106163036</link><description>A man resembling Bondi gunman Naveed Akram has been captured on CCTV in Davao City in mid-November, as authorities continue to investigate the movements of him and his father, Sajid Akram, in the lead-up to the attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ed32a133aaab274b4b34574138c8774</guid></item><item><title>Family demands probe into NSW Police use of force after video of Dubbo arrest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/family-seeks-investigation-into-nsw-police-arrest/106144022</link><description>An Aboriginal man who was known by NSW Police to have mental health issues was hospitalised after his arrest over a traffic stop.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e251acd9086df2e30c92e78447a28001</guid></item><item><title>Communities rally to battle tragic fires near Ongerup and support each other in wake of tragedy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/communities-rally-to-battle-tragic-fires-near-ongerup/106158088</link><description>Following fatal fires in Western Australia's south earlier this week, stories are emerging of how homes were saved and communities rallied in the wake of tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98001542e748a825278a6c3b287c006e</guid></item><item><title>Bedford creditors vote to hand over reins to The Disability Trust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/bedford-creditors-vote-in-favour-of-new-operator/105943028</link><description>Creditors have voted to support the sale of Bedford to NDIS provider The Disability Trust, which would guarantee the jobs of 1,100 workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9a922696cb7e31d90763393c14da8bb</guid></item><item><title>Chris Scott re-signs as Geelong coach until the end of the 2029 AFL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/chris-scott-re-signs-with-geelong/106164740</link><description>Already the longest serving coach in Geelong history, Chris Scott's new deal with the club will put him in the company of some of the AFL's greatest ever mentors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4b20efa127af39d99150577e3a53ae1</guid></item><item><title>Ben Stokes slows down and blows up, Travis Head makes Harry Brook pay for his drop — quick hits from day three of third Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/ashes-test-england-australia-travis-head-harry-brook-quick-hits/106161810</link><description>Harry Brook drops Travis Head on 99, which would have only soured the mood of his captain, who started the day already pretty ticked off. Here are the quick hits from day three of the third Ashes Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17abe94dd547033d54d230dc18710d01</guid></item><item><title>Travis Head, the last of Australia's larrikins, revels in his Ashes summer of love</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/travis-head-summer-of-love-ashes-adelaide-day-three/106163328</link><description>Travis Head has become Australia's most beloved cricketer, and as another glorious Ashes century guided his team ever closer to the urn, he was eager to return the love.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09216a2fa13a29eff00df344ef2e870a</guid></item><item><title>The 'heroic' couple in twin coffins, a 'gifted musician' and a 'woman of integrity' laid to rest across Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/bondi-victims-funerals-sydney/106161406</link><description>A couple hailed as "heroes in every sense of the word", a "gifted musician" and a "woman of integrity" have been farewelled in ceremonies across Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45c9d9967cc59224e9c66194b5fe4bf3</guid></item><item><title>Marlinyu Ghoorlie native title group in Goldfields celebrates recognition as traditional owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/marlinyu-ghoorlie-recogised-traditional-owners-kalgoorlie/106158324</link><description>The result comes eight years after the native title claimant group first registered for native title, with a counterclaim by another group dismissed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7a64fcf1e4c5ed61e4447ce811ebbca</guid></item><item><title>Teens sentenced over deadly Wollongong street brawl fuelled by social media group chat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/wollongong-teens-sentenced-over-social-media-fuelled-brawl/106160012</link><description>A social media feud between teenage girls in Wollongong in 2023 erupted into a deadly street fight, leaving Kristie McBride dead and several teens now sentenced for her manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef38daa94195dd83aea57329916011ee</guid></item><item><title>Search suspended for deep-sea diver Timothy Bennett in Coral Sea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/search-suspended-for-deep-sea-diver-timothy-bennett-coral-sea/106164760</link><description>A professional deep-sea diver, with several fish species named in his honour, is remembered as a loving father and well-respected in the science community for his contributions to the study of fish species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cff240e4360bb7f080d72c372b643e3</guid></item><item><title>ABC News - Trusted Source of Latest News &amp; Headlines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/106165092</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf4dd05a8663342dc61f114f5c066608</guid></item><item><title>Smashed windscreen in remote SA unlikely caused by meteorite, museum says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/smashed-windscreen-unlikely-caused-by-a-meteorite/106163728</link><description>Scientists were hoping an object that smashed the windscreen of a self-driving car in October was a meteorite, but SA Museum's investigation says it remains a mystery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6fa23fca3359f35b6d3b27db2fa12d50</guid></item><item><title>Famine ends in Gaza, Integrated Food Security Phase Classification report says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/gaza-famine-ends-israel-hamas-ceasefire-holds/106165370</link><description>A report by the Integrated Food Security Phase Classification is still warning that over 100,000 children face malnutrition over the coming months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c6151ecb5e6bdd2178b63054f95c9d6</guid></item><item><title>Taipei Metro stabbing attack leaves at least three people dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/taipei-metro-stabbing-attack-leaves-at-least-three-people-dead/106165504</link><description>The suspect is also dead after falling from a building during a police chase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e69855cddd6e5cd5b274931d0967afa2</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese faces primary test of his prime ministership in Bondi response</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/anthony-albanese-bondi-terror-attack-jewish-community-safety/106156710</link><description>While the prime minister will forever struggle to shed the perception that he was too slow to recognise the threat to Australia's Jewish community, he is taking action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cd87a798462fffe818491a4a089e35b</guid></item><item><title>Today in history: Picasso painting worth millions stolen in daring art heist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/today-in-history-picasso-art-heist-brazil-2007/106143440</link><description>The 2007 Brazilian heist was not the last time a nimble thief made off with a Picasso. And as many Melburnians know, it certainly wasn't the first.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdf9b392c5353c4783705b64fcc9f41d</guid></item><item><title>Jewish man Gaby Silver never felt unsafe in Australia, then October 7 and Bondi happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/jewish-mans-life-after-october-7-and-rise-of-antisemitism/106163426</link><description>The rise in antisemitism in Australia since October 7 has reshaped the way Gaby Silver's family lives. After the Bondi attack, they're even more on edge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9851d21b89dc8f7cccb89b841ec74de</guid></item><item><title>The teacher, driver and host who helped strangers take refuge during the Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/nsw-bondi-beach-cafe-households-help-strangers-terror-attack/106154094</link><description>These are the stories of everyday people who stepped up during dark times, and of a community coming together when two gunmen sought to tear them apart on December 14.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34c2994bb9893ffb4129bdf4c7f89f1b</guid></item><item><title>How the Bondi shooters got access to now-banned guns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/how-the-bondi-shooters-got-access-to-now-banned-guns/106165084</link><description>With Australia's strict gun laws, how was Sajid Akram able to legally own the gun he was using to slaughter innocent people in Bondi on December 14?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">327eaa363877743b6d9ce2546bb346d0</guid></item><item><title>BOM Christmas weather forecast shows cool day in the east, searing heat in the west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/bom-christmas-weather-forecast/106163070</link><description>Australia is experiencing a smorgasbord of wild weather in the lead-up to Christmas, featuring extreme heat, humidity, severe thunderstorms, and tropical storms all on the cards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">504f34082ff519e7f1eba368acf1bc86</guid></item><item><title>Grace Tame demands law reform after Diocese of Ballarat cleared of vicarious liability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/grace-tame-campaign-to-change-vicarious-liability-laws/106049438</link><description>In every Australian state and the NT, churches cannot be held vicariously liable for historical child sexual abuse perpetrated by their priests. Grace Tame is leading the charge for change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e23edcbb74ce54f9058cc6c8c40fe844</guid></item><item><title>Coronial inquest into deaths of cultural leaders Big Brother and Little Brother recommends spit hood ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/australian-aboriginal-men-coronial-alice-springs-hospital/106163524</link><description>The NT coroner makes nine recommendations following an inquest into the deaths of two disabled Aboriginal brothers who spent a number of years homeless in Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4b688369100d2435e0a0d0e1020a9c3</guid></item><item><title>Environmental experts, detection dogs team up to protect native freshwater turtles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/environmental-experts-fight-for-freshwater-turtle-conservation/106091598</link><description>A team of environmental experts, Indigenous rangers and conservation detection dogs is working on recovering the population of native freshwater turtles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b061a8b99e175b4f025e0503dbe8a7f8</guid></item><item><title>Oxford evolutionary researcher says humans may have been kissing Neanderthals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/why-do-humans-kiss-has-scientists-puzzled/106162070</link><description>Why is swapping saliva something all human societies have normalised? Turns out kissing isn't just a human thing — all sorts of species appear to kiss, and new research suggests Neanderthals did it too.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">762208e206debcd0ceb6214694d71739</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne University Women's Football Club was once a powerhouse. Now it's at risk of folding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/melbourne-university-womens-football-club-at-risk-of-folding/106098428</link><description>Melbourne University is the latest women’s Aussie Rules club fighting for survival, but it is hoping intervention from an AFL executive can turn the club’s fortunes around.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3f071d8111dd0ba9981cb00395aae18</guid></item><item><title>Murgon residents 'at breaking point' during end-of-year crime spike</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/murgon-crime-spike-leaves-residents-at-breaking-point/106146606</link><description>The crime rate spikes every year around the holidays, according to the police. Tensions are rising in the Murgon community, as residents say they don't feel safe in their homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c291dafdc2bb6411078d2494857c394a</guid></item><item><title>Queensland family saves thousands of dollars after embracing the spirit of 'Thriftmas' over holiday period</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/queensland-family-prepares-for-second-hand-christmas/106155536</link><description>Rising expenses across the festive season have driven a family of five in Brisbane to set a rule to only purchase Christmas presents from second-hand stores — and they've been pleasantly surprised by the treasures they've uncovered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a698b3c24a2ff86ece2dd9e31e0d9cb8</guid></item><item><title>Former patients 'left waiting for justice' after damning report into Brisbane's Wolston Park Mental Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/wolston-park-mental-hospital-review-patients/106164118</link><description>Brisbane's Wolston Park Mental Hospital closed in 2001, but a 12-month review has shed light on its history of sexual abuse and patient mistreatment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35b74cdc101b0ce65c8769c1b3dea6dd</guid></item><item><title>How are Australian parents responding to the social media ban for under-16s?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/social-media-ban-teenagers-parents-respond/106163362</link><description>For some parents, the social media bans for under-16s have come as a relief. But others say they are fuelling conflict.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d0e1f980c1e1f5b8b0ab9069307bc9c</guid></item><item><title>Health and safety case against Tasmania's Adams gin distillery dismissed in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/adams-distillery-fire-health-and-safety-case-dismissed/105728508</link><description>A work health and safety case against a distillery in Perth, northern Tasmania, is dismissed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">576053b0239b5830d97cc46b4dd6a6fe</guid></item><item><title>Mourners and support services gather in Bondi as Anthony Albanese calls for unity — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/bondi-beach-shooting-terrorist-attack-live-blog-december-20/106165292</link><description>Hundreds of surf lifesavers have gathered on Bondi Beach to pay tribute to the victims of last Sunday's terrorist attack. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49576f64cb345b8d0f5d965367e8aeb1</guid></item><item><title>WA researchers find 'alarming number' of children with strep A</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/west-australian-study-strep-a-findings-kimberley-broome-derby/106149204</link><description>An infectious disease study hopes to see faster and earlier diagnosis of strep A to prevent chronic diseases in high-risk communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15ec0e83dcd9ac966c1d7c09d456e909</guid></item><item><title>Islamic State made headlines after being linked to the Bondi attack. Here's why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/why-islamic-state-back-in-news-link-to-bondi-2026-attack/106165328</link><description>What is this group, which once ruled a territorial "caliphate" and inspired attacks all over the world?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23a7781fd5ac752147430590cdd9699f</guid></item><item><title>Grace Lillian Lee weaves a path from the Torres Strait to Paris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/grace-lillian-lee-weaves-a-path-from-the-torres-strait-to-paris/106158378</link><description>Lee's woven, wearable art creations have catapulted her from Cairns and the Torres Strait to Paris, a bustling textile mecca more than 15,000 kilometres away.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f035e8cd3c98ce09e384b45807dd935</guid></item><item><title>The uninhabited Scottish isle where the sport of curling sources its most important resource</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/winter-olympics-2026-the-scottish-isle-used-for-curling/106165748</link><description>For all intents and purposes, Ailsa Craig looks like it has nothing to offer the human experience. But on its desolate shores, golden dreams are quietly being mined.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b459214afa31a99044fedb8a53b3f40b</guid></item><item><title>US strikes dozens of Islamic State targets in Syria, officials say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/us-strikes-dozens-of-islamic-state-targets-in-syria/106165794</link><description>Described as "a declaration of vengeance" by US Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth, the strikes come after Donald Trump vowed retaliation for an attack on US personnel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09ec6e6d885276f00ad6d95cabebccf5</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Nathan Lyon's massive wickets end England hopes of record run chase in third Test at Adelaide Oval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/ashes-third-test-day-four-live-blog/106165808</link><description>Three enormous wickets from Nathan Lyon leave Australia four wickets away from winning the Ashes after day four of the third Test at the Adelaide Oval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">369d9bef32c3e34602e80558d280f4e0</guid></item><item><title>How a Queensland family is pushing for change after a devastating loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/tyler-pask-firefighter-mens-mental-health-suicide-prevention-qld/106154520</link><description>Tyler Pask devoted his life to being an incredible father, selfless brother and a diligent emergency service worker for the Queensland Fire Department. Now his family is transforming their grief into encouraging other young men to access support for their mental health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e043b9ab1cce3b514337e5e776c53588</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian government faces questions over Pulse advertising spend after it asked for an election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/tasmanian-government-pulse-advertising-spend-questioned/106165120</link><description>The Tasmanian premier's department authorised more than $13,000 of taxpayer money to be spent with a local media organisation to promote the budget after the government asked for an election to be held, documents show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c34711e08607faed47b6a2b2c70d843</guid></item><item><title>Ambitious plan to share Carnarvon's food bowl both locally and statewide faces hurdles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/ambitious-plan-to-share-carnarvon-food-bowl-for-those-in-need/106122230</link><description>Carnarvon's fresh produce could help Western Australia's food insecurity crisis, but there is concern not enough is being done to address the issue locally first.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e0c57d3291083607501b742a9d01829</guid></item><item><title>Race discrimation commissioner Giridharan Sivaraman issues violence warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/giridharan-sivaraman-issues-racism-warning/106165932</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b57b103921fd834e696b13cdcc399be5</guid></item><item><title>Kalgoorlie the glittering prize for Frenchman Bruno Vincent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/frenchman-bruno-vincent-and-his-golden-kalgoorlie-dream/106153794</link><description>Bruno Vincent has spent his life searching for gold, so there was only one Australian city on his travel bucket list.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">581076f764038e0b5f97f7a1bdb5dc64</guid></item><item><title>Lifesaver discusses 'healing' moment as hundreds gathered for silent vigil at Bondi Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/-lifesaver-discusses-healing-moment-/106165992</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf6ad8fd9ec71ebfa33ede066e35b18e</guid></item><item><title>Why new Perth Glory coach Adam Griffiths might be Australian football's most interesting character</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/adam-griffiths-new-perth-glory-footballs-most-interesting-man/106163416</link><description>In a team struggling to retain fans, in a league battling for attention, newly appointed Perth Glory coach Adam Griffiths may just be the man with the answers for both problems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4057aeb87bd9dcb463f0d5788dd76bf2</guid></item><item><title>Rare pink platypus spotted in East Gippsland river</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/rare-pink-platypus-spotted-in-east-gippsland-river/106137316</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9501b542d7707b4027e32255d214fc5e</guid></item><item><title>Rare pink platypus spotted in East Gippsland river by Melbourne fisherman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/story-rare-albino-pink-platypus-found-in-east-gippsland-river/106106194</link><description>In a remote river in Victoria's east, a fisherman says he has encountered an ultra-rare pink platypus, one of only a handful ever sighted in the past 200 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2210570f1b72946b56f526c3f1ca81e4</guid></item><item><title>NSW Premier Chris Minns backs calls for royal commission into Bondi Beach terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/nsw-premier-backs-calls-for-royal-commission-into-bondi-attack/106165816</link><description>New South Wales Premier Chris Minns is supporting calls for a royal commission to be held into the Bondi Beach terror attack, which claimed the lives of 15 innocent people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d56d9150fa06febba672ef81d588aa64</guid></item><item><title>England slammed for sending assistant coaches to front media after 'nonsense' Ashes interview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/ashes-2025-jason-gillespie-slams-england-over-nonsense-presser/106166094</link><description>Australian Test cricket great Jason Gillespie slams England after a "contradictory" interview from an assistant coach following day three in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fd678fe46c14b16834ccd4fab0f790e</guid></item><item><title>In pictures: Surf lifesavers pay tribute to Bondi victims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/nsw-surf-lifesavers-pay-tribute-to-bondi-victims/106166140</link><description>Hundreds of surf lifesavers and lifeguards, many of whom responded to the Bondi terror attack, form a human chain in a moving tribute to the 15 people killed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">259f9d3e9b53d11c180ca7cec88ea48d</guid></item><item><title>Political reporter Samantha Dick summarises the prime minister's press conference</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/pm-albanese-press-conference/106166356</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfa5201e566abfbb375d982efcd53824</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu continues to rebuild one year after devastating earthquake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/vanuatu-marks-one-year-since-devastating-earthquake/106148676</link><description>Tourists are returning to Vanuatu a year on from a major catastrophe. But many demolished buildings are yet to be rebuilt and some locals are frustrated with the pace of repairs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64d21f1d0b5d95bccfdd147cae3ae0f7</guid></item><item><title>Epstein files contain new photo of former prince Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/new-photo-former-prince-andrew-mountbatten-windsor-epstein-files/106166672</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor, the former prince, appears in the first tranche of the so-called Epstein files.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6eecd6194d73f15e27e79dd511e68c0</guid></item><item><title>Focus on Bill Clinton in Epstein Files raises questions about how curated the documents were</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/white-house-pointing-at-clinton-after-epstein-files-release/106166576</link><description>The thousands of photos paint a picture of a life spent with the rich and famous but little that is incriminating to anyone but Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4450710bef7e28696e746ec81cb1c8da</guid></item><item><title>Men left 'shaken' and 'overwhelmed' after arrest in Liverpool intend to sue NSW Police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/victorian-men-arrested-liverpool-to-sue-nsw-police/106166008</link><description>The group were detained on Thursday after tactical police rammed a car in Liverpool in what was characterised as a precautionary measure following the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4d45fb72a0ba497067a9170be96af11</guid></item><item><title>Valentino Guseli wins snowboard halfpipe bronze at Copper Mountain World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/valentino-guseli-wins-halfpipe-bronze-copper-mountain/106166736</link><description>Valentino Guseli returns to half-pipe competition after 21 months to claim his 10th FIS World Cup podium and receive a huge confidence boost ahead of the Winter Olympic Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d85ee7b3e3194fb86a78553e91bc25ca</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the Trump-Epstein relationship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/what-we-know-about-the-trump-epstein-relationship/106166814</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6653a89f1ce96e1149075f44154e252f</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne takes miracle catch and Nathan Lyon breaks England's resistance — quick hits from day four of third Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/ashes-adelaide-test-quick-hits-marnus-labuschagne-nathan-lyon/106165884</link><description>Australia finishes day four needing four wickets to reclaim the Ashes thanks to Marnus Labuschagne and Nathan Lyon. Here are the quick hits from day four of the third Ashes Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">292785d1e6db9c09359cd50fe63753d6</guid></item><item><title>England abandons Bazball but is still no match for Australia with Ashes triumph imminent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/england-abandons-bazball-no-match-australia-ashes-adelaide/106166260</link><description>England's belated abandonment of Bazball gives it temporary life, but reveals a painful truth — no version of this team is a match for the soon-to-be victorious Australians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d308d23d201fb686a094091b31dc695b</guid></item><item><title>Former Pakistani PM Imran Khan and wife Bushra Bibi given 17-year jail sentence in new graft case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/imran-khan-bushra-bibi-sentenced-17-years-prison-graft-pakistan/106166948</link><description>The case against Imran Khan and his wife Bushra Bibi centres on the alleged misuse of luxury state gifts from Saudi Arabia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8475037508df624b19eee2f15eacd17e</guid></item><item><title>With heads bowed after the Bondi terror attack, now is the time to listen to the Jewish community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/bondi-massacre-time-to-listen-jewish-community-australia/106161492</link><description>If we are to inch towards unity, the more we pause to listen, the more sure-footed our path forward will be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbf74fcf2928d62907dba7bc4a5262f2</guid></item><item><title>As Sydney's Jewish community reels from the Bondi attack, the path forward is unclear</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/bondi-attack-sydney-jewish-community-darkness-light/106160056</link><description>As Sydney marks one week since the antisemitic Bondi attack, the Jewish community is grappling with the question of where to go from here.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a56da5b7fcfb7b6cfac78ccd5e369fe</guid></item><item><title>How Psy's billion-views trailblazer Gangnam Style presaged K-pop dominance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/psy-trailblazer-gangnam-style-presaged-k-pop-dominance/106157038</link><description>Who'd have guessed a South Korean man doing a goofy horse dance was a recipe for a global phenomenon? Thirteen years after it made YouTube history we revisit the legacy of Psy's Gangnam Style.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be097fcc494a0b907293bced095b78e9</guid></item><item><title>Christmas movies quiz: How well do you know festive films?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/christmas-movies-quiz/106163774</link><description>From Home Alone to Nightmare Before Christmas, how well do you know these Christmas classics?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f41ef1d4c848a74b2e5f33310af308a3</guid></item><item><title>Bondi mass shooting shows how extreme danger can spark bravery from bystanders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/heroes-bondi-shooting-official-advice-armed-attacks/106156678</link><description>Experts advise to "escape, hide, and tell" in a terrorist attack. These men and women did otherwise and saved lives when gunmen opened fire at Bondi Beach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e5f8b93a86aa9c6bde4a275cd02bb9a</guid></item><item><title>Spain uses an algorithm to rank how safe women are. Sometimes it's wrong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/spain-viogen-algorithm-women-safety-domestic-violence/106156062</link><description>In Spain, police have developed technology to work out how at-risk women might be from domestic violence. Some people have grave concerns about how often the algorithm is wrong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6fc13e6b98001bca1859104bf7cc6197</guid></item><item><title>Who's named in the Jeffrey Epstein files and who else was he connected to?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/epstein-files-who-is-named-in-the-released-emails-documents/106026984</link><description>The Epstein files offer another glimpse into the financier's vast network of wealthy and influential figures. Here's what we know about his relationships with some of the world's most powerful people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9773505c8702d6e868322c7330787dc</guid></item><item><title>In a 'conservative' sport, this Richmond lawn bowls club has become a haven for LGBTQI+ inclusion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/richmond-lawn-bowls-lgbtqi-community-sport/106071874</link><description>Three years ago, Richmond became the first lawn bowls club in the world to hold a Pride Cup. Since then, it has attracted a community of queer people who were otherwise lost to sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdf255811a33f0def3fe7b98e7e298b0</guid></item><item><title>How 3D movie animation technology is helping injured athletes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/3d-movie-animation-technology-helping-injured-athletes-acl/106024028</link><description>The reasons for high rates of serious knee injuries among female athletes are not fully understood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">519ae2d1daec62a35b1d8f8ec17a5f91</guid></item><item><title>White and grey kangaroos to be sold to prevent overcrowding at Bordertown Wildlife Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/group-white-and-grey-kangaroos-for-sale-bordertown-wildlife-park/106134948</link><description>White western grey kangaroos are a popular sight in a small wildlife park nestled near the South Australia – Victoria border and some are now being sold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">526ef39d38fec931410601e4a5bff601</guid></item><item><title>The Hidden Line: Art of the Boyd Women uncovers the stories of the women in Arthur Boyd's family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/the-hidden-line-art-of-the-boyd-women-arthur-boyd-bundanon/106051870</link><description>A new exhibition highlights the women behind acclaimed Australian mid-century artist Arthur Boyd, bringing their overlooked stories and art practices to the fore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71460a3cf4b948690cdd46266bd10da8</guid></item><item><title>The fight to save Australia's beaches from coastal erosion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/fight-to-save-australias-beaches-from-coastal-erosion/106153088</link><description>Most Australians live by the beach, but the coastline we have built our lives around is disappearing before our eyes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bcf12c59c885cada4ace7fca8e02440</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Bree Walker seals back-to-back World Cup wins ahead of the Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/bree-walker-seals-back-to-back-world-cup-wins/106167358</link><description>Australia's Bree Walker claims back-to-back World Cup wins to firm as the monobob favourite heading into the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8463f6aef7bd723520660cce279494c8</guid></item><item><title>Temporary recreational fishing restrictions eased amid SA's algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/fishing-restrictions-eased-amid-algal-bloom-improvement/106166214</link><description>Some recreational fishing restrictions initially put in place to protect fish stocks impacted by South Australia's algal bloom have now been eased.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c02df0a0eb02fb2711cc0147c75ebb36</guid></item><item><title>Automatic tipping becomes prominent due to rising cost of doing business in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/automatic-tipping-on-the-rise-amid-cost-of-business-crisis/106167380</link><description>Australia's tipping culture is in the spotlight, following reports more businesses are adding automatic tips to diners' bills in response to rising operating costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37b679047b87feb9034e2a7b2fbd74ac</guid></item><item><title>Limited options for people trying to donate blood in regional NSW in wake of Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/limited-options-donate-blood-for-bondi-victims-regional-nsw/106154832</link><description>Residents in parts of regional NSW could be left waiting months to give blood, with limited donation options available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3929a1dc995a6c59683ae73624ba922</guid></item><item><title>Jake Paul confirms he has a double broken jaw after controversial Anthony Joshua fight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/jake-paul-suffers-double-broken-jaw-in-anthony-joshua-fight/106167374</link><description>Jake Paul calls out Canelo Alvarez as the American recovers from a double broken jaw from his controversial fight with Anthony Joshua.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acdc9e8ac1244e45a1359a9ae0d68e1d</guid></item><item><title>Survivors search the Jeffrey Epstein files but find no sign of their evidence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/survivors-of-epstein-search-released-files-to-find-nothing/106167268</link><description>Despite giving an FBI interview and victim statement, Epstein victim Jess Michaels finds no trace of her evidence in the vast trove published online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">057cbf521763d48d86c35f3684d7b9d3</guid></item><item><title>Australia Post confirms improper mail sorting in Queensland suburb</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/australia-post-confirms-mail-missing-due-to-improper-sorting/106145698</link><description>Residents of a popular north Queensland suburb say they are receiving bills and overdue notices on the same day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b90fb6f17765fa965424304eca6667b0</guid></item><item><title>Retirement dreams shattered after woman pays tens of thousands of dollars for a home that was never built</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/russell-island-home-dreams-shattered-building-deposit-paid/106024576</link><description>Multiple people are speaking out about their experience paying too much to a building company for work never delivered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44c386ff2892c0da9bcc2c645650ea7b</guid></item><item><title>Ms Hemley surveys what could have been.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/lorraine-hemley-russell-island/106088246</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3778672a982122c3d9374e20c907bf6</guid></item><item><title>'Dead zones' prompt tour operator Pennicott to fund marine study of D'Entrecasteaux Channel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/dentrecasteaux-channel-imas-study-pennicott-tours/106097994</link><description>For more than two decades, Rob Pennicott has taken tourists to see the D'Entrecasteaux Channel. But what he describes as "dead zones" have him so worried that he is funding a study to find what is going wrong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9109da1b1f370a434a82b082068c92cf</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting live updates: Thousands at Bondi mark a week since terror attack; Albanese booed by angry crowd</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/bondi-beach-shooting-national-day-of-reflection-live-blog/106166856</link><description>A National Day of Reflection is being held and people across the country are invited to light a candle to honour the victims of the Bondi attack, one week on. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a68b38061450900ece6a17570c585120</guid></item><item><title>Yerrabi Cricket Club eyeing premier status as it grows within Gangahlin community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/the-new-gungahlin-cricket-club-growing-at-an-exponential-rate-/106166592</link><description>Within five years, the junior club has grown from two teams to having close to 200 players and has plans to become Canberra's first new Premier Cricket club in decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f53008b0a6702cad6334be3e13d523ee</guid></item><item><title>Victorian stock agent retires Toyota LandCruiser after 1 million kilometres</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/toyota-landcruiser-4wd-clocks-up-one-million-kilometres/106072806</link><description>A Victorian stock agent's four-wheel drive LandCruiser has reached a rare milestone, as experts say Australians are keeping their cars longer than ever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53305ec775f24703df6d19e7a24c3cb2</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: England batter Zak Crawley says Australia 'were the favourites' in defence of series disaster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/ashes-2025-zak-crawley-says-there-is-still-plenty-to-play-or/106167428</link><description>England batter Zak Crawley says there's still plenty to play for despite Australia being on the verge of a 3-0 series lead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e6c4eacec2955c277b1a4a1fa0a9ea3</guid></item><item><title>Images removed from Epstein files less than a day after being posted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/images-removed-from-epstein-files-less-than-a-day-after-posted/106167464</link><description>At least 16 Jeffrey Epstein-related files, including a photo of US President Donald Trump, disappear from a US Department of Justice webpage within a day of being posted, with no explanation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1169e04c29c15212ffa478f90262da2</guid></item><item><title>Pilbara mining towns left out of government's battery rebate schemes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/mining-pilbara-towns-left-out-of-battery-rebate-schemes/106025508</link><description>Residents in small Pilbara towns with power grids run by mining companies are excluded from home battery rebate schemes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd12d9c00ad0b9fa1138dad056f18caf</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu nationals celebrate faith and friendship in Bundaberg under the PALM scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/vanuatu-workers-sunday-worship-in-bundaberg/106128564</link><description>Moving to another country to provide for your family is not an easy choice but singing, hugs and faith make it easier for these Pacific island workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c95e3f6e5fb06f7cab8d6e5b783370a9</guid></item><item><title>Beloved Ballarat tai chi teacher granted visa after community push</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/ballarat-tai-chi-teacher-granted-permanent-residency/106158924</link><description>Jack Yang's immigration lawyer said his chances of staying in Australia were "nearly zero," but Ballarat's tai chi community had other plans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b579d2c5b69f7a4f1b050822da274b73</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs program Bikes Mwerre marks four years of after-school riding, learning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/nt-alice-springs-youth-program-bikes-mwerre-mountain-biking/106161762</link><description>An Alice Springs teenager who grew up with cycling program Bikes Mwerre is now sharing his knowledge with the next generation. It's a full-circle moment for the outback program built on pride, skills and belonging.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67b09a29c5885577f0ff42d2c18ffd4a</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Nathan Lyon injured as Australia wins series on day five of the third Test at the Adelaide Oval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/ashes-third-test-day-five-live-updates/106167504</link><description>Ben Stokes laments the end of England's Ashes "dream" as Australia wins the third Test by 82 runs on a surprisingly tense final day to take an unassailable 3-0 series lead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2314dd8e46e87a2245a76c42f0c6b1e</guid></item><item><title>Salt lakes' 'unreal' rainbow of colours captured by photographer in WA's Wheatbelt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/rainbow-of-colours-of-west-australian-salt-lakes/106102272</link><description>For photographer Scott Jon McCook, seeing the unique salt lakes of WA's Wheatbelt from the air was so captivating it started a five-year passion project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72731fec6a9968a297d0ccf073903a3e</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios handed wildcard into Brisbane International as his tennis return continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/nick-kyrgios-handed-wildcard-entry-into-brisbane-international/106167614</link><description>Former Wimbledon finalist Nick Kyrgios is handed a wildcard to the Brisbane International as he sets sights on an Australian Open return.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9748afa9a526c6153ea0e3409d050568</guid></item><item><title>Paraplegic engineer becomes the first wheelchair user to blast into space</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/first-paraplegic-engineer-in-space/106167430</link><description>The flight was just 10 minutes but the capsule still managed to soar 105 kilometres up, skimming into space.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d68ba7a26cb7926fb817a41140a09a0</guid></item><item><title>German aerospace engineer Michaela Benthaus becomes the first wheelchair user to go to space</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/german-engineer-becomes-first-wheelchair-user-to-go-to-space/106167474</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c5777d37f36f262d74e4c4e6dd97f05</guid></item><item><title>Destructive storms pass through Melbourne with extreme fire danger in north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/wild-weather-storms-set-to-hit-victoria/106167442</link><description>Victorians faced intense rainfall, damaging winds and large hailstones after severe storms swept across parts of the state. Emergency services called on road users to drive carefully in dangerous conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">267dc57e0c90d44868dab100bf31c99d</guid></item><item><title>Approaching her 80th birthday, Joan Jeffery is still riding high</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/horse-riding-melbourne-pakenham-upper-riding-club/106167500</link><description>While many people entering their 80s are struggling with physical or mental limitations, Joan Jeffery still manages to do all the heavy lifting of caring for a horse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78b8daf211928fe0801fe1cd43341c1f</guid></item><item><title>Kiama baker Les Warby was jailed for baking bread at weekends</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/warby-family-reflects-on-changing-baking-laws/106045298</link><description>Richard Warby still remembers the day his local community piled into a mini-bus bound for Long Bay Jail to pay a fine and release his father, who was locked up for the bizarre crime of baking bread on a weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78c518d812793e0c6511bfc36445d3cc</guid></item><item><title>Sea Harvest, Westmore Seafoods launch Supreme Court challenge over WA fishing ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/seafood-companies-launch-legal-challenge-of-wa-fishing-ban/106166174</link><description>Two seafood companies that conduct trawling in WA's Pilbara region launch legal action in the WA Supreme Court against the state government's new demersal fishing restrictions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d5f37d1ee842df1eafd1fc2d411b835</guid></item><item><title>Port Macquarie charity Every Daughter Matters helps stop Nepali girls being trafficked to India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/every-daughter-matters-stops-nepali-girls-being-trafficked/106033126</link><description>After hearing harrowing stories of abuse against young Nepalese women and girls, Port Macquarie man Ross Nancarrow wanted to help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77583efe561c15ed47891e2cc2a0e231</guid></item><item><title>Plans to ease congestion when Fremantle Traffic Bridge closes could drive up prices, industry warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/transport-industry-warns-price-hikes-fremantle-bridge-shutdown/106158628</link><description>Plans to mitigate traffic congestion when the Fremantle bridge shuts in six weeks could push up transport costs and consumer prices, the transport industry warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6acf7c943f67b58a8e39f0b58179bb64</guid></item><item><title>Agnes Water Museum says it houses a 100-year-old orange in its collection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/orange-100-agnes-water-museum/106158496</link><description>Visitors question why the piece of citrus was kept in the first place, but the small town museum credits the region's weather conditions which kept it from rotting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">220bc94b35c217d84468f923330a15f6</guid></item><item><title>US strikes kill at least five IS members in Syria, monitor says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/us-strikes-killed-at-least-five-is-members-syria-monitor-says/106167704</link><description>The operation employed more than 100 precision munitions targeting known IS infrastructure and weapons sites, according to a US Centcom statement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">714332fd27498946d7b47907ae3966d8</guid></item><item><title>PM announces review of intelligence and law enforcement in wake of Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/pm-announces-review-into-intelligence-and-law-enforcement/106167788</link><description>Former top bureaucrat Dennis Richardson is appointed to lead the review, which will report in April of next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a57e65069432e4bf4c3dbdafea0a1ce3</guid></item><item><title>After the Bondi attack, the contrast between Chris Minns and Anthony Albanese has been stark</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/bondi-attacks-chris-minns-anthony-albanese/106167738</link><description>As Sydneysiders paid their respects to the Bondi terror victims, one moment captured the contrast between two Labor leaders and their perceived responses to antisemitism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66f485429fd0f2daf2205867b0dc5324</guid></item><item><title>Chris Minns says Sydney anti-immigration rally 'the last thing we need'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/chris-minns-says-sydney-anti-immigration-rally/106167712</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c377723df52a02cfd8c5835485ce80a3</guid></item><item><title>NT government pulls funding for puberty blockers, gender-affirming hormones for children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/nt-government-defunds-puberty-blockers-gender-affirming-hormones/106167676</link><description>Northern Territory Health Minister Steve Edgington announces the withdrawal of public funding for puberty blockers and hormone treatments for children, labelling them "dangerous, ideologically driven practices".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76236274e5027a99a7945e981d4f8292</guid></item><item><title>Australian 15-year-old Indra Brown claims World Cup silver in the freeski halfpipe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/indra-brown-claims-world-cup-silver-in-freeski-halfpipe/106167810</link><description>Melbourne 15-year-old Indra Brown claims her second medal in her World Cup debut in the freeski halfpipe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80954cd03e29f2a887efebdc42b4f121</guid></item><item><title>Governor-general calls for ‘national project’ of kindness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/governor-general-calls-for-national-project-of-kindness/106167882</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95100176d10b9ba1584bdb713dac5c29</guid></item><item><title>Nathan Lyon injured on fifth day of Adelaide Test as England hunt a miracle to keep Ashes series alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/nathan-lyon-out-of-ashes-third-test-adelaide-oval/106167622</link><description>The 38-year-old spinner pulls up lame after diving to save a boundary in the morning session of the fifth day of the third Ashes Test at Adelaide Oval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2a0354dce3cadefd2b89d7bb464aab4</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate alleged daylight assault of woman at Burleigh Heads National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/police-investigate-alleged-daylight-assault-of-woman/106167804</link><description>Police are appealing for information after a woman was allegedly assaulted in broad daylight on a popular Gold Coast walking track.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">039d6e9b57ae8974559f389fa30b7f0a</guid></item><item><title>How a Reddit tip proved vital for uncovering the suspect of the Brown University shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/brown-university-shooting-suspect-reddit-tipoff/106167702</link><description>On December 13 a gunman killed two Brown University students and wounded nine others, escaping by foot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0171503282c7ed1792cdaaa0707f94b9</guid></item><item><title>How staying quiet led Pluribus to be one of the most talked about shows of 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/pluribus-vince-gilligan-interview-grand-finale/106123758</link><description>Pluribus, the new show from Breaking Bad and Better Call Saul creator Vince Gilligan, presents a life of perfect harmony — all you have to do is give up your individuality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbc80d2e3833aa32532ea544467c574d</guid></item><item><title>Nathan Lyon's hamstring, Marnus Labuschagne's hands and Jamie Smith's hack — quick hits from day five of third Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/ashes-day-five-third-test-quick-hits-nathan-lyon-jamie-smith/106167606</link><description>Jamie Smith is pilloried as "a dope" after an ugly dismissal as Nathan Lyon is injured and Marnus Labuschagne creates more catching magic. Here are the quick hits from day five of the third Ashes Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">288ad302313240c6d2b0d93d3b4ab597</guid></item><item><title>One Nation MP Barnaby Joyce calls for PM to be removed from role</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/barnaby-joyce-calls-for-pm-to-be-removed-from-role/106168272</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bead7f95e6c8ecfb0bb94f8015df368</guid></item><item><title>A candle burns brightly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/candle-frame/106167168</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88d807cc8e98b0b95896dc15ae452270</guid></item><item><title>At 6:47pm, Australia paused to remember victims of Bondi Beach shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/bondi-beach-shooting-victim-commemoration-candle/106167470</link><description>In a nationwide memorial, Australians have taken a moment to light a candle and quietly remember the 15 people killed at Bondi. Their names, stories and legacies are held close by a shaken, grieving community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7642ef50458b1e3b536e7b815b8184e5</guid></item><item><title>Australia defeats words with actions to outclass England and romp to Ashes glory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/australia-defeats-words-with-actions-win-ashes-adelaide/106167652</link><description>In the pre-series furore, with England crowing and injury concerns mounting, Australia stayed quiet. Its response has been an emphatic and quite brilliant Ashes domination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a960ab205a5a2a65332a56bc79a1d79b</guid></item><item><title>How have you honoured the victims of Bondi? Share your images and stories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/bondi-day-of-reflection-callout/106164734</link><description>As the nation pauses to honour those affected by the Bondi attack, we'd like to reflect what it looks like around the country through your images and stories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d05d8b862bbfcedbbad3278cff1ffa42</guid></item></channel></rss>