<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 06:55:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Western Sydney is set to dramatically heat up, this is how communities are preparing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/western-sydney-plans-to-address-climate-change-warming/105775030</link><description>A "shocking" warning that heatwave deaths could skyrocket brings the issue of urban heat back into sharp focus, particularly in the city's west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8587e0ed7880e781adeb84da2b9f99da</guid></item><item><title>Will it happen? Crunch time imminent for Tasmania's proposed Macquarie Point stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/macquarie-point-stadium-planning-decision/105759040</link><description>It's not the be all and end all — but the impending delivery of the Tasmanian Planning Commission's final report is a major moment for the Macquarie Point stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b39f129ad1988ebe3b71971d4e7bb065</guid></item><item><title>Residents encouraged to attract native bees amid varroa mite spread</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/backyard-owners-encouraged-to-attract-native-bees-gardening/105767140</link><description>A pollination ecologist says it is important people play their part in preserving native bees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2de85a81cf81cdc683c925dfd059c30</guid></item><item><title>Jacinta Nampijinpa Price and Kerrynne Liddle a 'unity ticket' on Indigenous affairs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/kerrynne-liddle-backs-jacinta-nampijinpa-price/105776102</link><description>Kerrynne Liddle speaks for the first time since Jacinta Nampijinpa Price was dumped from the frontbench, saying the pair are "on a unity ticket" when it comes to Indigenous affairs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">baf6de4a9c0796b996abab3ba46e1810</guid></item><item><title>Fears parts of Queensland will have to 'retreat' amid predicted sea level rise and increased severe weather events</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/climate-report-national-climate-risk-assessment-queensland/105775976</link><description>The warning comes amid a national report finding up to 185,000 residential buildings in Queensland could be in "very high-risk areas" if climate change is not addressed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c13eb12a1db1234d6f66dae28d2620c</guid></item><item><title>Nikki Webster sings with her children for 25th anniversary of Sydney Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/nikki-webster-sings-with-her-children-for-25th/105778014</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c83bf0274f16a9fa314e120145c3d8f</guid></item><item><title>Shire of Coolgardie awaits decision on future after giving evidence to minister</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/shire-of-coolgardie-show-cause-notice-response/105774072</link><description>The embattled Shire of Coolgardie waits to hear whether it will be suspended ahead of local government elections over concerns about financial and managerial mismanagement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a60af1587b72855d0965e133f66c3a65</guid></item><item><title>Lisa Reihana's exhibition, Voyager, recasts history through an Indigenous lens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/lisa-reihana-ngununggula-exhibition-voyager-indigenous-maori/105760474</link><description>The internationally renowned Maori artist's technically complex, visually mesmerising exhibition spans nearly a decade of artwork.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ed46a76298102094bcf604b8536fb9b</guid></item><item><title>How to determine if your kid is well enough for child care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/the-advice-around-sending-a-sick-kid-to-child-care/105734762</link><description>Work demands and a lack of village mean keeping a child at home from care every time they have a sniffle can be a dilemma for many parents. So when it it OK to send them?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3431c0d66326982196374e9a6c348b5f</guid></item><item><title>Family comes first for Queensland newsreader Rob Brough after months off air</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/newsreader-rob-broughs-family-battle/105775464</link><description>The long-time nightly newsreader says it was an "instant choice" to leave work as his daughter faced a battle with cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23d10f83e00ccce3717d0f0a569d4a1c</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Olympics inflatable art reappears after 25 years in rural NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/sydney-olympics-reg-mombassa-inflatable-art-reappears-in-nsw/105735020</link><description>A Coonabarabran artist made a lucky find at an online auction two years ago when she recognised a Reg Mombassa art piece from the Sydney Olympics mixed in with advertising devices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f4eacf145efc7f64bf56ffdaca13099</guid></item><item><title>Craig McLachlan withdraws from Cluedo stage show following backlash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/craig-mclachlan-withdraws-cluedo-the-play/105779280</link><description>Less than a week ago, Craig McLachlan was announced to play Colonel Mustard in the forthcoming national tour, making his return to the theatre after The Rocky Horror Show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2abe05c441b509ea22995eb926f87711</guid></item><item><title>Australia Diamonds announce netball squads for Test series against New Zealand, South Africa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/australia-diamonds-announce-test-netball-squads-new-zealand-sa/105779230</link><description>Goal-shooter Lucy Austin is a shock selection in the Australian netball squad to face South Africa, winning a place after initially being included as an "invitee" to their training camp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f84722b6abee542504171a8343b1b82</guid></item><item><title>Central Queensland included in fire ant biosecurity zones</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/fire-ant-biosecurity-zones-introduced-in-central-queensland/105777728</link><description>New restrictions in place on moving materials into five central Queensland sites to reduce the spread of the invasive species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f62a27c6d9e79b642f55fa3dab985fb8</guid></item><item><title>Aaron Chen talks comedy, faith, and moving to New York</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/aaron-chen-take-5-comedy-interview-music-tonight-fisk/105773602</link><description>How Aaron Chen went from being booted out of Sydney pubs to winning Logies and chasing global stardom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd43f88c371be470e8b83b1b925f650a</guid></item><item><title>Does washing your fruit and veggies remove chemicals?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/best-way-to-wash-fresh-produce-fruits-veggies-remove-chemcials-/105773664</link><description>This is what experts have to say about washing fruit and veggies, when looking to reduce the amount of chemical residues we generally consume.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57b4d4864180c3c11eed8be0eca03f20</guid></item><item><title>Concurrent disasters will overwhelm responders, stress ADF, risk report warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/defence-forces-disaster-response-climate-risk-assessment/105778304</link><description>A dedicated disaster recovery force is needed, or else responders and defence forces could be "overwhelmed" by multiple concurrent natural disasters, the National Climate Risk Assessment warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79a82e7988ce64cb47e2aea9d939b300</guid></item><item><title>Breastfeeding Gold Coast mum says she was asked to leave Virgin Australia lounge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/virgin-australia-apologises-mother-pumping-breast-milk/105779738</link><description>Mother-of-two Elise Turner says she was asked to leave the Virgin Australia business lounge after refusing to go to a bathroom to pump breast milk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a5d01ae6ec3bc3224e376127e761ff5</guid></item><item><title>How Isabelle Kelly shook off getting her 'teeth pushed back' to return for Roosters' NRLW finals charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/isabelle-kelly-injury-jaw-teeth-roosters-nrlw-finals/105780582</link><description>Isabelle Kelly was meant to rest up for a few weeks after suffering an oral fracture that nearly cost her several teeth but the Roosters skipper missed just one match and has now returned to lead the club's premiership charge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">062a7201f7cd32cadeb54c8069a61337</guid></item><item><title>Israel is committing genocide in Gaza, major United Nations report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/israel-committing-genocide-in-gaza-un-report-says/105780230</link><description>Israel has committed and is continuing to commit genocide in Gaza, according to the "most authoritative assessment" to date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e547fcd275b42fb12bbaa7d9028fd7aa</guid></item><item><title>James O'Connor still hopeful of playing Bledisloe Cup for Wallabies against All Blacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/james-oconnor-still-hopeful-of-playing-bledisloe-cup/105780738</link><description>James O'Connor has flown to England with his Test future still up in the air, but the Wallabies playmaker has not given up on playing in his first Bledisloe Cup match in five years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fe6060cfa537dad8e49fa78e8c41f63</guid></item><item><title>NRL finals week two team lists: Canterbury Bulldogs pick new halves combination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/nrl-finals-week-two-team-lists-bulldogs-panthers-raiders-sharks/105781098</link><description>Winger Jacob Kiraz has revealed he is happy to keep playing with painkilling injections as a patched-up Canterbury turn to a barely tested halves combination of Lachlan Galvin and Toby Sexton to save their NRL season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e00963cd95ccbc1a7f4dac1f88d12452</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105781402</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e2b5a3b30f5fdf1b8c8739f00047ca8</guid></item><item><title>Man 'choked to death' on ribbons and food in Adelaide nursing home, inquest told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/sa-inquest-hears-nursing-home-resident-choked-on-ribbons/105697736</link><description>A nursing home resident known to wander and ingest foreign objects died after choking on ribbons at a facility in Adelaide’s north, an inquest has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95ba5d590939d36f5248d85d89547a6f</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste protesters vow to continue rallying until plan to buy MPs 65 cars is overturned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/timor-leste-protests-over-mp-car-plan-grow/105781726</link><description>The protests nearly doubled in size on Tuesday as people continued to vent their frustrations at a plan to buy MPs 65 new SUVs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">feeb6a6ab4a2322ebf2709358b8c2353</guid></item><item><title>Australians too dependent on government, says Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/australians-too-dependent-on-government-says-sussan-ley/105781276</link><description>In her first major economic speech, the opposition leader hits out at universal subsidies and says "dependency" has affected Australia's "national character".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">651c319b8e005af88f9f36c064e26d9e</guid></item><item><title>Botox, fillers among the cosmetic injectables targeted in medical regulator's new rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/cosmetic-injectables-rules-botox-fillers/105778596</link><description>New rules have come into place aimed at better protecting patients from unsafe cosmetic procedures. Here's what it mean for your next appointment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f034dc98c168b046f196741357b091bf</guid></item><item><title>Threat of stagflation bears down on world's largest economy as Federal Reserve decision looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/threat-of-stagflation-bears-down-on-world-s-largest-economy/105781264</link><description>The world's largest central bank is less than 24 hours from announcing one of the most anticipated interest rate decisions of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">317d2acf44c6b55d5cef638469f7338f</guid></item><item><title>The Federal Home Guarantee Scheme is expanding, but just how many will be able to afford to buy in?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/home-loan-guarantee-scheme-cost-first-home-buyers/105772918</link><description>The expansion of the scheme, which allows first home buyers to purchase a property with as little as a 5 per cent deposit, has some warning it will also inflate the market. Here's what you'll need to be earning to get a foot in the door.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4fd4e5c6040f2d8b9de5c0800458317</guid></item><item><title>SA's ongoing harmful algal bloom labelled 'cultural emergency' by First Nations groups</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/sa-algal-bloom-cultural-emergency/105631230</link><description>First Nations South Australians say the harmful algal bloom impacting the state's coastline is a cultural emergency, as it continues to devastate beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ed15cf74630a813b331beecfe638cdf</guid></item><item><title>Children are being 'poisoned' by high lead levels as state government agency is accused of report cover-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/broken-hill-lead-poisoning-cover-up-mudgee-silver-mine-fears/105775230</link><description>A state government body sat on a report into lead dust that was "poisoning" children for nearly four years and tried to keep its release quiet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c539d0a8e324dc8143836fe465192aec</guid></item><item><title>Griffith locals push for new health district to meet needs of their community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/griffith-locals-push-for-new-health-district/105729862</link><description>Residents and medical professionals in south-western NSW are pushing to establish a new local health district in Griffith, arguing current services are not good enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">811a2f3a903585b4dace7ad758f6a3f0</guid></item><item><title>Cashrewards's abrupt closure leaves shoppers many unanswered questions. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/cashrewards-abrupt-shutdown-stuns-many-australians/105765936</link><description>Two and a half million Australians have signed up for this cashback app, which leaves them wondering what's next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74d5aaf89ebaad05dd5c26265b442d23</guid></item><item><title>New doco Signorinella: Little Miss celebrates the Italian women who shaped modern Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/signorinella-little-miss-documentary-italian-film-festival/105774428</link><description>Signorinella: Little Miss, the new documentary from the filmmakers behind Lygon St — Si Parla Italiano, celebrates the tenacity of Italian Australian women in business and beyond.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dc3ea23b27aab754a73fa0319a25aee</guid></item><item><title>Sam Konstas scores Australia A century in four-day game in India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/sam-konstas-scores-australia-a-century-against-india-a/105782060</link><description>Sam Konstas's push for an Ashes spot continues as he clatters a century in an extended session for Australia A in Lucknow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cec1e71dd86b61ad4d12f75e6292662</guid></item><item><title>South Australia's feral deer culling program targets eradication amid plague warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/sa-deer-eradication-program-aerial-culling-reduces-population/105763068</link><description>South Australia has ramped up its feral deer aerial culling program as drought-affected farmers battle the pest on their properties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62ba923682e9f4c1c2fea7cd969ab7fd</guid></item><item><title>Australia and PNG fail to clinch defence agreement, resorting to communique</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/australia-png-fail-defence-agreement-communique/105782424</link><description>A major defence treaty between Australia and Papua New Guinea has failed to get over the line today, with the countries resorting to signing a communique in lieu of the actual document.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d5916f8d88a6bb049ef9ef389165d8e</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Roosters, Brisbane Broncos NRLW favourites, Andrew Abdo banking on finals surprise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/roosters-broncos-nrlw-dominance-ahead-of-finals/105782346</link><description>As the NRLW finals kick off with the Roosters and Broncos miles ahead of the competition, chief executive Andrew Abdo is hoping the unpredictability of sudden-death finals will generate some surprises.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86b0bb2a5b175f5f803d5ee41052ecb1</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested over alleged domestic violence-related death of Palmerston woman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/nt-police-arrest-man-over-death-of-female-partner-in-palmerston/105782526</link><description>A man has been arrested over the alleged domestic violence-related death of his female partner overnight, after she was found unresponsive in the front yard of a Palmerston home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7c47df92c73582fdc3ec37e313630f3</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters honoured for Black Summer efforts as CFA warns about fire season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/black-summer-five-years-on-albury-wodonga/105761592</link><description>Firefighters say they learnt a lot from the Black Summer bushfires, but fear Victorians have become complacent in preparations ahead of this fire season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fccaf6727b3b5a68b220b1fb5f86623b</guid></item><item><title>Only social media companies know for sure how the teen ban will work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/social-media-ban-law-rules-analysis/105780188</link><description>The social media saga has produced its fair share of intrigue. But the latest big reveal on how the ban will work has left us with just another cliffhanger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81ea0e9097c27edcfe3bce09fd63b970</guid></item><item><title>Khapra beetle, a threat to grains industry, discovered in imported nappy pants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/khapra-beetle-found-in-imported-nappy-pants-threatens-grains/105782306</link><description>Authorities are investigating how khapra beetle, the number-one-priority pest for the grains industry, entered Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c65ef8036bcd15cd64dcb1342bb737aa</guid></item><item><title>Warnings of flash flooding after torrential rain drenches Far North Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/weather-warning-rain-far-north-queensland/105783282</link><description>Huge rainfall totals of more than 300 millimetres have taken even rain-hardened Far North Queenslanders by surprise at a typically drier time of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4fd41dcd4db489d39bf56181f35eeaf</guid></item><item><title>Why 'everything feels easier' for Chloe Rykers since her breast reduction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/breast-reduction-changed-my-quality-of-life-chloe-rykers/105763294</link><description>Chloe Rykers says her "big boobs" had, in various ways, made her career harder and left her feeling uncomfortable and in pain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfb6d7d9d5d29c944f231ddddf5980dc</guid></item><item><title>Robert Redford's most notable movies with Jane Fonda, Barbra Streisand and Paul Newman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/robert-redford-movies-jane-fonda-barbra-streisand-paul-newman/105782412</link><description>The Hollywood icon leaves a legacy of classic films with a career that stretched over decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a65466a8bed654c5a2f46954d2cfb614</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Barnes, Dave Faulkner among music industry voices in open letter urging ANU to keep School of Music</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/jimmy-barnes-against-anu-school-of-music-cuts/105784002</link><description>Jimmy Barnes is among more than 40 music voices supporting an open letter to the embattled Australian National University (ANU) calling for the School of Music to be saved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c2e11e10aa99b2ef294abc946d1feaa</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's only large-scale private mental health clinic, the Hobart Clinic, to close inpatient site by end of October</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/tasmanian-mental-health-inpatient-site-hobart-clinic-to-close/105783678</link><description>The Hobart Clinic, which employs 100 people and has provided private mental health services for Tasmanians for 40 years, will close its inpatient site by the end of October, citing financial woes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd61d37d4e64d804e365a3ede3165983</guid></item><item><title>Farmer asks partner to marry him with special canola crop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/farmer-asks-partner-to-marry-him-with-canola-crop/105783070</link><description>NSW farmer Will Henderson had no choice but to bide his time to pop the question. In the end his efforts were rewarded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05e5cefa73531016d6c02d243bfa85a7</guid></item><item><title>Panthers reflect on how Knights loss fuelled run to NRL semifinals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/nrl-penrith-panthers-canterbury-bulldogs-semifinal/105784766</link><description>The Panthers were last on the ladder after round 12, but a "brutal reality check" helped fuel the four-time defending premier's run to this season's finals series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0dcc57f6305015fb40b939f591ef646f</guid></item><item><title>Does the damning planning report mean the end for Hobart's Macquarie Point stadium?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/is-hobart-stadium-now-dead-explainer/105780834</link><description>The Tasmanian Planning Commission described the Hobart stadium as a "singular, large, bulky monolith" with "optimism bias" in the government's cost-benefit figures. What does this mean for the stadium?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6d2b782c8ad36854242ff8269a71dd8</guid></item><item><title>Albanese has found out nailing down Pacific agreements is harder than expected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/papua-new-guinea-defence-treaty-delays/105783902</link><description>Anthony Albanese was meant to emerge from his recent flurry of Pacific diplomacy holding no fewer than two major agreements — instead he's returning home conspicuously empty-handed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef894cba91b42943ab469518f13e2d11</guid></item><item><title>In Donald Trump's America, questions not to the president's liking are met with hostility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/president-donald-trump-and-hostile-relationship-with-media/105783964</link><description>As America enters a dark tunnel of dangerous internal divisions and an increasingly violent public discourse, Donald Trump is escalating his attacks on many of this nation's institutions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d3fbf6b1e6db2875d16740bdc3f6ed4</guid></item><item><title>Australia's first Aboriginal parliamentarian Neville Bonner commemorated with bronze sculpture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/first-indigenous-parliamentarian-neville-bonner-bronze-sculpture/105784526</link><description>Neville Bonner is honoured as Australia's first Indigenous parliamentarian.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f34625e3694dce1ffe76963cc385cf62</guid></item><item><title>Australia refusing to panic over Pat Cummins's injury ahead of Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/ashes-cricket-australia-england-pat-cummins-injury/105785808</link><description>Australia coach Andrew McDonald is confident injured captain Pat Cummins will be fit to play a major role in the men's Ashes, even if he does not feature in all five matches of the series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3764f86fe491f37a58f6d749d3f0b446</guid></item><item><title>Labor MP John Carey fathers five children through sperm donation, as WA surrogacy debate continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/wa-minister-john-carey-anonymous-sperm-donor/105785570</link><description>Western Australian Labor MP John Carey reveals he is a sperm donor for five children, as parliament debates legislation to change the state's surrogacy and in vitro fertilisation (IVF) laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">260ee303852d33207bc186fbf514847a</guid></item><item><title>WA government minister John Carey has revealed he has donated sperm to assist and support couples in experiencing the joy of parenthood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/wa-government-minister-john-carey-has-revealed-he/105785740</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9b035aa4bafdf7463217d1986b535b9</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105786068</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4fdf32035483c97cc8e3b3c2ceb960b</guid></item><item><title>Hasan Piker opens up on Charlie Kirk's death, Donald Trump and Elon Musk's campaign against him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/hasan-piker-speaks-charlie-kirk-death-and-death-threats-trump/105784072</link><description>Prominent left-wing commentator Hasan Piker opens up to 7.30 on Donald Trump's left-wing crackdown, the Charlie Kirk he knew and attempts to have him deplatformed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b7081bd7a10cb144ba6685b100983fa</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout makes his senior debut at the World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/gout-gout-makes-his-senior-debut/105786306</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a6f67c414742d7e07f12c1c5287ed55</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout finishes third in 200m heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/gout-gout-finishes-third-in-200m-heat/105786314</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d8312214b2b9a31a74786f0c79c4763</guid></item><item><title>Australia's 2035 climate target will strike a middle path. Will it be enough?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/2035-climate-emissions-target-middle-path/105782220</link><description>Australia's next major climate commitment will be more ambitious than New Zealand's and Canada's, but less than the United Kingdom's, as the government strikes a middle path in pursuit of an "achievable" 2035 target.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09490579740954d02af7a3ac935593e5</guid></item><item><title>NT regulator takes new side job with miner amid calls to quit over gas leak 'scandal'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nt-regulator-takes-new-side-job-with-miner-amid-calls-he-quit/105783120</link><description>The chair of the Northern Territory's Environment Protection Authority has become a "strategic adviser" to a miner but denies he has a conflict of interest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80fb3748f8891eb305aaaffb96c7fc55</guid></item><item><title>Why rower Jean Mitchell got an Olympic rings tattoo over her chemo scar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/olympics-jean-mitchell-rowing-olympic-rings-tattoo/105722046</link><description>Making it to the Paris 2024 Olympics was a career highlight for Jean Mitchell — and the brain cancer survivor marked the achievement in a special way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d089a522d586e7ccb4748b49b146ed6</guid></item><item><title>Coal miner Anglo American confirms job cuts in Brisbane, Bowen Basin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/anglo-american-confirms-more-qld-coal-job-losses/105784432</link><description>Mining giant Anglo American confirms job cuts in Brisbane and the Bowen Basin in the wake of BHP Mitsubishi Alliance axing 750 workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2c2ffd3fcd4ff63bb350e73f18ebbc1</guid></item><item><title>Man claims council bid to remove 'therapy' roosters is contrary to human rights conventions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/therapy-roosters-owner-tries-to-halt-court-proceedings/105775968</link><description>A South Australian council has taken a disability pensioner to court to remove his allegedly noisy roosters, but he has argued the council's application should not proceed because it is discriminatory and the birds are his "therapeutic" animals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12ef938f04ff77b3326d973d37ac0830</guid></item><item><title>Northern WA communities already adapting to extreme climate future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/northern-wa-communities-react-to-dire-climate-change-predictions/105774370</link><description>Locals in small northern WA communities say the potential dangers identified by the Climate Risk Assessment are already starting to appear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">185143eda8f80ebbaf513dfccf0aa6c3</guid></item><item><title>The Sydneysiders saving thousands by leaving the city on 'financial gap year'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nsw-sydney-cost-of-living-financial-gap-year/105733960</link><description>As Sydneysiders struggle with the soaring cost of living, a teacher has found financial freedom thousands of kilometres away, while a digital marketer swaps the city for the bush to save up $100,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">379c2823f1c04ed91ae2805632e60f30</guid></item><item><title>Hobart's Macquarie Point stadium now needs to go to parliament, and we don't yet know if it'll survive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/tas-hobart-macquarie-point-stadium-can-it-pass-parliament/105786052</link><description>The fate of Hobart's proposed stadium was never tied to the planning commission's report. Not when the government had long already made up its mind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">657727706256a2ac288cc358af2f85be</guid></item><item><title>Rural citizen scientists monitor wildlife activity to help conservation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/rural-landholders-monitor-wildlife-helping-conservation/105774622</link><description>Citizen scientists have collected more than 1.4 million photos and 15,000 hours of audio recordings to help shape the future of conservation management.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7a1f22fdf4d0278c08a2ff9b874099c</guid></item><item><title>A flowering grass tree on Andy McCoubrie's property attracted plenty of visitors.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/a-flowering-grass-tree-on-andy-mccoubries-property/105783970</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cda0bf78608d2a2e4639a2e00ba39db0</guid></item><item><title>Gaming history goes on display with Australian titles Hollow Knight Silksong and Team Fortress chronicled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/acmi-game-worlds-hollow-knight-silksong-neopets-team-fortress/105754152</link><description>An exhibition at Melbourne's ACMI will pull back the curtain on how iconic games like Hollow Knight Silksong, Team Fortress, Neopets and Sim City were made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fccda39e18804bf9590546dadaed39f</guid></item><item><title>Tom Atkins says players are just 'cogs in the machine' for Geelong ahead of AFL finals clash with Hawthorn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/geelong-vs-hawthorn-tom-atkins-on-being-a-cog-in-the-machine/105786768</link><description>Tom Atkins hasn't missed a final since being dropped in the 2020 season, and the midfielder says one mindset helped him accept the heartache of that season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a802e345a2162e1c3058d232c408a238</guid></item><item><title>How youth orchestras foster lifelong friendships and open career pathways for musicians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/youth-orchestra-lifelong-friendships-career-pathways-musicians/105775992</link><description>With youth orchestras set to busk on the streets of Sydney and Melbourne this weekend, Australian musicians share how those orchestras helped shape their careers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39cc489e47ad597a9a2e2610c3bf0e4a</guid></item><item><title>Cairns maternity ward named as exposure site in Far North Queensland measles outbreak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/four-new-cases-confirmed-in-cairns-measles-outbreak/105786794</link><description>More locally acquired cases have been confirmed with exposure sites now including Cairns Hospital's maternity ward and areas on the Atherton Tablelands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82362ca4ac1144d4e4b78657ca9250d4</guid></item><item><title>Kmart broke privacy laws by using facial recognition technology, commissioner finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/kmart-facial-recognition-technology-privacy-commissioner/105785802</link><description>The privacy commissioner has found Kmart broke the Privacy Act with its use of facial recognition technology, ordering the retail giant not to repeat the practice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">951624fe912cfaedd0c6e7cac0bca47d</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill launches LGBTQIA+ festival Rainbow in the Outback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/broken-hill-lgbtqia-festival-rainbow-in-the-outback/105782774</link><description>The outback city of Broken Hill is no stranger to celebrating the LGBTQIA+ community, with a new festival focusing on diversity and inclusion launching last weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cca328c6d304217ca3ecde48d89cfac4</guid></item><item><title>Patient 'devastated' as Sydney's dedicated long COVID clinic to close</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nsw-sydney-long-covid-clinic-st-vincents-hospital-closing/105786680</link><description>A patient of NSW's first dedicated long COVID clinic in Sydney says she is "devastated" and "bewildered" that it will close at the end of the month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6eec0e1b65b01a94cbd8f6b1c7dd571</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel Live pulled from air by US broadcaster ABC over 'insensitive' Charlie Kirk comments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/jimmy-kimmel-live-cancelled-indefinitely/105787192</link><description>The late-night talk show's host suggested during a monologue earlier this week that Charlie Kirk's alleged killer may have been a pro-Trump Republican.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42b62491994f952ca23ef1806fafc33b</guid></item><item><title>Gardeners share the joys of turning dust to daisies in the Australian outback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/gardeners-share-the-joys-of-growing-flowers-in-the-outback/105761510</link><description>Flower farmer Suzanne Stanton says generations of outback women have taken comfort in their gardens, proof that life can survive in the harshest of climates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">983de27f94440a9ba1f44837800269ac</guid></item><item><title>Palliative Care Australia art prize inspires conversations about death and grieving</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/palliative-care-australia-art-prize-helps-process-grief/105763880</link><description>In its fifth year, Palliative Care Australia's Live Well, Die Well national art prize continues to spark important conversations about dying.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11b336b74532eacba654f9700b7c36e0</guid></item><item><title>South Sydney Rabbitohs player Brandon Smith faces court on drug, betting charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nrl-star-brandon-smith-faces-court-drug-betting-charges/105786838</link><description>South Sydney Rabbitohs player Brandon Smith has appeared in a Gold Coast court to face drug supply and illegal betting charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b03f8de4d4dec53affefd7745fa2312</guid></item><item><title>Sam Butler reflects on his horrific broken leg as Hawthorn prepares for Geelong in the AFL preliminary final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/afl-finals-sam-butler-on-his-horrific-broken-leg/105787094</link><description>As he prepares to take on Geelong at the MCG for a place in the AFL grand final, Sam Butler reflects on his incredible journey back from a horrific leg break.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acd2f24bddc708e4022af88442c1fecb</guid></item><item><title>Man sets out to combat 'isolating experience' of spinal cord injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/spinal-cord-injury-survivor-helps-to-combat-social-isolation/105567754</link><description>David Ham says the reality of his spinal cord injury hit him when he returned home from hospital and had no-one to talk to with a similar experience.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">435c8feb69f9cd68efda827b14435fab</guid></item><item><title>How the Collingwood Magpies are righting the ship this AFLW season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/aflw-collingwood-magpies-round-six-hawthorn/105785982</link><description>A year after finishing dead last in the AFLW, the Magpies have started making moves up the ladder thanks to a new approach at both ends of the field.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09dcd2a4338fbef6fc6396c784fa2fe5</guid></item><item><title>Australian cow market at record high as US demand hits 'scary times'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/us-cattle-prices-soar-increasing-demand-for-aussie-beef/105776020</link><description>Australian cow prices are at record highs, but are still way below the United States where beef demand is going "crazy".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56f2d0555cc98f7f69e717a8162ea988</guid></item><item><title>Australia vows to cut emissions 62 to 70 per cent by 2035</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/australia-vows-to-cut-emissions-62-to-70-per-cent-by-2035/105786880</link><description>Australia will vow to cut its emissions by 62 to 70 per cent by 2035, lifting its sights further as the world strives to reach net zero emissions by 2050.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2e21efb7e74be7accc0d01defc0839f</guid></item><item><title>PNG's much-wanted NRL team has had setbacks. Experts say history is on its side</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/png-rugby-league-history-new-nrl-club/105782492</link><description>Observers say Papua New Guinea's decades-long history of rugby league success and passion is on its side as it prepares for the next sporting leap into the NRL.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d3deca6b656ff8bd1468e46bc6f527e</guid></item><item><title>Magpies overlook Bobby Hill for AFL preliminary final against Lions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/afl-collingwood-magpies-brisbane-lions-bobby-hill/105789152</link><description>Coach Craig McRae reveals he has spoken with Bobby Hill about his chances of playing in the AFL finals, as the Magpies ramp up preparations for Saturday's preliminary final against Lions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fd53afc0b532e11cc1c5091bdf7734c</guid></item><item><title>The AFL is in danger of becoming a 'two-tier competition' as multiple club captains search for the exit door</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/afl-player-movement-merrett-curnow-simpkin-paul-roos-analysis/105784732</link><description>Three captains from the AFL's four worst-performing clubs are searching for the exit door. It is the symptom of a player movement era that has left the gap between the AFL's strongest and weakest larger than ever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fe6fc38b706e2d5bb69fdebfcdad181</guid></item><item><title>What are the best ways to clean windows and fly screens?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/what-are-the-best-ways-to-clean-windows-and-fly-screens/105757576</link><description>Windows and fly screens are often the first things we see when we walk into a home, but rarely at the top of the spring-cleaning to-do list. Experts share their tips on the easiest and most effective ways to clean them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7541abd5471ba63f11dace84578558cf</guid></item><item><title>Australia's 2035 climate targets on path to net zero judged by the experts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/climate-targets-australia-2035-on-path-to-net-zero/105719910</link><description>After much anticipation, Australia has its new climate targets. Now that the dice have fallen, we consult experts on their assessment of how these targets stack up with what’s at stake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dabb8156d4044b51ff0dc8bd8feb97a4</guid></item><item><title>Amid Trump's biggest, best state visit ever, the king delivers a pointed message</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/trump-state-visit-king-charles-message/105788584</link><description>Amid the diamonds, whisky sours and flattery of a royal banquet for Donald Trump's state visit, tiara diplomacy was on full display.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55c7f64974504498042a988379cc1542</guid></item><item><title>Authorities urge parents to check Little Ones Nappy Pants for khapra beetle larvae</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nappy-pants-still-unaccounted-for-khapra-beetle-larvae-found/105787812</link><description>Hundreds of cartons of nappy pants remain unaccounted for after one of the biggest threats to Australia's grain industry, khapra beetle larvae, was found in the imported products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45cfd2bf95d89861ab6dc3f7a688868c</guid></item><item><title>Cats coach Chris Scott regrets run-in with AFL staffer after qualifying final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/geelong-cats-chris-scott-afl-staff-qualifying-final/105789664</link><description>Geelong coach Chris Scott says long-held frustration with the AFL was behind his regrettable post-qualifying final win outburst at a junior league employee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64f8afe41599735121373a93d14d1aff</guid></item><item><title>WA government flags tougher fishing rules, with dhufish and snapper at 'severe risk'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/stricter-fishing-rules-flagged-in-wa/105789778</link><description>Prized fish species including dhufish, snapper and red emperor are at severe risk of population collapse along WA's coast, prompting the state government to flag even stricter measures to protect stocks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fa2f37d5f1c4018f011797861e3f28d</guid></item><item><title>Hobart stadium proponent dismisses planning commission key issues as 'matters of opinion'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/tasmania-hobart-macquarie-point-stadium-tpc-report-opinions/105787276</link><description>The agency behind Hobart's Macquarie Point stadium build says it is undeterred by the three key issues raised by the recent planning commission's final report, arguing it comes down to "priorities".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95214532bc602d9fbcd7742ff8b727a4</guid></item><item><title>Disability employment provider Bedford's financial situation concerns SA, federal government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/disability-employment-provider-bedford-financial-concerns/105787712</link><description>The federal disability minister says his concerns about Australia's second-largest disability employment provider, Bedford, have grown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26088ccc4b0d7adc561a4f0cb51bf652</guid></item><item><title>Family of Aboriginal man killed in Darwin hit-and-run speak out over driver's sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/family-of-man-killed-in-darwin-hit-and-run-speak-out/105787700</link><description>The family of an Aboriginal man killed in a hit-and-run in Darwin have spoken out about the sentence handed to the man who killed him, and the "racist, dehumanising" messages he sent afterwards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc87964fabc0227fe5c48880a62ad60b</guid></item><item><title>Former Canberra Institute of Technology CEO Leanne Cover loses bid to challenge 'serious corrupt conduct' finding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/act-former-cit-ceo-loses-bid-challenge-corrupt-conduct-finding/105789508</link><description>Former Canberra Institute of Technology CEO Leanne Cover loses her bid to challenge a finding that she engaged in "serious corrupt conduct" over the arrangement of contracts to a consultant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">351c95d64d3c26f324b1e04584f777fe</guid></item><item><title>Domestic violence comments on fishing show breached classification rules: ACMA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/domestic-violence-comments-on-channel-seven-in-breach-says-acma/105789254</link><description>An exchange about domestic violence between 'Bush Cook Ranger Nick' and the host of Step Outside with Paul Burt, broadcast on 7mate, was in breach of classification rules, the watchdog has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0793754492a6a1f2c4bb7b9112a6cb41</guid></item><item><title>Albanese to meet with Trump after returning from Pacific empty-handed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/anthony-albanese-png-coalition-climate/105767026</link><description>This week in politics, the prime minister returned home from the Pacific empty-handed and the climate debate continued to unsettle the Coalition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e48586b5fbd1829a80e680eae1c55719</guid></item><item><title>National Gathering backs plans for new First Nations body, but tensions remain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/national-indigenous-gathering-post-voice-referendum/105787906</link><description>First Nations leaders have endorsed plans for a new national representative body to be established. Here’s what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31e9e3c6ecd0c09297f677025d57e6b6</guid></item><item><title>Albury Wodonga Regional Cancer Centre to become public hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/albury-wodonga-cancer-centre-hospital-ramsay-health-public/105786700</link><description>A major cancer centre on the Victorian-New South Wales border will become a fully public hospital in a move that has caught a healthcare provider by surprise and sparked community concern.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6af03fa22837640d34b69f4c529cc60f</guid></item><item><title>WA coal phase-out uncertainty amid Bluewaters power station closure backflip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/wa-coal-phaseout-uncertain-amid-energy-grid-upgrade-plan/105788864</link><description>Efforts by WA's government to force the premature closure of a privately owned coal plant appear to be unravelling after the market operator backed the power station to keep running towards the end of the decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4f55f2cbe6604ced891de18ea6af73a</guid></item><item><title>Henley residents advised to keep windows, doors closed amid algal bloom crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/sa-beach-residents-algal-bloom-advice/105790474</link><description>Authorities have told a group of residents living near a metropolitan Adelaide beach to close their doors and windows to prevent symptoms related to South Australia's ongoing algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">094835ce530689c0fec54c85ace98853</guid></item><item><title>The Albanese government has learned from the last major climate commitment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/2035-target-energy-debate-power-prices/105787072</link><description>The government is keenly aware that the cost of the transition is a sensitive issue, which is why the prime minister was flanked not just by his climate minister but also his treasurer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb04f44e27c2583896465cd35dce2ecb</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel is the latest to be put on pause. How Trump is influencing the world of late-night TV</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/jimmy-kimmel-stephen-colbert-late-night-in-trump-america/105788394</link><description>Emmys watchers could assume there's never been a better time in Hollywood to hold its most powerful to account, but Jimmy Kimmel's axing proves otherwise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aebb28d38d1022146481b424b8a62c82</guid></item><item><title>Roosters hand Victor Radley 10-match ban for bringing NRL club into disrepute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nrl-sydney-roosters-victor-radley-10-match-ban/105790722</link><description>The Sydney Roosters suspend Victor Radley for 10 matches without pay following media revelations he allegedly requested an illegal substance from former teammate Brandon Smith.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0476c9486f857e18734c6e0056795098</guid></item><item><title>Bindi Magic art exhibition opens in Alice Springs as organisation celebrates 25 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/bindi-magic-art-exhibition-opens-in-alice-springs/105789908</link><description>For 25 years Bindi Mwerre Anthurre Artists has been helping people with a disability to communicate through creativity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac6f9add20cd12006d1f874f0c4e4ec</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout, Torrie Lewis miss finals in brilliant 200m semifinal displays at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/live-updates-gout-gout-200m-world-athletics-championships-2025/105789710</link><description>Gout Gout and Torrie Lewis have missed the final of the 200m, both running to a hugely respectable fourth place in their semifinals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d91eed956c7bb07dd7aa6825e1414ea3</guid></item><item><title>Police officer found not guilty of assault during shopping centre scuffle at Batemans Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/police-officer-not-guilty-assault-batemans-bay-shopping-centre/105775816</link><description>A New South Wales police officer is found not guilty of using unreasonable force while removing three girls and a woman from a scuffle at a shopping centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c14d987edba1b9dfa103c7bd81c6de2</guid></item><item><title>All the latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/all-the-latest-financial-news/105791258</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01b895719353cf122016325431e84219</guid></item><item><title>Pope Leo talks Trump, sex abuse scandals, welcoming the LGBTQ+ community and China in his first interview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/pope-leo-first-interview-discusses-trump-and/105791360</link><description>Pope Leo says he recognises the influence of the United States on world affairs but makes clear he is not a supporter of US President Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23b4b5afac2ea78ffe86d81dd9c478ea</guid></item><item><title>Two people killed in a shooting at West Bank-Jordan border crossing, ambulance service says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/reported-shooting-israel-jordan-border/105791580</link><description>In a statement, the IDF said a person "arrived in a truck transporting humanitarian aid from Jordan, and opened fire".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">703258d1b55da8993ac80b29b6bc1f8b</guid></item><item><title>Trump says Jimmy Kimmel off-air for 'bad ratings' as Democrats slam regulator for 'bullying' US ABC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/trump-kimmel-bad-ratings-democrats-fcc-bullying/105791856</link><description>Prominent leaders in the Democratic Party are accusing the US's communications regulator of "bullying" a network to take the long-running late night show off air.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a35d01ad79ff21536357113faa2da610</guid></item><item><title>AI-generated minister addresses Albanian parliament for first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/ai-generated-minister-addresses-albanian-parliament/105791708</link><description>The world's first AI government minister was appointed last week by Albania's prime minister to oversee decisions on public tenders and to ease voter concerns about corruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6ebff04dd13bb994197a62feb3160b9</guid></item><item><title>Clashes and disruption in France amid nationwide protests over Emmanuel Macron's austerity policies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/france-protests-austerity-macron/105791966</link><description>The CGT trade union claims more than a million people took part in demonstrations, while police say more than 90 people have been detained.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8e5b19f23415522807b4f1cf83b7b63</guid></item><item><title>What Donald Trump and Keir Starmer had to say after the US president's historic second UK state visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/what-did-donald-trumps-second-uk-state-visit-achieve/105791450</link><description>The US and UK leaders held a wideranging press conference after nearly two days of carefully crafted pomp and ceremony. Here's what they had to say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec99933b10d971a98ad93c4964a4e4dc</guid></item><item><title>UK prime minister urges Trump to pressure Putin amid escalating 'recklessness'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/trump-starmer-russia-ukraine-oil-drone-strikes/105792022</link><description>Sir Keir Starmer says recent incidents, including Russian drones' incursion in Poland, show the Russian president is not "someone who wants peace".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7d6fb04c7bb765a5f84193a917ae9bc</guid></item><item><title>Independent advice spells out mammoth task ahead for government to reach 2035 target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/the-task-ahead-to-reach-2035-emissions-target/105789538</link><description>Getting to even the bottom end of the government's 62 to 70 per cent emissions reduction target by 2035 will require drastic increases to solar and wind power capacity, electric vehicle take-up and an extension of the safeguard mechanism, according to the Climate Change Authority.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">112c61869ecf0e96b28c94212500d843</guid></item><item><title>After deadly floods in Bali, its people want answers. Many are blaming overtourism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/bali-overtourism-blamed-in-wake-of-deadly-floods/105785674</link><description>Unexpected and deadly flooding rocked Bali last week at a scale many had never experienced before. In the wake of this disaster, the search for answers has begun.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">744d51865bef7cb34f9b946d580e8498</guid></item><item><title>The climate conversation is stuck in a loop, but out in the world things are changing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/climate-conversation-is-stuck-but-things-are-changing/105787796</link><description>We don't have to wait for moonshot technologies to reach our climate targets. Most of the solutions to the climate crisis are already around us.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36fccec4cd29f75e6be2134b94cacc07</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine could face waves of 2,000 drones as Russia ramps up mass production</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/russia-record-drone-missile-mass-strikes-ukraine-conflict/105753634</link><description>Ukraine is struggling to defend against growing drone attacks, and with Russia's mass production factories in full-swing there are fears thousands will soon be launched in a single night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e9f9a29907d82d98effe7c010edc04a</guid></item><item><title>First Guardian, Shield superannuation disasters expose deep flaws in Australia's $4.3 trillion retirement system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/first-guardian-shield-collapse-asic-and-superannuation-flaws/105783328</link><description>The failed First Guardian and Shield schemes have cost about 12,000 Australians more than $1 billion in retirement savings and exposed deep flaws in how Australia's $4.3 trillion superannuation sector is regulated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b80687a0c984dcbca73fbbe0b5a3dbb7</guid></item><item><title>Therapists, patients raise concerns over The Hobart Clinic closure with fears it could be 'dangerous' for some</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/hobart-clinic-therapists-patients-raise-concern-over-closure/105788162</link><description>For more than four decades, The Hobart Clinic has provided private mental health services to clients. Since the announcement of its October closure, clinic staff, therapists and patients have warned of the negative impact on those reliant on the service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fbc511d8b370e60dea926bbab98c0ab</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout's understanding of patience shows World Athletics Championships performance in 200m semifinal won't be one off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/gout-gout-patience-and-time-at-world-athletics-championships/105779054</link><description>Gout Gout's promise and progress are on full display at the 2025 World Athletics Championships. But by showing patience, he could get even better.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5091c293c2d85d7e3aebae30a5ecf2b5</guid></item><item><title>New Huon Aquaculture head Charles von der Heyde says salmon review followed spread of 'gossip'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/huon-aquaculture-new-ceo-charles-von-der-heyde/105789320</link><description>Huon Aquaculture's new chief executive officer has described the upcoming review of Tasmania's salmon industry as "unnecessary", saying that a pause on expansion would not stop the company's plans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd9a2d49083a01e8bc6ceb46139fee35</guid></item><item><title>Home owners warned to consider 'liveability' of properties amid climate change impact warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/climate-change-impact-on-housing-warning-queensland/105786926</link><description>Property experts say a "dizzying" report forecasting the impacts of worsening climate conditions on Australian properties has sounded a clear warning for the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3721e9130b606a97a1dbc326ef394a9</guid></item><item><title>Parents call for football club culture change after death of 21-year-old son</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/football-club-culture-drugs-alcohol-mental-health/105735836</link><description>Steven Callanan had the world at his feet and loved footy like it was a religion. The talented player could bring together communities while he played, but after a night of partying he took his own life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08703380b01374e017480cd3f1b0b710</guid></item><item><title>Drug checking services handed bitter pill as Queensland government rams through law changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/queensland-government-passes-laws-to-ban-drug-testing/105784786</link><description>The Queensland government has been unrepentant in its tough stance on drugs, with Health Minister Tim Nicholls telling state parliament this week it doesn't "support drug dealers", writes Janelle Miles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af4fc7b6109d00503933ebcf46173537</guid></item><item><title>Carnival of Flowers visitors brace for wet weather while smelling the roses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/storms-set-to-dampen-toowoomba-carnival-of-flowers/105790282</link><description>Visitors flocking to Queensland's Darling Downs for the annual Carnival of Flowers in Toowoomba are advised to take an umbrella, with thunderstorms forecast for the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb4dfb7296770565076ab2a1302356b1</guid></item><item><title>Earthquake off Russia's east coast causes Pacific tsunami warnings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/russia-kamchatka-peninsula-earthquake-sparks-tsunami-warnings/105792290</link><description>A quake that struck at a depth of 10 kilometres off Russia's Kamchatka Peninsula sparks warnings of potential waves three metres above a standard tide level in parts of the Pacific.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96dde97559efe5f569cb01a999cf4bfa</guid></item><item><title>Man fined for dumping 'volatile' chemicals into gutter on suburban Adelaide street</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/robert-wakefield-hydrocarbons-drain-fullarton-erd-court-fine/105783228</link><description>An Adelaide man who emptied drums containing hazardous chemicals into a suburban gutter — causing nearby residents to experience headaches and nausea — has been fined thousands of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61d6ba5dcfcc5161d7db85413cfe7261</guid></item><item><title>Surprise La Niña hints at another wet and stormy Australian summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/la-nina-hints-at-wet-stormy-australian-summer/105790134</link><description>Australia's key drivers of weather variability are stacking up to produce another wet, severe-weather season, with an increased risk of flooding, thunderstorms and cyclones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a42ca16638c1124b410a58f0cccc3ecf</guid></item><item><title>Riverina family grapples with daughter's devastating childhood dementia diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/riverina-family-grapples-with-childhood-dementia-diagnosis-/105789234</link><description>Rachel Anderson says she knew something was not right when her daughter Hannah began struggling to remember things she had just done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30cd776df827d075049497355a0ec58f</guid></item><item><title>Market live updates: ASX rises, Aus Post to resume US parcel deliveries sooner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/asx-markets-business-live-news-september-19/105792346</link><description>The Australian share market gains, after Wall Street's S&amp;P 500 hit a record high. Australia Post has announced it plans to resume postal sending to the United States on Monday, 22 September, 2025. Follow the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a824ad58cb292f6dfdd5a044e5b3e806</guid></item><item><title>Mount Isa waits for '11th-hour' decision on financial support for copper smelter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/mount-isa-copper-smelter-glencore-negotiations/105787756</link><description>Copper production is on the chopping block in outback Queensland, with mining giant Glencore about to decide on its future. What is the cost of losing a legacy industry?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6389a1b1230c562f480fd57d5cbe967b</guid></item><item><title>Kitchen floor at Palmerston Regional Hospital ripped up, replaced following food safety failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/nt-palmerston-hospital-defective-flooring-freedom-of-information/105783016</link><description>Large sections of flooring at the Northern Territory's newest, multi-million-dollar hospital are having to be ripped up and replaced after the facility failed food safety checks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cd028b5f635de4a7585465e210754bf</guid></item><item><title>Miranda Tapsell and Gwilym Lee show it 'takes a village' to raise a child in Top End Bub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/top-end-bub-miranda-tapsell-gwilym-lee/105775286</link><description>Miranda Tapsell and Gwilym Lee return to their characters from the hit movie, Top End Wedding, to take on parenthood in the TV series, Top End Bub.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6b3a94883d6882b00c7e6f5904787b6</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Albanese seizes on Ley's climate slip up — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/federal-politics-live-sept-19/105790890</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has seized on remarks made by Opposition Leader Sussan Ley about Australia's climate targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d8c53f5355ddd10031e0a3f823e1972</guid></item><item><title>AFL finals fever takes hold as fans line up to buy tickets offline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/fans-line-up-for-afl-grand-final-tickets/105783152</link><description>AFL fans fed up with the online ticketing system have opted to line up in person days in advance to secure their finals tickets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae67e6d9e7b54c457bfa6e91a30fd4f7</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with performing Nazi salute at Brisbane anti-immigration rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/qld-man-charged-performing-nazi-salute-anti-immigration-rally/105792450</link><description>ABC News made police enquiries after being sent a photo of a man raising his arm in what is alleged to be a Nazi salute at the Brisbane rally on August 31.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">450cdefce4b6278dffcbabbca339d49d</guid></item><item><title>Israel-Gaza war protests in Melbourne contribute to $25m Victoria Police spend, report shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/israel-gaza-protests-in-melbourne-victoria-police-bill/105792396</link><description>The report by Victoria's Parliamentary Budget Office includes the estimated cost of wages and other expenses to police the weekly protests in Melbourne's CBD and other operational activities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c79de170c413bbd3d49a71a2e050e1a</guid></item><item><title>Young members bring new life to the Rural Fire Service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/rural-fire-service-brigades-seek-new-members/105778996</link><description>Nearly a quarter of all western NSW Rural Fire Service volunteers are older than 70, but some younger recruits are urging others to follow in their footsteps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a9645dec99c6b79501e9b7ecffcd0c1</guid></item><item><title>How Hawthorn can upset Geelong as the Hawks meet the Cats in 2025 AFL preliminary final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/afl-preliminary-final-preview-geelong-vs-hawthorn/105792398</link><description>With a plethora of options up forward, there's one issue the Hawks need to pay attention to out of their back half if they want to upset the Cats tonight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">690d853e61b84e53b4907310f22bd294</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull falls into world championships 800m semifinal with Claudia Hollingsworth, Abbey Caldwell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/jess-hull-fall-into-world-athletics-championships-800m-semifinal/105792394</link><description>Three Australian women progress to the world championship 800m semifinals for the first time. And while Claudia Hollingsworth and Abbey Caldwell did it the usual way, Jess Hull took the scenic route.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abed573e7b28200229bcb90eb92d4214</guid></item><item><title>No live export ships coming for WA sheep amid high prices, looming ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/no-live-sheep-export-ships-wa-ban-looming/105789752</link><description>Market dynamics are stopping live export ships from coming to WA for the rest of the year, raising the prospect of an official end to the trade years before a legislated ban is enforced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24596fcbd14ee045fa2b692080145ca9</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government commits $4.5 million for locust control as swarms intensify</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/outback-locust-control-funding-queensland-graziers/105787162</link><description>As the native pest destroys crops and pasture across outback Queensland, graziers say authorities must move swiftly to tackle them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2e44afff23dbf4b7b4c4a66888af068</guid></item><item><title>Chris Bowen says 2035 target would require Australia to double emissions reduction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/chris-bowen-says-2035-target-would-require/105792710</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49c178abd32cf1714be8462ccbc99aab</guid></item><item><title>Seven people charged over stabbing deaths of Dau Akueng and Chol Achiek in Cobblebank</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/seven-charged-dau-akueng-chol-achiek-cobblebank-stabbing-deaths/105792860</link><description>Police have charged seven people ranging from 15 to 19 years old in relation to the deaths of 15-year-old Dau Akueng and 12-year-old Chol Achiek in Melbourne's outer north-west earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74ee4c1706ae3ca92c796665e415e849</guid></item><item><title>Water Corporation admits no water left for major new development in Port Hedland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/port-hedland-water-supply-at-capacity/105789308</link><description>The Water Corporation has confirmed Port Hedland's groundwater source is at capacity and cannot accommodate major development.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48f23c509f4c2d1738afdb51e51b8e70</guid></item><item><title>Gippsland farmer blocks AusNet maintenance workers from entering property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/gippsland-farmer-ausnet-transmission-line-dispute/105767192</link><description>A Victorian farmer who has hosted transmission lines on his property for decades says he is sick of maintenance workers damaging his property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">567d67427b571a1d541a4aceb24ac48b</guid></item><item><title>Australian Submarine Agency lobbies Fremantle locals amid protest over AUKUS defence hub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/submarine-agency-lobbies-fremantle-locals-amid-aukus-protest/105791174</link><description>A push to earn the public's trust over a defence hub south of Perth by the Australian Submarine Agency draws protesters and sceptical residents in Fremantle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8095393b39a51688425e02f38c8b989</guid></item><item><title>Social media and webcam vision shows earthquake in Russia's far east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/social-media-vision-shows-earthquake-in-russias/105793024</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8dd307baeab5063c6657ada09b31b35</guid></item><item><title>Magnitude 7.8 earthquake hits Russia's Kamchatka</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/magnitude-7.8-earthquake-hits-russias-kamchatka/105792910</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d01660a1d3750b4ef677fc1980a19f0a</guid></item><item><title>Erin Patterson trial doctor Chris Webster stands by 'sociopath' comments despite AHPRA sanction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/ahpra-sanctions-chris-webster-calling-erin-patterson-sociopath/105790942</link><description>The doctor who called triple murderer Erin Patterson a "crazy bitch" and a "sociopath" has been sanctioned by AHPRA, but says he does not regret making the comments about the mushroom murderer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a747bc2c91804b7477f5a7d7cec6d86a</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri says McLaren has clarified team orders after controversy at F1 Italian Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/oscar-piastri-says-mclaren-has-clarified-team-orders/105792972</link><description>Formula 1 drivers' championship leader Oscar Piastri says McLaren has "had a lot of discussions" since the controversial ending to the Italian Grand Prix two weekends ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">503d5c7f94ef8fd5bf1c826419864b72</guid></item><item><title>Australian Alanna Smith wins WNBA defensive player of the year with A'ja Wilson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/australian-alanna-smith-wins-wnba-defensive-player-of-the-year/105793098</link><description>Alanna Smith splits the WNBA defensive player of the year award with three-time league MVP A'ja Wilson, marking the first major individual award for an Australian since 2010.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">239b19bf7416b7db282219500e69a3a4</guid></item><item><title>Warm currents bring tens of thousands of giant yellowfin tuna to NSW South Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/unprecedented-yellowfin-tuna-season-south-coast/105784426</link><description>Fishers are reporting an unprecedented number of yellowfin tuna travelling from the tropics to the NSW South Coast, causing "mayhem" and excitement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d71fe5d9066c0d4471f7c22b0f966ba4</guid></item><item><title>NT Director of Public Prosecutions files appeal against Jake Danby fatal hit-and-run sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/nt-dpp-files-appeal-against-fatal-hit-and-run-jake-danby/105793334</link><description>The NT's Director of Public Prosecutions has filed an appeal against the sentence of hit-and-run driver Jake Danby, who killed one Aboriginal man and injured another.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e3838dc5519f987bfb13479b62436c3</guid></item><item><title>Liam Paro beats David Papot in welterweight fight despite black eye</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/liam-paro-beats-david-papot-despite-boxing-black-eye/105793472</link><description>Liam Paro fights through a hugely swollen right eye to hand Frenchman David Papot the first defeat of his career in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d7ca14f9e26929e0c3cec7239c43b74</guid></item><item><title>Tom Koutsantonis appointed SA Treasurer after Stephen Mullighan and Susan Close step down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/tom-koutsantonis-sa-treasurer/105793036</link><description>Mr Koutsantonis takes the role from Stephen Mullighan, who is one of two senior ministers to resign from cabinet this week. The cabinet now has more women than men for the first time in SA's history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">342b122fa03c5a15dd639f10b14e79f2</guid></item><item><title>Julie Bishop again denies bullying allegations levelled against her</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/julie-bishop-again-denies-bullying-allegations/105793926</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eb5297aea0ab2d0f4ea07d586e1ac36</guid></item><item><title>Gardens of Stone State Conservation Area walks open path to incredible vistas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/gardens-of-stone-state-conservation-area-walks-open/105788604</link><description>New South Wales National Parks and Wildlife staff have spent 18 months transforming eroded vehicle trails into rehabilitated walks, opening previously inaccessible viewpoints.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0da6f8f660e8929fd1ce6563b317648c</guid></item><item><title>QCOAL's Cook Colliery coal mine in central Queensland to close half of operation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/cook-colliery-coal-mine-to-close-half-of-operation/105792906</link><description>A third Queensland coal miner has confirmed job cuts as it prepares to close one of its underground mine sites, with the company also putting the blame on rising costs and state government royalties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adae0677efe1894effb74c23021af5ba</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's anti-corruption commission searches Chinese language school over alleged misuse of public funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/anti-corruption-commission-searches-chinese-language-school/105792674</link><description>The search at one of the state's biggest Chinese language schools relates to an investigation into alleged misuse of public funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ef3a20e0a98966ec9ddf33dc171e8ed</guid></item><item><title>Rabbits cause 'devastating' damage to Junee cemetery in southern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/rabbits-cause-devastating-damage-to-junee-cemetery-southern-nsw/105792784</link><description>The Junee Shire Council says it is battling a rabbit problem, which forced a recent closure of the town's main cemetery for a week, including on Father's Day, for a baiting program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6e24632645222977003b4a6af3561fc</guid></item><item><title>Wiluna leaders hoping 'bounty' will reduce stray dog numbers in town</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/wiluna-dog-bounty-questions/105595030</link><description>Wiluna, in Western Australia's far northern Goldfields, is looking to revive a cash incentive for community members to surrender domestic dogs for rehoming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d68e67f88048247f2f3f75048b91b24</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos discovery further delays Willyama High School demolition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/demolition-of-mouldy-willyama-high-school-delayed-by-asbestos/105733678</link><description>Nearly two years after a mould-infested high school was closed indefinitely, high-risk friable asbestos has caused further delays to its demolition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a23e41ae074ff173d5db5c3d17aa081</guid></item><item><title>RONA. weaves together country, colonialism and club music on new EP It's All Here</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/rona-its-all-here-ep-bush-beats-country-colonialism-club-music/105758094</link><description>This Kaytetye producer has a fresh take on the space race that draws from First Nations knowledge and culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f63cbfd798f6826103c82f171f571494</guid></item><item><title>In pictures: Melania Trump bonds with royals over scouts, miniature books and bug hotels</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/melania-trump-queen-camilla-princess-kate-royal-engagements/105792736</link><description>As US President Donald Trump left Windsor to meet UK Prime Minister Sir Keir Starmer, first lady Melania Trump spent the day with the Princess of Wales and Queen Camilla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d9de57ca47acbc2799702a7bbebec86</guid></item><item><title>Victoria Police arrest seven people over stabbing deaths of two boys at Cobblebank</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/victoria-police-arrest-seven-people-over-stabbing/105794330</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40d779dc059b3fc23e9d42dade8cdefc</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man jailed for three years after violently assaulting his partner until she was unconscious</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/act-man-jailed-for-attacking-partner-choking-until-unconscious/105794116</link><description>The 43-year-old man was found guilty of attacking his partner, despite her having withdrawn her complaint against him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c96ba96c080cca0bb9360328dd58b82d</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann likely to face four-day hearing in Tasmania over motor vehicle stealing charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/bruce-lehrmann-likely-to-face-four-day-hearing/105794304</link><description>Former Liberal staffer Bruce Lehrmann appears in the Hobart Magistrates Court after pleading not guilty to one count of motor vehicle stealing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">680bec6e2ce2b4d53ae9b27667c53e23</guid></item><item><title>Russell Vale Mine Shaft 4 to trial Green Gravity renewable energy technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/russell-vale-mine-shaft-4-to-trial-green-gravity/105780830</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89d1b1e00372ede47986a5b7fb9f02ce</guid></item><item><title>Green Gravity secures old coal mine shaft to test gravitational energy storage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/green-gravity-deal-old-mine-shaft-gravitational-energy-storage/105782756</link><description>A disused coal mine in Wollongong will be the first test site for a renewable energy company that lowers weights down old mine shafts to spin turbines and create electricity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">624bc063af2f9be2f1ecc1717cd562e3</guid></item><item><title>China urges Papua New Guinea not to exclude other countries after it signed 'Pukpuk' communique with Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/china-warns-papua-new-guinea-against-bilateral-deal-australia/105794018</link><description>China has urged Papua New Guinea not to sign any deal that might exclude or restrict third parties from cooperating with the Pacific nation, as Australia scrambles to clinch a landmark defence treaty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad04d0391ea73681a5f0351d55692b32</guid></item><item><title>Matthew Draganoff sentenced for murder of tenant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/matthew-draganoff-sentenced-murder/105792818</link><description>A man who was found guilty of the "execution-style murder" of his "unarmed" tenant on the northern outskirts of Adelaide has been jailed for at least 28 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa3b06fba77a80f9fd7bdb530be66fe4</guid></item><item><title>Julie Bishop again denies bullying allegations levelled against her</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/julie-bishop-again-denies-bullying-allegations/105794320</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3eec9f286027b0fb84cf9836b34054e8</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: A royal visit, a glitzy award show and a new city plays host to Laneway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/september-19-friday-news-quiz/105788054</link><description>A lot happened this week. Have you been paying attention?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62ecd5fbe8b87d12bdb2cd9e003b1e8d</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley returns after press conference to clarify her comments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/sussan-ley-returns-after-press-conference-to/105794464</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd5bbd98a0172483c48df6e2c1dfdf74</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins hints at Ashes strategy amid recovery from back injury with 'starting aim' of playing in all five Tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/ashes-pat-cummins-australia-england-back-injury/105794594</link><description>As the men's Ashes approaches, the Australian captain reveals his hopes for taking part in the five-Test series against England as he steps up his injury recovery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cfd72c66626cbf51c7aab8346b10585</guid></item><item><title>Cowboys prepare to make NRLW finals debut against Sharks in Townsville</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/nrlw-north-queensland-cowboys-play-sharks-in-first-finals-match/105790490</link><description>As the Cowboys eye the path to premiership glory ahead of their sudden-death semifinal against the Sharks, they are also creating pathways off field for the next generation of NRLW stars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45bc33d0af030a85b06c99d0ea5dc2f8</guid></item><item><title>Gareth Ward's victim tells sentencing hearing of abuse trauma</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/gareth-ward-victim-speaks-sentencing-hearing/105793278</link><description>One of the victims of convicted sex offender Gareth Ward has told the former NSW MP's sentencing hearing the abuse left him traumatised and suicidal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c555dbb452cc7bfbec788ed505ddc1a</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Greens candidate Hannah Thomas injured in pro-Palestinian protest awarded $22k over dropped case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/nsw-hannah-thomas-court-costs-dropped-charges/105794888</link><description>Hannah Thomas, who sustained an eye injury during an arrest at a pro-Palestinian rally, is awarded legal costs to the tune of nearly $22,000 after all of her charges were dropped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac34d8d826da71ac7bf6bc3b8d3c5ac0</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout receives praise from Noah Lyles at World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/world-athletics-championships-tokyo-gout-gout-noah-lyles/105794882</link><description>Nothing Noah Lyles has seen in Gout Gout during the past week at the World Athletics Championships in Tokyo has changed the American great's opinion of the Australian teenager.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28b33140a9273c415fa78f470c7af769</guid></item><item><title>Bus driver pleads not guilty to dangerous driving over triple-fatal collision in Gumlu</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/bus-driver-in-gumlu-fatal-pleads-not-guilty-to-dangerous-driving/105792662</link><description>A Townsville bus driver involved in a crash that killed three women in north Queensland last year pleads not guilty to dangerous driving causing death or grievous bodily harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">970c592c33595cd809efea0f4925bf86</guid></item><item><title>Former police officer sentenced over perjury in NRL star Jack de Belin's rape case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/ex-police-officer-avoids-jail-for-perjury-in-de-belin-rape-case/105789796</link><description>A former police officer received a 12-month intensive community correction order after he lied about accessing privileged text messages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21518a52dfd7cac5d30c94281cb36bdb</guid></item><item><title>Late-night hosts call out 'unitary intimidation' in aftermath of Jimmy Kimmel's axing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/stephen-colbert-seth-meyers-jon-stewart-back-jimmy-kimmel/105794466</link><description>Jimmy Kimmel's fellow late-night stars accuse the Trump administration of overriding free speech with the indefinite axing of the ABC America host, as parent company, Walt Disney, faces growing protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2f64fab37da9ee4ace2388f587b1eab</guid></item><item><title>Hakyung Lee, mother accused of killing children, had a 'disease of the mind', defence expert tells court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/hakyung-lee-suitcase-murders-auckland-new-zealand/105781562</link><description>Hakyung Lee has been charged with murdering her children and has pleaded not guilty by reason of insanity after leaving their bodies in an Auckland storage facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">690cb00a0c2ca94e57c34909bfc58001</guid></item><item><title>Driver, bus company added as cross-defendants in wedding bus crash class action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/class-action-seeks-damages-after-fatal-greta-bus-crash/105793458</link><description>Jailed bus driver Brett Button and the bus company that employed him have been added as defendants in a class action stemming from a crash that killed 10 people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65dfe5148085e247e6293ae5a2790844</guid></item><item><title>What to know about the Macrons' legal bid to prove the French first lady was not born a man</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/what-to-know-about-macrons-defamation-suit-against-candace-owens/105794900</link><description>Emmanuel Macron and his wife, Brigitte Macron, have said they intend to provide evidence in court to disprove a right-wing influencer's claims the French first lady is transgender.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4503c882debdf66e431a20c149a3de3b</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann applies for Toowoomba rape complainant's phone download as court hears some evidence may be missing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/bruce-lehrmann-toowoomba-rape-complainant-mobile-phone/105792890</link><description>Mr Lehrmann is facing two charges of rape, alleged to have occurred in Toowoomba in 2021. He's indicated he intends to plead not guilty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74c1ad5180bcd48cd8a70cf3751c0111</guid></item><item><title>Sharks vow not to taunt Raiders in sudden-death NRL semifinal as minor premiers look to bounce back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/nrl-cronulla-sharks-canberra-raiders-semi-final/105795410</link><description>Cronulla suggests it will not niggle Canberra in Saturday night's semifinal, despite the Brisbane Broncos successfully getting under the Raiders' skin in their thrilling one-point win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de811a022c87a3d1a6baef74c8c54ce6</guid></item><item><title>How to build a flourishing garden in a courtyard or smaller space</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/how-to-create-a-garden-with-not-much-space-or-sun/105763316</link><description>Living in a smaller space doesn't mean you can't have a lush garden. Here's how to rejuvenate your garden with some easy tips.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10fca8a72dcf1eb2dd616158042c2c3b</guid></item><item><title>Varroa mite could still be in SA despite removal of infected hives, PIRSA says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/varroa-mite-threat-south-australia-pirsa/105787606</link><description>PIRSA says there is a chance the deadly parasite remains in the state where it was detected for the first time earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">199d5d292dcbe93495cf2534c11fa8a2</guid></item><item><title>Report scathing of police and CCC over failure to respond to complaints of police misconduct</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/police-ccc-complaints-misconduct-report-/105791424</link><description>WA Police and the CCC are put on notice after failing to adequately respond to complaints of serious police misconduct, including an allegation an off-duty officer choked a man following a road rage incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22bf87447571d6b73f5b6fc17bd6283e</guid></item><item><title>Justin Holbrook arrives at Newcastle Knights after club's wooden spoon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/newcastle-knights-coach-justin-holbrook-arrives-club/105787242</link><description>Justin Holbrook has started his tenure as Newcastle head coach, tasked with turning the struggling NRL side around.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da5ef0727b375ae392cde4c88789e5ee</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill man runs 1,100km to Newcastle to raise funds for Angelman syndrome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/broken-hill-man-runs-to-newcastle-fund-angelman-syndrome/105788134</link><description>A Broken Hill man has run to Newcastle to raise funds and awareness for a rare condition called as Angelman syndrome.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b64dbd898ade0be1f04b32775520eb67</guid></item><item><title>AFLW great Daisy Pearce aiming to take down former club Demons with Eagles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/aflw-daisy-pearce-west-coast-eaglers-melbourne-demons/105795842</link><description>With a West Coast Eagles squad intent of reaching the finals, coach Daisy Pearce has the club she captained to a premiership in her sights this weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4489526b70edc342d88d5fdd23730376</guid></item></channel></rss>