<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 06:57:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Truck driver pleads guilty over Bacchus Marsh school bus crash that left students with lifelong injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/bacchus-marsh-bus-crash-plea-loreto-college/105837978</link><description>Brett Michael Russell was driving a truck that hit a school bus north-west of Melbourne in 2022, leaving some students and staff with life-changing injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2642f4f69cd08f5d352863a3a552ca8</guid></item><item><title>States shoot down hospital funding offer, claiming it amounts to a shortfall of 'billions'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/states-shoot-down-commonwealth-hospital-funding-offer/105839904</link><description>State and territory leaders say the Commonwealth's offer for the next five years of hospital funding would leave them billions out of pocket, claiming the federal government is walking back a promise to pay 42.5 per cent of the share of expenses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fedb548d09882166c3bc80df7a44fd0a</guid></item><item><title>Roadworks completed as construction of new Paradise Dam wall sparks environmental concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/paradise-dam-construction-progresses-amid-environmental-concerns/105838512</link><description>More than 53 hectares of bushland and riverine habitat will be cleared for a major upgrade to a regional Queensland dam, prompting environmentalists to raise concerns about protected lungfish and turtles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36ad0a2a27ea2e06aac14038c314e3da</guid></item><item><title>Will Keir Starmer become the latest UK prime minister to be ousted?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/will-keir-starmer-latest-uk-prime-minister-to-be-ousted/105837812</link><description>A successful party conference speech has rallied the troops and offered the Labour leader a reprieve from mounting speculation about his leadership, but for how long?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">413558c3fafc2465097322840acb6e67</guid></item><item><title>SA Police issue warning about fake currency after more than 200 incidents and two arrests in recent months</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/sa-counterfeit-currency/105839292</link><description>SA Police says there have been more than 200 reported cases of counterfeit currency being used in the state in the past two months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdb80015a7fe1737a385a7a52823ec03</guid></item><item><title>Last Cab to Darwin director advocates for voluntary assisted dying as film marks 10-year anniversary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/last-cab-to-darwin-film-anniversary-voluntary-assisted-dying-vad/105834830</link><description>The director of Last Cab to Darwin — which explores the subject of voluntary assisted dying — wants all terminally ill Australians to be afforded access to dignified end-of-life care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14a49f6a2666dabe169977d9ff867027</guid></item><item><title>Why the NRLW 2025 grand final looms as a defining moment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/nrlw-grand-final-broncos-roosters-premiership/105839942</link><description>The Roosters and Broncos have both dominated the NRLW, but the winners this weekend can legitimately stamp themselves as the pre-eminent club in the competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20618a0d68e527c2ac06c1f2e48522f3</guid></item><item><title>Former prisoners to stand trial over alleged extortion, murder of inmate Benn Schinkel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/qld-court-hearing-alleged-murder-extortion-inmate-benn-schinkel/105839586</link><description>Two fellow prisoners, who were charged over the 2022 alleged murder and extortion of Benn Schinkel, will stand trial in the Supreme Court in Brisbane over his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d72e2ac6a28835428c1ecb9ac214b635</guid></item><item><title>Australia posts six-wicket win over New Zealand in opening men's T20I</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/t20-new-zealand-vs-australia-scorecentre/105840160</link><description>The Australian men's team claims a 1-0 series lead after recording a six-wicket win over New Zealand at Tauranga's Bay Oval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f2d3e8a19b888d2019cba126eba9dde</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian Devils' AFL draft concessions for 2028 announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/tasmania-devils-afl-draft-concessions-2028-team-announced/105838224</link><description>Tasmania's fledgling AFL team, the Devils, will have a $5 million signing bonus pool in addition to the salary cap to help lure players from interstate. It's one of the many draft concessions released by the AFL for the team's entry to the national league.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8a0eb552ee496d363a82b4911b1ab47</guid></item><item><title>NSW government to allow registration of old farm utes and trucks used to fight fires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/incentive-helps-farmers-register-firefighting-vehicles/105838510</link><description>Farmers will pay lower registration fees on the old vehicles they keep on hand to fight fires under a new scheme in NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13f635fcd1378b8a6166f1da1e3f9825</guid></item><item><title>Inside the search for missing four-year-old boy Gus on isolated SA sheep station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/missing-boy-gus-yunta-search-timeline/105838592</link><description>Authorities are searching for a missing four-year-old boy on a sheep grazing station in the mid-north of South Australia. Here's what we know about the search so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1d3ba565b40f77a7bb990999b5cf38f</guid></item><item><title>NT Police seize more than 240 guns from former Kakadu park ranger who captured 5.1m crocodile, Sweetheart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/nt-police-seize-more-than-240-guns-from-dave-lindner-at-kakadu/105839596</link><description>A Kakadu National Park firearms dealer faces charges by NT Police for failing to properly store hundreds of guns being kept on a property at the park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be39bbc31ad71ea60ba658e07138213c</guid></item><item><title>Queensland youth worker jailed for nine years for 22 child exploitation offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/devante-lorenz-kr-richardson-guilty-of-child-expoitation/105840514</link><description>A 26-year-old man from Mackay who raped a child and was found with almost 2,000 child abuse images and videos on his phone is given a nine-year prison sentence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8e0a31d5c4d46501e0ab41b61736022</guid></item><item><title>Senate Republicans and Democrats blame each other for shutdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/senate-republicans-and-democrats-blame-each-other/105840984</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d49a09bbd1cb5309db5482c7e215978a</guid></item><item><title>Specialist search teams deployed near Benalla in search for Dezi Freeman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/fugitive-gunman-dezi-freeman-search-continues/105841044</link><description>Police are continuing the search for alleged gunman Dezi Freeman, deploying search teams to the area around Benalla in Victoria's north-east on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">741e4d73a1bdb12e6fbbd2e3251cf425</guid></item><item><title>Woman remains traumatised by police strip search as new commissioner issues apology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/woman-strip-searched-police-commissioner-offers-apology/105839310</link><description>At just 18 years old, Kristelle would step through the gates of a music festival in Sydney's west and leave feeling like she had been sexually assaulted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ace58a0669684993b23ba5cede75a806</guid></item><item><title>Wagga Wagga horse trader pleads not guilty to running an illegal knackery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/wagga-horse-trader-charged-over-alleged-illegal-knackery/105839370</link><description>Wagga Wagga property operator Adrian Talbot has been charged with operating a knackery and "animal food van" business without a licence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d21eb5cdfc6ca4179a624a5f6211876</guid></item><item><title>Dally M Awards 2025: James Tedesco and Tamika Upton win medal for second time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/dally-m-awards-2025-james-tedesco-tamika-upton/105841076</link><description>Sydney Roosters NRL captain James Tedesco and Brisbane Broncos NRLW fullback Tamika Upton have each created their own slice of history, winning the Dally M Medal for a second time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7d15948e9e4e8f20a40a16f5bf7f935</guid></item><item><title>Alleged cop killer Dezi Freeman's extreme and fanatical views existed for many years, say family and former friends</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/dezi-freeman-nephew-luke-filby-extremist-views-growing-pre-covid/105832296</link><description>Luke Filby remembers looking up to his uncle Dezi, right up until the point he didn't. And he's not alone in having stepped away before the killing of two police officers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9fe3822f92ca6b8d9c2d6f295f35c03</guid></item><item><title>Dally M 2025 red carpet: NRLW and NRL stars dress up for awards night</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/dally-m-awards-nrl-red-carpet-2025/105840674</link><description>The awards night for the NRL and NRLW gives players the chance to step out in something other than their grass-stained jerseys. So we're expecting big things on the Dally M red carpet in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec60f31828c3b9e85686085732fa31d7</guid></item><item><title>Cats apologise for 'inappropriate' Mad Monday behaviour, AFL 'not thrilled'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/afl-geelong-cats-bailey-smith-mad-monday/105840052</link><description>Geelong breaks its silence about the club's Mad Monday antics, revealing future post-season events "will not continue in this current form".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c7def3975ba28ff2ad000b6f29bec31</guid></item><item><title>Ash Gardner century guides Australia to win over New Zealand to start Women's World Cup defence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/womens-cricket-world-cup-australia-new-zealand/105839424</link><description>All-rounder Ash Gardner makes a landmark century as Australia kicks off its World Cup defence in India with a comfortable win over New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9571e8acd588e7d317bd8785353cb2a</guid></item><item><title>Dr Marianne Gale appointed new Queensland Chief Health Officer after lengthy search</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/dr-marianne-gale-named-as-queensland-chief-health-officer/105841346</link><description>Dr Marianne Gale previously held the high-profile role of NSW deputy chief health officer during the pandemic and will take on the top job in December.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5ddcb051f4f568ecba7e33265ebedbd</guid></item><item><title>2005 Bali bombings at Jimbaran Bay, Kuta remembered by survivors in Newcastle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/2005-bali-bombings-newcastle-vigil-20th-anniversary/105829890</link><description>Survivors of the 2005 Jimbaran Bay bombings gather in Newcastle to mark the 20th anniversary of the tragedy, which some feel is not as widely remembered as the 2002 Kuta blasts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46ee6ed8cdbc027297022965358254a9</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105841486</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da667996abee3f16b01a9ce07a601c25</guid></item><item><title>Former employees of sunscreen testing lab Princeton Consumer Research blow whistle on alleged questionable practices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/australian-sunscreen-brands-dump-spf-testing-lab-pcr/105841262</link><description>Two former employees of a leading international testing laboratory used by major Australian sunscreen brands have blown the whistle on alleged questionable data and incorrect testing practices, amid ongoing concerns about whether consumers can trust the products they are relying on for sun protection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1829a9601e42cc7008ce391c382c56a0</guid></item><item><title>The number of large companies paying no tax in Australia has declined, says ATO</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/companies-paying-no-tax-in-australia-has-declined/105838268</link><description>The proportion of large companies in Australia that paid no tax in the most recent income year has declined from 36 per cent to 28 per cent over the past 11 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">265d9aa2fb2dc799537c0206ea4c6c0b</guid></item><item><title>Israel steps up Gaza City offensive as Hamas weighs up ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/israel-issues-last-warning-to-leave-gaza-city/105842102</link><description>Witnesses reported heavy bombardment in Gaza City, as Israel's defence minister, Israel Katz, said the army was tightening its encirclement of the city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3c4fc429c7c0ff3156393e578aa6fb5</guid></item><item><title>Jane Goodall, renowned conservationist, dies aged 91</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/jane-goodall-dies-aged-91/105842164</link><description>The conservationist was renowned for her groundbreaking chimpanzee field research and globe-spanning environmental advocacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0bc08ad97bebddf06a9725d1cdcebd0</guid></item><item><title>Social media and online dating exposes girls to greater risks of child marriage, new report shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/social-media-digital-connection-child-marriage/105837010</link><description>Modern technology is allowing girls to choose their own partners but some remain vulnerable to child marriage to escape hardship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffcbc8ff415233f19e015967f810d465</guid></item><item><title>Greta Thunberg detained as Israel's military intercepts Gaza-bound aid flotilla</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/global-sumud-flotilla-intercepted-by-idf-near-gaza/105838920</link><description>The activists are expected to be detained and then taken to Ashdod, where they will be told to sign deportation orders and flown out of the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">535a79372b15f15f2a53967a4057c0a7</guid></item><item><title>From pharmaceuticals to kitchen cabinets, Trump's tariff program expands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/us-tariffs-industries-countries-most-impacted/105822256</link><description>Since returning to the White House, the US president has placed tariffs on more than 90 countries and a number of industries. Here are the countries and sectors most impacted by the tariffs from the Trump administration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52611230484b1f07cb56204c72c8d01c</guid></item><item><title>Calls to reform Australia's pension age as labourers consider early retirement due to injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/reform-by-occupation-needed-for-australian-pension-age/105836058</link><description>For some Australians, continuing to work until the pension age of 67 can be a struggle. Peita says a life of heavy lifting has taken its toll on her body, and she is trying to survive on JobSeeker payments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26bcf63c522f3bbec3e132d84b8f6b43</guid></item><item><title>The oceans keep score in a year of record heat around Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/hottest-year-on-record-in-oceans-around-australia/105698530</link><description>For the past year, Australia's oceans have been hotter than ever before. The impacts are being felt all across the nation — as far away from the coast as you can get.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54120136b83762f1dbbc0ac1cb4070b3</guid></item><item><title>VPNs, 'old man' masks, and AI: The holes in the social media ban and their fixes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/social-media-ban-vpns-masks-age-checks-disguises/105836134</link><description>From December 10, social media platforms will be forced to block under 16s in Australia from holding accounts, but experts warn age checks can be easily bypassed in several ways, including a $22 "old man" mask.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eeaf0bd64c8eab6d67fcdb13899b31a8</guid></item><item><title>Family of Indigenous man says NSW government apology for death in custody 'too little, too late'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/tj-denniss-family-rejects-apology-for-death-in-custody-inquest/105839270</link><description>The family of an Indigenous man who died in prison says an apology from Corrective Services NSW has come "too little, too late".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04c76042f49ade389bcc63a0798c2772</guid></item><item><title>JD Vance urges Democrats to 'open the people's government'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/jd-vance-urges-democrats-to-open-the-peoples-government/105842224</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">553b99247ec575cb9135c72d5af57ab5</guid></item><item><title>New 124-bed Launceston private hospital a step closer after unanimous council approval for planning change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/launceston-health-service-124-bed-private-public-hospital-plans/105839626</link><description>A plan that will enable a state-of-the-art medical facility with 10 operating theatres, a laboratory, pharmacy, helipad and a bridge to Launceston's public hospital is unanimously supported by all Launceston councillors in a vote.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f47005e2d71424e267f82803cbee7f82</guid></item><item><title>Staff shortage limits maternity services at St Vincent's Private Hospital Toowoomba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/staff-shortage-st-vincents-private-hospital-special-care-nursery/105810290</link><description>St Vincent's Private Hospital at Toowoomba sets up a hotline for expectant mothers, after temporarily scaling back services at its special care nursery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c2590f3ffce4756af342cf85ef62a7f</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide lord mayor confident on being COP31-ready despite hosting decision delays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/adelaide-confident-cop31-despite-delays/105841520</link><description>Adelaide's lord mayor is confident the city will be prepared to host the event, even though it is 13 months away and Australia remains in a deadlock over hosting rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30d7b35793ec02998db83cdcf2e64a0f</guid></item><item><title>'International Stabilisation Force' in Trump Gaza plan will be biggest challenge in peace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/international-stabilisation-force-trump-gaza-challenge-analysis/105841802</link><description>The US president's peace plan for Gaza includes the creation of a temporary "International Stabilisation Force", but analysts say this will be a challenging task.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c53e75be6fe418aeb21bbde7b2cbb21</guid></item><item><title>Police issue warrant for Sydney rapper YC Ewzy, aka Harley Johan, over Niddal Acherkouk shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/sydney-rapper-yc-ewzy-harley-johan-wanted-for-niddal-acherkouk/105842176</link><description>Police are looking for a Sydney rapper they believe fled the country after a gangland murder where a man was ambushed and gunned down at an inner-city service station in 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe9e6f30645a8932851c084664536574</guid></item><item><title>Year 7 students build open-source, 3D-printed hand for classmate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/3d-printed-hands-made-by-port-macquarie-high-school-sudents/105793670</link><description>Lois Agnello was born with only part of her left hand and came up with the idea to use her school's 3D printer to make a new one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3d31eb73797a3b74b3190d03ddcc240</guid></item><item><title>In winning his second Dally M player of the year award, James Tedesco is defying time itself</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/james-tedesco-sydney-roosters-dally-m/105841906</link><description>Roosters fullback James Tedesco held off the challenge of players over a decade his junior to defy time and claim his second Dally M player of the year award.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9b7d4d89b657c972a250ec831d33d86</guid></item><item><title>Disability advocates call for rethink after Palmerston Hospital's hydrotherapy pool closes to external providers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/palmerston-hospital-hydrotherapy-pool-closed-disability-provider/105833492</link><description>Robyne Burridge lives with a disability that severely impacts her mobility, and hydrotherapy is vital. But she hasn't received that treatment in months after the NT government cut off public access to the only suitable local facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">858ae7fc55c0e624a6ba1987e542bfa7</guid></item><item><title>Police release first picture of Gus as ADF joins the search for missing child</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/outback-search-for-boy-enters-sixth-day/105838064</link><description>Police have released the first image of Gus since his disappearance, with almost 50 members of the Australian Defence Force joining the search for the four-year-old in mid-north South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a99525f04f4d120b81c167ff33648857</guid></item><item><title>US government shutdown impacts felt across America as Trump administration threatens mass sackings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/us-government-shutdown-effects-day-one/105842146</link><description>The effects of the US government shutdown are being felt across America as the White House warns federal workers will be fired en masse if Democrats don't back down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e9e638864316a79689e887f741d2e58</guid></item><item><title>Australia's favourite authors share their top books of the 21st century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/radio-national-top-100-books-favourite-authors-21st-century/105835904</link><description>We asked Australia's favourite authors to share their top books of the 21st century. Here's what they said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16bbbcadeaf709b20e67dc7f0e8047f0</guid></item><item><title>Employee injured after he was startled by wasp has $870k damages win upheld</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/employee-who-suffered-trip-injury-has-damages-win-upheld/105834350</link><description>A groundsman who tripped over a bag of rubbish as he tried to evade a wasp says he wants workers to understand their rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2388d0a1754c37cc486832d75ae0e870</guid></item><item><title>'Tomorrow could be the day': Jordan Brunoli from Bugs opens up about terminal cancer fears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/bugs-bassist-jordan-brunoli-on-terminal-cancer-diagnosis/105839994</link><description>At 29, Australian musician Jordan Brunoli was diagnosed with incurable cancer. He says he's terrified of what comes next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa08a02f5d726657bc79b3e01ede5fdb</guid></item><item><title>Top statistician breaks silence over Murujuga rock art study near Woodside gas plant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/murujuga-rock-art-study-woodside-government-interference/105806508</link><description>A scientist who quit a major study on WA rock art is accusing the government of downplaying findings linking damage to heavy industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f66f15af3b15830fb1d8d958a73a835</guid></item><item><title>Top statistician accuses government of spinning rock art science</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/top-statistician-accuses-government-of-spinning/105841800</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74b9c5052592fd07c029066450853c90</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: PNG's PM says landmark treaty with Australia will strengthen its security — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/federal-politics-blog-oct-2/105841154</link><description>Papua New Guinea's Prime Minister James Marape confirms his cabinet has formally approved a landmark defence treaty with Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a68d88b3bc136dcfd088b17227fb19f</guid></item><item><title>Police find prisoner who went missing from Julia Creek Work Camp</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/prisoner-tory-ross-rose-absconds-from-julia-creek-work-camp/105842320</link><description>A 32-year-old serving a prison sentence for serious assault has been located after going missing in north-west Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0321481fde77c73c331ccb1dca5840dd</guid></item><item><title>NSW EPA blamed for slow contamination warning on Belubula River</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/belubula-river-community-unhappy-with-epa-response-on-pfos-pfas/105694456</link><description>Documents sought through freedom of information laws show the extent of fish contamination in a NSW river, information an inquiry found the EPA kept from the community for eight months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">237721a66d2f4bf2d0d31e48419bee52</guid></item><item><title>Phil Gould hospitalised over heart concerns, Canterbury Bulldogs football boss says 'everything is OK'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/phil-gould-hospitalised-with-heart-concerns/105842400</link><description>The Canterbury Bulldogs boss assures fans he is on the mend after being hospitalised when doctors found a problem during routine blood tests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fca2cdafe9c2f3febde1b0d4f863fc0</guid></item><item><title>Matildas star Mary Fowler continues her Manchester City career with one-year contract extension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/mary-fowler-extends-manchester-city-career-with-new-contract/105842402</link><description>Mary Fowler praises Manchester City for its support as the Matildas star announces a contract extension.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6cf27bc6840cef2b50b5c49c1eb7bbe</guid></item><item><title>Geraldton residents push for public medical imaging amid high costs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/geraldton-medical-imaging-petition-hospital-redevelopment/105822158</link><description>Residents in WA's Midwest are travelling hundreds of kilometres to avoid costly medical imaging fees. They say it is time that changed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8015e6d7b246dbcdd4c566c71b6bb96c</guid></item><item><title>Democrats blame Republicans for government shutdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/democrats-blame-republicans-for-government-shutdown/105842514</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">053b74de1df7d9b78b6136a1cc639987</guid></item><item><title>Nicole Kidman and Keith Urban have split. Here's what couples can expect when separating</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/nicole-kidman-keith-urban-what-couples-separating-can-expect/105837112</link><description>Nicole Kidman and Keith Urban are separating after 19 years of marriage. Separation is common — and here’s what experts say those of us living outside the public eye can expect when going through it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd0db49d65e1ac8c4979b60f6ecc9cc9</guid></item><item><title>Atherton small butcher buys local meatworks to supply beef across the country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/doug-cross-butcher-buys-innisfail-meatworks-to-expand/105830022</link><description>A Far North Queensland butcher expands his business into an established beef brand, with products sent all over Queensland and interstate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8762f2eb885bbdcb0827ce47f0596d66</guid></item><item><title>Couple rescued from Cradle Mountain Overland Track sheltered in 'freezing' conditions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/tas-cradle-mountain-hypothermia-rescue/105842526</link><description>Two bushwalkers with mild hypothermia have been walked out of Cradle Mountain National Park in Tasmania's central highlands after activating their emergency beacon on Wednesday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eea6e9808b60f9ef16b3c4563b262f98</guid></item><item><title>Helen Garner shortlisted for Baillie Gifford Prize for collected diaries, How to End a Story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/helen-garner-diaries-baillie-gifford-prize-how-to-end-a-story/105841834</link><description>This year, Helen Garner has been in Dua Lipa's book club and the SATC spin-off. Now she's in the running for the Baillie Gifford Prize for non-fiction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14369602aedac3875a90957a25b1e898</guid></item><item><title>Jane Goodall, who revolutionised our understanding of animals, dies at 91</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/primatologist-jane-goodall-obituary/102197696</link><description>British primatologist Jane Goodall entered the African wilderness at 26, without any formal scientific training or university degree. She emerged with research that forever changed how we understand the animal kingdom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">153dfb487b399dbad44404420549f752</guid></item><item><title>Mushroom murderer Erin Patterson's lawyer announces intention to appeal guilty verdicts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/vic-mushroom-murderer-erin-patterson-to-appeal-guilty-verdicts/105842550</link><description>The 51-year-old's lawyer says she will appeal a jury verdict that found her guilty of three murders and attempted murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e31e686a882dd6aa36f2c2b8d0bbe8c6</guid></item><item><title>Date set for Townsville mayoral by-election by postal ballot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/townsville-mayoral-election-date-confirmed/105842690</link><description>Townsville voters who have been in limbo since their mayor was suspended last year will vote in a by-election to select the city's next civic leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71672c41ad5dd03e2bd1ee3e3924c63d</guid></item><item><title>Review of west coast bushfires finds flaws in Tasmania's firefighting responses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/west-coast-bushfires-review-finds-flaws-tasmanian-response/105841250</link><description>A COVID outbreak that "spread quickly" through a cramped fire management headquarters was just one issue faced during the response to Tasmania's west coast fires last summer, a review finds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a66366e3bfd9f6a757b4494ed77ee3f9</guid></item><item><title>Dartbrook Hunter Valley mine to stop running after failed revival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/dartbrook-coal-mine-to-go-into-care-and-maintenance/105842500</link><description>The struggling Dartbrook Coal Mine will stop running less than a year after its new operators tried to revive it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dcd01bc3041595dab52e5bcf36d840c</guid></item><item><title>Former Queensland MP Michael Trout sentenced over misguided vigilante attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/former-queensland-mp-michael-trout-vigilante-attack/105842704</link><description>Michael Trout, along with his brother and friend, have been sentenced for attacking three innocent people, believing them to have been involved in making threats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01a75622672131d72da37ee2dd998c07</guid></item><item><title>Global financial stability risks have not receded, Reserve Bank warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/rba-financial-stability-review/105842650</link><description>The Reserve Bank warns risks to the global financial system are "rising", not receding, and Australia is not immune from any fallout.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">851ae0a01a9787f56e8f54291d6c183c</guid></item><item><title>Death of Dr Tiffany Wilkes and her daughter in suspected murder-suicide 'keenly' felt by medical community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/kenmore-hills-tiffany-wilkes-death-suspected-murder-suicide/105842600</link><description>Queensland's child safety and domestic violence prevention minister says the death of a mother and her daughter has "shocked" the community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe6f17f27398642dc58882c618fe80a8</guid></item><item><title>Glenelg beach blanketed with foam as Premier announces algal bloom hotline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/algal-bloom-hotline-phone-glenelg-beach-foam/105843172</link><description>Brown foam has blanketed one of the state's most popular tourist beaches in South Australia, as the state government launches an algal bloom hotline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2d5b9e47ac46a5465fba869e25c0169</guid></item><item><title>China's K visa scheme has some worrying about jobs in a country already facing challenges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/china-k-visa-draws-fierce-criticism/105840312</link><description>The new visa is designed to attract top global STEM talent but has sparked fierce backlash, with critics warning it could squeeze Chinese nationals out of the graduate job market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83c304642bcc0e464acc5ea89a172ec6</guid></item><item><title>First survey in five years shows feral deer population boom in Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/tas-new-feral-deer-survey-shows-population-boom/105843366</link><description>The first survey for feral deer in Tasmania in five years reveals an unanticipated increase of nearly 20,000 to the population.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcb4298825aee50a26688ab98726401b</guid></item><item><title>Murder investigation launched after father-of-two Chris Robertson's body found at Lonsdale workshop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/murder-inquiry-launched-after-body-found-at-lonsdale/105843258</link><description>The death of Chris Robertson, whose body was found at an industrial site in Adelaide's south on Tuesday, is now being treated as a major crime, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c06e6a130e76bcde2bf3ac0ea885de4e</guid></item><item><title>Papua New Guinea's cabinet approves 'Pukpuk' defence treaty with Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/papua-new-guinea-australia-pukpuk-treaty-signed/105843900</link><description>A landmark defence treaty between Australia and Papua New Guinea has been approved by PNG's cabinet, marking Australia first new alliance in more than 70 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8acda269673abe0de338cc7fb4537d4c</guid></item><item><title>Aussie travellers devastated after US government shutdown forces tourist attractions to close</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/us-government-shutdown-impact-on-australian-travellers/105842656</link><description>Australian travellers heading to the United States are being warned to expect disruptions with some tourist attractions closed, flights disrupted and national parks and museums affected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5165a8eefde415a0ffc3c848e0f0e8f</guid></item><item><title>Appeal for help over body in burnt-out SUV on Kamilaroi Highway near Brewarrina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/body-in-burnt-out-vehicle-kamilaroi-highway-brewarrina/105843926</link><description>Detectives have a possible identity for a body in a burnt-out station wagon in north-west New South Wales and have appealed for more information.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b22552689a4014f473aaf7cc7fece89e</guid></item><item><title>Afghan women's refugee team return to international football amid calls for more autonomy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/fifa-afghanistan-women-refugee-team-pauline-hamill-khalida-popal/105654814</link><description>Australian-based players headline the Afghan women's refugee football team preparing to play for the first time since the Taliban takeover in 2021, but they're still pushing for greater autonomy over their future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0d7815cd16393d1fc9c4d303f42e392</guid></item><item><title>Jarred Drew Heath pleads guilty after pointing replica gun at police in Gatton caravan park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/jarred-drew-heath-guilty-assaulting-police-after-gatton-incident/105844036</link><description>Jarred Drew Heath told police he wished he had a bullet and an "AK" to shoot officers with.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf1a67e48829338e5f0f6558b2899a44</guid></item><item><title>Menindee fish passage trial aimed at preventing mass deaths enters second stage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/menindee-murray-darling-basin-fish-passage-trial-stage-two/105834850</link><description>A fish passage that connects the Darling River with Lake Wetherell in order to redistribute native fish is being trialled with the aim of preventing more ecological disasters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55ec4cb350395391058860ad9a46d492</guid></item><item><title>Players to watch this Sheffield Shield season ahead of Ashes Test summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/players-to-watch-in-sheffield-shield-season-for-ashes/105842346</link><description>With Australia's men's Test team largely settled, there are a few key spots that could hang on a handful of Sheffield Shield performances before the start of the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">789a6a04a5d751968e98ce58ea9ea421</guid></item><item><title>Max Verstappen has never won the F1 Singapore Grand Prix but has a chance as he chases Oscar Piastri and McLaren</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/max-verstappen-f1-singapore-grand-prix-oscar-piastri/105843662</link><description>Max Verstappen has won the previous two grands prix in Formula 1, but this weekend's race in Singapore is the only circuit on the calendar on which he has never triumphed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87e6eaeb3c042f6e16d829282d81e75c</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia boarding school collapse reflects a 'widespread' building problem</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/indonesia-boarding-school-collapse-reveal-building-flaw/105842728</link><description>An operation to rescue around 60 children trapped under an Islamic boarding school in Indonesia’s East Java province has now shifted into a recovery operation, with the death toll expected to significantly rise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23bfe7434da9ebb565a471325bafb552</guid></item><item><title>Organisers refuse offer to move Agnes Water festival off rainbow bee-eater bird nesting site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/1770-cultural-festival-fears-for-protected-bird-nests/105835892</link><description>A two-day cultural festival will go ahead this weekend on top of a protected bird's nesting site in Queensland after organisers declined an offer of help to relocate it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4434e606677c5097da9ee84055bb42e9</guid></item><item><title>Ley fires off letters, Albanese reminds everyone he's home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/albanese-trip-optus-crisis-sussan-ley-letter/105830528</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and opposition energy spokesperson Dan Tehan have both arrived home from trips abroad with a spring in their step.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6219bec9e7727d19bcd5b5a19e1e3221</guid></item><item><title>What to know about the international flotilla that sought to break Israel's blockade of Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/what-to-know-about-global-sumud-flotilla-gaza/105842900</link><description>The activists expected Israeli authorities to intercept them, as has happened in past flotilla attempts to reach Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4684825a8da0061bdbad1d685ccd055</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Kaylen Bassett wins bronze at ICF Slalom World Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/icf-slalom-world-championships-bassett-bronze/105844750</link><description>Australia's Kaylen Bassett manages Australia's first podium finish at the ICF Slalom World Championships in Penrith, while Olympic gold medallist Noémie Fox is left to reflect on what might have been.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c36f3ebff2b86d3940711747156cc086</guid></item><item><title>Retired detective hopes for justice in Cheryl Grimmer missing person case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/search-conducted-for-missing-child-cheryl-grimmer-remains/105841818</link><description>A retired detective is urging the man who once confessed to Cheryl Grimmer's murder to hand himself in, as volunteers search for her remains in Wollongong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a5cc40529897054c7661a9c21f1fadc</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Constance's Shoalhaven council CEO appointment to be probed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/investigation-after-andrew-constance-appointed-shoalhaven-ceo/105843568</link><description>The NSW Office of Local Government will investigate the appointment of former state minister Andrew Constance as the CEO of Shoalhaven City Council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdcfb2a15b8d24f408232acc12f76327</guid></item><item><title>Tesla and SpaceX CEO Elon Musk becomes world's first person to be valued over $500 billion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/elon-musk-worlds-richest/105844954</link><description>The Tesla and SpaceX CEO's net worth hit $US500 billion ($755 billion) on Wednesday, the "Real-Time Billionaires" tracker reported.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f5f4348c0e522fc29cd9a6ee3775837</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with lighting fires after start of fire bans in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/alleged-chinchilla-fire-starter-in-court-during-qld-fire-ban/105842770</link><description>A 27-year-old man has been charged with deliberately setting fire to bushland in Blackswamp, south-west Queensland, during a total fire ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">043ca5e23eb0529cbc5cb8bf7e1966fc</guid></item><item><title>Details of sophisticated drug distribution system run by teenager revealed in ACT Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/act-teenager-faces-court-for-running-sophisticated-drug-ring/105844950</link><description>Details of a sophisticated drug distribution system run by a teenager emerge after she pleads guilty to charges including attempting to possess a marketable quantity of cocaine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2be80fc3aada161e9b9e6812f55a6d1b</guid></item><item><title>South West Aboriginal Medical Service members expelled after allegedly 'storming' headquarters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/south-west-aboriginal-medical-service-members-expelled/105835570</link><description>The South West Aboriginal Medical Service has expelled several of its members who it has accused of sowing community division.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d58f590226ffd5ec4e623b45427995e</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies bolstered by Will Skelton's return for Bledisloe Cup Test against All Blacks in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/wallabies-all-blacks-bledisloe-cup-rugby-championship/105845674</link><description>The Wallabies regain enforcer Will Skelton for Saturday night's sold-out Bledisloe Cup Test in Perth, but veteran fly half James O'Connor is dropped to the bench.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77cf19e4d52cf3a8b1ad279f6be25948</guid></item><item><title>Review finds Barkly bushfire overwhelmed authorities and killed 37,000 cattle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/barkly-fire-killed-thousands-of-cattle-review-finds/105842564</link><description>The fire threatened communities, destroyed more than 3,500km of fencing and cost the NT's cattle industry an estimated $120 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf2f515eef61b0484d09c2a9ceec4e9f</guid></item><item><title>Report into proposed Burswood racetrack finds noise concerns for locals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/burswood-racetrack-noise-concerns-report/105845314</link><description>Noise levels from a controversial motorsport racetrack planned for inner-city Perth are likely to be excessive for residents of nearby apartments and guests at the adjacent Crown entertainment complex, a new report finds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dde0f26a9c584b6ebb95b4b4c84f567</guid></item><item><title>Fertility treatments impacted by donor limit mix-up can proceed under NSW Health exemption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/fertility-treatments-to-proceed-after-nsw-health-exemption/105845260</link><description>Fertility treatments in NSW will be able to continue even in cases where the family donor limit has been breached after the state government issued a temporary exemption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7a47a0b5e094fc99008d0d76761db5b</guid></item><item><title>Colonnades, Modbury, Tea Tree and Rundle Mall among latest shopping centres to become Declared Public Precincts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/colonnades-modbury-tea-tree-plaza-rundle-mall-public-precincts/105844740</link><description>Three Adelaide shopping centres are among the latest sites where police can search for knives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e424510c86d4274f12853bc186cfbf98</guid></item><item><title>Coutts Crossing bushfire downgraded from emergency to advice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/coutts-crossing-bushfire-emergency-nsw-north-coast/105845190</link><description>A day into the bushfire season, a blaze threatening more than a dozen buildings in the Clarence Valley has been downgraded after escalating to an emergency level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">883abe4989535ef75a9a275843e0cfd0</guid></item><item><title>Who was Jane Goodall? Here's a look back at her life in photos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/jane-goodall-chimpanzees-photos-/105842700</link><description>Primatologist Jane Goodall has died aged 91, leaving behind an impressive legacy in science and conservation. Here's a look back at her life in photos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed6bf152f63bc75d080dd7d2fa4d7230</guid></item><item><title>Canberra cyclist captures 'incredible' moment magpie plucks earphone from his ear on camera</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/magpie-swoop-pluck-earphone-from-ear-captured-camera/105845372</link><description>A Canberra man has captured footage of the dramatic moment a magpie plucked his earphone from his ear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b576bf57bf07e8e6ec534073ae5af4a1</guid></item><item><title>Demons meet with Clayton Oliver amid rumoured exit from AFL club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/afl-melbourne-demons-clayton-oliver-christian-petracca/105845936</link><description>Clayton Oliver appears set to leave Melbourne after the Demons reveal they will not stand in his way if he wants to consider a trade to another club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd9730e9523ad122afacace37169f5a2</guid></item><item><title>Broncos respond to Storm star Stefano Utoikamanu's 'stuck up' barb ahead of NRL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/nrl-grand-final-brisbane-broncos-melbourne-storm/105846050</link><description>The mind games continue in the build-up to Sunday's season decider, with the Broncos reacting to Storm front-rower Stefano Utoikamanu's sledge earlier this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">108176c74a5c4c7627684927f34b7745</guid></item><item><title>Endangered numbats stressed by over-eager nature photographers, authorities say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/photographers-urged-to-maintain-distance-from-numbats-wa/105844130</link><description>Authorities say getting to close to numbats can make them anxious enough to abandon their young and are urging photographers to give the endangered animals their space.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67cb631989ddbc5dd6344e8eb42942fe</guid></item><item><title>Mildura leaders label Qantas staff base closure a 'slap in the face' to region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/closure-of-mildura-qantas-staff-base-slammed-by-politicians/105839232</link><description>Regional politicians unanimously condemn Qantas over the impending closure of its Mildura crew base, saying it underscores the city's vulnerability to the "whims" of private transport companies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36df8aca49b62a9d5ccd4097b776a5df</guid></item><item><title>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy accuses Russia of raising nuclear risk after Chernobyl power cut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/ukraine-accuses-russia-of-raising-nuclear-risk-chernobyl/105846000</link><description>Volodymyr Zelenskyy said more than 20 Russian drones had been deployed in the attack on the town of Slavutych that cut power to the nearby Chernobyl plant for three hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdc2f2d1ffa9520461b858bd3a31e5c0</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/105846282</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40beaae9cbc027d987206ec2f8fee66f</guid></item><item><title>Review into senior NT police appointments made under ousted commissioner released to the public</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/review-into-nt-police-senior-appointments-released/105845308</link><description>An inquiry into recruitment processes for senior NT police positions recommends "significant improvements", noting there are "widely held beliefs" that "bias", "favouritism" and "nepotism" have impacted promotions within the force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">439354def5398861162db68ac6aadc7b</guid></item><item><title>BBC exposes hidden culture of misogyny and racism inside UK Police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/bbc-filming-exposes-hidden-culture-of-misogyny-and-racism-inside/105846128</link><description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer has called for a "robust" response by the head of London's Metropolitan Police after an undercover investigation exposed the force's hidden culture of misogyny and racism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a5e49ee8734de794306f0e01d0f37e5</guid></item><item><title>Protesters restrained at snap pro-Palestinian rally at Sydney Town Hall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/nsw-floatilla-protest-sydney-town-hall-police-restrain/105846204</link><description>The unauthorised event was held in response to the interception of a Gaza-bound aid flotilla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d349b964559368d88442b48dbc749c73</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm and Brisbane Broncos face off in NRL Grand Final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/melbourne-storm-and-brisbane-broncos-face-off-in/105846424</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7c17a506df456fc9c620d5c07d1e268</guid></item><item><title>Terror incident declared after two killed in Manchester synagogue attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/three-people-dead-synagogue-attack-manchester/105846410</link><description>The assailant, who has been shot dead by police, drove a car into people outside a synagogue in northern England before stabbing them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2ffbc85d4c9b01ce1d0a17968deafb9</guid></item><item><title>Manchester Police name UK synagogue attacker as Israel calls for action on antisemitism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/manchester-police-name-suspect-in-uk-synagogue-attack/105846608</link><description>Police say that three suspects — two men in their 30s and a woman in her 60s — are also currently in custody and "have been arrested on suspicion of commission, preparation and instigation of acts of terrorism".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1683a08119eebbcfc41d687331f8a172</guid></item><item><title>Japan's top contenders for prime minister are an 'Iron Lady' and the son of a former PM</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/japan-next-prime-minister-candidates-are-starkly-different/105843004</link><description>Japan's Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba is stepping down as leader after only a year in the role. It has left his party looking for a new face — and the frontrunner options could not be more different.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a64b8b4367e615f378ad174a6e30f17</guid></item><item><title>Sexual predator taught in Brisbane schools for nine years after parents' complaints</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/brisbane-schools-sexual-predator-teacher-complaints/105822874</link><description>Even after putting a stop to their abuser's access to students, Alliyah faced an uphill battle to get basic information about what had happened behind the scenes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">995443c9f91e6f16d7611a4494aeaf37</guid></item><item><title>COP climate talks are 'heartbreak' for Pacific Islands. Here is why they want to host them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/pacific-cohosting-cop-31-climate-change/105834230</link><description>The global COP climate talks have been a source of frustration and disappointment for Pacific nations. They hope hosting the event will change that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4b14479d18ffc36161728080a2125fc</guid></item><item><title>Nine people killed in violent Kashmir protests that took place during internet blackout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/nine-killed-in-violent-anti-government-kashmir-protests/105846508</link><description>The extent of the violence is still becoming clear after days of protests took place amid an internet blackout in the region of Kashmir administered by Pakistan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4241a7a41504a46692c346d92c0a1b6b</guid></item><item><title>One per cent of road damage and injury claims lodged by Victorian drivers approved for compensation over two years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/victoria-potholes-road-repairs-compensation-claims-drivers/105835794</link><description>New data obtained by the ABC under Freedom of Information laws show the majority of claims for compensation by drivers encountering hazards on Victorian roads are being rejected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd2cf984548fcdfcd0f52d75b31d143b</guid></item><item><title>Should we have more federal politicians?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/grattan-on-friday-case-for-more-politicians/105778642</link><description>A Labor factional heavyweight is making the case for more federal politicians and longer, fixed parliamentary terms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f7fa0ebf6987e59a372cdca577e1bc2</guid></item><item><title>Keir Starmer addresses 'terrorist' attack at a synagogue in Manchester</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/keir-starmer-addresses-terrorist-attack-at-a-synagogue/105847016</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc7fd6d9c4f4ec8c1d5c67272aea546d</guid></item><item><title>Jarrod Bleijie hopes the CFMEU inquiry will lead to a cultural shift in the union</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/jarrod-bleijie-hopes-the-cfmeu-inquiry-will-lead/105844804</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c4610785aca637173cdd9561edef32d</guid></item><item><title>Mr Bleijie is asked if he considers himself an 'attack dog'.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/mr-bleijie-is-asked-if-he-considers-himself-an/105845296</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ed4b0b4f507126c39745767be837896</guid></item><item><title>Deputy premier Jarrod Bleijie says government won't deregister Queensland branch of CFMEU</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/qld-stateline-deputy-premier-wont-deregister-cfmeu/105841406</link><description>Jarrod Bleijie says the government will not abolish the union, as a major inquiry gets underway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e749491ed307876a79dc9599963f1b9</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: A game-winning shot, a shocking Hollywood separation and a government shutdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/abc-weekly-news-quiz-october-3/105843780</link><description>It's that time of the week again. Test your news knowledge to see how much you remember for the week that was.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dca4e8dd7cdcc2d4bf57dbae3179c202</guid></item><item><title>Were you paying attention to this year's NRL season? Test your memory here</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/nrl-2025-season-quiz/105844022</link><description>There are just four halves left of the NRL and NRLW seasons this year. As we get ready for the grand final this Sunday, test your memory on the year that was.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4f239501101ad6444c2b76292a4e657</guid></item><item><title>As Dezi Freeman search goes on, Porepunkah businesses wait for government support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/porepunkah-business-waiting-financial-support-dezi-freeman/105845384</link><description>Businesses hurt by stay-away orders issued during the search for alleged police killer Dezi Freeman say they have yet to receive the government support they were promised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e19a0607dc2b3d096b10370f40e57ff</guid></item><item><title>Mascots, superfans prepare to shine in NRL grand final clash between Storm and Broncos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/qld-nrl-superfans-mascots-grand-final-broncos-storm/105845318</link><description>As the Brisbane Broncos prepare to take on the Melbourne Storm in Sydney on Sunday, fans and mascots are gearing up for the match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6603d035702db9d3ce9f7f90d88f6b54</guid></item><item><title>Superfan moved to tears after Broncos prelim win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/superfan-moved-to-tears-after-broncos-prelim-win/105846294</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fa83af8fb0313f93621ef6b79233b7d</guid></item><item><title>Hollywood director James Cameron opens up on AI, future Terminator films and the Avatar franchise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/james-cameron-ai-avatar-terminator-films/105840784</link><description>The Hollywood director has been present in the film space for many years but the emergence of AI and its power has him somewhat scared for the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5b6816d043cafca9efcdcda90714b4f</guid></item><item><title>The magic of the mountain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/first-australian-ascent-mount-everest-anniversary-never-repeated/105810348</link><description>In the 41 years since the first Australians summitted Mt Everest, the mountain has been transformed into a tourist attraction. Does the original magic still exist?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d512f5111787af05781d026f521a5f22</guid></item><item><title>Jane Goodall changed how we thought about chimps. Why did we know so little before?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/jane-goodall-death-why-we-knew-so-little-about-chimpanzees/105843330</link><description>In the chimp world, there was the time before Jane Goodall and the time after. This is the reason we knew so little about the great ape before 1960, according to the woman who dedicated her life to humankind's closest cousins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">572926e6282ff94c6f46f75de5805dae</guid></item><item><title>Bendigo nurses call for hospital mental health hub as ED presentations climb</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/nurses-call-for-mental-health-hub-at-bendigo-hospital/105840548</link><description>An increase in mental health and drug-related emergencies puts strain on Bendigo hospital's emergency department, prompting calls for a dedicated treatment hub.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c0de9a4d977eb2ecb8d406519aca81c</guid></item><item><title>NT Attorney-General Marie-Clare Boothby sits down for exclusive one-on-one interview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/the-nt%E2%80%99s-attorney-general-has-said-she-questions/105846468</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2db9f76664a72fda406320b43846a1ee</guid></item><item><title>'It's not racist to want a safer community': NT attorney-general defends CLP crime policies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/nt-attorney-general-says-tougher-punishments-help-close-the-gap/105834110</link><description>The NT's attorney-general says she is focused on protecting victims regardless of their cultural background and questions allegations that the government's suite of crime reforms is targeting Aboriginal Territorians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00d7536a0466c72d21ef26195c655f52</guid></item><item><title>Police commissioner says there's no 'boys' club'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/police-commissioner-says-theres-no-boys-club/105846328</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64157b2f489884378f2442175e2e0dcb</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon says he wants to get force's culture 'right'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/new-nsw-police-commissioner-mal-lanyon-stateline/105845430</link><description>The new commissioner of NSW Police does not believe there is still a "boys' club" within the force, but says behaviour that prompted a workplace culture review will not be accepted under his leadership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b9d517e4455ac65cdd6d31ceb09532a</guid></item><item><title>Community comes together as search for missing 4yo Gus enters seventh day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/search-for-missing-boy-gus-enters-seventh-day/105845972</link><description>The search for missing four-year-old Gus has entered its seventh day, with no new signs of the boy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae5919e64d67cdd5c968e28dd35f55b0</guid></item><item><title>Hawthorn beats Fremantle by 15 points as gritty performance proves AFLW top-four credentials</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/hawks-prove-aflw-top-four-credentials-with-tough-win-over-freo/105847060</link><description>Hawthorn posts a third consecutive AFLW victory to boost its top-four hopes, outlasting Fremantle in cold and windy conditions in Frankston.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a72ff41e01a7fdcc21a95c419f64182</guid></item><item><title>Mind games and magic as Maguire and Bellamy battle it out for NRL supremacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/nrl-grand-final-roy-masters-2025-preview/105838296</link><description>Craig Bellamy and Michael Maguire know each other better than most NRL coaches, and that familiarity will play a major part in how they tackle the NRL grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f0764586bc67adb2b1fd85c05e3b384</guid></item><item><title>Outback residents lose solar farm as Ergon battles push owner to close</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/normanton-solar-farm-turns-off-after-ergon-energy-negotiations/105843958</link><description>The owner of a huge solar farm in outback Queensland hits the kill switch after almost a decade, saying his contract with Ergon Energy was unfair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d66d8ac5f8725a41e5ce4bbcfda73e48</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Greens urge government to swiftly secure release of Australians on Gaza flotilla — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/federal-politics-live-blog-oct-3/105846016</link><description>The Greens have urged the federal government to swiftly secure the release of a number of Australians who were detained by Israel while sailing to Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbb2ef304481b9ae06310993de6e80ff</guid></item><item><title>Frustrated residents facing 24-hour Sydney Metro excavation and hammering</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/sydney-metro-construction-noise-complaints-hammering/105845774</link><description>Sydney Metro construction once made John Finucane's home "uninhabitable" for two years. Now he has been told to expect 24-hour hammering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5630135b077e0a3b3d3e2e754487f762</guid></item><item><title>Housing crisis, massive cows and canola fields visible from space feature in our top September news photos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/september-photo-wrap/105836854</link><description>From gargantuan cows to Canola fields visible from space, here are our top photos from WA's first month of spring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fd14132c025578a2fa6734757a965cb</guid></item><item><title>WA gold projects forecast to create more jobs than iron ore in next five years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/job-opportunities-in-gold-mining-surge-as-confidence-booms/105816580</link><description>The gold-mining sector is set to boost WA's economy, with 2,400 new jobs forecast over the next five years compared to 1,200 in iron ore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a04a633d449ab31d0999b87c11c53b3</guid></item><item><title>Vladimir Putin swipes back at Donald Trump's 'paper tiger' comment, sends warning to NATO</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/vladimir-putin-swipes-back-at-donald-trump-paper-tiger/105847048</link><description>The Russian president says it is NATO that is the "paper tiger," and "if anyone still has a desire to compete with us in the military sphere, as we say, feel free, let them try".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a18d3f1ad6b0568eb4154f5b2acf85d</guid></item><item><title>ASX rises as DigiCo surges as Telstra fined $18m over misleading customers — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/105847156</link><description>The ASX has made modest gains after trading flat early on, as a slide for energy producers offset gains for industrial, healthcare and tech stocks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81fe3fdb111272da960ac13234d5bc7a</guid></item><item><title>Zach Merrett's Essendon future in Bombers' hands despite star's apparent best and fairest farewell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/zach-merrett-future-in-essendon-hands-best-and-fairest/105847122</link><description>Zach Merrett's speech after winning Essendon's best and fairest seems like a farewell, but it will be up to the Bombers as to whether the captain is allowed to leave the club in the AFL trade period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1108ff7c2a5cc348cfe10a2a9f3b2fb2</guid></item><item><title>Family of man killed in level crossing crash says safety trial a 'waste of time'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/ethan-hunter-mum-says-level-crossing-safety-trial-waste-of-time/105830854</link><description>Ethan Hunter's mother says governments have failed to learn from her son's death at a level crossing in regional New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">272fe29f80e9b45182b8950f0bf577fc</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters tackle Brisbane bushfire, dozens of other incidents after hot weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/brisbane-bushfire-warning-issued-after-unusually-hot-weather/105847132</link><description>Queensland firefighters respond to more than 100 active incidents following unusually hot October temperatures, while one city breaks an October heat record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01e2c8f64ee747e83fb700528bbcb26b</guid></item><item><title>Revised corridor for New England REZ leaves Walcha residents 'shocked'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/walcha-residents-shocked-at-revised-transmission-corridor-rez/105842964</link><description>Property owners in the path of a proposed new route for the New England renewable energy zone corridor fear their land values will plummet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec4bbfacc4b08613f739bd1cfd4c7f75</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Rooster Captain James Tedesco wins Dally M Medal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/sydney-rooster-captain-james-tedesco-wins-dally-m/105847216</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cc61338bbde21a344a791921104e547</guid></item><item><title>Emily Blunt and Dwayne 'The Rock' Johnson on their new movie The Smashing Machine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/emily-blunt-and-the-rock-johnson-on-their-new/105847192</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8ef066682c45612bb74fd923087ebe0</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja prepares for Australia's monumental Ashes summer, unafraid of 'the end'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/usman-khawaja-on-cricket-religion-and-the-end/105847220</link><description>Usman Khawaja is riding his late-career resurgence into another Ashes summer, and says his comfort with an inevitable end has inspired it all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01d27eb1d14f1f2ebcf664c5d5b80e2c</guid></item><item><title>Veteran Kalgoorlie trainer weighs in on this weekend's $1 million Golden Saddle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/golden-saddle-shines-spotlight-on-kalgoorlie-race-round/105803638</link><description>Kalgoorlie prepares for one of the biggest events in more than a century of country WA racing — this Saturday's $1 million Golden Saddle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eaef787a8198665f540245d066bc7687</guid></item><item><title>Darwin businesses call for return of late-night security patrols amid violence, anti-social behaviour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/nt-businesses-want-late-night-private-security-patrols-tps/105832474</link><description>There's been a spike in reports of violent and anti-social incidents in the CBD, as Darwin businesses call for more government investment in late-night security patrols.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9129b1374b7c1fe9c3ca953bfdac1f96</guid></item><item><title>Hopes new Australian fabric will revitalise domestic clothing manufacturing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/mud-to-marle-project-australian-cotton-wool-blend-fabric/105782204</link><description>Scientists, farmers and the fashion industry collaborate to create a natural fabric that is both woven and knitted, low on emissions and set to shake up how we think about clothing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8786260615151a28c4914c124e51572</guid></item><item><title>NSW psychiatrists win 20 per cent pay rise in industrial relations commission ruling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/nsw-psychiatrists-pay-dispute-decision-industrial-relations/105847556</link><description>The NSW Industrial Relations Commission has delivered its decision in a wages dispute between the state's public psychiatrists and the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c49714cfa5671e09061595c06176ac82</guid></item><item><title>Rabbi and security hailed as heroes after they stopped attacker getting inside Manchester synagogue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/rabbi-and-security-heroes-after-manchester-synagogue-attack/105847376</link><description>British Prime Minister Sir Keir Starmer said "there is no doubt whatsoever that they have prevented an even greater tragedy".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4616f086ff7d40a84d1ab340a92847dc</guid></item><item><title>Top six bugs nominated for 2025 ABC Australian Insect of the Year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/2025-australian-insect-of-the-year-finalists/105660068</link><description>Whether you love beetles or the giant mantis it's time to cast your vote for Australia's top insect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">434faa509dab4b4572373554ad829cab</guid></item><item><title>Officers wrap up police operation in Sydney's south-west following reports of a person carrying a gun</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/nsw-police-operation-in-panania-southwest-sydney/105847752</link><description>NSW Police said a member of the public reported seeing four people, one of whom appeared to be carrying a gun, leave a dark-coloured sedan or station wagon and go into a home on the street.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">017942901920271035705460937cf26d</guid></item><item><title>New Melbourne flood mapping sparks outrage from inner-city council</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/melbourne-water-flood-mapping-yarra-darebin-council-outrage/105847310</link><description>The City of Yarra mayor has lashed the government over the mapping, saying residents will bear the costs of inadequate infrastructure investment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a80116639f6fff903b19e327a88cc5b</guid></item><item><title>Man threatened woman with gun before rape, kidnap, police allege</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/man-charged-kidnapping-raping-woman-from-maroochydore-business/105847734</link><description>A court hears the charges against a man police allege threatened a 33-year-old woman at a Maroochydore business with a firearm before raping her, kidnapping her and driving hundreds of kilometres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4719acc4465c44e1e16dec5bffeb1c96</guid></item><item><title>Tony Mokbel acquitted of some drug convictions but faces a retrial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/tony-mokbel-appeal-court-decision/105847094</link><description>The drug kingpin has had a mixed result in his appeal against three convictions, with a possible retrial looming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2701adaad45bdef6d071813ec68777a6</guid></item><item><title>Disability employment provider Bedford kept afloat with $4.4m funding injection as hunt for buyer continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/bedford-federal-government-support-as-hunt-for-buyer-begins/105847272</link><description>Australia's second-largest disability employment provider Bedford will be kept afloat by a $4.4 million federal government funding injection as it seeks a buyer for the embattled business.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ef5dcdbe0fc0107fc169a4f64467b91</guid></item><item><title>South Australian Riverland welcomes summer tourists avoiding algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/sa-riverland-welcomes-summer-tourists-avoiding-algal-bloom/105810500</link><description>An algal bloom causing toxic foam and fish kills along South Australia's beaches prompts holiday-makers to consider alternative summer travel plans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a566a7a332296798c499f3901cf5243c</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian tractor convoy unable to break stalemate on potato farmer pay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/tasmanian-potato-farmer-tractor-protest/105843374</link><description>Tasmanian potato farmers have rejected a second pay offer from multinational processor Simplot that would see farmers paid less per kilo than last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09e973a835d628032b574923d09e8ee3</guid></item><item><title>AEC launches legal action against man accused of distributing unauthorised pamphlets attacking Allegra Spender</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/aec-allegra-spender-pamphlets-court-action-alternates/105847806</link><description>The Australian Electoral Commission has launched legal action against a finance executive and Wentworth constituent in relation to 47,000 unauthorised pamphlets which were distributed in the electorate during the 2025 election campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">341176b5da5c0891e79278703f463f38</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the synagogue terrorist attack in Manchester</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/manchester-synagogue-stabbing-terrorist-attack/105847346</link><description>A witness says the attacker crashed his car and then began "stabbing anyone near him" before trying to get into the synagogue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">305cc0f31bc44efe40e915cfaeed519e</guid></item><item><title>When does daylight saving time start in Australia? Here's your pocket guide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/daylight-saving-time-2025-pocket-guide/105801688</link><description>Here's your quick pocket guide on daylight saving as Australia comes into the warmer months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78826411bece51ca43fdb5b03dc8a1fb</guid></item><item><title>Understanding the grief of euthanising a pet after Lewis Hamilton's dog's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/lewis-hamilton-how-to-cope-with-the-euthanasing-pet/105842858</link><description>Vets and counsellors say owners can prepare for and address the complicated grief that can come with euthanasing a pet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc284bd2d3e74988ee2cec198a7a2dcc</guid></item><item><title>Murder accused former police officer Beau Lamarre-Condon makes courtroom outburst</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/beau-lamarre-condon-murder-accused-courtroom-outburst/105848016</link><description>Former NSW Police officer Beau Lamarre-Condon tells a Supreme Court judge that he "will not be silenced" and declared "the truth will prevail".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9679372483dfd7fa72742615d65e1249</guid></item><item><title>Prisoner who bit off opponent's ear after volleyball game to spend extra time in jail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/prisoner-bit-off-opponents-ear-volleyball-game-sentenced/105848268</link><description>A prisoner has been sentenced to additional jail time, after admitting to biting off part of the ear of another inmate during a fight after a volleyball game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1ee6b54b500288d84e8f30ef80c42e6</guid></item><item><title>Ben Hunt's Brisbane Broncos return comes full circle with shot at NRL grand final redemption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/ben-hunt-nrl-grand-final-redemption-with-brisbane-broncos/105848298</link><description>The Broncos have had their share of NRL grand final heartache over the years, but no-one feels it quite as acutely as Ben Hunt</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f065a83450971fe4e65c14394779aaf</guid></item><item><title>Snowy 2.0 faces cost blowouts beyond previous $12 billion target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/snowy-hydro-cost-blowout-assessment-deliver-project/105775866</link><description>Snowy Hydro says it will need to acquire more funds to deliver the Snowy 2.0 renewable energy project, as costs continue to spiral beyond the previous $10 billion blowout.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09bf43d6bf450508ce050b2d7473bf7d</guid></item><item><title>Brett Button appeals 32-year sentence over Hunter Valley bus crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/brett-button-hunter-valley-wedding-bus-crash-sentence-appeal/105820966</link><description>Lawyers for the driver of a bus that crashed in the New South Wales Hunter Valley, killing 10 people, have detailed his appeal against a 32-year sentence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f083c9cf0971263b7f88a1efd520f190</guid></item><item><title>Is Israel breaking international law by seizing humanitarian ships bound for Gaza?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/israel-interception-of-the-gaza-bound-flotilla-international-law/105847392</link><description>According to a UN legal framework, a nation's territory does not extend beyond 19km from its shores but enforcing international maritime law is a challenge across the globe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e52292baa216c056f7d8d213ce9e2b14</guid></item><item><title>Case against Molly Ticehurst's alleged domestic violence murderer Daniel Billings adjourned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/daniel-billings-court-adjourned-molly-ticehurst/105848224</link><description>Daniel Billings's defence lawyer tells the court negotiations are in a "fragile place", as the case over the alleged murder of the 28-year-old mother is adjourned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c847b82dc47c7c9118aeeb8d0c31294</guid></item><item><title>UK police shoot Manchester synagogue attacker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/uk-police-shoot-manchester-synagogue-attacker/105847630</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71f04eac47c3331909c53b7dde27fca9</guid></item><item><title>Formal complaint lodged against ACT Opposition Leader Leanne Castley, later withdrawn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/formal-complaint-lodged-withdrawn-against-leanne-castley/105833852</link><description>Documents obtained by the ABC under a freedom of information request reveal that a complaint about Leanne Castley was formally lodged on June 25, though it was later withdrawn.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dbe5daabde2025d40ca3d144d396b8e</guid></item><item><title>Police scale back search for missing 4yo boy Gus in outback South Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/search-for-missing-gus-remote-south-australia/105847846</link><description>South Australian Police are scaling back the search for a four-year-old boy, who disappeared in the state’s mid-north almost a week ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce6a11fb2bb0817a73aa43bb01238ef4</guid></item><item><title>Tactical police attend property in Panania.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/tactical-police-attend-property-in-panania/105848382</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">539c909c3263ed85dedcc5f550055db4</guid></item><item><title>South Korea’s president apologises on Facebook for poorly managed foreign adoption programs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/south-korea-president-apologises-foreign-adoption-programs/105848604</link><description>South Korea President Lee Jae Myung apologises for poorly managed foreign adoption programs that were rife with abuses and fraud, months after the country’s truth commission admits state responsibilities for such practices for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dde3e7aca4dc16cd436cdd145fb1f36</guid></item><item><title>St Kilda take Carlton's Jack Silvagni, Tom De Koning in line as free agency begins; Charlie Curnow and Christian Petracca in focus for trade period</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/afl-free-agency-trade-period/105847468</link><description>Clubs move to formalise deals as the free agency period gets underway, and a series of big names could be on the move in next week's trade period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4be88f41eb233126ffc3551457f4079</guid></item><item><title>Pro-Palestinian protesters told Sydney Opera House 'off-limits' for planned rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/pro-palestine-march-planned-for-sydney-opera-house/105848564</link><description>NSW Police says the location and expected scale of the rally planned by the Palestinian Action Group poses public safety concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75e8ff7e77c0e3b00a8c435b6cb3bb22</guid></item><item><title>US investigators launch review into 2005 death of journalist and author Hunter S Thompson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/hunter-s-thompson-death-case-review/105845274</link><description>A Colorado sheriff says his office wants to address lingering questions surrounding the author's death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7c08b3f4d166f6816566d7522b8df0a</guid></item><item><title>Queensland doctors provide rural health road map at generalist forum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/queensland-doctors-provide-framework-for-rural-health-in-roma/105848602</link><description>More than 150 medical practitioners and stakeholders gather in Roma to discuss the future of rural generalist medicine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49cd92b3b374e065a8d17ebb61a6c63c</guid></item><item><title>Carnarvon locals help rescue tourist hit by 'king wave' along Quobba coastline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/carnarvon-tourist-rescued-swept-off-quobba-rocks-fishing/105848502</link><description>Quick-thinking locals leapt into action after a tourist in WA's north was swept into the ocean while rock fishing. A rescue in rough seas and "pitch-black" conditions ensued.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd5d139d1a7bfe5641b9654ad0befc1b</guid></item><item><title>How long will the government shutdown last? Here's what history tells us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/us-government-shutdown-history/105848348</link><description>While shutdowns have been a possibility since 1976, when Congress introduced the modern budget process, they've been a relatively rare occurrence. Here's a look at how previous shutdowns have played out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c750a0b6fd7401cde6d7c28b10bd236b</guid></item><item><title>Derailed Melbourne train was travelling on a recently upgraded set of tracks, preliminary report says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/derailed-melbourne-train-travelling-on-fresh-tracks-report-finds/105847388</link><description>A Melbourne passenger train that derailed earlier in the year was travelling on a set of tracks that had been upgraded just days earlier, a preliminary report into the incident has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c8a334378ef384e48ad54ed280da149</guid></item><item><title>Queensland education authorities to review case of eight-year-old girl killed in suspected murder-suicide in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/qld-kenmore-hills-suspected-murder-suicide-education-review/105849170</link><description>Queensland's education minister wouldn't be drawn on reports the girl — who was found dead with her mother at an Airbnb in Kenmore Hills on Monday — had only sporadically been attending school prior to her death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">077f12538834c511b07823cb67915c6b</guid></item><item><title>Australian Jewish community devastated by attack at UK synagogue that shows 'the risk is real and the fears are justified'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/australian-jewish-community-devastated-by-uk-terror-attack/105848360</link><description>Leading members of Australian Jewish communities are reeling after a fatal attack at a synagogue in the UK on the holy day of Yom Kippur.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5b01eb7907699f70ccdbf7dbfeee4b7</guid></item><item><title>NT Opposition Leader Selena Uibo uses VIP chauffeur service for private travel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/nt-opposition-leader-selena-uibo-vip-chauffeur-service-foi-/105849478</link><description>NT Opposition Leader Selena Uibo held a press conference on Friday to disclose the misuse, just days after travel logs were released to the ABC through Freedom of Information.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7aae0e4cf3f9abff627e848ca7199888</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Kate Eckhardt wins bronze medal at Slalom World Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/icf-slalom-world-championships-kate-eckhardt-wins-bronze/105849856</link><description>Australia wins its second medal at the ICF Slalom World Championships at Penrith's Whitewater Stadium, with Kate Eckhardt claiming bronze in the women's K1 final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56c4f1ece0f271ec20fb14340fe45cf1</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the NBA investigation into the Clippers' Kawhi Leonard-Aspiration saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/basketball-nba-kawhi-leonard-clippers-salary-cap-drama-explained/105838906</link><description>Kawhi Leonard finds himself at the centre of the NBA's latest salary cap firestorm courtesy of a four-year sponsorship deal signed with a company that went bankrupt. Here's everything we know about the drama and the league's investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45814f2699098944a3f9d17cb6432b56</guid></item><item><title>Germany's Munich Airport reopens after several drone sightings halt flights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/munich-airport-reopoens-after-drone-sightings-stop-flights/105849094</link><description>Nearly 3,000 passengers were grounded in the latest incident in a string of drone interferences across European airports, creating heightened fears they could be linked to Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">134409750ff4eff38d8f1ba20cc2c70a</guid></item><item><title>CCTV footage of Dee Annear</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/cctv-footage-of-dee-annear/105848428</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22b8fe3784c454d15b05f26a3f21d2c3</guid></item><item><title>Rohen Hanson sentenced to 28 years in prison for murder of partner Dee Annear</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/rohen-hanson-jailed-dee-annear-domestic-violence-murder/105843936</link><description>Rohen James Hanson will spend at least the next 17 years behind bars for murdering his partner in a remote cabin on the NSW Mid North Coast in 2021.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47899833b4bd8f3a92b010ad8e37860c</guid></item><item><title>Thriving Kids autism service causing 'significant anxiety', Labor MP warns, and may need changing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/labor-mp-significant-anxiety-thriving-kids-freelander/105848958</link><description>A Labor MP puts his party on notice after a hearing into the proposed 'Thriving Kids' autism service delivers little detail, warning that the lack of information is causing families "significant anxiety".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d5444e59993d5fd8f9596c291427db2</guid></item></channel></rss>