<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 09:51:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Update your ABC News homepage for more local stories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2020-09-03/update-to-abc-news-homepage/12579988</link><description>We've got an ABC News homepage for you. Adjust your settings for the right mix of local and national news.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">146f1699ce6b1b7420a91b6bb80d0309</guid></item><item><title>Call for button battery redesign after new study reveals horrific injuries and fatalities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/button-battery-warning-danger-deaths-lithium-swallow/103986966</link><description>A new study reveals the horrific injuries suffered after swallowing or inserting button batteries but manufacturers aren't prioritising their redesign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46ab5f96ade65908ecf6b7be8673e61f</guid></item><item><title>The US election is about style more than substance. It's why Kamala Harris needs to nail her DNC speech in about eight seconds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/us-election-kamala-harris-dnc-speech-style-substance/104256162</link><description>When the Democrat presidential candidate Kamala Harris delivers her speech to the Democratic National Convention today, style will be almost everything.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bddf8093759d999153dfd749b90e144a</guid></item><item><title>Reserve Bank restructure closer to reality after Treasurer Jim Chalmers offers olive branch to Angus Taylor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/reserve-bank-restructure-closer-to-reality/104260250</link><description>The Reserve Bank of Australia is a step closer to its biggest restructure in three decades after the treasurer offers an assurance to his Coalition counterpart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e920ec5b24583b8f74962ecc7f9c2585</guid></item><item><title>Have Your Say: What was the issue, policy or event that decided your vote?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-02-26/federal-election-your-say/104788518</link><description>After a five-week campaign, the results are in with Labor returned to government. Is there a policy or issue that swayed your vote? Have Your Say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">320dfcbec9cd8fe02e449407ce78e618</guid></item><item><title>Voters tell ABC's Your Say they want politicians with a vision, not bickering</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-13/abc-your-say-federal-election-politicians-with-vision/105164874</link><description>Voters tell ABC's Your Say campaign they want courage and vision from politicians, not bickering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">033ddce5ad54070fbce620dc6760d9ba</guid></item><item><title>Push for seniors' dental scheme grows ahead of federal election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-13/aged-care-dental-scheme-australia-federal-election/105149782</link><description>Imagine living in aged care and not having your teeth or dentures properly cleaned and checked each day. That's a risk faced by elderly Australians, prompting calls for the next federal government to boost oral health training and services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36d312d336a36247fd1c01e78814112b</guid></item><item><title>Australians tell ABC's Your Say they are struggling more than ever with housing costs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-15/abc-your-say-federal-election-2025-housing-policies/105175180</link><description>Voters tell ABC's Your Say campaign they are struggling more than ever with housing costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54451646ec8e9f100cc2fe59fc9c08c5</guid></item><item><title>Australia's growing cohort of tenants fear they will rent forever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-16/australias-growing-tenant-cohort-fear-forever-renting/105127148</link><description>Home ownership rates in Australia have been falling for decades, and with rental vacancies at record lows and prices at historic highs, many fear their dream of owning a home may be out of reach. Some experts say rental caps could help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36f35fe439f533ac9522c679c7e37187</guid></item><item><title>Graduates in 'debt vortex' as HECS front and centre for first time in an election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-16/federal-election-2025-hecs-student-debt-policies/105177248</link><description>New research shows a sharp rise in HECS debts, despite graduate earning power declining, as student loans become a potent election issue for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48707ffafbe02c400b1200e6269fd40e</guid></item><item><title>Housing advocates seek federal funding election promise for co-op model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-17/housing-cooperative-solution-proposed-for-rental-crisis/105108816</link><description>Advocates admit co-operative housing models are not for everyone but say for the right residents, they offer more security and affordable pricing than traditional rentals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3608b0c1ae56f5a5b36968898f65df5e</guid></item><item><title>Next-generation voters call for better engagement ahead of federal election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-18/federal-election-rural-next-generation-voters/105173450</link><description>Young people in Albury say issues that directly affect them and their communities are not being addressed by major parties for the 2025 election campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ae182892b8c9591cd9ec35e6e57fcb9</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne seat of Calwell highlights Labor woes as Gaza pain galvanises Muslim voters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-20/calwell-labor-backlash-over-gaza-islamophobia/104850500</link><description>Dissatisfaction with the Albanese government's stance on Israel-Palestine among many Arab and Muslim voters threatens to unseat Labor MPs, in some places for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63e7f9854fee5bc20e54ee2f5bd136f4</guid></item><item><title>Cost of living, housing among key concerns in SA marginal seat of Boothby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-21/boothby-cost-of-living-federal-election-2025/105190262</link><description>At this year’s federal election, the South Australian seat of Boothby is one of the state’s two marginal seats. As part of the ABC’s “Your Say” campaign, we spoke to residents in the electorate about their biggest concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dfd66b0605d29b960082ff52f18c170</guid></item><item><title>Energy projects in South West WA threaten votes for major federal parties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-21/energy-projects-south-west-wa-federal-election-labor-liberals/105152524</link><description>Australia's two major parties have tied their federal election fates to controversial energy projects in WA's South West where the issues have polarised voters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8962a53de05f0293b3a104690022111a</guid></item><item><title>Tiwi Islanders eager to have their say as remote voting for the federal election begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-22/early-voting-starts-in-remote-communities-tiwi-islands-aec/105201318</link><description>Voters in the small remote community of Pirlangimpi on the Tiwi Islands, north of Darwin, have become some of the first to cast their votes for the federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0c419fe3ae44debe7edf27241c0e5c1</guid></item><item><title>Mobile coverage is an election issue in regional areas. What's been promised?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-23/telecommunications-mobile-coverage-federal-election-promises/105080674</link><description>For many regional and remote Australians, reliable mobile coverage can be life-saving. They are desperate for both sides of politics to take meaningful action towards eliminating black spots.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ceda72e552d98e5f293d3c037efeefa</guid></item><item><title>Health, climate and community sport: What older voters in the Tasmanian seat of Bass are talking about this election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-29/health-climate-sport-election-older-voters-bass-tasmania/105224138</link><description>The federal seat of Bass is held by a margin of just 1.4 per cent. For these older voters who live in the electorate, health, climate and community sport are the issues that will decide their vote.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a3579db910b5a7ee8e11d2618bf798f</guid></item><item><title>Comanche wins Sydney to Hobart line honours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/comanche-wins-sydney-to-hobart-line-honours/106183250</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a72afefec57b8ae17123abe534199049</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Ferguson offered Jeffrey Epstein woman with 'great body' after his release from prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/sarah-ferguson-emails-to-jeffrey-epstein-revealed/106302466</link><description>Emails contained in the Epstein files show former British royal Sarah Ferguson told the convicted child sex offender she knew a "single" woman with a "great body" he should meet, weeks after his 2009 release from prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8216f6d90bb222bab0daa5d9f345c016</guid></item><item><title>More people say they'll vote One Nation. What are they voting for?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/one-nation-policy-platforms-pauline-hanson/106296838</link><description>One Nation questions if man-made climate change is real, wants to wind back access to abortion care and plans to pay the HECS debts of doctors working in the regions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed4bdf450e353d8bca00c742667777f</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth asks to meet Roblox following reports of child grooming. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/commonwealth-roblox-reports-of-child-grooming/106323242</link><description>Roblox has been called to an urgent meeting with the federal government in the wake of reports that children are being groomed by predators and exposed to sexually explicit material on the popular online gaming platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8186dce135dbe17f29c38ae0b2e5a4fb</guid></item><item><title>Transparency concerns as Bougainville's Panguna mine that sparked civil war on path to reopen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/bougainville-signs-secretive-deal-to-reopen-panguna-mine/106331778</link><description>The Autonomous Bougainville Government signs a secretive deal to reopen the huge Panguna gold and copper mine that sparked a catastrophic civil war three decades ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7a5ff00e0503cc102c30c6e22dae858</guid></item><item><title>Destanee Aiava announces retirement, calls out online trolls and 'racist' tennis culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/destanee-aiava-announces-tennis-retirement/106346282</link><description>Australian tennis player Destanee Aiava says 2026 will be her last year in professional tennis, announcing her impending retirement in an expletive-laden statement on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e49fc707471384a3f7c79ab4b00b492a</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: The anxiety and joy of dual moguls bronze for Matt Graham, leader and captain of the Australian team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/matt-graham-bronze-leader-moguls-duals-winter-olympics/106347650</link><description>Matt Graham's brilliant bronze in the dual moguls, and the incredible response from his teammates, proved to everyone that he is the true leader of this Winter Olympic squad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cba69d73cf10c866f2189e3ff247f598</guid></item><item><title>Chalmers mocks Taylor's proposal for bipartisan budget savings taskforce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/coalition-proposes-bipartisan-budget-taskforce/106348078</link><description>Angus Taylor wrote to the prime minister pitching the plan just days after being elected leader of the Liberal Party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2e1b7a17f7bbb632412e2760a78b3ec</guid></item><item><title>Senior Liberals deny involvement in draft policy to ban migrants from Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/ley-draft-migration-policy-australian-values-statement/106348870</link><description>A leaked copy of the Liberal Party's migration policy prepared before Sussan Ley was ousted included plans to "elevate" the current non-binding Australian values statement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afcbb687b8d26ea4579377278e93aa57</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor bets on migration politics amid global rightward shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/migration-social-cohesion-language-support-division-policy/106348608</link><description>If migration is treated primarily as a cultural fault line, rather than an economic system embedded in national growth, the debate will remain loud. The structural reform will remain unfinished.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86414a7a131a25b45dbc0a43798c1c16</guid></item><item><title>How to decide what type of car insurance is best for you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/how-do-i-know-what-car-insurance-is-best-for-me-/106260688</link><description>Choosing the right car insurance option can feel daunting, but it's the kind of task that it pays to get right. So, how can you decide which type is most suitable for you?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19c1a606228973fe803d3604b38ad3b1</guid></item><item><title>Results show high levels of lead contamination in dust around Hobart, as EPA flags further tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/nyrstar-lead-pollution-epa-tests-hobart/106339682</link><description>High levels of lead contamination have been found in dust samples taken from suburban locations close to Nyrstar's Hobart zinc smelter, documents obtained by the ABC show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df4c929be90ce6716c442950274a84e2</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate hike worries? Here's some good news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/why-the-reserve-bank-interest-rate-hike-may-be-a-one-off/106350914</link><description>Fresh warnings of further rate rises have been enough to send shivers up the collective spine of new homeowners, but if there's any comfort to be had, it's this: Don't believe a word of the forecasts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67fb51f52c86bc4d83c2be7c7d52564e</guid></item><item><title>Anti-slavery commissioner calls for tougher laws amid forced labour concerns for Ansell and Kmart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/anti-slavery-commissioner-tough-laws-dumping-ground-kmart-ansell/106349728</link><description>Australia's anti-slavery commissioner calls for tough new laws forcing companies to take slavery in their supply chains seriously, as Ansell and Kmart face scrutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">304d8b8d78c81209b940b9f107989101</guid></item><item><title>News quiz: Year of the Horse traditions, zodiac facts and festive customs across Asia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/lunar-new-year-of-the-horse-quiz-china-south-korea-vietnam-asia/106348886</link><description>How much do you know about the Year of the Horse and unique Lunar New Year traditions in Asian countries? Put your knowledge to the test with these 10 questions and see if you're a true Lunar New Year expert!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">664780860b8f5a75f0169a583ee380ca</guid></item><item><title>Mould, asbestos, collapsed ceilings plague some South Australian schools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/sa-schools-in-need-of-repair/106334244</link><description>Almost two years after a state government report revealed 35 per cent of all buildings within the Department for Education's portfolio were past their design life, many schools are still plagued with issues including mould, asbestos and rotting windows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fabb2b4476c5886be92e1dda09f3283</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the ISIS-linked families in Syria who want to return to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/who-are-isis-linked-australian-families-in-syria-al-roj-camp/106352074</link><description>Australia has made limited progress in clearing a passage for the Australian women and their children, citing safety issues in and around the camps, and security concerns back home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b94dd1490b366423951626bba907299</guid></item><item><title>Australia leads the world in moguls skiing. This is why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/australia-winter-olympics-moguls-dominance/106346256</link><description>To the surprise of many, the "beach nation" that is Australia is the best moguls skiing nation on earth. How the team got there is no accident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edc24052fc71a153cb8523cb4c296d67</guid></item><item><title>Albanese says Australian government will not help ISIS-linked families leave Syria or return home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/anthony-albanese-on-isis-families-trying-to-leave-syria/106352492</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese insists the federal government will not repatriate the Australian families with links to Islamic State fighters who remain in Syria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faa866e3881f2d6646422dcbe7b56295</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor reveals shadow ministry, elevating Andrew Hastie and Jacinta Nampijinpa Price</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/angus-taylor-preparing-to-unveil-shadow-ministry/106354092</link><description>The new Liberal leader announces his shadow ministry, elevating prominent right-faction supporters including West Australian MP Andrew Hastie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">989975fa7a8805821e114a08b60c7715</guid></item><item><title>French Polynesia drug haul hits $2.4 billion in a month as third shipment intercepted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/french-polynesia-third-drug-shipment-cocaine/106352864</link><description>French authorities seized a 2.4-tonne drug shipment near French Polynesia during a joint operation with the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8b05b9703fd79abe25cc2318a523413</guid></item><item><title>Mother of former Manly player Keith Titmuss breaks silence on lawsuit against NRL club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/keith-titmuss-mother-speaks-on-manly-sea-eagles-lawsuit/106354504</link><description>The mother of Manly player Keith Titmuss, who died of exertional heat stroke following a 2020 Sea Eagles training session, breaks her silence on her family's multi-million-dollar lawsuit against the NRL club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0be5af7a65024f5d1249c96c36ab639d</guid></item><item><title>Jesse Jackson, civil rights leader and US presidential hopeful, dead at 84</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/civil-rghts-leader-jesse-jackson-dies-age-84/106356528</link><description>The two-time Democratic presidential hopeful remembered for powerful speeches died peacefully surrounded by loved ones, his family said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bef1e4b64b56ce290b7d00444b297818</guid></item><item><title>Millionaire Gary Stevenson's dire warning for Australian property market losing the 'fair go'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/economist-gary-stevenson-warns-australia-losing-the-fair-go/106342536</link><description>British economist Gary Stevenson is on a speaking tour, warning Australia will follow the path of the UK with "poverty exploding" unless politicians deal with inequality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f588e11282bda2e3e28ac0a5b4d7af5d</guid></item><item><title>HungryPanda riders say Chinese police intimidating families in China over Sydney protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/hungrypanda-riders-chinese-police-threats-sydney-australia/106353996</link><description>Riders embroiled in a dispute over pay and conditions with food delivery company HungryPanda in Sydney say Chinese police have asserted pressure back home to stop them protesting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00b78e0a081535d928622de443de63b8</guid></item><item><title>Hindmarsh Island bridge dispute told through Ngarrindjeri women's art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/ngarrindjeri-women-retell-hindmarsh-island-bridge-story/106282804</link><description>In the 1990s, a group of Indigenous women were accused of fabricating claims of sacred sites to stop the construction of a bridge south of Adelaide. It was a decision that has impacted a community for decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c8df9f180475c2f0cfe199f0433a284</guid></item><item><title>Pauline Hanson issues partial apology for suggesting there are no 'good' Muslims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/pauline-hanson-partially-apologises-for-muslim-remarks/106357130</link><description>The One Nation leader qualified her earlier remarks, which had been met with condemnation, while reiterating calls for tougher vetting processes for Muslim migrants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef8666bfdfbfd0c8dffd9a0c82b5b3cd</guid></item><item><title>Is it ever a good idea to stay together for the kids?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/should-you-ever-stay-together-for-the-kids/106281890</link><description>When a relationships breaks down, sometimes we think staying in the familiar discomfort is less scary — and even protective — for our kids. But is it ever a good idea to stay in an unhappy relationship for the sake of the children?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbe4bbc74caa9ba1918949fae6630fe1</guid></item><item><title>Chalmers suggests ex-RBA governor's spending critique is due to personal vendetta</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/chalmers-dismisses-criticism-from-philip-lowe/106359398</link><description>Treasurer Jim Chalmers says Philip Lowe was critical of the government over spending because it did not re-appoint him as RBA governor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4578c9f616d6026ee0f378a69efa25e</guid></item><item><title>Mazda, Nissan, Hyundai and Subaru face multi-million-dollar penalties under NVES</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/new-vehicle-efficiency-standard-results-mazda-nissan-penalties/106358770</link><description>Major car brands are staring down the barrel of multi-million-dollar penalties for exceeding their emissions, the first results of the federal government's climate laws for new vehicles have revealed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45198840bd21329442d531c79bcbff0d</guid></item><item><title>Alcoa hit with record fine for unlawfully clearing WA jarrah forests for bauxite mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/alcoa-fined-for-clearing-jarrah-forest-for-bauxite-mine/106359988</link><description>US mining giant Alcoa is forced to pay $55 million after unlawfully clearing parts of a Western Australian native forest to mine bauxite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f74bb47c6f321183a916fc154005c8ee</guid></item><item><title>Former Coles manager admits 'human error' over Shapes 'Down Down' pricing in federal court showdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/coles-accc-discounts-federal-court/106358474</link><description>A former Coles manager has given evidence in the federal court on day three of a bombshell case between the consumer watchdog and supermarket giant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fac3387b11a41f3cb04ca5d82d1e043</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106359046</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">077e4b34cad227fccef803151960b1af</guid></item><item><title>Tackling 'blatant' fake discounting, restoring consumer trust among ACCC's priorities for 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/accc-outlines-priorities-for-2026-including-fake-discounting/106359994</link><description>ACCC chair Gina Cass-Gottlieb outlines the consumer watchdog's priorities for 2026, including targeting "blatant" fake discounting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2937ff2740ca14e3dac8a4082576d74e</guid></item><item><title>Government spending is creeping up and threatening Australia’s 'low-debt' status</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/government-spending-threatening-australias-low-debt-status/105579046</link><description>Australia will cease to be a low-debt country and be more vulnerable in a future crisis without a combination of spending restraint and tax reform, a new report has warned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13ac01b1668865c59fb5bf518f92a919</guid></item><item><title>Senate committee features climate disinformation, the Atlas Network, and Dr Karl's clash with One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/climate-disinformation-senate-committee-dr-karl-atlas-network/106350002</link><description>The scourge of AI-slopaganda, viral disinformation campaigns and online attacks against individuals and institutions is going to get far worse before it gets better, if the latest public hearings on the topic are any indication.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc806ab7e06e7cc45d048d4f225dbed0</guid></item><item><title>Danielle Scott's Winter Olympic silver ends years of pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/danielle-scott-aerials-silver-medal-2026-winter-olympics/106361322</link><description>In this most tension-filled Winter Olympic sport, it's no wonder tears are a by-product of both success and failure. Thankfully for Dani Scott, this time she was crying tears of pure joy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e5d5a3ecb08453f6f6bb9cdeaccc263</guid></item><item><title>Fiji's former prime minister Frank Bainimarama charged with inciting mutiny</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/former-fiji-prime-minister-bainimarama-arrested-charged-mutiny/106360516</link><description>Long-serving Fiji prime minister Frank Bainimarama and a former police commissioner will face court on Tuesday on charges of mutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfb056a8d72b38a8175534edc2ea18aa</guid></item><item><title>How exclusion orders could ban Australian citizens from returning home indefinitely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/australian-citizens-banned-returning-overseas-exclusion-orders/106361634</link><description>One of the Australian women being held in a Syrian refugee camp has been barred from returning home after being given a temporary exclusion order — but the ban may not be as temporary as the name implies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b69ea4e5ccbec5d9f3ed7794e281795c</guid></item><item><title>SA secures Australian MotoGP, world-first street circuit announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/sa-secures-motogp-world-first-street-circuit-announced/106361722</link><description>The South Australian government has confirmed the Australian MotoGP will move to Adelaide from 2027, bringing with it huge economic benefits, but the opposition and Greens say the state has other priorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a957e6c008c2cd348424eaa2acecad49</guid></item><item><title>The Kyneton women's football team's story was always about more than just one club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/kyneton-womens-football-story-widespread-issue/106338680</link><description>The women's team from Kyneton's 15-month public and bitter saga suggests it is the canary in the coal mine of a widespread issue for women's players across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af213a5a4c0ac76bfd7fb9926ae5b4ef</guid></item><item><title>Unemployment rate remains at 4.1pc in January, leading to talk of another rate rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/unemployment-rate-australia-january-2026-steady/106362428</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate remained at 4.1 per cent in January, with 17,800 more employed people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3deb22f01e8aa72f8fccc75f74faf25b</guid></item><item><title>The heartwarming tribute to injured aerials star Laura Peel at the Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/heartwarming-aerials-tribute-laura-peel/106361392</link><description>This Winter Olympics aerials competition saw plenty of Aussies achieve lifetime goals, but they never forgot the one person who was missing — injured champion Laura Peel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">837dd8955b1207595385711ea5af7ba8</guid></item><item><title>Wayne Gardner disappointed Victoria won't host Australian MotoGP</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/former-motogp-champion-disappointed/106363350</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">431dc933aa3e70b73ec6f2262d8685f3</guid></item><item><title>Hanson digs her heels in, Taylor goes on tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/pauline-hanson-barnaby-joyce-angus-taylor-anthony-albanese/106349216</link><description>This week, the new opposition leader revealed his shadow cabinet while Pauline Hanson spun through a cycle she knows well.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ea3a4f2179a8b0064925ee07ccfca6c</guid></item><item><title>Vegetable scraps to be turned into bioenergy by Scenic Rim farm as part of $291 million project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/qld-kalfresh-bioenergy-scenic-rim/106363982</link><description>A new $291 million project set to turn farm scraps to energy has begun construction in Queensland's Scenic Rim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db61a8e13ba17ab198287e56aca27dc2</guid></item><item><title>Coles manager moved product onto 'Down Down' promotion days after price hike to be more competitive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/coles-accc-federal-court-dog-food-down-down-pricing/106358664</link><description>A second Coles manager has been grilled in the federal court over whether rushing a product onto a "Down Down" promotion could have broken internal guidelines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41ca3a7b1fd4851df375d2220574fd44</guid></item><item><title>South Korea's ex-president Yoon Suk Yeol sentenced to life in prison over insurrection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/south-korea-president-yoon-suk-yeol-sentenced-insurrection-guilt/106363456</link><description>Former South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol is sentenced to life in prison on charges of rebellion for his attempt to put the country under military rule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8145bfdf54ebbed599a2b489a9edabf6</guid></item><item><title>Gas explosion kills 16 after apartment building partially collapses in southern Pakistan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/gas-explosion-kills-16-apartment-building-collapses-pakistan/106365612</link><description>Women and children are among 16 people killed after a gas explosion ripped through an apartment building in Pakistan on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bac5b7cbd5dc5905b6f47c64562d41d5</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/thursday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/106364470</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4c5b51e530a659b7487c6517551d5d1</guid></item><item><title>Former prince returns home as police investigation continues — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-epstein-police/106365802</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor has returned to his Sandringham home after being arrested and questioned on suspicion of misconduct in public office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5fc074cadfc2697a563fee6e91b29af</guid></item><item><title>What we know about ex-prince Andrew's arrest on suspicion of misconduct in public office</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/what-we-know-about-former-prince-andrew-arrest/106365894</link><description>Police are searching two addresses in the UK, including Royal Lodge on the Windsor Estate where the former prince lived until last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8039d5e6abc316002657b559e90ee456</guid></item><item><title>Ally Hickman showed her grit at 2026 Winter Olympics after heavy fall on second run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/ally-hickman-crash-snowboard-slopestyle-2026-winter-olympics/106366350</link><description>In a Winter Olympics beset by both glory and injury, Ally Hickman's heavy fall in the snowboard slopestyle could have turned a happy day into another disappointing one. Instead, the young Aussie showed her grit to get back up and go again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a129ccb67369e26da08c0952f439ed6</guid></item><item><title>Former premier joins community calls for speed reduction at 'dangerous' fatal intersection in Newham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/community-calls-for-speed-reduction-newham-intersection-victoria/106364280</link><description>A community in central Victoria is calling for a 20 kph speed limit reduction at a "terribly dangerous" intersection after four major accidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d28bf645384eca294d072c5b45849511</guid></item><item><title>Sisters Lisa and Rachael Maza reunite on stage for the world premiere of Black Light</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/lisa-rachael-maza-sisters-black-light-malthouse-theatre/106357630</link><description>The former head of Indigenous theatre company Ilbijerri teams up with her sister Lisa for the world premiere of Black Light, which tells the story of three generations of Blak women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1799e84905988608fb42c35ca34a445</guid></item><item><title>As electric car prices fall, will affordability win over drivers?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/cart-electric-vehicles-becoming-more-affordable/106348534</link><description>The price tag of EVs has been a barrier to uptake. As cheaper models hit the market, will more drivers go electric?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8e8609bc047b4700deb6c7a5c8c5aa4</guid></item><item><title>Voters divided as Barnaby Joyce considers contesting New England for One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/new-england-divided-over-barnaby-joyce/106353714</link><description>One Nation MP Barnaby Joyce says he might recontest his seat of New England as a candidate for One Nation if the party needs him to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8216e2cb0110f0bcd4db9bab70757914</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's arrest could end monarchy's 'never complain, never explain' mentality</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrest-a-problem-for-monarchy/106365934</link><description>British royals have lived by the adage "never complain, never explain", but these days, many of their subjects are demanding answers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69ce80bb0d80419516702662a1c32494</guid></item><item><title>Can Angus Taylor get beyond slogans to craft a sound immigration policy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/angus-taylor-immigration-pauline-hanson/106349268</link><description>The rifts in Australia's social cohesion can be seen in the blow-up over the so-called ISIS brides and their children, who want to come to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81483ff7c63fdba169c22b024c766cea</guid></item><item><title>Coalition willing to help stop passports for IS-linked women— as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/federal-politics-live-albanese-taylor-labor-coalition/106363700</link><description>Angus Taylor says the Coalition is willing to help the government strengthen legislation so women with ties to Islamic State are not issued Australian passports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e73f6a4c21f2ed041db318fdf5bfddfe</guid></item><item><title>Major US fund's credit squeeze could 'blow up' — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-friday-20-february/106366740</link><description>Shares in US asset manager Blue Owl have fallen sharply after it announced it was having challenges meeting investors' cash demands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8cfa058595f0f84f2b91273acd73f15</guid></item><item><title>Ingham abuzz as recovering sugar town prepares to host Tones And I concert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/ingham-buzzing-ahead-of-tones-and-i-concert/106357352</link><description>A dedicated community campaign results in the Australian singer performing a one-off, almost sold-out show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54a2843af718594604b8837c663e03da</guid></item><item><title>Canadian skier Cassie Sharpe's horrific crash in the halfpipe reminds us of Winter Olympics dangers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/cassie-sharpe-canadian-freeski-halfpipe-crash/106366818</link><description>As Cassie Sharpe lay motionless on the base of the Livigno halfpipe, the excruciating tension reminded us all that winter Olympians are only ever seconds from disaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca8a04bde9604f081e69e3f402a12a68</guid></item><item><title>Fiji, Palau and Tuvalu set to show world leaders climate change impact ahead of COP31</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/pacific-nations-set-to-host-world-leaders-on-climate-change/106366110</link><description>Fiji, Palau and Tuvalu look set to host world leaders and climate change ministers in the lead-up to COP31 in a bid to encourage larger countries to accelerate cuts to emissions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efb0153cc3ad4a4f839fc3664ed151a9</guid></item><item><title>Is it OK to feed Australia's wild birds?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/is-it-ok-to-feed-australias-wild-birds/106349168</link><description>Many of us love interacting with and feeding wild birds, but experts say giving them the wrong types of food can do more harm than good.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eec910366a2f5aeb070b335682010295</guid></item><item><title>Eric Dane, star of Grey's Anatomy and Euphoria, dies aged 53</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/eric-dane-star-of-greys-anatomy-and-euphoria-dies/106188556</link><description>The star was best known for his role as Dr Mark Sloan in long-running medical drama Grey's Anatomy, and as the patriarch of the Jacobs family in teen hit Euphoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38f5c65f82f5e42103bcfbd84e4e18ea</guid></item><item><title>What to watch, read and listen to this weekend: Eternity, "Wuthering Heights" and new Meg Mac</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/what-to-watch-read-and-listen-to-this-weekend/106348892</link><description>From a cursed vagina to a classic retold, there's plenty of culture to dig into this weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de104c63d006fce83127b9a4e083d6bd</guid></item><item><title>Scientists model best-case and worst-case climate scenarios for Antarctica</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/antarctica-faces-devastating-impacts-under-climate-change/106354182</link><description>Scientists say parts of Antarctica face "devastating" and "irreversible" impacts from climate change unless urgent action is taken to limit greenhouse gas emissions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f426dd0a1878420ce756c07766ef447c</guid></item><item><title>Glider pilot creates aviation history in Central Australia flying 1,266 kilometres</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/glider-pilot-makes-history-central-australia/106364374</link><description>A Queensland pilot has made aviation history in Central Australia, flying more than 1,200 kilometres without an engine in a record-breaking glider flight launched from Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3a3e44b629b032cc34ddda0931e8d1e</guid></item><item><title>Police receive 'reports of crime' in relation to Pauline Hanson interview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/police-investigation-pauline-hanson-afp-one-nation-muslim/106370420</link><description>One Nation senator Pauline Hanson accuses the government of trying to put her "back in jail", after police received reports of a crime in relation to the senator's inflammatory comments about Muslims during a media interview.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">185dd63416cc7c6d747e0e5e37316352</guid></item><item><title>Man whose girlfriend froze to death after he left her mountain convicted of manslaughter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/austria-manslaughter-after-woman-froze-to-death-on-mountain/106371008</link><description>A man who left his girlfriend to freeze to death on an Austrian mountain has been handed a five-month suspended sentence for manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">effae5ababb3ac61ba124a96f11fe003</guid></item><item><title>Jeffrey Epstein's estate agrees to pay up to $US35 million to settle class action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/epstein-estate-agrees-to-pay-up-to-us-35m-to-settle-class-action/106371194</link><description>Jeffrey Epstein's estate has agreed to pay as much as $US35 million to resolve a class action lawsuit, according to a court filing on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">883c1ed664dc93038eba1c101323e85d</guid></item><item><title>Trump vows to resurrect global tariffs after Supreme Court strikes them down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/supreme-court-rules-against-donald-trumps-tariffs/106371286</link><description>The US president says he is "absolutely ashamed" of members of the court who struck down his global tariffs after finding he lacked the authority to implement them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c00aabed63715023fee1232c77fe8c38</guid></item><item><title>UK government to consider removing Andrew from succession line, as royal protection police face grilling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/royal-protection-police-to-be-grilled-over-mountbatten-windsor/106371406</link><description>The UK government is to look at removing Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor from the line of succession, an official says, as royal protection police face a grilling on "anything they saw or heard".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3493cf1504035f8670aff82102e21ef1</guid></item><item><title>Putin is betting Ukraine and the West run out of resources first</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/russia-ukraine-four-year-war-vladimir-putin/106349238</link><description>Russian President Vladimir Putin is betting that the West and Ukraine will run out of resources first.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11d7efa9b8e3b49ad2d1ac3d15d64f51</guid></item><item><title>Should Labor do its own refresh after Angus Taylor's Liberal 'rebrand'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/angus-taylor-shadow-cabinet-albanese-government/106337018</link><description>In the past few days, in a series of largely ignored milestones overshadowed by news of Angus Taylor's new frontbench, Albanese overtook Scott Morrison and John Curtin to become the 12th-longest serving prime minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">070d46246d34302a081ac085940a13ec</guid></item><item><title>ABC 50/50 quiz: This week we're testing your knowledge of Ninja Turtles, Netflix and nagging pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/abc-5050-quiz-feb-21/106362470</link><description>Every question has only two options: One is right and the other is wrong. You have an even chance of guessing correctly each time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75de69d84e56309d413d4f77423b7583</guid></item><item><title>Andy Griffiths, author of the Treehouse books, named new Australian Children's Laureate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/andy-griffiths-author-australian-childrens-laureate/106331360</link><description>Famous for writing stories about toilets and tree houses, the bestselling kids' author is taking on a new challenge on the national stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4faf4f52c970006ea1d74e0f15c753b</guid></item><item><title>The town that turned its back on a rape victim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/balmoral-home-town-boys-rape-divides-football-farming-town/106145646</link><description>A local footy star and his mate are convicted of raping their friend. In the tiny town of Balmoral, where the footy club reigns, the town makes it clear whose story they believe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcced53be78cf23e4251d66c753ae52d</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's future uncertain under monarch willing to let 'the law take its course'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/andrew-arrest-will-go-down-in-history-books/106367696</link><description>Like so many of the elite caught in Epstein's web, Andrew believed he would escape scrutiny for his behaviour. But it is precisely because of his name and position that his alleged wrongdoing has now delivered him into the hands of the law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">876a05a2e2317a3aa1a9f28c7c53ce70</guid></item><item><title>Why Pacific Islands are rapidly de-flagging Russia's fleet of 'shadow tankers'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/pacific-islands-flags-of-convenience-shadow-vessels/106357172</link><description>Pacific Islands are rapidly de-flagging vessels on their shipping registries after gaining international attention for their role in Russia's "shadow fleet".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f072b9260e3417979d4a703c003d41e0</guid></item><item><title>Landholders fear large-scale battery project will impact Mount Gambier housing developments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/mount-gambier-residents-oppose-blanche-battery-over-housing/106352934</link><description>Landholders call for a proposed 500-megawatt battery energy storage project to be moved amid concerns it will impact on housing developments in South Australia's second largest city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07de98d6be338d20a09b260236ad8580</guid></item><item><title>At Melbourne's Mission to Seafarers, a small team keeps an invisible global workforce afloat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/melbourne-mission-to-seafarers-global-maritime-workforce/106305250</link><description>In a 109-year-old building wedged between mirrored high-rises in Melbourne's CBD, a volunteer team supports a little-known workforce that spends months at a time at sea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e44f3fdcd48ad5e31a22c51f2c67d041</guid></item><item><title>The art and origins of the courtroom sketch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/the-art-and-origins-of-the-courtroom-sketch/105817718</link><description>They're a small and curious cohort in a line of work rapidly evolving. Welcome to the world of courtroom artists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5051373d22a373be7ac83c73f3f9a4bb</guid></item><item><title>Peregrine falcon drone could save Australian fruit and almond orchards from hungry birds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/robird-peregrine-falcon-drone-to-scare-birds-from-crops/106105572</link><description>A new falcon drone wards off peckish birds that have been destroying valuable fruit crops.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ad160c79a85d52dff1c43c429b91f7d</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's arrest shows money talks louder than women's testimony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrest-jeffrey-epstein/106349250</link><description>Why is an email about the trade trip apparently more compelling than the detailed and painful evidence of a woman?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c126708b2400a064fec41430e0ad12c1</guid></item><item><title>Campbell Newman argues new Queensland hate speech laws going down 'dangerous path'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/campbell-newman-criticises-hate-speech-laws-free-speech/106368924</link><description>The new laws will allow the government to ban phrases it deems problematic by regulation once the legislation passes state parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68ff5ad00c6a07b420d4ed9629204d0b</guid></item><item><title>After 60 years, there are fears Myer may walk away from Launceston's CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/concerns-myer-may-leave-launceston-shopping-strip/106367746</link><description>Community and business leaders say the possible departure of retailer Myer would leave a "giant hole" in the heart of the city's shopping district.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c928733eebf54cd5eadca8fc44e69d7</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Lindsey Vonn goes 'bionic' as the curling war of words continues — day 14 quick hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/winter-olympics-day-14-quick-hits-curling-barb-lindsey-vonn/106370974</link><description>Swedish curler Oskar Eriksson hits Canadian nemesis Marc Kennedy with his most devastating barb yet as Lindsey Vonn shares an update on her recovery. Here are the quick hits from day 14 at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e305a380a102e8649ea935e7dd6ce29</guid></item><item><title>Queensland woman wakes from coma after contracting meningitis and septic shock on ski holiday to Japan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/queensland-woman-coma-meningitis-septic-shock-in-japan/106367880</link><description>When 24-year-old Anna Gallo woke up shivering in a Tokyo hotel, she thought it was food poisoning. Hours later, she was in a coma fighting for her life against a disease she thought she was vaccinated against.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df154e4e3de16e61796b2871c5c9fe9b</guid></item><item><title>Cattle tick outbreak raises questions over Queensland's biosecurity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/tick-outbreak-raises-questions-over-queenslands-biosecurity/106367970</link><description>Queensland is known for its hardline biosecurity stance against foreign pests, but farmers say a recent cattle tick outbreak has exposed systemic weaknesses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11798db4c4a29dca21b6773386e53cb7</guid></item><item><title>Americans fearing death of democracy see a glimmer of hope in the Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/supreme-court-tariff-decision-confirms-democracy-isnt-dead/106371496</link><description>Until now, Donald Trump has been one of the most unstoppable presidents ever. But the Supreme Court's tariffs decision proves there are limits to his power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d596259cf551d1d1afc79b3621e90f2d</guid></item><item><title>Herby potato salad with green beans and tuna - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/herby-potatoes-with-green-beans-and-tuna/106252480</link><description>Turn a potato salad into a tasty meal with pantry staples and fresh greens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bf3639cafb3b89fadd2f76dbfd84322</guid></item><item><title>Opposition does its best to land blows on WA government in parliament's first week back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/wa-parliament-week-one-analysis-basil-zempilas-roger-cook/106365878</link><description>Housing, health and household stress — that's what WA's opposition leader says he's focused on in 2026 as he and his party face an uphill battle against the state government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56f1332a78e625f94d5312f5b9b52fd4</guid></item><item><title>Why economists hate low unemployment for inflation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/why-economists-hate-low-unemployment-for-inflation/106367852</link><description>The theory goes that if you have just the right amount of workers on the unemployment scrap heap, you can keep inflation in check. The problem is that no-one knows exactly what the magic unemployment rate is.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43e029d93818ef09b173d99095546fef</guid></item><item><title>Potential release of carp control virus into waterways delayed until 2028</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/national-carp-control-plan-decade-delay-carp-herpes-virus/106348408</link><description>Release of a virus to control carp in Australian waterways has been delayed until 2028, a decade after it was initially slated for release.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dbde53e8280f083aef35066d7c03374</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with hate crime after allegedly ramming Brisbane synagogue with ute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/brisbane-synagogue-rammed-man-charged-hate-crime/106371834</link><description>It's alleged the 32-year-old rammed a ute into the gates of the Brisbane Synagogue on Margaret Street on Friday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">560aa622bfc80adf305756789d41b300</guid></item><item><title>Teagan Micah forced out of Matildas' Asian Cup campaign as concussion issues continue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/matildas-teagan-micah-out-of-asian-cup-concussion/106371804</link><description>Teagan Micah's horror run with concussions continues as she reveals she will miss the Matildas' upcoming Asian Cup campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbcf7ae7402006cdd468aa9c66f144ee</guid></item><item><title>How Reuters captured that photo of former Prince Andrew leaving custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/how-reuters-captured-the-photo-of-former-prince-andrew-leavi/106371770</link><description>The image, taken by Reuters photographer Phil Noble, went viral when it was published on Thursday. He says capturing the moment came down to a tip-off and more than a little luck.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23d31204491246cc184daea89e905d39</guid></item><item><title>Balinese women find shared culture and community in WA's Pilbara</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/balinese-indonesian-women-in-fifo-mining-town/106190742</link><description>The Pilbara is known for spinifex and mining, but has also become a melting pot of cultures from across the globe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">897c042e4f513ac1f82e6b02921636b5</guid></item><item><title>I had a miscarriage over the summer. It was nothing like I expected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/miscarriage-loss-grief/106308830</link><description>My understanding of miscarriage was built on a handful of Hollywood representations and snatches of stories I'd read. Outside of this, I had few reference points.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a18951e43e4efa639be7b2845bc9d57e</guid></item><item><title>A 'return to craft' for the NT's award-winning young artists showcased at this year's Exit Art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/nt-exit-art-exhibition-return-to-crafting-darwin-gallery-museum/106368426</link><description>Almost a dozen high school-aged artists have received awards as part of a prestigious Northern Territory showcase, with a number of finalists exhibiting self-portraits.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ed4262d4757e1158f4f7f9fb3c9f716</guid></item><item><title>Concerns over death of iconic salmon gums in WA's Great Western Woodlands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/concerns-over-tree-deaths-great-western-woodlands/106355300</link><description>Kalgoorlie horticulturalist Phil Stanley says he is struggling to get authorities to take the deaths of more than 100 salmon gums near the mining city seriously.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cef65ddf1756cc101cb4a0d10888de3f</guid></item><item><title>Anna Murdoch-Mann, author and ex-wife of Rupert Murdoch, dies aged 81</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/anna-murdoch-mann-dies-aged-81/106371640</link><description>The author, journalist and philanthropist was Rupert Murdoch's "active partner" in his media empire News Corp over their 31-year marriage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4277353646eb61bcf0bb37d726dbda4</guid></item><item><title>Displaced on the dial by changes to Perth's FM spectrum, Kalamunda community radio is undeterred</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/kalamunda-community-move-down-the-dial/106358500</link><description>Kalamunda Community Radio has been providing a local radio service on 102.5FM to the Perth Hills for more than 25 years, but has now had to move frequency as the ABC switches its Perth radio services to FM.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35daf39c9f69b3c3582dd0627cacab2a</guid></item><item><title>Adam Zampa says claims Australia does not care about T20 cricket 'totally false' after World Cup flop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/cricket-zampa-defends-australia-t20-prep-world-cup-exit/106371894</link><description>Adam Zampa hits back at claims that Australia does not care about T20 cricket after a disappointing World Cup campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47ff9ce19c56b6ba685a684eb3b125df</guid></item><item><title>How a window opened for IS-linked Australians to leave Syria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/how-a-window-opened-for-is-linked-australians-to-leave-syria/106368348</link><description>After holding a large swathe of autonomous territory that included two detention camps, Kurdish-led forces are now reluctantly handing over control to Syrian government forces, following their successful military offensive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79af036f525934cd4e37d746768f51d7</guid></item><item><title>The shamans and designer handbags before Yoon Suk Yeol's insurrection conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/the-scandalous-downfall-of-yoon-suk-yeol/106358072</link><description>Former South Korean president Yoon Suk Yeol's sentence for insurrection comes after a tumultuous era of shamanism, Chanel bags and conspiracy theories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c392edec639f36481f4ec7269ef84031</guid></item><item><title>How a Belgian techno producer with some old synthesisers has reimagined Terminator 2</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/terminator-2-new-score-hear-my-eyes-mess/106369562</link><description>Terminator 2: Judgment Day is getting the live score treatment, but not in the way you might expect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">689c4da252c634c2c4554ed5d31bba80</guid></item><item><title>Viral AI videos raise questions about how we view reality</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/viral-ai-videos-raise-questions-about-how-we-view-reality/106307568</link><description>For a bit of a laugh, Travis Marshall uses artificial intelligence to create wacky videos about his hometown, but his light-hearted content also raises serious questions about reality in the age of AI.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cbd3a6d66eeb25ca5cb5d78fb34fba0</guid></item><item><title>NASA boss blasts Boeing and agency over bungled test flight that left astronauts stranded on space station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/nasa-report-reveals-starliner-mission-failings/106371706</link><description>A bungled Boeing mission that left two astronauts stranded on the International Space Station for nine months has been criticised by NASA's new boss.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3928101430826cc338efc88bfa7afd86</guid></item><item><title>Teenager dies in hospital a week after being hit by car in Melbourne's south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/teenager-dies-after-being-hit-by-car-in-narre-warren-south/106372124</link><description>A 16-year-old boy has died in hospital after being struck by a car that veered off the road in Narre Warren South on February 13.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6086a2e2d667ce3b26e869598f0fc370</guid></item><item><title>Drugs with estimated street value of $1.45 million seized in traffic stop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/nabiac-traffic-stop-leads-to-drug-seizure-police-say/106372078</link><description>A traffic stop on the Pacific Highway on the NSW Mid North Coast has led to the seizure of hundreds of thousands of dollars' worth of cocaine and cannabis, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52ce47c8e206ebeeccdec73dced1e56e</guid></item><item><title>Farmer builds chapel for Tongan workers, the 'backbone' of her banana farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/lakeland-chapel-tongan-workers-palm-scheme-queensland/106362494</link><description>A Queensland banana farmer spent 10 years saving to build a chapel for the Tongan workers who form the backbone of her family’s operation on Cape York Peninsula.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9129d4087a3dedd75e8c65e58a866cf</guid></item><item><title>The US Supreme Court's take-down of Trump's tariffs explained</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/explaining-the-us-supreme-court-takedown-of-trumps-tariffs/106372118</link><description>The ruling on tariffs is a hugely consequential decision that has infuriated the president, who is now looking for workarounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d66c597b8db50bd67f75d00125911020</guid></item><item><title>Punch the baby macaque draws a crowd at Japan's Ichikawa City Zoo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/punch-baby-macaque-japan-zoo-soft-toy-orangutan/106371376</link><description>The six month old macaque's relationship with a soft toy orangutan has become an internet sensation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76354b2a83722acb0b827836893c9d71</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after allegedly throwing 'lit incendiary device' during Navy chief's speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/man-charged-fake-explosive-hotel-window-navy-chief/106371970</link><description>A man faces court accused of throwing a fake explosive device through a Canberra hotel window during a speech from the Chief of Navy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95b8a361b3e4aba53d93366cf6307112</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on day 15</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/winter-olympics-2026-quick-guide-what-to-watch-on-day-15/106372058</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f86a080ae9e7d9178bbe13efe477941</guid></item><item><title>Formula 1 preseason testing: Ferrari has a rotating rear wing, Red Bull, McLaren and Mercedes show pace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/f1-preseason-test-bahrain-ferrari-red-bull-mclaren-mercedes/106370550</link><description>Preseason testing for the new Formula 1 season ends in Bahrain, with teams not putting their cars on a track until the first practice session of the Australian Grand Prix weekend on March 6.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0558efd2ad2bea9a138b21ff74317c2</guid></item><item><title>Rottnest Swim cancellation prompts dozens to descend on Perth pool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/team-saba-takes-rottnest-swim-to-bold-park-swimming-pool/106371972</link><description>Weather may have derailed the main event, but some swimmers were determined to complete their own version of the Rottnest Channel Swim in the name of charity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad37267373fc428efc986e0b1c03c7b0</guid></item><item><title>Auckland FC defeat Wellington Phoenix 5-0 in A-League Men, goalkeeper Josh Oluwayemi own goal begins rout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/auckland-fc-defeat-wellington-phoenix-5-0-in-a-league-men/106372300</link><description>Wellington Phoenix goalkeeper Josh Oluwayemi commits one of the worst howlers this A-League Men season, heading a clearance kick into his own net as Auckland FC romps to a big win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c520681fd47bae4fe6c8395992f4c0c7</guid></item><item><title>South Australian election countdown officially begins, campaign kicks off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/south-australia-election-2026-campaign-begins/106371978</link><description>Election campaigning in South Australia is officially underway, with candidates seizing the opportunity to begin making their formal pitches to voters before they head to the ballot box in March.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9242c102760eb4813ef7943f0f70998b</guid></item><item><title>Live: Indra Brown headlines Aussies competing for medals on day 15</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/winter-olympics-day-15-live-updates/106369762</link><description>Australian teenager Indra Brown headlines the list of Australians competing for medals on day 15 of the Milano Cortina Games. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e298710e69cb969b327f06f92b5f32f5</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout sets another record with 10-second 100m sprint in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/gout-gout-sets-another-record-with-10-second-100m/106372384</link><description>Australian sprinting sensation Gout Gout comes perilously close to breaking the 10-second barrier, with another eye-catching run in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f819100df65bcd7e882e251d29a23826</guid></item></channel></rss>