<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 10:55:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Encrypted police group chat stops case against Canberra Raiders star Josh Papalii</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/act-raiders-josh-papalii-permanent-stay-threaten-police-charge/105958068</link><description>Charges against Canberra Raiders prop Josh Papalii have been permanently stayed after it was revealed police had been discussing the case in a group chat on encrypted messaging service Signal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aaef57b417d822531d4e3545b641262e</guid></item><item><title>Miners asked to reconsider using industrial explosives involved in underground explosion which killed two</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/cobar-explosion-investigation-unearths-new-details/105958148</link><description>Regulator may ban the type of explosive used in fatal mining accident which claimed the lives of two workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8440ef045985b51177cebf0f6e2bf398</guid></item><item><title>In pictures: Andrew's journey from favourite son to outcast prince</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/prince-andrew-fall-from-grace-in-pictures/105956194</link><description>Prince Andrew has been stripped of his royal titles and removed from the Royal Lodge. Here's a photographic timeline of his scandalous downfall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f904ca72952e2c64ca743e707322f50a</guid></item><item><title>Large hailstones in Placid Hills, Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/large-hailstones-in-placid-hills-queensland/105959238</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2123c2aba2f8ec0e2c5de58fee26fdf3</guid></item><item><title>What do we know about Sandringham and Prince Andrew's new home?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/where-will-prince-andrew-live-next-mountbatten-windsor-/105955954</link><description>The disgraced royal will be moving to a house somewhere on the sprawling Sandringham Estate owned by King Charles — but the exact location has not been made public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3313032bdb329eee1ed90bbc10830d3c</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne happy to open in Australia's Test side for upcoming Ashes series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/cricket-marnus-labuschagne-ready-to-open-australia-ashes/105959688</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne is prepared to do whatever it takes to get back into Australia's Test side, even if that means batting in a non-preferred opening slot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aaceba17d7858f2de1a829904e732ca9</guid></item><item><title>Canberra will get its first dementia care village</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/canberra-will-get-its-first-dementia-care-village/105959468</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fb4bf48a55298218731fa4663c10083</guid></item><item><title>Hailstorm across parts of Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/hailstorm-across-parts-of-queensland/105959796</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e74d6778d9df1fe7451e3c5d267d15c9</guid></item><item><title>Australia vs India second T20: Hazlewood and Marsh dominate in Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/cricket-australia-india-second-t20i-melbourne-live-scorecentre/105959222</link><description>A lethal spell from Josh Hazlewood has propelled Australia to an emphatic four-wicket Twenty20 win over India in front of 82,438 fans at the MCG.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c924fd75cf27f00160799d33b1310dce</guid></item><item><title>WA man fined over neglect of two dogs which 'suffered greatly'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/wa-regs-animal-cruelty-sentence/105959396</link><description>A man in Western Australia's far north has been fined and banned from owning pets for five years after being found guilty of neglecting two dogs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">648d1b522382b84d5b061d66a9095663</guid></item><item><title>Dutch centrist leader Rob Jetten claims election victory and is set to become country's youngest PM</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/dutch-centrist-d66-party-confirmed-as-election-winner-anp-says/105960122</link><description>Dutch centrist party D66 is now expected to take the lead in a first round of talks to form a coalition government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">837e28c07f59e4f52cf2bada907deebe</guid></item><item><title>The mystery of Prince Andrew's finances and why there are calls for more transparency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/former-prince-andrew-mountbatten-windsor-questions-about-fina/105950742</link><description>Andrew remains the subject of a mystery many are flummoxed by. The king's brother has not had a paid job for large chunks of his life, yet somehow he has managed to fund a luxury lifestyle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a8d36fbdb037f6b85cc3fffb504e0fd</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew's downfall is Virginia Giuffre's justice, but can it save the monarchy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-virginia-guiffre-charles-jury-out/105959842</link><description>Prince Andrew has been exiled to a kind royal house arrest but the jury is still out on whether it's enough to stem damage to the monarchy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3a2ba1ff4cef4efc1e36e9eae1cde57</guid></item><item><title>Conjoined twins in PNG could be sent to Germany for surgery after Australia hopes fall through</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/png-conjoined-twins-not-getting-treatment-in-sydney-australia/105952802</link><description>The parents of conjoined twins in PNG who were hoping to send their babies to Sydney for an operation are now trying to go to Germany instead because Australia is too expensive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ebb82535b2f5b422a620c992c9c6562</guid></item><item><title>Nurse among patients calling for better access to long COVID treatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/calls-for-more-specialist-treatment-into-long-covid/105836026</link><description>Patients are calling for better access to long COVID care after the closure of one of the country's last public clinics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5638d2425e01e1612dee5ffec366fbe4</guid></item><item><title>Virginia Giuffre's brother demands Prince Andrew investigation, wants King to pressure Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/virginia-giuffre-s-brother-wants-andrew-investigated/105960436</link><description>Sky Roberts also appealed to King Charles to pressure Donald Trump into putting "big boy pants on" over the release of the Epstein files.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">510d4de91745e3e2adeaeeea4ac1ca84</guid></item><item><title>Survey reveals nine out of 10 NSW farmers are victims of crime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/farm-crime-survey-rural-theft-nsw-farmers/105953178</link><description>Widespread farm crime is frustrating rural communities, with almost 90 per cent of farmers in New South Wales reporting they have been victims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca3685010c044834d674786d3fcc67b0</guid></item><item><title>Alcohol industry explores smaller packaging as consumers seek convenience</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/alcohol-industry-looks-towards-smaller-packaging/105898004</link><description>From wine in 187ml bottles to spirits in sleek aluminium cans, producers are downsizing to meet a growing demand for convenience and variety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06918ace93ca9c6d4266e307b0e5a7d1</guid></item><item><title>David McCormack on Bluey, Custard, and the power of popular music</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/david-mccormack-custard-bluey-polaroids-interview-bandit/105957448</link><description>From indie rock to children's TV icon, David McCormack has done it all — and now he's back with a new album and zero expectations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e656df70aaecbde8d98aa2dcaa094b9</guid></item><item><title>Lawyers move to block Nauru deportations over lack of adequate healthcare</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/lawyers-launch-fresh-bid-to-block-nauru-deportations/105956438</link><description>Human rights lawyers have applied to intervene in the High Court case of a man facing deportation to Nauru, arguing the government should be barred from deporting people to places where they face death or serious harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">925338d4024bf4344d379d1c6ca05899</guid></item><item><title>Master Builders Association of Victoria board member fails in legal bid to unmask purported whistleblower</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/master-builders-victoria-board-lisa-hollingsworth-legal-dispute/105949206</link><description>A Master Builders Association of Victoria board member fails in their bid to identify the person who made a complaint about their conduct — provoking a colourful ruling from the presiding judge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">965b5cad0d3ed974d94abd0c878cfedb</guid></item><item><title>Why Australia's spring housing market this year is set to go into overdrive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/is-the-spring-real-estate-selling-season-boom-accurate-australia/105910630</link><description>NSW sees a 16.8 per cent increase in new property listings during spring — ringing true to the age-old saying this time of year is the best time to jump into the housing market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">701696510367692d1ffd5716678135dc</guid></item><item><title>North makes history with 24th consecutive AFLW win, Carlton finals-bound after win in the west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/north-melbourne-makes-history-with-24th-consecutive-aflw-win/105960520</link><description>North Melbourne becomes the first male or female VFL/AFL team to win 24 consecutive games after prevailing over Hawthorn by 49 points.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8853825ea0c5e574c574d6747f015958</guid></item><item><title>Wastewater from a metal and critical mineral refinery in Baotou, China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/wastewater-from-metal-critical-mineral-refinery-baotou-china/105957548</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92d209e2752baae60fe47a0c5913a2ad</guid></item><item><title>Australia's pursuit of critical minerals holy grail could come at great cost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/will-critical-minerals-cost-australia-too-much/105954636</link><description>Researchers warn Australia's pursuit of a critical minerals industry could come at a significant cost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cf1f06e0c623e2822f22f0ac0d1c4d5</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur upset by Alexander Bublik again in Paris in repeat of Roland Garros heartbreak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/alex-de-minaur-upset-by-familiar-foe-again-in-paris/105960540</link><description>Alex de Minaur suffers another nightmarish defeat in Paris at the hands of his old tormentor Alexander Bublik.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa59a406bdfa767d6298d015b3d7a047</guid></item><item><title>Trump wants to resume US nuclear weapons testing. This is what it could look like</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/what-donald-trump-us-nuclear-weapons-testing-would-mean/105955836</link><description>The US has not conducted nuclear weapons testing for 33 years. Now Donald Trump is calling for a resumption, raising concerns about what that may involve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">592dbf744580aa6b4dc97f32018e4581</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja has seen politicians 'all over cricket', now he's joining other athletes to get action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/usman-khawaja-players-coalition-end-game-sport-politics/105956976</link><description>Cricketer Usman Khawaja is one of the highest-profile Australian athletes who regularly wades into political issues. Now, Khawaja and other athletes have agreed to form a Players' Coalition to influence policy change on issues ranging from racism and human rights to social media abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4244b2427f7b8691e7f1ec870cd90b45</guid></item><item><title>Trans people push to make healthcare more inclusive in the regions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/healthcare-for-trans-people-in-regional-australia/105951286</link><description>A Queensland trans man says healthcare workers did not fully understand his needs when he sought fertility treatment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c50eae967b4c2f86c1115dbff28cbcb</guid></item><item><title>Is the AI bubble too big to burst?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/if-youre-listening-ai-bubble-too-big/105960072</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6c58216143f41625b58dc75818bde30</guid></item><item><title>How the Lions conquered their growing pains to reach AFLW top four</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/aflw-how-brisbane-lions-reached-top-four/105951226</link><description>After a shaky start to the season the Brisbane Lions showed faith in a shift in game style to climb up the ladder and guarantee themselves a top-four finish.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89b1abd2fd62d24a392eafb8dd58b8f9</guid></item><item><title>Suzanne Rees died alone on Lizard Island. How did it happen?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/suzanne-rees-death-on-lizard-island-cruise/105956918</link><description>Suzanne Rees joined a hike on Queensland's Lizard Island as part of a cruise stopover. She would never make it back to the boat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90d14897b44cfcfaaff300b8e71f0405</guid></item><item><title>Emergency doctors say RAH admitted more patients than bed limit, SA Health denies claim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/ed-doctors-under-pressure-at-royal-adelaide-hospital/105952042</link><description>The Australasian College of Emergency Medicine says on a day in September there were 70 admitted inpatients in the Royal Adelaide Hospital's emergency department that has 68 beds — a claim disputed by SA Health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dffcfe5d9444278730f4f2b4c51d1fd</guid></item><item><title>Holiday workers propping up key sectors exposed to serious workplace injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/working-holiday-makers-face-higher-risk-of-injury/105876542</link><description>Many young people on the Working and Holiday Visa programs come to Australia to fill labour shortages in industries like meat processing and farming, but there are concerns around their health and safety in dangerous workplaces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4d109f50ed67b18b9f731588e56f11a</guid></item><item><title>The Canberra Liberals need to put their internal feud behind them. It's hard to see how they'll do that</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/canberra-liberals-internal-feud-distracting-from-job-opposition/105959904</link><description>After suspending two backbenchers from her party room this week, Canberra Liberals leader Leanne Castley has been silent. And it's hard to see how staying silent is helping Canberrans build trust in her party and her as the ACT's alternative chief minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6092a469630022aa6e000888ae487a5c</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate electric dirt bike crash as 15yo dies on the Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/gold-coast-teenager-dies-electric-dirt-bike-crash/105960602</link><description>A teenage boy has died overnight after falling from an electric dirt bike in Broadbeach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc5d59d80676974c2eebc6d9359f1507</guid></item><item><title>Who made the 2025 Booker Prize shortlist, who missed out and who will win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/booker-prize-shortlist-2025-reading-guide/105938154</link><description>'Spiky characters' and 'luminous writing': Here's what we thought of the prestigious literary award's 2025 shortlist, the first with Sarah Jessica Parker as judge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e56d5d64ebed92baa37fc7bef87c9e1</guid></item><item><title>Pen pals enjoy 60-year friendship from opposite sides of the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/pen-pals-for-60-years-joy-doevendans-diane-hatt-friendship/105893420</link><description>Sixty years ago in Canada, 12-year-old Diane Hatt went searching for a pen pal in Australia. She found one in South Australian Joy Doevendans and they've become best friends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">804dd3e41d88618206c0d9211f0d6ef9</guid></item><item><title>What are you going to pay for your aged care? Here are all the details</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/what-aged-care-recipients-will-pay-under-government-proposal/105958056</link><description>A new fee structure for aged care takes effect today. Find out what it will mean for you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf85089e4290931f295656e23d71fb2a</guid></item><item><title>Quick and easy tomato and halloumi bake for busy weeknights - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/quick-easy-tomato-and-halloumi-bake/105929094</link><description>This tomato and halloumi bake requires only a handful of ingredients, sliced and seasoned and popped in a baking dish.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">789c5895d72e095e35c552b7d464aacf</guid></item><item><title>She accused him of rape, but Prince Andrew's downfall is too late for Virginia Roberts Giuffre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/virginia-giuffre-voice-finally-heard-prince-andrew-epstein-fight/105957478</link><description>In many ways, justice has been robbed from Epstein survivor Virginia Roberts Giuffre. Prince Andrew's stripped titles are a posthumous victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a998edbe78ca9949991b2d99999cc68</guid></item><item><title>Nhulunbuy Tennis Club faces final serve as Rio Tinto mine closure looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/future-of-gove-tennis-centre-in-doubt-as-mining-winds-down/105917060</link><description>The impending departure of Rio Tinto raises concerns about the future of sporting clubs in Nhulunbuy. But there are hopes increased investment in regional sports can help sustain the community's active lifestyle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36e3a7519ef27e93f34f9e7dd926b7d3</guid></item><item><title>Tanzania election protests leave hundreds dead, main opposition party says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/tanzania-election-protests-hundreds-killed/105960546</link><description>President Samia Suluhu Hassan this week held an election in which her main challengers were either jailed or barred from standing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f85f9f5ab328bb8cb1f4493b83c85059</guid></item><item><title>Buy Australian campaign aims to save dwindling domestic food manufacturing industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/federal-government-buy-local-campaign-food-shoppers/105947768</link><description>Experts warn that Australian food manufacturing is under threat as shoppers turn to cheaper imported items, but the federal government is trying to promote locally grown produce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">456a65f4e2f0a77a89ea886399f89dfc</guid></item><item><title>Fathers and daughters, international rowing champions and wartime love feature in our top WA October photos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/wa-photo-wrap-october/105944870</link><description>Our photographers this month illustrate a significant day for WA's history, a woman's struggle with her tiny home and a group of rowers competing on the world stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6387b2ce70b14afd3782e7b709897cc4</guid></item><item><title>Nationals ditch net zero support in party platform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/nationals-ditch-net-zero-support-in-party-platform/105959532</link><description>The decision by the party's Federal Council does not bind federal parliamentarians but could pave the way for them to make a similar move as early as this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b81d174da3188fa2eec1d3a9d141af4</guid></item><item><title>Liam Gallagher incensed by flare let off at Melbourne Oasis concert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/oasis-concert-flare-melbourne-concert-liam-gallagher/105960702</link><description>A flare let off by a crowd member at the first of three Melbourne Oasis concerts has angered the band's co-founder Liam Gallagher, sparking an expletive-laden post.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d900445763b5a4b59252cb54dd16bdb6</guid></item><item><title>Warren Tredrea was the Power's premiership captain, but has now been booted from its board</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/how-port-adelaide-great-warren-tredrea-lost-a-board-position/105467820</link><description>The Port Adelaide Football Club continues to describe Warren Tredrea as one of its greatest-ever players — but on Friday it dismissed him from its board of directors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a28d3f1051b04fcdcdfb0195c975542c</guid></item><item><title>Japan wants to hire more bear hunters after record number of people attacked</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/japan-hires-bear-hunters-after-record-number-of-attacks/105960706</link><description>In the past six months, there have been four times the number of people killed by bears compared with last year, and the Japanese government wants to hire hunters to help cull the animals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b94b0d493eff834ff8f63809da300887</guid></item><item><title>Monkey escape in Mississippi gives a glimpse into the secretive world of animal research</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/monkey-search-us-animal-research-questions/105960876</link><description>A truck carrying 21 research monkeys overturned in Mississippi, spilling wooden crates labelled "live monkeys" into the tall grass near the highway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">837b49eea6678d18176e391ed60579b7</guid></item><item><title>Australia criticises 'lost opportunity' for strengthened Antarctic conservation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/antarctic-conservation-krill-fishing-ccamlr/105958414</link><description>The Australian government says it's "disappointed" after an international conservation meeting in Hobart failed to reach agreement on improved protection measures in Antarctica.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b8e997fb574570c44cb438a1c4ea1b6</guid></item><item><title>NSW mental health nurse disqualified after intimate relationship with patient</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/mental-health-nurse-disqualified-intimate-patient-relationship/105960708</link><description>The NSW Civil and Administrative Tribunal has found a mental health nurse guilty of professional misconduct after she was observed hugging and kissing a patient.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24944a801043e0de150b7f3c3a619f28</guid></item><item><title>Eagles to make historic AFLW finals appearance after Swans fall to Bombers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/aflw-power-giants-tigers-suns-swans-bombers-cats-demons/105961268</link><description>Daisy Pearce's West Coast Eagles have reached the AFLW finals for the first time after the Sydney Swans blew their chance in a shock three-point loss to struggling Essendon at Coffs Harbour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8352fdea61b61a74d7d71d411279529b</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after woman's body found in home near Cessnock</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/police-make-arrest-after-womans-death-cessnnock/105960920</link><description>Police have charged a man in connection with the violent death of a 39-year-old woman in a home near Cessnock.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da28036e83cf08345f69ac738cde7e04</guid></item><item><title>APEC world leaders meeting highlights idea of 'free and fair' global trade is severely wounded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/apec-highlights-idea-of-free-and-fair-global-trade-is-wounded/105961066</link><description>While Donald Trump skipped the APEC conference, Xi Jinping was positioning China as a believer in free and fair trade, and multilateralism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0566f6102894ef7c78bf89e77059156</guid></item><item><title>Police charge teen after officers allegedly assaulted at Byford Halloween party</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/two-arrested-over-police-assault-at-byford-halloween-party/105961178</link><description>Two police officers were allegedly assaulted while shutting down an out-of-control Halloween party attended by hundreds of people in Perth's southern suburbs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97de9b08824a32ec2c7df8196e8c47af</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Cup 2025 field, horses, form guide and betting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/melbourne-cup-2025-field-horses-form-guide-and-betting/105895400</link><description>The chances of this year's contenders are reshaped as more than 23 millimetres of rain falls at Flemington on Monday. Explore our interactive form guide to all the horses set to line up in Tuesday's great race.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5c14042d610687b63933e018c602f35</guid></item><item><title>US House Democrats call on Prince Andrew to answer questions about Epstein links</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/democrats-call-on-prince-andrew-to-answer-questions-on-epstein/105961492</link><description>Democratic members of a US congressional committee investigating the Jeffrey Epstein case are calling on Andrew Mountbatten Windsor, the former prince, to answer questions about the convicted sex offender.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f57c675ccc781fe736d2f04a9a94931f</guid></item><item><title>Tanzanian president Samia Suluhu Hassan wins disputed election with more than 97pc of vote, results show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/samia-suluhu-hassan-tanzania-election-results-disputed-win/105961496</link><description>The result is likely to amplify the concerns of critics, opposition groups and others who said the election was not a contest but a coronation, after the president's two main rivals were barred or prevented from running.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f882ddb778d8b55165f699bcfb9ca3f7</guid></item><item><title>Three players sin-binned as Australia win torrid second Test 14-4 over England to retain Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/rugby-league-ashes-live-updates-australia-england-second-test/105961660</link><description>Australia have won a tough physical battle in Liverpool to claim the second Test against England and ensure they will retain the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00cefecb9b09081da42f3e08f2474f9e</guid></item><item><title>England power past Wallabies 25-7 at Twickenham as Matt Dawson slams Australians as being 'woeful'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/live-updates-england-vs-wallabies-rugby-union-international/105950672</link><description>The Wallabies are overpowered by a disciplined and ruthless England team, which wins its eighth-straight international to claim victory at Twickenham.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a65e895909c012bbf81dead627b70dc</guid></item><item><title>Two more people charged over Louvre heist in Paris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/louvre-heist-suspect-released-without-charge/105961712</link><description>The man and woman deny any involvement in the heist as investigations continue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b684b03bddb0c65cf3adf01f8e0f665d</guid></item><item><title>Trump and Xi prove they aren't just great rivals but politicians fighting for survival back home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/donald-trump-xi-jinping-meeting-busan-trade-taiwan/105957454</link><description>Donald Trump's gains are immediate and personal while Xi Jinping's are quiet, reversible, and strategic</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39b4047e9d75d88c7897c44769cd5431</guid></item><item><title>Share your experience with the housing market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/audience-callout-housing-experiences/105958352</link><description>What's your experience looking to buy your first home, or find an affordable, stable rental? We want to hear from you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d2af351a2853732a55f711d6a86bdde</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew is leaving Windsor Estate. Why wasn't he given another property on the grounds?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/prince-andrew-windsor-estate-who-lives-where/105961082</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten Windsor's eviction from his mansion in Windsor Castle is the latest part of a reshuffle of royals around the estate's grounds. Here's where everyone lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40999d5b8081f180d9837a54afab649e</guid></item><item><title>Australians are being priced out of the property market and first home buyers schemes might not be helping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/real-estate-property-market-first-home-buyers-schemes/105941822</link><description>A recent auction for a three-bedroom townhouse in Brisbane has captured just how much property prices have skyrocketed in recent years, highlighting the nation’s fast-growing housing affordability crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b516c705020e5d11eef2fa6ae1e76d3</guid></item><item><title>When is the RBA meeting next? When will interest rates go down?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/reserve-bank-australia-rba-meeing-interest-rates-october/105942272</link><description>Many people paying off mortgages were hoping for a cash rate cut, but recent inflation data means that is highly unlikely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f329c2691a88d508e7837d35f646745</guid></item><item><title>Labor takes fight to Greens in key seats over environment laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/labor-takes-fight-to-greens-on-environmental-laws/105959854</link><description>As it negotiates with the Greens and the Coalition over its proposed overhaul of environment laws, Labor is preparing a campaign accusing the minor party of obstructing its agenda.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e24fd6f4bdadc2cf53792201d360334c</guid></item><item><title>New York's underbelly is thriving — this FBI case pulled back the curtain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/new-york-mafia-families-caught-running-complex-gambling-ring/105958744</link><description>The New York mafia is alive and an "historic" FBI bust has shown that underworld crime is still kicking across the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">262122226118c0158e14d96cee51a5d0</guid></item><item><title>Talking about aged care in multicultural families can be hard but these tips may help</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/talking-about-aged-care-in-multicultural-families/105938294</link><description>Discussing aged care in culturally diverse families can be a sensitive subject. Here's how some approached the conversation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2ac3beed4221115a2488574253ef35c</guid></item><item><title>Horse racing replays edited to remove falls and deaths as industry grapples with social licence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/horse-racing-disappearing-video-replay-ethical-concerns/105812252</link><description>For years, the racing industry has been quietly removing falls and deaths from its replays. Now, industry insiders are speaking out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60509cf475521db2072628c3e8b45285</guid></item><item><title>A game for the ages: Nan and teen granddaughter line up together in country netball</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/newstead-netball-game-for-the-ages-nan-and-teen/105944908</link><description>A grandmother and granddaughter played for their regional Victorian netball team, turning a secret plan into a moment of country sport history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95920eb90f08d84fbc57ca7f8a5ec5ad</guid></item><item><title>Copper theft costing Queensland taxpayers millions of dollars every year, as rate of crime increases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/copper-theft-costing-queensland-millions-crime-rates-increase/105943088</link><description>Experts say cost of living pressures, and the ability to make money quickly, is behind a surge in copper thefts which are leaving highways and sporting fields in the dark.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0f0ec08f1204c4a7360840a2b521d86</guid></item><item><title>Do the Queensland government’s claims about the surgical waiting list stack up?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/queensland-goverment-claims-surgicial-wait-times/105958488</link><description>Queensland's government declared victory on elective surgery wait times but thousands of patients are waiting longer than recommended — and specialists warn the fix is short-term at best.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1addc634e85cc415f058a6f711c9770</guid></item><item><title>From death masks to selfies: The history of our love-affair with portraits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/history-of-the-portrait/105915764</link><description>Whether it's an ancient death mask found on an Egyptian sarcophagus or the selfie you have just cropped on your phone, we have been creating portraits for centuries. So why do we love them so much?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e709c70c97458c7783289aaa7bc0da4</guid></item><item><title>How taxidermists are 'honouring the life' of extraordinary creatures through art and science</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/inside-the-role-of-taxidermists-and-nsw-rules-around-taxidermy/105858594</link><description>From a taxidermied mynah bird perched on a teacup to a mammoth leatherback turtle, here are the "extraordinary creatures" these taxidermists are preserving.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0ffe9b37d678fe031e628d33e163a35</guid></item><item><title>House prices have been climbing for a generation. Undoing the damage could take even longer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/house-prices-climbing-for-generation/105954416</link><description>It's an inconvenient truth that a housing crisis that took a generation to create cannot be fixed easily. The damage will likely take another generation to undo, unless the solution comes at the expense of those who already own their homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">029813aa2a3bd32b3760400b372935b2</guid></item><item><title>Australian number one Maya Joint loses in Hong Kong Open semis, Kim Birrell through to Chennai final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/hong-kong-open-semifinals-maya-joint-kim-birrell/105962042</link><description>Australian number one Maya Joint falls short of reaching the Hong Kong Open final, but compatriot Kimberly Birrell wins through to the tournament decider in Chennai.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88b411666705cb40a6cf868fe350d23a</guid></item><item><title>Think you've got what it takes to top this quiz? It's time to play ... HARD!</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia-tom-gleeson/105938854</link><description>Let's get it straight: you'll probably do badly on this quiz, and I'll judge you. It's time to play … HARD!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">466367d1bfc6da25874b17e1169c00f1</guid></item><item><title>Pitch invader stands with Kangaroos during national anthems before Ashes Test against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/pitch-invader-stands-with-kangaroos-at-ashes-test/105962104</link><description>A man is arrested by police after he lined up next to Cameron Munster before the Kangaroos' victory over England in the second Ashes Test in England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">659b8535fd83d29f6d57607dbfa2d552</guid></item><item><title>Rock climbers' defiance grows over Mount Arapiles cultural site requests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/arapiles-dyurrite-rock-climbers-defy-parks-victoria-requests/105950420</link><description>Rock climbers are publicly urging others to ignore Parks Victoria's requests to avoid culturally significant routes at Mount Arapiles Dyurrite in western Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f94931f9679aa559cb31740079bcf6c6</guid></item><item><title>Kirsha Kaechele banned men from MONA's Ladies Lounge — and won</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/mona-kirsha-kaechele-artist-curator-ladies-lounge-court-tasmania/105950618</link><description>No men are allowed at Kirsha Kaechele's Ladies Lounge and the Supreme Court agrees. The artist, curator and "missus" of MONA's owner knows how to cross boundaries, but can she solve Tasmania's thorniest dispute?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9eb89d5990fedbf1ad146e5a325a75f4</guid></item><item><title>Fishers and researchers are working together to create a 'transformational' data set</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/fishsoop-to-changes-ocean-knowledge/105946294</link><description>An international program in which researchers collaborate with the fishing industry is generating a dataset that will change global weather forecasting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d0be8dd19db857d8bebdf3c09e48455</guid></item><item><title>Sting linked to AN0M encrypted app which brought down criminals around the world enters new phase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/operation-ironside-an0m-arrests-messages-new-phase-explained/105950980</link><description>An international covert sting linked to the encrypted AN0M platform which brought down hundreds of alleged criminals and netted cash, drugs and weapons has reached a new phase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c81f46b90927df3ed2f640543f7ceadd</guid></item><item><title>UK train stabbing leaves 10 in hospital, nine with life-threatening injuries, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/multiple-people-stabbed-on-uk-train-two-arrested/105962212</link><description>British police declare a "major incident", with counter-terrorism officers investigating a mass stabbing attack on a London-bound train.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a06b26a629b9fb1767a6f889a22afab</guid></item><item><title>Women's crisis shelter waits years to sub-lease vacant NT building</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/nt-galiwinku-womens-space-waits-years-to-lease-vacant-building/105947400</link><description>An Aboriginal-led domestic violence support service is demanding answers over stalled progress in establishing a women's shelter in remote Northern Territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c5519c7e21bec78ba2608589fe13d55</guid></item><item><title>Jockey Ethan Brown makes rise from from near-fatal fall to Melbourne Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/fall-and-rise-of-alice-springs-jockey-ethan-brown-melbourne-cup/105959830</link><description>Two years after a near-fatal fall, 25-year-old Alice Springs-born jockey has had a bumper season with 32 wins. Now he is riding in the Melbourne Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">119e82e58075acf4c274d207a8b07167</guid></item><item><title>Calls for road map for disability employment providers after Bedford's troubles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/advocates-call-for-road-map-for-disability-employment-sector/105952760</link><description>Some in the disability employment sector say they are operating in an increasingly complex and changing environment, and that there is a need for a clear way forward for organisations supporting people with complex needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1c23b56d2930c0a42e75b55696ab779</guid></item><item><title>There was a large police presence after reports of stabbings on a train in Cambridgeshire.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/large-police-presence-after-reports-of-stabbings-on-uk-train/105962274</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23f5eefc621d4af1bbe941ed925aee86</guid></item><item><title>Coalition won't back environment reforms without changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/coalition-wont-back-environment-reforms-without-change/105962194</link><description>The Coalition says it cannot support major reforms to Australia's environment laws in their current reform, setting a bar as they enter deep negotiations with the federal government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2234622f8159395c0c50b31e8b6a5e92</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Island shrew declared extinct after decades without a sighting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/christmas-island-shrew-declared-extinct/105949448</link><description>A researcher says the long-suspected extinction of the mouse-sized mammal is "another stain" on Australia's environmental record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5881e83cdbfcb4b8a03bf21dcfcc021</guid></item><item><title>Did a former Perth bikie order the public assassination of his one-time gang leader?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/david-pye-nick-martin-assassination-supreme-court-murder-trial/105946084</link><description>With all the hallmarks of a Hollywood blockbuster, the high-profile murder trial of ex-bikie David Pye in WA's Supreme Court was never going to be a pedestrian affair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dbdcfef0061b6ca8b57bb1f0884bfe5</guid></item><item><title>Southern NSW summer rice and cotton crops shrink amid water shortages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/nsw-rice-and-cotton-plantings-slashed-amid-water-shortage/105899914</link><description>Southern NSW rice and cotton growers are heading into one of their smallest summer cropping seasons in years, with tight water allocations forcing many to halve their plantings or sit the season out altogether.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb84268cc4e631402cd4bcac564e8480</guid></item><item><title>Spotlight on youth justice after dozens arrested in WA's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/community-government-split-on-how-to-manage-youth-crime/105960744</link><description>The political spotlight has once again turned to preventing and managing youth crime in Western Australia, but decision-makers are split on how best to tackle the issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e66797b37f7b947c54d8cfd5aefe6249</guid></item><item><title>What is the difference between an e-bike and an e-motorbike? What are the laws around them?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/e-bike-electronic-bicycle-e-motorbike-state-laws-speed/105580790</link><description>Noticing a lot of e-bikes around lately? Here's a state-by-state breakdown of the laws about them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78ae976ce50c968a6f2276556b5fa4af</guid></item><item><title>Veteran credits his local RSL with helping to pull him out of darkness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/regional-rsl-helps-veteran-during-time-of-darkness/105945666</link><description>A veteran in Victoria says he found hope and solace in his local RSL that "had his back" when he felt overwhelmed by his wife's early onset dementia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e62e59e10ad6400b36d4782f5d0997a</guid></item><item><title>High demand for ambulances in Melbourne and Geelong as weather warms up on Cup weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/vic-ambulance-victoria-high-demand-in-melbourne-and-geelong/105962168</link><description>Victorians are being urged to only call triple-0 for critical cases as demand for an ambulance soars on the quasi-Melbourne Cup long weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ccec54418d7485d71cf4d6c80c677ec</guid></item><item><title>Critically endangered shrub on NSW Northern Tablelands could have prosperous future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/endangered-plant-grows-only-on-nsw-northern-tablelands/105924048</link><description>There are signs a critically endangered plant that grows on a rural property near Armidale could have a prosperous future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65eed854defe58937336b9a998c6ad1a</guid></item><item><title>The tensions inherent in Australia's housing crisis laid bare at Perth gallery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/need-for-housing-inspires-artist/105939626</link><description>In an exhibition exploring the fraught issue of finding a home, artist Alana Hunt is directly inviting owners of multiple properties to solve her own, personal housing crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1ede08335cf42653d92cae8ec5a73da</guid></item><item><title>Koalas found at Avonside in the NSW Snowy Mountains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/koalas-found-in-nsw-snowy-mountains/105951296</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fa344b8bed5c5e2a2839eba39c799c2</guid></item><item><title>Drones spot hidden koala population in NSW Snowy Mountains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/drones-spot-hidden-koala-population-in-nsw-snowy-mountains/105938022</link><description>A hidden group of koalas is found for the first time in a remote area of the New South Wales Snowy Mountains.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75fc1668ffcc40181a0b318a70f9f929</guid></item><item><title>Canadian PM Mark Carney apologises to Donald Trump over anti-tariff Reagan ad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/carney-apologises-to-trump-over-reagan-tariff-advertisement/105962422</link><description>Canadian PM Mark Carney says he apologised to an "offended" US President Donald Trump over the ad, which led to trade talks being suspended and an additional 10 per cent tariff.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89ce7bb7bb3d2290248dbce8ffdd2505</guid></item><item><title>Nationals formally abandon commitment to reach net zero emissions by 2050</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/nationals-formally-abandon-net-zero-by-2050/105962162</link><description>The Nationals have formally abandoned a commitment to reach net zero emissions by 2050, setting a challenge for Opposition leader Sussan Ley whether to follow or risk splitting the Coalition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46eb3da651430f25d065e42b19a4b4ec</guid></item><item><title>Female jockey Jamie Melham discusses riding Melbourne Cup favourite Half Yours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/jamie-melham-half-yours-melbourne-cup-2025/105962620</link><description>Jockey Jamie Melham says she will be doing a "rain dance" on Monday, ahead of riding Melbourne Cup favourite Half Yours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c470aa33d7806c624d07e1920957cc8</guid></item><item><title>Christopher James McLoughney refused bail over alleged murder of Rhukaya Lake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/court-hearing-for-man-accused-of-murder-of-rhukaya-lake/105962286</link><description>A man charged with the domestic violence murder of 39-year-old Hunter woman Rhukaya Lake is remanded in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e02a89e9350dc3c1d31c5a2c1ded6326</guid></item><item><title>Police stop train at Huntingdon Station after mass stabbing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/police-stop-train-at-huntingdon-station-after-mass-stabbing/105962658</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fe2514f2e3fe196c8c30a4c2f2604f6</guid></item><item><title>AFLW round 12: Crows hold on to eliminate Dockers from finals contention, Lions finish third after beating Magpies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/aflw-round-12-collingwood-lions-st-kilda-bulldogs-crows-dockers/105962532</link><description>Adelaide has hung on for a thrilling 12-point win over Fremantle that secures its AFLW finals spot and ends the Dockers' season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e10849f6e5a398d9f4c6195ad557c31</guid></item><item><title>Easy low-alcohol cocktails and non-alcoholic drinks for summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/low-alcohol-cocktails-and-non-alcoholic-drinks-mocktails/105763344</link><description>Having a range of drinks on offer can help everyone feel included, especially at end-of-year gatherings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf0b38dd980309d44e125e1fc03ddb6b</guid></item><item><title>Eliesa Katoa fitted with oxygen mask during Tonga vs New Zealand Test match, Jillaroos defeat Kiwi Ferns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/australia-jillaroos-defeat-new-zealand-kiwi-ferns-10-4/105962804</link><description>Tongan forward Eliesa Katoa has been fitted with an oxygen mask during the Pacific Championship Test match against New Zealand, after copping multiple blows to the head.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c73a30eb3d2eb448a458821f369b445</guid></item><item><title>Inmate taken to hospital after alleged assault at SA's Yatala Labour Prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/inmate-taken-to-hospital-after-alleged-prison-assault/105962732</link><description>A prisoner was taken to the hospital after the second alleged violent assault in two weeks in the South Australian prison system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2f67da22d83a326dc19f70b0a9d48bf</guid></item><item><title>Australia's scandal-ridden childcare sector is a legacy of the 'golden age' of reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/australia-childcare-sector-scandal-golden-age-of-reform/105952006</link><description>The decision by past governments to push Australia's childcare industry in the direction of marketisation and corporatisation has left a lasting legacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1d56cc77ce2fe08cd4f6170ffaaaeeb</guid></item><item><title>India levels T20 series against Australia with impressive run chase in Hobart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/cricket-australia-india-third-t20i-hobart-live-scorecentre/105962480</link><description>India levels the Twenty20 series against Australia, sharing the blows with the bat for a five wicket win with nine balls to spare in Hobart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bd43953a9d2e34ceba1672873e920ea</guid></item><item><title>India defeats South Africa by 52 runs to claim maiden Women's ODI Cricket World Cup title</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/india-vs-south-africa-odi-world-cup-final-live-blog/105962972</link><description>All-round performances from Deepti Sharma and Shafali Verma have led India to a breakthrough World Cup triumph against South Africa in Navi Mumbai.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">491dce6762cbeeff4645783266a86c2c</guid></item><item><title>'Nothing to suggest' stabbing attack on train was a terrorist incident, UK police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/nothing-to-suggest-terrorist-attack-on-train-say-uk-police-/105963010</link><description>Police investigating a mass stabbing on a train bound for London on Saturday say there is nothing to suggest it was a terrorist attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9ecfd2362c9a76384f5e506470829e9</guid></item><item><title>Investors and first home buyers flock to property market, driving up prices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/investors-versus-first-home-buyers-flock-back-to-property-market/105943356</link><description>Australia's property market is seeing rising demand, with record auctions over spring and a rise in both first home buyers and investors pushing up house prices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0dc7ecf241d905d6c06b9d0a12ff2f49</guid></item><item><title>Calls for football clubs to divest from pokies with more than $110 million lost to machines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/afl-football-pokies-machines-gambling/105953142</link><description>There are calls for football teams to distance themselves from poker machines after data found more than $110 million was lost at venues owned by football clubs and leagues in the last financial year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdb126202dde835a7f847688b62cc9df</guid></item><item><title>Australia supplying China with critical mineral vital for hypersonic missiles and its nuclear program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/china-critical-mineral-nuclear-program-australia-supplying/105951072</link><description>Australia is supplying raw materials vital for China's military build-up, while at the same time signing up to be a partner of choice for the United States as it seeks to break Beijing's critical minerals stranglehold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e933fd3fd9f2a350a634f3b2db3b3986</guid></item><item><title>House prices are accelerating again and the housing crisis is back on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/house-prices-increase-again-mortgages-rba-interest-rate-decision/105962246</link><description>The nation has not yet embraced the idea that housing needs to be more affordable, or that it's the most important economic and social issue facing the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ba30d1a79581e1d53d207dd55298d74</guid></item><item><title>Prepaid electricity consumers sweltering under regular disconnections, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/first-nations-right-to-power/105941906</link><description>Communities on prepaid power meters face regular disconnections amid 40 degree-plus heat, meaning no aircon, food rotting in the fridge and long, hot walks to get reconnected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ef435fba593c2156d567a3d871dd4a3</guid></item><item><title>The Nationals dumping net zero is dangerous territory for the Coalition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/net-zero-nationals-coalition-climate-change/105962434</link><description>To borrow the words of former prime minister Tony Abbott, the net zero emissions by 2050 policy for the Coalition is now dead, buried and cremated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b330051db386938f13b08c23ad661075</guid></item><item><title>Russian drones kill Ukrainians and Kyiv targets Moscow's oil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/russian-drones-kill-ukrainians-as-kyiv-targets-moscows-oil/105963596</link><description>At least two people have been killed in a drone attack in Ukraine's south-western Odesa region, and Kyiv has stepped up its attacks on Russia's oil industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7131d35bfef055b590c12c0070dd33aa</guid></item><item><title>From England to Flemington — 20 years on from Makybe Diva's third Melbourne Cup victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/makybe-divas-third-melbourne-cup-20-years-on/105713334</link><description>From quiet beginnings, an unknown English filly came Down Under and changed Australia's racing history by achieving the impossible. This is how Makybe Diva won a historic third Melbourne Cup 20 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b00d87aee930c94249ed44e8122b286b</guid></item><item><title>Weightlifting empowers women of all ages to stop feeling 'invisible'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/women-weightlifting-no-longer-invisible-empowering-women-all-age/105945008</link><description>Teenager Mira Mohan, and Francee and Carolyn, both in their 60s, are changing the face of weightlifting, showing it is a sport for women at any stage of life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cf967ca9f315dc1aac5cb618c34b326</guid></item><item><title>Louvre heist suspects believed to be small-time criminals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/louvre-heist-suspects-believed-to-be-small-time-criminals/105963634</link><description>Four thieves raided the world's most-visited art museum last month, in broad daylight, taking just seven minutes to steal jewellery worth an estimated $150 million before fleeing on scooters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d7d21c2e3f32289b8a9be4f2f72931f</guid></item><item><title>ACT voluntary assisted dying scheme begins, allowing Canberrans to 'die with dignity'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/act-voluntary-assisted-dying-scheme-begins-die-with-dignity/105960688</link><description>From today Canberrans like Gail Ford will be able to apply for the ACT's new voluntary assisted dying scheme, which its advocates say gives dignity in death to applicants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cef55f218d79294ba609c758da3f26c9</guid></item><item><title>UK train stabbing attack investigators questioning British man as only suspect</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/uk-huntingdon-train-attack-police-questioning-sole-suspect/105963742</link><description>British police are not treating a mass stabbing attack on a London-bound train as an act of terror. It left at least 11 people in hospital, some in critical condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4117ddde296f9d8a4b3088828c8067e9</guid></item><item><title>Granite Island's little penguin population climbs despite SA's algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/granite-island-penguin-population-climbs-despite-algal-threat/105920654</link><description>The small, fragile colony of surviving little penguins on South Australia's Granite Island records a "significant increase" in numbers amid the state's harmful algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92e580c7cc58e51567df7100b014ca56</guid></item><item><title>Westpac posts $7 billion profit, leads ASX to a small gain as rare earth miners continue to slump — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/105963788</link><description>A solid full year result from Westpac propelled banks higher and the ASX to a positive close despite miners being sold off.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96aae2324d9b3b7f5725d79d8e7c1488</guid></item><item><title>Former Prince Andrew set to be stripped of military rank by UK government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-to-be-stripped-of-uk-military-title/105963786</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten Windsor will be stripped of his last remaining military position as part of King Charles's decision to remove him from public life, according to the UK defence minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">186ca1d62c6cac740505a135890fa206</guid></item><item><title>Aftermath of mass stabbing on UK train</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/aftermath-of-mass-stabbing-on-uk-train/105963734</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8861ca23e346f8bceb631f4c77b0edc4</guid></item><item><title>Remains of three hostages held in Gaza return to Israel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/israel-receives-three-more-hostages-remains-from-gaza/105963844</link><description>Israel says Hamas has handed over the remains of three hostages held in Gaza, as a fragile month-old ceasefire with the terror organisation continues to hold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">055c6ac5e9dd8b3c5703b6b540784571</guid></item><item><title>Daycare drought causes worker shortages in southern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/childcare-drought-leads-to-workforce-shortages-nsw-physio/105958574</link><description>Daycare droughts are all too common in regional Australia, but in one New South Wales town, the shortage is so acute, the community is cracking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12e8e618355668093e98d9cef24b5f6d</guid></item><item><title>Legal Services Board of Victoria warns lawyers about AI in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/legal-services-board-of-victoria-warns-lawyers-about-ai-in-court/105916628</link><description>The use of artificial intelligence to prepare court documents raises questions in the legal profession about its use and misuse in the industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11322fbec4ebb8c0fb7d75a1fd9addf2</guid></item><item><title>Possible storms and showers forecast for south-east Queensland as weather cools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/queensland-weather-forecast-seq-wet-and-cool-in-west/105962724</link><description>More wet weather is expected in south-east Queensland before clear skies return later this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17d6c7e8a2a890639ef4fea05feb61b7</guid></item><item><title>Treasurer Rita Saffioti defends $1 million advertising blitz, as WA GST deal fight ramps up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/wa-government-takes-fight-for-gst-deal-to-canberra/105962830</link><description>The state government defends spending $1 million on an advertising campaign about Western Australia's GST deal, as the fight to protect the state's carve-up of the distribution ramps up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">640744a3dd8f5df596fae80dbe3300d1</guid></item><item><title>Funding health is one of the biggest challenges facing Tasmania, as Eric Abetz prepares to hand down his first budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/health-funding-budget-challenges-tasmania-eric-abetz/105962530</link><description>A peak health body is worried Tasmania's public health system won't receive enough support in Thursday's state budget to address ballooning demand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">023af7486079fa987a12ff634173e47c</guid></item><item><title>'Net zero is not the only way to address climate change': David Littleproud</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/net-zero-is-not-the-only-way-to-address-climate-change/105964060</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be73351aadcf48b288c88fd302ecba24</guid></item><item><title>How hitchhiking 'suckerfish' reveal humpback whales' 'web of life'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/hitchhiking-suckerfish-reveal-humpback-whales-web-of-life/105950862</link><description>Suckerfish, the ocean's ultimate hitchhikers, cling to humpback whales for thousands of kilometres and reveal surprising insights into life on the whale highway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4897fceb3d1bc8314797d0f765a3d7b2</guid></item><item><title>Boy dies, man injured in mango farm quad bike crash south of Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/darwin-river-quad-bike-boy-11-death-mango-farm/105963960</link><description>An 11-year-old boy has died in a quad bike crash that also injured a 38-year-old man at a mango farm south of Darwin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8371782d854d497e54f01798c97d305</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Kimberly Birrell loses Chennai Open final but earns sportsmanship award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/tennis-kimberly-birrell-loses-chennai-open-final/105963952</link><description>Gold Coast tennis star Kimberly Birrell loses in the Chennai Open final but claims a sportsmanship award for touching moment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b050174d333d3fad08b33509268b994</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr and Ellie Carpenter score for Chelsea as manager praises impact of Matildas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/wsl-sam-kerr-scores-for-chelsea-as-ellie-carpenter-stars/105964142</link><description>Matildas Sam Kerr and Ellie Carpenter both score for Chelsea in an impressive performance from the Australian stars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b399797570ec89c343ac07e8138e3b3b</guid></item><item><title>Maternal health forum reveals gaps in NT system, families choosing to move interstate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/our-birth-our-voice-maternal-health-forum-mother-maternity/105962312</link><description>Women who have had traumatic birth experiences at Royal Darwin Hospital have gathered to share their stories and call for urgent action from the territory and federal governments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0c7f28022601c339568e89af3235be4</guid></item><item><title>Magnitude-6.3 earthquake hits Afghanistan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/afghanistan-earthquake/105964078</link><description>It is unclear how many people have died following an earthquake in northern Afghanistan, two months after a tremor killed more than 2,200 people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ab4460816792f6ad91fddd2214646c5</guid></item><item><title>Rescues on Bluff Knoll increase fourfold in one year as visitor numbers rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/bluff-knoll-hiker-rescues-increase-stirling-range/105957436</link><description>About 50,000 people climb Bluff Knoll in WA's Stirling Range each year, and emergency services say they are being called to more rescues as hikers underestimate the challenging track.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32734c6f058d18bc10fa2dc7af9d7dda</guid></item><item><title>New York Marathon won by Benson Kipruto in classic photo finish, Eliud Kipchoge announces final tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/new-york-marathon-photo-finish-benson-kipruto-eliud-kipchoge/105964270</link><description>Benson Kipruto holds off a fast-finishing Alexander Mutiso to win the New York Marathon by 0.2 seconds, while Hellen Obiri breaks the course record to win the women's race.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a2cf472d74e37649fb8e8c1ebe3e9ed</guid></item><item><title>Italian Alps avalanche kills five Germans, including father and daughter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/five-germans-killed-in-italian-alps-avalanche/105964286</link><description>The avalanche struck the German climbers as they headed for the summit of Cima Vertana about 4pm on Saturday at an altitude of more than 3,500 metres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c43675667dde714744e3976ee465222</guid></item><item><title>What time is the Melbourne Cup? How to watch and the weather forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/melbourne-cup-time-how-to-watch-weather-forecast/105964240</link><description>Rain in Melbourne is set to play a factor in Australia's most famous horse race, with Flemington Racecourse predicted to be rated a Soft 7 or Heavy 8 for Tuesday's Melbourne Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cae8d149b2d1975610eeb0ced6093cde</guid></item><item><title>NRL and RLPA to investigate Eli Katoa handling after Tonga star suffered 'seizure activity' during New Zealand Test match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/eli-katoa-undergoes-surgery-after-head-knocks/105964618</link><description>The Storm say Eli Katoa had surgery after suffering "seizure activity" following multiple head knocks in the Tonga and New Zealand clash, and the league and players' association are set to investigate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e73e2e6676e0caeba54a4615e22b408a</guid></item><item><title>Charges laid after 'trail of destruction' and rock thrown at firefighters in regional SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/arrests-over-fire-and-trespass-in-riverland-and-murray-bridge/105964118</link><description>Three arrests have been made in two separate incidents in regional South Australia, one in which a man allegedly lit a fire before throwing a rock at firefighters and another involving a car being discovered in flames after allegedly leaving a "trail of destruction" on a property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">799a6ca9d677c3487e26d5efc182022a</guid></item><item><title>Father of Molly Ticehurst frustrated by court delays in murder case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/daniel-billings-molly-ticehurst-court-delays/105074740</link><description>The father of murdered childcare worker Molly Ticehurst breaks down while expressing his frustration at the delays in the case against her alleged killer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d85f678d019d66080538c67931898225</guid></item><item><title>ATSB report finds communication failures led to Maersk ship smashing into Leeuwin II</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/leeuwin-damage-atsb-report-released-fremantle-port/105964856</link><description>A lack of effective communication contributed to a collision between the sail training ship Leeuwin II and a container ship in Fremantle Harbour last year that injured two crew members, a new report has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59ad57c60f339cc6a43334a7361086c4</guid></item><item><title>Mental health reform needed to stop children ending up in prison, doctors say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/experts-raise-alarm-over-nt-prison-mental-health-crisis/105964576</link><description>As incarceration rates continue to soar in the Northern Territory, experts say mental health reform in the justice system is crucial for improving community safety in the long term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c0cf2e9fb892f39645d934494cf0e9</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne hoping for chance to face undefeated North Melbourne in AFLW finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/melbourne-want-to-play-north-melbourne-aflw-2025-finals/105963086</link><description>North Melbourne may be undefeated for the second home and away season in a row, but a star Melbourne player says the short AFLW season means they haven't proven themselves against everyone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">593daee658710b712d3b31a8d7333c87</guid></item><item><title>Dark Mofo sees drop in interstate visitors despite return of full program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/dark-mofo-announces-2026-dates-interstate-visitor-numbers-drop/105964376</link><description>Tasmania's provocative midwinter festival Dark Mofo will return in 2026, as this year's festival reports fewer interstate visitors as "budgets are tightening" across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7592eeb31970369291e1fd1d07958fa</guid></item><item><title>Bathurst childcare worker sentenced over head injury to four-year-old</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/bathurst-childcare-worker-sentencing/105956356</link><description>The Bathurst childcare worker is said to have used "considerable force" on the child, resulting in his head needing medical adhesive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">881b637a3380f570bc2a0ebc764e3c1e</guid></item><item><title>Optus held 11 crisis meetings before telling government about triple-0 deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/stephen-rue-optus-senate-inquiry/105963860</link><description>A Senate grilling of Optus executives reveals the company sat on information about deaths resulting from its triple-0 outage for nearly a day before telling the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b21e83b6151f06a528993bfaa56fb5a</guid></item><item><title>Review of mass salmon mortalities in Tasmania points to litany of failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/tasmanian-government-salmon-mortality-report/105964772</link><description>The state's environment watchdog has released a debrief of lessons and reflections from a mass salmon mortality event in which dead fish washed up on Tasmanian beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9ca2922a14f04ffa535ac0a9c93a414</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs lashed by 'fierce' storm and wild wind, cutting power</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/fierce-storm-moves-lashes-central-australia/105964766</link><description>A severe thunderstorm brought down trees and cut power for several hours in Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">489e7a71a7046213a075a3ca36697ba7</guid></item><item><title>Alleged manslaughter victim resorted to eating from school bins, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/jenni-gaye-wilmott-criminal-neglect-manslaughter-trial/105964930</link><description>A girl who died, allegedly as a result of criminal neglect by her mother, had resorted to eating food out of bins at her school, a court has heard. Warning: This story includes references to child abuse and self-harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bbef5bcd61372c610efe3388118962d</guid></item><item><title>What led to the giant, damaging hail which smashed parts of Queensland over the weekend?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/queensland-giant-hail-explainer-injuries-and-damage/105964362</link><description>Hailstones of up to 8 and 9 centimetres hit parts of Queensland over the weekend. What caused them to be so large?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70300d1d341a518478b5c5d333831809</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump renovates White House Lincoln bathroom with marble and chandelier over toilet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/donald-trump-white-house-marble-renovation-lincoln-bathroom/105964474</link><description>The US president says the new look is more appropriate than the "Art Deco green tile style" from the last renovation in the 1940s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b13a226fd8e400e785b4d5703b24eab2</guid></item><item><title>Jennifer Mui Len Chin avoids jail after stabbing daughter's boyfriend in her home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/jennifer-mui-len-chin-sentenced-for-stabbing-daughter-boyfriend/105729024</link><description>A Perth mother who stabbed her daughter's teenage boyfriend when she found him semi-naked in the family home avoids a prison sentence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">063cff8edce9a9e7ff9e75fd7461ce4f</guid></item><item><title>Brief of evidence in Pheobe Bishop murder case reissued due to server crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/pheobe-bishop-murder-accused-case-delayed-due-to-server-crash/105965760</link><description>Thousands of pages of evidence had to be reissued to defence team after it was lost in server crash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a663bff41ea244b253ec402335426338</guid></item><item><title>Your rights when it comes to breastfeeding and expressing at work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/your-rights-when-it-comes-to-breastfeeding-at-work/105885406</link><description>There are many ways to combine breastfeeding and paid work, for example expressing milk, breastfeeding during breaks, or working from home. Knowing your rights can help you feel more confident when negotiating what that looks like.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9bc5be5b34fd60252cd240bea55393e</guid></item><item><title>Ash Barty urges Australians to be patient with tennis young guns Emerson Jones and Maya Joint</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/tennis-ash-barty-emerson-ones-maya-joint-patience-fans/105965970</link><description>Australia's last women's singles grand slam champ is encouraged by the new crop of kids coming through, but has urged fans to remain patient with their progress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5473442a6386a6e6963a8c2fdd24ada1</guid></item><item><title>Former SA opposition leader David Speirs shares ideas for algal bloom recovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/david-speirs-writes-document-about-algal-bloom-recovery/105964388</link><description>Former South Australian opposition leader David Speirs says he will make a decision about his political future in the coming weeks as he launches his own plans for the algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">152096256b48251dcf5b836c9f15dcc9</guid></item><item><title>Outspoken Mexican mayor known for anti-crime stance killed during Day of the Dead festivities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/carlos-alberto-manzo-rodriguez-killed-during-festivities/105965498</link><description>In recent months Mayor Carlos Alberto Manzo Rodríguez had publicly appealed to the Mexican president for help to combat cartel violence and organised crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71067bc9dcf0697e95fb21e2c73e17c8</guid></item><item><title>Mid North Coast blueberry farmer counts losses after severe storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/blueberry-farmer-counts-losses-after-severe-nsw-storm/105964770</link><description>Stephen Thandi says a storm tore through his northern New South Wales blueberry farm "like a freight train" at the weekend, causing at least at least $300,000 worth of damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bc95aea2afdbdba268996de3d3870d9</guid></item><item><title>Labor pledged to ban nuclear weapons in opposition. In government it got a reality check</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/labor-retreats-from-nuclear-weapons-ban-pledge-four-corners/105959312</link><description>Anthony Albanese and Richard Marles once pledged Labor would sign a treaty to ban nuclear weapons. Why have they walked this back in government?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7b97f5dfd33f372d2e20a376341948d</guid></item><item><title>US judge ends Justin Baldoni lawsuit against Blake Lively for missing court deadline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/justin-baldoni-loses-lawsuit-against-blake-lively/105964392</link><description>The actor's lawsuit against his co-star Blake Lively ends after he missed a court deadline on October 17 to file an amended complaint.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d67cfbc085cd2577ee4a2e2aab8e657</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast Mayor Tom Tate calls for urgent e-transport law changes after deaths of two children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/e-bikes-gold-coast-mayor-legislation-police-parents-safety/105965460</link><description>Following the deaths of a 15-year-old and an eight-year-old in the space of less than two days, Gold Coast Mayor Tom Tate calls for urgent change to Queensland laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08a8c9380f4da24917de076c43271ed4</guid></item><item><title>CCTV footage of alleged kidnapping of George Ayoub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/-alleged-kidnapping-of-george-ayoub/105965734</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f3c9230aaae7e3fa1670c9933abcddd</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate Sydney developer's brother's alleged kidnapping, claim $1 million ransom paid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/nsw-george-ayoub-belfield-kidnapping-ransom-charlie-developer/105964220</link><description>George Ayoub was allegedly taken and shoved into the back of a car while he was walking outside his Belfield home about 5am on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aafe92c1f3295450c142351348b3509c</guid></item><item><title>Hinchinbrook by-election a 'test' for Queensland LNP government as writs issued</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/hinchinbrook-by-election-test-for-lnp-government-as-writs-issued/105964322</link><description>One year after sweeping to power, Queensland's LNP government will face voters at the Hinchinbrook by-election, with the poll seen as a test for the premier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffb39a2372f3dd7130e26a17dfd9fb82</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne's delayed Fishermans Bend redevelopment labelled 'biggest planning failure in Australia's history'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/melbourne-fishermans-bend-redevelopment-planning-failure/105964410</link><description>It has been touted as "Australia's largest urban renewal project" right next to one of the country's biggest CBDs. But critics say the development is being held back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e32f5968dd08e374d3a56eb4c677335</guid></item><item><title>Gorden Tallis and Matthew Johns join Gold Coast Titans ownership group under Frizelle family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/rugby-league-nrl-gorden-tallis-matthew-johns-titans-owners/105966490</link><description>Former Broncos captain Gorden Tallis joins interstate rivals as a part-owner alongside former Knights playmaker Matthew Johns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7199394dfc05ad97a23f69927e5fbccb</guid></item><item><title>Liberals shifting towards dumping net zero, despite moderate faction fears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/liberals-shifting-towards-dumping-net-zero-2050/105966032</link><description>The centre of debate inside the Liberals appears to be shifting towards dumping net zero, as a tumultuous debate unfolds following the Nationals' decision to formally abandon the 2050 target.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b9fc63959d7c9500d200678644eb8a2</guid></item><item><title>Trial begins for man charged with murder over alleged hit and run at Browns Plains in Logan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/browns-plains-alleged-hit-and-run-murder-trial-begins/105966476</link><description>Umar Al Enizi is charged with the murder of Troy Vandenberg in September 2021. The jury heard both men were "total strangers" who had been involved in an altercation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54aed34dbd3e42cbf6fa00df287384bc</guid></item><item><title>Teenager avoids conviction over 'racist' attack on security guard at Bendigo Marketplace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/teen-avoids-conviction-over-bendigo-marketplace-attack/105965024</link><description>A teenager involved in the violent attack on a security guard that forced a country Victorian shopping centre into lockdown avoids jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5957c3cafab69872dcfc6853254978cd</guid></item><item><title>Coral Adventurer had mechanical problems ahead of passenger Suzanne Rees's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/coral-adventurer-mechanical-problems-passenger-death/105965482</link><description>Passengers have left the the ill-fated Coral Adventurer following the death of Suzanne Rees. Ongoing mechanical problems have cut the journey short and the ship is returning south from the Torres Strait.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa55667757e304862c44d58c2f9830ea</guid></item><item><title>6.3 earthquake damages Afghanistan's historic Blue Mosque</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/6-3-earthquake-damages-afghanistan-s-historic-blue-mosque/105966886</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fb07bb376838203237c6e9cef3ee9f4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says UK royals suffered 'terrible thing' with pressure over Jeffrey Epstein scandal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/trump-says-uk-royals-suffered-with-pressure-over-epstein-scandal/105966134</link><description>Donald Trump says he felt badly for the British royal family after King Charles stripped his brother Andrew Mountbatten Windsor of his title as prince amid mounting pressure over his ties to convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d370207082665fc3845970254d9582a</guid></item><item><title>Suspected meteor spotted in afternoon sky across Victoria's Gippsland region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/suspected-meteor-gippsland-sonic-boom-afternoon-sky/105964144</link><description>Victorians living in the state's Gippsland region say they saw a streak of light whizzing through the Sunday afternoon sky and heard a sonic boom, with many wondering if they saw space junk or a meteor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e9bed216b9650f760b92074d851e252</guid></item><item><title>Chinese ship spies on Australia, Philippines and the US in South China Sea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/chinese-ship-spies-on-australia-philippines-us-naval-exercise/105966362</link><description>A sophisticated Chinese spy ship monitors Australian, Philippines, United States and New Zealand naval forces as they conduct another round of joint exercises in the South China Sea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f50ebe538b32fabcc174dd6fada42689</guid></item><item><title>Champion trainer Chris Waller compares Buckaroo to 2021 Melbourne Cup champ Verry Elleegant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/melbourne-cup-horse-racing-waller-buckaroo-verry-elleegant/105967072</link><description>Buckaroo might have failed to get the job done at last year's Melbourne Cup and this year's Cox Plate, but trainer Chris Waller believes its build-up is tracking perfectly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e79d53022f0334e75d77be11f8c0d915</guid></item><item><title>The key takeaways from Anthony Albanese's time at ASEAN and APEC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/anthony-albanese-apec-asean-summits-key-moments/105966626</link><description>While Australia's relationship with China has improved, there is still growing unease about Beijing's military power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b3fc8fafd7b0d2699a5af5b3187d993</guid></item><item><title>Monday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/monday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/105966924</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ad6cfc9cbdeeb8601d746ca1d77c3c2</guid></item><item><title>Angel Seafood halts oyster relocation amid protesters' algal bloom fears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/angel-seafood-halts-oyster-relocation-after-blockade-algal-bloom/105966998</link><description>A blockade at a boat ramp to prevent oysters from entering an open fishing bay, over fears of spreading the algal bloom, leads to the destruction of nearly $70,000 worth of oysters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">312ff1f17c13dc66e91576d81bf0bbca</guid></item><item><title>Woman concussed after south-east Queensland hit by giant hail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/queensland-severe-storm-hail-injuries-damage/105965990</link><description>A Queensland small business owner was hospitalised with concussion after she "copped hailstones to the back of the head" at a community market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">572418a8c561447f36be91311c828d8f</guid></item><item><title>O'Neil welcomes housing progress despite price surge, while Bragg says no to 'NIMBYs'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/oneil-welcomes-housing-progress-liberal-vows-to-ditch-nimby/105967310</link><description>As the government comes under pressure for rising house prices in the first month of its expanded home deposit guarantee, Clare O'Neil welcomes signs of progress on supply.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d615c45d8cbcf9247facb7fb761d60f1</guid></item><item><title>Erin Patterson lodges appeal request in attempt to fight mushroom murder convictions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/erin-patterson-mushroom-murder-appeal/105964152</link><description>The triple-murderer lodges documents in Victoria's Court of Appeal requesting an appeal against her convictions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bae0972bcb7f8344aef07b88621b35c3</guid></item><item><title>Suspected meteor lights up Gippsland afternoon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/suspected-meteor-lights-up-gippsland-afternoon-/105967540</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4750d5c5b5812e12c639053b39fa1700</guid></item><item><title>Sale of WA's Yeeda Pastoral Company near Broome completed, NT abattoir tipped to reopen in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/kimberley-yeeda-pastoral-company-sells-nt-abattoir-may-reopen/105966118</link><description>The sale of Yeeda Pastoral Company, including the Kimberley Meat Company, to TLP4 Australian Holdings is now complete.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a69121df3b6fe37235154873f254a5f</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man avoids jail sentence over part in violent home invasion in ACT Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/act-canberra-man-avoids-jail-sentence-over-violent-home-invasion/105966702</link><description>Xiantao Shang went to an apartment seeking a woman who owed him money. When told she was not there, he and an accomplice forced their way in and assaulted the couple inside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7512d8ad9e3641601dd71f1628c2ea2d</guid></item><item><title>Students with disability isolated, unsupported in ACT public schools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/act-students-disability-isolated-unsupported-public-schools/105967090</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">066a3e3391a8532274683bb8634d750f</guid></item><item><title>Delays plague Melbourne’s Fishermans Bend development</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/delays-plague-melbourne-s-fishermans-bend-development-/105967018</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdcfd8a76292dfe3ddc98d187018549e</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with 10 counts of attempted murder after UK train stabbing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/uk-police-charge-train-stabbing-suspect/105967688</link><description>British prosecutors have charged a 32-year-old man with 10 counts of attempted murder after a mass stabbing on a London-bound train that left multiple passengers injured on Saturday, including two critically.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc5e2ce2990bdfc1fec9afb2bb8ce6e6</guid></item><item><title>Corrections officers placed spit hood on Wayne Hunt, stripped him naked after seizure, coroner hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/wayne-hunt-inquest-darwin-correctional-centre-death-seizure/105964646</link><description>A 56-year-old man was stripped naked, handcuffed and made to wear a spit hood after suffering a seizure inside prison, a coronial inquest into his death has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfbe155202a32163de63ee8ef7180e19</guid></item><item><title>Rosie's owner said despite the incident, she is happy and healthy.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/rosie-video/105966750</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab4077e1658950d04e6065d7dec97aea</guid></item><item><title>Man who shot poodle in Central Coast caravan park robbery sentenced to eight years in prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/man-who-shot-poodle-during-robbery-sentenced-8-years-jail/105951672</link><description>A man who shot a dog in the face during a robbery on the Central Coast of New South Wales has been sentenced to eight years in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6d5c661df1e9fa1fd08a0c0a69f1702</guid></item></channel></rss>