<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 17:43:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>West Coast Council's vehicle fleet left unregistered for a week after 'administrative error'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/west-coast-councils-fleet-of-vehicles-unregistered-for-week/105878164</link><description>Tasmania's West Coast Council has blamed an "administrative error" for a week-long lapse in the registration for its entire fleet of vehicles, compromising insurance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeef7d3ebe41a78cf42f59c21e055f69</guid></item><item><title>Gregory Porter on turning personal pain into powerful music</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/gregory-porter-interview-australia-mister-holland-no-love-dying/105866372</link><description>From the pain of racism to the joy of love, Gregory Porter's voice carries it all with power and purpose.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a61497653a2cd8967d2930635faab18</guid></item><item><title>Spring rains sow seeds of hope among Limestone Coast farmers after months of drought</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/south-east-emerges-from-drought-and-price-slump/105848144</link><description>After months of dust and dry skies, farmers on South Australia's Limestone Coast have welcomed early spring rain and a promising season ahead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2051346c282334589fac6a762170c40e</guid></item><item><title>Mango the muster cat draws attention to western Queensland's ongoing recovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/mango-the-muster-cat-draws-attention-to-western-qld-recovery/105783150</link><description>Raised alongside working dogs, Mango isn't your average feline and comes complete with his own Facebook page, loyal followers and fan mail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63b26a87a12960a7f43cb484f5d058c7</guid></item><item><title>The NT has changed the way it responds to domestic violence. Here's what that means.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/domestic-violence-response-nt-co-responder-model/105862072</link><description>The NT has Australia's highest rates of domestic and family violence, with an intimate partner homicide rate seven times the national average.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07816eca6f1c61f284cb6e5bd7fd185f</guid></item><item><title>Two arrested after Ian Watkins, disgraced former Lostprophets singer, killed in UK prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/two-arrested-ian-watkins-lostprophets-singer-killed-in-uk-prison/105882008</link><description>British police have arrested two men on suspicion of murder after Ian Watkins, the disgraced former Welsh rock band Lostprophets singer who was serving a 35-year jail sentence for child sex offences, was killed in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">223e07d6ac712b874d9d5ff2a114ff36</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous community Bidyadanga hosts From the Desert to the Seaside music festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/bidyadanga-music-festival-from-the-desert-to-the-seaside/105879698</link><description>From the Desert to the Seaside arts and music festival brings Western Australia's largest remote community of Bidyadanga together.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bd7b22727457c514f2c9772ca9393b8</guid></item><item><title>Roads in WA's East Pilbara need millions of dollars in repairs eight months after Cyclone Zelia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/road-cyclone-damage-repairs-pilbara/105857014</link><description>Australia's largest shire says it needs state and federal support to repair roads damaged during a cyclone, which provide a "lifeline" to remote communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d923148ba64c43bdcc00574fb481443</guid></item><item><title>Kelpies for Kids fundraiser at Perth Royal Show raises nearly $50k for sick children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/kelpies-for-kids-runs-for-second-year-raising-money-for-children/105862942</link><description>A working dog auction at the Perth Royal Show raises nearly $50,000 for charity Telethon to support sick children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">181b1baf4cc31df1c53d52860f37c8fe</guid></item><item><title>From The Godfather to The First Wives Club — here are Diane Keaton's best films</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/diane-keaton-movies-woody-allen-where-to-watch/105882070</link><description>With a career beginning in the late 1970s, Diane Keaton would star in more than 100 films and earn several Oscar nods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14d0a28df6e1de7e26d3c91ac4faf413</guid></item><item><title>Record beach patrols in South Australia this summer as life savers help battle algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/sa-life-savers-summer-beach-patrol-algal-bloom/105882102</link><description>A record number of beaches in SA are set to have Surf Life Saving patrols seven days a week this summer, as the state grapples with its toxic algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f070b8801a8bfee9819fde617335d087</guid></item><item><title>Police search for man who disappeared during camping trip with wife in Victoria's east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/vic-missing-camper-troy-milne-sale/105882390</link><description>Police are appealing to the public for help in locating a man who left to pick up supplies while camping with his wife in Gippsland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f4f698753fa2532b5dc1e4ddde87d54</guid></item><item><title>At least 41 dead in Mexico's Veracruz region after landslides, floods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/dozens-dead-in-mexico-veracruz-after-landslides-floods/105882420</link><description>Authorities have attributed the deadly downpours to Tropical Storm Priscilla, formerly a hurricane, and Tropical Storm Raymond, both off the western coast of Mexico.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">849ea547c18416e2aa0d551a85bfe9f1</guid></item><item><title>China accuses US of 'double standards' over new tariffs threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/china-responds-to-us-tariff-threat/105882356</link><description>Donald Trump says he will impose extra levies in response to what he called "extraordinarily aggressive" new Chinese export curbs on rare-earth minerals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47e859acbd6ffddc89eb03d8b3a76cf1</guid></item><item><title>How long can you safely store and reheat leftovers?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/how-long-can-you-safely-store-leftover-food/105844878</link><description>Experts share their tips on how to best store cooked food to save money and avoid food waste.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce0d4f73a17f91c0b31eb05a75824b09</guid></item><item><title>Dockers stun Demons in 5-point AFLW upset, Swans snap losing streak, Saints down Magpies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/aflw-swans-blues-saints-magpies-demons-dockers/105882626</link><description>Fremantle keeps its faint AFLW finals hopes alive with a five-point nail-biter against Melbourne, Sydney arrests a massive form slump against Carlton, while St Kilda notches its fifth consecutive win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df3573f2cc285db9b9466558e3598502</guid></item><item><title>Why the Gaza ceasefire could collapse over coming days</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/why-the-gaza-ceasefire-deal-might-collapse/105880872</link><description>There is any number of ways the ceasefire could fall over — perhaps within days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e18514bb800ce6837a2e1588c9a2da4</guid></item><item><title>Tributes to 'fantastic people' killed in light plane crash near Wollongong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/friends-pay-tribute-to-plane-crash-victims/105882278</link><description>Friends and neighbours of three people killed in a plane crash at Shellharbour Airport in New South Wales say their deaths are a "big loss to the community".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9491c14de3fb06aaf7a44d3a1bc7dd44</guid></item><item><title>PM's XIII hammer Orchids 50-0 in Port Moresby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/pms-xiii-orchids-png/105882744</link><description>In their annual clash, the Prime Minister's XIII outclass the Orchids 50-0 in Port Moresby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8613c3f1ac993b642b76ac402d167fb4</guid></item><item><title>Australia could be left behind on renewables – 12 October 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/as-the-world-shifts-away-from-fossil-fuels,/105882858</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcdc037acd4e65b4d364c1b8b9c3d38d</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Diamonds defeat South Africa's Proteas 65-42 in third netball Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/netball-test-australia-diamonds-defeat-south-africa-proteas/105882776</link><description>Australia warms up for the eagerly anticipated Constellation Cup with a convincing 65-42 victory over South Africa in the third and final Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f1ff5a0a480446ef675b46afe105c3f</guid></item><item><title>Ethan Strange stars as PM's XIII defeat Papua New Guinea 28-10</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/strange-stars-pms-xiii-down-png/105882870</link><description>Ethan Strange underlines his case for Kangaroos selection and Trai Fuller scores four tries in the Prime Minister's XIII 28-10 defeat of Papua New Guinea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eed2497e30235bd850a45f4d7782c62</guid></item><item><title>Australia beats India by three wickets in Women's World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/australia-beats-india-by-three-wickets-in-womens-world-cup/105882054</link><description>Skipper Alyssa Healy scores a super ton and Ellyse Perry sees Australia home in a world-record women's ODI chase to beat India by three wickets in a World Cup thriller.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">793b5b7cd7bd870847524ccb5b3a51ca</guid></item><item><title>Vacherot becomes lowest-ranked ATP Masters winner after defeating his cousin Rinderknech in Shanghai</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/valentin-vacherot-wins-shanghai-masters-atp-tournament/105883038</link><description>He beat his cousin Arthur Rinderknech 4-6, 6-3, 6-3 on Sunday local time to claim the first title of his career after a stunning run from the qualifying rounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb81965abf5ff6abbfd51d7bc8b541f5</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump accused of profiting from presidency as crypto ventures rake in hundreds of millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/trump-president-wealth-family-business-crypto-four-corners/105876782</link><description>Donald Trump's wealth has skyrocketed since his return to the White House nine months ago, leading to accusations that he is profiting from the presidency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a085f22828b5fca9aac9493ad39f159</guid></item><item><title>Australians join race for fusion energy as AI pressure on electricity sector starts to bite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/the-australians-in-the-race-for-fusion-energy/105882230</link><description>The two great technology revolutions of the modern era — artificial intelligence and renewable energy — are colliding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e55bc7ba701556faca8e00198d03be1</guid></item><item><title>Russia expresses 'extreme concern' over US providing Tomahawk missiles to Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/russia-expresses-extreme-concern-over-us-tomahawk-missiles/105883082</link><description>Kyiv and the US are openly floating the idea of providing Ukraine with long-range Tomahawk missiles, in a move Russia says would mark "a very dramatic moment".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3276f5d539ed6330fde6aaa1c0c8618</guid></item><item><title>Uber drivers refusing rides due to guide dog, handler says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/guide-dog-handlers-call-for-harsher-penalties-for-uber-refusals/105754360</link><description>Sarah Maculans says she was refused rides by four Uber drivers within a week due to her guide dog, Sunny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4767c5abe70ec191abca333f88092f6b</guid></item><item><title>Israel 'ready to receive all of our hostages' from Gaza, Netanyahu's office says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/gaza-hostages-to-be-released/105883378</link><description>The final 20 living Israeli hostages in Gaza are set to be released by Hamas in a matter of hours, with preparations by Israeli defence and medical authorities to receive the captives after more than two years hidden away from the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b9a5eb8243f6852bb6c4f770512b950</guid></item><item><title>Koala killed by a car on Appin Road after being hailed a conservation success story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/appin-road-in-sydney-claims-life-rescued-koala-gage/105879322</link><description>Koala deaths on Appin Road are not unusual this time of year, but the fatality of rescued koala Gage is cause for more than the usual frustration and despair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a01be949d5b85d86fa6ff42ba3ea7c6d</guid></item><item><title>Former tennis star Jelena Dokic grapples with complex grief after abusive father Damir's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/jelenadokic-says-abusive-dad-showed-no-remorse/105849988</link><description>Jelena Dokic was abused by her father for years, with no tennis success enough to stop the beatings. She reveals the complex grief of losing a parent who showed no remorse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69cd6af49b40951598418e7e78d42249</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump addresses Israeli Parliament after hostages, Palestinian prisoners freed — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/israel-gaza-hamas-ceasefire-live-updates/105882948</link><description>Hamas has handed over all the remaining living Israeli hostages, as a ceasefire with Hamas continues to hold in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be02b702b81f90b4f983344fa10ab6ad</guid></item><item><title>Wetland ecosystem welcomed at Tasmanian sheep farm after 20-year restoration effort</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/tasmania-saltmarsh-wetland-restoration-on-merino-sheep-farm/105883488</link><description>A sheep farmer has welcomed the restoration of an internationally significant wetland on his property outside of Hobart. The collaboration of a non-profit organisation with landowners, scientists, the Aboriginal community and governments has allowed the return of a vital ecosystem.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1e6acb760d399a693f75e216ea48417</guid></item><item><title>Social media ban will further isolate regional and rural youth, LGBTIQA+ advocates say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/social-media-ban-will-isolate-regional-queer-teens-more/105829530</link><description>LGBTIQA+ advocates are concerned the social media ban will have a significant impact on queer youth in regional and remote areas of Australia. They say there are not enough offline, physical supports for these teens to access when the ban comes into effect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cbc396370d50cfb8a5287d529e393b7</guid></item><item><title>Rebecca, the haunting story adapted into a Hitchcock classic, is now a gripping psychological stage play</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/rebecca-melbourne-theatre-company-hitchcock/105863212</link><description>First dismissed as "Gothic romance" when it was published by Daphne du Maurier in 1938, the haunting tale has evolved into a modern thriller about the expectations placed on women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1669144caa73fcb084b2ee6660bce19d</guid></item><item><title>Isolated storms forecast for Queensland after weekend hail storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/isolated-storms-forecast-for-queensland-this-week/105882378</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology is also predicting a return to regular spring temperatures after a spell of warmer days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78ba8aa6dcb095d740cbead406d25d9e</guid></item><item><title>Michael Pratt, George Cross recipient and former Victorian police officer, dies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/michael-pratt-victorian-police-officer-george-cross-recipient/105883558</link><description>Former Victoria Police officer Michael Pratt has been remembered for his bravery when he confronted three armed bank robbers in Melbourne in 1978.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">387d0a1122baa4ab5a5052fc5f8da703</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar's President Andry Rajoelina says student protesters are attempting a coup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/madagascar-president-claims-coup-attempt-underway/105883466</link><description>Troops from an elite unit of the country's military are urging fellow soldiers to disobey orders and back student protesters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f041025445012537603be910fd6490a</guid></item><item><title>WA lawyers write to attorney-general calling for in-person court hearings to return to remote Balgo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/kimberley-based-lawyers-struggling-to-support-balgo-residents/105866646</link><description>With in-person court hearings suspended and video links cancelled, lawyers are struggling to ensure access to justice for the remote community of Balgo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08e509522e73a26e49192e99129f2347</guid></item><item><title>Climate Integrity says 'distorted research' behind government policy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/climate-integrity-accc-to-investigate-gas-lobby-ey-modelling/105866988</link><description>Advocacy group Climate Integrity has accused the gas industry of using "distorted research", produced by the accounting firm EY, to influence the Australian government's Future Gas Strategy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28322136f22de6e61de34a7e4e872c4b</guid></item><item><title>Brad Pettitt questions WA Labor's commitment to increasing Perth's tree canopy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/brad-pettitt-questions-wa-labors-commitment-to/105879012</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74296c695f705429cfd19d9d6685f4d5</guid></item><item><title>Fresh doubts over WA Labor election commitments to boost Perth’s tree canopy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/wa-tree-canopy-election-promise-walked-back/105865416</link><description>The WA government is facing renewed questions over its plans to boost Perth's tree cover, with experts saying current funding will not come close to delivering on Labor's election promises.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">755ddb616df68a32d5fd28309f6717e9</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, day six recap: Zach Merrett, Charlie Curnow and Christian Petracca remain in limbo seeking moves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/afl-trade-period-day-six-live-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca/105883736</link><description>Zach Merrett is one of a number of former All-Australians currently in limbo as West Coast continues to wheel and deal after another wooden spoon and Port Adelaide secures a midfielder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b30b12b2a3a7724532b5ba22d8a1df3b</guid></item><item><title>Mount Magnet Shire councillor Ian Black suspended after no apology for defamatory notice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/mount-magnet-shire-deputy-suspended-after-defamatory-notice/105880958</link><description>Mount Magnet Shire deputy president Ian Black is suspended after failing to apologise for posting a defamatory notice about staff to a public noticeboard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56ad1f0b0ee68c823f21a856debc307a</guid></item><item><title>Committee formally recommends NT government adopt voluntary assisted dying</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/nt-government-voluntary-assisted-dying-report-recommendation/105515296</link><description>On the verandah of their Darwin home, Judy Dent held her husband's hand as he became the first person in the world to die through legally accessible voluntary assisted dying. That world-first would not be possible in the Northern Territory today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3da225f565d839bdf449bf4b26951d4</guid></item><item><title>Australian cricket captain Pat Cummins says he is 'probably unlikely' to play in first Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/pat-cummins-unlikely-to-play-first-ashes-test/105883832</link><description>Pat Cummins all but rules himself out of the first Ashes Test, saying he is still a way short of completing his condensed recovery schedule from a back injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b1d8292aabc1b91a7c4ac0cc55cdb3a</guid></item><item><title>Fox Resources collapses, but fight against coal exploration in Bundaberg food bowl continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/fox-resources-collapse-bundaberg-coal-mine-exploration/105884008</link><description>Exploration company Fox Resources has gone into administration, but the community that successfully fought off its mining advances vows to keep fighting to cancel the tenement altogether.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bfdc45a674d8408b12424221c8e22b2</guid></item><item><title>World's biggest light installation to illuminate landscapes of Albany, WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/biggest-light-installation-ever-on-earth-planned-for-albany/105866412</link><description>A light installation, projected onto King George Sound in Albany, will be the largest ever created.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0c3fad2d619ba1d36ef0034dc9d4ec0</guid></item><item><title>Treasurer announces rework of stalled superannuation tax increase plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/treasurer-announces-rework-of-stalled-super-tax-increase/105884568</link><description>The government has bowed to pressure on its superannuation tax policy, one of the few revenue-raising measures it had promised, two years on from when it was first announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6423e004d64ee9090f2694aa27bcd949</guid></item><item><title>Travel and dining vouchers on offer in SA's algal bloom summer plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/summer-algal-vouchers-south-australia/105883636</link><description>Some travellers to South Australia's coast over summer will be able to access $500 accommodation vouchers and $50 cashback on their meal, under a state and federal government plan to stimulate tourism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c47d767109a71d2102d3268c1f6df24</guid></item><item><title>Video games could fall under the social media ban, researchers say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/video-games-could-fall-under-social-media-ban-researchers-say/105859842</link><description>Online video games are excluded from the social media ban, but digital media researchers say the definitions are too broadly defined and games could yet be included.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b0b6fa140b851f58a53917e93936fe0</guid></item><item><title>Eugowra flood inquest told official information was not accurate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/eugowra-flood-inquest-hears-official-information-was-inaccurate/105876674</link><description>A coronial inquest is told residents and emergency responders got inaccurate information from the Bureau of Meteorology (BOM) and Water NSW during a devastating flood that claimed two lives in the NSW town of Eugowra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cc7439df585114af7440bc0a3a659e8</guid></item><item><title>Carter Gordon rushed back into Wallabies squad after quitting NRL's Titans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/rugby-australia-queensland-reds-carter-gordon-quits-nrl-titans/105884978</link><description>The Wallabies waste no time in welcoming back fly half Carter Gordon to rugby union, less than two hours after it was announced he was leaving the NRL.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3aa32c62a9f0aa84542aa4fe59849c01</guid></item><item><title>How to tell if your Qantas personal data has hit the dark web and what you can do if it has</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/qantas-cyber-hack-has-my-data-been-leaked-what-should-i-do/105884604</link><description>Hackers have released Qantas customer data onto the dark web. Here's what experts say to look out for if you think your personal data may be caught up in the leak and what actions you can take.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0686253e2a0f07a77f7a19d16ef3924b</guid></item><item><title>Pink Elephants report highlights care gaps for rural women experiencing miscarriages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/pink-elephants-miscarriage-report-care-gaps-remote-rural-women/105869210</link><description>Pregnancy loss is a lottery determined by location, according to a report that has sparked calls for the federal government improve care for women who experience miscarriage in regional and rural communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd359295e0f7d58eb51fd7c2a78c928d</guid></item><item><title>GrainCorp settles class action over noise and odour pollution in Numurkah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/graincorp-settles-class-action-over-pollution-in-numurkah/105884138</link><description>The class action was brought by a northern Victorian man who alleged that noise and odour pollution from a GrainCorp factory affected his health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4b7709cd3095f489f46b33d3cdcb673</guid></item><item><title>Peter Damjanovic pleads guilty to Tiffany Woodley's murder in Bedford home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/peter-damjanovic-pleads-guilty-to-bedford-tiffany-woodley-murder/105884738</link><description>Peter Damjanovic changes his plea at the last minute and pleads guilty to murdering his former partner Tiffany Woodley at her home in Bedford two years ago. WARNING: Indigenous readers are advised this story contains photos of someone who has died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27ba88199b3ea947698defbfa9cc5a78</guid></item><item><title>Patients of a Mortdale dentist practice urged to get tested for blood-borne viruses including HIV</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/blood-borne-virus-risk-to-patients-of-mortdale-dentist/105885230</link><description>Safuan Hasic, also known as Steven Hasic, has been barred from practising after breaching infection control standards at his Mortdale dentistry practice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b15b2836f126265f7a5c59c923e63cae</guid></item><item><title>What to do if your mortgage payments haven't gone down despite an RBA rate cut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/how-to-lower-mortgage-repayments-after-rba-interest-rate-cut/105844258</link><description>You might assume home loan repayments will automatically reduce when an interest rate cut is passed on, but this isn’t always the case. Here's how to check.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9321ceed8438c8f5233f33dc1bbcc97</guid></item><item><title>Israelis gather in Hostage Square ahead of hostage release</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/israelis-gather-in-hostage-square-ahead-of-hostage/105885492</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9db2cc122e3575d82a435b2c099eb850</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian MP Craig Garland temporarily disqualified from driving over drug driving charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/mp-craig-garland-sentenced-for-drug-driving-charge/105773362</link><description>Independent MP Craig Garland applied in court for a restricted license, saying it would be a "terrible situation" if he wasn't able to attend parliamentary sitting weeks in Hobart due to the ban after being found guilty of drug driving.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c66d699bcd04007a1aae088275012df</guid></item><item><title>Israeli military releases video of reception area for hostages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/israeli-military-releases-video-of-reception-area/105885582</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a4692af0e06201820a12ff6e7a1cbd7</guid></item><item><title>Here's how Labor's revised super proposal would work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/labor-super-tax-changes-explained/105885434</link><description>Every prominent criticism of the tax has been addressed, with the result that it will apply to fewer people and raise less money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e8eac54b40c708087b8083935640a86</guid></item><item><title>Major review of medical scans at Caboolture Hospital to include 3,500 more patients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/caboolture-hospital-medical-scan-review-broadened/105884950</link><description>Thousands more patients have been caught up in a bungle involving medical scans not being reviewed by doctors at a major south-east Queensland hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8bef54c1a408a99f99190c88af1abba</guid></item><item><title>Pheobe Bishop accused Kieren Daniel Mittelheuser misses court due to medical episode</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/pheobe-bishop-accused-kieren-daniel-mittelheuser-misses-court/105884432</link><description>A medical episode has prevented Kieren Daniel Mittelheuser from appearing in court to face charges of accessory after the fact to murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01df134fd6e5027db2b7c483ec14d8f9</guid></item><item><title>Trump says Netanyahu was "right guy at right time" for Gaza deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/trump-says-netanyahu-was-right-guy-at-right-time/105885748</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db23f0a5c074faa2c47ac9d11317a68e</guid></item><item><title>Jesse Southwell signs with Broncos amid fears of lopsided NRLW competition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/nrlw-jesse-southwell-signs-with-broncos-after-leaving-knights/105885604</link><description>NSW State of Origin halfback Jesse Southwell's two-year deal with the Brisbane Broncos may add to the debate about the NRLW's competitiveness since it expanded to 12 teams.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abe905c2182f063b37016dc4e7f38ab5</guid></item><item><title>Lidia Thorpe's 'burn down Parliament House' remark faces AFP probe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/afp-investigating-lidia-thorpe-burn-down-parliament-house/105885602</link><description>The Australian Federal Police has issued a rare statement confirming it is investigating whether independent senator Lidia Thorpe broke any laws by saying she was prepared to "burn down Parliament House" in support of Palestinians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2fccb71564f1bd7edfc068317149745</guid></item><item><title>Jason Thomas King pleads not guilty to murdering landlord Susan Walker on the Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/jason-thomas-king-pleads-not-guilty-to-murdering-landlord/105885548</link><description>Jason Thomas King is charged with 74-year-old Susan Walker's murder, and pleaded not guilty at the beginning of a Supreme Court trial in Brisbane on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7698ff5a772eef758d0bfa5979b9ee48</guid></item><item><title>Former teacher Rodney Neville Watkins guilty of sexually abusing boys in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/teacher-rodney-neville-watkins-sex-abuse-trial-verdict/105874798</link><description>A former teacher is found guilty of sexually abusing primary school-aged boys in Perth, and one on Rottnest Island, in the 1970s in 1980s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">699b38068724bae2768d7a3807fbfbae</guid></item><item><title>Hamas releases all remaining Israeli hostages in Gaza, IDF confirms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/hamas-releases-all-remaining-israeli-hostages-in-gaza/105885332</link><description>Israel says Hamas has handed over all 20 living hostages in the first phase of the Israel-Gaza ceasefire agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1da4a5a9ff5c0b24b017021965f0b640</guid></item><item><title>Dolphin calf rescued after spending weeks tangled in fishing line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/dolphin-calf-rescued-from-fishing-line-at-forster/105884112</link><description>Marine rescuers issue an urgent plea for people to responsibly dispose of fishing gear after freeing a dolphin calf from a fishing line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90d0d7d157b2b4ce3c86f1c7a19eb88c</guid></item><item><title>Shire of Coolgardie avoids suspension following 'serious concern' over financial management</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/shire-of-coolgardie-avoids-suspension-after-show-cause-notice/105884860</link><description>A debt-laden shire in WA's Goldfields has avoided being suspended over mismanagement allegations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16e5e2b6e5725473f69cc02f3d0213ae</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Diamonds mindful they need to lift against New Zealand's Silver Ferns in Constellation Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/constellation-cup-australia-new-zealand-diamonds-silver-ferns/105885876</link><description>Despite the comfortable series win over South Africa, Australia is mindful it will need to step up a gear in the Constellation Cup against New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5fb5d579d17d83c75a2e69cee809c80</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of Israelis gather at Hostages Square</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/thousands-of-israelis-gather-at-hostages-square,/105886086</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f850a0bac366588a46b981577479166c</guid></item><item><title>Tatiana Dokhotaru told triple-0 her ex-partner was 'trying to kill' her before alleged murder, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/danny-zayat-trial-for-alleged-murder-tatiana-dokhotaru-liverpool/105885166</link><description>Danny Zayat has pleaded not guilty over the alleged murder of his former partner Tatiana Dokhotaru on May 26, 2023, in a high-rise complex in Sydney's south-west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97587d3d724a31ef37090e00aaebbacd</guid></item><item><title>Court hears of 'irreparable damage' inflicted by former Canberra academic awaiting sentencing for rape</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/victim-irreparable-damage-inflicted-by-convicted-rapist-canberra/105884230</link><description>Prosecutors have called for the man to be jailed for a significant period of time after he was found guilty of raping two women by an ACT Supreme Court jury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e73a6eedd6c7c07d93b6a9510cb21e11</guid></item><item><title>Convoy of Red Cross buses drive through devastated Gaza cityscape</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/convoy-of-red-cross-buses-drive-through-devastated/105886166</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e4a8f198fb10cee7f84442e510ad9a6</guid></item><item><title>Woodside North West Shelf gas project extension challenged in Federal Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/federal-court-appeals-over-woodside-north-west-shelf-extension/105884752</link><description>Two separate appeals are launched in the Federal Court in a bid to overturn Environment Minister Murray Watt's approval of Woodside's gas hub extension on the North West Shelf.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">342bee27bf9dff6d11dddd935c41d8df</guid></item><item><title>SA Premier says algal bloom is not 'toxic', despite word appearing in official government advice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/algal-bloom-not-toxic-sa-premier-says/105884118</link><description>South Australia's Premier has questioned the use of the word "toxic" to describe the state's ongoing algal bloom, despite the word being used in government advice and by scientists researching it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0743c8445b475273de4ae2bd594c0830</guid></item><item><title>John Torney's mother gives evidence in his manslaughter committal hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/john-torney-committal-hearing-emma-bates/105883888</link><description>John Torney's committal hearing begins as his mother tells the court she was the one who called police to check on the woman before her body was found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27f97cc7b1bc58b7979769f5ce683c9f</guid></item><item><title>Red Cross vehicles carrying hostages leave Gaza City</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/red-cross-vehicles-carrying-hostages-leave-gaza/105886272</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7abe747fbd04a6b6c29d3d125b6ca2d4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump touches down in Israel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/donald-trump-touches-down-in-israel/105886378</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2da0fd6431100f72b5e26c2aefa69995</guid></item><item><title>Coronial inquest into death in custody of Dictor Dongrin begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/dictor-dongrin-coronial-inquest/105881152</link><description>A coronial inquest has heard that a 29-year-old man was left for 21 hours without physical observation despite telling staff he had a history of suffering seizures while withdrawing from alcohol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8a0dcfc06d0a8b925f8dddcae2cfd13</guid></item><item><title>Who's in and who's out in Sussan Ley's new shadow cabinet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/shadow-cabinet-reshuffle-federal-politics-ley-hastie-duniam/105886202</link><description>The changes follow two high-profile departures from shadow cabinet within a month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04f8fd366d0a2f3ed19841529ba4629a</guid></item><item><title>Inside Victoria's escalating crime wave, where a car is reported stolen to insurers every 44 minutes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/victoria-carjacking-rises-as-families-left-on-edge/105885482</link><description>A rise in car theft and carjackings in this state has also seen parents left terrorised as cars are taken with their children inside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1d8b1d3339f8fa66e6e20ad33fdcab3</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance for Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/monday-finance-for-alan-kohler/105887926</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">059ac3c8d842823d67aab6854a8417bb</guid></item><item><title>Money wiped from alleged vandals' bill over Bendigo artefact damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/bendigo-dragon-museum-alleged-vandals-damage-bill-reduced/105885912</link><description>Lawyers for a couple accused of vandalising significant artefacts say the damage caused by sprinkling vegetable oil was unintentional and part of a "blessing".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55d7778c273f3b330ec42c4727ff697b</guid></item><item><title>ACT family violence victims 'waiting 3 or 4 days' for help, inquiry hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/act-family-violence/105886158</link><description>A levy meant to improve support for victims of family violence in the ACT has come under scrutiny in an inquiry, which has heard concerns about how funds are managed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0953fe9b1b0c85e2488c739e87e4df7b</guid></item><item><title>New testimony seeks to shed light on mysterious death of Mark Haines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/mark-haines-inquest-returns-for-fifth-week-of-hearings/105134566</link><description>An inquest has heard evidence contradicting the story told by a driver whose crashed car was found near the body of Mark Anthony Haines almost four decades ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0254cc5f1992da32e9ae401f0ebbfed7</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump writes a message upon arrival at Israel's Knesset</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/donald-trump-writes-a-message-upon-arrival-at/105886564</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b98ce558df901aa34da9e041a08f54b3</guid></item><item><title>Frustration mounts among Qantas customers as personal data released on dark web</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/frustration-mounts-among-qantas-customers-over-data-breach/105885312</link><description>The airline's customers voice their concerns and disappointment after cybercriminals release their personal data on the dark web.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b231e8012746670f061284735b7d6e0</guid></item><item><title>Families of Israeli hostages prepare to be reunited with their loved ones</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/families-of-israeli-hostages-prepare-to-be/105886614</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d55e8a434f5bffabf15e1e0ef6096349</guid></item><item><title>Government overhauls its proposed superannuation changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/government-overhauls-its-proposed-superannuation/105886646</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7832422b564ea7c9e914c9d44a5a76f6</guid></item><item><title>Family of hit and run victim call for justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/family-of-hit-and-run-victim-call-for-justice/105886666</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">023224101da80413f1e83fd4566ab93f</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian prisoners return to West Bank</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/palestinian-prisoners-return-to-west-bank/105886688</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edc1c510491d57e93a9f4e3d2901fcc6</guid></item><item><title>Israeli Knesset greets Donald Trump with standing ovation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/israeli-knesset-greets-donald-trump-with-standing/105886700</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bfffb3b35f2e8af404061c39f16a163</guid></item><item><title>Queensland council loses $2 million in alleged international fraud incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/queensland-council-alleged-victim-international-fraud/105886682</link><description>Noosa Council alleges it was targeted by "international criminal gangs" in December last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a81b0adf1072bdc643391700c8d3dc7</guid></item><item><title>Released Israeli hostages wave at crowds as they arrive at hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/released-israeli-hostages-arrive-at-hospital/105886776</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">818105ab787786e2c78fa5d4f2be0c23</guid></item><item><title>Israeli hostages reunite with their loved ones</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/israeli-hostages-reunite-with-their-loved-ones/105886836</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02d664b5e02fdd144286753ad07b004f</guid></item><item><title>Trio win Nobel economics prize for work on innovation, growth and 'creative destruction'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/trio-win-nobel-economics-prize-for-work-on-innovation-growth-and/105886992</link><description>Joel Mokyr, Philippe Aghion and Peter Howitt have won the 2025 Nobel economics prize for their work on how innovation and the forces of "creative destruction" can drive economic growth and lift living standards across the globe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8781524bde9665adaee30cdbfbb4cd0</guid></item><item><title>Plumbers charge 'pain tax' as inspector shortage holds up Hobart planning approvals, frustrates tradies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/plumbers-charge-pain-tax-for-hobart-city-council-jobs/105884286</link><description>Tasmanian plumbers openly admit to inflating prices and charging up to 30 per cent extra on jobs in the Hobart City Council area, as "frustrating" red tape adds lengthy approval delays and costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5ec2d6a172fe15a9e14822133cdeded</guid></item><item><title>Jared Kushner's ties to the Middle East go far beyond diplomacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/jared-kushner-diplomacy-investment-middle-east-real-estate/105862606</link><description>The US president's son-in-law had little diplomatic or successful investment management experience before helping to broker the Gaza ceasefire deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e80b125b4a710b1ae8957f6fa131ce2c</guid></item><item><title>Corporate watchdog slams superannuation funds on 'customer service', communications with retirees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/corporate-watchdog-asic-slams-super-funds-customer-service/105885474</link><description>ASIC's review of 12 super funds collectively responsible for more $1.2 trillion in member assets finds they are failing in customer service and communications, and may not be giving members information to make informed retirement decisions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">780cd3ed2fb645b79ac84aec52bde554</guid></item><item><title>'We have won': Trump hails ceasefire deal in address to Knesset</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/we-have-won-trump-hails-ceasefire-deal-in-knesset-speech/105887354</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4d4881a538f91f6662d1801c4e424ad</guid></item><item><title>Trump heralds 'new beginning' for Middle East</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/trump-heralds-in-new-beginning-for-middle-east/105887360</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abcba0de3ca7736d6aaa21008fbb6016</guid></item><item><title>Australia's best surf lifesaving atheletes begin Iron Series with a re-imagined Gold Coast classic, Coolangatta Gold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/iron-series-begins-new-season-with-round-one-coolangatta-gold/105806780</link><description>The Coolangatta Gold may have been trimmed down, but the quality of the field sets up an exciting opening round of the 2025/26 Iron Series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae9a7bae31745eead6ca9197c9ad710c</guid></item><item><title>England provides the blueprint for 2029 Women's Rugby World Cup in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/rugby-world-cup-women-england-wallaroos/105874404</link><description>The recently concluded Women's Rugby World Cup in England took the game to new heights. But, as Alicia Lucas writes, Australia needs to take big strides to ensure its hosting of the tournament in 2029 continues to raise the bar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b19337aaae0b20b96cc6cd07fe6cffb7</guid></item><item><title>US and Arab countries sign deal throwing support behind Gaza ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/israel-gaza-ceasefire-us-trump-deal-arab-countries/105887224</link><description>The deal comes as one group representing hostages accuses Hamas of breaching aspects of the ceasefire agreement, with the remains of 24 hostages yet to be returned to Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ec5c2bc5161b8e45516c12dc73fa2f2</guid></item><item><title>Modelling shows gas project emissions will cause hundreds of heat-related deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/fossil-fuel-climate-impact-study-models-heatwave-deaths/105870098</link><description>Fossil fuel companies and governments argue it's not possible to link climate impacts to specific projects, but Australian researchers have done the numbers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2d5647990e49e0294d580166c094c07</guid></item><item><title>Emotional reunions during hostage-prisoner exchange between Israel, Hamas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/emotional-reunions-during-hostage-prisoner-exchange/105887370</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd24f63c836bfe278cba517857117ed8</guid></item><item><title>Why Santos is behind your soaring electricity and mortgage costs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/why-santos-is-behind-your-soaring-electricity-and-mortgage-costs/105885202</link><description>It was a primary force behind Australia’s inflationary surge, it’s forced businesses either to the wall or to shift offshore, undermined national industry policy and resulted in the loss of countless thousands of jobs. And it all hinged on one disastrous decision in an Adelaide boardroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">103585cee22276b5b682cf9cc4c3ec88</guid></item><item><title>Outback golf tournament brings together 150 players to support Royal Flying Doctor Service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/north-moolooloo-station-golf-classic-rfds-fundraiser/105885132</link><description>There are no manicured greens in sight, but this golf tournament brings more than 150 players to an outback sheep station to raise funds for the Royal Flying Doctor Service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba5593cb8043d656cd820fd84f44f406</guid></item><item><title>Advocates call for better measure of poverty, saying Australia's approach falls short</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/calls-to-measure-how-many-australians-live-in-poverty/105862926</link><description>We get detailed measurements of population, participation and productivity. Advocates want to add a fourth "p" — poverty — so we can understand our economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09b9c5ac7057df2484a85462c70d727f</guid></item><item><title>Hamas returns some bodies of hostages to Israel as Trump hails peace — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/israel-gaza-hamas-ceasefire-october-14/105886534</link><description>Israel's military says Hamas has returned the bodies of four hostages from Gaza, with the remains of 24 others yet to be returned — as it happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83968a4078992a41c9ee341aa9aa93a8</guid></item><item><title>The political theatre of Donald Trump's Middle East trip masks glaring questions about the peace plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/donald-trump-motivations-for-gaza-peace-deal-crucial-for-future/105884836</link><description>Donald Trump's unconventional and often haphazard approach to diplomacy means there are countless questions about what has driven him to date, and what might determine whether he stays engaged in the Middle East peace process in the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d711918a0f392be9269eff374938c3b</guid></item><item><title>Youth crime rates in the bush still high as leaders look for solutions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/inquiry-searches-for-solutions-to-regional-youth-crime/105839372</link><description>Official figures show youth crime is decreasing across NSW, but that does not ring true in some rural communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">123913d2e8ea9f90bf4ab88828346b14</guid></item><item><title>Cape Verde qualifies for 2026 FIFA World Cup in United States, Canada and Mexico</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/cape-verde-qualifies-for-2026-fifa-world-cup/105887380</link><description>Cape Verde will play in the men's FIFA World Cup for the first time after beating Eswatini 3-0 to win its group in African qualifying for the 2026 showpiece.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a68c49530029934617e84ae8ecd3b5f</guid></item><item><title>Convoy carrying hostage bodies return to Israel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/convoy-carrying-hostage-bodies-return-to-israel/105887450</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34235d76fbbef52e55e47c303b184317</guid></item><item><title>Taskforce launched as search for Gus expands in SA's mid-north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/search-for-gus-focuses-on-expanded-area-in-outback-sa/105886332</link><description>As SA Police and the Australian Defence Force resume their search for missing four-year-old Gus in South Australia's arid mid-north, authorities have announced a new taskforce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd0d718ad9ecf977e8a8303c21f43125</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with arson over Glen Waverley and Mount Waverley sporting club fires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/man-charged-after-glen-waverley-mount-waverley-sports-club-fires/105887406</link><description>A man is charged with setting two community sports clubhouses on fire in Melbourne's south-east this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f28063a642dd9f7ea376afa4dbaae98</guid></item><item><title>After 738 days, Israelis share mixed emotions as hostages are released from Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/israelis-shared-mixed-emotions-in-hostage-square/105887218</link><description>Israelis gather to watch a historic day unfold as hostages held for two years are finally set free.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf68b9df5ada430b879c7ac27176cd9a</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Chalmers, Keating spoke 'half a dozen times' ahead of super U-turn — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/federal-politics-live-blog-oct-14/105886082</link><description>Treasurer Jim Chalmers confirms he spoke with former prime minister Paul Keating last week ahead of the government's U-turn on superannuation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3c45ced41e4a31dd0fefa6b1b2aacf3</guid></item><item><title>Roblox wants exemption from social media ban despite evidence of predators targeting children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/social-media-ban-roblox-predators-access-online-gaming-platform/105884322</link><description>Experts warn Roblox has a predator problem, amid reports Australian children are being exposed to a range of disturbing experiences on the platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f02d3f9a9d7f28e496b39c07746ced7</guid></item><item><title>NT government accused of 'turning a blind eye' to gas company's alleged environmental breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/alleged-environmental-law-breach-nt-beetaloo-basin-gas-company/105854186</link><description>A gas company operating in the Northern Territory has been accused of breaching environmental laws by an NT government department, which decided against prosecution in favour of a formal letter encouraging "behaviour change".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c52c0271aad0cf9daffab8391d37b37</guid></item><item><title>How to help kids prepare for music exams and competitions and manage performance anxiety</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/music-exam-competition-manage-performance-anxiety/105873254</link><description>Music exams and competitions aren't easy, but our experts have some tips to make the process as stress-free as possible, including managing performance anxiety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ce54e25b952b97ee1ce5b2b5c2b6f1c</guid></item><item><title>ASX inches higher, RBA minutes suggest one or no more rate cuts likely — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/asx-markets-business-live-news-14-oct/105887484</link><description>The ASX closed slightly higher, and RBA board minutes suggested one or no more rate cuts are likely. Catch up on the day's economic and business news on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56518202a772518c1c9efb6df83160d1</guid></item><item><title>Chalmers wielded the axe on his super tax, but the PM's fingerprints were obvious</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/chalmers-retreat-on-super-tax-had-prime-minister-behind-it/105886080</link><description>The treasurer has never been afraid to venture beyond his prime minister with his tax reform ambitions, but on superannuation, he has been pulled into line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4152bdb0b9ceed06054c180a355d7942</guid></item><item><title>Fresh doubts over plans to boost Perth's tree canopy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/fresh-doubts-over-plan-for-perth-tree-canopy/105886692</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eeff764a51281b1a24aecd32b078248f</guid></item><item><title>Six NRL players named in England rugby league Ashes sqaud, Man of Steel winner not selected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/six-nrl-players-named-in-england-rugby-league-ashes-sqaud/105887552</link><description>Six NRL players are in the England rugby league squad for the upcoming Ashes series against Australia, but there's no room for the most consistent player of the Super League season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78de8086dd1c502899a17e878f7658b2</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, day seven recap: Zach Merrett, Charlie Curnow and Christian Petracca waiting for deals, Brayden Fiorini goes to Bombers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/afl-trade-period-day-seven-live-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca/105886172</link><description>The big three of Zach Merrett, Charlie Curnow and Christian Petracca remain in limbo with one day left in the trade period, with Brayden Fiorini going from Gold Coast to Essendon the main move of the day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a857679f1703f600b143ca6bda2e17c5</guid></item><item><title>Generator trial to address mobile phone tower outages during WA emergencies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/mobile-phone-power-outages-during-emergencies-generator-trial-wa/105835910</link><description>Rural communities battling power cuts to mobile towers during natural disasters are being offered a temporary solution with a trial of community-operated generators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4ff5e0410778619fa307c454be94887</guid></item><item><title>Alexei Popyrin defeated in ATP Tour Stockholm Open by American Sebastian Korda</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/alexei-popyrin-defeated-in-atp-tour-stockholm-open/105887672</link><description>Alexei Popyrin's ATP Tour return has ended with defeat as Australia's second-highest-ranked men's player returns following a back injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">886c345c6250bdf03fcbbc00174f57fb</guid></item><item><title>Linda Reynolds launches bankruptcy proceedings against Brittany Higgins after defamation win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/brittany-higgins-faces-bankruptcy-proceedings-linda-reynolds/105887676</link><description>Former senator Linda Reynolds files a creditor's petition in the Federal Court against her ex-staffer, Brittany Higgins, as she tries to recover damages awarded to her for defamation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73d83a01246222ea001cb02d5ce0a719</guid></item><item><title>Midnight Oil fans rally to keep Rob Hirst's drum kit 'in public hands' at charity auction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/midnight-oil-fans-secure-rob-hirsts-drum-kit-at-charity-auction/105887566</link><description>Midnight Oil drummer Rob Hirst auctions off the kit, which he has had since 1979, saying he can no longer play it because of his battle with pancreatic cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4b1a250f2c50ae072e79e344e2dc5fa</guid></item><item><title>Plans for national art gallery in Alice Springs scrapped after government rift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/nt-aboriginal-and-torres-strait-islander-art-alice-springs/105887842</link><description>The Northern Territory government scraps controversial plans to build the Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Art Gallery of Australia in Alice Springs after nine years of back and forth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">218dcceb9a72a6805cd42afc69e27584</guid></item><item><title>Search underway in icy conditions for bushwalker Daryl Fong in Tasmania's Mt Field National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/bushwalker-missing-in-mt-field-national-park-tasmania/105887818</link><description>A search is underway for a Tasmanian man in Mount Field National Park in challenging, snowy conditions after his last contact on Sunday morning said he would seek shelter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc1077490070d9be093a67a29c0fcfa7</guid></item><item><title>Endangered powerful owl among 'sound bath' of bird calls captured by recordings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/powerful-owls-recorded-for-bird-sound-bath/105884696</link><description>Powerful owls prey on possums, and even koalas, but local bird watchers are excited by the discovery of new pairs in South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aff96e27d81dfb12e8372bce926a4ef6</guid></item><item><title>Delays forecast for solar panels, batteries amid soaring demand, but advocates say gaps in access remain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/queensland-energy-road-map-solar-reaction-industry/105885848</link><description>The Queensland government unveiled its energy road map last week, introducing a new solar rebate scheme. The industry says similar subsidies mean demand is already surging.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a14f84a7696915258df284321e0d768</guid></item><item><title>When to share the news of a pregnancy with your employer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/when-to-share-the-news-of-a-pregnancy-with-your-employer/105865350</link><description>Experts on the rules around when you need to inform your employer if you’re planning to take parental leave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdd7ceffb7b18af44c36f8079e6d9e03</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar's president flees country on French plane amid student protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/madagascar-president-andry-rajoelina-flees-country/105888408</link><description>Andry Rajoelina flees the country amid widespread protests that saw an elite military unit join demonstrators in opposing the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d597776aaaad785146891e7f721ca00</guid></item><item><title>Australia call up Josh Philippe and Matt Kuhnemann for ODI against India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/australia-call-up-josh-philippe-and-matt-kuhnemann/105888558</link><description>Josh Philippe is set to play his first ODI for Australia in four years, after Josh Inglis failed to recover from his calf strain in time for the series opener against India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8aab5eb6aeaedbaf7d2b9dcae9ce4d44</guid></item><item><title>Dave Hughes back in hospital with lung issues six weeks after AFL Legends match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/dave-hughes-hospital-again-afl-legends-game/105888798</link><description>Comedian Dave Hughes has returned to hospital, six weeks after suffering five broken ribs and a punctured lung in the AFL's Legends game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93a8308251a6c7103b1ea07bf46519bf</guid></item><item><title>Governments announce full details of $102.5m algal bloom summer plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/sa-summer-plan-announced-state-algal-bloom/105887504</link><description>Large scale reef restoration, new real-time water monitoring and a $1 million trial of "AI-powered submersible cytobots" are part of a $102.5 million government algal bloom program to ensure "South Australians can enjoy their summer".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c633c7e72d90c62a5362f4c5d30fb14d</guid></item><item><title>The Hobart Clinic offered government funding lifeline to stay open for six months</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/hobart-clinic-offered-funding-lifeline-government/105871126</link><description>A southern Tasmanian private mental health clinic will remain open for at least six months after securing $2 million in government funding while it explores a new business model.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35cc0c7b5d6ca1be32aa4ab4247addc4</guid></item><item><title>Children under 16 will soon be banned from social media — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/under-16s-social-media-ban-explored-in-digital-dilemma-blog/105884486</link><description>From December, children under 16 will be blocked from accessing social media. Take a look back at our live coverage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87501dff82daeea05a09dc513bd643ab</guid></item><item><title>Mount Buffalo National Park reopens as search for alleged gunman Dezi Freeman continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/mount-buffalo-national-park-partially-reopens-freeman-search/105888550</link><description>Victoria Police says its search for alleged gunman Dezi Freeman will continue as the Mount Buffalo National Park partially reopens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0df5fd73ab4cb55f61d65dbab1ec7cb6</guid></item><item><title>Homicide detectives investigate discovery of man's body in Armidale</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/homicide-detectives-investigate-suspicious-death-in-armidale/105888230</link><description>Police are eager to speak to a second man who was taken to hospital, after the body of a man believed to be in his 70s was found at a home on the NSW northern tablelands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bb60e25f7c21b566ee4cbadd58042fe</guid></item><item><title>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese's mobile phone number made available online</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/anthony-albanese-mobile-phone-number-available-online/105889284</link><description>Sussan Ley and other prominent Australians are among those whose details have also been made available on a US-based website.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8575617fd69a49f6fd196271d2ecccdb</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Antarctic icebreaker RSV Nuyina 'makes contact with ocean floor' near remote Heard Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/icebreaker-nuyina-scrapes-ocean-floor-near-heard-island/105888904</link><description>Antarctic icebreaker RSV Nuyina has headed to deeper waters off remote Heard Island in the Southern Ocean while assessments are undertaken to see if the hull has suffered any damage after scraping the ocean floor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebfe574522a440336bd83f4b4bd7906e</guid></item><item><title>Paul Kelly on the songs that inspire him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/paul-kelly-influences-archie-roach-go-betweens/105840822</link><description>As the 70-year-old songwriter prepares his 30th album, he talks about the music that has driven him creatively.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeb74292394ee123f769e46166b7fd50</guid></item><item><title>Former Collingwood coach Nathan Buckley to join Geelong as assistant coach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/nathan-buckley-moves-back-into-coaching-with-surprise-cats-role/105889810</link><description>Nathan Buckley takes a surprise assistant coaching job as the Collingwood legend awaits on a likely offer to lead Tasmania's inaugural AFL team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fd3d52a338ea52e945304cb458dc004</guid></item><item><title>Australia hosts hottest place on Earth, but here's why it's not a heatwave yet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/australia-hosts-hottest-place-on-earth/105888248</link><description>Parts of Pilbara and Kimberley surpassed 40 degrees Celsius yesterday but meteorologists say the temperatures will not trigger a heatwave warning yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d5466674485d37a8a2a5d373d647f80</guid></item><item><title>Almost 130 people dead or missing in Mexico floods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/dozens-dead-after-torrential-rains-lash-mexico/105889300</link><description>The death toll from flooding in Mexico's central region has risen to 64, with another 65 people missing, according to the Mexican government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8015efd23b16e6fafd30e13d802aae13</guid></item><item><title>Katter's Australian Party MP Nick Dametto resigns from Queensland parliament to run in Townsville mayoral by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/qld-nick-dametto-resigns-parliament-townsville-mayor/105889624</link><description>Katter's Australian Party MP Nick Dametto has formally resigned from state parliament to run for Townsville mayor — forcing a by-election in his north Queensland seat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa2231bc0621c602e2e41f67dbbfc8a8</guid></item><item><title>Nikita Tszyu recovering after suffering 'minor injuries' following a car accident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/nikita-tszyu-recovering-after-car-accident/105890074</link><description>Nikita Tszyu was involved in a car accident last weekend, putting a possible grudge match fight against Michael Zerafa at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca27801adbd0c4b78e8ad6edbc13d224</guid></item><item><title>Noosa mayor says fraudsters used AI imitation in $2.3m council scam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/noosa-council-scam-mayor-blames-ai-imitation/105887962</link><description>The mayor of a small council that lost nearly $2 million in a "sophisticated" scam says international fraudsters were able to "imitate personalities" using AI.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ad393b46f5cfb4651924cd453233651</guid></item><item><title>Top executives at Affinity Education Group resign after childcare scandals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/affinity-education-group-childcare-child-sex-abuse-resign/105890292</link><description>The chief executive and chief operating officer at one of Australia's biggest childcare chains have resigned following a string of scandals, including dozens of sex abuse charges being laid against a former employee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">337a16e2ba397496fa1d04fe1e122efc</guid></item><item><title>Eugowra flood inquest hears evidence of a 'day of hell'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/eugowra-flood-inquest-day-two-hears-of-inland-tsunami/105887756</link><description>A Eugowra resident tells an inquest into deadly flooding how she put her six-day-old granddaughter in a roof cavity after a wave of water hit the Central West town, killing two people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d6a5ec2b5dd8ff9a04b9d8f7c7f8998</guid></item><item><title>WA Police investigating after man fatally injured in Hocking in Perth's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/wa-police-investigating-after-man-injured-in-hocking/105889242</link><description>A man is in custody and homicide detectives are investigating following the death of a man in Perth's northern suburbs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">841b94009ba276cbc8a8f1eed7a0f878</guid></item><item><title>Prosecutor calls for jail term for former Weston Creek Children's Centre director who defrauded more than $300,000</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/canberra-childcare-centre-director-fraud-sentence-hearing/105888502</link><description>Prosecutors call for a jail term to be imposed over the theft of more than $300,000 from a Canberra child care centre by its then-director Emma Louise Morton.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47526cef5a448d8881ece89a92f460e5</guid></item><item><title>Used car dealer Alexander Hallett fined $25,000 for winding back car odometers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/alexander-hallett-used-car-sales-odometer-fraud/105889740</link><description>Alexander Thomas Hallett pleaded guilty to winding back a total of 648,000 kilometres on the odometers of seven vehicles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94c33e5687ddd173e64734786537d735</guid></item><item><title>Bridget Archer announces funding for Hobart Clinic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/bridget-archer-announces-funding-for-hobart-clinic/105890098</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb1b30d865a9a239f2642a4dd843222b</guid></item><item><title>Roblox 'taken to task' but may not be included in social media ban, says eSafety commissioner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/esafety-commissioner-social-media-ban-roblox/105889222</link><description>Australia's eSafety commissioner says her team has "taken Roblox to task" over its risk of exposing children to harm but warned the online gaming platform may not be included in the upcoming social media ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db4b3f6eea6b606948efa08757097591</guid></item><item><title>'Appalling history' of abuse at Mount Penang Juvenile Justice Centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/mount-penang-juvenile-justice-centre-child-abuse-trial/105880634</link><description>A former detainee at a notorious Central Coast juvenile justice facility is suing the state of NSW over alleged sexual abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ea58877b31a0dbb108948f4a003a7ce</guid></item><item><title>Suggestion AFLW being used as a 'trial run' for new rules causes frustration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/frustration-as-aflw-used-as-trial-run-for-new-rules-for-afl-mens/105889756</link><description>Collingwood's Tarni White says it feels as though the women's competition is being used as a trial run for new rules before they are implemented into the men's league.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22b2ee856b6c7691dbc3cfbefcc9b672</guid></item><item><title>Inquest continues into death of energy worker mauled by dogs at Logan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/kane-minion-dog-attack-meter-reader-inquest/105889012</link><description>After meter reader Kane Minion was fatally mauled by dogs at a Queensland property, the Coroners Court hears details about the electricity provider's work procedures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01182291988c671db501930a1e01bf14</guid></item><item><title>Victory in Socceroos' friendly against United States could ease World Cup draw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/socceroos-friendly-against-us-could-impact-world-cup-draw/105890480</link><description>The Socceroos' friendly against the United States is a positive step in their World Cup preparation, while a positive result could also influence their tournament draw.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">818fc0fb7ab727bff2ff2f14d8091448</guid></item><item><title>Vessel breaks apart soon after leaving port in northern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/vessel-runs-aground-maritime-shipwreck/105889334</link><description>Authorities say they were concerned about the seaworthiness of a vessel that left port in Ballina early on Monday and broke apart less than 24 hours later off Kingscliff in northern NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bfc95a7f83b29b7977fb5420256c779</guid></item><item><title>Parts of Coffs Coast Wildlife Sanctuary evacuated due to 'highly venomous' sea snake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/coffs-coast-wildlife-sanctaury-evacuated-due-to-sea-snake/105888174</link><description>Visitors to a northern New South Wales wildlife sanctuary were forced to evacuate after a woman brought in a rescued sea snake, one of the world's deadliest reptiles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf19e8dfb92ca49756f2b5a4a596a77f</guid></item><item><title>John Torney's brother tells court he knew 'how violent' accused could be</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/john-torney-emma-bates-negligent-manslaughter-witnesses-cobram/105888568</link><description>The brother of a man accused of negligent manslaughter has told a Victorian court that he knew how violent his brother could be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a3cf30b506b640dc3f99cde8cfa328e</guid></item><item><title>Joseph French remembered as 'beautiful' young man after Bunbury boating tragedy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/family-of-joseph-french-pay-tribute-to-teen/105891046</link><description>The family of a boy who drowned after a boating mishap off Bunbury pays tribute to a "beautiful and fascinating young man".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa4ae5d2ec5bf2680464f308f747324b</guid></item><item><title>As illicit tobacco sales rise into the billions, economist Arthur Laffer puts blame on high tobacco taxation rate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/illegal-tobacco-sales-billions-arthur-laffer-critiques-australia/105873994</link><description>Internal tobacco industry data estimates the illicit tobacco market now makes up 64 per cent of all tobacco consumed in Australia and 82 per cent of the total nicotine consumed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d4469b8b84f45d625bbb2ec0086b843</guid></item><item><title>Police officer had 'high likelihood of PTSD' at time of death, inquest told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/inquest-into-death-of-sa-police-officer-benjamin-warren/105887870</link><description>A coronial inquest will explore whether the 2022 death of SA Police Senior Constable Benjamin Edward Warren could have been prevented if his mental health issues had been identified.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd13e8e347a708108fd3eddb6aa8ea74</guid></item><item><title>Monitors reappointed to City of Whittlesea council, with 'wrecking ball' former mayor set to return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/whittlesea-mayor-aidan-mclindon-return-municipal-monitors/105890768</link><description>Municipal monitors will be reappointed to an embattled council in Melbourne's booming outer north following an inquiry probing the lead-up to the suspension of a former mayor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb06b13fda9df4cb6cb453876c867f18</guid></item><item><title>Indie film producers tell SXSW Sydney about how to survive and thrive making horror</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/sxsw-sydney-indie-producers-on-how-to-survive-making-horror-film/105890988</link><description>Horror films can be a great training ground for filmmakers, but there is also a gritty reality, a panel of indie producers tells SXSW Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1c6edf129ce345474e049a6b56c5528</guid></item><item><title>Body-worn camera shows Tatiana Dokhotaru's ex-partner wailing at crime scene</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/danny-zayat-alleged-trial-murder-trial-camera-evidence/105890906</link><description>The jury on Tuesday was played several police body-worn camera videos of a wailing Danny Zayat with officers at the scene when police found his ex-partner's body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">029ab8b3ccd887a64682f88b949b1341</guid></item><item><title>WA's flu season exceeds 30,000 cases as authorities blame low vaccination rates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/wa-flu-season-worst-ever-poor-vaccination-rates/105891252</link><description>Western Australia records its worst flu season on record, with more than 30,000 influenza cases reported this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f1f2484096733debed58e21c7b6682</guid></item><item><title>Abducted by Hamas, Noa never lost hope she would see her 'soulmate' again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/noa-argamani-avinatan-or-hamas-hostages-freed/105890692</link><description>Noa and Avinatan's abduction from a music festival became an enduring illustration of the horrors endured by Israelis on October 7. Now safely in each other's arms, a chapter has closed on a harrowing two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e795ebb238cdbebca7f0fd0bfe11d9d4</guid></item><item><title>Truck driver to face trial over fatal 2024 Bulli Pass crash in Thirroul</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/truck-driver-mosa-vaimalu-thirroul-crash-bulli-pass/105891118</link><description>Mosa Vaimalu has pleaded not guilty to charges of dangerous driving over the crash that left one man dead and two people seriously injured.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0401d99c8fd303913beabe8d29ea20d</guid></item><item><title>Concerns teenagers in regional West Australia face further isolation as social media ban looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/regional-teens-left-lonely/105888190</link><description>Advocates are concerned rural and remote children will experience compounding challenges with the looming social media ban for people under 16.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1170b18fc2aa14fb4b4494d3cfed0a2f</guid></item><item><title>Correspondent Eric Tlozek in Ramallah when 80 Palestinian prisoners were released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/correspondent-eric-tlozek-in-ramallah-when-80/105890214</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87ffa977c5e6ad6bbabc2ef68f45a988</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian prisoners reunite with loved ones in Gaza and West Bank, many alleging mistreatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/freed-prisoners-detainees-reunited-in-gaza-and-west-bank/105885078</link><description>Nearly 2,000 Palestinians who were imprisoned in Israel have been reunited with their families as part of an exchange for hostages held by Hamas in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac15bd7ffe224e45bb90bb8c1ae75550</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105891880</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">653774c141b651a45c0a8cb8f098cded</guid></item><item><title>Senior conservative James Paterson cautions Liberal Party against splitting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/james-paterson-urges-liberals-not-to-break-up-farage-teal/105888150</link><description>In a major address to his party, James Paterson says "marginal" voices agitating for the Liberal party to split must be kept on the sidelines, cautioning it would spell "disaster".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b19c93195b4681ddf79b775907477599</guid></item><item><title>Could the social media ban be a good thing?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/could-the-social-media-ban-be-a-good-thing-/105891632</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c85f8b938a7f760052637822d18bf6d3</guid></item><item><title>Allegedly armed man who sparked hours-long lockdown of Brisbane City Botanic Gardens in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/queensland-police-lockdown-brisbane-botanic-gardens/105890698</link><description>The Brisbane City Botanic Gardens shuts down for three hours as police respond to reports of a man allegedly wielding a weapon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">998c22d5709a1a7dcf5c01a200df488e</guid></item><item><title>ACT Director of Public Prosections says she may have to turn away some cases if funding not increased</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/act-top-prosecutor-concerned-cases-may-be-dropped/105889058</link><description>The ACT Director of Public Prosecutions says her office does not have enough funding to deal with an increasing annual case load of more than 23,000 charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">847e8e82d9373bc775e40e74105a64c0</guid></item><item><title>Emotional scenes as Israeli hostages and Palestinian prisoners freed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/emotional-scenes-as-israeli-hostages-and/105891960</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46c705ab6822229fff3f8708faec0fbf</guid></item><item><title>Illicit tobacco sales are increasing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/illicit-tobacco-sales-are-increasing/105891964</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8d1214737914e6a6d0af3b49d07c3f6</guid></item><item><title>How do you sell the essence of the Liberal Party to young people?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/how-do-you-sell-the-essence-of-the-liberal-party/105891974</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d2e2222a1c6222c5f25ea65b5eb8d51</guid></item><item><title>Released prisoners face the harsh reality of possible homelessness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/released-prisoners-face-the-harsh-reality-of/105891986</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df6e8f47847e2528e3c72ed075d68068</guid></item><item><title>Man once accused of murder of three tourists in Mount Isa in 1978 gives evidence at inquest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/qld-cold-case-trial-mount-isa-178-bruce-preston/105888178</link><description>Bruce Preston was once accused of killing three tourists in Mount Isa in 1978, but the prosecution was later dropped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e198e1fb969f369c602495130d92610</guid></item><item><title>South Sydney Rabbitohs player Tyrone Munro charged with domestic violence offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/rabbitohs-player-tyrone-munro-charged-domestic-violence-offences/105891952</link><description>New South Wales Police launched an investigation on Monday after a woman reported she had been assaulted by her partner near Homebush in April 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42571ab1bfc50d6fa43bac1c5791bffe</guid></item><item><title>NSW Parramatta Council CEO breaks silence after late-night sacking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/chief-executive-gail-connolly-sacked-city-of-parramatta-council/105888808</link><description>Nine councillors voted in favour of firing Gail Connolly, while three voted against the move and three abstained.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bec572e14e7f221976e7304b9a3a9f90</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians released from prisons in Israel return to Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/palestinians-released-from-prisons-in-israel/105891014</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82e279152762010eb5181fac6de4625e</guid></item><item><title>Five takeaways from the ABC's Your Say: The Digital Dilemma forum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/abc-your-say-the-digital-dilemma-key-takeaways/105890184</link><description>An emotional plea to the country, concerns about privacy and how Australia's social media ban will actually work. These are the key takeaways from the ABC's Your Say: The Digital Dilemma forum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de6e80e7d191490fa6fdf7119bf8ab6e</guid></item><item><title>Top stories from ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/top-stories-from-abc-news/105892300</link><description>Listen to ABC News interviews and commentary and analysis from radio programs like AM, PM and The World Today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c25df1b3fe5f27ea500064cd2e1d9d9</guid></item><item><title>Bangladesh garment factory fire kills 16, toll may rise, official says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/bangladesh-factory-fire-kills-at-least-sixteen-people/105892400</link><description>At least 16 people have died after a fire broke out in a garment factory and a nearby chemical warehouse in Bangladesh.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8a2de734e13c2a9c78c22f302808120</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar military says it is seizing power after president flees country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/madagascar-military-takes-control-coup-president-flee/105892454</link><description>The country's parliament voted to impeach President Andry Rajoelina after he fled the country in the face of growing opposition from soldiers and police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55efccf0b4c7a9354d313eee5adbd18d</guid></item></channel></rss>