<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:56:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Prime minister's national security adviser Philippa Brant resigns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/prime-minister-national-security-adviser-resigns/106252214</link><description>Philippa Brant has resigned just months after the PM's top foreign policy adviser departed to run the Office of National Intelligence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">763f42a5aafcf9f8eac55afeda3e30ce</guid></item><item><title>Trash and treasure trike proves powerful tool for brain health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/trash-treasure-trike-broken-hill-brian-slater-brain-health/106234034</link><description>Brian Slater, 77, is heeding advice to "use it or lose it" as he devotes his retirement to cognitive challenges that keep his mind healthy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b18a19aba6c1c38aadd2e1cbd0a8bc9</guid></item><item><title>WA meat processor says using AI for counting livestock has improved accuracy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/ai-camera-counting-sheep-at-wa-abattoir/106249366</link><description>One of WA's largest meat processors is using AI technology to count thousands of head of cattle a day with pinpoint accuracy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3d77b876e3e1623dcb17ef294264615</guid></item><item><title>Sheep under the eye of AI</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/using-ai-to-count-sheep/106250690</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c5af840e880887503748d0dd1f0eb2a</guid></item><item><title>Naomi Osaka reveals inspiration behind Australian Open outfit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/australian-open-naomi-osaka-outfit-rod-laver-arena-entrance/106252208</link><description>Naomi Osaka reveals a visit to Japan as a 13-year-old and the Williams sisters helped inspire the outfit she wore on Rod Laver Arena.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">528ac61929a6c6ba38e1b22414ff0959</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's bushfire-affected communities remain on edge ahead of another heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/bushfire-weather-concerns-victoria-heatwave-forecast/106248072</link><description>Bushfire-affected communities remain on edge as forecasters warn of another heatwave, raising concerns about fire risk and extreme temperatures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cee291dbc6e657b9bec3616303975fb</guid></item><item><title>Towns brace for potential 50-degree days as heatwave grips Pilbara and Gascoyne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/wa-towns-brace-for-possible-50-degree-days/106244600</link><description>Towns in WA's north-west could be about to experience Australia's hottest day on record, with the weather bureau expecting temperatures of 50 degrees Celsius in some areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd0dbc66d0f14f7042e6a44511e6e27d</guid></item><item><title>NT pomelo growers fear imports from Vietnam will flood market, risk reintroducing citrus canker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/pomelo-growers-citrus-canker-disease-fears-vietnam-imports/106250118</link><description>The Top End's pomelo industry is worried about the impending importation of the citrus fruit from Vietnam. They say it will depress the local market and bring a biosecurity risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e675248017bdeb51be021cca1210a130</guid></item><item><title>Angus Crichton to leave Sydney Roosters and NRL to chase Wallabies World Cup dream</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/angus-crichton-leave-roosters-chase-wallabies-world-cup-dream/106252548</link><description>Star second-rower Angus Crichton will leave the Sydney Roosters at the end of the NRL season to pursue a career in rugby union.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a295c7e2e59bb0b91dbf8ffd55deb05</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's America-first policies are pushing countries into China's embrace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/donald-trump-is-a-gift-to-china-that-keeps-on-giving/106249578</link><description>Inside China, there's a nickname for Donald Trump that tells you everything you need to know about how the US leader's actions are increasingly seen as a gift to Beijing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e84cef9503369eecbd2a2ca690b2398</guid></item><item><title>Crime gangs restocking shops 'up to 10 times a day' with illegal cigarettes and vapes, WA police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/behind-the-scenes-of-wa-s-illegal-tobacco-business-model/106252960</link><description>WA's police commissioner says the restocking is happening faster than authorities can seize the products, as tobacco black market violence escalates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c85e3ad402b68eddf68bb31ca5929a65</guid></item><item><title>American rider and brumby complete 4,400km journey across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/american-rider-brumby-journey-across-australia/106238888</link><description>Gin Szagola and her brumby, Fable, have completed a coast-to-coast journey, covering 4,400 kilometres in eight months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c87bb28b98216d3d360a3f82c9d902b5</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs Mayor Asta Hill will not attend Australia Day ceremony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/alice-springs-mayor-will-not-attend-australia-day-ceremony/106252002</link><description>Asta Hill will not take part in celebrations of Australia Day, which she sees as a day causing harm to First Nations peoples — a decision described as "disgraceful" by the local member of the Northern Territory Legislative Assembly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">948bb6a11a41e328ce594aca829df759</guid></item><item><title>WA premier Roger Cook extends embattled Griffin Coal's lifeline, citing energy security concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/roger-cook-extends-griffin-coal-financial-lifeline/106250998</link><description>Since 2022, the WA government has already tipped $300 million into propping up the insolvent Indian-owned miner, which is more than $1 billion in debt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67e740016a3de5b8c9985d9a5054f374</guid></item><item><title>Canadian PM says smaller nations must 'band together' to stop larger countries overpowering them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/carney-blasts-trump-canada-davos-world-economic-forum/106252354</link><description>Canadian PM Mark Carney told the World Economic Forum "middle powers must act together".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3d402b5ff2519732956effe5b696207</guid></item><item><title>NZ Prime Minister Christopher Luxon calls for election on November 7</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/nz-pm-calls-for-election-to-be-held-on-november-7/106253286</link><description>NZ's Prime Minister Christopher Luxon has announced the election date for 2026, promising economic prosperity if New Zealanders vote for him again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2151ed94bdf31735ca532b3eee1999e3</guid></item><item><title>Liberals 'not that stressed' by leak — but Labor seizes on attempt to 'destabilise' leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/labor-liberal-war-of-words-over-sa-document-leak/106251982</link><description>The leaking of an SA Liberal document two months before the state election has been described by the Labor government as a "calculated and methodical" attempt to "destabilise" new leader Ashton Hurn — but her party says it is "not that stressed" because the policy is old.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfcdecbed89774f218970ce8605ff790</guid></item><item><title>What we know about changing UK passport requirements effective February 25</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/what-we-know-about-changing-uk-passport-requirements-explainer/106252182</link><description>Hundreds of confused UK and Irish dual citizens in Australia have written to the ABC with questions around the new changes for entry requirements into the UK. Here's what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ad4283cc2e20810a878022673bc9745</guid></item><item><title>Australian NATO envoy Di Turton warns North Korea has 'combat-ready troops in our region'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/turton-warns-north-korea-has-combat-ready-troops-in-our-region/106246654</link><description>Australia's outgoing military envoy to NATO is preparing to return to Canberra after two years in the role, and she is coming home with a warning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b24fa33cd95a9f83851e93c8d2239d49</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police slap bans on neo-Nazis entering Sydney CBD on Australia Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/nsw-police-ban-neo-nazis-entering-sydney-cbd-on-australia-day/106251992</link><description>Up to 12 neo-Nazis have been issued public safety orders banning them from entering central Sydney, shutting down plans to attend anti-immigration rallies on Australia Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b80afd68912726767d758f1cbdcc7672</guid></item><item><title>Why Elina Svitolina is prioritising her mental health at the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/australian-open-elina-svitolina-prioritises-her-mental-health/106253922</link><description>In the highly competitive world of professional tennis, it is refreshing to learn that Elina Svitolina has her priorities in order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">231dc2e91147acfd4cd1936346129dc9</guid></item><item><title>New South Wales man charged with allegedly threatening prime minister</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/man-charged-threatening-politician-bellingen-prime-minister/106252292</link><description>A NSW Mid North Coast man is granted bail after he allegedly threatened to shoot the prime minister, in a video uploaded to social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a162f7503002a63f89c62572cb4f408</guid></item><item><title>Midnight Oil's Rob Hirst died of pancreatic cancer. It's one of Australia's deadliest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/midnight-oil-rob-hirst-pancreatic-cancer-death/106252876</link><description>Rob Hirst was first diagnosed with pancreatic cancer in 2023. It is estimated to be the third most common cause of cancer death in Australia, and has among the lowest survival rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9ddc9310c0db0de11b44dad7f91d666</guid></item><item><title>Have you been gifted an ancestry DNA test? The results could be 'life-altering'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/why-ancestry-dna-tests-arent-just-a-bit-of-fun/106225222</link><description>If you're thinking of taking an ancestry DNA test as "a bit of fun", experts warn there is the risk of uncovering more than you bargained for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c18adfae6ecc122d7b0786df99d29aa2</guid></item><item><title>Police believe Mandurah teacher's baby fathered by student she allegedly sexually abused</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/wa-teacher-gives-birth-after-child-sexual-assault-charges/106254008</link><description>Police believe a Mandurah teacher gave birth to a baby fathered by a student she allegedly sexually assaulted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f8bdf15c3dbf7525b3248fd20d0c29e</guid></item><item><title>Zeynep Sönmez thrills Turkish fans with latest Australian Open win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/australian-open-zeynep-sonmez-turkiye-second-round-melbourne/106254442</link><description>In front of her loyal supporters, Türkiye's Zeynep Sönmez advances to the Australian Open third round, as her remarkable run continues at Melbourne Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22727b155241893e1895d1a9d793586a</guid></item><item><title>New hate laws have passed parliament. What do they actually do?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/what-will-new-hate-laws-do/106253754</link><description>The new laws grant powers for the government to list so-called hate groups, more easily deport or cancel the visas of individuals associated with hate groups and create new aggravated penalties for leaders who advocate violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22f42220711e3e177be96bf784d2def9</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's second presidency is about 'might makes right' and reshaping the world order be it in Venezuela or Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/donald-trumps-year-one-lays-ground-for-new-world-order/106252232</link><description>As Donald Trump celebrates one year of his second term in the White House, he is rewriting all the rules for global order, and no-one seems ready to stop his "imperial ambitions".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68e8d76ada9efedaa2427ff84102d70f</guid></item><item><title>WA gold companies 'floating on a sea of cash' as the commodity hits new price record</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/gold-price-continues-to-smash-historic-records/106252736</link><description>A Kalgoorlie miner hopes the soaring price of gold will incentivise investment into regional WA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">727c087761f0b6ae2a28d0df6ed03a2c</guid></item><item><title>Why Emmanuel Macron was wearing sunglasses at Davos World Economic Forum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/why-emmanuel-macron-wore-sunglasses-to-davos/106252204</link><description>The French president's appearance at the annual meeting of the World Economic Forum makes headlines, but not for any policy reasons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae7b6da24375daf367a7ce77fd45d66d</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106254400</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96b2d0610f77559240b421960b39fc7a</guid></item><item><title>Banned Adelaide doctor Bill Tolis in court over steroid importation charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/adelaide-banned-doctor-bill-tolis-charged-steroid-importation/106253698</link><description>A man who was banned from working as a doctor in 2022 appears in court charged with importing steroids and peptides that the Australian Border Force allegedly found in a medical clinic and at his home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15ae84013164210499851a72702a1db6</guid></item><item><title>Plane landing aborted after alleged trespassing incident near runway at Melbourne Airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/melbourne-airport-trespasser-afp/106255022</link><description>A pilot is forced to abort a landing attempt at Melbourne Airport, and two take-offs are delayed after an alleged late-night trespassing incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e0008c004dc5e6ce444d59ffa49fcad</guid></item><item><title>Benjamin Netanyahu, Azerbaijan agree to join Trump's 'Board of Peace' as Norway and Sweden reject invitations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/israel-and-azerbaijan-to-join-trumps-board-of-peace/106254994</link><description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu agrees to join US President Donald Trump's "Board of Peace" despite his office previously criticising the makeup of the executive committee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a809f7bafb25060ffc5b77861c179cb</guid></item><item><title>Father of Adelaide girl who died due to mother's alleged neglect tells court of coffin threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/jasmine-willmott-father-gives-evidence-in-manslaughter-trial/106254726</link><description>The father of a 15-year-old girl whose mother is accused of her manslaughter, tells the South Australian Supreme Court of a threat made against his daughter and punishment she was made to do.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">877e18523e326afbcffe861376220e59</guid></item><item><title>Coalition on the brink as Nationals quit shadow ministry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/nationals-coalition-littleproud-ley-hate-laws/106254676</link><description>Opposition leader Sussan Ley says the Nationals' mass resignation from her frontbench is "unnecessary" and has urged the rural party to remain in the Coalition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2506e2c3d1df8a3e6b416a4e1ad58809</guid></item><item><title>K'gari traditional owners raise dingo management issues after teen's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/kgari-traditional-owners-dingo-management-issues/106252220</link><description>The body of Piper James, 19, was found surrounded by dingoes on a beach on the island's eastern coast, but how she died may not be known for some time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac54ad630f52e053a14ca4033cf0af1e</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump drops Greenland tariffs threat as he heralds 'future deal' with NATO</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/donald-trump-tells-davos-he-wants-greenland-deal-with-denmark/106255244</link><description>Donald Trump says he has agreed to a "framework of a future deal" on Greenland after talks with NATO's secretary-general, and he will no longer impose tariffs on European nations that had opposed a US takeover.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f89614fd2c7c59f2ce651d55a6edb4</guid></item><item><title>Japan restarts nuclear power plant almost 15 years since Fukushima disaster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/worlds-biggest-nuclear-power-plant-restarted-after-fukushima/106255280</link><description>The world's biggest nuclear power plant has been rebooted by the same company that operated the Fukushima facility, despite concerns about safety from some locals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">449f4979bd3a97dd3cade26e5436d195</guid></item><item><title>Emotional Prince Harry says media made his wife Meghan Markle's life 'an absolute misery' at Daily Mail trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/prince-harry-gives-evidence-at-high-court-in-privacy-case/106255216</link><description>An emotional Prince Harry held back tears as he described the impact of media coverage on his wife Meghan Markle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0303b3d89bae8745f194d9374bac2748</guid></item><item><title>Why Ukrainians are shivering through their fourth winter in wartime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/energy-crisis-kyiv-winter-ukraine-russia-blackouts/106255468</link><description>The war-ravaged country has been plunged into an energy crisis as temperatures plummet below freezing, leaving millions unable to heat their homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccb3c54d802b1a2340a3cc49537ca8e3</guid></item><item><title>Children and journalists killed by Israel in separate incidents in Gaza, Palestinian medics say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/children-and-journalists-killed-by-idf-in-gaza/106255512</link><description>According to Palestinian medics, two boys aged 10 and 13 were among those killed on Wednesday in the latest violence which threatens to undermine a fragile ceasefire deal between Israel and Hamas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd3c1332546ddcee2f19fb827ee29a26</guid></item><item><title>Royal Hobart Hospital medical scan backlog creating late diagnosis risk, AMA says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/royal-hobart-hospital-medical-scans-outsourced/106250608</link><description>The Royal Hobart Hospital is facing a significant backlog of medical scans, with at least one patient experiencing a late diagnosis. The AMA and a union say it's a sign of a system facing a range of pressures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b176a825f6f77ae4bd8c9f6625b7666e</guid></item><item><title>Students have their say in disaster planning in Melbourne's bushfire-prone outer east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/school-bushfire-preparation-upwey-high-school-cfa/106180444</link><description>In a bushfire-prone area in outer Melbourne, a group of students is taking part in a two-way learning exchange to improve bushfire safety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40307f950dbaec9d8ce11741eb18b179</guid></item><item><title>How closely have you been following the 2026 awards season?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/mid-awards-season-quiz/106236836</link><description>Fancy yourself an awards season whiz? Test your knowledge as we rocket towards the 2026 Academy awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17381a39bd7b2538186d35a6037811fe</guid></item><item><title>Republicans push to hold Clintons in contempt of Congress over Epstein probe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/clintons-us-house-contempt-over-epstein/106255510</link><description>The Clintons are refusing to testify before a committee in the US House of Representatives, accusing Republicans of leading a weaponised process against them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c80ed23b03f8eb6f6c2be9bc2e08dae</guid></item><item><title>Calls to bring back hard-hitting anti-smoking campaigns to warn off gen Z</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/calls-to-bring-back-hard-hitting-anti-smoking-campaigns/106076928</link><description>Experts say Australia risks becoming complacent in the war against tobacco, with big companies pivoting to social media to "greenwash" their products to generation Z.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a3755c5faf71c4ae310c4fa1f70cef6</guid></item><item><title>Nationals' walkout leaves Coalition in tatters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/national-walkout-coalition-on-life-support/106252042</link><description>The departure of every single member of the Nationals from the frontbench is bizarrely both a failure of the Coalition agreement and a result of it functioning as intended.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87d0ee925d656b9cc5bc9005730349bd</guid></item><item><title>Australia earns global praise for economic 'soft landing' but still dependent on China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/reserve-bank-earns-global-praise-for-economic-soft-landing/106254000</link><description>A new report from the OECD says Australia's economy is returning to normal but remains vulnerable and lacks dynamism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05e404f80625145a36267752e37fcb5d</guid></item><item><title>Europe holds the trump card as the US faces a mountain of debt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/trump-us-debt-carney-davos-fractured-world-order/106254272</link><description>For decades, global investors have bought US government debt as a safe haven when things turn pear-shaped. But investor attitudes are changing, and America's financial domination is at stake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef5ba145fdb46fb1740c5e13e6f77eb3</guid></item><item><title>'Ten-pound Pom' vows to boycott UK over 'money grab' passport changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/ten-pound-pom-boycotting-uk-over-passport-changes/106252052</link><description>People who came to Australia as children from the UK as part of an organised migration scheme say they the UK's new regulations for dual citizens unfairly targets them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">589e215128e03f85233423439cb2ca67</guid></item><item><title>Hobart Hurricanes beat Melbourne Stars in rainy thriller to keep BBL title defence alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/hurricanes-win-in-the-rain-to-get-bbl-title-defence-alive/106255630</link><description>The Hobart Hurricanes hold their nerve to beat the Melbourne Stars in a rain-shortened Big Bash elimination final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b3de8ccef426aa4a98bc8ad84b9fc29</guid></item><item><title>Sinner weighs up Kyrgios and Kim Jong-Un, plus an Aussie exodus — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/australian-open-2026-quick-hits/106252228</link><description>Jannik Sinner was stuck in an awkward moment discussing Nick Kyrgios and Kim Jong Un while Coco Gauff shared her top artists. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">910ec10d7ff7c87b7739ef59bc8e52af</guid></item><item><title>Taskforce set up to address ongoing power outages across SA from dust pollution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/power-outages-across-regional-south-australia-from-dust/106252096</link><description>Ongoing dry conditions across South Australia since 2024 are causing dust and salt to build up across inland and coastal power networks, polluting insulators and leading to mass blackouts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfa755b708992c638b64e4eaec702edf</guid></item><item><title>Police Association says Coober Pedy and APY Lands are 'unacceptably compromised' by police shortage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/coober-pedy-police-station-shortage/106254028</link><description>South Australia's police union says some officers in the remote town are working 18-hour days and have been unable to respond to all incidents, amid an ongoing industrial dispute with SA Police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c95b2aa716dd7117122caf12eb92208</guid></item><item><title>Trump rules out using force to acquire Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/trump-denies-possibility-of-using-force-to-acquire-greenland/106255572</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">055ef0c7ec96765a861e340c4f3ff2fe</guid></item><item><title>Back-to-school budgeting a chance for kids to learn financial literacy and empathy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/how-to-involve-your-kids-in-back-to-school-budgeting/106225314</link><description>Managing back-to-school costs, especially when kids want expensive brand name items, can cause a lot of stress for families. But including children in the budgeting and decision-making process is key to helping everyone get on the same page.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37b64c02787d589912788d033586f11c</guid></item><item><title>Manchester City players reimburse travelling fans after shock Champions League loss to Bodo/Glimt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/man-city-players-reimburse-fans-champions-league-bodo-glimt-loss/106255684</link><description>Manchester City players combine to pay back the cost of match tickets to fans who travelled to freezing Norway for a shock Champions League defeat to Bodø/Glimt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3961b71b542f027eda47766f4098781a</guid></item><item><title>Former and current presenters share 50 years of memories at ABC Classic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/abc-classic-presenters-celebrate-50-years-of-broadcasting/106245866</link><description>From late-life love stories to musical discoveries, presenters reveal what has made ABC Classic special for audiences for 50 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e95bb9135719c0184072ebc1bb2d1890</guid></item><item><title>More than one disaster a week raises concerns over mental health support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/mental-health-natural-disasters-floods-bushfires/106248008</link><description>Mental health experts warn of significant barriers to support in disaster-affected communities, as Australia records more than one natural disaster a week since January 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1754a727c59bc8d6ab652edb65847dd</guid></item><item><title>$10 billion data centre planned for Hazelwood in Victoria's Latrobe Valley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/keppel-data-centre-latrobe-valley/106123748</link><description>Victoria's east is set to become home to a $10 billion data centre that will support the technology necessary for artificial intelligence systems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9956deb90fefb9d8c74ef249d8393b13</guid></item><item><title>Concerns raised after sawfish, sharks and turtle found mutilated on northwest WA beaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/sawfish-shark-turtle-found-dead-in-carnarvon/106254342</link><description>Residents and experts say they are shocked and concerned after social media images showed a number of endangered and protected marine animals impaled and severed on a stretch of WA coastline in just a few weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14db6bd51044c50feade70e00cdb04e5</guid></item><item><title>Plan to rebuild world's largest living coral aquarium explained after years of delays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/townsville-reef-hq-aquarium-great-barrier-reef-australia-rebuild/106233472</link><description>The world's largest living coral reef exhibit is yet to be rebuilt five years after the Queensland aquarium closed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8a00984196c7af8a42ee31f3ff4fcb0</guid></item><item><title>Tour website's AI sends visitors to Tasmanian sites that do not exist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/ai-images-of-tasmania-on-tour-website/106253448</link><description>Weldborough in remote north-east Tasmania has lots of natural beauty. But it does not have hot springs — and it is causing headaches for locals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17596b208021bc09f69e25ce3d3ee9cf</guid></item><item><title>Administrators seek buyers for Sanjeev Gupta's Tahmoor Coal mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/tahmoor-coal-sale-gupta-administrators/106254968</link><description>Administrators have put Sanjeev Gupta's Tahmoor Coal mine up for sale, seeking buyers to recover value for creditors and potentially restart operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc73e72ea7427583d3403e8301d3c525</guid></item><item><title>Why did Queensland's flood warning gauges fail when they were needed most?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/how-queenslands-flood-gauges-broke/106236592</link><description>Queensland's flood emergency exposed vast holes in the patchwork of river gauges relied on for early warnings. But getting them back online will take a lot more than a reboot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f5b6c8f6a565b9ea8df5000357371c9</guid></item><item><title>Coalition splits for second time since election after Nationals quit shadow cabinet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/coalition-splits-for-second-time-since-election/106255898</link><description>David Littleproud says the Nationals have been put in an "untenable" position and are not willing to serve in a shadow ministry led by Sussan Ley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da003f94bbd7e082339a8bd3ef36d5c7</guid></item><item><title>'You have no idea what fair play is': Osaka and Cirstea in tense exchange</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/australian-open-2026-live-novak-djokovic-kyrgios-kokkinakis/106256036</link><description>There is no love lost between Naomi Osaka and Sorana Cirstea after the Japanese star prevails in a hard-fought three-setter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc3dbf5886ebf502a83d62ef67ff3bdc</guid></item><item><title>Sydney council explores offshore sand dredging as locals fear losing beaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/sutherland-shire-explores-offshore-sand-dredging-cronulla-beach/106251664</link><description>A group of passionate locals have called for a long-term solution to the disappearing sand from beaches in Sydney's Sutherland Shire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58c0ea5fd754280000e1a36d1fef918d</guid></item><item><title>Murray-Darling water-sharing study proposes combining agriculture and conservation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/water-sharing-policy-proposal-for-murray-darling-basin/106251850</link><description>Can breeding birds and growing rice combine to help both conservation and agriculture in the basin?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64845f1f36a9ad2ae78f48d4f6d928ef</guid></item><item><title>Frances Tiafoe psyched up to play Alex de Minaur in Australian Open third round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/australian-open-alex-de-minaur-frances-tiafoe-third-round/106256130</link><description>It says a lot about the presence of youth in professional tennis that Alex de Minaur and Frances Tiafoe can already be considered veterans on the tour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad79a2741bd570aac7d24180c8fae85f</guid></item><item><title>Several people missing after landslide hits Mount Maunganui campground in New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/several-missing-after-new-zealand-landslide/106256408</link><description>A landslide hits campervans, cars, tents and a toilet and shower block at the Mount Maunganui camping site in New Zealand in what has been described as a "major incident".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b4cec5194ec536cae4b04ee1f0c1b74</guid></item><item><title>Unemployment rate drops to 4.1 per cent ahead of RBA's next rates meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/abs-jobs-unemployment-december-2025-figures/106256288</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate fell from 4.3 to 4.1 per cent in December, according to seasonally adjusted figures from the Australian Bureau of Statistics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca9a4c57a25ef4052b004d05710e2490</guid></item><item><title>Young girl among several missing after landslide at NZ campsite — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/new-zealand-landslide-search-for-missing-people/106256570</link><description>Several people are missing after a landslide at a campsite in the tourism hotspot of Mount Maunganui, south-east of Auckland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23379a7a711cb4f2aedc78ee1266c283</guid></item><item><title>March for Australia administrators encouraged members to join White Australia political party</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/verify-neo-nazi-group-linked-to-political-party/106254196</link><description>March for Australia organisers are planning a fresh round of mass demonstrations across the country on January 26, with members encouraging others to join the now disbanded White Australia Party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61c84afa4ed39ce502156f3c3e35ad8b</guid></item><item><title>The optics are diabolical for Liberals and Nationals, as chaos reigns on a supposed day of mourning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/optics-diabolical-liberals-nationals-split-chaos-reigns/106256942</link><description>Littleproud and his team have now basically broken one of the most fundamental political rules of the Coalition — the Nationals are now effectively dictating to the Liberals who their leader should be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfc29a319f10b7654b1744b2408480f8</guid></item><item><title>In Davos, European leaders met Donald Trump with strength and he backed down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/european-leaders-stood-up-to-trump-at-davos/106256300</link><description>European leaders will be breathing a sigh of relief that the extraordinary threat of a US invasion of Greenland has receded. But some things cannot be undone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbd4efa493fa52920fc34df51ab08033</guid></item><item><title>Mount Hot Pools damaged in landslide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/mount-hot-pools-damaged-in-landslide-/106257412</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2367d81a746a6d3b8eaa418a7889faa5</guid></item><item><title>Former Texas police officer acquitted of child endangerment in Uvalde school shooting trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/former-police-officer-acquitted-response-uvalde-school-shooting/106257186</link><description>A former officer charged with child abandonment and endangerment over the police response to the Uvalde school massacre in 2022 is acquitted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17708e8c1b29425fc797e317e56d6675</guid></item><item><title>Territorians working hard to cull cane toads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/territorians-working-hard-to-cull-cane-toads/106254792</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01dc070978534f4b990110319cca61b2</guid></item><item><title>More than 1,000 cane toads captured in first Darwin botanic gardens bust in years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/nt-cane-toads-community-bust-invasive-pest-darwin-rain/106254926</link><description>Volunteers in Darwin have chipped in to capture more than 1,000 cane toads at one of the city's main attractions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b11df1d2cdc1b23fc82c0ad1ac738a15</guid></item><item><title>Australian writer Murray Hunter apologises to Malaysian regulator over criminal complaint in Thailand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/australian-writer-murray-hunter-faces-prosecution-in-thailand/106071904</link><description>Rights groups slam Thai authorities' detention and legal proceedings against Australian writer Murray Hunter, after Malaysia's communications regulator submitted a criminal defamation complaint.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a398c92859ab9deed27a35a44ed1eedc</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the landslide at Mount Maunganui in New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/what-we-know-about-the-mount-maunganui-landslide/106256852</link><description>A young girl is among those missing after a landslide hit a popular campsite south-east of Auckland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e511e863199a9a0e1e2142a420952e0</guid></item><item><title>Darwin locals volunteer at local cane toad bust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/darwin-locals-volunteer-at-local-cane-toad-bust/106257890</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85b6d139a7f1ea346764657bb5f1b245</guid></item><item><title>What's next, as Liberals and Nationals go their own way?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/what-next-sussan-ley-leadership-coalition-split/106256498</link><description>In the wake of the Coalition's divorce, there are few options for besieged Opposition Leader Sussan Ley, who must again reshuffle her cabinet and return to parliament with a diminished Opposition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">994575ca7514db7940e29e80b787ba77</guid></item><item><title>The 'Golden Dome' and why Trump wants the defence system in Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/why-trump-wants-golden-dome-missile-defence-in-greenland/106255982</link><description>Donald Trump wants a US "Golden Dome" missile defence system to be built in Greenland. This is what it involves and why some experts are skeptical of the plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7283312beb72caebfa691b8786b889d2</guid></item><item><title>Woman who assaulted psychiatrist and other healthcare workers remanded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/woman-who-assaulted-psychiatrist-healthcare-workers-remanded-vic/106256858</link><description>A judge tells a Victorian court the safety of healthcare workers must be protected while remanding a mentally ill woman to jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9a8a342d45019c7e529a6831781d169</guid></item><item><title>Friends pay tribute to Canadian Piper James after her death at K'gari beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/kgari-beach-death-piper-james-friends-pay-tribute/106256026</link><description>Friends of 19-year-old Canadian woman Piper James pay tribute to a woman who loved adventure and nature.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9391837a6355875001ab3cdb3c15b312</guid></item><item><title>Perth financial advisor Anthony Paul Torre jailed for taking more than $1 million from clients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/anthony-paul-torre-jailed-stealing-fraud-1million-from-clients/106255256</link><description>Victims of a Perth financial adviser jailed for misappropriating more than a million dollars from investors say his six-year jail term is not enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d61027d39caaea38c6adc2658d7601e</guid></item><item><title>Temperature could reach 48 degrees in northern Victoria as state set to swelter through heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/victoria-to-face-heatwave-conditions-temperatures-soar/106258280</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says maximum temperature records could tumble in some areas early next week — with the town of Ouyen tipped to reach 48 degrees — with heatwave conditions set to send temperatures soaring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffc39b6bc45cafd23e9f8074e1baa863</guid></item><item><title>National Party's Coalition split timing deemed 'unbelievable' on National Day of Mourning for Bondi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/regional-voters-react-to-national-party-liberals-coalition-split/106256646</link><description>The second messy break-up between the National and Liberal parties is concerning regional voters across the country, even in diehard conservative heartlands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70ea918e48b086454d41c22e7c84bed8</guid></item><item><title>Hot air mass travels across the country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/hot-air-mass-travels-across-the-country-/106258982</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6350b2e40cb4ca343f7d6fa28c5888b</guid></item><item><title>Geraldton man found floating off coast after WA police discover empty boat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/missing-boatie-in-geraldton-kenneth-robinson/106258882</link><description>Geraldton police find 61-year-old Kenneth Robinson in the water near Chapman Bay after they discovered his boat unoccupied this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46c8bbc7a43c4a84b2beb0c04bace03d</guid></item><item><title>Severe heatwave to affect eastern Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/severe-heatwave-to-affect-eastern-australia-/106258990</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">402399edc4093f7ebc9cfd5549cfb37a</guid></item><item><title>Two women and man killed in shooting in NSW town, gunman at large</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/lake-cargelligo-shooting-central-west-nsw-police-operation/106258896</link><description>Three people have been shot dead in the Central West town of Lake Cargelligo, with the gunman still at large.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ac8b0eb3a5d60e126006e896390812a</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Reynolds being interviewed by Gary Adshead in 2025.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/bruce-reynolds-interview/106258878</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db30559dfeea5ac89674f1a6e7a8959a</guid></item><item><title>City of Perth probe lays bare workplace 'crisis', erosion of trust between Mayor and CEO</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/city-of-perth-workplace-behaviour-probe-/106250502</link><description>The City of Perth has rapidly descended into a workplace of psychological harm, according to a secret report obtained by the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64fc50ebb57a43747397b8920642f9ac</guid></item><item><title>From Bone Temple to Oscar hopefuls, here are January's best movies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/what-to-watch-in-cinemas-january/106233164</link><description>Multiple Oscar hopefuls are finally hitting Australian shores this month, as well as the return of zombie franchise 28 Years Later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2272f4f6ef3115ef6805bda843c70c9</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106258766</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e59c5ef1942298829e1214a0c64fd5dc</guid></item><item><title>First LNG cargo from Santos Barossa gas project bound from Darwin to Japan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/nt-first-cargo-lng-santos-barossa-gas-leaves-darwin-for-japan/106258638</link><description>After a series of delays, Santos announces the first gas from its $5.6 billion Barossa project will be shipped from Darwin bound for Japan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd8bba37d4f040d1881712e836830e01</guid></item><item><title>DFES says thousands of lightning strikes behind bushfires across southern WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/wa-bushfires-great-southern-south-west-emergency/106256762</link><description>DFES says dry lightning and difficult weather sparked an ongoing fire emergency across southern WA, with one town still under direct threat from the flames.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6338c86bbb729cd5bf7447aff0cf8d50</guid></item><item><title>Maddison Inglis wins epic Australian Open second-round match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/australian-open-maddison-inglis-wins-second-round-melbourne/106258820</link><description>With a 10-point tiebreaker to decide her Australian Open fate, Maddison Inglis knew there was only one avenue to victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7da89e4d1adfe1038099cca78fbd4468</guid></item><item><title>Albanese apologies for Bondi Beach terror deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/albanese-apologies-for-bondi-beach-terror-deaths/106259358</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94b82df021fca2826d2b7b9e1c9e2f51</guid></item><item><title>Naomi Osaka apologises for 'disrespectful' post-match comments aimed at Sorana Cirstea after tense Australian Open exchange</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/tennis-naomi-osaka-apologises-sorana-cirstea-aus-open-exchange/106259566</link><description>Naomi Osaka walks back her aggressive retort to a tense handshake between her and second-round opponent Sorana Cirstea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09581ba0cb5ce587403760bbfce3cced</guid></item><item><title>Oscars 2026: Sinners break record with nominations, Jacob Elordi and Rose Byrne receive nods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/oscar-nominations-2026-academy-awards-sinners-jacob-elordi/106259128</link><description>Vampire film Sinners broke the Academy Award record for nominations with 16, while Rose Byrne was recognised for If I had Legs I'd Kick You and Jacob Elordi got a nod for his role in Frankenstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48c475fdedf71590ecb11f7edcbff1a8</guid></item><item><title>Climate change increased the chance of intense Australian heatwave fivefold, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/climate-change-increased-australian-heatwave-january-study/106253192</link><description>A study by World Weather Attribution has analysed temperatures during the intense early January heatwave. It found that what was once a rare event is now happening far more often.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c1638010033b66e55d7fe8893d1a603</guid></item><item><title>France seizes suspected Russian 'shadow fleet' oil tanker in Mediterranean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/france-seizes-oil-tanker-that-left-russia-in-mediterranean-sea/106260102</link><description>The move is the latest by Western allies to crack down on a so-called "shadow fleet" of tankers suspected of carrying Russian oil against international sanctions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43d6477f8aa1dc4292de5def3f75e127</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy flags trilateral Ukraine, Russia and US talks, while slamming 'lost' Europe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/zelenskyy-announces-ukraine-talks-with-russia-us/106260134</link><description>The Kremlin has confirmed the Ukrainian president's announcement, made at the World Economic Forum in Davos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7545f1ac1fc90719bebdd764e896542e</guid></item><item><title>The Nationals split shows the foundations of right-wing politics are shifting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/liberals-nationals-split-coalition-right/106257774</link><description>It is impossible to view this week’s events without the broader context of the relationship between the Liberals and the Nationals, how the electoral map is changing and what that means for right-wing politics in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e5d77a30c76d5a35cb630af005cbb89</guid></item><item><title>Questioning your relationship in the new year? You're not alone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/why-the-new-year-exposes-relationship-problems-/106224924</link><description>The fresh start of a new year causes us to reassess many parts of our lives, including relationships. Knowing whether it's time to call it quits or give things more time requires reflection — and support — as our experts explain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a8679e8fb180c317100f0812cb15f67</guid></item><item><title>Trump touts 'total access' Greenland deal as NATO asks allies to step up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/trump-greenland-deal-access/106260210</link><description>The leaders of both Denmark and Greenland say they don't know what's in the deal, announced by the US president after he backed away from threats of tariffs and military force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c54c670db00f8511a0c0a5ef5e47e881</guid></item><item><title>Australia names second-largest Winter Olympic team in history for 2026 Milan-Cortina Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australia-names-athletes-for-2026-winter-olympics-milan-cortina/106257140</link><description>From five teenagers making their Winter Olympics debut to five-time Olympian and gold medal hopeful Scott James, Australia has named its second-largest team in history for the Milan-Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9364382cbf12d3eab2d2239d3c30bf50</guid></item><item><title>Anger and confusion after Australian courier Sendle collapses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-courier-tech-sendle-collapses/106237380</link><description>The Australian company's customers feel like they have been "ghosted", while investors and shareholders are angry and confused about what happens next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75d4d8cc352fa82cac285f1a0bcac529</guid></item><item><title>Seven-day heatwave to engulf south-east states, raising bushfire danger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/seven-day-heatwave-for-south-east-australian-states/106258360</link><description>South-east states are predicted to bake through a prolonged severe heatwave from Saturday onwards, which has the potential to break all-time temperature records and fuel another round of dangerous bushfires.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e206661f047d7153c78444b4bf38fcc</guid></item><item><title>Fiji police allegedly seize $780m cocaine shipment in drug operation targeting Pacific Ocean 'narco sub'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/fiji-vatia-alleged-cocaine-bust/106252766</link><description>Fijian chiefs reported suspicious activity along their stretch of coastline to law enforcement agencies — which then swooped on an alleged $780 million drug operation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7b65c9bfdd418c9e913eeb19db1490c</guid></item><item><title>Daylesford op shop may permanently close after donation causes bed bug infestation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/daylesford-op-shop-closed-after-bed-bug-donation/106257322</link><description>The future of a Victorian op shop is in doubt after a worker opened a bag containing the stuff of nightmares, leading to the destruction of stock and hefty cleaning bills that may prove to be a deadly financial blow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92343d5a6b3a6f9e91a7d081f2faf352</guid></item><item><title>Six people confirmed missing in landslide at New Zealand's Mount Maunganui</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/new-zealand-landslide-search-at-mount-maunganui-continues/106259556</link><description>Specialist officers have worked through the night with earthmoving equipment to try and find those trapped under the rubble at a popular tourist spot on New Zealand's North Island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b56c3c64c991749e723a32a089f025b8</guid></item><item><title>Gunman wanted over triple shooting could be difficult to find, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/police-search-for-lake-cargelligo-gunman-after-three-shot-dead/106260214</link><description>Police have warned residents in villages neighbouring Lake Cargelligo to remain vigilant after three people were shot dead in a domestic violence attack on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6237034df4c10ee4887c72324b79c0b</guid></item><item><title>'Catastrophic' fire danger forecast for eastern Eyre, Yorke Peninsula, on Saturday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/adelaide-australia-day-forecast-fire-danger-yorke-peninsula/106257684</link><description>Catastrophic fire conditions are forecast for both the Yorke Peninsula and the eastern Eyre Peninsula for Saturday, while Adelaide is forecast to have its hottest Australia Day on record and its hottest day since 2019.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a53a3d4adffd3b13e7a584d13132823a</guid></item><item><title>David Speirs not entitled to public campaign funding, electoral commission says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/david-speirs-not-entitled-to-campaign-funding-commission-says/106252588</link><description>Former opposition leader David Speirs would "not fulfil the nomination requirements" if he applied to be a candidate at the upcoming state election, the state's electoral commission says, raising significant doubts about his chances of a political comeback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b51d1258f01f889f9ffa8d09f9b01925</guid></item><item><title>Solid start to AI camera trial with rock fisher rescue at one of NSW's deadliest locations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/ai-camera-rescue-rock-fisher-kiama-blowhole/106252572</link><description>Surf Life Saving NSW says the successful rescue of a rock fisher at Kiama Blowhole using two AI-enabled surveillance cameras proves the technology works.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e967a1d1c2cfc39de99b807ffaa9f852</guid></item><item><title>triple j's Hottest 100 of 2025 — when it happens, how to listen and more</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/triple-j-hottest-100-of-2025-date-start-finish-time/106255830</link><description>Australia's favourite music poll is back for another year — here's when it happens and how to listen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1040e2c0baec6105e30c997bf6a0c8f8</guid></item><item><title>Wawrinka's post-match recovery beer and an 'elite coffee snob' — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-open-2026-quick-hits/106256482</link><description>Madison Keys praises Melbourne coffee, Stan Wawrinka says he deserves a beer and Nick Kyrgios back to racquet throwing ways. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdb19a2b8f7adeb672b77b643c9797c4</guid></item><item><title>Homeschool 'drop-off' groups are booming but some say they are unregulated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/homeschool-drop-off-groups-australia-regulation/106192824</link><description>Education experts say homeschooling's exploding popularity has sparked a growing market of "drop-off" groups.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0ca7121cc29813c44dbfbed385a671b</guid></item><item><title>DNA found in an ancient Colombian skeleton may hold answers to origin of syphilis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/ancient-dna-in-colombian-skeleton-syphilis-finding/106257238</link><description>A previously unknown strain of syphilis bacteria has been discovered in human remains in Colombia, dating back 5,500 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">761f4136bcbedf14e3f88cb864e27b50</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios and Thanasi Kokkinakis lose first round Australian Open men's doubles clash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/special-k-nick-kyrgios-thanasi-kokkinakis-aus-open/106260326</link><description>After playing like "shadows of our former selves", Nick Kyrgios and Thanasi Kokkinakis are out of the Australian Open men's doubles and into an uncertain future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c0855d44f970a7bd97e76435b181e56</guid></item><item><title>ASX slightly up, Aussie dollar hits 15-month high — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/asx-markets-business-live-news-jan23-2026/106260382</link><description>The Australian share market has finished slightly higher after a rally on Wall Street, as investors showed signs of relief a day after US President Donald Trump dropped tariff threats against eight European countries. Look back on our Friday business blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40932dc245b230489389510db47af34d</guid></item><item><title>Inside the Syrian city of Raqqa, once known as Islamic State's 'Roundabout of Hell'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/inside-raqqa-syrian-government-kurdish-fighters/106259928</link><description>Syrian government forces have wrested back control of vast parts of its territory in recent weeks, as a new president moves to assert control over the war-torn country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7976dc278e108c80f77b0c705e6920d</guid></item><item><title>How cool rooms and cold storage work to keep fruit fresh year-round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/cool-rooms-keep-apples-fresh-year-round/106244706</link><description>Apples only grow for three months of the year — but thanks to an ancient technique, that doesn't stop us grabbing one from the grocery store year round.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18d4e3c1e52e7cd899af23bc7bc1ad00</guid></item><item><title>Defiant Sussan Ley downplays Nationals' split, vows to remain leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/defiant-sussan-ley-vows-to-remain-leader/106260460</link><description>The Liberal leader did not speak about the Nationals' decision to terminate the Coalition on yesterday's National Day of Mourning, but on Friday insisted her focus was on the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a7f9d5a8b73b778d178181d0ad4f49c</guid></item><item><title>Japan's demand for Australian table grapes drives export growth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-table-grapes-export-to-japan-demand-rises/106237572</link><description>A rise in demand is making it feasible for some Australian grapes to be on sale in South-East Asia within 48 hours of being dispatched.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7648010b07efe81af52be5bcd7df448c</guid></item><item><title>Canberra woman to face court after allegedly assaulting airline crew member on flight to Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/act-woman-to-face-court-after-alleged-assault-airline-crew/106260556</link><description>Police say the 52-year-old woman "forcibly grabbed the arm and head" of a crew member, causing them minor injuries, as the plane was preparing to take off from Canberra on December 13.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8d313f02dd8a6264c1556516aafe4d5</guid></item><item><title>Oscar nominations 2026: All the snubs, successes and surprises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/oscar-nominations-2026-snubs-successes-surprises/106260530</link><description>Hybrid horror Sinners came up as the big winner in the 98th Academy Award nominations, with Aussie actors also eyeing up gold, and Wicked: For Good wiped off the map.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d761bb2879eaa9851b2172d6c644d374</guid></item><item><title>De Minaur powers through with straight-sets win over Tiafoe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-open-2026-live-sabalenka-alcaraz-de-minaur-osaka/106260854</link><description>Alex de Minaur defeats American Frances Tiafoe in straight sets on Rod Laver Arena after Yulia Putintseva mocks Turkish fans after knocking out qualifier Zeynep Sönmez.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a04cafe18c649afd498aa7f1f3f47fbb</guid></item><item><title>NBL star urges middle ground on Pride Round after Breakers jersey boycott</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/nbl-star-urges-pride-round-middle-ground/106260522</link><description>As the NBL's Pride Round begins, Marcus Lee warns an all-or-nothing approach could shut down the very conversations the round is meant to start.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58242609ac0484472fb20c7700974f98</guid></item><item><title>Taylor Fritz pays tribute to 40-year-old Stan Wawrinka ahead of Australian Open match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-open-stan-wawrinka-taylor-fritz-third-round/106261080</link><description>It was meant as a compliment, rather than a show of disrespect, when Taylor Fritz answered a question about Australian Open rival Stan Wawrinka's age.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c2e005d319489a9f8a0eccc72657f11</guid></item><item><title>1,000 cakes and eight complaints: Brisbane picnic event under investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/qld-cake-swap-food-safety/106254312</link><description>An investigation has been launched into a viral Brisbane 'cake swap' event after attendees raised concerns over food safety and hygiene, with cakes reportedly left uncovered in hot weather for hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1e5dc3e8811ac8635e15909c20516d4</guid></item><item><title>ICE officers detain five-year-old Minnesota boy as he arrives home from preschool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/ice-officers-detain-5-year-old-minnesota-boy/106260888</link><description>School officials and the family's lawyer say the boy and his father were taken to a detention facility in Texas, making the boy the fourth student from Minneapolis detained by immigration officers in recent weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f1e66129057f445bb42e4ec7cae6d7</guid></item><item><title>Man allegedly doused Gungahlin Police Station foyer in petrol and lit fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/man-arrested-for-lighting-fire-in-canberra-police-station-foyer/106261084</link><description>Police allege the man entered the station with a jerry can, poured petrol onto the floor and lit it on fire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f76650c41aafda93d65436a756e99021</guid></item><item><title>Fresh melioidosis infections spark warnings for North Queensland flood clean-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/melioidosis-infections-mackay-region-flood-clean-up/106260730</link><description>Health authorities investigate a spike in case numbers for the soil-borne disease melioidosis over the past year as heavy rains again bring the bacteria to the surface.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1876832b56ff04f3a85e502de592162</guid></item><item><title>Illegal dumping creates eyesore and hard work at Sunshine Coast op shops</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/sunshine-coast-op-shops-frustrated-with-illegal-dumping/106247800</link><description>Volunteers say they are tired of "lazy" residents dumping their unwanted goods outside op shops to avoid paying tip fees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">871279b041aa2167b88a4b69d8849176</guid></item><item><title>Lanlan Yang admits to breach of bail after Rolls-Royce crash in Sydney's east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/nsw-lanlan-yang-court-rolls-royce-crash/106261518</link><description>The 23-year-old has sparked curiosity and intrigue among Chinese Australians due to her apparent wealth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b43c3604703b1dd2574a016e52f8ee24</guid></item><item><title>$17 million announced to push Wollongong sports and entertainment precinct closer to reality</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/wollongong-sports-entertainment-precinct-funding-announced/106261074</link><description>The NSW government has unveiled long awaited plans for the redevelopment of Wollongong's sporting precinct as it commits $17 million to develop a business case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff60335d34dbbef747d64f935b214079</guid></item><item><title>Paris Hilton brings sex tape story to Washington for AI deepfake porn fight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/paris-hilton-returns-to-washington-for-deepfake-porn-fight/106260660</link><description>The party girl turned anti-abuse advocate throws her glamorous celebrity heft behind a push to tackle deepfake pornography.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be3bdab756405b29eee8fe4b96735764</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone warning extended as tropical low edges closer to Kimberley coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/tropical-low-cyclone-kimberley-coast-weekend/106257742</link><description>A tropical cyclone warning has been issued for residents along the far north WA coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40b1ded951323489c7af96436cdb5857</guid></item><item><title>Interstate police reviewing use of force in Kumanjayi White's death in custody in Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/kumanjayi-white-case-update-death-in-custody/106261098</link><description>After resisting calls for an arms-length investigation, NT police are "facilitating" prosecutors' request for an independent review of the arresting officers' use of force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b04ff3a2a2c57cfe96d3912780dbf7f4</guid></item><item><title>US and China sign off on TikTok agreement to avoid ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/us-and-china-sign-off-on-tiktok-agreement-to-avoid-ban/105946464</link><description>Social media giant TikTok reaches a deal for a new joint venture in the United States to avoid being banned for American users. The platform's Beijing-based parent company, ByteDance, will retain a 19.9 per cent stake in the company.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98db492f98dbae94336107116f99f2ec</guid></item><item><title>What Bernard Fanning and Ben Lee's Hottest 100 topping hits tell us about them in 2005</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/ben-lee-bernard-fanning-2005-tea-sympathy-precocious-awake-sleep/106254430</link><description>In 2005, Bernard Fanning and Ben Lee were very different men with very similar struggles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4104fb0576195f6d49333b282b330b1c</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump is obsessed with Greenland, but now his comments point to the 'entire Arctic'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/donald-trump-greenland-maps-explain-battle-for-arctic/106248192</link><description>After a week of escalating rhetoric over Greenland, Donald Trump says he has now secured "total access" to the Arctic island. This is why that region is so important.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80258e25c9b73d3a371cfd33873c0456</guid></item><item><title>Queensland brothers charged by Australian Federal Police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/queensland-brothers-charged-by-australian-federal-police/106260960</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbe8574470d5b56affd5bb91706d698d</guid></item><item><title>Who is Indra Brown, the 15-year-old Melbourne schoolgirl going for gold at Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/indra-brown-australia-15-year-old-freeski-halfpipe-star/106220172</link><description>When 15-year-old Indra Brown reached the podium in her first World Cup event, she needed help from global superstar Eileen Gu to pop the cork on her champagne. She's had plenty more practice since, as she heads into the Milan Cortina 2026 Winter Olympic Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1bd2a59bbb1851f70a1c81a87c262dc</guid></item><item><title>Letter sent to Lakemba Mosque threatening violence on Australia Day investigated by police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/nsw-australia-day-mosque-threat-police-investigation/106260802</link><description>The note, seen by the ABC, incited violence against several groups, including Middle Eastern communities, Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islanders and a number of political figures from Labor, the Greens and "socialists" were also singled out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40a93d7c9c85c5131545560539c3e2e1</guid></item><item><title>Trump sues JPMorgan Chase for $US5 billion, alleging bank closed accounts for 'political reasons'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/trump-sues-jp-morgan-chase-jamie-dimon-closes-accounts-political/106260598</link><description>Donald Trump is suing banking giant JPMorgan Chase and its chief executive for $US5 billion ($7.3 billion) over allegations that JPMorgan stopped providing banking services to him and his businesses for political reasons in January 2021.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89430bef8f415825580494dd7adb60f5</guid></item><item><title>US officials tout 'New Gaza' plans filled with shiny luxury skyscrapers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/us-touts-new-gaza-filled-with-luxury-real-estate/106261524</link><description>US officials have presented their vision for a "New Gaza" that would turn the shattered Palestinian territory into a glitzy resort of skyscrapers by the sea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">332468f105e8f38eeb197372324b59be</guid></item><item><title>Track temperatures as heatwave sweeps across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/temperatures-heatwave-tracker-australia-day/106261904</link><description>Use our tracker to keep an eye on temperatures as a heatwave moves across much of the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e57e1f2214ee021677fa9f1ede08fbdd</guid></item><item><title>Final report urges Queensland to opt out of building accessibility requirements, government says it won't</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/qld-building-accessibility-standards-productivity-construction/106261950</link><description>A final report by the Queensland Productivity Commission recommended the state opt out of standards outlined in the National Construction Code.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44412ebf5637154213ddf0ac0f84d478</guid></item><item><title>Launceston City Council staff to vote on four-day, full-pay work week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/council-seeks-to-usher-in-four-day-work-era-on-full-pay/106261380</link><description>Launceston City Council and the Australian Services Union have reached in-principle agreement on a deal for employees to work 30.4 hours over four days, and be paid their full salaries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6de6e4998c9225528e97f7a38ee2254</guid></item><item><title>Who is the Neo-Nazi who was booed at Hobart's March for Australia rally?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/who-is-neo-nazi-nsn-member-at-hobart-march-for-australia/106243774</link><description>With the organisers of March for Australia rallies saying they "are in no way concerned by the presence" of members of the National Socialist Network, the ABC can confirm a Tasmanian man whose words were too extreme for many in the Hobart crowd is believed to be a leader within the state's Neo-Nazi movement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dd9e1cf44e49a7d888aa48587dc3692</guid></item><item><title>Labor identity Tim Picton remembered at Perth Stadium memorial service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/tim-picton-memorial-service/106255116</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is among political figures and business leaders who travel across the country to pay their respects to Mr Picton.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5d7055f3334cbd3e08a1546f091c39f</guid></item><item><title>Federal Court finds extended Victoria Police stop-and-search declaration was unlawful and invalid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/federal-court-police-designated-area-designation-unlawful/106262240</link><description>The Federal Court has found a Victoria Police move to give officers greater powers in Melbourne's CBD for six months was invalid and unlawful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff906739ce6790b737ba6a47ae4879b9</guid></item><item><title>What is a landslide, how do they happen and where are they most common?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/how-landslides-happen-and-where-they-are-most-common/106261240</link><description>Two people have died after a landslide hit their home in New Zealand and authorities are searching for several others feared dead in another slip nearby. Here's how landslides occur, the warning signs and where they are most common.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">851733bbedf99ceab4b1c59174b2194c</guid></item><item><title>How to attract native wildlife and birds to your garden</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/how-to-attract-native-wildlife-and-birds-to-your-garden/106042150</link><description>There are simple things we can all do to encourage more native wildlife to our gardens, backyards, balconies and shared spaces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a86ce4b9695adc5a6d1286749a33f7cf</guid></item><item><title>Video of bull shark washed up on Brisbane River bank sparks debate over AI technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/qld-bull-shark-brisbane-river-ai-speculation/106261868</link><description>A video posted to social media of a bull shark washed up in the Brisbane River went viral and prompted speculation that it was AI-generated, but experts say it appears to be legitimate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79cee32b8f5ede448241764cbe5b102e</guid></item><item><title>Sam Welsford wins Tour Down Under stage three, fears for riders with 42C temperatures Saturday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/sam-welsford-wins-tour-down-under-stage-three/106261424</link><description>Sam Welsford claimed a brilliant Tour Down Under stage victory, the seventh of his career, as experts fear for riders ahead of 40-degree Celsius temperatures predicted for Saturday's fourth stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38187f744e5d2eca7d5d7ad509f0a094</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania to introduce new gambling reforms, including mandatory facial recognition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/tasmania-to-introduce-new-gambling-reforms/106261384</link><description>The Tasmanian government has announced a suite of new harm minimisation measures to be implemented across hotels, clubs, and casinos, aiming to "reduce red tape and regulation".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3654d29a075aacd0656bac99b985bda</guid></item><item><title>Lake Cargelligo residents in shock after three people shot dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/lake-cargelligo-urged-indoors-a-neighbours-recall-gunshots/106260708</link><description>Residents of a remote NSW town of just 1,500 residents have expressed shock at a deadly shooting spree where three people were shot dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d8d66d4d35e438eccff0c1e13a7f7fa</guid></item><item><title>UK government says new passport rules designed with national security in mind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/uk-government-says-new-passport-rules-improve-national-security/106263628</link><description>The requirement for dual British citizens to have a valid UK passport while entering the country would help prevent the arrival of people who present a threat, Australia's British High Commission says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43f832a9617243fb7df73acd79487d61</guid></item><item><title>Friday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/friday-finance-with-david-chau-230126/106263986</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34ec08ab02b049799d6e47323e23bab7</guid></item><item><title>Fatigue a concern as massive fires continue to burn across southern WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/wa-bushfire-update-wandering-boddington/106263020</link><description>DFES says there have been no confirmed property losses as the battle to contain fires near Boddington and Wandering continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65513a7670758f54ef3746e5ebf3161a</guid></item><item><title>Yulia Putintseva taunts Zeynep Sönmez's Australian Open supporters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-open-yulia-putintseva-zeynep-sonmez-crowd/106263414</link><description>Kazakhstan's Yulia Putintseva happily plays the role of villain following her three-set win over Zeynep Sönmez at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97bc78ebf825d2b6a958edc49355cb10</guid></item><item><title>Japanese PM Sanae Takaichi dissolves parliament after only three months in office, setting up snap election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/japan-prime-minister-dissolves-parliament-after-3-months-office/106263926</link><description>Japan's prime minister, Sanae Takaichi, has dissolved the lower house of parliament, paving the way for a snap election on February 8.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7af2f321d4a3c3f3d0dfbbc805f880f</guid></item><item><title>To Lam wins second term to rule Vietnam through 2030</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/vietnam-to-lam-reelected-second-term-rule-2030/106263924</link><description>Vietnam's leader To Lam has been re-appointed as head of the ruling Communist Party for the next five years, and pledges to turbocharge growth in the export-reliant nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9955cc5f187fbcce22b63cc8db6f3dcd</guid></item><item><title>Lawyers call for Australian investigation into Israeli President Isaac Herzog amid genocide allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/calls-to-probe-israeli-president-isaac-herzog-australia-visit/106263374</link><description>The Australian Centre for International Justice has formally requested a police investigation into Israel's president for alleged incitement to genocide. He is expected to visit to Australia next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79c6b12747235201bc8fcc9a866d9ce4</guid></item><item><title>West Coast Eagles player Tyler Brockman charged with assault after Geraldton fracas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/afl-tyler-brockman-charged-over-geraldton-fight/106264146</link><description>West Coast Eagles player Tyler Brockman is charged with causing grievous bodily harm following an incident in Geraldton in late December.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ec2577e804e9db4e400b95d5de33a53</guid></item><item><title>Fire threat means Tour Down Under stage four loses iconic Willunga Hill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/tour-down-under-loses-willunga-hill-fire-threat/106264208</link><description>Tomorrow's fourth stage of the Tour Down Under has been shortened due to local bushfire threats and forecast temperatures in excess of 40 degrees Celsius.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dab1bf69dcea4fc7cf309f12ab43d0ee</guid></item><item><title>Jake Fenner sentenced to three years in prison over father's death in Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/jake-fenner-sentenced-for-death-of-father-nt-supreme-court/106252140</link><description>Jake Fenner, 32, has been handed a partially suspended sentence for causing the death of his father at their Moil home in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab2c8bc6fdb3610ca213e6d4be73e833</guid></item><item><title>Remaining bodies found from Indonesia plane crash that lost contact mid-flight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/remaining-bodies-found-from-indonesia-plane-crash/106264180</link><description>Indonesian rescuers find the remaining bodies of 10 passengers on a fishery surveillance plane that went missing in Indonesia's South Sulawesi province at the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2637844492492119507ce2830f1a639a</guid></item><item><title>Dingoes unlikely to have caused death of Canadian backpacker Piper James on K'gari, coroner says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/canadian-teen-piper-james-likely-died-from-drowning-on-kgari/106256020</link><description>A preliminary report from the Coroners Court of Queensland finds dingo bites are not likely to have caused the death of Piper James on K'gari.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12168408beb719f457f5902194785958</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith delivers again as Sixers down Hurricanes to cruise into BBL decider</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/steve-smith-fires-sydney-sixers-into-bbl-final/106264300</link><description>Steve Smith top scores for the fifth time in as many innings as the Sixers down the Hurricanes to book a place in Sunday's BBL decider in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e348c53fcfa7f88f916aeae4be93ff8</guid></item><item><title>UK PM Keir Starmer demands Donald Trump apologise for 'appalling' claim NATO troops swerved frontline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/european-veterans-outraged-over-trump-nato-troops-comments/106264332</link><description>Donald Trump criticised NATO during a Fox News interview on Thursday, saying the US had "never needed" the alliance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38f721a042e64bd07408956226a8a2b0</guid></item><item><title>Ukrainian, Russian and US officials meet for first trilateral talks to end war in Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/ukraine-russia-us-meeting-in-abu-dhabi-peace-deal/106264648</link><description>The Abu Dhabi talks mark the first known trilateral meeting between the countries since Moscow launched its invasion of Ukraine more than four years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58eba80797f636c2f7db6241a46e665a</guid></item><item><title>Hottest 100 quiz: How well do you remember past countdowns?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/hottest-100-history-quiz-triple-j/106237066</link><description>While you wait to hear who is number one this year, test your memory of past Hottest 100 countdowns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">355a47b8d47ae7693d3035362c3c91a4</guid></item><item><title>As Russia's war intensifies Europe is exploring military and economic independence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/davos-donald-trump-zelenskyy-russia-war-technology/106252046</link><description>As the world's elite gathered in Davos, European leaders confronted a reality in which they might need to defend themselves, and potentially against, the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">777407f3d912131f903aabe2a0e5650c</guid></item><item><title>From ultimatum to implosion: How the Coalition went its separate ways</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/how-the-coalition-split-played-out/106263654</link><description>Dissecting the implosion of the Coalition and figuring out what comes next has become a full-time vocation for the newly emancipated Liberals and Nationals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f29b55a2c0c1f764650c346e4ccff7cd</guid></item><item><title>US copied Iran's Shahed drones — now they are deployed in the Middle East</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/us-copy-replica-iran-shahed-kamikaze-attack-drone-strikes-trump/106232818</link><description>The US copied Iran's Shahed 136 drone. Now, as Donald Trump threatens military action against the regime, analysts say the US could soon use Iran's weapons technology against it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea93691d3fd263480d17ca56f198efa1</guid></item><item><title>Prince Harry takes on the Daily Mail in High Court privacy showdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/prince-harry-duke-sussex-daily-mail-court-case-principle-anger/106261250</link><description>The Duke of Sussex takes on the publisher he believes poisoned his childhood, his marriage, and his peace of mind in a legal battle driven by anger as well as principle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0734b45ec2433eaff1d6c9115bfcbc11</guid></item><item><title>Search for Julian Ingram enters third day following Lake Cargelligo shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/lake-cargelligo-search-resumes-for-gunman-julian-ingram/106262074</link><description>The search for a gunman accused of killing three people and seriously injuring another in New South Wales' Central West enters a third day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be92b25778e6ce54592c9759ee196224</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Luana forms into category one system off Kimberley coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/tropical-cyclone-luana-forms-off-kimberley-coast/106257746</link><description>Residents in WA's West Kimberley are being warned to prepare for days of wild weather, with a tropical cyclone forming up off the region's coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25fb2f9c9cb6af9ec15007da7b412fc9</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur driven to prove doubters wrong as Australian Open campaign continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/australian-open-tennis-alex-de-minaur-frances-tiafoe/106264260</link><description>Alex de Minaur is back in familiar territory, on the cusp of the Australian Open quarterfinals, but he is adamant he can make a deeper run at Melbourne Park than his previous appearances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f65a72004cb1c174e578be2ecb878b9b</guid></item><item><title>Australia smash Sri Lanka by nine wickets to stay unbeaten at Under-19s Cricket World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/australia-u19s-result-will-byron-sri-lanka/106264830</link><description>Australia have continued their dominant run through the Under-19s Cricket World Cup with Will Byrom's 5-14 leading the way in a nine-wicket win over Sri Lanka in their final group match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d9de7093079101b37bad476ef784e63</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur's wedding confession and Yulia Putintseva plays the villain — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/australian-open-2026-day-six-quick-hits-putintseva/106261160</link><description>Alex de Minaur has some thoughts on his upcoming wedding with Katie Boulter, while Yulia Putintseva plays the villain on day six. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89847952f8857b2a9bac637c4dd83daa</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Luana tracker map: When will it hit Kimberley coast in WA?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/cyclone-luana-tracker-map-kimberley/106263550</link><description>Track the path of Tropical Cyclone Luana and monitor wind speeds as the system approaches the WA coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">917916ce4c3d18e0f4e55b7d43427ad3</guid></item><item><title>Crews prepare iconic landmarks in Wonnangatta Valley ahead of total fire ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/wonnangatta-dargo-fire-high-country-landmarks-protection/105802954</link><description>A number of historic landmarks across Victoria's east have been given protective cover in case a nearby bushfire breaks containment lines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa61137659ad34170b48a7d0be70bdb7</guid></item><item><title>Australian Neo-Nazis use symbols that may evade hate speech laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/verify-neo-nazi-symbols-explainer/106258068</link><description>Viking symbols and a Norwegian jacket have now become synonymous with Australia's Neo-Nazi groups, but what do they mean?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f2701670a0fb89f719abd3c6cfdc0f4</guid></item><item><title>Track temperatures as heatwave sweeps across continent over Australia Day weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/temperatures-heatwave-tracker-australia-day/106263796</link><description>Use our tracker to keep an eye on temperatures as a heatwave moves across much of the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d78fc3dc49dc4e45663bc0aa841072a</guid></item><item><title>Inside Minnesota, Reverend Ashley Horan is helping people steer clear of ICE agents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/leading-the-fight-against-ice-in-minnesota/106248564</link><description>Reverend Ashley Horan lives one block from where Renee Good was shot and killed and by ICE agents. She and her neighbours have been tracking ICE's movements around Minneapolis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e946a892ab913ccf34bcadc83d433d0f</guid></item><item><title>Worst crown-of-thorns starfish outbreak in decades emerging on Great Barrier Reef</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/crown-of-thorns-starfish-outbreak-great-barrier-reef/106252468</link><description>Scientists are rushing to contain an emerging outbreak of coral-eating crown-of-thorns starfish on the Great Barrier Reef, warning it could be one of the worst in 60 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd5b86f1137da7bacc6ec43d7b35523a</guid></item><item><title>Anxious wait continues for families as New Zealand landslide search enters third day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/new-zealand-landslide-search-at-mount-maunganui-enters-third-day/106264352</link><description>Authorities have vowed to continue searching for those missing in the disaster, as officials announce an official review into the incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40fa8b66f6aae7a9864de0493e07b04d</guid></item><item><title>SA heatwave leads to total fire bans, catastrophic conditions and Tour Down Under changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/sa-heatwave-saturday-total-fire-bans-catastrophic-conditions/106262450</link><description>South Australia's hottest weather in six years creates dangerous bushfire conditions, which the head of the Country Fire Service says are "as serious as it gets".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3c13d73d888acbf298fb2981f3b0728</guid></item><item><title>Regional Victorian city of Bendigo facing future drinking water shortage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/vic-water-supply-regional-town-population-growth-bendigo/106008756</link><description>One regional city is 15 years from a shortfall of drinking water and some experts are calling for a trial to recycle wastewater into something drinkable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bc7037538f27474fe7cc21e66a877c0</guid></item></channel></rss>