<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 11:47:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Thailand and Cambodia set to resume ceasefire negotiations amid deadly border conflict</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/thailand-cambodia-set-to-resume-ceasefire-negotiations/106172396</link><description>Bangkok says the two countries will return to the negotiating table this week amid claims the initial peace deal was rushed for Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0a9248cdf5eb6362d084c7900e38b90</guid></item><item><title>Uber and Lyft partner with Chinese tech giant for self-driving cars in London</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/self-driving-uber-lyft-london-partnership-baidu-chinese-tech/106172408</link><description>Rideshare companies Uber and Lyft are planning to bring self-driving cars to the streets of London in the first half of 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07799d8eecaa4d60447d538bd0d97367</guid></item><item><title>Fire Rescue Victoria sues United Firefighters Union over $1.6m in taxpayer-funded 'service fees'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/fire-rescue-victoria-federal-court-united-firefighters-union/106170486</link><description>Taxpayers have funded $1.6 million in payments to the firefighters union via Fire Rescue Victoria, court documents allege, under an income protection scheme the state's fire chief has said should outrage all Victorians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d296d259896573cfec65636302462d92</guid></item><item><title>Unhinged Christmas movies quiz: Can you pick the real movies from these ridiculous plots?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/unhinged-christmas-movies-quiz/106170030</link><description>Once December rolls around, there's nothing the minor movie studios love more than getting their most unhinged Christmas tropes out of cold storage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbbe198736c3d76fbaa178e1abcf739b</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 23: Uruguay legalises recreational cannabis use</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/today-in-history-marijuana-is-legalised-uruguay-cannabis/106098248</link><description>Twelve years ago today, Uruguay became the first country to legalise recreational marijuana use. The experiment is still unfolding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dbd4de94678eacea566d0fe35fb3876</guid></item><item><title>Stephen Cubis was the face of GIM Trading when investors lost millions but his story began long before then</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/stephen-cubis-gim-trading-fraud-allegations/106119304</link><description>Stephen Cubis hides behind a charming facade, but his former lover and friends say the career con man ruined them financially and emotionally long before he was caught up in allegations of a multimillion-dollar fraud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cfe5b5d8f07f80cfb8a833285485b17</guid></item><item><title>Better late than never: The gas fix to a problem that should never have been</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/the-gas-fix-to-a-problem-that-should-never-have-been/106171870</link><description>The gas export industry has cost the nation dearly. East coast prices trebled soon after exports began.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0470bd441d7d2a44b48a2ac3241cd8d2</guid></item><item><title>Videos and CCTV give fresh insight into gunmen's plot to target Bondi Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/nsw-sydney-bondi-beach-gunmen-captured-on-cctv-court-documents/106171074</link><description>Security camera footage captured the Bondi Beach gunmen carrying what appears to be firearms out of a south-west Sydney property on the morning of the terror attack, court documents reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03c6804e5c43be5c058c3ba789861201</guid></item><item><title>Beekeepers on high alert as bee-killing varroa mite spreads in South Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/beekeepers-on-high-alert-varroa-mite-spreads-sa/106169566</link><description>The varroa mite may be tiny — only a millimetre or two long — but it poses a huge threat to honey bees, beekeepers and honey producers, who are on high alert after the destructive mite's recent arrival in South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5aa3ee9662557b777ee50394594dd024</guid></item><item><title>The Christmas display at West Hindmarsh delighting children, adults and nuns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/adelaide-christmas-display-with-more-than-50000-lights/106169742</link><description>Families from all over Adelaide visit Joe Ferraro's home to marvel at his Christmas display, which he has amassed a collection of more than 50,000 lights since he began nearly 20 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2338cd0eb9ddf16d0907b6d947de1ab</guid></item><item><title>A chaotic 'up-crash' as markets and economic realities made for a turbulent 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/trump-tariffs-interest-rates-and-ai-2025-was-a-chaotic-up-crash/106086538</link><description>AI. Market records. Tariffs. Penguins. TACO. It's been a big year of economic shocks and surges as the international framework of global trade was shredded. Here's how key players saw the year that was.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e7ddc548ef694d8dfa1af89e65ddf89</guid></item><item><title>Liberal-linked Tasmanian public relations firm Font PR shuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/font-public-relations-liberals-linked-firm-closes/106166618</link><description>It has helped keep the Liberals in power in Tasmania and lobbied on behalf of Airbnb, the salmon industry and the Catholic Church — but the PR firm, described as having "fingers in a lot of pies", is closing down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">543f948fad5f12a7a29dcf1d485996a2</guid></item><item><title>Sisters in Sweat — the Sunday football session that grew a sporting movement of over 15,000 Indian women</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/sisters-in-sweat-football-movement-without-judgement/106099240</link><description>Eight years ago, Swetha Subbiah was asked to run a single football session for a friend. She ended up starting a sporting movement, which now has 15,000 women and girls as members across Bengaluru, Mumbai, Hyderabad and Delhi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed9651ef82e6b78ef579a015ead48f9c</guid></item><item><title>Driving Home for Christmas singer Chris Rea dies aged 74</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/chris-rea-driving-home-for-christmas-singer-dies-aged-74/106172544</link><description>The man best known for his festive hit Driving Home for Christmas died surrounded by his family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e6f7b3d1f27dcde6842162454cd7219</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of birds are dying on a remote island with no end in sight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/bird-flu-h5n1-virus-outbreak-ground-zero-no-end-in-sight/106023290</link><description>The Isle of May is the epicentre of a deadly outbreak of the H5N1 bird flu strain which has spread throughout the globe. Scientists are warning Australia could be next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7ae9b9c9bcd889396f8f2a11ed8cabc</guid></item><item><title>Swiss court to hear Pari islanders' climate change case against cement giant Holcim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/swiss-court-set-to-hear-pari-island-climate-case-against-holcim/106172666</link><description>Residents of the tiny Indonesian island of Pari, which risks being swallowed by rising seas, win the right to have their climate change case against cement giant Holcim heard in a Swiss court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a371896b76ac1bd1722ed1a44c061714</guid></item><item><title>New early detection cameras in NSW spotting fires before they spread</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/early-detection-cameras-spotting-fires-in-nsw/106148476</link><description>New cameras using AI have been installed in southern New South Wales forests and are spotting fires before they have a chance to spread.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a01dbc68f02ba1994f106929e1d6f0e</guid></item><item><title>The Epstein files divided Trump's base and now more fights are brewing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/issues-dividing-donald-trump-maga-republicans/106156312</link><description>The release of the Epstein files followed some of Donald Trump's dedicated supporters launching a rare revolt against the US president. Here are six more issues that could also divide Republicans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8814af50d9c3ad3af1eb48acea71502a</guid></item><item><title>Cross-border commissioner's death leaves border towns in limbo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/queensland-cross-border-commissioner-role-remains-vacant/106170830</link><description>Towns, like Goondiwindi on the Queensland-New South Wales border, wait to see who will replace the late Ian Leavers in the role of cross-border commissioner and continue his work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cefe55302dc6b2a07e9509d21744486</guid></item><item><title>WA's water regulator is probing South32's impacts on neighbouring farmland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/farmers-south32-bauxite-mine-water-issues/106172120</link><description>The owner of a farm neighbouring South32's major bauxite mine in WA claims the miner is responsible for rising salinity and reduced water availability at his property. His claims are now being probed by WA's regulator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6844be562d85205ce3246437497d87ad</guid></item><item><title>Poor sleep, unhealthy diets and stress compound to leave homeless at risk of dying decades early</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/homelessness-poor-health-life-expectancy-falls-wa-research-finds/106165168</link><description>Western Australian research is showing a strong link between homelessness and poor health, with life expectancy more than 30 years lower for people without secure housing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">082793cf40319386a9f52dfc3194b670</guid></item><item><title>In a 'complete 180', graziers get early Christmas present with significant rainfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/outback-graziers-praise-rainfall-after-long-dry-spell/106171108</link><description>The heavy rainfall is welcomed by graziers and follows months of dry conditions in the state's far-west, with hot temperatures and wind battering the land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca7b1cd17ca020e646a26fdc2cb6df3d</guid></item><item><title>Thunderstorm arrives in Broken Hill ahead of Christmas.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/thunderstorm-arrives-in-broken-hill-ahead-of-christmas/106170696</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e8ddb3436c2f5f3dad01fef3259f950</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump sparks Denmark's anger by appointing US envoy to Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/donald-trump-appoints-us-envoy-to-greenland/106172806</link><description>US President Donald Trump appoints a special envoy to Greenland, drawing renewed criticism from Denmark and the territory's leader over Washington's interest in the mineral-rich Arctic island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d47e695db837cedbfa0b9806569e3d3</guid></item><item><title>Bonnie Deas putting WNBL lessons to use in US college basketball with University of Arkansas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/bonnie-deas-putting-wnbl-lessons-to-use-in-us-college-basketball/106172980</link><description>Bonnie Deas is shining in US college basketball, and she puts a lot of her success down to a WNBL semifinal trial by fire against Australian basketball great Sami Whitcomb.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d1a2899fdb1ccd94c03369778353fe4</guid></item><item><title>Plans to burn red tingle trees temporarily suspended following treetop protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/treetop-protester-wins-red-tingle-trees-fight/106171960</link><description>The WA government abandons plans to burn a parcel of forest that is home to a species of rare tree after a 70-year-old man spent six nights living in the canopy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f32f2e1eea3f2aa3d9b18dd66aa61514</guid></item><item><title>Residents of The Rock, in southern NSW, take on businesses to keep town alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/the-rock-community-takes-on-businesses-to-keep-town-alive/106127058</link><description>After giving to her community for decades, Barb's town is now working hard so people like her never have to leave for necessities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e190401ee760a35bdaa21ce228f4d2a</guid></item><item><title>Serie A soccer game between AC Milan and Como at Perth Stadium called off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/ac-milan-versus-como-serie-a-game-at-perth-stadium-called-off/106173042</link><description>A historic Serie A soccer clash between AC Milan and Como at Perth Stadium in February is called off, with sanctions imposed by the Asian Football Confederation blamed for making it "impossible".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7e9b55a5baed2dfd1d19b283c89073d</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Pat Cummins, Nathan Lyon out of Boxing Day Test, Jhye Richardson and Todd Murphy in squad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/ashes-boxing-day-test-squad-pat-cummins-jhye-richardson/106173288</link><description>West Australian fast bowler Jhye Richardson comes into Australia's squad for the fourth Ashes Test, while Victorian off spinner Todd Murphy has been named, and is a chance to play his eighth match and first on Australian soil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">806287eed1927541e69f203f07a9d6dd</guid></item><item><title>Man sentenced to home detention after hiring crane to damage Mount Gambier home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/mount-gambier-sentencing-crane-damage-home/106170580</link><description>A Mount Gambier man is sentenced after hiring a crane and partially destroying another man's home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9b22684c6fe49af81821fb37c05c2df</guid></item><item><title>Despite warnings from Donald Trump, the push for Israeli control over the West Bank continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/push-inside-israel-to-annex-west-bank-approve-settlements/106171756</link><description>Despite US President Donald Trump's objections to the annexation of the West Bank, new settlement projects are approved, with some Israelis excited while Palestinians are left fearful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a926996550c67c96a2815d6df973734</guid></item><item><title>Ferrari crash reportedly kills Call of Duty co-founder Vince Zampella in California</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/vince-zampella-dies-car-crash/106173016</link><description>Vince Zampella has died after a crash on a scenic road north of Los Angeles, according to local broadcaster NBC4.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1b47f1713b30f9a5548511d9072e9c6</guid></item><item><title>Newmont's Cadia Gold Mine to spend $300,000 on monitors after dust incidents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/newmont-cadia-gold-mine-buys-dust-monitoring-stations-epa/106170892</link><description>One of the country's largest gold mines in the NSW Central West will buy five new dust monitors after incidents at its tailings dam.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8b16aa24b0110d31f9b6c0be2269d84</guid></item><item><title>Historic giant sequoia tree in Hobart's St David's Park 'very, very sick' after fires and vandalism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/historic-giant-sequoia-tree-in-hobart-park-is-sick/106171168</link><description>An 88-year-young giant sequoia tree is "declining rapidly" in St David's Park in central Hobart due to a range of disturbances, including vandalism and fire, the council says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6948c23add1761505282eddcc4c6ca92</guid></item><item><title>Rain-hit orchards still producing 'best quality' lychees in time for Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/weather-impacted-christmas-lychees-are-best-quality-in-decades/106162250</link><description>After season constraints and rain-delayed harvests, this summer is producing exceptional Queensland lychees, according to the wholesalers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16e5cb33ab2fdee1026c2a58720857da</guid></item><item><title>Woman appears in court after failing to 'keep the King's Peace' and allegedly biting ACT police officer's leg</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/woman-fails-keep-king-peace-biting-police-officer/106173712</link><description>A failure to 'keep the King's Peace' and biting a police officer has almost landed a Canberra woman in jail for Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2531d9cd74672f55bbc06e81b72969cf</guid></item><item><title>Central West horticulturist supplying Australia's Christmas trees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/christmas-tree-farm/106170822</link><description>From a backyard in Wollongong to a booming farm in the NSW Central West, Christmas trees are big business for Lawrence Ranson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e22af694f47b16302ea864b1c9a24574</guid></item><item><title>Search underway for missing rock fisherman at Bushrangers Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/missing-rock-fisherman-illawarra-shellcove-bass-point/106173674</link><description>Emergency services launch a multi-agency search for a man last seen rock fishing at Bushrangers Bay, south of Wollongong, on Monday evening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">037b3f3ab8cd3a7554831089b0f671e7</guid></item><item><title>Judge accepts guilty pleas from Colorado funeral home owners for abuse of 191 corpses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/colorado-funeral-home-abuse-of-corpses-guilty-plea/106173848</link><description>Authorities say Colorado funeral home operators Carie and Jon Hallford gave fake ashes to some families of the dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94510927141a67201a522b4c22ebae6b</guid></item><item><title>Activist groups flag constitutional challenge to proposed NSW protest restrictions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/nsw-proposed-protest-laws-challenge-parliament/106172910</link><description>Three prominent protest groups flag they will launch a constitutional challenge to NSW Premier Chris Minns's new laws restricting protests in the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">468cd24a58fe5ee022ff63b33b818153</guid></item><item><title>Latest 'Battle of the sexes' commodifies and risks mocking historic event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/nick-kyrgios-aryna-sabalenka-battle-of-the-sexes-lose-lose/106174192</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka and Nick Kygrios' match marketed under the "Battle of the Sexes" banner makes a mockery of first era-defining match between Billie Jean King and Bobby Riggs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f9df8171a4c08b8311e5a2c2fe729eb</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese recommends changes to parliamentarians' travel rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/anthony-albanese-recommends-changes-parliamentary-travel-rules/106174182</link><description>Under the recommendations, family of parliamentarians would be restricted to economy class flights and an allowance for three annual "Australia-wide" return trips would be scrapped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dffd23670c5c0a70913dbe382d609bc</guid></item><item><title>Koala protection in south-east Queensland to be shaped by new strategy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/qld-koala-strategy/106173284</link><description>The Queensland government is inviting the public to have their say on a new strategy to protect the south-east's koala population.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">515cc2988cc82186aa02db050a98c33a</guid></item><item><title>Gregory John Walker jailed over Arthur Haines' death after 1998 Sydney firebombing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/nsw-gregory-walker-sentencing-arthur-haines-firebombing/106173498</link><description>Gregory John Walker is sentenced to at least six-and-a-half years in prison for unlawfully killing a teenager by firebombing a Sydney home in 1998 during an escalating neighbourhood dispute.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09dc039ee5b005aa683345d6db3c87cc</guid></item><item><title>Best podcasts of 2025, from Forged to Fela Kuti: Fear No Man</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/best-podcasts-2025-forged-fela-kuti-fear-no-man/106138476</link><description>Our favourite podcasts of the year include tales of art forgery, a documentary about the life of Fela Kútì and a true-crime thriller about a dead body in the ocean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ccd2f33573cb77c395b8b3bf699ea6c</guid></item><item><title>As a newly single mum, I am redefining Christmas with my kids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/spending-christmas-without-my-child-perspective/106129654</link><description>This is my first Christmas as a single mum where I will wake up without my son in the home. I won't be watching him excitedly tear into presents. It's not easy, but there's also some relief, writes Catherine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d5a38448fa2d7d2e1fb3e4cab6272b3</guid></item><item><title>No air conditioning in Shellharbour Hospital ward during heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/hospital-patients-swelter-without-air-con-during-heatwave/106173174</link><description>Patients swelter in an Illawarra hospital ward after an air conditioning unit fails during a heatwave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0799f44f22f84a2e18d9dabd6186cff</guid></item><item><title>Therapeutic Goods Administration issues warnings over heavy metals in Ayurvedic tablets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/complementary-ayurvedic-medicines-heavy-metals-safety-alert/106156510</link><description>Australia's medicine watchdog has issued another safety alert for contaminated Ayurvedic medicines. So what do consumers need to know about this multi-million-dollar industry?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f839cfc4577b67765d53fe3970548e3</guid></item><item><title>NSW oyster growers face contrasting holiday seasons as Christmas Eve rush looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/holiday-season-oyster-farms-christmas/106150290</link><description>The Christmas oyster harvest is flourishing on the NSW south coast, but further north it is a very different story as growers face the fallout of this year's record-breaking floods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f8cb8dd51a20c0fcd6787563277d3e2</guid></item><item><title>Severe Christmas heatwave scorches WA as Tropical Cyclone Grant strengthens offshore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/perth-wa-severe-christmas-heatwave-tropical-cyclone-grant/106174278</link><description>Perth, and much of WA, is enduring a severe Christmas heatwave with extreme fire danger, while Tropical Cyclone Grant intensifies offshore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2b1297740e2718b68e3eea718278a7f</guid></item><item><title>ECB managing director Rob Key to investigate England's Noosa break following Ashes failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/england-rob-key-ashes-noosa-drinking/106175002</link><description>ECB managing director Rob Key will investigate reports England's recent break in Noosa resembled a "stag do" as the tourists pick up the pieces from their Ashes defeat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12762fcf89066cd205121cc1842d1263</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins could miss T20 World Cup to manage back injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/pat-cummins-no-certainty-for-t20-world-cup/106175190</link><description>Pat Cummins could be held back from the upcoming T20 World Cup as Australia look to manage his workload following his recent back injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b31b570afd3d68bce0cd5d9eea32e598</guid></item><item><title>NSW police officer Jack Hibbert released from hospital after being shot in Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/nsw-police-constable-jack-hibbert-out-of-hospital-after-bondi/106165734</link><description>A young police officer who was rendered blind in one eye after being shot during the Bondi terror attack is released from hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">863fae5e27a1267508c77e7e0ee8c79e</guid></item><item><title>Delta Electricity found guilty over 2022 fish kill near its Vales Point Power Station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/delta-electricity-guilty-for-fish-kill-near-power-station/106173120</link><description>A court rules a maintenance failure caused hundreds of fish to die near Delta Electricity's Vales Point coal-fired power station in September 2022, a month after another kill triggered by natural causes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6a3a4a71e4f4e25cab04a2f450b4dd7</guid></item><item><title>Up to 1,700 jobs axed days out from Christmas as security firm MA Services collapses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/ma-services-security-cleaning-company-enters-administration/106175160</link><description>A "significant number" of employees have been made immediately redundant as MA Security — which provides security and maintenance services to major retailers like Coles, Kmart and Amazon — enters administration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f44180052c8f395d11dc624bad4134da</guid></item><item><title>CommBank reverses refusal to refund $68m in excessive fees for low-income earners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/commbank-reverses-bank-fee-refusal/106174050</link><description>The Commonwealth Bank of Australia will refund low-income earners receiving Centrelink payments approximately $68 million in unfair fees — just over a quarter of what was charged.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36c96e32b41f5ea3d1c941877dab0efa</guid></item><item><title>Woman treated for suspected bite after eastern brown snake became trapped in her shoe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/woman-finds-eastern-brown-snake-trapped-in-shoe/106174484</link><description>A woman has been rushed to hospital after a brown snake curled around her leg, becoming trapped in her shoe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96f7252ca6f2c8da2e9e7248ba2f775a</guid></item><item><title>Robert Donald Blackberry jailed after hay bale scam targeting Tasmanian farmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/hay-bale-scammer-robert-donald-blackberry-jailed/106173248</link><description>A judge blasts a man's "complete and utter disregard for the law" and jails him for scamming farmers desperate for feed out of money for hay bales he never delivered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae49e3a22372ec0d044afd7fcd498144</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal legal aid lawyers launch High Court challenge to NT bail laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/northern-territory-bail-laws-to-be-challenged-in-high-court/106175228</link><description>The North Australian Aboriginal Justice Agency says hundreds of people are likely being held on remand in Northern Territory jails "unlawfully and unconstitutionally".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e49a5a405e445c1c3aa1b16b1159033</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese and Sussan Ley release Christmas messages in wake of Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/anthony-albanese-sussan-ley-christmas-messages/106175306</link><description>Anthony Albanese and Opposition Leader Sussan Ley are urging Australians to "stand together" this Christmas in the wake of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5161d332a202792544fa6606a0dcdd23</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide academic accused of attempting to kill her ex searched methods to kill, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/lisa-lines-bail-application/106173090</link><description>A woman accused of trying to murder her ex-husband before fleeing to Palau has made a bid in South Australia's Supreme Court for release on bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2d2b9c476702795542e404d1c34872b</guid></item><item><title>US approves Wegovy pill, giving Novo Nordisk an edge in obesity drug competition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/wegovy-pill-approved-in-us-new-obesity-treatment/106175652</link><description>A daily weight-loss pill will soon be available in the US, after the regulator gave approval to Danish drug company Novo Nordisk's oral version of the popular injectable, Wegovy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2a5ee3d3b6d8085cb49ee03f61d25e8</guid></item><item><title>Cooler spring blamed for Tasmania's later Christmas berry, cherry harvest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/cooler-spring-blamed-tas-late-berry-cherry-harvest/106173424</link><description>Christmas is usually a boom time for Tasmanian berry producers, but this year's cold spring has slowed crops and hurt profits.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">705a5995417dbc7739b8e638b75d975b</guid></item><item><title>Do you know how to make the gravy? Test your Christmas song knowledge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/christmas-songs-quiz/106133752</link><description>Which Christmas hits didn't do as well on the charts as you'd think? Test your knowledge of festive cheer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a6f069aa41b131375949561d682b968</guid></item><item><title>Boxing Day sales set to be biggest on record as interest rate relief drives retail rebound</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/boxing-day-sales-australia-2025/106171474</link><description>Boxing Day spending is expected to hit a record high, supported by revived household spending after three interest rate cuts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad1a713797696e8327e634ed101ddcf6</guid></item><item><title>Australian businessman Ranjit Thambyrajah languishes in Vietnam jail after string of failed loan deals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/australian-businessman-ranjit-thambyrajah-jailed-in-vietnam/106174026</link><description>A high-flying Australian financier accused of swindling a struggling Vietnamese petroleum trading company has been languishing in a Ho Chi Minh City cell for two months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32afb45f1768c514427193990162ebc0</guid></item><item><title>A $7m unpaid tobacco fine and online sales emerge amid government crack down on illegal trade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/qld-illicit-tobacco-unpaid-fines-health-smoking/106170904</link><description>Illicit tobacco retailers have racked up millions in unpaid fines since the introduction of stronger penalties, with one owing more than $7 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">787337ed5dcf9686f03d4e519b1e3e37</guid></item><item><title>Rain on Queensland's Christmas forecast, north-west on flood watch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/rain-forecast-christmas-qld-north-west-flood-watch/106173584</link><description>It may not be the most welcome weather at the beach, but out in the west, rain is the best Christmas gift.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b341d575edef8b6616b4176339c1bf1a</guid></item><item><title>When Australia could get 6G after Trump launch of 'race' to next generation of mobile connectivity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/when-australia-could-get-6g-after-trump-us-announcement/106170702</link><description>Donald Trump says he wants the United States to lead the world in the "6G race" and has given his government one year to find out how to begin making it happen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37053cb6a573dc07d696125b84041868</guid></item><item><title>Pressure builds on Milano Cortina organisers amid climate concerns and funding issues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/milan-cortina-winter-olympics-pressure-rotation-system/106176102</link><description>The head of the FIS has raised concerns over snow and financial issues affecting the Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games, suggesting that a radical rotation system of hosts should be considered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1c1538ae355003cfb460794ad2eba12</guid></item><item><title>Runner Nancy Dickman, 83, prepares for her next marathon at 90</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/83yo-runner-nancy-dickman-preparing-for-her-next-marathon/106027164</link><description>Nancy Dickman has run marathons in London, New York, Rome and Sydney, and at 83 shows no signs of slowing down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ce23e10ca9dfe12fea5638e3ceed667</guid></item><item><title>Australian dollar jumps to 14-month high, ASX falls as gold and silver hit record highs — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/asx-markets-business-live-news/106176162</link><description>The Australian share market is down on Christmas Eve, despite the value of US stocks, gold and silver climbing to their most expensive levels ever, while the Australian dollar has jumped to its highest level since October 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c78068110747ab7aaa5444e314acc337</guid></item><item><title>Samoan weightlifters Seine Stowers and June Sipaia are breaking records and inspiring women</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/samoan-weightlifters-seine-stowers-june-sipaia-inspiring-women/106094176</link><description>Last month Samoan weightlifters Seine Stowers and June Sipaia broke World and Oceania records. Their success is due to a generational shift in attitudes to women in the sport, and a world-class facility at home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ff7f18ddc8be4a1eaf6607f4da501e7</guid></item><item><title>Woman's miraculous Arnhem Land survival story after ankle 'snapped in half'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/arnhem-land-survival-story-woman-crawled-for-help-ankle-snapped/106166278</link><description>Lying on the ground with her ankle snapped in half in the remote bushland of western Arnhem Land, her mind racing, and with no help or phone reception, Margie Moroney began to crawl.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2b76790497fb883ac74f29812ef09e4</guid></item><item><title>Mohamed Salah claims Africa Cup of Nations record as Egypt beat Zimbabwe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/mohamed-salah-claims-africa-cup-of-nations-record/106176216</link><description>Mohamed Salah scored at his fifth Africa Cup of Nations tournament in a row, becoming the first Egyptian player to do so.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f8aa2987bb15d6e3b13ebf9afa6596c</guid></item><item><title>Double-lung transplant recipient Johnnie Tumai's plea for Christmas organ donors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/double-lung-transplant-recipient-johnnie-tumai/106033118</link><description>Johnnie Tumai is preparing to spend his first Christmas at home since receiving a new set of lungs. He's urging others to register as donors this festive season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46e9d57e567decf05cbc39dff061528e</guid></item><item><title>Father of three meets bone marrow donor who saved his life for 'most special Christmas'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/wa-bone-marrow-recipient-meets-donor-special-christmas/106172104</link><description>Battling acute myeloid leukaemia, Gennaro Rapinese finally found a suitable bone marrow donor on the other side of the world in the US. And, after making a full recovery, he got to thank her in person in the lead-up to Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff6481214c7dc01941ff0685683c806d</guid></item><item><title>A US bone marrow donor is reunited with the Perth man she saved.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/us-bone-marrow-donor-reunites-with-perth-man-she-saved/106175644</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f6a78b0d2dd8bb934d9d8359a026d5</guid></item><item><title>Tarina Warren has been legally blind since she was 16, now a seeing eye dog is helping her navigate life on Moolooloo Station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/seeing-eye-dog-helping-on-outback-south-australian-sheep-station/106119816</link><description>Moolooloo station, nestled in South Australia's Flinders Ranges, might look like your typical outback farm, but the workforce at this station has one unique addition — a black labrador called Mika.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b31e319b326ff413922ba6b31841ec3e</guid></item><item><title>Convenience over tradition as gen Z and millennials favour pre-peeled prawns over the Christmas period</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/young-australians-not-peeling-christmas-prawns/106173238</link><description>New research shows younger Aussies prefer to save time and mess by buying pre-peeled prawns over the festive season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c26bc33a33387bfea269786da7f0eeed</guid></item><item><title>Bondi terror attack heroes to be recognised in new honours list</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/bondi-heroes-to-be-recognised-in-new-honours-list/106176488</link><description>The prime minister announces those who showed "extraordinary" bravery during the Bondi terror attack will be recognised in a new honours list.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51c14b2bdf7a6685f0595618026787e0</guid></item><item><title>WA farming community loses 500 sheep, thousands of hectares of crops in fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/western-australian-farming-community-loses-500-sheep-in-fires/106153256</link><description>A bushfire emergency in Warradarge is over, but farmers say the work to recover what was lost has only just begun.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80cdd9268fb9fd905e22ffb4920dd350</guid></item><item><title>Through my eyes: Jean Mitchell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/through-my-eyes-jean-mitchell/106162552</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f91acbae2647822d58a176ffd0a9be5</guid></item><item><title>Brooks Koepka leaves LIV Golf in major blow to breakaway league</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/brooks-koepka-leaves-liv-golf/106176562</link><description>Golf superstar Brooks Koepka has cited family priorities as he announces he is leaving the breakaway LIV Golf league.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">810822568c249759fa95a72196633a8c</guid></item><item><title>Kate Winslet makes her directorial debut with family Christmas movie Goodbye June</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/goodbye-june-kate-winslet-directorial-debut-movie/106150390</link><description>The actor talks about why she felt compelled to make the Christmas-themed film and why she was lucky to get Helen Mirren to play the titular role.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e87fd55db98fa5d4e281f9f4594d605</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Grant approaches Cocos (Keeling) Islands as severe Christmas heatwave scorches WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/tropical-cyclone-grant-nears-islands-amid-wa-christmas-heatwave/106176456</link><description>Preparations are underway far off Western Australia's north-west coast for the impact of a category one cyclone as Perth and much of the state continues to swelter in heatwave conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9eb942cdf56564b96e8cfcbca5123d93</guid></item><item><title>Sydney to Hobart yacht race not expecting repeat of last year's horrific conditions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/sydney-to-hobart-conditions-set-to-be-ok/106176678</link><description>The Sydney to Hobart fleet is in for milder conditions this year than in 2024, when two people died on the first night of racing, although sailors have been warned to expect strong winds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">997b2e54e1de0f06c49f224650477ac0</guid></item><item><title>'Fake' letter and 'false claims' among latest Epstein files, US Justice Department says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/epstein-files-contain-fake-documents-us-justice-department-says/106173212</link><description>The US government says newly released documents from the Epstein files contain "untrue and sensationalist" claims about Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bef3e57d6bc4b93383de3f48852bb8d</guid></item><item><title>Video purported to show Ben Duckett drunk in Noosa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/video-purported-to-show-ben-duckett-drunk-in-noosa/106176806</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4eada5fc8d18466db504c6096920074</guid></item><item><title>England investigates Ben Duckett Noosa video as disastrous Ashes tour takes another turn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/england-investigates-ben-duckett-noosa-video/106176788</link><description>A video said to feature Ben Duckett is under ECB investigation in another problem for England's disastrous Ashes tour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a005c9dfc957b64f8748c248130e1b6</guid></item><item><title>Sewage leak prompts Broadwater swimming warning ahead of Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/sewage-spill-broadwater-swimming-warning-gold-coast/106176726</link><description>Swimmers and boaties are being warned to avoid part of the Gold Coast Broadwater at Biggera Waters after a sewage leak just days out from Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2552642669cb5df34e8d569632c6cb66</guid></item><item><title>Girl, 12, critical after being pulled from water at Trigg Beach in Perth's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/girl-critical-after-being-pulled-from-water-at-trigg-beach-perth/106176930</link><description>A 12-year-old girl is in a critical condition after a surfer pulled her unresponsive from the water at Trigg Beach on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dc476927fc0183985b0e8c682a29246</guid></item><item><title>Young motorcyclist warns others after surviving high-speed crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/young-motorcyclist-warns-others-after-surviving-high-speed-crash/106174926</link><description>Liam Ganter does not remember the crash that nearly killed him, but he is living with the consequences, and hopes his story will stop others making the same mistake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75be536dbd463232b2f3e35ef40ba731</guid></item><item><title>Woman accused of 'repeatedly encouraging' partner to suicide granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/jacinta-drust-accused-encourage-suicide-granted-bail/106176852</link><description>An Adelaide woman accused of repeatedly encouraging her partner to take his own life has been granted home detention bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2aecc20ffe4f6337bc27a2b2f886f23</guid></item><item><title>WA Police charge man over alleged antisemitic comments on social media</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/wa-man-charged-over-alleged-antisemitic-comments-social-media/106177056</link><description>A WA man's eligibility to hold a gun license will be reviewed after police charged him with allegedly posting antisemitic comments on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98352c8c09ced2a521975680289691f9</guid></item><item><title>Man in his 30s dies in e-scooter accident in Geraldton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/geraldton-e-scooter-death/106176946</link><description>Police say a man has died after losing control of an e-scooter in Geraldton overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6e22dae3326e39867c80d88af856799</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after weapons, detonators allegedly found at Dublin property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/sa-man-charged-after-weapons-allegedly-found-at-dublin/106177098</link><description>A man has been charged after police allegedly seized explosive detonators and three unregistered firearms among other weapons from his property in Adelaide's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29bedf5020f9f578b2bc51f0e8088d88</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach gunmen's phone pinged near Philippine region known for Islamic extremism: police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/bondi-beach-shooter-pinged-near-philippines-extremist-region/106176954</link><description>Mobile phone data suggests the Bondi Beach gunmen may have travelled near a region in the Philippines where Islamic State-aligned militants could still be operating, a police source has told the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d612ea3d7aa44793790596fd88c30a31</guid></item><item><title>Low-income adults and children in jail denied lawyers over Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/legal-aid-nt-cancels-all-grants-of-aid-for-december/106176494</link><description>Legal Aid NT pauses all grants of aid for December, meaning people in the territory held in custody over Christmas — including children — will not have access to a legal aid lawyer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">740ca74252c85286eabe0390db4e2c46</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate alleged attack of Norwegian tourist on Melbourne's St Kilda Pier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/norwegian-tourist-attacked-st-kilda-pier/106177528</link><description>Police are searching for at least seven more people allegedly involved in an assault last Thursday, which left a Norwegian tourist with a broken arm and facial injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96f28abd7068699d673afb06c3d1af5f</guid></item><item><title>Concerns over abortion, vasectomies, IVF, gender-affirming care access as Catholic organisation Calvary buys Hobart Private</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/hobart-private-hospital-sale-calvary-abortion-concerns/106177108</link><description>The operator of the Hobart Private Hospital has agreed to sell the facility to Catholic healthcare provider Calvary, leading to concerns about access to surgical abortions, vasectomies and some other legal procedures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5430d43a7cde42fec16d598dafd02f8d</guid></item><item><title>England skipper Ben Stokes defends his team as Jofra Archer ruled out of Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/england-boxing-day-ben-stokes-noosa/106177474</link><description>England's disastrous Ashes tour has received another blow with Jofra Archer ruled out of the remaining two Tests while skipper Ben Stokes has dug in to defend his beleaguered team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d30958882c35c298deebc595e0fbf384</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs veteran Geoffrey Shaw remembered as tireless advocate for Aboriginal rights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/vietnam-veteran-land-rights-champion-geoffrey-shaw-remembered/106177422</link><description>Alice Springs war veteran Geoffrey Shaw OAM has been remembered as a tireless advocate for Indigenous rights in Central Australia, who leaves a legacy of courage and service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9eadafd0e8f634cc10d6af15eb22c34</guid></item><item><title>Bomb-making list, firearms, extremist flags seized from Perth man accused of backing Bondi attackers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/bondi-attack-supporter-charged-in-perth-raid/106177710</link><description>Police found a bomb-making shopping list when they searched the home of a man who allegedly posted on social media that he supported the gunmen behind the Bondi terror attack, a Perth court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36521dccd8b218e73f0e8c2c3deeac09</guid></item><item><title>Cocos (Keeling) Islands residents bunker down as Tropical Cyclone Grant approaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/tropical-cyclone-grant-approaches-cocos-keeling-islands/106176598</link><description>Residents on a remote Indian Ocean territory are bunkering down and scrapping Christmas plans as Tropical Cyclone Grant approaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1820ed804954b120204ea851c62b1136</guid></item><item><title>Even in the markets, it's beginning to look like Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/finance-report-241225/106177792</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b4f9300c7f3d9aad335a7ab323c356c</guid></item><item><title>US and Ukraine reach consensus on key issues to end war with Russia but territorial disputes remain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/us-ukraine-reach-consensus-on-key-issues-to-end-war/106178118</link><description>President Volodymyr Zelenskyy has said that Ukraine has reached consensus with the US on key issues to end the war with Russia but sensitive issues around territorial control, along with the management of a nuclear power plant, still remain unresolved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05c4eb8bd99fe5b814901714a1641ea9</guid></item><item><title>US sanctions five Europeans involved in regulating tech companies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/european-countries-slam-us-visa-bans/106178152</link><description>Leaders in Germany, France, Spain and the European Union slam the move as "intimidation and coercion".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64e74175013c5e059816621ae0498780</guid></item><item><title>Christmas quiz: How well do you know traditional Christmas carols?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/christmas-songs-quiz-traditional-carols/106133808</link><description>Do you know your Merry Gentlemen from you Three Kings? Your Dancers from your Prancers?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">824d802373eed7060a62552b3ca0c026</guid></item><item><title>Rental Family offers connection in an increasingly polarised world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/brendan-fraser-rental-family-hikari/106156660</link><description>Academy Award-winner Brendan Fraser speaks to ABC News about his new film and why human connection is the antidote to an increasingly polarised world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64796142ed39b4c48912a9c0e0b1a59d</guid></item><item><title>Daniyl's journey through the Carpathian mountains to escape Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/daniyl-s-journey-through-the-carpathian-mountains/106165118</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d7ab5a934f950abe14d683115d0e5b6</guid></item><item><title>These young men fled Ukraine, but found a Europe far less welcoming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/young-men-fleeing-ukraine-russia-war-find-europe-less-welcoming/106164084</link><description>Since Russia launched its full-scale invasion in 2022 thousands of men have fled Ukraine. Once welcomed, they are increasingly finding a Europe that is running out of patience.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d905f9e1324bb3c59e9004f0528c536</guid></item><item><title>How political divides are putting more pressure on Australian couples</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/political-differences-pressure-australian-couples/106048876</link><description>More Australian relationships are struggling because of political divides. But experts say this does not have to be the end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfdae25d8b39d3f18ef6996ee10d6146</guid></item><item><title>What you need to know before you buy lab-grown versus natural diamonds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/what-to-know-about-laboratory-grown-and-natural-diamonds/106167962</link><description>Diamonds are generally considered a luxury asset that holds its value, but the emergence of laboratory-grown diamonds in the jewellery industry over recent years could challenge that belief.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24202eae3fcc5aaa1137df26f99527c9</guid></item><item><title>Second-hand shopping is a sustainable alternative, but could it be fuelling consumption?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/qld-second-hand-shopping-thrifting-consumption-apps/106173026</link><description>The rising popularity of second-hand and vintage fashion has been viewed as an opportunity to reduce fast fashion consumption; however, Australia remains one of the world's highest waste producers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71947152529f5c6dfc7368acdb22a6f8</guid></item><item><title>'Aussie' poster in Adelaide vandalised with white supremacist message</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/racist-vandalism-of-aussie-poster-in-adelaide/106177068</link><description>An Adelaide street artist's poster aimed at provoking thought about national identity has been vandalised with racist graffiti.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72bd030ba7fd002b69b762b1060405de</guid></item><item><title>She readies for a 23rd Sydney to Hobart as the crew honours late owner Peter Rodgers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/sydney-to-hobart-she-peter-rodgers-memorial-race/106056430</link><description>A fellowship of sailors will embark on She's 23rd Sydney to Hobart campaign. As they do they will honour one of the most resilient boats in the race's history and remember late owner Peter Rodgers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e98f67c47d1cb8aba16c38df8cad139f</guid></item><item><title>What athletes mean when they talk about 'flow state' or being 'in the zone'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/the-science-and-art-behind-flow-state-sport-music-maths/106172880</link><description>There is a state of mind athletes talk about when they are totally absorbed in the moment and the actions of their sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3dd60dd0ec9a1fb90c71aed61ccdaf6</guid></item><item><title>Aged care centre confronts racism, improves staff retention with cultural celebrations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/aged-care-centre-starts-cultural-celebrations-to-address-racism/106085844</link><description>In 2024 a nurse reported racist abuse from some residents and family members. A year later, instances of abuse have plummeted and staff say it is because of a new program promoting respect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">106bbaf745444b130937df055a3765c6</guid></item><item><title>A million more Epstein files found, US Justice Department says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/more-epstein-files-found-by-us-department-of-justice/106178284</link><description>The Department of Justice says the release of the Epstein files will take "a few more weeks" after a million additional documents were uncovered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">864b6e61dd0c9445d283aae091533e8b</guid></item><item><title>White House orders US forces to focus on 'quarantine' of Venezuelan oil, official says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/us-forces-to-quarantine-venezuelan-oil-as-un-condemns-aggression/106178276</link><description>The White House has ordered US military forces to focus almost exclusively on enforcing the "quarantine" of Venezuelan oil, a US official says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29c3a7ae3d0bfc2c7ac85c07e2b281fc</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Grant expected to remain category one system as it passes Cocos (Keeling) Islands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/tropical-cyclone-grant-impacts-cocos-islands-christmas-day/106178056</link><description>Tropical Cyclone Grant is expected to remain a category one system as it passes just to the north of the Cocos (Keeling) Islands off the West Australian coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ee3c8641c0d4437378e06a43346d1a2</guid></item><item><title>Australia's 'outback fashion capital' promotes healing through fashion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/fitzroy-crossing-fashion-event-helps-to-heal-community/106037952</link><description>Almost three years ago, a region in Western Australia's far north was devastated by once-in-a-century floods. Now fashion is stepping in, to heal scars and promote confidence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e3fc90c6543ea536adf803f980f1417</guid></item><item><title>Christmas morning snow in Tasmania, amid Western Australian heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/christmas-day-weather-snow-in-tasmania-heat-across-australia/106178338</link><description>Snow has arrived in the island state on Christmas morning, but hotter conditions are expected around the country, including a scorcher in the west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fb3eda7326f3e7bb000780545f48802</guid></item><item><title>Pope Leo XIV, in first Christmas mass, says denying help to poor is akin to refusing God</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/pope-leo-celebrates-christmas-as-people-return-to-bethlehem/106178358</link><description>Pope Leo XIV holds the first Christmas mass of his pontificate, greeting thousands of faithful in St Peter's Square before the Christmas Eve service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1bbfae3937aecf803eae27b469b4e63</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate fire attack on 'Happy Chanukah' car in St Kilda East</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/happy-chanukah-car-firebombing-on-christmas-day-in-st-kilda-east/106178444</link><description>Authorities were called to a St Kilda East residence about 3am, where a car with a sign celebrating the Jewish holiday had been set alight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25fe8d829748789520bc501f02af6f27</guid></item><item><title>Why is there a massive camera in this tiny outback town?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/why-is-there-a-massive-camera-in-this-tiny-outback-town-/106178014</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ad7e44111139ee42ee84852115b69d6</guid></item><item><title>Analogue camera technicians with decades of experience retiring amid boom in film photography</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/future-of-film-as-camera-repairers-retire/106012478</link><description>As film photography surges in popularity among younger generations, technicians who repair analogue cameras are retiring, raising concerns it will become a dying art.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f2260136cba1cb406538e0cd51e9a96</guid></item><item><title>Nick Bolkus, long-time Labor senator and Hawke-Keating-era minister, dies aged 75</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/nick-bolkus-obituary/106178484</link><description>Nick Bolkus, the long-time Labor senator who played an influential role in shaping Australia's migration policy under prime minister Paul Keating, has died aged 75.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2580267b3575e4e215ac342a2ffa5f6a</guid></item><item><title>Public assemblies banned for 14 days across Sydney as police enforce new powers under protest laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/public-assemblies-banned-14-days-in-sydney-under-new-protest-law/106178406</link><description>The NSW Police Commissioner, Mal Lanyon, has activated new powers prescribed under changes to NSW protest laws sparked by the terrorist attack at Bondi Beach on December 14.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0ffae786ed4d39fb5070328bf4f1a2a</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Australia leaves out a spinner in all-pace bowling attack for MCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/australia-boxing-day-test-12-man-squad/106178630</link><description>With up to 10mm of grass on the MCG pitch, Australia has opted for a bold and historic option and left out offspinner Todd Murphy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa9a9b3b335c8c7dde4f63a8f42f6ad8</guid></item><item><title>'Scandinavian sleep method' could help your bad sleep</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/scandinavian-sleep-method-hot-cold-doona-temperature/106171152</link><description>This arrangement allows couples to continue sleeping together while meeting each person's individual needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd2b759a8a0d6dd541f517639ef58108</guid></item><item><title>Multiple bushfires threaten homes north and south of Perth, triggering power outages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/christmas-day-boddington-bushfire-emergency/106178756</link><description>Several bushfires burning north and south of Perth have caused major power blackouts, including the entire town of Margaret River.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02cd42472ece8c0d5742158fbddf1ee2</guid></item><item><title>Police make emergency declaration after partial crane collapse on the Gold Coast on Christmas Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/qld-crane-collapse-gold-coast-christmas-day/106178834</link><description>Storms hit south-east Queensland on Christmas Day afternoon, knocking out power to thousands of homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">554a17c52ea5b34c83e1e5244c87a2a7</guid></item><item><title>Pope Leo decries conditions in Gaza during Christmas Day speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/pope-leo-decries-conditions-in-gaza-christmas-speech/106178920</link><description>During his Urbi et Orbi (city and world) speech on Christmas Day, Pope Leo XIV has called for an end to all wars and for people to think about the conditions in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1023451f4ca1f78f346c0e2c228d714b</guid></item><item><title>King Charles pays homage to acts of 'spontaneous bravery' in Christmas Day message</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/king-charles-pays-homage-to-bondi-bravery-in-christmas-message/106176872</link><description>King Charles III pays homage to those who confronted terror at the Bondi Beach massacre, acknowledging their "spontaneous acts of bravery" in his annual Christmas message.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d976b5e35ca80ce775947a9f3227240b</guid></item><item><title>The marathon mums competing in the Olympics and breaking records postpartum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/marathon-mums-competing-olympics-breaking-records-postpartum/106158638</link><description>For decades, pregnancy was seen as an "injury" that could end a career. But now, determination and growing industry support are seeing marathon-running mothers reach new heights after giving birth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">911ad6e201fbaac1ec3430b377f3fe12</guid></item><item><title>From Spongebob to Orwell: Here's your guide to Boxing Day movies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/what-to-watch-boxing-day-cinemas/106170510</link><description>The soaring mercury has you craving the cool, dark sanctuary of the cinema. But what to see? The art-house awards-season hopeful? The psychological book adaptation? The one with the big snake?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0067604e8d12d4c660cec1c700395679</guid></item><item><title>Before Prince Harry fled the royals there was love-sick Edward</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/royal-family-prince-edward-history-love-harry/105522404</link><description>Before Harry fled the royals for Meghan and Montecito, this would-be king of England was famous for trading his title for love. And the cracks began to show on a trip to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0ca9182ddc5496c024a43a96389693c</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 26: Babe Ruth is sold to the Yankees to start the 'Curse of the Bambino'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/today-in-history-babe-ruth-is-sold-from-red-sox-to-the-yankees/106135072</link><description>It was the deal that changed the face of baseball for good, and set in motion the most infamous sporting curse of all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e5ab3496ff758523bc2b53626c7ae12</guid></item><item><title>Gamba grass risks star attractions in NT's beloved Litchfield National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/nt-national-park-under-threat-from-invasive-gamba-grass-weed/106167898</link><description>Much-loved by locals and bringing in more than 250,000 visitors a year, Litchfield National Park has become one of the Northern Territory's star attractions. But it's under threat from a near-invisible invader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b403c062bde0be6fd104443d00f5983e</guid></item><item><title>How to track Sydney to Hobart yacht race 2025 and other questions answered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/sydney-hobart-yacht-race-2025-how-to-watch-explainer/106165964</link><description>Black sails, a tiny cannon, no prize money — everything you need to know about the Sydney to Hobart yacht race, ahead of its 80th edition, starting today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93cb21fc77a0e2af01d8a8b4e6258273</guid></item><item><title>Shield and First Guardian raise the question, who pays when super funds collapse?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/first-guardian-investors-dealt-another-devastating-blow/106145496</link><description>Thousands of First Guardian investors were dealt another devastating blow when it was revealed just $1.6 million had been recovered from the almost $450 million invested in the collapsed fund. Who will end up paying investors back their lost retirement savings?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61ee5120fe363a2c94729fb05ef29323</guid></item><item><title>King Charles delivers annual Christmas message</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/king-charles-delivers-annual-christmas-message-/106179278</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39d40c75c736870f8c155790eac970df</guid></item><item><title>Monitoring cameras help determine Adélie penguin colony size</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/adelie-penguins-timelapse/106157940</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87708cd86d3a08507b2e7ec75b9abd83</guid></item><item><title>Scientists on 'high alert' as bird flu threat looms over Australian Antarctic Territory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/bird-flu-threat-looms-over-australian-antarctic-territory/106171164</link><description>Preparations are underway for the arrival of the deadly H5 strain of bird flu in the Australian Antarctic Territory, as scientists gather baseline population data so they can measure potential deaths among wildlife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e7609304214a3894f11e91309f5811f</guid></item><item><title>Women and girls coming to the crease in more numbers at regional Victorian cricket clubs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/country-womens-cricket-victoria-batswomen-bowlers/105904124</link><description>More women of all ages are signing up to play cricket in regional Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7db42b0b2843ee1230ad3286d1379a35</guid></item><item><title>Social media can help save lives during cyclone season, but also has a tendency to spread misinformation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/qld-cyclones-social-media-pros-and-cons-misinformation/106159684</link><description>State government reports have found that while social media plays a vital role in warning communities during tropical cyclones, some posts can lack context and spread misinformation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27e545f26b68033e05466ed4d78a058d</guid></item><item><title>Entertainer Kamahl, now 91, reflects on life, career spanning 70 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/kamahl-entertainer-reflects-on-life-70-year-career-racism/106132732</link><description>At 91, Malaysian-born Australian entertainment legend Kamahl reflects on his life and career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b946d4eaecacc1a82baa773ab3a7fab2</guid></item><item><title>Aunty's Free Feeds volunteers serving free meals from Palmerston car park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/feeding-the-hungry-food-insecurity-nt-australia/106168364</link><description>For almost six years, Aunty's Free Feeds has been serving home-cooked meals to anybody who needs them from a pop-up buffet in the car park of a swimming pool.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5411d2c7760ac2f1c3e1ed9f136453d</guid></item><item><title>The best classical music and jazz stories of 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/best-classical-music-and-jazz-stories-2025/106176460</link><description>From homegrown heroes to visiting legends, here are Australia's favourite classical music and jazz stories this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e20a46b15fc67a0c56dc741372cd716d</guid></item><item><title>Boxing Day Test more than just cricket for descendant of Australia's First XI Aboriginal team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/boxing-day-test-medal-presenter-honours-aboriginal-cricket-team/106137822</link><description>They travelled on horse and cart and were smuggled on a boat for three months to England, the story of the First XI Aboriginal cricket team is being remembered as a descendant presents the Boxing Day medal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b50808a74cf8fa3304dee6cab90223c8</guid></item><item><title>Cricket cartoons illustrate a match to rival the Ashes played by prisoners of war during WWII</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/substitute-ashes-world-war-2-prisoners-of-war/106169886</link><description>As Australia and England clash in The Ashes cricket series, Australian War Memorial historians have uncovered two diaries that recount a cricket series played behind barbed wire in prisoner of war camps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbbcb825611802eb1f7caa6a303768cd</guid></item><item><title>Bells and bonfires — Christmas celebrations around the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/christmas-celebrations-around-the-world/106179306</link><description>From Bethlehem to Beijing, people around the world have been celebrating Christmas in their own traditional way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9b0565c226191e73c1d21e704691bc1</guid></item><item><title>Hoop dreams come true as first Indigenous basketball team heads to USA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/indigenous-basketball-team-heads-to-usa/106158408</link><description>School attendance was just as important as a jump shot for the scouts picking a First Nations team to take part in a prestigious US basketball competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d34d1da0da81d4b5ea855db9d5a3d0b9</guid></item><item><title>Why Australian Open organisers will be torn on offering Nick Kyrgios a wildcard berth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/nick-kyrgios-australian-open-wildcard-update/106179426</link><description>Nick Kyrgios remains one of Australian tennis' biggest names, but, according to Mark Philippoussis, there are clear pros and cons to offering him a wildcard berth for the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db1b5fc77ce0878c8ec246e2f1b02586</guid></item><item><title>New virtual fencing laws could promise safer bushfire response by allowing farmers to move stock remotely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/virtual-fencing-could-help-in-bushfire-response/106170506</link><description>New technology allowing livestock to be remotely moved via electronic collars has been legalised in SA. Industry says virtual fencing has the potential to save animals and even human lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">192897585527f4b7df9b5fd155d53c37</guid></item><item><title>Endangered malleefowl chick saved in 2,000-hectare fire at Wyperfeld National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/malleefowl-chick-saved-wyperfeld-national-park-bushfire/106176370</link><description>An endangered malleefowl chick has been saved from a 2,000-hectare bushfire in a regional Victorian national park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddefccd7a2b1c56365c12e2baad72bb7</guid></item><item><title>Endangered malleefowl chick saved from fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/endangered-malleefowl-chick-saved-from-fire/106177074</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b90ce9d521644bc3b0b15c52ef61269</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Australia all out for 152 on Boxing Day Test, England bowled out for 110 in reply on day one at the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/live-updates-ashes-boxing-day-test-australia-vs-england-day-one/106179504</link><description>Australia lead England by 42 runs on a wild Boxing Day after 20 wickets fall on the first day at the MCG. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c303409339583878a217bf5cfe4bcd88</guid></item><item><title>Skippering school kids along Magela Creek system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/skippering-school-kids-along-magela-creek-system/105848148</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">086f23f55822e022cf4fbfd0a56d6f3f</guid></item><item><title>Drone shot above Kakadu sandstone country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/drone-shot-above-kakadu-sandstone-country/105848288</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7abfe75eded55e4d3e718a23038566e</guid></item><item><title>Driving near Kakadu wetlands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/driving-near-kakadu-wetlands/105848610</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44a6b4f95afbb0fa7eee54fb5a7f017c</guid></item><item><title>King tide at Nightcliff beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/king-tide-at-nightcliff-beach/105848020</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18f6764d3b52708bd856985f15fa3f13</guid></item><item><title>Dead trees in Tommy Cutt creek</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/dead-trees-in-tommy-cutt-creek/105848200</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a02e7b174f7540e1f7c00b2fcb96175</guid></item><item><title>Panning shot over Kakadu National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/panning-shot-over-kakadu-national-park/106179456</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eeb462767c44fbab555df86f304749f4</guid></item><item><title>When can you get a refund or exchange under Australian law?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/what-are-the-return-and-exchange-rights-in-australia/106078512</link><description>It can feel awkward asking for a refund or to exchange an item if you’re not sure what you’re entitled to. We’ve broken it down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2723be7871092c53be9590ed79e4005</guid></item><item><title>Türkiye detains 115 alleged Islamic State members 'planning attacks during Christmas'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/turkiye-detains-115-alleged-is-members/106179536</link><description>Istanbul's prosecutor general says intelligence picked up on plans for potential Islamic State attacks during the end-of-year holiday period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f836656caae2c1112d7b73e0c41506e0</guid></item><item><title>Pedestrian struck in hit-and-run during Christmas Day Tasmania breath test evasion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/pedestrian-tasmanian-hit-and-run-after-police-breath-test/106179584</link><description>A 23-year-old driver in a hit-and-run on Christmas Day following a roadside breath-test evasion in Tasmania's north west has been charged by police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">056c2be17ffd6886c7f1fa385294adb8</guid></item><item><title>Vladimir Putin critic and pro-war activist sentenced to six years in prison by Russian court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/russian-court-sentences-war-activist-and-putin-critic-to-prison/106179590</link><description>Sergei Udaltsov, the leader of the Left Front movement that opposes President Vladimir Putin, was arrested last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f46694fd12b3eb7d27f87246e14db092</guid></item><item><title>In search of the perfect lasagne in South Fremantle — the annual bake-off that has become a tradition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/lasagne-competition-in-south-fremantle-resumes-italy-taste/106155364</link><description>Neighbours in Perth's southern suburbs are baking-off in an annual lasagne-making competition that shuts down the entire street and has been running since 1998.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cc678ad1899f1c5b33f3a8d6f49d0a7</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump launches US strikes against Islamic State militants in Nigeria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/donald-trump-ordered-strikes-against-islamic-state-nigeria/106179626</link><description>Donald Trump says he ordered a "powerful and deadly strike against ISIS terrorist scum" for targeting Christians at levels not seen for years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e78e946ebf1f357d5108534304674ddc</guid></item><item><title>Revellers swarm Coogee Beach for Christmas Day celebrations after Bronte Beach off-limits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/nsw-christmas-cleanup-at-coogee-beach/106179370</link><description>As thousands of revellers spend Boxing Day recovering, Randwick City Council staff worked through the night to remove 20 tonnes of rubbish following a wild pop-up Christmas Day dance party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd1eb32a6dbb9b663390c3bdee8ebf93</guid></item><item><title>Tim Wilson desires to one day lead the federal Liberal Party</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/tim-wilson-liberal-party-politics-now-the-interview/106162420</link><description>In a broad ranging interview for the Politics Now podcast, Liberal MP Tim Wilson speaks about what the Liberal Party should be fighting for and why he would one day like to be its leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0109c7585acd76bdfd34229961e7858a</guid></item><item><title>Were you paying attention to the news cycle this year? Test your memory here</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/year-in-news-quiz-2025/106131666</link><description>The new year is fast approaching and it's naturally got ABC journalists reflecting on the year that's been. But how much of it do you remember?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">348990f5ad9942bf13ae9306c1c147b5</guid></item><item><title>Fishing facilities lacking despite high boat ownership in Karratha</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/karratha-boating-fishing-lack-of-toilets-filleting-facilities/106093260</link><description>Female fishers say the lack of toilet facilities at Karratha boat ramps does not cater for the increasing number of women on the water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef18396e1b505919d63f589ce903e197</guid></item><item><title>Boddington gold mine infrastructure damaged in out-of-control bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/boddington-fire-western-australia-christmas-fires/106179544</link><description>The bushfire remains uncontained and out of control, and has burnt through nearly 3,700 hectares.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e98a4c122f6d614247d735cd5c74867d</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast exclusion zone displacing tourists will continue until crane can be dismantled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/damaged-crane-gold-coast-80-tourists-evacuated/106179414</link><description>Holiday-makers spent Christmas night in temporary accommodation after a crane damaged in a Gold Coast storm caused authorities to evacuate several streets around Southport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0e6df85ea6ebde13f9f577d928f21f5</guid></item><item><title>Police name person of interest in arson attack on 'Happy Chanukah' car in Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/police-name-person-of-interest-hanukkah-vehicle-arson/106179668</link><description>Officers in Melbourne's south continue to investigate an arson attack on a car with a Hanukkah decoration in the early hours of Christmas morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8296de41305e534266d705e1ae6c66e</guid></item><item><title>2025 Sydney to Hobart Yacht Race: Day one of the 80th edition of the blue water classic, as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/sydney-to-hobart-yacht-race-live-blog/106179718</link><description>Master Lock Comanche takes over from LawConnect late on day one of the Sydney to Hobart, as tough conditions take their toll on the fleet, forcing a number of retirements. Look back at the action in our blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a51b09c950062dc669c8df81130ac30e</guid></item><item><title>Shopper stampedes are a thing of the past, but Boxing Day sales are still a big driver of spending</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/shoppers-hit-boxing-day-sales/106179634</link><description>The Australian Retailers Association is predicting a 4 per cent rise in spending in the Boxing Day sales, despite tough economic conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1fccd889508af2afe87117790536d76</guid></item><item><title>US judge blocks deportation of British anti-disinformation activist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/us-barred-from-deporting-campaigner-imran-ahmed/106179794</link><description>A US judge temporarily blocks the Trump administration from detaining a British man over his work combating online hate and disinformation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a392805d99ee3699f0176ec99c0501a</guid></item><item><title>Storms leave at least three people dead in Southern California</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/storms-cause-floods-mudslides-and-deaths-southern-california/106179572</link><description>State authorities have declared a state of emergency in several counties, including Los Angeles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6004e51695b9dfeaf39ed3284b05a5d4</guid></item><item><title>Winner in Arkansas lands a $2.7 billion Powerball lottery jackpot on Christmas Eve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/powerball-lottery-us-jackpot-winner-arkansas/106179926</link><description>The winning ticket was sold at a Murphy USA in Cabot, lottery officials in Arkansas said on Thursday, local time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">369e217e3507b496448f8101cf7120d1</guid></item><item><title>Teenager charged over Nazi salutes granted bail after spending Christmas Day in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/teen-zachery-hook-charged-nazi-salutes-canberra/106179974</link><description>An 18-year-old Canberra man accused of performing Nazi salutes in public and spreading extremist propaganda has been released on strict bail conditions after spending Christmas Day in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e82e1ecbbb5eea6afa21d1c319e3b449</guid></item><item><title>Poland intercepts Russian plane over Baltic, reports airspace breaches from Belarus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/poland-intercepts-russian-plane-over-baltic/106179994</link><description>Poland has warned several incidents regarding airspace during the holiday season may signal a provocation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e6bb0e0fce20217418dbbc6e3e3d1dd</guid></item><item><title>US Department of Defense releases missile launch video after northwest Nigeria operation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/us-missile-launch-video-nigeria/106180096</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05859f74ae3122414840f1530da6383c</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with assaulting pregnant woman, firing at police in Christmas Eve stand-off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/canberra-man-charged-firing-gun-police-whitlam/106179976</link><description>A 39-year-old man has been remanded in custody after police allege he fired multiple shots at officers during a Christmas Eve incident in Canberra's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a30589cbe907ba80131c1057fc542f0</guid></item><item><title>Paddleboarders rescued after drifting from Portarlington to Wyndham Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/victoria-family-rescued-christmas-day-paddelboard-mishap/106179858</link><description>Police say two holidaymakers are lucky to be alive after being rescued from the cold waters of Port Phillip, south-west of Melbourne, on Christmas Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50da2ebb51bc40fb017ee61ba1c7f634</guid></item><item><title>Japan okays record defence budget amid rising tensions with China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/japan-approves-record-defence-spending-china-tensions/106180112</link><description>Japan's cabinet approves a record defence budget plan aiming to fortify its strike-back capability and coastal defence amid rising regional tensions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">226514049ef3fb20b15245e7b63db459</guid></item><item><title>Sydney to Hobart pays tribute to Bondi victims with petals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/sydney-to-hobart-boat-tributes-bondi-victims-with-petals-/106180276</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1eb26c06a311d6aa9fafe2681d251de5</guid></item><item><title>An emergency-level fire came within a few kilometres of the Boddington town site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/boddington-fire-dfes-/106180144</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cb85fa865b33f8d345d75ae22ee16d8</guid></item><item><title>Kazuaki Ono's photo exhibition Southern Crust melds Australian scenery with our bakery culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/southern-crust-bakery-photography-exhibition/106169972</link><description>Kazuaki Ono wanted to entice people from Japan to visit Australia by showing we have as much to offer with our food culture as we do with our iconic scenery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92d7b7dca9079219e2846df04f166a65</guid></item><item><title>Police seeking to identify offender after man stabbed to death north of Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/laramba-stabbing-death-police-seek-to-identify-offender/106180286</link><description>Northern Territory police are investigating after a 35-year-old man was stabbed to death in a small town north-west of Alice Springs on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f71bf95fa0cc7db88b498dde4d7d7fb</guid></item><item><title>The storm brought down a tree branch onto a roof, smashing it to pieces</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/storm-branch-gold-coast/106180396</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f88058e9a715553947466971bfab3c9</guid></item><item><title>The best documentaries to binge in the weird week after Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/best-docos-to-binge-over-christmas-summer/106022170</link><description>Summer is here and so are those long leisurely days of nothing following Christmas. Here are five documentaries that will help you while away the time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e551aa5c5e8b609e0c5d9d9e10e9bab2</guid></item><item><title>Paddleboarders rescued from waters near Wyndham Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/paddleboarders-rescued/106180450</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">683af46d6bfa4d80eb1a675b273d2153</guid></item><item><title>Harry Brook's on the attack, Cameron Green runs himself out and Josh Tongue cashes in — quick hits from Boxing Day at the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/ashes-test-england-australia-quick-hits-harry-brook-cam-green/106179806</link><description>A record crowd for cricket at the MCG saw another fast-forward day of Ashes action as calamitous run outs and wild Bazball batting took centre stage. Here are the quick hits from the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75bc2f7fccf9d4a6d699188d9e20e531</guid></item><item><title>England's cowardly batting response spares Australian blushes on farcical Ashes Boxing Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/cowardly-english-batting-spares-australia-s-boxing-day-blushes/106180182</link><description>Australia's batting order is unsettled, unbalanced and out of form, but it matters little as England throws in the towel and considers the challenge of a Boxing Day Ashes Test all too hard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">187ff36f0baab20891ef104286fac289</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy agrees to meet with Trump as peace plan with Russia inches closer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/volodymyr-zelenskyy-donald-trump-meeting-peace-plan-russia/106180632</link><description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy says he has agreed to meet with US President Donald Trump in the near future and that they are working hard to end the war with Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c94842f6bc240f2c1f589fba07963d6d</guid></item></channel></rss>