<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 21:45:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Police investigating reports of explicit deepfake images of girls from Sydney school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/police-investigate-sydney-school-image-deepfake/105896812</link><description>The ABC understands a number of families attended Eastwood Police Station on Wednesday evening after growing frustrated that a local high school had failed to act on a complaint.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">913aa7d6ba3fc90880d957db2eaf13db</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill man who ran 27 marathons in 29 days finishes with fractured hip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/broken-hill-man-ran-to-newcastle-with-broken-femur/105866122</link><description>Mitch McKenny is unlikely to run again after spending four weeks running from Broken Hill to Newcastle, including the last 380 kilometres with severe pain in his hip.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de6f9d09fba1260c22272a56efcf4fa3</guid></item><item><title>Calls for federal oversight of Indigenous deaths in custody rejected in the NT</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/nt-parliament-rejects-aboriginal-deaths-in-custody-motion/105895810</link><description>Three decades after the landmark Royal Commission into Aboriginal Deaths in Custody, the Northern Territory parliament rejects a motion proposing the federal government establish an independent oversight body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf403f214ebf0a2f051e0cb3ec8f817b</guid></item><item><title>Australia's unemployment rate jumps to 4.5pc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/australia-unemployment-rate-rises-september-2025/105898244</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate jumped to 4.5 per cent in September, up from 4.3 per cent in August.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">944d983f4c3e591e79c311c6deea0d20</guid></item><item><title>Kingston residents rally to save 130yo oak tree from transmission project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/campaign-to-save-algerian-oak-kingston-western-renewables-link/105885046</link><description>Residents are getting creative in their fight to save a "magnificent" 130-year-old Algerian oak tree from being felled for a controversial transmission line project in western Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f54bb8b9ecab1e3d0af3c172dfd77c73</guid></item><item><title>Female shearer sets world record by shearing 500 merino lambs in one day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/shearer-sets-womens-record-shearing-500-merino-lambs-in-a-day/105897736</link><description>Nikki Lyons's clippers started humming at 6am. Twelve hours later, she was a world record holder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d962c3ee2503118469de3426af4a2f</guid></item><item><title>Matt and Kate built an earthship house with recycled bottles and the help of strangers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/grand-designs-australia-earthship-cygnet-matt-kate/105782588</link><description>Kate and Matt knew they had to do things differently if they ever wanted to live in their dream home. Not only did they swap the city for regional Tasmania and build a house using recycled bottles — they also relied on volunteers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b3b99d66906b239cfc3f2de65aaf196</guid></item><item><title>Ariarne Titmus's retirement ends years of sacrifice and allows her to at last savour her greatness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/ariarne-titmus-retirement-a-career-of-sacrifice-and-greatness/105898280</link><description>Ariarne Titmus has given her life to a dream. As she sets off on her next adventures, she can be in no doubt that her years of sacrifice and devotion were worth it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ace92f301f8bbd380cf4ea10e08f291</guid></item><item><title>Consumer groups, regulator concern as number of Australians accessing super to fix health surges again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/concern-over-accessing-super-for-medical-care-rises/105876384</link><description>Australians were allowed to withdraw $1.37 billion from their superannuation accounts for medical costs last financial year, in another jump from previous years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc6ab38204feeb436342c69f39e8b1a1</guid></item><item><title>First Nations artists warn against AI 'double colonisation' as Meta uses work for training</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/first-nations-creatives-warn-against-ai-double-colonisation/105889290</link><description>The rapid development of AI is testing the effectiveness of the Copyright Act, with creative and media industries calling for better protections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fc2ae378cfa0f6d485867eb2b770985</guid></item><item><title>Trump confirms the CIA is conducting covert operations inside Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/trump-confirms-cia-conducting-covert-venezuela-operations/105899100</link><description>Donald Trump says he authorised the CIA operation in part to stop the flow of "drugs coming in from Venezuela".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e085079c4af6fbf7e7281c139d73b6c8</guid></item><item><title>'Aggressive' man restrained on Adelaide Metro O-Bahn bus during peak hour, passenger claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/man-charged-after-incident-on-adelaide-metro-bus/105898484</link><description>A man has been restrained by passengers on a full bus during peak hour in Adelaide's north-east after allegedly being "aggressive and abusive", a witness says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c526d3adbb0fde1f7755abd96031eb5b</guid></item><item><title>Endangered regent honeyeaters released in Hunter breeding effort</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/critically-endangered-regent-honeyeaters-released-hunter-valley/105897506</link><description>Dozens of regent honeyeaters have been released in woodlands in the NSW Hunter Valley in an effort to boost the critically endangered population.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">383b1b3969cfdfce4abe0f4f51474d27</guid></item><item><title>Hope at last for families as NSW backs inquiry into unsolved murders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/hope-as-nsw-backs-probe-into-unsolved-murders/105898598</link><description>The NSW Parliament has backed an inquiry into decades of unsolved murders and missing persons cases, following a campaign led by Illawarra families.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">967e3ff5e688cbc3cc4d948f1955a838</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar's president Andry Rajoelina rose to power off youth discontent and was taken down by it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/madagascar-explainer-andry-rajoelina-president-ousted/105898028</link><description>Former DJ Andry Rajoelina was the world's youngest head of state when he came to power in Madagascar in a 2009 coup. The military and youth movement were pivotal in his rise — and fall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18df5036d8670e01811282249766d2e5</guid></item><item><title>Curators among 45 full-time jobs to be axed in Art Gallery of NSW cuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/curators-among-45-jobs-to-be-axed-at-art-gallery-of-nsw/105892942</link><description>Leaked documents show curators and conservator jobs will go as 45 full-time roles are cut from the Art Gallery of NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cf617a6570a7217321d8d4482b5215b</guid></item><item><title>Review: After the Hunt has noble ambitions but misses the mark</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/after-the-hunt-julia-roberts-review/105876254</link><description>The ingredients are all here — public scandal, duelling divas and unearthed secrets — but Luca Guadagnino's provocative drama misses the mark.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f67b806ed73e7ac77c9e5486230066b3</guid></item><item><title>Albanese dismisses lobby concerns, Chalmers takes one for the team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/anthony-albanese-jim-chalmers-good-oppositions/105884222</link><description>This week, the PM was not wasting any time on "this" issue, and the treasurer took one for the team as Brett Worthington signs off with his final political wrap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8caaca04017f6e10ef0a87a9a892f94f</guid></item><item><title>Coroner expresses 'horror' at lack of infrastructure upgrades after 2022 Eugowra flood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/eugowra-inquest-day-four/105898058</link><description>A coroner has expressed "horror" at the lack of modern river gauge infrastructure around the NSW inland community of Eugowra three years after it was smashed by record-breaking floods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfabe5218f015faa669d4da3b163dd62</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government approves Arrow Energy gas plant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/darling-downs-arrow-energy-gas-plant-approval/105900018</link><description>The Queensland government's recent approval of a major coal seam gas-processing facility three kilometres from a farming family's home has left them feeling "extremely disappointed".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cfb1f65a2244ef0e91ff8d80b92092e</guid></item><item><title>Former Ballarat dentist Ian Lomax suspended after alleged Neo-Nazi ties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/former-ballarat-dentist-suspended-after-alleged-neo-nazi-ties/105876992</link><description>Dental board suspends practitioner, who was allegedly photographed at a Neo-Nazi rally, while it investigates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">318fe292d66345273a778b72f5f069a7</guid></item><item><title>Essendon CEO says Hawthorn AFL trade tactics for Zach Merrett were surprising</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/essendon-ceo-says-hawthorn-afl-trade-tactics-merrett-surprising/105900392</link><description>Essendon chief executive Craig Vozzo says the club was surprised Hawthorn waited until late in the AFL trade period to make an offer for their captain, Zach Merrett.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e96f0a6c62b0d3f1e70f37fd7a66a0b2</guid></item><item><title>The Hobart Clinic rescue hinges on Monday shareholder meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/hobart-clinic-rescue-hinges-on-monday-meeting/105893386</link><description>Despite the offer of a $2 million lifeline to keep a private mental health clinic in Hobart open, last-minute wobbles could yet scupper the rescue bid, as the clinic's shareholders prepare to meet on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bc39e20ce0caab5b58da7fe6590d2ae</guid></item><item><title>Mark Haines inquest hears differing opinions from detectives on teen's mysterious death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/mark-haines-inquest-hears-from-detectives-and-homicide-squad/105887822</link><description>Thirty seven years after his death, police still cannot agree on how 17-year-old Mark Haines came to be found on train tracks near Tamworth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f08356610886575aa5a825b2c6af363e</guid></item><item><title>Siver Ferns coaching saga casts shadow over Constellation Cup opener against Diamonds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/silver-ferns-coaching-saga-diamonds-constellation-cup/105900692</link><description>Imploring New Zealand Netball to reinstate coach Noeline Taurua, Silver Ferns skipper Karin Burger believes her team can put the turmoil aside when they face Australia in the Constellation Cup opener.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1e4ab0f4d9f51f247913a2c29d87c82</guid></item><item><title>Inquiry into Queensland container refund scheme makes referrals to Crime and Corruption Commission</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/qld-containers-for-change-referred-to-ccc/105899540</link><description>A parliamentary inquiry into the container refund scheme says it received "troubling evidence," including alleged conflicts of interest and unfair contracts, as well as bullying and harassment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dfbae0a619b4f5a916e4644cb466f1f</guid></item><item><title>Teddy Swims tells SXSW Sydney he uses AI when making music, but warns of its dangers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/teddy-swims-tells-sxsw-sydney-he-uses-ai-in-music/105897908</link><description>Grammy-nominated music artist Teddy Swims says AI is a "beautiful tool" when it comes to composing music. Swims was in conversation at SXSW Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dcc839da82c48def79030a917173b7e</guid></item><item><title>Ariarne Titmus's greatest races, from Olympic golds, world records and surprise silvers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/ariarne-titmus-a-swimming-legend-races/105899372</link><description>The races that made Ariarne Titmus an Australian legend, from her maiden world championships appearance to her perfect Paris farewell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db607ccb521dd952dfad409a01b1c02e</guid></item><item><title>Diabetes-related condition cause of Emma Bates' death, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/doctor-gives-evidence-in-john-torney-emma-bates-case/105893266</link><description>A medical expert has told a court hearing for a man charged with negligent manslaughter that a 49-year-old woman died from a diabetes-related condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5ae2f81c26d9d8f668485f8ae209b0a</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne improves Ashes Test case with another century for Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/marnus-labuschagne-scores-century-for-queensland-sa/105900926</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne has added to his case for selection in Australia's Test team for the Ashes, making an emphatic case for selection with his fourth century in five innings for Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c8ce13cfc70e71af84960d841aaf47</guid></item><item><title>Diane Keaton's family releases cause of death, urging tributes to homelessness services and animal shelters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/diane-keaton-cause-of-death-released/105898904</link><description>The actor's family says the 79-year-old died of pneumonia, expressing gratitude for the "extraordinary messages of love and support" received following news of her passing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ad4d9062c3fd28201c61a47954bccd0</guid></item><item><title>Release of Virginia Giuffre's memoir renews sex allegations against Prince Andrew</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/virginia-giuffre-book-prince-andrew-allegations-jeffrey-epstein/105898044</link><description>Extracts from Virginia Giuffre's posthumously released memoir have further intensified the recently renewed scrutiny on Prince Andrew.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40e21158edb995f36869ca565b0e2b53</guid></item><item><title>Cohealth's closure of three Melbourne GP clinics to affect 12,500 patients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/melbourne-cohealth-gp-clinics-closing/105897006</link><description>Inner-city Melbourne community health service cohealth will be shuttering its GP services at the end of the year, citing escalating costs and aging infrastructure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">206d1831d09920250b9663ff89ae7f92</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/thursday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/105900826</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39251dff22abd93c574816fddff415b9</guid></item><item><title>Developer lodges plan to build 34-storey residential tower above derelict Broadway Hotel in Woolloongabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/plans-lodged-for-broadway-hotel-34-storey-tower/105898462</link><description>Developers submit plans to build a $140 million, 34-storey residential tower on top of the derelict three-storey Broadway Hotel in Woolloongabba.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef8291aa5fbee730ddff2177bbf492d9</guid></item><item><title>National Gallery will host APY artwork exhibition after paintings cleared of improper interference</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/act-apy-indigenous-art-interference-national-gallery-exhibition/105901272</link><description>The National Gallery will host an exhibition of art from the Aṉangu Pitjantjatjara Yankunytjatjara Lands three years after a video appearing to show a non-Aboriginal assistant helping to paint an artwork led to it being postponed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f256cd75d8dd22a070a0b023a2212e2</guid></item><item><title>Tasma Walton and Robbie Arnott share $100,000 ARA Historical Novel Prize</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/tasma-walton-robbie-arnott-ara-historical-novel-prize-2025/105886334</link><description>Robbie Arnott's Dusk about twins hunting a puma in Tasmania, and Tasma Walton's I Am Nannertgarrook about an Aboriginal woman kidnapped and sold into slavery, have tied to win the ARA Historical Novel Prize.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36563ad06ad055a6eaead4a3f8596a89</guid></item><item><title>Rugby Championship scrapped for 2026 due to Test calendar squeeze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/rugby-championship-scrapped-for-2026-test-season/105901714</link><description>The competition will not be played next year but will appear on the global calendar the following three years, including ahead of the 2027 Rugby World Cup, the organisers say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84c38b2c85ed36bf3a8054c41860989d</guid></item><item><title>Alyssa Healy scores second straight century as Australia qualifies for World Cup semis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/womens-world-cup-australia-beats-bangladesh-for-semifinal-berth/105899700</link><description>Australian captain Alyssa Healy scores her second straight century as her side maintains its unbeaten record at the cricket World Cup with a 10-wicket win over Bangladesh.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa8f9519f2a73e65f2eef48c11a9f988</guid></item><item><title>Female shearer sets world record by shearing 500 merino lambs in one day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/female-shearer-sets-world-record-by-shearing-500-merino-lambs-in/105901376</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f540d190f772539d16d4658bec564b0</guid></item><item><title>Government unveils a plan to combat South Australian algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/plan-to-combat-sa-algal-bloom/105900918</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb673ff2efdfdb07d4b825046c407370</guid></item><item><title>French PM Sebastien Lecornu survives no-confidence votes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/french-pm-sebastien-lecornu-survives-no-confidence-votes/105901916</link><description>Despite the reprieve, the motions underscore the fragility of President Emmanuel Macron's administration midway through his final term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef9eb69bc5c812ba483714c1ea1b2bea</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says Narendra Modi has pledged that India will stop buying Russian oil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/donald-trump-says-india-will-stop-buying-russian-oil/105901976</link><description>The US president says his Indian counterpart has made the pledge, as pressure continues to mount over the purchases that fund Moscow's war in Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfa3d657832c0a2a078b14f16d2fc9e8</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump and Vladimir Putin to discuss Ukraine war at Budapest summit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/donald-trump-vladimir-putin-to-meet-again/105902260</link><description>Donald Trump and Vladimir Putin will meet face-to-face in Hungary to discuss ending Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine, the US president announces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87e82ba667b74fbf2ab5298f72f1c729</guid></item><item><title>Calls for Australia to follow England's ban on supermarket junk food specials</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/calls-for-australia-to-follow-england-ban-on-junk-food-specials/105807974</link><description>Research finding supermarkets continue to offer discounts and multi-buy deals on junk food more frequently than healthy food prompts calls for Australia to follow England's lead and ban "buy one, get one free" deals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edbe2cd8f08f8c2fc9c6395f9edf30b7</guid></item><item><title>More Palestinian prisoners allege mistreatment in Israeli prison system after being reunited with their families</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/palestinian-prisoners-allege-mistreatment-in-israel/105895592</link><description>Shadi Abu Sido spent 18 months in Israeli detention believing that his entire family had been killed in Gaza. Then he was reunited with his wife and children in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c31a6cc30147c611bd4bfc23280a0c4</guid></item><item><title>Temperatures across Australia to soar, threatening October records</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/forecast-for-australian-weather-weekend-high-records-october/105901378</link><description>Unseasonable temperatures have lasted along the eastern seaboard for weeks — which has Sydney, and possibly Brisbane, on track to observe their warmest October on record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f4bf36d4491c7073e70092e07ba68cc</guid></item><item><title>Oil leaking from WW2 shipwreck the Rio de Janeiro Maru in Chuuk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/oil-leaking-from-ww2-shipwreck-the-rio-de-janeiro-maru-in-chuuk/105889748</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2be0837ab0fb4ac0467e1f6078adc4e</guid></item><item><title>WWII shipwrecks a 'ticking time bomb' for Federated States of Micronesia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/war-relics-threat-for-federated-states-of-micronesia/105884710</link><description>The Federated States of Micronesia's biggest tourism asset has become one of its largest threats, with as much as 22 million litres of oil from World War II shipwrecks slowly leaking into the ocean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5a5e22c5b7f81e23acf8feb4ae870bd</guid></item><item><title>'Dangerously low' funding to Tasmanian arts sector creating reputational damage, minister warned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/tasmanian-arts-industry-highly-vulnerable-low-funding-investment/105899498</link><description>"Dangerously low" arts sector funding has rendered the Tasmanian industry "highly vulnerable", with funding stagnant since 2016-17, the state government has conceded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a29de7c4d5bc252c9a785dea93220878</guid></item><item><title>Jim Chalmers and Tony Burke are in a long race for prime position</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/jim-chalmers-tony-burke-leadership/105884226</link><description>There is general agreement in Labor that Jim Chalmers is the government's best communicator. But insiders watching this race know Tony Burke is the master tactician.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93f58dc170f3f37c70cca03a69e3a6f5</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: A deported star, a shock retirement and the hottest place on Earth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/abc-weekly-news-quiz-oct-17/105899240</link><description>It's that time of the week again. Test your news knowledge to see how much you remember for the week that was.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcb568d8e78190bb9398f72d37d5bd5c</guid></item><item><title>Expanded search for Gus ends as missing persons advocate speaks out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/renewed-search-for-missing-boy-gus-continues-in-sa-outback/105900448</link><description>SA Police and ADF personnel have concluded a four-day renewed search for four-year-old Gus, as a missing persons advocate speaks out about the emotional impact of such cases on all families who have experienced the disappearance of a loved one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a97a1bed1323118fc2f898d318dc3426</guid></item><item><title>Drunken motorcyclist crashes with daughter riding as passenger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/drunken-motorcyclist-crashes-with-daughter-passenger/105898498</link><description>A Mildura father-of-six avoids jail after drunkenly crashing his motorbike while carrying his young daughter as a passenger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b7dbbdb3b9ed775f287c7490a9599c8</guid></item><item><title>Warnings for explicit deepfakes, 'image-based abuse' amid rise of AI technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/sydney-school-students-explicit-ai-images-investigation-police/105901372</link><description>A senior academic has warned a Sydney school caught up in an investigation into digitally altered explicit images of female students is just "another shocking iteration" of gendered violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9bb776a70b24518b0d2a82348f1046f</guid></item><item><title>ASX slips as gold price surges to new record above $US4,300 — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/asx-markets-business-live-news-date-year/105902438</link><description>The Australian share market falls after a downbeat session on Wall Street, weighed down by a sell-off across US regional bank stocks. Gold jumped to a new record high, above $US4,300 an ounce, as investors flocked to safe haven assets amid US-China trade tensions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c45f9ed11d3fac698ab6fe04be5606</guid></item><item><title>BHP vs China Inc: What the iron ore dispute says about Australia's present and future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/what-bhp-china-iron-ore-dispute-means-to-australia/105901692</link><description>The resolution of negotiations between Australian mining giant BHP and China's state-backed iron ore buyer China Mineral Resources Group could reshape not just the resources industry, but also international trade flows, global markets, and the relationship between China and the West.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f17745151acc39e0b5f38368c4928c68</guid></item><item><title>From cult web series to cinema: Nirvanna the Band the Show the Movie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/nirvanna-the-band-the-show-the-movie/105898756</link><description>Canada's cult web series heads to the big screen, after creators Matt Johnson and Jay McCarrol were told they could make any movie they liked after their success with BlackBerry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcab9960bf8462cac061bee2cf98745a</guid></item><item><title>Zach Merrett trade drama a reminder that deals can no longer be judged by amount of first-round picks involved</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/afl-trade-period-analysis-zach-merrett-first-round-pick-value/105898588</link><description>The AFL trade period offered three different test cases on just how much value a first-round pick holds during negotiations. Two stars got their moves, while one was left stranded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28e8bb8d5802a90c22f1d69d1a4727c3</guid></item><item><title>New research shows impact of lead poisoning on ancient humans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/new-research-shows-impact-lead-poisoning-ancient-humans/105899188</link><description>A new study claims lead might be the reason why Homo sapiens came to dominate the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12aa86f8c8828a99bbdb6054ea89c8c1</guid></item><item><title>Dangerous flammable cladding still not removed from dozens of NSW high-rise apartment buildings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/government-yet-to-fix-cladding-on-dozens-of-apartments-re-scheme/105900296</link><description>Dozens of high-rise apartment buildings across the state are still covered in flammable cladding as the NSW government's scheme has failed to fix them on schedule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">900570fd41fc7cafb3f056a176d7d52c</guid></item><item><title>Specialist health services shortfall for women in regional WA leave many struggling for support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/women-missing-out-on-specialist-health-services-in-regional-wa/105866424</link><description>Faced with a lack of specialist women's health services, women in regional WA are researching their own conditions and volunteering to raise awareness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a46a1f1f255a795ba616233f2bb18c5</guid></item><item><title>How a 15yo autistic boy tinkering in his bedroom triggered WA's biggest ever data breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/joshua-unwittingly-triggered-major-wa-health-data-breach-autism/105455250</link><description>Joshua's "passion project" with a radio scanner led to one of WA's most significant public health data breaches. His story highlights the challenges confronting autistic people caught up in the legal system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13c71de037de480416dd879b9c6eab51</guid></item><item><title>Former Trump national security adviser John Bolton indicted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/ex-trump-national-security-adviser-charged-in-probe/105902540</link><description>Donald Trump's former national security adviser John Bolton has been charged with mishandling classified information.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d572b768f51c9023aa7d06f2a1ca468b</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government seeks private market interest to develop riverside precinct in South Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/qld-riverfront-precinct-south-brisbane-private-sector/105902488</link><description>The government says construction could begin from March 2027 and has suggested the site could feature over 4,000 homes, as well as "event lawns" and promenades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71e510b6fa92de09ab4aec4b9b044d41</guid></item><item><title>NicheLiving customers continue to find defects</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/nicheliving-customers-continue-to-find-defects/105899574</link><description>Nicheliving customer Kathy Ellis thought her three-year nightmare was finally over in July, only to discover defective plumbing work in her new house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c827db340a1c42daeb836818d1a1c034</guid></item><item><title>McLaren's 'papaya rules' may be over as Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris battle for the F1 drivers' championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/mclaren-papaya-rules-oscar-piastri-lando-norris-f1/105855110</link><description>"Papaya rules" have dominated Formula 1 for two seasons, but with both McLaren drivers in the heat of a world championship battle, Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris may no longer prioritise what is best for the team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c1dd9f6429245aceb6baaa21e041d3e</guid></item><item><title>Starmer criticises police decision to ban fans of Israel's Maccabi Tel Aviv from Aston Villa match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/football-maccabi-tel-aviv-fans-banned-police-aston-villa/105902590</link><description>Fans of Israel's Maccabi Tel Aviv are banned from attending next month's Europa League match against Aston Villa in Birmingham over "public safety concerns".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">effc61153d88fcce13575af2eb2a3f1c</guid></item><item><title>Coronado Curragh fined for death of miner Clark Peadon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/coronado-curragh-fined-for-death-of-worker-clark-peadon/105893210</link><description>The MEU has described the fine as "inadequate" for the loss of someone's life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">302b71db67d68b4b399d0e78f4be1f6f</guid></item><item><title>Ace Frehley, founding member of rock group KISS, dies at 74</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/ace-frehley-guitarist-kiss-dies-aged-74/105902920</link><description>The original lead guitarist of the glam rock band captivated audiences with his elaborate makeup and smoke-filled guitar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70f68f5def708160810eec0ad80e8354</guid></item><item><title>King Charles marks land rights milestone in first visit to London's Australia House</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/king-charles-commemorates-40th-anniversary-of-uluru-handback/105902056</link><description>King Charles marked the major milestone in Aboriginal land rights alongside Uluru-Kata Tjuta's traditional owners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7d5382ea3e29445cd53373bb9eda014</guid></item><item><title>SA Education Department fined after teen fell from school playground swing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/sa-education-department-fined-playground-swing-fall/105900366</link><description>South Australia's Education Department has been fined $225,000 after a student at a special school fell from a swing which had not had a comprehensive safety inspection for eight years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cdc7ec760bf1e318791fcad162c615f</guid></item><item><title>Defence in talks to support Gaza peace plan but Australia says no request yet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/defence-in-talks-with-us-to-support-gaza-peace-plan/105902742</link><description>Australia's defence force has had discussions with the Unted States to provide support for its Gaza peace plan but the government says no formal request has been made yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd80619b996f35eb17de143a6b7e07dc</guid></item><item><title>Virtual emergency department a lifeline for patients in regional areas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/virtual-emergency-department-option-for-patients-remote-areas/105371852</link><description>A virtual emergency room app created during the pandemic could help bridge healthcare gaps in regional Victoria. But more patients need to dial-in and use the resource.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cce3e05039289d83c6bdbae0a5d4e7b</guid></item><item><title>How wild bird poo testing in northern Australia is helping keep eggs on the shelves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/bird-flu-poo-testing-in-northern-australia-keeps-eggs-on-shelves/105894598</link><description>Hundreds of kilometres from the nearest supermarket, Indigenous rangers in Australia's remote north are working to keep eggs on your breakfast table.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">126bc279f84d1b05bc9d6ac31fa6b513</guid></item><item><title>Indigiearth founder inspires Indigenous women to chase business dreams</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/indigiearth-award-sharon-winsor-australian-cuisine/105899236</link><description>Sharon Winsor is honoured for her pioneering work in native Australian cuisine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9867852928883c2abad3f488c0d1bf3b</guid></item><item><title>Bears kill record number of people in Japan amid scores of attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/record-number-of-bear-attacks-in-japan/105902770</link><description>At least seven people have been killed by bears in the country since April and many more have been injured as the hungry animals venture into human territory to find food.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41b4b93bb120166534952debb22263e8</guid></item><item><title>US dangled threat of Tomahawks for Ukraine, then Russia called to negotiate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/us-tomahawk-long-range-missiles-supply-ukraine-russia-talks/105884192</link><description>US President Donald Trump threatened to send Tomahawk missiles to Ukraine if Russia did not return to peace talks, but analysts say the long-range weapons are not the game-changer they are made out to be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab37297fc9b45cbc08d59856d14f85f4</guid></item><item><title>Venezuela says US strike on suspected drug vessel 'extrajudicial executions'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/new-usa-strike-on-venezuelan-drugs-boat-leaves-survivors/105903128</link><description>A US strike against a suspected Venezuelan drug-smuggling vessel has left multiple survivors, as Venezuela's ambassador to the United Nations condemned the strikes as a "series of assassinations".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a3ad366e7e0f7f78fc016c52b612098</guid></item><item><title>King Charles commemorates 40th anniversary of Uluru-Kata Tjuta handover</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/king-charles-commemorates-40th-anniversary/105903854</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c93eec247a1e442de98f772d2428ec4</guid></item><item><title>'No doubt' Anthony Albanese and Donald Trump will discuss critical minerals: Chalmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/albanese-trump-chalmers-critical-minerals-deal/105903392</link><description>Anthony Albanese will "no doubt" use a meeting with Donald Trump next week to discuss critical minerals, the treasurer says as he dismisses a call for Australia to "decouple" with China over rare earth materials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fe4351ff10e966c7a84c8e260555fa8</guid></item><item><title>Hamish McIntyre elected new president of National Farmers' Federation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/hamish-mcintyre-new-president-of-national-farmers-federation/105903736</link><description>Hamish McIntyre is named the new president of Australia's peak farmer representative body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c317e433f02d76c14e44c86f15f08ecd</guid></item><item><title>Pacific Championships set to start without Australia as strong Samoa and Tonga teams take on New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/pacific-championships-stars-embrace-their-island-heritage/105903826</link><description>Emerging superpowers Samoa and Tonga will field formidable teams loaded with NRL talent in the third edition of the Pacific Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07fb63cc9e9ec53c5f2664aaf516d600</guid></item><item><title>WA's insolvent Griffin Coal ramps up operations as taxpayer bailout deadline looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/insolvent-wa-griffin-coal-ramps-up-operations/105901120</link><description>The receiver of a WA coal mine says it is ramping up operations in a final attempt to trade out of insolvency before millions of dollars in taxpayer support dries up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2e888ffc914c66fe0fec7316e9144da</guid></item><item><title>Pet-friendly flights are taking off in Australia. Here's what to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/pet-friendly-flights-what-to-know/105903876</link><description>The first pet-friendly commercial flights have taken off in Australia this week. Here's what you need to know about the new service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4379a2d55c184d75fb0dbc167127d3db</guid></item><item><title>Cameron Green ruled out of Australia vs India ODI series, Marnus Labuschagne called into squad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/cameron-green-ruled-out-of-australia-vs-india-odi-series/105904798</link><description>Cameron Green has been ruled out of Australia's ODI series against India, just over a month out from the start of the Ashes series against England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfecd41bffae6db1aa484dbde8addcc6</guid></item><item><title>Australia Test batter Nic Maddinson reveals testicular cancer diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/australia-test-batter-nic-maddinson-testicular-cancer-diagnosis/105905220</link><description>Former Australia batter Nic Maddinson has revealed he underwent chemotherapy for testicular cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7f603e8cc45b625885d16071d38bc7a</guid></item><item><title>What has John Bolton, former Trump adviser, been charged with and what happens now?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/john-bolton-indictment-donald-trump/105902918</link><description>Donald Trump's former national security adviser has been charged with storing top secret records at home and sharing classified information. Here's what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">569be9199a04f65daa7c6dd527bdf71c</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's plan to leave his mark on Washington DC by building Paris-style arch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/trump-plans-to-build-paris-style-arc-in-us-capital/105904744</link><description>The arch would stand at the Washington end of Memorial Bridge, which spans the Potomac River from Arlington, Virginia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">602d98d8a4c8909392f7e0e5d59de569</guid></item><item><title>Ways to increase safety on a first date and red flags to watch for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/red-flags-on-first-date-safety-tips/105805388</link><description>Both people involved in a date are responsible for creating a safe environment, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f5f2638f6ee24d2f8b7347e8441dce8</guid></item><item><title>Europe unveils plans for 'drone wall' to shield continent from Russian threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/europe-drone-wall-defence-system-russia-threat-incursions/105893030</link><description>The European Commission unveils plans for its so-called "drone wall", which is part of a range of initiatives to get the continent ready to defend itself by 2030.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15ca3d3f92a6b391e69aeb1231da05cd</guid></item><item><title>Endemic frog and gecko species identified on Dauan Island in Torres Strait</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/frog-gecko-species-found-dauan-torres-strait/105790146</link><description>Two new frog species and a banded-patterned gecko are believed to have sheltered among the boulders of Dauan, in the Torres Strait, for millions of years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02d7af04ef02838cbdfc93bff8ff13f8</guid></item><item><title>Inquest hears of grief, trauma from families of Eugowra locals after record-breaking 2022 flood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/eugowra-inquest-day-five/105902498</link><description>Families speak of loss, trauma on final day of the coronial inquest into the deaths of Les Vugec and Diane Smith.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dcae5aba593220ee08189da0bc90ff1</guid></item><item><title>Video released of moments leading up to strip search that breached Aboriginal woman's human rights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/julianne-williams-strip-search-canberra-jail-video-release-court/105905888</link><description>The ACT Supreme Court has made public confronting video showing the moments leading up to a strip search that violated an Aboriginal woman’s human rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdcb7325932b405b24aab30e15587062</guid></item><item><title>Video of attempted strip search that breached Aboriginal woman's human rights made public</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/video-of-attempted-strip-search-canberra-jail-released-court/105904704</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3fd11c0749eadaff81abffecd47f378</guid></item><item><title>Wayne Swan steps down as Labor president urging party to focus on membership boost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/wayne-swan-labor-president-leaves-role-politics/105905064</link><description>Labor party president Wayne Swan will step down next July and has warned the ALP must boost membership if it is to survive into the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75e127f2e28c7f78ce730de287d98398</guid></item><item><title>Wittenoom asbestos contamination prompts legal threat from Banjima traditional owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/wittenoom-asbestos-litigation-documentary/105886444</link><description>After decades of disconnection, the traditional owners of Wittenoom say they are prepared to take legal action to ensure the area is properly remediated so they can return to country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">713ee52afb0c4689f99c025841f00428</guid></item><item><title>Friday the pelican captured and washed after three-week chase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/friday-the-pelican-captured-and-washed-after-three-week-chase/105906028</link><description>Friday the pelican evaded capture for weeks. But a long-overdue bath is for her own good.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08e29ab2dd99920f8f64165e8034ff2b</guid></item><item><title>Grimmer family sets parliamentary privilege deadline for cold case identity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/cheryl-grimmer-brothers-set-deadline-parliamentary-privilege/105904330</link><description>A brother of three-year-old Cheryl Grimmer, who vanished in 1970, has given the man who confessed to her killing a deadline to come forward or be named.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f15982335786071048424d142871b2b9</guid></item><item><title>Strict conditions imposed on future LIV Golf site at North Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/strict-conditions-on-north-adelaide-golf-course-redevelopment/105905844</link><description>South Australia's Aboriginal affairs minister has imposed 31 strict conditions on the government's planned redevelopment of the North Adelaide golf course.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc6d01343d110faca4bb8653ade74cc5</guid></item><item><title>Chinese national charged with foreign interference granted bail despite concerns she could flee country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/act-chinese-national-charged-foreign-interference-granted-bail/105906106</link><description>A woman accused of covertly gathering information for the Chinese government has been granted bail in Canberra, despite police warning she could try to flee the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f8a82b873c67ac845e029c6fb5fd2f1</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/friday-finance-with-david-chau/105906178</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6b775f25a05cb343702a02cf5d8de47</guid></item><item><title>Scott Boland bowls Victoria to Sheffield Shield victory over NSW, ahead of Ashes against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/scott-boland-bowls-victoria-to-sheffield-shield-victory-over-nsw/105905076</link><description>Scott Boland has produced a man-of-the-match performance, bowling Victoria to a 38-run win over New South Wales in their Sheffield Shield clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">729329d9bae119b36c0706d109492cf3</guid></item><item><title>Former Japanese prime minister Tomiichi Murayama, famous for WWII apology, dies aged 101</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/ex-japan-prime-minister-tomiichi-murayama-dies-aged-101/105906158</link><description>Known for his landmark apology for Japan's World War II aggression and the phrases "deep remorse" and "heartfelt apology", Tomiichi Murayama has died at a hospital in Oita City.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03b35ac069e03d3037f52ba5261468f2</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar military leader Michael Randrianirina sworn in as president after coup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/madagascar-new-president-sworn-in-after-military-coup/105906334</link><description>An army colonel who seized power in a military coup has been sworn in as Madagascar's new leader, after a sudden power grab that ousted the president and sent him fleeing from the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96dcc3f3b1832b7f3704ff8662f60934</guid></item><item><title>Australia Diamonds defeat New Zealand Silver Ferns 69-52 in game one of Constellation Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/australia-diamonds-defeat-new-zealand-silver-ferns-69-52/105905070</link><description>Australia has stormed to a commanding win in the first Test of the Constellation Cup series, defeating New Zealand 69-52.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f36860ee433d3f4861c1144ddc36164e</guid></item><item><title>AFLW Round 10: Port Adelaide Power defeat Hawthorn Hawks, West Coast Eagles down Geelong Cats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/aflw-round-10-power-hawks-eagles-cats/105906400</link><description>Port Adelaide defeats Hawthorn to record its fourth win of the AFLW season, while West Coast moves closer to a maiden finals appearance with victory over Geelong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae0cbd52bca8dc6756cd2ffe42c3b8bd</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide United defeats Sydney FC 2-1, Brisbane downs Macarthur on A-League Men opening night</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/aleagues-men-adelaide-sydney-brisbane-macarthur/105906556</link><description>Adelaide United begins its season with a 2-1 win over Sydney, while Brisbane coach Michael Valkanis sees son Dimitri sent off in the Roar's 1-0 defeat of Macarthur.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82bb437ece317276dd69493b6848e7ad</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's Trump meeting comes amid global geopolitical circus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/gaza-ceasefire-deal-donald-trump-anthony-albanese-trade-tariff/105884238</link><description>All signs suggest Anthony Albanese will be sticking with Plan A in his meeting with the US president on Tuesday, rather than becoming a prop for the bigger global circus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7369e04e283103228bfcf69dddc12dd2</guid></item><item><title>Creating deepfakes has never been easier, so what should parents do?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/creating-deepfakes-is-easy-what-should-parents-do/105902982</link><description>Some parents may feel distressed and ill-equipped to tackle the issue of image-based abuse and deepfakes. This is what to watch out for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">136e26003e31a95432cd2b1c4b32704d</guid></item><item><title>Video appears to show March for Australia organiser coordinating with Neo-Nazi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/march-for-australia-organiser-coordinates-with-neo-nazi/105902754</link><description>A previously unreported video has emerged appearing to show a key March for Australia organiser coordinating with a Neo-Nazi at the first rally in Sydney in August, ABC NEWS Verify has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc104ef4e2d70260f456bb05e05b9a6c</guid></item><item><title>Administrative Review Tribunal swamped by surging demand, more than 100 members short</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/administrative-review-tribunal-overwhelmed-surging-demand/105893728</link><description>The Administrative Review Tribunal was set up to resolve issues with its predecessor, but has struggled with staffing and long wait times over its first year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fd2f156e95340a969daa8b6003273f1</guid></item><item><title>Education department admits not enough done to stop Dubbo College Delroy aide harming children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/systemic-failure-to-investigate-nsw-dubbo-school-staff/105807290</link><description>The NSW government says it should have taken allegations of wrongdoing by a male school staff member more seriously. That failure left those who reported it so isolated their mental health spiralled and never fully recovered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c22f6955d77c23cb8f7c088405ad508</guid></item><item><title>Benjamin Netanyahu's name prompted boos in Israel but is it a signal he has lost favour?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/benjamin-netanyahu-popularity-in-israel-in-spotlight/105903240</link><description>As the dust settles on the ceasefire and hostage exchange deal, the question arises as to whether the partial resolution could deliver Benjamin Netanyahu a bounce in the polls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3cc3003b8b28e951e730e5aa18bbb1f</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Games' impact on Paralympic athletes Kurt Fearnley, Louise Sauvage and Lisa Llorens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/sydney-paralympics-changed-athletes-kurt-fearnley-louis-sauvage/105898554</link><description>The Sydney Paralympic was a watershed moment for the Paralympic movement. A quarter of a century later, Kurt Fearnley, Louise Sauvage and Lisa Llorens reflect on the Games that changed everything.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f362b8e587fb7f379169b6c7eef5073d</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou defends record as pressure builds at Nottingham Forest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/ange-postecoglou-launches-passionate-defence-of-record/105907112</link><description>Amid growing pressure of his poor start at Nottingham Forest, Ange Postecoglou delivers a five-minute defence of his record as a manager.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1863ae28c5532d8ed98a6a975abd634</guid></item><item><title>China expels top-ranking military leaders from Communist Party</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/china-expels-top-military-leaders-amid-corruption-charges/105907114</link><description>He Weidong, China's second-most-senior general, and navy admiral Miao Hua, the military's former top political officer, have been accused of "serious duty-related crimes involving an extremely large amount of money".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bbf6aaab1e32a9d0d9c40a249845d46</guid></item><item><title>Fire authorities warn of 'above average' fire season as NSW starts to warm up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/nsw-above-average-fire-season-bushfire-risk-weather/105900120</link><description>Fire authorities warn of above average fire season in NSW despite previous modelling showing a wet summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52eaca3898c563789480ae66f0c7a43f</guid></item><item><title>Trump tells Zelenskyy and Putin to 'stop right now at the battle line'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/donald-trump-volodymyr-zelenskyy-meet-after-vladimir-putin-call/105907092</link><description>The Ukrainian president offers the US thousands of military drones in exchange for American Tomahawk missiles, but Donald Trump says he wants to end the war "without thinking about Tomahawks".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c7ba4e71bbd1cb098a9e72ec1aa1c48</guid></item><item><title>Water testing in the Murweh Shire returns negative for dangerous amoeba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/murweh-mayor-charleville-hospital-negative-water-testing-amoeba/105899494</link><description>South-west Queensland residents are questioning the detection of a dangerous amoeba at Queensland Health sites after all follow-up tests were negative.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f732b4b65ef2c9618812d9b472a6ce26</guid></item><item><title>Brad Battin under pressure as Liberal MPs weigh up second leadership spill in less than 12 months</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/brad-battin-victorian-liberal-leader-analysis/105904104</link><description>The Victorian Liberals could be headed for their third leader in less than 12 months, with MPs internally dissatisfied with the performance of current leader Brad Battin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c7498fe9c9833ab207d978dc7164bb6</guid></item><item><title>Is the transfer of Australia's best young soccer players a good thing?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/soccer-a-league-player-transfers/105893566</link><description>Are A-League soccer fans right to be frustrated when its best young players are sold off, or should they accept it is a 'selling' league?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0e06963459d7a95465fff2d57464f52</guid></item><item><title>As the Australian op shop turns 100, the legacy of Lady Millie Tallis lives on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/lady-millie-tallis-australian-op-shop-100-year-anniversary/105901846</link><description>One hundred years ago, showgirl-turned-philanthropist Millie Tallis spent weeks preparing for a major second-hand goods fundraiser in Melbourne, giving rise to the Australian op shop.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92ea4c4664694717607b7fd6c4bd9662</guid></item><item><title>Young people with chronic pain feel 'unheard', misunderstood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/young-people-living-with-chronic-pain/105898314</link><description>Chronic pain affects one in five Australian children. Two young people who experience it want more people to understand their conditions and better support for all children in pain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">946486ae5287caf11084ac18ee24e69e</guid></item><item><title>Renewed search for Gus concludes without answers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/sa-renewed-search-for-gus-finishes-long-read/105903652</link><description>When police announced a new search for a missing four-year-old earlier this week, it came with a renewed hope for answers. But the latest search came to an end on Friday with crews finding no sign of little Gus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a9c245450519d0f9b810a9b73bb0806</guid></item><item><title>Trump 'risking full-fledged war' against Venezuela as US military action escalates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/trump-risking-war-in-venezuela-as-military-action-escalates/105905370</link><description>The US military has launched six strikes on Venezuelan vessels the Trump administration claims were involved in drugs trafficking, and some are warning the intervention is threatening to spark an all-out war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b073ef6c9e14d9494c974248c3a4de84</guid></item><item><title>Protesters clash with police as Bangladesh's political parties agree to pathway for reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/protesters-clash-with-police-in-bangladesh-over-political-reform/105907038</link><description>Tear gas and stun grenades were used to disperse hundreds of protesters who were calling for more provisions for those who helped oust the former government of Sheikh Hasina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">487bc6155e85e21b8f55d26aa4aa70b8</guid></item><item><title>Lack of housing in remote NT community Borroloola forcing families off country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/borroloola-housing-lack-forcing-families-leave-country/105895586</link><description>Remote NT residents are calling on the government to fund new housing in the Gulf community of Borroloola, fearing limited access to appropriate homes has forced families to move off country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df22bcf01f5fa2c70abd461d204c6d03</guid></item><item><title>A few simple questions reveal the games adults aren't brave enough to play</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/square-game-melbourne-fringe-adults-children/105884234</link><description>This game revealed how rarely we are vulnerable in front of our children, and in front of each other.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4a1361b33d61feac343da5bc4faba25</guid></item><item><title>Former Trump adviser John Bolton pleads not guilty to sharing classified information</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/john-bolton-pleads-not-guilty-to-sharing-classified-information/105906928</link><description>John Bolton has become one of Donald Trump's most vocal critics after he was ousted from the US president's administration during his first term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8908cf93af441dee92e8c2b344ce9896</guid></item><item><title>James Duckworth returns to ATP Tour semifinal four years after his last</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/james-duckworth-atp-tour-astana-open-semi-final/105907190</link><description>Four years since he last reached an ATP tournament semifinal in Kazakhstan, Australian James Duckworth is back in the last four at the Almaty Open</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dceb858841c1c847c349b2a7432508b3</guid></item><item><title>Locals swarm when air freight carrying fresh food arrives on the island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/locals-swarm-when-air-freight-carrying-fresh-food-arrives/105896242</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">874c9e4756d74a99a787d3dd04623436</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Island wants more tourists but luggage is often left behind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/christmas-island-travellers-luggage-regularly-left-behind/105778992</link><description>On Christmas Island, locals are not surprised if tourists' checked baggage does not arrive with them. Fragile supply chains on the remote Indian Ocean island are a part of life in this unique community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf635fd57a7aedc3288c6869b3851e6d</guid></item><item><title>AI tech takes on one of NSW's deadliest rock fishing spots</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/ai-camera-trial-rock-fishing-safety-nsw/105902900</link><description>Surf Life Saving NSW is testing artificial intelligence cameras at Kiama Blowhole to detect when fishers are swept into the water and alert rescuers within seconds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">151eddbf0d62e8e7f4aeb5cec27a435d</guid></item><item><title>Hospital in the Home program helping young man with agoraphobia who 'cut himself off from the world'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/hospital-in-the-home-northwest-tasmania-mental-health/105789004</link><description>Tom French's agoraphobia meant he couldn't leave the house to access the mental health care he needed, but a Hospital in the Home program means the care is coming to him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1b964e8ba63ca42e36daf1af0d1b9c8</guid></item><item><title>The face of Brisbane is changing — but should thousands of homes be developed in a flood zone?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/visy-montague-road-riverfront-precinct-thousands-of-homes-floods/105904030</link><description>Plans to build a riverfront precinct in a flood-prone area of Brisbane have urban planners and locals wary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d506b00fbc8d45eff04ef30c465454e6</guid></item><item><title>Pakistani soldiers killed by suicide bomb near Afghanistan border</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/suicide-bomb-attack-kills-soldiers-in-pakistan/105906932</link><description>The attack on a military base near the Afghanistan border comes as Taliban and Pakistani officials say a peace deal has been extended.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a43f6b1a97e689f439e7e9bc7a686da6</guid></item><item><title>Tool's Maynard James Keenan on touring Australia, making wine and martial arts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/tool-australia-tour-2025-maynard-james-keenan-interview/105865706</link><description>The alt-metal band's frontman is a world-class multi-tasker. He tells us how he balances it all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">501350518724f7dcac6393cd0c095da6</guid></item><item><title>Western Australia starts harvesting what could be a record-breaking grain crop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/western-australia-harvest-record-grain-crop-expected/105900332</link><description>Farmers in Western Australia have begun harvesting a grain crop that could set a new record. It is a different story on the other side of the Nullabor though.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a84a87f36461e65b587de7b1fd2f66c6</guid></item><item><title>Greek-inspired lamb kebabs with olive potatoes baked in the oven - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/easy-oven-baked-lamb-kebabs-with-olive-potatoes/105291672</link><description>The lamb is fuss-free and full of flavour. No barbecue needed — the oven takes care of everything.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97732d3bb23552f5f8a4e4e0fa75a14b</guid></item><item><title>From a Springsteen biopic to a doggy horror: here are the movies out in October</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/october-movie-wrap-what-to-watch/105893300</link><description>From the highly anticipated Bruce Springsteen biopic to a horror movie from the viewpoint of the family pup, here are the films filling up cinemas in October.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f217a9477d3de1211d4744ae2ba19bd8</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne's record-setting AFLW winning streak is clear in the numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/north-melbourne-setting-aflw-standards/105905842</link><description>Having developed the program layer by layer since joining the AFLW in 2019, North Melbourne's disciplined, professional style of footy is forcing the rest of the league to rise to their level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3f69ec228f1094f89b081dd9d305cb5</guid></item><item><title>Cool weather prescribed burn on WA's south coast should be expanded, environmental group says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/call-to-expand-cool-weather-burns-to-protect-the-environment/105896512</link><description>The success of a small, autumn prescribed burn on WA's south coast has prompted calls to replace the regular program to reduce environmental damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">164585befee231bbcfbedee418ccc7bd</guid></item><item><title>Phoebe Litchfield learning from opening partner Alyssa Healy at Women's Cricket World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/phoebe-litchfield-alyssa-healy-womens-cricket-world-cup/105907312</link><description>Alyssa Healy has joined an elite band of women batters with 7,000 international runs, and Australia's captain is giving her brilliant young opening partner something to aim for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a50f38a0dacc4756881494b6edf4d5e</guid></item><item><title>Trump commutes former Republican George Santos's federal fraud jail sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/trump-commutes-george-santos-us-fraud-jail-sentence/105907366</link><description>George Santos, a former Republican Congressman who is serving more than seven years in a US prison, was charged with stealing from donors, fraud and lying to Congress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1466625a8dcb4419ab8ef2d6ea190387</guid></item><item><title>Minister flags compulsory voting in local government elections, 4-year terms amid low voter turnout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/compulsory-voting-flagged-for-wa-local-government-election/105901804</link><description>Voting in council elections could become mandatory in Western Australia if the turnout for this weekend's poll continues to plummet, the local government minister warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90ce7dc5327df5d0b3904814e2638839</guid></item><item><title>Black Swans rowing crew from WA set sights on Head of The Charles Regatta in Boston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/black-swans-rowers-take-on-head-of-the-charles-regatta/105840934</link><description>Former Olympic medallists and a founding member of a platinum-selling band form part of a veteran crew from WA who have set their sights on the world's biggest and most famous rowing race.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7890e76f907f31fe1fe9d3e1d7e724a</guid></item><item><title>What to know about the thousands of No Kings protests planned in the US this weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/what-to-know-about-the-us-no-kings-protests/105901300</link><description>Millions of Americans are expected to take to the streets this weekend as part of nationwide protests against US President Donald Trump. Here's what to know about the events, which could see the single biggest day of protest in US history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e668c54ff73c334b8918b940c3ba524</guid></item><item><title>Heavy horsemen keep farming traditions alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/heavy-horsemen-keep-farming-traditions-alive/105887988</link><description>Aleks Berzins is farming the land in the same way his grandfather did, using draught horses for jobs now widely done by machines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f47d3bf2b7c8199053c352b6aaf54536</guid></item><item><title>Female electricians win awards after overcoming health struggles, rejection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/women-trades-electrician-mining-awards-support-needed/105902706</link><description>A woman who overcame a rare disease and another who spent two decades applying for apprenticeships have been recognised for excellence in their trades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acd2f07ab60e8de36ed2f0621b0c972a</guid></item><item><title>Gulgong woman changes career to honour murder victim Michelle Bright</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/michelle-bright-murder-leads-abby-honeysett-on-forensic-career/105866588</link><description>The murder of Michelle Bright altered Abby-Lee Honeysett's childhood in Gulgong, New South Wales and guided her towards a career in forensic medicine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b220bc940fcd8f7c374cc9f9976a5291</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy says he trusts Trump wants to finish Ukraine war</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/zelenskyy-says-he-trusts-trump-wants-to-finish-ukraine-war/105907350</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a02436a06499efc13375877506c05db</guid></item><item><title>Trump tells Putin and Zelenskyy to ‘stop right now at the battle line’</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/trump-tells-putin-and-zelenskyy-to-stop/105907490</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a042aa321b911d55cae568609cf02a54</guid></item><item><title>Max Verstappen claims sprint pole ahead of Lando Norris and Oscar Piastri at US F1 Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/f1-max-verstappen-lando-norris-oscar-piastri-us-grand-prix/105907488</link><description>Max Verstappen topples McLaren pair Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris to claim pole position for the sprint race at the United States Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0aead0d7f508abc19c76aa70fab17de8</guid></item><item><title>Coroner finds snakebite death of 11yo Tristian Frahm preventable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/coroner-finds-snakebite-death-of-tristian-frahm-preventable/105907556</link><description>The death of an 11-year-old Queensland boy from a snakebite may have been prevented had he received early medical attention, according to the findings of an inquest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7845efcc529ff7078aaecea2c035d784</guid></item><item><title>A history of the Israeli settler movement in the Occupied Palestinian Territory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/israeli-settlers-rear-vision/105789284</link><description>Since October 7, tensions have been rising between Palestinians and Israeli settlers in the Occupied Palestinian Territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23198e502573622dd9f58f17a1d48075</guid></item><item><title>Gungahlin United Football Club to fold after losing NPL licence, leaving 2,000 grassroots players club-less</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/gungahlin-united-fc-fold-capital-football-licence-revoke/105907530</link><description>Just last year, the club won the league, and a former president was jailed for stealing $20k. Now they are going to fold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b94409bd3e5cff77f2199cae368e6fbf</guid></item><item><title>Shohei Ohtani dominates to send Dodgers through to World Series after defeating Brewers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/mlb-shohei-ohtani-la-dodgers-milwaukee-brewers-nlcs-world-series/105907728</link><description>Shohei Ohtani propels the Los Angeles Dodgers back to the World Series with a two-way performance for the ages to clinch the National League Championship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07e3dc307a703e9f5b64e129d87445fe</guid></item><item><title>Who is Prince Andrew? Why is he giving up his royal title?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/why-prince-andrew-gives-up-royal-titles-duke-of-york/105907380</link><description>The third-born child of Queen Elizabeth II will still be referred to as a prince and is expected to continue living in his Windsor mansion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08536e709980d0a36f65e1774362c22d</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce hasn't quit the Nationals yet but he's got one foot out the door</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/speers-analysis-barnaby-joyce-has-not-quit-the-nationals-yet/105907744</link><description>In declaring he won't be recontesting his lower house seat and letting speculation run that he might jump ship for One Nation, Barnaby Joyce is declaring he's had enough with the Nationals under David Littleproud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f61bd6ea4984b1bc51fdcb3bae580b</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos defeat Crows by 40-points to move closer to winning record as Saints, Dockers and Demons notch victories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/aflw-demons-swans-kangaroos-crows-giants-dockers-blues-saints/105907762</link><description>North Melbourne moves one victory away from equalling the all-time VFL/AFL and AFLW winning record with a 40-point drubbing of Adelaide as St Kilda moves closer to a maiden finals appearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3036c640f5f12f4b89b3526d94476ea</guid></item><item><title>Ka Ying Rising wins $20 million The Everest at Randwick</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/ka-ying-rising-wins-the-everest/105907784</link><description>Ka Ying Rising produces a storming finish to claim victory in the world's richest horse race, The Everest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19c3a83fa115de614a667a17229d4779</guid></item><item><title>NT chief minister claims tough-on-crime approach has led to 'significant' crime drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/nt-chief-minister-claims-tough-on-crime-led-to-crime-drop/105906588</link><description>NT Chief Minister Lia Finocchiaro says the Country Liberal Party's tough-on-crime approach "is working". But after two teens broke into a play centre and left a trail of destruction, operator Steve Mason is not convinced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ceb1811e211ef03f608859e94141ede6</guid></item><item><title>Chinese Communist Party's Central Committee set for major shake-up at plenum meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/xi-inner-circle-major-shakeup-ccp-meeting-beijing/105885472</link><description>A key meeting of the Chinese Communist Party Central Committee is expected to include a major shake-up of President Xi Jinping's inner circle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41655c3a7bf399a2c8c3669a0f55d79b</guid></item><item><title>Collingwood cult hero Mason Cox not offered new contract for 2026 AFL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/mason-cox-leaves-collingwood-magpies/105907852</link><description>Mason Cox, the first American to become an AFL regular, confirms he will not be with the Magpies in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faaa19652e592fb7fd468bdd25c33d4d</guid></item><item><title>Jamie Melham creates Caulfield Cup history after riding Half Yours to victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/caulfield-cup-jamie-melham-makes-history-with-half-yours-win/105907872</link><description>Jamie Melham breaks new ground as the first female jockey to win the Caulfield Cup in its 149-year history, steering favourite Half Yours to victory in the $5 million handicap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">667ff62cf5c5a273ffd2a976a56004c6</guid></item><item><title>Jack Miller eyeing breakthrough MotoGP podium at Australian Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/jack-miller-eyeing-australian-grand-prix-podium/105907966</link><description>Jack Miller qualifies in the front row for Sunday's Australian Grand Prix — the first Aussie to do so since Casey Stoner in 2012.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7268d01cc3711cc55d464d5f7e8f5393</guid></item><item><title>Israel identifies remains of 10th hostage handed over by Hamas as 76-year-old Eliyahu Margalit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/israel-10th-hostage-handback-identified-76yo-eliyahu-margalit/105907884</link><description>Eliyahu Margalit's body was found after two bulldozers ploughed up pits in the earth in the city of Khan Younis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1d5a64c472215dfc37dd3ae22ab51a6</guid></item><item><title>Nottingham Forest sack manager Ange Postecoglou immediately after loss to Chelsea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/ange-postecoglou-sacked-nottingham-forest/105908162</link><description>Nottingham Forest sacked the winless manager moments after their 3-0 defeat by Chelsea on Saturday local time, which left the club 17th in the standings and on the brink of slipping into the relegation zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57c551c6fd2ddff4af0d49de00cd0a77</guid></item><item><title>Death doulas, family-led funerals and the deathcare movement hope to change the way we die</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/death-funeral-deathwalker-dying-well-vad-palliative-care/105831418</link><description>For many, voluntary assisted dying has come to symbolise control over how life ends. Yet dying well isn't just about those final hours. That's where a deathwalker like Zenith can help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a75637c06692c5f3a4e705ccb7269654</guid></item><item><title>China's economic slowdown has become its diplomatic weapon in the Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/china-economy-pacific-australia-united-states/105884758</link><description>For Australia and the US, the Pacific is no longer a comfortable backyard — it's a battleground of credibility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2b0e48dd4fde1249a89b421640ef595</guid></item><item><title>The deep Indigenous history of Australia deserves to be up in lights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/deep-time-indigenous-history-65000-years/105693082</link><description>We've flipped the script to put Indigenous Australians back at the centre of telling their own stories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1b24be62527f979869b9fe019461e17</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese is set to sit down with Donald Trump. What can he learn from other world leaders?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/anthony-albanese-sits-down-with-trump-what-can-he-learn/105894690</link><description>As other world leaders have discovered, a visit to Donald Trump's White House can become an unpredictable, if not uncomfortable, encounter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4b6d1356ae3c998aaee4553a3793db7</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew's decision to give up his titles may have been quietly orchestrated by members of his own family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/is-prince-andrews-decision-enough-to-stem-damage-to-monarchy/105907688</link><description>With the swirl of news around Prince Andrew this week, something had to be done; the question was whether he would do it himself or if his brother would be forced to show him the door.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b77456c907ef9b548850123a9b10fa3e</guid></item><item><title>BOM's first long-range summer forecast shows increased chance of extreme heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/bom-summer-weather-forecast-hot-and-dry-with-high-fire-risk/105899594</link><description>Hot nights coupled with high daytime temperatures could see Australia heading into an extremely hot summer, BOM's first long-range forecast indicates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f141a77feebbff9dd877f9c172a7d949</guid></item><item><title>Native mussel restoration project supported by Victor Harbor community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/mussel-bed-rebuilding-at-encounter-bay-after-algal-bloom/105887684</link><description>Victor Harbor was one of the first areas affected by SA's harmful algal bloom. Now its citizens are funding and supporting research into rebuilding native mussel populations as it looks to the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5482853b2341d466e8d2331ff929036a</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz Kids: Who says trivia is just for grown-ups? It's time to put your thinking cap on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/hard-quiz-kids-weekly-trivia-tom-gleeson/105894882</link><description>Hard Quiz Kids is here again, and we're gifting you a bunch of straightforward questions. Don't embarrass yourself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eae196e3bd245bc87722d2b719e6f741</guid></item><item><title>After Ukraine, Finland hopes it won't be Putin's next target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/inside-finlands-preparations-for-russian-invasion/105859992</link><description>Blasted into the bedrock, deep below the streets of Helsinki, these massive bunkers are currently used for recreation. Their primary function, however, is much more sinister: preparing for a Russian invasion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3896c79d12d96bc2c66108ed2320d926</guid></item><item><title>China's 'special forces'-style tourists packing big itineraries in small budgets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/china-hong-kong-special-forces-style-travel-sleep-mcdonalds/105902602</link><description>Young Chinese tourists with limited time and money are travelling 'special forces'-style — inspired by the efficiency, endurance, and intensity of military units.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecc8983a388385cd9855eaf49fa6fe2b</guid></item><item><title>The Assembly Steve Waugh video</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/the-assembly-steve-waugh-video/105794268</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d05552f7947a929fba15ced91f77322b</guid></item><item><title>How Mother Teresa helped Steve Waugh channel his 'power' for children in need</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/steve-waugh-on-meeting-mother-teresa/105671818</link><description>When Steve Waugh retired from cricket, he knew he wanted to use his influence to make a difference. It was meeting Mother Teresa that made him realise his new path.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f532c8e947e73fb6c25eb280850294d</guid></item><item><title>Lando Norris and Oscar Piastri crash in Formula 1 US Grand Prix sprint race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/lando-norris-and-oscar-piastri-collide-in-formula-1-us-sprint/105908518</link><description>Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris have once again made contact with each other in a Formula 1 race, this time taking each other out at the sprint race of the US Grand Prix, just two weeks after their collision in Singapore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0f825561d6966341b8a99ea5341d7a1</guid></item><item><title>Gellung Warl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/gellung-warl/105887694</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf0fe968e72376f9816a5efb2bcd3919</guid></item><item><title>Nginma Ngainga Wara</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/nginma-ngainga-wara/105887688</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83c32e5e94f6c2ec9f717181d30f1691</guid></item><item><title>Nyerna Yoorrook Telkuna</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/nyerna-yoorrook-telkuna/105887680</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93e42589db4490a6e86b296e2255f3d6</guid></item><item><title>'Gellung Warl' and other Victorian Aboriginal words that are part of Australia's first Treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/victoria-treaty-aboriginal-language-words-gellung-warl/105874164</link><description>Victoria's first Treaty with First Peoples' was debated in state parliament last week. The Treaty introduces some Victorian Aboriginal words you may not have heard before — here's how to say them and what they mean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5888d4d050285e49bfa8b0319e6bfc2c</guid></item><item><title>Mural of Sydney's queer history removed from Surry Hills Police Station days after going up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/queer-sydney-history-mural-removed-surry-hills-police-station/105906396</link><description>The artwork, Queer Sydney: A History, was hung at Surry Hills Police Station, metres from where the annual Gay and Lesbian Mardi Gras parade is held.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18b1a6dd261ce61a763340e63c32d468</guid></item><item><title>Aussie Bird Count brings together students, photographers and nature-lovers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/aussie-bird-count-students-volunteer/105903124</link><description>A primary school teacher is getting her students involved in a volunteer-led bird count, to gather a snapshot of birds across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1902614b6d2d117e4440091bf145ffb</guid></item><item><title>'No Kings' protest crowds gather across the US against Donald Trump's leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/no-kings-protests-across-us-against-donald-trump/105908510</link><description>Organisers say the rallies reflect frustration over the Trump administration's prosecutions of the president's perceived enemies, immigration raids and the sending of troops into US cities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">844c41c111bff92bc93ef28915c54a4f</guid></item><item><title>Cheap energy driven by rooftop solar means larger solar farms could be unviable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/cheap-solar-household-energy-pushing-solar-farms-out-of-market/105898336</link><description>Australia's renewable energy push has resulted in a surge in household solar power. But what does that mean for private solar farms?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36014b920dd1bc4459bb64a96d7ea4d1</guid></item><item><title>Julian Assange seeks 20-year jail term for David Morales, the Spaniard who spied on him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/julian-assange-suggested-sentence-for-david-morales/105908048</link><description>His lawyers suggested the jail term for David Morales, accused of discovery and disclosure of secrets, bribery, money laundering and illegal possession of weapons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d09193e99604a479bc0cc7a2da23e6e</guid></item><item><title>Sheffield Shield round two quick hits: Marnus Labuschagne confirms form ahead of Ashes, Scott Boland bullies and spinners offer reminder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/sheffield-shield-summary-marnus-labuschagne/105907142</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne's magical early season form continues with the bat, Scott Boland and a pair of spinners offer a reminder of their skill, while Sam Konstas turns on the flair at round two of the Sheffield Shield.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">054ff0d8e5945ea2d312a9468fd3278e</guid></item><item><title>Iconic house for sale for only second time in 193-year history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/iconic-house-for-sale-for-only-second-time-in-193-year-history/105838914</link><description>Classical musicians Richard and Suzy Miller count their circa-1832 home as one of their greatest creative achievements as they prepare to leave it for someone else to love.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0cb817277090afe4c3ee03c0a1fb2c2</guid></item><item><title>James Duckworth falls at Almaty Open semi-final stage against Daniil Medvedev</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/james-duckworth-falls-almati-open-semi-final-daniil-medvedev/105908658</link><description>Australian seed-slayer James Duckworth has finally met his match in Almaty, where Daniil Medvedev dug deep to beat him in three sets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0d127a1f537ae19f3d552f01bce600f</guid></item><item><title>North Queensland by-election to provide snapshot of state's politics a year on from LNP victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/qld-hinchinbrook-by-election-analysis/105902784</link><description>The looming by-election in Hinchinbrook will not have a significant impact on the makeup of Queensland parliament, but it will give insight into the state of play of politics a year after the LNP swept to power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">172765f854cdca401a9862668704f49f</guid></item><item><title>Flood mapping is different between councils, but one resident is calling for change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/qld-flood-mapping-local-council-development-ban-petition/105885362</link><description>Ben Parkinson is proud of the five acres he calls home in south-east Queensland, but what is missing is the ability to develop his land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7ccf073b5939120e126c4119a081064</guid></item><item><title>It's been called Canberra's 'forever government' — but ACT Labor's brand is growing tired</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/act-canberra-forever-government-but-labor-brand-growing-tired/105904332</link><description>It's been a year since Canberrans re-elected an ACT Labor government for a seventh consecutive term — but as budget pressures bite, analysts say Labor's stocks are suffering from brand fatigue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ee3cbb31b12feb0dbf9a314f57eeb6d</guid></item><item><title>Mike Hewson creates controversial children's playgrounds. Explore his latest creation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/mike-hewson-takes-kids-four-storeys-underground/105896640</link><description>This designer's "risky playgrounds" are often divisive. His latest is four storeys underground in a former World War II oil tank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5af465a6bbf0383d41c1060eddfa1af6</guid></item><item><title>New Tasmanian Integrity Commission head will decide whether to release report from six-year investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/tasmanian-integrity-commission-finishes-six-year-investigation/105894390</link><description>Seven years after allegations were made against a practitioner who was allegedly misusing public resources, Tasmania's Integrity Commission has finalised its investigation into the matter. However, the report has not been released to the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c5fd50bb3ddf358b3e61158eed83e42</guid></item><item><title>Social media promotion of raw milk 'misleading and dangerous'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/raw-milk-trend-worries-experts/105636166</link><description>A public health expert says social media content creators are undermining years of scientific research by promoting raw milk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be479a18a9b8b5bd2c9c5515b5b11008</guid></item></channel></rss>