<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:55:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Chevron invests $3b to continue development of the Gorgon gas project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/chevron-to-continue-development-of-the-gorgon-gas-project/106105984</link><description>The works will connect gas fields in the Greater Gorgon Area to existing infrastructure on Barrow Island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6605d42224c13ea286e827760abcd918</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Usman Khawaja's Test future questioned as Travis Head, Jake Weatherald open at Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/usman-khawaja-test-future-ashes-travis-head-jake-weatherald/106107710</link><description>After another slashing partnership between openers Travis Head and Jake Weatherald, the future of Usman Khawaja in the Test arena appears to be getting murkier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d23b20fc5430b142af6fa84641c3d79a</guid></item><item><title>Energy giant AGL latest company to abandon Gippsland offshore wind zone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/third-victorian-offshore-wind-project-abandoned/106108856</link><description>Energy giant AGL has become the third company this year to abandon plans to develop an offshore wind farm in Victoria's east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19f92be5472dd61c253a13021a293eff</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania Devils could play extra year in existing venues during Macquarie Point stadium construction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/tasmania-devils-prepared-to-wait-for-stadium-afl/106105976</link><description>The Tasmania Devils CEO says the club will likely play in the AFL from existing venues for a year longer than expected, while awaiting construction of the Macquarie Point stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54590a0bd459a15b3d2cf0dc2fb1bb57</guid></item><item><title>Cary-Hiroyuki Tagawa, actor who performed in Mortal Kombat, has died at 75</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/cary-hiroyuki-tagawa-died-at-75/106109270</link><description>Tagawa died surrounded by his family in Santa Barbara from complications due to a stroke, according to his manager Margie Weiner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f2505d88563bec72acd402c8981f1fa</guid></item><item><title>Gocs cameo leaves Smith starstruck, England mourns dropped catches, Weatherald winks — five quick hits from Ashes second Test day two</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ashes-second-test-day-two-gocs-smith-archer-head/106107888</link><description>Steve Smith is starstruck by a surprise cameo, England rues a slew of drops and Jake Weatherald announces his arrival with a wink. Here are the quick hits from the second day of the pink-ball Ashes Test in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fca052ae07b72821a3591793d738cec2</guid></item><item><title>Jacob Elordi, Nicole Kidman, Alison Brie among the 2026 AACTA nominees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/aacta-nominations-2026-jacob-elordi-nicole-kidman/106101160</link><description>Apple Cider Vinegar, a partly fictionalised retelling of accused wellness scammer Belle Gibson's public fall from grace, leads this year's AACTA nominations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95d35035fb82bef329f01389c5ded03f</guid></item><item><title>EU hits Elon Musk's X with $210 million fine for breaching bloc's social media law</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/eu-fines-x-120m-euros-for-breaching-online-content-rules/106109626</link><description>European Union regulators say the breaches of the bloc's digital regulations could leave users exposed to scams and manipulation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5d067a74e0c45efa3f59dd28fad3866</guid></item><item><title>WA Police charge children over Geraldton bushfire that destroyed home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/geraldton-bushfire-police-lay-charges/106109634</link><description>WA Police allege young boys were responsible for lighting a fire in Geraldton last weekend that later reignited and destroyed a home in an outer suburb of the Mid West city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26a6ef4372cdf369a5ed6f71699e208d</guid></item><item><title>Netflix wins deal to buy Warner Bros's film and TV studio and streaming service for $108b</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/netflix-buys-warner-film-and-television-unit/106109630</link><description>The merger will see beloved shows and movies such as The Big Bang Theory, Game of Thrones and The Wizard of Oz join Netflix’s portfolio.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">981ddc6ccc5d007d5023ffd52e9e62d2</guid></item><item><title>Russian manpower challenges Ukraine's technological edge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/russia-ukraine-drones-europe-warfare-technology-weapons/106088044</link><description>When it comes to weaponry, Russia has strength in manpower despite Ukraine's early technological edge while Europe's arms production efforts are running into infrastructure hurdles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1265c860b9aa0cca74479ed0aaf2a6e</guid></item><item><title>Porridge back on the menu as budget pressures grow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/budget-pressures-anika-wells-peter-costello-porridge-senate/106088014</link><description>How does a treasurer tell households the government will no longer continue a $300 energy rebate when it's happy to blow $100,000 on three flights?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9275c262e4575f63a63a407e008ac21</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 6: The day scientists found evidence of water on Mars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/today-in-history-december-6-water-on-mars/106096326</link><description>Scientists said at the time that the flow of water would have filled multiple swimming pools.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">054766de87b60e22cc18569655b05e35</guid></item><item><title>Lebanon says it's trying to disarm Hezbollah but fears sparking internal conflict</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/hezbollah-refuses-to-disarm-as-israel-bombs-lebanon/106105328</link><description>Lebanon's government says it is trying to disarm militant group Hezbollah, but there are fears of sparking an internal conflict.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08ff3200b8808497c7b511f7adb8cdda</guid></item><item><title>Senator who backs social media ban says she was a victim of a catfishing attempt in high school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/youngest-senator-reveals-she-was-catfished-online/106107346</link><description>As the social media ban for teens looms, the parliament's most recent senator reveals she knows firsthand the dangers that can confront young people online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36f20c5139f55ad3d007ff21ef249880</guid></item><item><title>Australia delights in a familiar Ashes tale of English woe to take control at the Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/australia-delights-in-a-familar-tale-of-english-woe-at-the-gabba/106109124</link><description>Australia took control of the second Ashes Test at the Gabba on a day that carried plenty of the hallmarks of failed English tours of yesteryear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19c15eaa8e29f069a6d5569366cc2322</guid></item><item><title>Vladimir Putin offers India 'uninterrupted' fuel supplies at summit in New Delhi with Narendra Modi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/vladimir-putin-offers-india-uninterrupted-fuel-supplies/106109824</link><description>The offer is made at a summit in New Delhi, where new deals on energy, agriculture and labour have also been announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b238a3fa21ca446dc7aa3c074f7c98b</guid></item><item><title>Under deadline, Donald Trump is remaking the White House in his own image</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/donald-trump-is-remaking-the-white-house-in-his-own-image/105552330</link><description>The US president has spent much of his first year back in office changing the historic building he fought to reclaim in a bid to cement his legacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f4b9ceff316e49e4842fbae903137c2</guid></item><item><title>Council finally funds fix for Townsville residents bracing for sewage through homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/back-flow-that-sends-raw-sewage-through-wulguru-homes/106091194</link><description>After decades of sewage back flow problems, Townsville City Council is funding a fix that could keep raw human waste out of homes and backyards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">173bf17e6b1e996b426d7a6df0d57357</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide Strikers - Hobart Hurricanes WBBL match called off due to hole in the pitch after ball goes under roller</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/hole-in-adelaide-pitch-complicates-wbbl-finals-puzzle/106109872</link><description>The Adelaide-Hobart WBBL match has to be abandoned after a ball goes under the roller during the innings break, creating a hole in the pitch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b795c8f5b7bd995ab59a5ef2d2d5177</guid></item><item><title>It's been a tumultuous time for SA's Liberals — they now need to find another new leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/sa-liberal-party-new-leader-analysis/106108800</link><description>SA Liberal leader Vincent Tarzia has stepped down. Pressure had been mounting in the lead-up to the 2026 state election, and predictions for the Liberal Party's chances are not looking promising.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">712c9410084cf6a74ba0ca3ce24a92a2</guid></item><item><title>First-aid advice for venomous bites and stings at your fingertips with new app</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/australian-bites-stings-app-provides-emergency-first-aid-advice/106100610</link><description>As a new app is launched to provide first-aid advice for venomous bites and stings, a reptile expert urges people to learn how to respond in an emergency ahead of an expected spike in demand for antivenom over summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ac170200b55d76f51f1e86dd2f9539b</guid></item><item><title>Efforts turn to helping survivors and recovering the dead after devastating floods in Indonesia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/indonesia-sumatra-floods-landslides-weather-recovery-efforts/106097076</link><description>Landslides across Sumatra in Indonesia have cut off roads and destroyed homes, creating several pockets of isolated villages where a helicopter is the only way in.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a73b3e2b1904da69e708162f515043ac</guid></item><item><title>Sexism, harassment and inflexibility drive women out of winemaking, survey reveals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/sexism-harassment-driving-women-out-of-winemaking/106092352</link><description>Among the main factors contributing to women leaving Australia's wine industry were sexism, discrimination, and a lack of flexibility, a nationwide study has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">094e243fb1468c4e673b13fdb1a2a964</guid></item><item><title>Australian Christmas in full bloom as flora and fauna burst with colour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/christmas-flora-and-fauna/106105702</link><description>As the summer heat settles in, flora and fauna associated with Christmas in Australia can be spotted throughout the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f8a1842054bfafbb5f4f2081770f575</guid></item><item><title>State Theatre's new name speaks to the philanthropy predicament in the arts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/arts-funding-philanthropy-melbourne-state-theatre-ian-potter/106088052</link><description>No sensible organisation can now afford to turn down money or its requirements. So, cash-strapped institutions find themselves between a rock and a hard place with a big name painted on it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d39e9f43068b001c6ce3e2e947fdcc11</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane community radio station 4ZZZ celebrates 50 years against all odds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/4zzz-brisbane-radio-station-50-years/106101658</link><description>Brisbane community radio station 4ZZZ has withstood political, social and financial pressure for 50 years and it's still thriving as a loud and proud beacon of counterculture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1532fda67974c3d08f8e86892a5ce3e2</guid></item><item><title>Young people urged to join stem cell donor roll with full matches hard to come by</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/stem-cell-donor-campaign-rowan-tong-law/106086354</link><description>Rowan Tong-Law, 18, was diagnosed with acute myeloid leukaemia last year and has been searching for a full stem cell donor match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7619250c0c8fe5a61dbd35854893da66</guid></item><item><title>Woman's two-year journey advocating for Auslan support highlights cracks in aged care system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/deaf-seniors-falling-through-aged-care-cracks/106084008</link><description>One Deaf woman living with dementia has been without basic care services for two years. Advocates warn her story represents a much larger problem.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">857456218e73eb03ba41a265e65343e3</guid></item><item><title>English teenager Tommy Lamb closing in on 100-day, 21-country overland journey to Adelaide's Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/tommy-lamb-ashes-trip-to-adelaide-manchester/106109176</link><description>Tommy Lamb is taking the long way from Manchester to Adelaide for the third Ashes Test and the 18-year is closing in on a 100-day odyssey that must be seen to be believed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fef5110c9f56da13b3f39f394c0576b0</guid></item><item><title>When will construction begin on the new Hobart stadium?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/what-is-next-for-approved-hobart-afl-stadium/106105676</link><description>That and other questions answered now that the $1.13 billion stadium project has passed Tasmania's parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">498c74d67f1a43d39e7bfef08a626fee</guid></item><item><title>BOM says 'threshold' for fire weather warning wasn't met ahead of Tasmanian bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/bom-warnings-ahead-of-bushfires-across-tasmania/106105962</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says the initial forecasts did not meet the threshold to trigger fire weather warnings ahead of Thursday when 30 blazes burnt across Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c246f885887b104140d861380f48ad7</guid></item><item><title>Coronial inquest investigates Terry Airey's death at Sunshine Coast University Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/coronial-inquest-investigates-terry-airey-death/106090278</link><description>A Queensland hospital has increased staffing and revamped its radiology protocols and systems following an 87-year-old's death from organ failure after routine surgery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bbe0dfc8c2f6c068198bdae68e0b6d1</guid></item><item><title>Life on the APY Lands where family, country and culture are protected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/apy-lands-culture-lifestyle-protected-but-calls-for-houses-jobs/105999584</link><description>The stark beauty of Australia's protected APY Lands is alive with ancient songlines and culture. But Elders see a need for change to secure the future of today's children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">353653a4d89cd1c2c5636c30029525d0</guid></item><item><title>Frank Gehry, world-renowned architect who designed the Guggenheim Museum Bilbao, dies aged 96</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/frank-gehry-guggenheim-bilbao-dies-aged-96/106109892</link><description>Gehry's most memorable creations were either celebrated as works of genius or reviled as self-indulgent messes — but either way, people were looking, as he liked to say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecfb4aee4144b1097d9f9d29ef26c3fc</guid></item><item><title>Blue whale calf numbers rise after slow migration start along WA's south west coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/baby-blue-whale-numbers-wa-south-west-coast/106104766</link><description>Researchers are relieved as baby blue whale numbers increase after a slow start to the migration season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce2461b0ebf884ba690caf4fa73f245f</guid></item><item><title>Blue whale swimming off Busselton Jetty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/blue-whale-swimming-off-busselton-jetty/106105306</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d10be79b81cc7f5bcfab5c804d73069</guid></item><item><title>Blue whales off Dunsborough</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/cow-and-calf-blue-whale/106106620</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2679d706e21deadabffe76fdbb7dce0</guid></item><item><title>This tasty, veggie-filled omlette is a fast and satisfying meal - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/ejjeh-zucchini-omelette/106102824</link><description>Ejjeh is a traditional omelette made with eggs, herbs, spices and that soft zucchini flesh that would otherwise go to waste. It's simple, fresh and full of flavour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77fef1ae7c6da366ad1c89e922b140e5</guid></item><item><title>'Australia's biggest' miniature railway opens to the public in the central Victorian town of Harcourt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/victorian-miniature-railway-opens-harcourt-trains/106095804</link><description>A group of dedicated volunteers say they have built "Australia's biggest" miniature railway in regional Victoria and after a decade of hard work it's finally open to the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b38c116f5a6f1b0aa11f8db22a3d014</guid></item><item><title>Roger Cook wants to change the rules on project approvals to avoid FOMO, but critics have their doubts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/concerns-as-roger-cook-seeks-to-speed-up-project-approvals/106100190</link><description>The WA premier is seeking wide-reaching powers to change the rules on approvals for "big, shiny, job-creating projects" — but it has prompted concern from the opposition, environmentalists and even lawyers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">457c6d34d10955987fa825d514bfdd0a</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos found in new Edith Cowan University campus in Perth CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/asbestos-found-in-new-ecu-campus-in-perth-cbd/106109070</link><description>WA's parliament is told asbestos has been discovered in fire doors at Edith Cowan University's flagship new campus in Perth's CBD, and it won't be removed until after the first semester next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59fb25929fe3469ce6ffd2b649633c6f</guid></item><item><title>The National Indigenous Art Triennial in Canberra reflects on legacy, rebirth and renewal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/national-indigenous-art-triennial-after-the-rain-tony-albert/106105020</link><description>Indigenous artists from across Australia, including Alair Pambegan and Grace Kemarre Robinya, feature as part of the National Indigenous Art Triennial in Canberra: After the Rain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">298d22642d30f831c89ee4391ea7cd3c</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide residents 'in the dark' over Gilbert Street development proposal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/adelaide-residents-in-the-dark-over-gilbert-street-development-p/106108752</link><description>Residents of Gilbert Street who originally opposed a development proposal say a deal was struck behind closed doors to proceed with planning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b07dfb5d471400b76964018e9e410e36</guid></item><item><title>Up to 16 homes lost in Bulahdelah and Koolewong fires in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/strong-winds-intense-heat-thunderstorms-nsw/106109226</link><description>More than 1,500 firefighters with 300 vehicles were deployed by the RFS across eastern and central NSW amid extreme heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97594e0790a4e0dbae88468a24108d86</guid></item><item><title>Bunbury Indigenous elders write children's book in Noongar language to preserve culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/noongar-kala-bunbury-aboriginal-elders-south-west-wa/106101058</link><description>Once forbidden from speaking their local language, a group of Indigenous elders in WA use it in a children's book, hoping to breathe life into a dying dialect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8c8164c0eeec9b3ba3ab586b29b8bad</guid></item><item><title>Residents still unable to return home as north-east Victoria bushfire continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/markwood-fire-recovery-houses-lost/106110100</link><description>North-east Victorian residents are still unable to return home as firefighters assess bushfire damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b13e50e22ebfcfa29edd47ab97b690b5</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate hikes increasingly likely in 2026 but a major event would produce the opposite result</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/interest-rates-2026/106106712</link><description>Inflation is a problem as 2025 comes to a close and it's set to remain that way. Without a swift rise in productivity or a financial markets meltdown, borrowers are facing several interest rate hikes next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d746d4688a4127389fb3a4b35770ed4</guid></item><item><title>Controversial genetically modified mosquito release paused after backlash in Qld</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/controversial-gm-friendly-mosquito-release-paused-csiro-oxitec/106108190</link><description>An organisation that planned to sell "friendly" mosquitoes to reduce the spread of diseases like dengue withdraws its licence application after backlash from scientists and health experts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99c152b0ac25af67c26215182860c9d9</guid></item><item><title>Malaysian football in chaos after FIFA suspends national players from Argentina, Spain and Brazil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/player-naturalisation-scandal-rocks-malaysian-football/106095646</link><description>A football players' union says seven South American and European members of the Malaysian national team suspended over allegedly forged documents are "victims".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4856b0aaec28e11010c2f73e3c63280</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos far from a World Cup 'group of death' against United States, Paraguay and a European qualifier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/socceroos-world-cup-draw-analysis/106110310</link><description>Nothing can be guaranteed in a World Cup, but the Socceroos' draw alongside the United States, Paraguay and a European qualifier gives a solid shot at advancing, with the Australians avoiding most of the big names.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49c5d81bdd2e928aa1bc4fde8d7d5a0b</guid></item><item><title>2025 US National Security Strategy warns Europe faces 'civilisational erasure', does not mention AUKUS</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/trump-warns-europe-faces-civilisational-erasure/106109888</link><description>The Trump administration releases a document saying its goal is to "help Europe correct its current trajectory", adding that it faces "civilisational erasure" due in part to "mass migration".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">031ccdcf7ac49d6c2a4eaf559d9d572f</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025 updates: Mitchell Starc's all-round brilliance puts Australia on the verge of 2-0 series lead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/ashes-second-test-live-gabba-day-three-australia-vs-england/106110146</link><description>Mitchell Starc and Scott Boland torment England with both bat and ball as Australia puts itself on the verge of claiming a 2-0 series lead in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d64b4e80361f254db5f9a88be54a499e</guid></item><item><title>Whale researchers in Timor-Leste are calling for regulation of the whale watching industry following reports of operators piloting boats too close to mammals.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/whale-tourism-in-timor-leste/106108468</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">234a2971d877726ad7e5837065f4dfeb</guid></item><item><title>Critics choice nominations 2026: Sinners scores 17 nods, One Battle After Another earns 14</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/critics-choice-awards-nominations-sinner/106110372</link><description>The gothic vampire period drama Sinners has topped the Critics' Choice Movie Awards, securing 17 nods, followed by One Battle After Another with 14.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a30900a46808c056c75a85fb6601196e</guid></item><item><title>Geraldton community raises funds and thanks responders as juveniles charged with alleged arson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/juveniles-charged-with-alleged-arson-following-geraldton-fires/106110454</link><description>While police say the investigation is over, the local community is still trying to move forward from the devastation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4122eb9d5167b06fe6f887df21b32420</guid></item><item><title>Teen seriously injured in e-bike crash in Claremont after e-rideables inquiry called for widespread changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/teen-seriously-injured-in-ebike-crash-in-claremont/106110818</link><description>A 14-year-old boy suffers serious injuries in an e-bike crash in Perth's western suburbs, just two days after a parliamentary inquiry into WA's e-rideable laws made 33 recommendations in a bid to make the devices safer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beba62eb0654ea9ca6f7cebcd2e680cf</guid></item><item><title>Not all babies need a hepatitis B shot at birth, US vaccine advisers say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/us-vaccine-advisers-say-not-all-babies-need-a-hepatitis-b-shot/106110932</link><description>President Donald Trump is calling the vote a "very good decision" after US vaccine advisers recommended ending the universal hepatitis B shots at birth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df40efa82146c8a5f6816b5bc09ffc1b</guid></item><item><title>Overnight fire exchange at Afghan-Pakistan border kills five and wounds eight, officials say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/overnight-fire-exchange-at-afghan-pakistan-border-kills-five/106110986</link><description>Each side has blamed the other for triggering the clash in violation of a tenuous two-month ceasefire, with the clashes lasting until dawn Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fa740808b4ac6ddc330d6757423b6ce</guid></item><item><title>Archer's English pillow, Starc's top score and a couple of firsts for England — quick hits from day three of the Gabba Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/ashes-gabba-test-day-three-england-australia-quick-hits/106110492</link><description>A sleepy Jofra Archer cops a rinsing from Matthew Hayden, as the English finally make it through the first over of an innings. Here are the quick hits from day three of the Gabba Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c64f50b01ae250aec71536d3473f161</guid></item><item><title>Opposition to social media ban scores minor political points at best</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/social-media-age-ban-albanese-government-sussan-ley-opposition/106097916</link><description>Australia's social media age ban is one of the most significant attempts to rebalance the asymmetric power relationship between government and tech.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1c19bd7f93be3f2eab79e2f3c0e9566</guid></item><item><title>Politicians in South-East Asia ignore climate change at their own political peril</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/floods-thailand-climate-leadership-monsoon-torrential-rain/106097870</link><description>Accused of incompetence and apathy in the aftermath of natural disasters, governments across Asia are facing increasing backlash as the impact of global warming intensifies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17caf11fe4eac45fbe9ce13a3ecbccb6</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: So, you think you're good at quizzes? It's time to play HARD!</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/106090792</link><description>Alright, show us what you've got. I'll keep my expectations low.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1614ab325a4465d488e9f23ca9b12335</guid></item><item><title>Gearing up for the school holidays? Here's how to survive them without social media</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/social-media-ban-school-holidays-parenting-children/106018636</link><description>These school holidays, children under 16 will find themselves with less social media access as a ban comes into place. We asked the experts how parents can best support their kids with the transition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df818395897eaf31c4423307fd9381fe</guid></item><item><title>How pregnancy is being criminalised in post-Roe America</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/pregnancy-criminalisation-abortion-fetal-personhood-miscarriage/106097546</link><description>In the wake of widespread abortion bans, US prosecutors launch hundreds of cases charging people with crimes related to their pregnancy, miscarriage, stillbirth or birth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b40d723313a028093c154415c269b698</guid></item><item><title>What life's like when you're Deaf and blind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/a-deafblind-day-in-the-life/105789718</link><description>Living with vision impairment throws up many challenges. Being Deaf on top of that requires you to go to even greater lengths just to fit in with the modern world. This is how one Deafblind woman does it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a956beee6b8ee94b7a2d6c74a16d9d78</guid></item><item><title>Rare piece of Australia's Indigenous history captured on camera in the desert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/aboriginal-elders-historical-photo-of-first-contact-lost/106010316</link><description>In the 1960s, the last of the desert families were coming into contact with white people. For one woman, the moment was captured on camera.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7abee498779fc3abfdd1edf31be65f7a</guid></item><item><title>Russia's claim it has captured key Ukrainian city could be Putin 'scaremongering'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/russian-claim-it-has-captured-pokrovsk-could-be-scaremongering/106099458</link><description>Russian President Vladimir Putin this week claimed Moscow's biggest battlefield gain in close to two years: the Ukrainian city of Pokrovsk. Some experts don't believe him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c91a557935861d797674d13560ce1b3b</guid></item><item><title>Republicans just won an election in Tennessee but it's still bad news for Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/tennessee-special-election-van-epps-behn/106106326</link><description>A Republican claimed a win at a by-election in Tennessee this week, but his party colleagues are sounding alarm bells.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd1c905795a22c1d914b665c6c9e82aa</guid></item><item><title>Australia senses Ashes kill as England and Bazball face day of reckoning at the Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/judgement-day-arrives-for-bazball-australia-moves-in-for-kill/106110882</link><description>Australia was patient, mature and ruthless on day three at the Gabba, widening the chasm between it and an England side now set for its day of reckoning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d6ade1bbdc1dcdabd936b05843d9f68</guid></item><item><title>Reedy Creek Reserve's Paperbark Forest Walk in Agnes Water closed after tourist and environment concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/agnes-water-reedy-creek-reserve-closed-paperbark-walk/106100738</link><description>Bush Heritage Australia says it is still considering how to safely reopen the walk, which prior to closure was being visited by 100,000 people a year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17e00acf204351a585a62c7e2fea5b8e</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne council responds to lunch-thieving seagulls knocking food from pedestrians' hands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/seagulls-learn-to-knock-food-from-peoples-hands/106043826</link><description>Pesky seagulls snatching food from unsuspecting members of the public has spurred a Melbourne council to start canine patrols of Federation Square.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7f4a5d7dbae1847da8ae3200e1e7d33</guid></item><item><title>'Less algal influence' seen in some SA waters, divers say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/divers-notice-improved-marine-conditions-algal-bloom/106090962</link><description>Open water divers say underwater visibility has improved and marine life is returning to some areas off South Australia's coast. Experts say it's a positive sign, but warn it's "way too early" to say the environment is recovering from the state's algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfad2cccdd7bf4dc93dddc21091b37d3</guid></item><item><title>Number of homes destroyed in NSW bushfires rises to at least 20 as recovery efforts begin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/sixteen-homes-lost-koolewong-central-coast-fire-but-maybe-more/106110700</link><description>Natural disasters are declared in six areas across NSW, as the number of homes destroyed rises to at least 20, with the majority concentrated on the Central Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f545b09a363eca4e348ed86afcb4cacf</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians in West Bank's Bethlehem hold first Christmas tree lighting ceremony since 2022</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/christmas-tree-lighting-ceremony-in-bethlehem-2025/106111514</link><description>As the ceasefire in Gaza enters its second month, the Palestinian city revered by Christians as the birthplace of Jesus holds a ceremony to light up a 20-metre tree at the edge of Manger Square.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c3f868b55d8496e879c05c64cdec9cc</guid></item><item><title>Criminals are trying new methods to get drugs into Australia but authorities say they are always watching</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/attempted-drug-imports-sea-australia-mothership-smuggling/106073102</link><description>The alleged use of an international livestock ship to smuggle drugs into Western Australia last month prompted a media storm, but one expert says it is just one among a "dizzying variety" of methods criminals are trying.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4191a2f6367c22bebf14314f40b9247</guid></item><item><title>Water leaks, electric shocks force 32yo breast cancer unit off road in Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/breast-cancer-screening-bus-pulled-after-staff-electric-shocks/106090358</link><description>Tasmania's health department was aware a 32-year-old breast cancer screening bus was unsafe for years, but continued operating it up until two staff suffered electric shocks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ff63e98eda12f40f8dbbd4beb2606a5</guid></item><item><title>Insurance doctor never spoke to traumatised former NSW Police officer before challenging his mental health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/nsw-police-officer-with-ptsd-wins-insurance-case-amid-battle/106093472</link><description>A former NSW Police officer with post-traumatic stress disorder had his mental health incorrectly challenged by a doctor who never consulted or examined him during a year-long battle with the force's insurer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d5e4694754c274d6be22a3bcd766afc</guid></item><item><title>Michael Neser takes two key England wickets with caught-and-bowleds as Australia in Ashes command</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/caught-and-bowled-king-neser-feared-his-test-career-was-over/106111568</link><description>Bowling all-rounder Michael Neser is back and taking vital wickets after beginning to think he had played his last Test match for Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34ca06f197f5d99c18fee149bc7f6cce</guid></item><item><title>QVMAG costs Launceston ratepayers millions of dollars every year, but there are fears reform has hit a wall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/qvmag-launceston-future-reform/106053812</link><description>More than three years after a Tasmanian council green-lit a plan to ease the financial burden of the Queen Victoria Museum and Art Gallery, stakeholders worry momentum has stalled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c2d4c946fd4053b35bac4240de05654</guid></item><item><title>Aged care in Australia under the microscope in new documentary Careless</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/careless-documentary-film-aged-care-australia-sue-thomson/106100558</link><description>Filmmaker Sue Thomson recently lost her mum. But before that, they made the beautiful documentary Careless together, which explores Australia's aged care system mess.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7eecf0bd88b748e1bbea443583c5e1e4</guid></item><item><title>Western Australia's Port Hedland marks 50th anniversary of Cyclone Joan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/cyclone-joan-remembered-50-years-on/106105218</link><description>Cyclone Joan made landfall near the WA mining town of Port Hedland a year after Cyclone Tracy flattened Darwin, and it was almost as powerful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07b2549729e7a97acaf7b3f01384c184</guid></item><item><title>Russian drone, missile attacks target Ukrainian railways and power infrastructure in overnight barrage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/russia-attacks-ukrainian-energy-infrastructure/106111570</link><description>A large-scale Russian drone and missile attack damages power facilities in eight Ukrainian regions, causing blackouts and forcing nuclear power plants to cut output.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9e28d3b538b262a66c7d54959ae2fe5</guid></item><item><title>Fire jumps a kilometre over water, disaster declared for NSW regions — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/heatwaves-fire-live-blog-december-6/106110894</link><description>NSW Premier Chris Minns says it has been a "difficult 24 hours", with more than 20 fires still uncontained across the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c18a4d1320eaa2ffec3079f7378c5589</guid></item><item><title>Researchers are teaching foxes not to eat freshwater turtle eggs, by making them feel sick</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/training-foxes-to-stop-killing-native-turtles-aversion-condition/106026320</link><description>Researchers in Victoria are using taste aversion conditioning to stop foxes eating native turtle eggs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">904402fb27dc1fd3146ccac2d254e7e0</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos FIFA World Cup 2026 times, dates and locations set, with games in Vancouver, Seattle and Santa Clara</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/socceroos-set-for-wild-west-north-american-world-cup-adventure/106111662</link><description>Australia's North American west coast adventure at the World Cup is confirmed, with matches in Vancouver, Seattle and Santa Clara in California.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7aaff72b6b041c20050aa4cde13783c</guid></item><item><title>Australia's new land clearing, regrowth laws spark concern among farmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/farmer-concerns-as-australian-land-clearing-laws-tighten/106104878</link><description>Queensland producers say a blanket approach to environmental laws will restrict their ability to manage land sustainably and responsibly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbd94438aad374b26c5da2a12aabe40c</guid></item><item><title>Prime minister's office approved Anika Wells's almost-$100,000 flights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/pmo-approved-wells-flights/106111598</link><description>The furore over Communications Minister Anika Wells's expenses continues, with just three days until the government's much-anticipated social media ban for under 16s comes into force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee55c4ecfec6b883eecfce1559d5f1b5</guid></item><item><title>Iconic Lagoon restaurant lease ends after 40 colourful and controversial years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/wollongong-iconic-lagoon-restaurant-lease-ends/106077292</link><description>For four decades Lagoon Restaurant has been one of Wollongong's most iconic and controversial establishments, enjoying a prime seaside location and a close relationship with the city's political class.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43794c1266f909517717039f3c339315</guid></item><item><title>Surf Life Saving WA brings all-abilities nippers program to regions for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/regional-first-for-all-abilities-nippers-surf-lifesaving/106093904</link><description>Catering to children with autism spectrum disorders, it is the first of its kind in regional Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08a0fa804bc4bd0a70cb58c4f3aad91a</guid></item><item><title>Cleveland Dodd inquest findings expected to unpack dysfunction in WA's youth justice system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/coroner-to-hand-down-cleveland-dodd-inquest-findings-/106105718</link><description>The coroner investigating WA’s first recorded death in youth detention is expected to hand down wide-ranging findings and recommendations following the death of 16-year-old Cleveland Dodd in 2022. Here's everything you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47288d99a3815da2fad534c77f62d2f9</guid></item><item><title>Perth Scorchers book WBBL finals spot with seven-wicket win over winless Brisbane Heat at the WACA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/scorchers-book-finals-spot-with-renegades-wbbl-defence-over/106111830</link><description>Beth Mooney's flawless 94 not out leads Perth to victory in its must-win game against Brisbane, ensuring the Scorchers will play finals again in the WBBL.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87f96387164efe42f678dbbec451dfd0</guid></item><item><title>Aerial view of bushfire destruction in northern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/aerial-view-of-bushfire-destruction-in-northern-nsw/106111894</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73a8f5b5ea93981b016a93ba7d568bdc</guid></item><item><title>Firefighting aircraft battle raging bushfires in northern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/firefighting-helicopters-battle-raging-bushfires-in-northern-nsw/106111892</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aacacb1a2f4512d4ae24f606b7415f35</guid></item><item><title>Child of Stolen Generations in WA given her birth certificate after 88 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/stolen-generation-survivor-given-birth-certificate/106074930</link><description>Maisie Harkin was born on country in Western Australia's Great Victoria Desert. It has taken 88 years for her birth to be officially recognised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62e588a6410a278cd6b6455bf3e6e671</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025 updates: Steve Smith and Jofra Archer in fiery clash as Australia wins second Test against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/ashes-live-gabba-test-day-four-australia-vs-england/106111832</link><description>Australian captain Steve Smith lets his bat do the talking following a fiery exchange with Jofra Archer in an eight-wicket win in the second Test in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f1b74fe8e3fff6ef045a8fd32663c93</guid></item><item><title>The $108 billion Warner Bros and Netflix deal has sparked backlash — here's why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/what-the-netflix-warner-bros-merger-means-amid-controversy/106111948</link><description>A major deal between Netflix and Warner Bros has sent shock waves through Hollywood and sparked backlash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c5b49941b708628215a93a2b57a70ed</guid></item><item><title>Ashton Hurn to run for SA Liberal leadership following Tarzia departure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/frank-pangallo-on-leadership-as-liberal-mps-back-ashton-hurn/106110202</link><description>South Australian Liberal frontbencher Ashton Hurn will run for her party's leadership, following the shock resignation of Vincent Tarzia just months out from the next state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf9963dcfec459a7ef2f9625a2955b3d</guid></item><item><title>Unpause and rewind: Cassette tapes are making a comeback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/cassette-tapes-are-making-a-comeback/106102136</link><description>For a supposedly obsolete music format, audio cassette sales seem to be set on fast forward at the moment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44b393e1bbc4bba401dd313c21117f0c</guid></item><item><title>South Australian distillers tap into trending thirst for limoncello</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/limoncello-tradition-trend-alcohol-south-australia/106077938</link><description>South Australian distillers are tapping into a growing global thirst for limoncello and finding a new market for lemons and grape spirit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eac2197d4c58b3bca193cfa97b9fc4c2</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania Fire Service confirms 19 homes destroyed and nearly 200 assets damaged in Dolphin Sands bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/dolphin-sands-residents-weigh-up-bushfire-risk/106111658</link><description>The Tasmania Fire Service confirms 19 homes have been claimed by a bushfire that ripped through Dolphin Sands this week, while nearly 200 assets have been damaged.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26ee56f15a04beadc995bbad8e91369f</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Sixers sneak home in final-ball thriller against Adelaide Strikers to secure WBBL finals spot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/wbbl-match-report-sixers-win-thriller/106112112</link><description>Ellyse Perry produced one of the best knocks of her career but the Sydney Sixers took until the final ball to see off the Adelaide Strikers and land a WBBL finals spot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4aaecf23893063e5ba947a2651efde38</guid></item><item><title>Albanese defends Anika Wells' weekend in Thredbo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/albanese-defends-anika-wells-weekend-in-thredbo-/106112252</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8727180d3e520acd8cf54da37f35175e</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters attend to smouldering homes in Koolewong, NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/firefighters-attend-to-smouldering-homes-in-koolewong-nsw/106112296</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4757ac3a3698c678aef8d64be2412a3c</guid></item><item><title>Record number of temporary residents in Australia - 7 December 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/record-number-of-temporary-residents-in-australia-/106112346</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c904f5b96f0f4a168bcaa5271462f0da</guid></item><item><title>Man smashes ambulance windscreen with head in Kalgoorlie-Boulder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/amulance-windscreen-smashed-by-community-member/106112330</link><description>A video circulated on social media shows a naked male using his head to smash the windscreen of a moving ambulance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33a142b37be9a826fb48feaf00b73ca2</guid></item><item><title>Japan and Australia urge calm after Chinese radar locks onto Japanese jets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/australia-and-japan-urge-calm-after-chinese-radar-locks-jets/106112526</link><description>Japan formally protests the incident, calling it "an extremely regrettable" and dangerous act that "exceeded the scope necessary for safe aircraft operations".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27d322c26523ac3fb38305e86556e60e</guid></item><item><title>Smith fires up, Bazball leaves the building and a miraculous grab — quick hits from day four of the Gabba Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/ashes-day-four-quick-hits-smith-archer-stokes/106112152</link><description>Smith "champs" Archer, Bazball leaves the building and the Australian captain breaks the game open with a miraculous grab. Here are the quick hits from the fourth and final day of the Gabba Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6ba650280f3a6ceb3b2e2da4950a896</guid></item><item><title>F1 Abu Dhabi: Lando Norris wins world title, Max Verstappen wins Abu Dhabi Grand Prix, Oscar Piastri second</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/f1-live-abu-dhabi-grand-prix-oscar-piastri-lando-norris-max/105995116</link><description>Max Verstappen has won the Abu Dhabi Grand Prix ahead of Oscar Piastri, but Lando Norris finishes third to claim the world title.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fd6f8c94f3d969c2ad20a822600258a</guid></item><item><title>Ben Stokes questions England's ability to handle Ashes pressure as Brendon McCullum warns of 'glass jaw'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/ben-stokes-brendon-mccullum-ashes-pressure-reaction/106110490</link><description>England's famed captain-coach duo aren't going to let their relationship fray in the face of the biggest test of their polarising tenure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c67b486eeeb03575c3b909dbdb4b94e</guid></item><item><title>Is it ever OK to leave a party or social event without saying goodbye?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/is-it-ever-ok-to-leave-party-social-event-without-saying-goodbye/106102146</link><description>We asked two experts for their advice on the etiquette of leaving a social gathering without notice and the best approaches to take if you do need to depart suddenly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f883ec7fc9efd90b556602eaec850898</guid></item><item><title>Australia and Steve Smith chase total Ashes domination as England pokes the bear in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/australia-is-out-for-ashes-domination-england-poked-the-bear/106112388</link><description>The snarl on Steve Smith's face proves conclusively that Australia doesn't just want to beat the English in this Ashes series. It wants to break them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8aad39a86986584da1d955db5d9d571f</guid></item><item><title>Australian MLM influencers are cashing in on the manosphere</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/multi-level-marketing-giant-enagic-accused-of-preadatory-tactics/105065260</link><description>A global multi-level-marketing business that sells expensive water ionisers is shifting its target audience to Aussie tradies, but critics say some of their predatory sales tactics are tantamount to a pyramid scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0e9050f1adfb8f45aafbb3485f5d0a3</guid></item><item><title>Have you been involved in a multi-level marketing business? Tell us your MLM story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/audience-callout-mlm-schemes-multi-level-marketing/106100604</link><description>Multi-level marketing networks have been around for decades. But their business models are changing, with consumer advocates warning that the industry is rife with predatory tactics. We want to hear about your experiences with MLMs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f2ac4367142e66fc108bd2b5bac5d47</guid></item><item><title>Devastated families grapple with ferocity of NSW Central Coast bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/nsw-central-coast-families-devasted-by-fierce-koolewong-bushfire/106111938</link><description>Residents on the NSW coast are coming to terms with property loss after bushfires swept through the region on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65624e96ff54c17f0c863108c3ebae98</guid></item><item><title>How Europe is gearing up to follow Australia's teen social media ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/how-europe-may-follow-australias-teen-social-media-ban/106035946</link><description>The European Union says it will learn from Australia's new laws to bar under-16s from social media, with steps to implement the world-first ban already underway and European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen praising Australia's "brave move".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55c8ac89d0b35b01d09cc1e297835546</guid></item><item><title>Communities harness the people power of co-ops to stave off privatisation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/castlemaine-cooperative-privatisation-economic-democracy/106103270</link><description>For its passionate members, saving a historic goldrush-era pub to protect their cooperative was about "economic democracy" and keeping the property out of developers' hands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ef75db79dadf3fd81685d34b6c2fb6e</guid></item><item><title>First-home buyers on government's MyHome scheme struggling to get sellers on board</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/buyers-purchasing-property-with-myhome-shared-equity-scheme/106009682</link><description>When Regan buys his first home, the government will own around 30 per cent of it. But he is fast realising that for that to even happen, a lot of things have to fall into place.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5feedf17c76acc7f38f85f248f101af4</guid></item><item><title>Russia increases recruitment of foreign fighters through targeted social media campaigns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/russia-recruitment-of-foreign-fighters-increases/106096108</link><description>Through a targeted social media campaign, Russia is offering citizenship and money to foreigners who join its fight in Ukraine, but experts say it is a desperate measure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4ee2dd53a43ee1b9f3a58ae1ab06442</guid></item><item><title>China's global technology and engineering ascendancy continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/china-us-technology-engineering-ai-plan-australia/106111696</link><description>China used to be trying to catch the West, specifically the US. Then it caught up. Now the West is trying to catch up to China, but likely can't.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73f515ced6456e40883658e372daaa99</guid></item><item><title>Exploitation fears over SA government aged care changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/elder-exploitation-fears-over-sa-aged-care-law-changes/106105940</link><description>The South Australian government is trying to speed up the transfer of hospital patients into aged care, but advocates say they are "trampling on the rights of older people" in the process.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40c41c3a15163c4ca5aec5bf5a984ef2</guid></item><item><title>Anika Wells's taxpayer-funded Thredbo ski trip a costly distraction for Labor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/anika-wells-travel-expenses-scandal-albanese-labor/106112088</link><description>What was meant to be a Sunday interview bookending a remarkable political year became an exercise in explaining the inexplicable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b8486cb5a97efe3b165f4060c2c7fa4</guid></item><item><title>Crops preferred to sheep in large parts of Australia's traditional mixed farming regions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/crops-preferred-to-sheep-in-traditional-mixed-farming-regions/106035940</link><description>Mixed farming, which involves growing crops and rearing livestock, used to be standard practice in Australia, but there are almost 100 million fewer sheep in Australia than there were 35 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3a750e588866118fa491cdd0f9f1d85</guid></item><item><title>Muster Dogs favourite Frank Finger makes final on-screen appearance with kelpie Annie in portrait show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/muster-dogs-frank-finger-annie-portrait-artist-of-the-year-tv/106073124</link><description>From hit series Muster Dogs to a new television show, Frank Finger and his beloved kelpie Annie's unbreakable bond steals the spotlight once again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa07300da9bf7b69d2501baa6ae26b21</guid></item><item><title>Damaged buildings in Darayya, Syria, one year after the civil war ended</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/damaged-buildings-in-darayya-syria/106111984</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d915d7b83a58750e84ce12785c8462f</guid></item><item><title>A year after the fall of Bashar Al-Assad, Syrians are scraping by</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/a-year-since-liberation-syrians-cautiously-celebrate-scrape-by/106112708</link><description>Today marks one year since the Assad dictatorship in Syria was toppled by Islamist rebels, bringing an end to nearly 14 years of civil war. Some are celebrating, while others continue to struggle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de06d898a7b2c881a7fbd7c1f302fb27</guid></item><item><title>Health regulator accused of failing to support patients amid complaints over doctors' conduct</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/ahpra-complaint-inappropriate-doctor-examination-queensland/106097566</link><description>Two women have told the ABC they believe the health regulator is failing to acknowledge the power imbalance between doctors and patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56c6fc8e1d4c1e7a8f7cb8a03ff94c4a</guid></item><item><title>Where Oscar Piastri lost the Formula 1 world championship, McLaren teammate Lando Norris claims ultimate prize</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/oscar-piastri-missed-f1-world-title-through-minor-moments/106113184</link><description>Oscar Piastri missed out on winning the Formula 1 drivers world championship by just 13 points to his teammate Lando Norris, the culmination of multiple small moments throughout the season that cost him dearly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb082e3701f1fe8b29d4db1328f26f4e</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri praised as future formula 1 world champion by rivals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/oscar-piastri-praised-as-future-formula-1-world-champion/106113274</link><description>Oscar Piastri's chief rival, new formula 1 world champion Lando Norris, says the Australian will "get the better of me" after their tension-filled title race decider in Abu Dhabi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bdac8d42b6f4d2a864e6f566e20a472</guid></item><item><title>The US fired on survivors clinging to a 'drug boat' — who gave the order?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/pete-hegseth-venezuela-boat-strike/106101966</link><description>What happened in the lead-up to a second strike on a speedboat in the Caribbean — who knew what and when, and who gave what order — is now under scrutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e0a0ab2661d3088030ebb72d729a0eb</guid></item><item><title>ASX slips ahead of RBA decision, miners sold off, National Storage agrees to $4 billion takeover — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-dec-8/106112736</link><description>The ASX has failed to follow Wall Street's positive lead, slipping 0.1 per cent ahead of tomorrow's RBA rates decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ba8c2f3f9865e4dcd530e7651d27a6e</guid></item><item><title>Murray-Darling Basin predicted to be hotter and drier by 2050 if nothing changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/murray-darling-basin-outlook-predicts-hotter-drier-by-2050/106091334</link><description>Water needs for river communities will be under increasing pressure over the next 25 years, according to predictions from the Murray-Darling Basin Authority.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ed309817c90e9e5c1a0070f6fa21fd3</guid></item><item><title>59yo NPWS firefighter killed by falling tree during bushfire prevention work at Nerong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/npws-firefighter-killed-by-falling-tree/106113538</link><description>A National Parks and Wildlife Service firefighter dies after being crushed by a tree during bushfire prevention work north of Newcastle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">561ad6d42df6b53a4d5d78d2893973dc</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Barnaby Joyce joins One Nation weeks after leaving Nationals — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/cph-pols-blog-dec-8/106113524</link><description>Former deputy prime minister Barnaby Joyce has joined One Nation after leaving the Nationals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0dda282736f165176cca4c3002e5f13</guid></item><item><title>Rory McIlroy did not win Australian Open but still completed one of his missions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/rory-mcilroy-restores-australian-open-prestige/106112750</link><description>Rory McIlroy's appearance at the Australian Open in Melbourne has gone a long way to restoring the prestige of the tournament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08480b9f91bf40b93667e71c6b206a6c</guid></item><item><title>New NT training program aims to attract and keep home tutors at remote stations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/training-program-aims-to-attract-and-keep-home-tutors/106096712</link><description>A course offered for the first time this year has upskilled home tutors working on remote central Australian cattle stations in a bid to ease education workforce shortages in the outback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0477d8345ddb6d66f02fe540b09a33f7</guid></item><item><title>WA economic regulator accuses power generators of overcharging utilities for wholesale electricity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/wa-power-producers-accused-overcharging-wholesale-electricity/106109294</link><description>The cost of electricity is being driven up by some Western Australian power producers breaking the rules and charging more than they're allowed, the state's economic watchdog alleges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">860ad6b80841060e4f6090269832620d</guid></item><item><title>Hitchhiking Pilbara mechanic Kevin Guiness recounts a lifetime on the road</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/hitchhiking-pilbara-mechanic-recounts-life-on-the-road/105845782</link><description>At 12 years old, Kevin Guiness was rebuilding engines on an outback cattle station. Now, after decades travelling the dusty roads in the Pilbara, the Yindjibarndi elder reflects on what kept him going.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63597aedacce7b26b6bd91fdc2853622</guid></item><item><title>How the internet reacted to Australia winning the second Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/how-the-internet-reacted-to-the-second-ashes-test/106102100</link><description>Mitchell Starc was the hero, again, as the English were comprehensively outplayed in Brisbane — but how did the internet react?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54a7ad441f6e075cb25a030091f327da</guid></item><item><title>Brendon McCullum says England 'over-prepared' ahead of Brisbane Test, as players head to Noosa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/ashes-2025-brendon-mccullum-says-england-trained-too-hard/106113606</link><description>England coach Brendon McCullum claims his team trained too hard for the Gabba Test, which ended in a bruising eight-wicket loss that leaves the tourists' Ashes hopes in tatters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a036f962842a5cadbc8e4bdc053a51b</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump Jr says there is little appetite for the US to fund the Ukrainian war effort.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/trump-jr-flags-no-us-appetite-to-fund-ukrainian-war-effort/106113346</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c1b9bd080807c45df3eefbfe55ebe87</guid></item><item><title>Kremlin praises Donald Trump's national security strategy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/russia-welcomes-donald-trumps-national-security-strategy/106113490</link><description>The strategy argues the US should revive the 19th century Monroe Doctrine, which declared the Western hemisphere to be Washington's zone of influence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">335c9f75f5b6876f832a8beac9835170</guid></item><item><title>'Everything destroyed' as Indonesia's Aceh grapples with disease after floods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/indonesia-aceh-grapples-with-disease-after-floods/106113542</link><description>Hit by deadly floods, Indonesians in the region around Aceh Tamiang are grappling with worsening diseases and a lack of medical care at the lone hospital in the area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3474ba744c45bf27f842c7d2d152ad4c</guid></item><item><title>City of Rockingham residents complain of maggots and flies after FOGO introduction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/perth-garbage-bins-leave-residents-unhappy/106112238</link><description>Perth residents say they are dealing with an "infestation of maggots" and stinking rubbish after the introduction of a third bin for food and garden waste. But the local council is adamant it will not be making any changes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">942d178ff66f8fa6776a5dfe4df5cdaf</guid></item><item><title>Jessica Stenson breaks Australian women's marathon record during Valencia race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/jessica-stenson-breaks-australian-womens-marathon-record/106113722</link><description>Jessica Stenson breaks the Australian marathon record before an emotional phone call to the former record holder, Sinead Diver.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a5a9164a7e8010a9906a27913e4be33</guid></item><item><title>How would your feed look if you got to control what you saw on social media?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/chanel-contos-teach-us-consent-fix-our-feed/106107546</link><description>Sexual violence prevention group Teach Us Consent is pushing for Australians to have the choice to "opt-in" to social media algorithms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5f4437d61b6c09b76d3d735425df36e</guid></item><item><title>Benin President Patrice Talon says coup attempt thwarted with help from Nigerian military</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/benin-coup-attempt-thwarted/106114130</link><description>Patrice Talon says the West African nation's government will punish those responsible for a coup attempt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ea8421ac418ad9f8ca71e83b162b1df</guid></item><item><title>Cleveland Dodd's care in Unit 18 'inhumane', coroner examining youth detention death finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/cleveland-dodds-care-in-youth-detention-inhumane-coroner-finds/106112004</link><description>Western Australia's first recorded death in youth detention was predictable, a coroner finds, declaring the care of 16-year-old Cleveland Dodd was "inhumane" and "reminiscent of 19th century jails". WARNING: This story contains the name and image of an Indigenous person who has died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6ae9813e2e602a349029e2320971ce1</guid></item><item><title>Water leak at the Louvre museum damages hundreds of works</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/hunderds-of-works-damaged-in-water-leak-at-louvre-museum/106114116</link><description>The leak occurred after a valve was accidentally opened in a heating and ventilation system, allowing water to seep through the ceiling of the Mollien wing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcd11071a8244d998a994b13c1876405</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce joins One Nation, concluding defection from Nationals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/barnaby-joyce-joins-one-nation/106114758</link><description>Barnaby Joyce's defection gives One Nation its first lower house seat since 1998.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">278b33937863e280a5410062430ada30</guid></item><item><title>England's lack of Ashes depth highlighted as Australia A thumps Lions at Allan Border Field</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/australia-a-thumps-england-lions-to-highlight-ashes-problem/106114756</link><description>England's lack of Test depth is highlighted as Australia A beats the Lions by an innings and 127 runs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cb0896b3276dafa3d9d5ad9a03b7b6e</guid></item><item><title>Government will not extend energy bill relief</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/government-will-not-extend-energy-bill-relief/106114842</link><description>Jim Chalmers says the end to the "temporary" subsidy was a "hard" decision but recognises pressures on the budget.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55398d2d5d6a262e7d4a8cd38ce0ebd8</guid></item><item><title>Thailand launches air strikes amid new border clashes with Cambodia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/thailand-launches-air-strikes-on-cambodia-border-clashes/106114878</link><description>Thailand launches air strikes along its disputed border with Cambodia, after both countries accuse one another of breaching a ceasefire agreement brokered by US President Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fff6be86fabeb871f89a1632dbbb598f</guid></item><item><title>One of PNG's rare conjoined twins dies after urgent surgery in Sydney, brother survives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/png-conjoined-twins-tom-sawong-surgery-sydney/106113822</link><description>Surgeons have separated a rare set of conjoined twins after they were urgently flown from Papua New Guinea to Australia, but only one of the boys has survived.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a079440a2938e807240cbf33338baccc</guid></item><item><title>Coalition puts heat on Wells over trips to cricket and AFL with family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/coalition-anika-wells-cricket-expenses-travel/106113546</link><description>The Coalition is applying more heat to Sport Minister Anika Wells over flights she claimed for herself and her husband to attend two Boxing Day cricket test matches in recent years, and several AFL Grand Final events.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4275bb62ee4e0bc79aac67e67b200901</guid></item><item><title>Dolphin Sands resident 'frustrated' by official communication after bushfire destroys homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/tasmania-dolphin-sands-bushfire-community-dismayed/106113646</link><description>More questions have been raised about the official warnings ahead of a bushfire that destroyed 19 homes in a tiny Tasmanian seaside community where there is one road in and out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be856664e93eb4ff4b5a4acac5ddecad</guid></item><item><title>Lithium-ion battery suspected to have sparked Caroline Springs house fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/lithium-ion-battery-house-fire-caroline-springs-warning/106114446</link><description>Fire services are urging people to buy lithium-ion battery products from reputable suppliers ahead of Christmas after yet another house fire was suspected to have been caused by a lithium battery on the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">800cb01f4ed7114abcce14e86bc10fa4</guid></item><item><title>Toddler's septic tank death 'likely would have been prevented' with sufficient NT government maintenance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/nt-septic-tank-death-toddler-remote-community-coroners-report/106114688</link><description>A coroner's report has found there were multiple missed opportunities to improve or replace the public housing septic system, which the NT government had responsibility for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98d947177f624dd68d704b5339256202</guid></item><item><title>Australian Ashes openers Travis Head and Jake Weatherald praised as Usman Khawaja call looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/ashes-test-series-travis-head-jake-weatherald-usman-khawaja/106116580</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne says Australia's opening partnership is making the rest of the batting order improve, as selectors deliberate over Usman Khawaja's Test future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd19c84e600636615e42a245d0785fe1</guid></item><item><title>Should you go screen-free after giving birth? These mums share their stories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/mums-mental-health-online-postpartum/106086872</link><description>Readers share how they approached their online and social media use in the weeks immediately after giving birth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42d427354161a31e013bc51ecf3cbd12</guid></item><item><title>Trump hosts Kennedy Center Honors in historic first</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/trump-makes-history-hosting-the-kennedy-center-honors/106115478</link><description>Donald Trump has made the Kennedy Center a touchstone in a broader attack against what he claims is "woke", anti-American culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1c346ecf0726a7d78fd03b0d4f5725b</guid></item><item><title>Rajwinder Singh found guilty of Toyah Cordingley's 2018 murder on Far North Queensland beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/rajwinder-singh-guilty-toyah-cordingley-murder/106102518</link><description>It took a jury in the Supreme Court in Cairns seven hours to reach the unanimous guilty verdict after an almost four-week retrial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86c525c4287096b2882fd5a6e52a2d18</guid></item><item><title>More than 30 zinc sunscreen brands using formula that failed preliminary SPF testing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/zinc-sunscreen-brands-spf-testing-lower-than-advertising/106050396</link><description>It's been almost two years since Craig Jones first ran preliminary tests on his zinc sunscreen. When he discovered it wasn't providing the SPF it was supposed to he threw it out and set out on a quest to find out why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4753ebb9b4860304072af5ef3e08466</guid></item><item><title>NRL proposes lengthy bans for Tonga officials following Eli Katoa head knocks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/nrl-tonga-officials-face-bans-over-eli-katoa-incident/106116872</link><description>Three Tonga team officials are facing two-year suspensions following the NRL's investigation into the incident that forced Eli Katoa out of the 2026 season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27f95fe22540f5745ec85088c7fcfb22</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106116270</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea3bba99a227f19b6ea86a8bd7bd1346</guid></item><item><title>City of Moreton Bay fronts Supreme Court after demolishing homeless camps</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/moreton-bay-council-faces-court-over-homeless-camp-destruction/106114178</link><description>The City of Moreton Bay council violated the human rights of homeless campers when they destroyed their tents and belongings in April, the Supreme Court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89e795fd15cfcaf47bbd19843497be14</guid></item><item><title>Perth boy's death in Department of Communities care may have been accidental, inquest told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/inquest-examines-death-of-10-year-old-boy-in-state-care/106112324</link><description>An inquest hears the 2024 death of a 10-year-old Indigenous boy while he was under the care of the Department of Communities may have been an accident, not suicide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83ca7dea763d310cb801eb99d903a67c</guid></item><item><title>Clermont's only GP clinic closes after hospital doctor suspended</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/clermont-hospital-doctor-tim-lane-suspended-after-dispute/106113774</link><description>The suspension of Tim Lane leaves a Central Queensland town of 3,000 people with no permanent hospital doctor or GP.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d72146816b82719750eec96cfb2ce126</guid></item><item><title>Thailand-Cambodia border conflict reignites.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/thailand-cambodia-border-conflict-reignites/106117524</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71ed64bea61eb140d343da497cb72d80</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce likens One Nation to Reform UK party under Nigel Farage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/barnaby-joyce-joins-pauline-hanson-in-one-nation/106116240</link><description>In his first interview since formally joining One Nation, Barnaby Joyce says he sees comparisons between his new party and Britain's far-right Reform UK party under populist leader Nigel Farage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec46698bc1eba717753f4b4770c24910</guid></item><item><title>Renters need $300,000 more superannuation in retirement than home owners, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/renters-need-twice-more-super-than-home-owners-in-retirement/106104784</link><description>Rising rents mean older Australians who are not home owners will need twice as much superannuation to enjoy the same retirement lifestyle as those who are mortgage-free, according to a study by a leading advocacy group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f0e8be479137557c82638664cac88ce</guid></item><item><title>Magnitude-7.6 earthquake in Japan prompts tsunami warning and evacuation order for 90,000 people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/japan-earthquake-prompts-tsunami-warning/106117964</link><description>The quake has seen a tsunami warning issued for large parts of Japan's northern coastline and about 90,000 people ordered to evacuate to higher ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bb4b46720be5433eaa15872180e00ad</guid></item><item><title>Jacob Elordi, Rose Byrne and Joel Edgerton score Golden Globes nominations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/golden-globe-nominations-2025/106117782</link><description>Jacob Elordi is Australia's big hope at the Golden Globes after scoring two nominations overnight for the 83rd iteration of the film and television awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aebf576e95042edfa57508a1e792b2c0</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 9: How smallpox was eradicated after it killled 300 million people in the 20th century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/smallpox-eradication-infectious-disease-ring-vaccination/105999388</link><description>The eradication of smallpox 46 years ago has been cheered as the greatest triumph of global public health. It has also been held up as a model for global cooperation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd95131d8068f6201274ad73e3783a82</guid></item><item><title>Australia's favourite political test depends on who is at the pub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/barnaby-joyce-annabel-crabb-expenses-one-nation-defection/106114804</link><description>The "pub test" tends to be applied when we've run out of avenues to pursue a public figure, but are still super annoyed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bb613641045e771ebed97e24f6e6ad9</guid></item><item><title>For some teenagers, 'life is better' without social media and they support the ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/teenagers-who-support-social-media-ban/106095948</link><description>Patrick, 15, does not use social media and hopes he never does. Nick, 15, had a flip phone for the first few years of high school. Here is why they support the social media ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11cd0cfc0070dd985225db4602176ddc</guid></item><item><title>Fluke discoveries of asbestos in children's sand strike twice decades apart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/fluke-discoveries-asbestos-children-play-sand-decades-apart/106056760</link><description>A doctor in the US who found asbestos in his son's sandpit tried in vain to get stronger regulations. Almost 40 years later he says he's "not surprised" the problem re-emerged in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">073011ed164029fa273c9d40b51498b2</guid></item><item><title>Logical ACTU gas exports policy could put the economy back on an even keel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/time-to-fix-gas-policy-to-ease-inflation-cost-of-living-pressure/106116030</link><description>For a decade, a disaster has unfolded. We've run short of gas through indecision and incompetence, and that's driving energy costs and inflation. We need a solution and an unlikely source may have one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">474f58cf1e220611fdd153145a49d0a9</guid></item><item><title>Domestic violence survivors using strength training for trauma recovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/west-project-domestic-violence-survivors-strength-training/106046732</link><description>In a suburban Canberra gym, no questions are asked. If you identify as a domestic violence survivor, you're in. The WEST Project is an innovative program helping women build themselves back up through powerlifting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19150622edf2f22115c32dd67228de96</guid></item><item><title>Wells spends thousands on Comcars to attend grand finals, but has plenty of company</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/wells-spends-thousands-on-comcars-for-grand-finals/106117742</link><description>The sports minister has endured scrutiny over her use of parliamentary expenses, but is one of dozens of MPs to have accumulated large Comcar bills.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">539e905664a43e0090610d9a8afe2e80</guid></item><item><title>Halfbrick Studios CEO Shainiel Deo on creating the first Bluey video game made in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/bluey-video-game-halfbrick-studios-brisbane/106113906</link><description>Halfbrick Studios, the company behind Fruit Ninja, has created the first ever Bluey video game made in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1957f4f6e0250e77e45f7285388a026</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy meets with European allies as Donald Trump accuses him of not reading US-led peace plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/zelenskyy-european-allies-downing-street-trump/106117756</link><description>Leaders express scepticism about US-led plans to end Russia's invasion, after peace talks between US and Ukranian officials at the weekend ended without a breakthrough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a788d9da4a6464c4aa1a3f92e35c20a</guid></item><item><title>Moment magnitude-7.6 earthquake strikes near Japan’s coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/moment-magnitude-7-6-earthquake-strikes-near-japan-s-coast/106118186</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6c3f48e38de8a8b929215f4f8541fbf</guid></item><item><title>Penny Wong and Richard Marles meet US counterparts in Washington after AUKUS review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/marles-wong-hegseth-rubio-hold-ausmin-talks-aukus-defence/106118088</link><description>Australia and the US will "expand" and "strengthen" the AUKUS security and submarine deal in coming months, top Trump administration officials say ahead of talks with their Australian counterparts in Washington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2ad9c9f6e38d4d71c90442aa95f7e80</guid></item><item><title>Wentworth Park greyhound track to be bulldozed making way for parkland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/wentworth-park-greyhound-track-to-go-making-way-parkland/106116584</link><description>After more than 90 years, greyhound racing will end at Wentworth Park in Glebe, with the public land to be be transferred to the City of Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da689c777d8d30c62c62836a477e384b</guid></item><item><title>From a Barossa 'baronial' background, Ashton Hurn has risen to the SA Liberal leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/ashton-hurn-explainer-following-liberal-leadership/106111804</link><description>South Australia's new opposition leader Ashton Hurn has likened the task ahead of her to climbing a mountain, but she's taking inspiration from a family background that includes a former state cricketer and an AFL premiership captain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa54cf54be49af6d3ed9ac168f41e2f2</guid></item><item><title>Victorian government to make historic apology to Aboriginal Victorians following signing of treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/government-apology-to-aboriginal-victorians-after-treaty/106116798</link><description>The Victorian government is set to make a historic apology to Aboriginal Victorians today, in one of the first public acts to follow the signing of the state's treaty agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c287b141c7986bd0cde18ca5ae9b903f</guid></item><item><title>Paramount counters Netflix with hostile bid for Warner Bros Discovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/parmount-hostile-bid-warner-bros/106118082</link><description>The offer paves the way for a battle between Paramount — whose owner, Larry Ellison, is an ally of Donald Trump — and streaming behemoth Netflix to buy one of Hollywood's most storied studios.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93ef9510034b731dd3999f07c1d34868</guid></item><item><title>Bulahdelah farmers count the cost after devastating bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/bulahdelah-farmers-count-the-cost-after-devastating-bushfire/106114632</link><description>Farmers and businesses on the Mid North Coast are reeling after a fire tore through the region, destroying homes and forcing families to evacuate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">468939875f6419fddbed642b64f925c5</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane City Council announces crackdown on short-stay accommodation in residential areas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/brisbane-council-short-stay-accommodation-crackdown-airbnb/106117338</link><description>Hundreds of properties in low and low-to-medium residential-zoned areas of Brisbane will have to seek development approval or be banned from acting as short-stay accommodation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63527c358de066bf43ebbacbc0f7730a</guid></item><item><title>Federal government deal sending non-citizens to Nauru faces critical High Court challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/high-court-interim-arrangement-non-citizens-send-nauru-challenge/106116480</link><description>An Iranian man facing removal to Nauru under a controversial agreement will ask the High Court to find the government's plans to deport him lack procedural fairness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e81f90955562a06f8615179633142390</guid></item><item><title>Some Israeli-backed anti-Hamas gang members surrender to group</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/some-israeli-backed-anti-hamas-gang-members-surrender-to-group/106117908</link><description>A handful of members of an Israeli-backed anti-Hamas gang in Gaza have surrendered to the militant group, days after their leader was killed in the strip.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edbd622b9355b843303b4233556f08a7</guid></item><item><title>AUKUS project ‘full steam ahead’, US top diplomat says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/aukus-project-full-steam-ahead-us-top-diplomat-says/106118264</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0155a4f0bdc8724995086a7da122b98b</guid></item><item><title>Mitch Marsh to retire from Sheffield Shield but leaves door open for Test recall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/mitch-marsh-announces-retirement-from-sheffield-shield-cricket/106118274</link><description>Mitch Marsh tells his Western Australia teammates he is retiring, but keeps the door ajar for a Test recall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7aeffa9d95cb18c8b91fc44297d744e8</guid></item><item><title>RBA live updates: RBA tipped to keep rates on hold as market awaits clues to next move</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/asx-markets-business-live-news-rba-9-dec/106117048</link><description>The cash rate is expected to be left steady at 3.6 per cent as the central bank board wraps up its final meeting of 2025. Follow the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00fc7f6cac2262937ab97fb252298a06</guid></item><item><title>Families left in the lurch after Zone RV caravan manufacturer collapse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/zone-rv-customers-in-limbo-after-collapse/106098684</link><description>The sensational shutdown of the luxury caravan manufacturer has had a gut-wrenching impact on families from Australia and abroad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f30fe67994eba4db444803d85e6c20e</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: AUKUS is 'full steam ahead', Richard Marles says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/federal-poltics-live-blog-dec-9/106115678</link><description>Defence Minister Richard Marles says AUKUS is "full steam ahead" following a meeting with his US counterpart in Washington. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d4831f888454f5f69cc1a8e0c33484e</guid></item><item><title>Uniting Church welcomes re-opening of Lindisfarne place of worship as a mosque</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/former-hobart-uniting-church-converted-into-mosque/106035642</link><description>A Tasmanian couple has bought a former Uniting Church on Hobart's eastern shore and plan to use it for Islamic education, Arabic classes and interfaith dialogue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57ed9c4cd66b6a8a18d660c7449d45b3</guid></item><item><title>Farmers and innovators say there is potential in Australia's untapped biofuel sector</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/australia-biofuel-sector-has-untapped-potential-say-farmers/105802948</link><description>Fuels produced from waste and agricultural feedstock are tipped to play a role in cutting emissions, but a leading Victorian farmer says political will is required to seize the opportunity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3de76cd91935af910eb720c85fa0a201</guid></item><item><title>Farmsafe Australia issues warning after two serious hay bale incidents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/farmsafe-australia-warning-after-hay-bale-incidents/106115168</link><description>A woman has died and a man has been hospitalised in two separate incidents involving falling hay bales in southern Queensland. Farm safety advocates are calling for increased caution while manoeuvring hay bales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f235659ff20a96eb4a19df846d06f8d6</guid></item></channel></rss>