<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 08:49:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Gout Gout makes his senior debut at the World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/gout-gout-makes-his-senior-debut/105786306</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a6f67c414742d7e07f12c1c5287ed55</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout finishes third in 200m heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/gout-gout-finishes-third-in-200m-heat/105786314</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d8312214b2b9a31a74786f0c79c4763</guid></item><item><title>Northern WA communities already adapting to extreme climate future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/northern-wa-communities-react-to-dire-climate-change-predictions/105774370</link><description>Locals in small northern WA communities say the potential dangers identified by the Climate Risk Assessment are already starting to appear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">185143eda8f80ebbaf513dfccf0aa6c3</guid></item><item><title>Gaming history goes on display with Australian titles Hollow Knight Silksong and Team Fortress chronicled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/acmi-game-worlds-hollow-knight-silksong-neopets-team-fortress/105754152</link><description>An exhibition at Melbourne's ACMI will pull back the curtain on how iconic games like Hollow Knight Silksong, Team Fortress, Neopets and Sim City were made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fccda39e18804bf9590546dadaed39f</guid></item><item><title>How youth orchestras foster lifelong friendships and open career pathways for musicians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/youth-orchestra-lifelong-friendships-career-pathways-musicians/105775992</link><description>With youth orchestras set to busk on the streets of Sydney and Melbourne this weekend, Australian musicians share how those orchestras helped shape their careers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39cc489e47ad597a9a2e2610c3bf0e4a</guid></item><item><title>Cairns maternity ward named as exposure site in Far North Queensland measles outbreak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/four-new-cases-confirmed-in-cairns-measles-outbreak/105786794</link><description>More locally acquired cases have been confirmed with exposure sites now including Cairns Hospital's maternity ward and areas on the Atherton Tablelands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82362ca4ac1144d4e4b78657ca9250d4</guid></item><item><title>Gardeners share the joys of turning dust to daisies in the Australian outback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/gardeners-share-the-joys-of-growing-flowers-in-the-outback/105761510</link><description>Flower farmer Suzanne Stanton says generations of outback women have taken comfort in their gardens, proof that life can survive in the harshest of climates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">983de27f94440a9ba1f44837800269ac</guid></item><item><title>Palliative Care Australia art prize inspires conversations about death and grieving</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/palliative-care-australia-art-prize-helps-process-grief/105763880</link><description>In its fifth year, Palliative Care Australia's Live Well, Die Well national art prize continues to spark important conversations about dying.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11b336b74532eacba654f9700b7c36e0</guid></item><item><title>Authorities urge parents to check Little Ones Nappy Pants for khapra beetle larvae</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nappy-pants-still-unaccounted-for-khapra-beetle-larvae-found/105787812</link><description>Hundreds of cartons of nappy pants remain unaccounted for after one of the biggest threats to Australia's grain industry, khapra beetle larvae, was found in the imported products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45cfd2bf95d89861ab6dc3f7a688868c</guid></item><item><title>Qantas to review staff bases in Mildura, Canberra and Hobart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/qantas-to-review-staff-bases-in-mildura-canberra-and-hobart/105787036</link><description>There are concerns the decision could impact regional flights, as staff would have to travel from Sydney, Melbourne or Brisbane to get to work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b12683d82bbcee89c77a3511592fb58</guid></item><item><title>Family of Aboriginal man killed in Darwin hit-and-run speak out over driver's sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/family-of-man-killed-in-darwin-hit-and-run-speak-out/105787700</link><description>The family of an Aboriginal man killed in a hit-and-run in Darwin have spoken out about the sentence handed to the man who killed him, and the "racist, dehumanising" messages he sent afterwards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc87964fabc0227fe5c48880a62ad60b</guid></item><item><title>Albanese to meet with Trump after returning from Pacific empty-handed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/anthony-albanese-png-coalition-climate/105767026</link><description>This week in politics, the prime minister returned home from the Pacific empty-handed and the climate debate continued to unsettle the Coalition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e48586b5fbd1829a80e680eae1c55719</guid></item><item><title>Albury Wodonga Regional Cancer Centre to become public hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/albury-wodonga-cancer-centre-hospital-ramsay-health-public/105786700</link><description>A major cancer centre on the Victorian-New South Wales border will become a fully public hospital in a move that has caught a healthcare provider by surprise and sparked community concern.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6af03fa22837640d34b69f4c529cc60f</guid></item><item><title>WA coal phase-out uncertainty amid Bluewaters power station closure backflip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/wa-coal-phaseout-uncertain-amid-energy-grid-upgrade-plan/105788864</link><description>Efforts by WA's government to force the premature closure of a privately owned coal plant appear to be unravelling after the market operator backed the power station to keep running towards the end of the decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4f55f2cbe6604ced891de18ea6af73a</guid></item><item><title>Henley residents advised to keep windows, doors closed amid algal bloom crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/sa-beach-residents-algal-bloom-advice/105790474</link><description>Authorities have told a group of residents living near a metropolitan Adelaide beach to close their doors and windows to prevent symptoms related to South Australia's ongoing algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">094835ce530689c0fec54c85ace98853</guid></item><item><title>Surprise La Niña hints at another wet and stormy Australian summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/la-nina-hints-at-wet-stormy-australian-summer/105790134</link><description>Australia's key drivers of weather variability are stacking up to produce another wet, severe-weather season, with an increased risk of flooding, thunderstorms and cyclones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a42ca16638c1124b410a58f0cccc3ecf</guid></item><item><title>Fire at the Jam Factory complex in South Yarra damages Melbourne construction site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/fire-at-the-jam-factory-movie-dining-complex-under-construction/105792298</link><description>Callers to triple-0 report thick smoke billowing from the historical complex in Melbourne's inner south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5145bb865b091f0702cf29ca09b9bd26</guid></item><item><title>Actress Joan Marion never returned to Tasmania, but 'her heart was always in Launceston'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/tasmanian-actress-joan-marion-maintained-links-to-launceston/105774964</link><description>Tasmania's Joan Marion became a star of the screen and stage abroad; her granddaughter says she maintained a connection to Launceston for much of her life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e512ba130678906d9cf74447a7e0d32</guid></item><item><title>Warm currents bring tens of thousands of giant yellowfin tuna to NSW South Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/unprecedented-yellowfin-tuna-season-south-coast/105784426</link><description>Fishers are reporting an unprecedented number of yellowfin tuna travelling from the tropics to the NSW South Coast, causing "mayhem" and excitement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d71fe5d9066c0d4471f7c22b0f966ba4</guid></item><item><title>Wiluna leaders hoping 'bounty' will reduce stray dog numbers in town</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/wiluna-dog-bounty-questions/105595030</link><description>Wiluna, in Western Australia's far northern Goldfields, is looking to revive a cash incentive for community members to surrender domestic dogs for rehoming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d68e67f88048247f2f3f75048b91b24</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos discovery further delays Willyama High School demolition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/demolition-of-mouldy-willyama-high-school-delayed-by-asbestos/105733678</link><description>Nearly two years after a mould-infested high school was closed indefinitely, high-risk friable asbestos has caused further delays to its demolition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a23e41ae074ff173d5db5c3d17aa081</guid></item><item><title>RONA. weaves together country, colonialism and club music on new EP It's All Here</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/rona-its-all-here-ep-bush-beats-country-colonialism-club-music/105758094</link><description>This Kaytetye producer has a fresh take on the space race that draws from First Nations knowledge and culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f63cbfd798f6826103c82f171f571494</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann likely to face four-day hearing in Tasmania over motor vehicle stealing charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/bruce-lehrmann-likely-to-face-four-day-hearing/105794304</link><description>Former Liberal staffer Bruce Lehrmann appears in the Hobart Magistrates Court after pleading not guilty to one count of motor vehicle stealing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">680bec6e2ce2b4d53ae9b27667c53e23</guid></item><item><title>Russell Vale Mine Shaft 4 to trial Green Gravity renewable energy technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/russell-vale-mine-shaft-4-to-trial-green-gravity/105780830</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89d1b1e00372ede47986a5b7fb9f02ce</guid></item><item><title>Green Gravity secures old coal mine shaft to test gravitational energy storage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/green-gravity-deal-old-mine-shaft-gravitational-energy-storage/105782756</link><description>A disused coal mine in Wollongong will be the first test site for a renewable energy company that lowers weights down old mine shafts to spin turbines and create electricity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">624bc063af2f9be2f1ecc1717cd562e3</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins hints at Ashes strategy amid recovery from back injury with 'starting aim' of playing in all five Tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/ashes-pat-cummins-australia-england-back-injury/105794594</link><description>As the men's Ashes approaches, the Australian captain reveals his hopes for taking part in the five-Test series against England as he steps up his injury recovery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cfd72c66626cbf51c7aab8346b10585</guid></item><item><title>Report scathing of police and CCC over failure to respond to complaints of police misconduct</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/police-ccc-complaints-misconduct-report-/105791424</link><description>WA Police and the CCC are put on notice after failing to adequately respond to complaints of serious police misconduct, including an allegation an off-duty officer choked a man following a road rage incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22bf87447571d6b73f5b6fc17bd6283e</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the Optus outage which disrupted triple-zero calls, linked to three deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/what-we-know-about-optus-network-outage/105796618</link><description>It's been two days since three people died after a devastating Optus outage caused hundreds of emergency calls to fail, but information about the incident remains scarce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81d841cfe097dc82a144e78eb4423953</guid></item><item><title>Investigation of eye-maker's online presence reveals multiple red flags</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/jack-mcdonald-ocularist-website-warning-signs/105788574</link><description>A reverse-image search of ocularist Jack McDonald's website shows that receptionist "Nadia" also appears on a dentistry blog and is known as "Donna" on a self-help guru's site. It's just one of the red flags that ABC NEWS Verify spotted during its investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d081d56d6116ad09be5333b0e23b73bc</guid></item><item><title>NSW RFS provides tips on preparing your home for bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/rfs-tips-on-preparing-your-home-for-bushfires/105787496</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9fb9639adb5adfa4953dfde776d2aeb</guid></item><item><title>Remote NSW council holds election after 12 years in administration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/central-darling-shire-council-election-nsw-votes-after-12-years/105757794</link><description>The 700 voters living in the remote Central Darling Shire Council area of New South Wales will finally head to the polls to vote again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2af8d61243c1a142aa5a6b000bb6dea5</guid></item><item><title>More than 800 Indonesian students get food poisoning from free school meals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/mass-food-poisoning-indonesian-students-government-free-meals/105797326</link><description>Over 800 students fall sick in two cases of mass food poisoning in one week after consuming free school meals sponsored by the Indonesian government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfb25b0f8356cd7bf1bbc285b8ae6a80</guid></item><item><title>'America is not happy': ABC under fire for pulling Jimmy Kimmel Live!</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/complaints-about-kimmel-axing-meant-for-us-abc-sent-to-australia/105793428</link><description>The ABC has received hundreds of complaints about US talk show Jimmy Kimmel Live! being pulled off air and threats to boycott sponsors ... but that's the problem when two broadcasters from different countries share a name!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">058463060dc5663ada42854e5496b80c</guid></item><item><title>Canada beats New Zealand 34-19 to reach Women's Rugby World Cup final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/canada-dazzles-to-end-new-zealand-women-rugby-world-cup/105797400</link><description>A changing of the guard in women's rugby union as two-time defending world champions New Zealand is beaten for the first time at the tournament since 2014 by a brilliant Canadian side.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db955f9919a07cd55204d1ec6a7e244c</guid></item><item><title>Near-blinded police officer reunites with those who saved him after rural motorcycle crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/police-officer-john-kenworthy-returns-to-thank-those-at-crash/105724428</link><description>Police officer John Kenworthy returns to thank the first responders in Mackay, and others who were with him in his darkest moments, after a rural motorcycle crash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af7195369dfa834fd85a7caed2683441</guid></item><item><title>Critical incident declared after man dies during alleged DV arrest in Sydney's south west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/nsw-sydney-critical-incident-declared-in-sadleir/105797330</link><description>Police were called to two separate domestic-related incidents in New South Wales overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bea73896721ecf6c280747e26d7597d</guid></item><item><title>Kamala Harris's frustration with Joe Biden, and other takeaways from her election trail memoir</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/kamala-harris-election-campaign-memoir-key-takeaways/105797598</link><description>Kamala Harris has kept a low profile since losing the US election, but she has plenty to say in her upcoming book — a diary from her doomed campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">889a1be8632644b869e3a832fcf2a96a</guid></item><item><title>Yolŋu people celebrate 50 years of the homelands movement in East Arnhem Land</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/nt-laynhapuy-homelands-movement-anniversary-indigenous-yolngu/105796404</link><description>Yolŋu children from nine Laynhapuy communities are screaming the Yothu Yindi anthem, Homeland Movement, in a ceremony celebrating the Indigenous elders who claimed back life on their country 50 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3184235034372056a06780912d5fe26e</guid></item><item><title>Super Netball celebrates bumper year as Sunshine Coast Lightning drives registration surge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/super-netball-sunshine-coast-lightning-registration-increase/105784044</link><description>A Queensland community is reaping the rewards of establishing the first regional professional netball team in the national league.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">266127730ccdcd9a64908f83b47107da</guid></item><item><title>Crowds flock to Toowoomba Carnival of Flowers despite wet weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/toowoomba-carnival-of-flowers-draws-crowds-despite-weather/105794286</link><description>Cold and damp conditions have not been enough to keep people away from Toowoomba's annual floral extravaganza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0670d318c12fc7fd9d19e3d22856487c</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's measles outbreak growing after case confirmed in rural town Middlemount</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/measles-outbreak-queensland-growing-middlemount-case/105798134</link><description>A rural town in central Queensland is the latest community affected, after a case was recorded in Middlemount.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85ce8d1b5f911925dc41badfdac6d776</guid></item><item><title>Former nurse shares devastating experience of attempts to get urgent cancer surgery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/hospital-logjam-blamed-for-delays-to-cancer-surgeries/105724218</link><description>Karenne Mosley was diagnosed with aggressive uterine cancer in March. She was booked in for surgery twice but is now in palliative care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">322dfad9007ac7be6793c351ff5df832</guid></item><item><title>Street artist Rone's new 90-metre mural a visual love letter to Geelong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/tyrone-rone-wright-new-mural-captures-geelong-faces/105762354</link><description>The faces of 14 people will be immortalised in an enormous mural on the side of a new building in Geelong by locally born, globally renowned artist Rone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28ac13e735d6c51ed4a4df9593e87271</guid></item><item><title>Republicans warn Anthony Albanese of 'punitive measures' over Palestinian recognition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/republicans-warn-australia-over-palestinian-statehood/105798830</link><description>As Anthony Albanese touches down in New York ahead of the UN General Assembly, Republicans issue a warning against formally recognising Palestinian statehood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebe5c9ff00ace1a2ffdeee5ad7a40913</guid></item><item><title>Inside Ninga Mia, a forgotten community in the shadow of Kalgoorlie the city of gold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/ninga-mia-kalgoorlie-mining-aboriginal-reserve-homelessness-gold/105774862</link><description>There's an eerie silence in Ninga Mia, a once thriving community on the edge of Kalgoorlie. The Aboriginal reserve is a microcosm of the cycle of displacement endured by many First Nations people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eafa5daeccecbae05c7c9ef093e72c5</guid></item><item><title>Koori Court marks 20 years in Mildura as Victoria approaches treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/twenty-years-of-koori-justice-in-mildura-victorias-north-west/105784288</link><description>Mildura marks two decades since its Koori Court opened, as Victoria sees mixed results in the push to reduce Indigenous incarceration and offending rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d57275cbeb1abf5d81f15d9fb2c32b08</guid></item><item><title>Life on Aboriginal reserve remembered by Carnarvon traditional owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/aboriginal-reserve-memories-carnarvon-traditional-owners/105510728</link><description>In 1975, an anthropologist wrote his thesis on Carnarvon's rich Aboriginal reserve. Decades later, traditional owners revisit the work to contribute to "big truth-telling" documentary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecf8bb607751e84f71648e4dfa5cd44a</guid></item><item><title>Australian-born singer drops out of Russian-hosted Intervision song contest after 'political pressure'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australian-born-singer-drops-out-of-russian-hosted-song-contest/105799020</link><description>Vassy dropped out of the contest at the last minute after coming under what Russian organisers said was "unprecedented political pressure from the government of Australia".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6f53824a2ed40b9ae66bd7ebdb25e1a</guid></item><item><title>Penola High School's agriculture program revives community and enrolments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/penola-high-school-ag-program-revives-falling-enrolments/105787042</link><description>Cory O'Connor's three-week teaching placement turned around his hometown high school. Now he's receiving an award for the agriculture program he started there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">800678cadea15a18ec482186c893d046</guid></item><item><title>Cats star Tyson Stengle desperate to win second AFL premiership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/afl-grand-final-geelong-cats-brisbane-lions-tyson-stengle/105799288</link><description>Three years after Tyson Stengle capped off his remarkable AFL career resurrection with a premiership, the Geelong forward believes a second premiership would hold greater significance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4c3712d165c2a42a93ac12de61b5a9d</guid></item><item><title>Penrith Panthers hammer Canterbury-Bankstown Bulldogs to keep NRL premiership five-peat hopes alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/nrl-semifinal-live-updates-bulldogs-vs-panthers/105799314</link><description>Penrith has crushed Canterbury-Bankstown after a phenomenal first half to claim a 46-26 victory, keeping their hopes of a fifth-consecutive NRL premiership alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73ad6ec14b559cb36a842edc842a9431</guid></item><item><title>How to clean out your wardrobe as the seasons change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/how-to-spring-clean-wardobe-clean-out/105780140</link><description>It's the kind of task that can seem overwhelming, but the change of season is the perfect opportunity to review what's in your wardrobe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf9c7f0a36323b3457588962f5d0b0b0</guid></item><item><title>Dayne Zorko fined by AFL for targeting Mason Cox's glasses in Lions' win over Magpies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/afl-brisbane-lions-collingwood-magpies-dayne-zorko-mason-cox/105799528</link><description>Brisbane Lions stalwart Dayne Zorko is punished by the AFL after he ripped off Mason Cox's glasses during their fiery preliminary final clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34b6f6c464fdb14a9fdb5f312f87feab</guid></item><item><title>Australia formally recognises state of Palestine as Anthony Albanese arrives in US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australia-formally-recognises-state-of-palestine/105799238</link><description>The historic decision foreshadowed last month has now become a reality, as Australia moves with Canada and the United Kingdom to join the growing list of countries to recognise Palestinian sovereignty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f7f36cbe6b5b1fbaaf3e78efd2951a2</guid></item><item><title>Gene editing is being sold on the promise of healthier babies — but what are the ethical concerns?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/ethics-of-gene-editing-designer-babies/105496228</link><description>The race to advance gene editing tech continues, spurred on by starry-eyed Silicon Valley investors, entrepreneurs and even pronatalists. But it is still deeply controversial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">073c888cabd844776c0f78ddf6d9f91a</guid></item><item><title>The government says its 2035 climate targets are achievable but mathematics suggests a different story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/climate-target-2035-2050-carbon-emissions-global-warming/105799080</link><description>The problem with an emissions reduction target is that its mere existence implies it is achievable and that if we do achieve it, we will be fine. The truth is more complex.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55dd3a3450e5da05cd2e7e786ef836f8</guid></item><item><title>Dementia-linked protein lower in people reporting vigorous exercise, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/how-exercise-can-reduce-risk-of-developing-dementia/105783238</link><description>Scientists have, for the first time, linked exercise with a particular protein in the blood that is associated with brain health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1927e46b141094965051ff5e6c95b5c2</guid></item><item><title>Australia has been free of endemic measles since 2014. Could that change?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/measles-cases-on-the-rise-australia-explainer/105799284</link><description>So far this year, there have been 121 measles notifications across Australia — the highest number since 2019, when there were 284 notifications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cebd25abdddc63773dde66358f7395f</guid></item><item><title>Murray River flood may not be to blame for SA algal bloom, Senate inquiry hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/murray-river-flood-link-to-algal-bloom-questioned-senate-inquiry/105733848</link><description>Scientists have questioned the link between the 2022-23 floods and South Australia's ongoing harmful algal bloom, despite the state government listing it as one of the three primary causes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e88db31a70e241e8774222579aebebdc</guid></item><item><title>Short-term stays are swallowing up housing stock in these WA coastal havens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/wa-coastal-towns-for-rent/105628728</link><description>With one of the nation's highest proportions of Airbnbs, some of WA's most popular tourist towns face a dilemma. Tourism is their biggest breadwinner — but with a housing crisis in full swing, short-term stays are pushing more and more locals away.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42e3387b3cda80c2ffd9d9842d5c1c42</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr earns a standing ovation in home game return as Chelsea defeats Leicester 1-0 in WSL</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/wsl-sam-kerr-returns-home-to-standing-ovation-in-chelsea/105800446</link><description>Chelsea fans stand and applaud Australian superstar Sam Kerr in her long-awaited return to Kingsmeadow in the WSL.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da70332495135e59ba3b6176d03d566d</guid></item><item><title>World leaders are meeting at the UN General Assembly this week. Here are four things to watch for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/united-nations-general-assembly-what-to-watch-for-in-new-york/105800440</link><description>World leaders are arriving in New York for the UN General Assembly — and for the first time, Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is among them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">761958b8abcd8c47c96a8d78d674b211</guid></item><item><title>Optus triple-0 outage investigation underway as minister warns of 'consequences'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/optus-investigation-triple-0-outage/105800556</link><description>The Australian Media and Communications Authority begins its investigation into the Optus triple-0 outage that has been linked to multiple deaths in South Australia and Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64e8d943c326b70c38e9b095d514da19</guid></item><item><title>Queensland CHO on state's measles outbreak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/queensland-cho-on-states-measles-outbreak/105801130</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">651d78f7433d688b560566682a3c8124</guid></item><item><title>Easy and healthy dinner recipes for spring</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/easy-healthy-recipes-for-spring-dinners/105660408</link><description>If you're looking for light dinner ideas as the weather warms up, we have plenty of easy options. Think veggie-filled frittatas and beef taco bowls with a few healthy swaps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c28e2a7be5345c5402fc685acca89162</guid></item><item><title>Is AI impacting your career or life plans? Has its rapid rise got you rethinking your future? The ABC wants to hear from you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/ai-artificial-intelligence-future-job-career-impact/105762606</link><description>Whether you’re a student halfway through a degree or a mid-career manager planning the next five years, artificial intelligence (AI) is reshaping lives across the country. If you've been feeling its effects, the ABC wants to hear from you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc9fb0b057b73e053ee1ce795957b20a</guid></item><item><title>Super Netball's Sunshine Coast Lightning enters new Global Sports Fund Management Group ownership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/super-netball-sunshine-coast-lightning-new-ownership/105801344</link><description>Almost a decade after being co-founded by the Melbourne Storm and University of the Sunshine Coast, Super Netball's Lightning is entering a new era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">725e5769d7aa41a90979ec4d3e47f5bd</guid></item><item><title>Brownlow Medal 2025: All the best fashion looks from AFL's night of nights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-red-carpet-wrap/105802436</link><description>Just after the fashion from this evening's Brownlow Medal? We've got you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8922390581e8430e878c1aa384dd8e2d</guid></item><item><title>Matt Rowell wins 2025 Brownlow Medal as Gold Coast star beats out Nick Daicos and Bailey Smith</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-medal-2025-live-blog-daicos-smith-dawson-rowell/105798968</link><description>Matt Rowell becomes the second Gold Coast player to win the prestigious AFL award, as a questionable voting call regarding Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera leaves the room stunned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08247d0fedaa413c59c8aea7818c6570</guid></item><item><title>Leopard sharks recorded mating by researcher in rare event off New Caledonia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/leopard-sharks-mating-rare-event-new-caledonia/105803858</link><description>A Sunshine Coast marine biologist has captured unique footage of two male sharks mating with a female in waters off New Caledonia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d272a5e23486cc628261c514c7180fe</guid></item><item><title>More than $4 million in drugs seized across WA's far north in ongoing operation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/kimberley-police-seize-meth-ammunition-and-other-drugs/105804038</link><description>Police in the Kimberley say an ongoing investigation has seized millions of dollars' worth of ammunition, methylamphetamine and other drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29a62dd5dae99250a80b3b8152cf6465</guid></item><item><title>Ley writes to Republicans vowing to revoke Palestine recognition ahead of Albanese's UN address</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/albanese-un-palestine-address-ley-republican-letter/105803078</link><description>In an unorthodox move, Opposition Leader Sussan Ley writes to a group of Republicans reassuring the Coalition would withdraw recognition of Palestine, ahead of a major United Nations address to be delivered by the prime minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98f3481476a06e3c9782e1032f1893d8</guid></item><item><title>Moldovan authorities arrest 74 people over alleged Russia-backed election plot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/moldova-election-arrests-russia-backed-plot/105804776</link><description>The widespread raids came ahead of the country's parliamentary elections on Sunday, expected to determine whether the country will pursue closer ties with the European Union.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a647be00ecfc0d387fa0b9a153bf4406</guid></item><item><title>Three Australians lay dead as investors of Optus's parent company Singtel were buying up its shares</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/three-australians-lay-dead-investors-buy-up-shares/105803922</link><description>The actions by Optus management in the hours following a series of failed attempts by its customers to call triple-0 raises questions about the telco's fitness to operate in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24e9f1bc9c2b8e3b2e1bdab5ae2ccb23</guid></item><item><title>The public hospital patients who ended up paying abortion clinics for miscarriage care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/qld-mater-miscarriage-care-catholic-hospital-abortion/105781022</link><description>Brisbane women have told the ABC they paid an abortion clinic for their chosen miscarriage care rather than getting it at their large public hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34accc25ffd487a2e3cb32cdcd8a582d</guid></item><item><title>Sustainable Timber Tasmania mistake 'compromised' arrests of logging protesters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/tasmanian-logging-company-mistake-compromised-arrests/105802784</link><description>New documents show some of the reasons why charges against a number of forest protesters were dropped in Tasmania, with police now assisting the company to stop it from happening in future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fab7148986a7bada52644003a03f11e</guid></item><item><title>Turtle strandings and soft-shell syndrome cases fall as seagrass beds recover</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/soft-shell-syndrome-in-turtles-decline-as-seagrass-beds-recover/105789276</link><description>Soft-shell syndrome had been devastating green sea turtle numbers since flood events began impacting their seagrass food source in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af2746d8c73bc7e2cae2f8fde2fd2c13</guid></item><item><title>Doctors concerned easily accessible illegal cigarettes are causing smoking rates to increase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/act-easy-access-to-illegal-cigarettes-seeing-high-smoking-rates/105803450</link><description>Doctors say smoking rates are at levels they haven't seen in a decade due to easy access to illegal cigarettes that are a "quarter of the price" of legal cigarettes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">150ad4af75b20ef2e67ba79a215e5c20</guid></item><item><title>Byron Bay's 60-day holiday rental cap yields mixed results in first year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/60-day-caps-in-byron-bay-results-uncertain-after-one-year/105799696</link><description>A year after controversial holiday rental caps were introduced in Byron Bay to boost rental availability, the data is unclear about whether the endeavour has been a success.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66035aa0e00835cc39a9f24d118bed47</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel reinstated after hundreds of stars back free speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/jimmy-kimmel-back-on-air-disney-says/105805048</link><description>US comedian Jimmy Kimmel's late-night show will be reinstated after being taken off air, following remarks he made referencing right-wing activist Charlie Kirk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">868e8a8d3b8279fa34a833b46463ee3f</guid></item><item><title>Dash camera mandate for WA driving instructors considered as part of regulation review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/wa-government-consider-driving-instructor-camera-mandate/105790618</link><description>The WA government is considering mandating the use of dash cameras for driving instructors, in a bid to better protect vulnerable student drivers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a8f037624e70614c35efe8b66ab697d</guid></item><item><title>Experts say paracetamol safe for pregnancy, no proof for autism link made by Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/trump-administration-links-autism-to-paracetamol-tga-says-safe/105803566</link><description>Australia's medicines regulator says paracetamol remains safe to use during pregnancy despite Donald Trump's administration linking its use to an increased risk of autism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9575c0f36522e77b42eccc5329990b40</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire survivors still camping years later amid construction backlog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/mallacoota-builders-struggle-five-years-after-black-summer-fires/105562838</link><description>Five years after devastating bushfires swept through Mallacoota, some survivors are still making do with tents and camp kitchens amid a backlog of construction jobs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1121db6b9066459f003795b1fb706907</guid></item><item><title>Dave Barham steps down as Essendon president as Zach Merrett apologises to fans over Hawthorn meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/afl-zach-merrett-essendon-fans-hawthorn-meeting-shame/105805134</link><description>Essendon president Dave Barham hands over his role to his understudy, continuing an off-season filled with change at the club as Zach Merrett speaks publicly for the first time on his flirtation with Hawthorn.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3289cc328afab23fef3d55a2fb2fddc1</guid></item><item><title>Darwin dancer with dislocated knee left waiting for ambulance for six hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/darwin-dancer-left-waiting-for-ambulance-over-six-hours/105803840</link><description>A 20-year-old dancer was left waiting for an ambulance for more than six hours after dislocating her knee during a competition in the Darwin CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e282340089a62fe29ce12b5bbe0cdbb8</guid></item><item><title>Paddleboarder gets too close to whales to film them, gets nudged away</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/paddleboarder-gets-too-close-to-whales-to-film-them/105801626</link><description>Drone footage shows a paddleboarder getting too close to film a southern right whale mother and calf, and being nudged away by the whale, off Point Ann.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccd42678f7b40484099efe1f5126dddd</guid></item><item><title>Devonport City Council approves memorial for victims of Hillcrest jumping castle tragedy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/devonport-council-hillcrest-memorial-approval-coles-beach/105804118</link><description>A proposed memorial at Coles Beach for the child victims of the Hillcrest jumping castle tragedy has been unanimously approved by the Devonport City Council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a5663271771429de2aa53e25b1c0e8e</guid></item><item><title>Women band together to create community for rural mums feeling lonely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/women-create-community-for-rural-mums-suffering-from-loneliness/105803024</link><description>After raising biological and foster children on a farm 60 kilometres from the nearest major town, Tracey Angwin says being part of a community is essential for rural mums.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da92ce9d728ad981483651f9d4c38527</guid></item><item><title>Chronic pain sufferer donates knitted goods for babies in intensive care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/thousands-of-donated-knitted-items-for-premmie-babies/105762552</link><description>Knitting has become an outlet for Port Stephens woman Kim Franks, who is mostly housebound after a diagnosis of debilitating psoriasis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f81a9667430db32dc168a444fd30d209</guid></item><item><title>Deeming rates have increased after a five-year freeze. Here's how that could impact pension payments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/deeming-rate-freeze-ends-impact-on-pension-payments/105798966</link><description>The changes impact people on Centrelink payments who earn an income from financial assets, but pensioners are the biggest group to be affected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2a6081a58d1e888118022ad40f5fcfd</guid></item><item><title>As a doctor I'm choosing self-care over resilience</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/doctor-choosing-self-care-over-resilience/105728568</link><description>As a doctor who advocates for self-care, it took me a surprisingly long time to look after myself. Now I'm trying to be a good example for my patients and other doctors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96d1bd7d0cdf02ba7b181e19ec630701</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police officer charged with assault over protest arrest of former Greens candidate Hannah Thomas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/nsw-officer-charged-assault-hannah-thomas-greens-arrest/105805966</link><description>Hannah Thomas was among a group of pro-Palestinian protesters who demonstrated outside a manufacturing facility in June when she sustained a serious eye injury during her arrest for failing to comply with a move on direction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ffd2b5888a415cc414e269d4943cf29</guid></item><item><title>Experts say it is safe to use paracetamol during pregnancy and Trump's autism declaration is 'baseless'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/taking-paracetamol-during-pregnancy-does-not-cause-autism/105806092</link><description>Donald Trump's advice that pregnant women should limit the use of paracetamol in pregnancy has been criticised as "baseless". So what does it mean for you?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81c81571674ce6c676915af2ca81de9b</guid></item><item><title>ICC prosecutors charge Phillipines' former leader Duterte with crimes against humanity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/icc-prosecutors-charge-duterte-3-counts-crimes-against-humanity/105806448</link><description>Former president of the Philippines, Rodrigo Duterte, is accused of being involved in the murder of dozens of people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">186fbab29d9070e10f640592f7123774</guid></item><item><title>Bill Gates pledges $US912 million to AIDS and malaria non-profit as US cuts funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/bill-gates-foundation-pleaged-millions-to-global-fund/105806406</link><description>The tech entrepreneur's announcement follows deep cuts from governments around the world, led by the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd0e8c660df290dadbcdf29a13957875</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Lions star Lachie Neale trains strongly and looks on track for a grand final spot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/neale-trains-as-lion-s-grand-final-return-hopes-gather-pace/105806698</link><description>The 31-year-old dual Brownlow medallist, who has been battling a calf injury, took part in training drills in front of 2,000 Brisbane fans at the team's Springfield home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c61b547c00f1a6df00fecccb68dde8b8</guid></item><item><title>Man known as 'Moore Park Rapist' pleads guilty to series of sexual assaults in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/moore-park-rapist-glenn-cameron-pleads-guilty-sexual-assaults/105806986</link><description>Glenn Cameron has remained in custody since he was arrested in February last year and charged with more than 30 offences in relation to eight victims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c631b0b48e05bf34d6cd7b4127803d77</guid></item><item><title>MS support agency MS Society SA &amp; NT outlines three-year losses, $2.5m debt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/ms-society-sa-nt-facing-millions-in-debt/105806282</link><description>Non-profit organisation MS Society SA &amp; NT, says it has debts of about $2.5 million and has been facing losses for three years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">170d075b7f4176d41d4a209cb5faf5bc</guid></item><item><title>Northern Territory CLP government is reviewing sentencing laws. But will it change anything?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/jake-danby-hit-and-run-nt-sentencing-act-changing-clp-government/105801232</link><description>The case of hit-and-run driver Jake Danby has brought renewed focus to the NT's legal system and the problems it faces. But will changing sentencing laws help?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">181ee879b9bbed91231a5952dddf97e9</guid></item><item><title>Kevin Bacon on the importance of music, philanthropy and acting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/kevin-bacon-take-5-actor-music-philanthropy-interview/105793360</link><description>He's a prolific fixture on our screens who's famously six degrees from almost anyone. But Kevin Bacon is also a passionate musician and philanthropist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45104e05b24001759cca6f2985a81b97</guid></item><item><title>Concerns 'off-brand' cigarettes easy to access and cheaper</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/concerns-off-brand-cigarettes-easy-to-access-and/105807734</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e1d889cc16fa1dfacac6368020592c5</guid></item><item><title>Optus triple-0 outage tragedy: What we know and how events unfolded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/timeline-on-optus-triple-0-outage-what-we-know/105805890</link><description>The first sign something was wrong came late on Friday afternoon. Now we have a clearer picture of how the triple-0 outage unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c548c42002e87e4dd015358e8d8279e9</guid></item><item><title>Sale of Australia's biggest sheep station at Rawlinna finally gets WA government approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/sale-of-australias-largest-sheep-station-at-rawlinna-station/105807106</link><description>The WA government has finally signed off on the sale of Australia's largest sheep station almost seven months after UK-based Consolidated Pastoral Company announced plans to buy Rawlinna Station.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">453798f3baadfee94d513f7ea0e7efc3</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of bees swarm Wagga Wagga CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/thousands-of-bees-swarm-wagga-wagga-cbd/105808258</link><description>Thousands of bees appear without warning in the regional city, alarming locals and causing a commotion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27722e02bcf2c9eb1efacb7eed1b7299</guid></item><item><title>Two teenagers sentenced to detention over attacks on Perth men lured via Grindr app</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/teenagers-detention-grindr-attacks-men-perth/105807670</link><description>Two "lawless" and "cruel" teenage boys who used social media to lure gay men to isolated locations in Perth before attacking them will remain in detention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04ac3ca89cb5b2ff893be3071e8400f4</guid></item><item><title>Record number of calls to poisons hotlines for children ingesting melatonin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/melatonin-poisons-hotline-kidshealth/105802406</link><description>The ABC has analysed data from poisons hotlines across the country, revealing almost 1,500 calls were made about children taking melatonin last year, a dramatic rise on previous figures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6379f1180fb83dd59536f7b7017c4f87</guid></item><item><title>Canola crop invaders seeking social media selfies told to stay off farms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/canola-crop-invaders-told-to-stop-trespassing-for-selfies/105802230</link><description>Selfie hunters seeking the perfect social media photo among flowering canola are putting their safety and growers' livelihoods at risk, farmers say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c76b7d5ced248e1d7be9cfa5c171c969</guid></item><item><title>Dickie Bird, former English cricket umpire, dies aged 92</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/dickie-bird-former-english-cricket-umpire-dies-aged-92/105809586</link><description>One of international cricket's most recognised umpires is being remembered for his "fairness, humour and love of the game".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ea286fdda73733b0f123adaeb2b514e</guid></item><item><title>NT government open to subdividing purpose-built State Square Art Gallery in Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nt-government-open-to-state-square-art-gallery-subdivide-darwin/105807672</link><description>A leading figure in Australia's art world has criticised the Northern Territory government for considering splitting up the lease for a building designed as a major new art gallery, describing the plan as "pure madness".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cea270549341f3bb40e1fafe548161cf</guid></item><item><title>Video record of violence and racism at Purnim Bears, Noorat country football grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/violence-racism-of-80s-country-victoria-football-grand-final/105741080</link><description>The Purnim Bears were supposed to be the feel-good story of country football — a team uniting black and white communities. But their 1987 grand final was so violent it ended with their expulsion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">231bb9fc7a4848fb3114f306c75ce3e0</guid></item><item><title>Offshore wind pioneer Henrik Stiesdal says Australia can learn from Europe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/offshore-wind-pioneer-henrik-stiesdal-lessons-for-australia/105783010</link><description>A Danish clean energy pioneer says Australia is poised for success with offshore wind, but there are lessons it can learn from abroad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e8e43f8da41b1a8bb53cc06569e333e</guid></item><item><title>Unexplained lights in the sky sparks UAP chatter across much of Western Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/unexplained-uap-sightings-reported-across-midwest-wa/105803264</link><description>Perth Observatory says it has received reports of lights dancing in the sky across a significant part of WA's Midwest and Goldfields, with an explanation yet to be found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b4cb4ae36f5ab9e984491b519fa7152</guid></item><item><title>Queensland speed skydiver Natisha Dingle shows off her impressive skills.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/speed-skydiver-natisha-dingle-shows-off-her-impressive-skills/105807064</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c809122700c1bf91a2b261a16e110608</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's meeting with Trump matters for AUKUS and the role of the US in the Asia-Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/anthony-albanese-donald-trump-meeting/105801298</link><description>Trump clearly disagrees with Albanese on Palestine and the reality of climate change, but it's not on the scale of the beef he has with other countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1daf71c6599467c19439c0e23875de0e</guid></item><item><title>Artemis program on track to take astronauts around the Moon: NASA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nasa-artemis-program-on-track-to-take-people-to-the-moon/105809764</link><description>NASA's first crewed flight in its Artemis program — a trip around the Moon and back — is on track for launch in April 2026 and could potentially be moved up to February, the space agency says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87a63c967423b595bde610ff51e979b6</guid></item><item><title>Trump claims paracetamol link to autism. Five experts explain what's wrong with that statement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/what-the-experts-are-saying-about-paracetamol-use-lead-to-autism/105806230</link><description>Some leading Australian experts in medicine, autism research and obstetrics say the US president's claims are "a misreading of science," or at worst, "a misuse". Here's why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bffee58bd319bdb466db1eb8559f629b</guid></item><item><title>Why the legacy of the 2023 NRL grand final hangs over the Broncos and Panthers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/panthers-broncos-nrl-preliminary-final-grand-final-cleary/105809026</link><description>On Sunday, the Broncos and Panthers will face off in the finals for the first time since the 2023 grand final, but the memory of that night still hangs over both sides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad8624f8c74a64751af52bbcd1e11c56</guid></item><item><title>ABC ordered to pay $150,000 fine for unlawfully sacking journalist and presenter Antoinette Lattouf</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/antoinette-lattouf-costs-decision-in-abc-unlawful-termination/105810052</link><description>The judge ordered ABC to pay a fine of $150,000 for unlawfully sacking journalist and presenter Antoinette Lattouf for reasons including her political opinions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dad4cb7dec36a5f662b73fe15e33939</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fullback Andrew Kellaway ruled out of first Bledisloe Cup Test match against All Blacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/wallabies-andrew-kellaway-ruled-out-bledisloe-cup-all-blacks/105810670</link><description>Wallabies fullback Andrew Kellaway will miss Saturday's Bledisloe Cup Test match against the All Blacks in Auckland, ruled out with a calf strain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11b979e7ef790b13cc2880a8a193f4dd</guid></item><item><title>Canberra golf course redevelopments providing both much-needed housing and financial lifelines for struggling clubs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/golf-course-redevelopments-providing-housing-financial-lifelines/105799100</link><description>With the ACT government pushing for greater urban density, golf courses in inner Canberra suburbs are becoming attractive sites for redevelopment to provide much-needed housing and a way for struggling clubs to bolster their budgets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b488a99ab4311911d8fa6f87e596dc4c</guid></item><item><title>Sculpture by the Sea could be cancelled due to $200,000 shortfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/sculptures-by-the-sea-facing-cancellation-funding-shortfall/105810510</link><description>Australia's famed sculpture walk is facing cancellation after failing to secure funding less than a month out from this year's event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ca69999aba4ff9483322749a16b717e</guid></item><item><title>Man behind iconic ABC TV programs, Graham White, dies aged 93</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/graham-white-abc-tv-and-radio-pioneer-dies-at-93/105806806</link><description>Graham White was a pioneer of Australian radio and television and played a key role in the creation of numerous television series, including A Big Country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54c9a84115c56f73f0923751c300a0e1</guid></item><item><title>Despite past controversy, NSW Police commissioner Mal Lanyon has a strong backing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nsw-police-commissioner-mal-lanyon-premier-chris-minns-analysis/105810774</link><description>For newly-announced Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon, Wednesday morning would have been both one of his proudest moments, and his most uncomfortable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed72f9bcc7ce20d2d722b8b43d539719</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel returns, addressing Charlie Kirk and 'un-American' axing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/jimmy-kimmel-returns-thanking-supporters-speaks-to-free-speech/105808410</link><description>Despite the late-night host's return, several US ABC affiliates did not air the episode, excluding an estimated one-quarter of American households.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac8b78a8e557c0d2a91d42ed04e2eed</guid></item><item><title>Rape case against Bruce Lehrmann delayed after lawyer misses deadline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/bruce-lehrmann-rape-case-faces-more-delays-in-toowoomba/105811608</link><description>A judge says the process of a bid to stop a criminal rape case against former Liberal Party staffer Bruce Lehrmann proceeding has been "problematic" after his lawyer missed a key deadline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20b38956daedd1cd16f45a4769958aa6</guid></item><item><title>Doctor who lost daughter to brain cancer receives grant in race to clinical trials</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/doctor-receives-grant-to-continue-brain-cancer-research/105810368</link><description>A professor who lost his daughter to brain cancer in 2018 is hopeful the research to find a cure in children is just five years away from clinical trials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc0272343034af8958b1ec9f51c4c20f</guid></item><item><title>Optus to pay $100m fine, as crisis engulfing Australia's second biggest telco continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/optus-fined-100-million-for-sales-misconduct/105810174</link><description>In enforcing the fine today, the Federal Court's Justice Patrick O'Sullivan described the company's conduct as "extremely serious" and "appalling".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5b8ef086dc95c25b9efd2536b1850d6</guid></item><item><title>Concerns Launceston City Council could give away Birchalls CBD site it bought for $8.8m</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/launceston-council-developer-plans-for-birchalls-building/105809796</link><description>Launceston City Council bought the historic Birchalls building for $8.8 million five years ago. A ratepayer association says it has learnt of a proposal to give it away "for nothing".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57bb6bb59e636d4105fd48c27dcdbaca</guid></item><item><title>Missouri woman gets more than four years jail for trying to sell off Elvis' Graceland property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/missouri-woman-jailed-for-elvis-graceland-property-scam/105810930</link><description>A woman's attempt to sell off one of the most storied pieces of real estate in the US has come to naught. Here's how it happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87c9bf726b751fc3728cdd75266b9d0d</guid></item><item><title>Electric vehicle-to-grid trial in Exmouth generates promising results for state power distributor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/electric-vehicle-to-grid-v2g-trial-in-exmouth-promising/105811868</link><description>State distributor Horizon Power says a trial of bi-directional charging with electric vehicles to both supplement the grid and take up excess power, known as V2G, has proved a success.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c657879091e2ce95be5b33b932b29f12</guid></item><item><title>Former A-League footballers Clayton Lewis and Kearyn Baccus sentenced over betting scam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/a-league-betting-clayton-lewis-kearyn-baccus-sentencing/105811400</link><description>Both players were paid $10,000 each to intentionally get themselves yellow cards while playing for Macarthur FC against Sydney FC to influence overseas bets on the game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4d047a9369284c7941aaf5cccc0a654</guid></item><item><title>Farmer Sam Bailey, who worked to be the world's first quadriplegic helicopter pilot, dies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/quadriplegic-helicopter-pilot-sam-bailey-dies/105811530</link><description>A "true blue" farmer, pilot, and pioneer for accessibility in agriculture has been honoured after his sudden death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1022bcfec676038f6c3bd27cde15e24c</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of Australians fighting 'cruel' battle for COVID vaccine injury compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/fight-for-compensation-for-covid-19-vaccination-injuries/105808630</link><description>Thousands of Australians who were injured by COVID vaccines say they are facing a 'cruel and complex' system to get compensation from the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc0182bdb4d37c0f24454edad8263808</guid></item><item><title>Former police officer Stephen Michael Calcutt pleads guilty to filming teenagers in shower and up skirt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/former-police-officer-pleads-guilty-filming-teenager/105812714</link><description>The former sergeant also filmed up another teenager's skirt and had a number of cartoons depicting children in sexual situations on a hard drive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d016f9d7ccabbb8651e7cb9fc607919e</guid></item><item><title>Senate inquiry examines federal environment department's SA algal bloom response</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/murray-watt-briefing-algal-bloom-july/105813252</link><description>Officials from the federal environment department say they were not aware of the impact of SA's algal bloom until the state government contacted them in May, two months after the bloom was first detected. Speaking at a senate inquiry, department officials say the federal environment minister was not formally briefed on the bloom until July.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47629bf3fc1342b70bb629add33dbfd9</guid></item><item><title>Alzheimer's drug Lecanemab approved by Therapeutic Goods Administration for use in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/alzheimers-drug-lecanemab-approved-by-tga/105813710</link><description>The Therapeutic Goods Administration approves the drug Lecanemab, which can slow down cognitive decline in the early stages of Alzheimer's.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4467a4bcfcdb0b2847fe165e1550be39</guid></item><item><title>Super Typhoon Ragasa hits south China as death toll rises to 14</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/super-typhoon-ragasa-kills-several-people-many-others-missing/105813684</link><description>Super Typhoon Ragasa has killed at least 14 people in Taiwan as it struck the southern Chinese coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3debe7584f1c0715ebb83364e81b822c</guid></item><item><title>One dead in 'targeted' shooting at Dallas immigration centre, DHS says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/multiple-dead-at-dallas-ice-shooting/105814138</link><description>Police were first alerted to the incident at 6:40am on Wednesday, local time, and later found the shooter on a nearby roof dead from an apparent self-inflicted gunshot wound.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41372aed6a1e8513347f563b066ef004</guid></item><item><title>London mayor calls Trump racist, sexist and Islamophobic, hitting back at US president's 'sharia law' comments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sadiq-khan-hits-back-at-trump-over-islamophobic-comments/105814108</link><description>The US president described Sadiq Khan as "terrible" and warned the British capital was heading towards "sharia law".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">422ae10fb37033a360fbadff60ea4a35</guid></item><item><title>Kimmel monologue racks up millions of views on social media as Joe Rogan slams government 'dictating'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/kimmel-video-and-rogan-lashing-viral/105814274</link><description>Kimmel's program was indefinitely suspended last week after he made comments about the late conservative commentator Charlie Kirk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">125445d0de8a02f7060a350896e799ff</guid></item><item><title>Australia's social media ban wins praise from Europe at UN event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/united-nations-general-assembly-social-media-ban/105814246</link><description>Australia's willingness to take on the social media giants is drawing significant international interest, winning the support of the European Commission president at a forum in New York.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13cbd1fcaa9fc632384fa2b086577151</guid></item><item><title>Australia in a 'dangerous place' as AI adoption ramps up, prompting calls to protect jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/australia-in-dangerous-place-as-ai-adoption-ramps-up/105807430</link><description>Artificial intelligence is coming for our jobs — but will it take them away, or just give us a powerful new assistant?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48e1ecb4ff4fc7a8cb46b98272af471f</guid></item><item><title>Who is really pulling the strings at Optus and what does that mean for you?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/who-really-controls-optus/105813620</link><description>The Singapore government's sovereign wealth investment vehicle is the majority owner of Singtel, which owns Australia's second-largest telco provider.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6aded4f6f61a6898c3ed39fc7af059c2</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie taunted over claim that high immigration is making Australians 'strangers in our own home'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/hastie-migration-strangers-liberal-policy/105813654</link><description>The home affairs minister says Andrew Hastie should name which visa classes he would cut after the shadow home affairs minister suggested "unsustainable" immigration was making Australians "feel like strangers in our own home".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13e71a456d250f5a995b477b981c4622</guid></item><item><title>Hastie downplays 'mischievous' leadership speculation – as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/federal-politics-live-sept-25/105812720</link><description>Liberal frontbencher Andrew Hastie brushes off suggestions he is a threat to Sussan Ley's leadership after a series of outspoken social media posts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a1855533ef7e4ee2263abc39c01aed0</guid></item><item><title>Will food prices ever come down? Don't bet on it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/will-food-grocery-prices-ever-come-down/105811296</link><description>While recent cuts to interest rates may have given mortgage holders a bit of a financial breathing space, the cost of food continues to creep upwards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fce87e998f0daf4d07d83c36c6038f70</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy blames Putin for 'most destructive arms race in human history'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/zelenskyy-blames-putin-for-most-destructive-arms-race/105814378</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7700655ee2a3abe520a419b677e6593f</guid></item><item><title>Free speech pathologist sessions turning poor literacy rates around in Logan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/qld-logan-children-literacy-boost-free-speech-pathologist/105809794</link><description>A federal government backed weekly reading session led by experts is helping improve literacy rates in Queensland children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6f3a9ca2aa561db64986a266e4fcdcd</guid></item><item><title>Independent review launched into fire ant eradication program amid 'closing window of opportunity'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/fire-ant-eradication-program-review-launched/105811790</link><description>Authorities launch an independent review of Australia's national fire ant eradication program to evaluate the country's fight against one of the world’s most destructive pests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c444298e462f9192611f3572f0c28de3</guid></item><item><title>Families demand inquiry into NSW Police handling of missing persons cases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/families-of-missing-persons-call-for-probe-into-police/105693338</link><description>Nikii Smith is one of 10,000 people who signed a petition calling for a NSW inquiry into the handling of missing persons cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86bd1e4db1094cebb0f4277ff0ad4c3b</guid></item><item><title>China retains narrow edge over US as South-East Asia's most influential partner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/china-us-influence-south-east-asia/105812866</link><description>New research shows that China retains a very narrow edge over the United States as South-East Asia's most influential partner, with experts predicting it will soon pull further ahead as the Trump administration's policies begin to bite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7b10409c8753c731ed70c5ed5ed7bea</guid></item><item><title>Super Typhoon Ragasa leaves trail of destruction in Hong Kong, mainland China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/super-typhoon-ragasa-leaves-trail-of-destruction/105814414</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea6a7a5ee520e38455556c3ef9f800c2</guid></item><item><title>Family calls for change amid frustration at seven-year coronial inquest wait</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/anger-at-seven-year-coronial-inquest-wait/105805234</link><description>Robert Hall was killed when he was struck by partially blind driver John Charles Robertson on the Horrocks Highway in 2018. It has been a long wait for the family ahead of the release of coronial findings into his death next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dedbef63ba8aa61b8045e0d358939858</guid></item><item><title>Elevated E. coli levels recorded at major NT crocodile farm owned by luxury label Hermès</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/lambells-lagoon-crocodile-farm-nt-high-e-coli-levels-in-water/105806340</link><description>One of Australia's largest crocodile farms, owned by a subsidiary of luxury label Hermès, is consistently irrigating with water containing E. coli concentrations almost 500 times the national guidelines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcebaaf92f52cb686dddde475db8c67b</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous teen speaks out against heckling of Welcome to Country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/indigenous-writes-essay-against-heckling-welcome-to-country/105808140</link><description>An Indigenous high school student's essay on the Anzac Day heckling of an Indigenous elder by far-right supremacists has earned her a nationally recognised award.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d0978c16ddeb79e39b966dd2e565459</guid></item><item><title>New gene therapy for Huntington's 'changes everything', say researchers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/huntingtons-disease-gene-therapy-slows-progression/105814436</link><description>Clinical trials of a groundbreaking new gene therapy for Huntington's disease have shown that it slows progression of the condition by 75 per cent after three years, researchers say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38bce5a01d090886db2ddeef7689a3bb</guid></item><item><title>Alexa Leary and Callum Simpson win gold medals for Australia at World Para Swimming Championships in Singapore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/alexa-leary-callum-simpson-gold-world-para-swimming/105814486</link><description>Alexa Leary's win in the final individual event of Wednesday night's action in Singapore bookended a golden night for Australia after Callum Simpson won gold in the first event of the evening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24509973b18c1db25ad97fe2c3eae8f7</guid></item><item><title>'On guard' for share market correction, Optus debacle began in India — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/105814572</link><description>Optus has now told the ABC the firewall upgrade that led to disrupted triple-0 calls was initiated in Chennai, India. Meanwhile veteran stockbroker Marcus Padley says he's "on guard" for a share market wipe-out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d14279b842237d15d950214fbd7b970</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy warns UN of 'the most destructive arms race in human history'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/united-nations-general-assembly-volodymyr-zelenskyy-speech/105814462</link><description>Ukraine's president calls for global action to regulate the twin threats posed by drone technology and artificial intelligence, warning "no-one can feel safe" from Russia's expansionist goals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5f96320cb70d90485b91a1058586e74</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final sprint won't feature all teams, as Gout Gout and Harry Garside to feature at the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/afl-grand-final-sprint-gout-gout-and-harry-garside/105814536</link><description>The AFL announces that only seven AFL players will run in the traditional grand final sprint, with Olympic boxer Harry Garside also joining in.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90c0207e2a6dabd51c17d24fbfdde78c</guid></item><item><title>Macquarie to repay Shield investors after super platform failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/macquarie-admits-to-shield-contraventions/105814728</link><description>Macquarie commits to repaying thousands of Australians who invested hundreds of millions of their retirement savings in the collapsed Shield Master Fund amid admissions it contravened the Corporations Act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6ef3dcad386254cfbd1a1063f29bbf1</guid></item><item><title>China's President Xi Jinping announces new climate goal to cut emissions by 2035</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/china-plans-carbon-emissions-cut-by-2035/105814492</link><description>Outlining China's new carbon targets in a video link to the UN climate conference in New York, President Xi Jinping says "green and low carbon transition is the trend of our time".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f28b3d1c00395f4695e9369d6c444f2</guid></item><item><title>Dramatic footage shows sinkhole swallowing up road in central Bangkok</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sinkhole-swallows-road-in-central-bangkok/105814850</link><description>Social media footage shows powerlines being pulled down into the 50-metre deep hole and vehicles teetering on the edge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">341b949dae61cd2058ac47c271016c61</guid></item><item><title>Growing AFL fan club for people with disability helps forge friendships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/afl-fan-club-gives-people-with-disability-a-place-to-socialise/105797970</link><description>A growing club on the border between Victoria and New South Wales helps AFL fans with disabilities connect with friends who share their love for the sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e88b83291b9bd7812031211c737290f</guid></item><item><title>Andrea James to lead Ilbijerri Theatre Company as artistic director Rachael Maza steps back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/ilbijerri-theatre-company-artistic-director-andrea-james/105806022</link><description>Andrea James will take the helm of Australia's oldest Indigenous theatre company Ilbijerri, as outgoing artistic director Rachael Maza steps back after almost 18 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4a3dbe4751b97f43dde74a8c6965376</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with multiple offences over pursuit, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/vale-park-man-arrested-over-alleged-dv-incident/105815044</link><description>South Australia Police says a Vale Park man has been charged following a pursuit that led STAR group officers and police negotiators to a unit in Adelaide's western suburbs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55d31264009557887152139ca68f0250</guid></item><item><title>NT para athlete Briseis Brittain wasn't born when Cathy Freeman won Olympic gold, but the moment fired a dream</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nt-para-athlete-briseis-brittain-new-delhi-world-championship/105810758</link><description>Arnhem Land teenager Briseis Brittain is set to represent Australia at the World Para Athletics Championships in New Delhi this month, competing in the 200m and 400m races.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc07264a34fb78aeac4e200e6ca98512</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese addresses UN on climate goals, Gaza and Australia's security council bid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/albanese-united-nations-general-assembly-speech/105815200</link><description>The prime minister uses his UN speech to talk up Australia's emissions plan after Donald Trump called climate change a "con job", and confirms Australia is still seeking a temporary seat on the body's security council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a232f435066d64bce12998bbb55c68d5</guid></item><item><title>New head of Queensland's troubled DNA lab says backlog of testing could take years to clear</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/queensland-dna-lab-forensic-lab-mick-fuller-investigation/105815548</link><description>More than 170 rape kits caught up in the Forensic Science Queensland laboratory's backlog will be sent offshore next week for vital forensic testing, as the facility's new boss says it will take years to clear them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f10104713dca5809a4ee3120e1d5a35</guid></item><item><title>Figure skating star scraps program amid probe involving artist who co-wrote music</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/figure-skating-star-scraps-program-amid-investigation-of-artist/105815302</link><description>Figure skaters spend months perfecting their programs ahead of big competitions, but now world champion Alysa Liu has to come up with a new short program months out from the Winter Olympics as her existing music involves an American artist under investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdb57cf2473b758d2fe046f294292f23</guid></item><item><title>Scott Selwood takes break from AFL after 'personally challenging year'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/scott-selwood-steps-away-afl-collingwood/105815996</link><description>Scott Selwood will take time away from football, stepping down as an assistant coach with Collingwood, following a year marked by personal tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41d251b3ccf71ca56edd70b60deeeab9</guid></item><item><title>AI image recognition technology used to detect traffic offences raises privacy concerns, Queensland audit finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/ai-image-technology-phone-speeding-offences-privacy-audit-qld/105815134</link><description>Queensland's transport department uses AI in its cameras to detect mobile and seatbelt offences, but a new audit has ordered called for a review into how that's done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11d46c909160642ceb7265e8809e201c</guid></item><item><title>Breastfeeding in public is protected in Australia. So why are mothers still facing discrimination?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/why-are-we-still-asking-mothers-to-hide-breastfeeding/105789046</link><description>Last week a breastfeeding mother was asked to leave a Virgin Australia lounge for pumping. Experts says while there is a level of awareness that breastfeeding in public is protected, some people in the community still view it as "inappropriate".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5341713f4b5168cc3ed1630a81ef91c6</guid></item><item><title>What are Australia's chances of returning to the UN Security Council?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/australia-renews-un-security-council-bid/105816596</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese makes a fresh push for Australia to get a seat on the United Nations Security Council in 2029-30.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12bbee71870039ed7798c50667d1fea5</guid></item><item><title>Snoop Dogg says AFL grand final is 'a way of life' ahead of headline show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/snoop-dogg-afl-grand-final/105816718</link><description>Snoop Dogg has strutted into the MCG for his official appearance ahead of a fascinating, somewhat controversial, AFL grand-final entertainment set.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b66d08f7f421a2cabf591d770048f0f</guid></item><item><title>Planned sale of RAC WA's insurance arm to IAG sparks member disquiet amid jump in profit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/rac-wa-insurance-sale-to-iag-sparks-unrest-amid-profit-jump/105816530</link><description>The head of Western Australia's biggest insurer says having a Sydney-based owner is the "best path forward" for its customers, but some are threatening to leave if the acquisition goes ahead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5fcf791a64b43eff274f2b836e41309</guid></item><item><title>Denmark PM apologises to indigenous Greenlanders who faced forced contraception</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/denmark-pm-apologises-to-greenland-over-contraception/105816090</link><description>The apology by Mette Frederiksen in Greenland’s capital, Nuuk, hopes to close a traumatic chapter in Greenland's history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10e2f68d02a379a76e33cb0667531d03</guid></item><item><title>Gisborne football netball club members hit back with legal threat after AFL rejects league switch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/gisborne-afl-rejection-bendigo-league-ballarat-football/105815498</link><description>The Victorian club wants to move into a different league because several clubs in the Ballarat league, including Darley, Sunbury and Melton, are much closer to Gisborne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e708bf9bf7ea8004e7e5fbc17be3d7b2</guid></item><item><title>Violent man abandons appeal to avoid jail for assaulting teenage ex-girlfriend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/appeal-fails-for-man-who-assaulted-teenage-ex-partner/105816094</link><description>A 19-year-old Victorian man, who recorded 67 prior convictions for stalking and breaching family violence orders against his young ex-girlfriend, has failed in a bid to stay out of jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20150ffcc414f4230c66ae54c5be6f85</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian government seeks to claw back $56k legal bill from former LGH boss Peter Renshaw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/tas-gov-try-to-recoup-legal-fees-from-peter-renshaw-and-others/105816024</link><description>A review has found three Tasmanian public servants did not act in good faith during the state's child abuse commission of inquiry and recommends clawing back up to $76,000 in legal fees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fe31766227e89081f1c386708c2ed38</guid></item><item><title>Trio of space weather satellites launched to study the Sun's violent side</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nasa-launch-three-spacecraft-sun/105815108</link><description>NASA successfully launches multiple satellites designed to get a better understanding of the Sun's influence on Earth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59a16bd185eeee6f5d85c73a75953dbf</guid></item><item><title>TGA approves new brain stimulation device for treatment of depression</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/brain-stimulator-device-approved-for-treatment-of-depression/105816064</link><description>Some international users of Flow Neuroscience's device have labelled the wearable tech as a game-changer in treating depression, but not everyone is convinced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d613860a63e9e5d904cc9b6ac0bd749</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies vs All Blacks Bledisloe Cup: Team lists, what time is kick-off? How can I watch?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/wallabies-vs-all-blacks-bledisloe-cup-team-lists/105814670</link><description>Wallabies prop James Slipper will notch an important milestone against New Zealand on Saturday, while James O'Connor will start at fly half.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03e6a514a7b10816017fc77c6d1b0aaa</guid></item><item><title>South Australia passes laws to protect victims of personal injury from 'claim farmers'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sa-claim-farming-laws-pass-parlia/105816232</link><description>Individuals who contact a survivor of abuse or personal injury without their permission to encourage them to make a claim for compensation could face fines of up to $50,000 under new laws which have passed in South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70085da5c5bdc719bc2ab735b7ccda09</guid></item><item><title>Hastie lets loose, one-on-one with Albanese and Trump, and the politics of Palestinian recognition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/hastie-ley-trump-un-palestine-cop-turkiye-bradfield-byelection/105814488</link><description>It turns out that Prime Minister Anthony Albanese didn't need a can of Diet Coke and a cheeseburger to attracted the US president's attention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93642a3e3240ad1fdff7cfac3d949f64</guid></item><item><title>Celebrity crocodile wrangler Matt Wright set to appeal guilty verdict on five grounds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/matt-wright-set-to-appeal-guilty-verdict-on-five-grounds/105816918</link><description>Matt Wright’s lawyers have confirmed they will file a notice of appeal within the next 48 hours, indicating it will be based on five different grounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">235091d5d14d90d64ed46d67022a1cf6</guid></item><item><title>Ahead of the biggest game of his NRL career, Nicho Hynes returns to where it all began</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/storm-sharks-nicho-hynes-nrl-preliminary-finals/105816184</link><description>Ten years to the day since his first moment in the spotlight, Nicho Hynes returns to AAMI Park for the most important game of his NRL career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ba9e5f21df0896a8a84e51f1a77817b</guid></item><item><title>SA government grapples with whether it should issue daily bloom updates during summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/algal-bloom-persists-on-adelaide-metropolitan-beaches/105815614</link><description>South Australia's Premier says the government is grappling with whether it should give daily updates on the bloom's location during summer, and says it has been "actively engaged" in conversations with the federal government since its emergence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58acb5d5694220c60122ae3f346438b9</guid></item><item><title>Liberal veteran Amanda Vanstone chides Andrew Hastie for not being a team player, warns of runaway ego</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/andrew-hastie-warned-of-division-amanda-vanstone/105817288</link><description>A doyenne of the Liberal Party and veteran of leadership battles dating back to the 1980s Howard-Peacock era has chided Andrew Hastie for not being a team player.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7155a17bde099fcac4270569e823ea49</guid></item><item><title>Matildas strike force could benefit from having both Sam Kerr and Michelle Heyman firing fit up front</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/matildas-could-have-sam-kerr-and-michelle-heyman/105817900</link><description>A fit-again Sam Kerr doesn't necessarily spell the end for Michelle Heyman's time in the Matildas, if anything the A-League star can't wait for her return.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c878d14058b221a67d55c4c8bdc80e94</guid></item><item><title>SA Water fined $60k for causing 'environmental harm' during botched maintenance of Warren Reservoir</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sa-water-fined-after-botched-maintenace-warren-reservoir/105817688</link><description>SA Water — which is owned by the SA government — has been fined for polluting the waterways with grey clay silt when draining the Warren Reservoir, in the Barossa Valley, in May 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fba0457dd1912373941155d18bca081c</guid></item><item><title>Albury Wodonga Health surgeon claims he was sacked for criticising development plans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/john-stuchbery-albury-hospital-redevelopment/105813170</link><description>An Albury Wodonga surgeon says the local health service dismissed him after he spoke out against a major redevelopment of the hospital and changes to the region's cancer centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5683d1879274b06a9d69932384c8ddb6</guid></item><item><title>Measles case detected in Brisbane, prompting calls for vaccination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/measles-brisbane-qld-health-alert-disease-infection/105817886</link><description>Queensland's health department says the person was believed to have contracted the virus in Bali, before visiting a number of businesses across Brisbane and the Sunshine Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69d52cc929c6deec63f591815c89b60a</guid></item><item><title>Lawyers for Raiders star Josh Papalii ask court to permanently stay charges over police group chat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/raiders-josh-papalii-lawyers-ask-court-for-stay-on-charges/105817698</link><description>The Raiders star's lawyers are asking the ACT Magistrates Court to permanently stay charges against him over a 2024 incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33a2e67d4e0df98eac893b5dbf74eab0</guid></item><item><title>University of Wollongong ordered to repay more than $6 million in underpayments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/university-of-wollongong-underpayments/105815928</link><description>Investigations have found 5,340 current and former University of Wollongong employees between 2014 and 2024 have been underpaid wages and superannuation amounting to $6.6 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae544080f66c622625badbc1d8fa0dd3</guid></item><item><title>Horse trainer Dwayne Schmidt jailed for raping and impregnating 13yo girl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/horse-trainer-raped-and-impregnated-13-year-old-girl/105813440</link><description>New South Wales horse trainer Dwayne Schmidt is sentenced to more than three years in jail for raping and impregnating a 13-year-old girl.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cff6a74bc32102a2a7bdba358773bf49</guid></item><item><title>Gympie Regional Council votes to remove fluoride from town's water supply</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/gympie-removes-fluoride-water-supply-dental-health-fears/105814678</link><description>Gympie scraps fluoride from its water supply and becomes the third region in Queensland to reject the practice in just over a year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9960f09af437f02819e5359d8481878</guid></item><item><title>Coroner finds Monash Health provided unreasonable care before toddler Dio Kemp's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/coroner-finding-into-death-of-dio-kemp/105816186</link><description>Three-year-old Dio Kemp was taken to Monash Medical Centre four times over 10 days before she died of sepsis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37b865829bea191edfe0af886035c9e4</guid></item><item><title>Huge red-bell jellyfish bloom and mass puffer fish deaths put Pilbara coast on alert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/pilbara-coast-alert-jellyfish-bloom-toxic-puffer-fish-deaths/105815554</link><description>Hundreds of dead puffer fish are found on a Pilbara beach, as an epic red-bell jellyfish bloom prompts a warning from the region's ports authority.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39c787a5232b58cd251e6bebea3ae077</guid></item><item><title>Arts industry leaders call for tax reforms to help struggling sector</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sydney-arts-leaders-calling-for-tax-reform-to-the-sector/105816210</link><description>Arts industry leaders say creative tax form is needed to create greater opportunities for Australian artists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7181bdf23c74d11e765b61f89bc136e</guid></item></channel></rss>