<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 08:48:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Timor-Leste protesters vow to continue rallying until plan to buy MPs 65 cars is overturned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/timor-leste-protests-over-mp-car-plan-grow/105781726</link><description>The protests nearly doubled in size on Tuesday as people continued to vent their frustrations at a plan to buy MPs 65 new SUVs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">feeb6a6ab4a2322ebf2709358b8c2353</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk shooting suspect Tyler Robinson charged with murder as prosecutors seek death penalty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/alleged-charlie-kirk-shooter-tyler-robinson-charged/105781872</link><description>Utah prosecutors say they will seek the death penalty for the 22-year-old alleged shooter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87bd66a147b9d8ff76e79fdd79e8ff76</guid></item><item><title>Sam Konstas scores Australia A century in four-day game in India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/sam-konstas-scores-australia-a-century-against-india-a/105782060</link><description>Sam Konstas's push for an Ashes spot continues as he clatters a century in an extended session for Australia A in Lucknow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cec1e71dd86b61ad4d12f75e6292662</guid></item><item><title>Animal advocates want WA to 'get on board' with phasing out greyhound racing amid welfare concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/wa-greyhound-racing-parliamentary-inquiry/105781496</link><description>Animal advocates call on the WA government to follow the lead of other jurisdictions and phase out greyhound racing, as a state parliamentary inquiry examines the sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d151b0111cbdf98135b0a72304ccd15</guid></item><item><title>Australia and PNG fail to clinch defence agreement, resorting to communique</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/australia-png-fail-defence-agreement-communique/105782424</link><description>A major defence treaty between Australia and Papua New Guinea has failed to get over the line today, with the countries resorting to signing a communique in lieu of the actual document.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d5916f8d88a6bb049ef9ef389165d8e</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk murder suspect appears in court by video from jail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/charlie-kirk-murder-suspect-appears-in-court-by-video-from-jail/105782372</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">358bbfc5a2557ea8a273c5a8fa4648ca</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters honoured for Black Summer efforts as CFA warns about fire season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/black-summer-five-years-on-albury-wodonga/105761592</link><description>Firefighters say they learnt a lot from the Black Summer bushfires, but fear Victorians have become complacent in preparations ahead of this fire season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fccaf6727b3b5a68b220b1fb5f86623b</guid></item><item><title>Khapra beetle, a threat to grains industry, discovered in imported nappy pants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/khapra-beetle-found-in-imported-nappy-pants-threatens-grains/105782306</link><description>Authorities are investigating how khapra beetle, the number-one-priority pest for the grains industry, entered Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c65ef8036bcd15cd64dcb1342bb737aa</guid></item><item><title>Does the damning planning report mean the end for Hobart's Macquarie Point stadium?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/is-hobart-stadium-now-dead-explainer/105780834</link><description>The Tasmanian Planning Commission described the Hobart stadium as a "singular, large, bulky monolith" with "optimism bias" in the government's cost-benefit figures. What does this mean for the stadium?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6d2b782c8ad36854242ff8269a71dd8</guid></item><item><title>Albanese has found out nailing down Pacific agreements is harder than expected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/papua-new-guinea-defence-treaty-delays/105783902</link><description>Anthony Albanese was meant to emerge from his recent flurry of Pacific diplomacy holding no fewer than two major agreements — instead he's returning home conspicuously empty-handed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef894cba91b42943ab469518f13e2d11</guid></item><item><title>Australia's first Aboriginal parliamentarian Neville Bonner commemorated with bronze sculpture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/first-indigenous-parliamentarian-neville-bonner-bronze-sculpture/105784526</link><description>Neville Bonner is honoured as Australia's first Indigenous parliamentarian.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f34625e3694dce1ffe76963cc385cf62</guid></item><item><title>WA government minister John Carey has revealed he has donated sperm to assist and support couples in experiencing the joy of parenthood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/wa-government-minister-john-carey-has-revealed-he/105785740</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9b035aa4bafdf7463217d1986b535b9</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout makes his senior debut at the World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/gout-gout-makes-his-senior-debut/105786306</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a6f67c414742d7e07f12c1c5287ed55</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout finishes third in 200m heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/gout-gout-finishes-third-in-200m-heat/105786314</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d8312214b2b9a31a74786f0c79c4763</guid></item><item><title>Coal miner Anglo American confirms job cuts in Brisbane, Bowen Basin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/anglo-american-confirms-more-qld-coal-job-losses/105784432</link><description>Mining giant Anglo American confirms job cuts in Brisbane and the Bowen Basin in the wake of BHP Mitsubishi Alliance axing 750 workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2c2ffd3fcd4ff63bb350e73f18ebbc1</guid></item><item><title>ASX slips amid Santos sell-off, weak jobs data and 2035 emissions target — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/asx-markets-business-live-news-sep18-2025/105786834</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate remains steady at 4.2 per cent in August with a decline in full-time employment that drove the overall drop in employment numbers, according to ABS.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c9b52757d4c8bed330dd9676c5f85da</guid></item><item><title>Australia loses second ODI to India by record runs margin ahead of Women's Cricket World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/india-hands-australia-biggest-odi-defeat-on-world-cup-eve/105786766</link><description>A 102-run thumping, the biggest loss by runs for Australia's women's team, sets up a thrilling ODI series decider in India ahead of the Cricket World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">681ebe3c21776dc5fc833ede22b42e3d</guid></item><item><title>WA coal phase-out uncertainty amid Bluewaters power station closure backflip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/wa-coal-phaseout-uncertain-amid-energy-grid-upgrade-plan/105788864</link><description>Efforts by WA's government to force the premature closure of a privately owned coal plant appear to be unravelling after the market operator backed the power station to keep running towards the end of the decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4f55f2cbe6604ced891de18ea6af73a</guid></item><item><title>The Albanese government has learned from the last major climate commitment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/2035-target-energy-debate-power-prices/105787072</link><description>The government is keenly aware that the cost of the transition is a sensitive issue, which is why the prime minister was flanked not just by his climate minister but also his treasurer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb04f44e27c2583896465cd35dce2ecb</guid></item><item><title>Police officer found not guilty of assault during shopping centre scuffle at Batemans Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/police-officer-not-guilty-assault-batemans-bay-shopping-centre/105775816</link><description>A New South Wales police officer is found not guilty of using unreasonable force while removing three girls and a woman from a scuffle at a shopping centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c14d987edba1b9dfa103c7bd81c6de2</guid></item><item><title>Independent advice spells out mammoth task ahead for government to reach 2035 target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/the-task-ahead-to-reach-2035-emissions-target/105789538</link><description>Getting to even the bottom end of the government's 62 to 70 per cent emissions reduction target by 2035 will require drastic increases to solar and wind power capacity, electric vehicle take-up and an extension of the safeguard mechanism, according to the Climate Change Authority.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">112c61869ecf0e96b28c94212500d843</guid></item><item><title>After deadly floods in Bali, its people want answers. Many are blaming overtourism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/bali-overtourism-blamed-in-wake-of-deadly-floods/105785674</link><description>Unexpected and deadly flooding rocked Bali last week at a scale many had never experienced before. In the wake of this disaster, the search for answers has begun.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">744d51865bef7cb34f9b946d580e8498</guid></item><item><title>First Guardian, Shield superannuation disasters expose deep flaws in Australia's $4.3 trillion retirement system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/first-guardian-shield-collapse-asic-and-superannuation-flaws/105783328</link><description>The failed First Guardian and Shield schemes have cost about 12,000 Australians more than $1 billion in retirement savings and exposed deep flaws in how Australia's $4.3 trillion superannuation sector is regulated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b80687a0c984dcbca73fbbe0b5a3dbb7</guid></item><item><title>Surprise La Niña hints at another wet and stormy Australian summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/la-nina-hints-at-wet-stormy-australian-summer/105790134</link><description>Australia's key drivers of weather variability are stacking up to produce another wet, severe-weather season, with an increased risk of flooding, thunderstorms and cyclones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a42ca16638c1124b410a58f0cccc3ecf</guid></item><item><title>Miranda Tapsell and Gwilym Lee show it 'takes a village' to raise a child in Top End Bub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/top-end-bub-miranda-tapsell-gwilym-lee/105775286</link><description>Miranda Tapsell and Gwilym Lee return to their characters from the hit movie, Top End Wedding, to take on parenthood in the TV series, Top End Bub.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6b3a94883d6882b00c7e6f5904787b6</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Albanese seizes on Ley's climate slip up — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/federal-politics-live-sept-19/105790890</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has seized on remarks made by Opposition Leader Sussan Ley about Australia's climate targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d8c53f5355ddd10031e0a3f823e1972</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout misses out on 200m final at World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/gout-gout-misses-out-on-200m-final-at-world-athletics-/105792462</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44814bf4d05e24efb9a86e9874126c57</guid></item><item><title>How Hawthorn can upset Geelong as the Hawks meet the Cats in 2025 AFL preliminary final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/afl-preliminary-final-preview-geelong-vs-hawthorn/105792398</link><description>With a plethora of options up forward, there's one issue the Hawks need to pay attention to out of their back half if they want to upset the Cats tonight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">690d853e61b84e53b4907310f22bd294</guid></item><item><title>Victoria Police arrest seven people over stabbing deaths of two boys at Cobblebank</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/victoria-police-arrest-seven-people-over-stabbing/105794330</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40d779dc059b3fc23e9d42dade8cdefc</guid></item><item><title>China urges Papua New Guinea not to exclude other countries after it signed 'Pukpuk' communique with Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/china-warns-papua-new-guinea-against-bilateral-deal-australia/105794018</link><description>China has urged Papua New Guinea not to sign any deal that might exclude or restrict third parties from cooperating with the Pacific nation, as Australia scrambles to clinch a landmark defence treaty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad04d0391ea73681a5f0351d55692b32</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins hints at Ashes strategy amid recovery from back injury with 'starting aim' of playing in all five Tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/ashes-pat-cummins-australia-england-back-injury/105794594</link><description>As the men's Ashes approaches, the Australian captain reveals his hopes for taking part in the five-Test series against England as he steps up his injury recovery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cfd72c66626cbf51c7aab8346b10585</guid></item><item><title>Hakyung Lee, mother accused of killing children, had a 'disease of the mind', defence expert tells court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/hakyung-lee-suitcase-murders-auckland-new-zealand/105781562</link><description>Hakyung Lee has been charged with murdering her children and has pleaded not guilty by reason of insanity after leaving their bodies in an Auckland storage facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">690cb00a0c2ca94e57c34909bfc58001</guid></item><item><title>All the latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/all-the-latest-financial-news/105796416</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6301e2bdeedf208ea5d5c5a791f35a27</guid></item><item><title>Optus CEO apologises to customers impacted by major network outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/optus-ceo-apologises-to-customers-impacted-by/105796546</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76fd1e56e640c3fcc4ec93132683da1d</guid></item><item><title>Optus CEO confirms three deaths during network outage affecting emergency calls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/optus-ceo-confirms-three-deaths-during-network/105796530</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2616d41c37b08dbe3f6b1464bddea5b</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the Optus outage which disrupted triple-zero calls, linked to three deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/what-we-know-about-optus-network-outage/105796618</link><description>It's been two days since three people died after a devastating Optus outage caused hundreds of emergency calls to fail, but information about the incident remains scarce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81d841cfe097dc82a144e78eb4423953</guid></item><item><title>Investigation of eye-maker's online presence reveals multiple red flags</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/jack-mcdonald-ocularist-website-warning-signs/105788574</link><description>A reverse-image search of ocularist Jack McDonald's website shows that receptionist "Nadia" also appears on a dentistry blog and is known as "Donna" on a self-help guru's site. It's just one of the red flags that ABC NEWS Verify spotted during its investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d081d56d6116ad09be5333b0e23b73bc</guid></item><item><title>Collingwood and Brisbane meet again, two years on from classic 2023 grand final, for tantalising rematch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/afl-preliminary-final-collingwood-brisbane-preview/105793028</link><description>The 2023 grand final will go down as one of the best deciders in AFL history, and though the stakes are only marginally lower two years on, the numbers suggest Collingwood and Brisbane's 2025 preliminary final could be another classic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ec81c3cb39b858091335eeff1f3c10e</guid></item><item><title>Storm damage sees shark net installation delay at Sydney's Shark Beach in Nielsen Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/shark-net-installation-delay-at-sydney-shark-beach-neilsen-park/105794772</link><description>Shark Beach in Sydney's east is seasonally netted with an enclosure to protect swimmers from sharks during Sydney's warmer months — but for the upcoming school holidays, it is unlikely the nets will be installed in time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fb506200ed1eacf664848d3c53c5964</guid></item><item><title>Chelsea FC Women's star Sam Kerr presented with special football to mark 100 goals for club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/like-a-new-person-sam-kerr-all-smiles-after-comeback-goal/105797260</link><description>Sam Kerr is honoured with a special football to mark her 100 goals for Chelsea — and she can't stop smiling since the landmark strike.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52628ebbe474caa569cc4274ed7dde0b</guid></item><item><title>One-tray honey chicken wings are an easy family dinner - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/one-tray-sticky-chicken-wings/105658174</link><description>It’s easy to make these irresistibly sticky wings that will have you licking your fingers and reaching for more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b49e38fcb0cc57c3220c789ba5301301</guid></item><item><title>Canada beats New Zealand 34-19 to reach Women's Rugby World Cup final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/canada-dazzles-to-end-new-zealand-women-rugby-world-cup/105797400</link><description>A changing of the guard in women's rugby union as two-time defending world champions New Zealand is beaten for the first time at the tournament since 2014 by a brilliant Canadian side.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db955f9919a07cd55204d1ec6a7e244c</guid></item><item><title>UN says there's evidence organised crime scam centres are moving from South-East Asia into new frontier of the Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/organised-crime-scam-centres-move-into-pacific-united-nations/105775972</link><description>As scam centres run by organised crime find it harder to operate in South-East Asia, evidence emerges of them moving into the Pacific and setting up lucrative operations estimated to net billions each year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb89464594316563fc34dc56a716880e</guid></item><item><title>Antinatalists say human suffering, and climate change, makes having children unethical. Are they right?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/antinatalism-child-free-climate-change-human-suffering-baby/105695328</link><description>Elon Musk believes the collapsing birth rate is humanity's biggest danger. But antinatalists argue having kids is little more than a procreational Ponzi scheme, and the risks are real.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28999cb939ddfbe63b4a8339d72f435e</guid></item><item><title>Asia's protests grew from social media where misinformation also spread</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/nepal-indonesia-gen-z-social-media-misinformation/105779038</link><description>These movements may be separated by time, distance and language, but they were all born on social media, led by a new generation of activists fed up with the old systems of corruption and nepotism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">553dda439e393b87eb7b6bc4eff754a9</guid></item><item><title>What makes China confident enough to ban microchips made by US firm Nvidia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/what-makes-china-confident-to-ban-nvdia-microchips/105795486</link><description>Beijing's decision this week to ban Chinese companies from using microchips made by US firm Nvidia indicates the country is increasingly confident about replacing them with domestically produced chips, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c451e4e0710bc1516100c22ae7e23289</guid></item><item><title>Pirate attacks and sea robberies surge in key South-East Asian shipping lane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/piracy-sea-robberies-rise-malacca-strait-asia/105736740</link><description>Piracy and sea robberies are increasing in the strategic straits of Malacca and Singapore, which could have implications for Australian imports and exports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2b3b37fb5cc2fee69c406b2aa0ccdc5</guid></item><item><title>Scrubs is getting a reboot just in time for the hospital procedural revival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/scrubs-reboot-the-pitt-cheat-sheet/105793612</link><description>In a sea of hospital-based TV, long-running sitcoms Scrubs is often highlighted as one of the most realistic options. Now the reboot has been confirmed, and off the back of The Pitt’s big Emmy wins, we look back at the beloved show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f7cc2efbfa7b3a4841ebb5cb0fb4b85</guid></item><item><title>Jay MacAskill and his daughters — Skylah and Ava — are building a strong bond over a new found love of skateboarding.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/jay-builds-skate-family-with-two-daughters/105795194</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bf33bd10464222df6899d961b643aff</guid></item><item><title>Tough times in Wagga Wagga as young tennis stars chase grand slam dreams</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/wagga-wagga-young-tennis-stars-chase-grand-slam-dreams/105782764</link><description>Cara Korhonen played on Rod Laver Arena when she was 10 years of age and is putting her blood, sweat and tears into setting foot on there again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f95f37d9c572b37b64f39f73603da74</guid></item><item><title>Women celebrate vintage glam, self-love and healthy body image with pin-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/women-embrace-modern-pin-up-culture/105574140</link><description>Women are embracing modern pin-up culture as a way to express confidence and joy in their own skin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccb73a345a28b69e567f342e489c58be</guid></item><item><title>The Adelaide Crows have been the powerhouse of the AFLW. Now they are being challenged</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/aflws-rapid-evolution-has-been-a-double-edged-sword-for-crows/105798110</link><description>The AFLW's rapid evolution has been a double-edged sword for Adelaide, which is the most successful club in competition history, having won three of the eight premierships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fca7baecebf0b1b986bd2de9e15eea87</guid></item><item><title>Government has not set 2035 renewables target, downplays 90 per cent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/government-yet-to-set-2035-renewables-target/105798906</link><description>In New York for the UN summit, Energy Minister Chris Bowen declines to offer a renewable energy target for 2035 after the Climate Change Authority projected more than 90 per cent would be needed to hit its recommended emissions target.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4880a6213f11733719ca49464957e58</guid></item><item><title>Life on Aboriginal reserve remembered by Carnarvon traditional owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/aboriginal-reserve-memories-carnarvon-traditional-owners/105510728</link><description>In 1975, an anthropologist wrote his thesis on Carnarvon's rich Aboriginal reserve. Decades later, traditional owners revisit the work to contribute to "big truth-telling" documentary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecf8bb607751e84f71648e4dfa5cd44a</guid></item><item><title>Explaining Aussie driving culture to make roads safer for recent arrivals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/safe-driving-temporary-migrants-short-stay-visa-roads/105752446</link><description>Driving a car or riding a bike may be essential for temporary migrants studying or working in Australia, but hook turns, wombat crossings, and roundabouts can be unfamiliar territory. Here are some locals working to change that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7459dc32dfaf72a6f90efe2c1755b962</guid></item><item><title>How to clean out your wardrobe as the seasons change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/how-to-spring-clean-wardobe-clean-out/105780140</link><description>It's the kind of task that can seem overwhelming, but the change of season is the perfect opportunity to review what's in your wardrobe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf9c7f0a36323b3457588962f5d0b0b0</guid></item><item><title>Optus CEO confirms further customer report calls, service outage at NSW-SA border.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/optus-ceo-confirms-further-customer-report-calls,/105799496</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99f2ad74ac543864780c38476c5a3384</guid></item><item><title>Penrith's win over Canterbury was a reminder there is no team like them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/panthers-bulldogs-nrl-finals-cleary-galvin-too/105799368</link><description>Canterbury is a team built in Penrith's image, but the Panthers served Canterbury a stark reminder that there can be only one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43391fdd3b75eadfd140d1ee7f293931</guid></item><item><title>Australia formally recognises state of Palestine as Anthony Albanese arrives in US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australia-formally-recognises-state-of-palestine/105799238</link><description>The historic decision foreshadowed last month has now become a reality, as Australia moves with Canada and the United Kingdom to join the growing list of countries to recognise Palestinian sovereignty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f7f36cbe6b5b1fbaaf3e78efd2951a2</guid></item><item><title>Can recognising the state of Palestine achieve a two-state solution as Israel continues bombing Gaza?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australia-recognises-state-of-palestine-two-state-solution/105799276</link><description>While the Israel Defense Forces bomb Gaza and bulldoze the West Bank for settlements, moves to recognise Palestine in pursuit of a two-state solution may appear like something of a sick joke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfa3467335da07f9ce07cf8e87421ac9</guid></item><item><title>Is artificial intelligence overhyped or is AI the 'fourth industrial revolution'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/is-ai-the-fourth-industrial-revolution/105790912</link><description>It's estimated 30,000 people are working in the AI industry in Australia, and fanfare is growing with start-ups tapping into billions of dollars of venture capital. Yet there are concerns about hype and a lack of regulation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26daac2bce5f986abcbf545a3ec82df2</guid></item><item><title>Older Australians to pay up to $50/hour for basic care at home under aged care changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/older-australians-to-pay-for-showers-under-home-care-changes/105796118</link><description>Older Australians entering the aged care system will have to pay for "non-clinical" services such as showers and help with medication under wide-ranging changes taking effect in November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fad2ebda86259a9a52aff0b346c39071</guid></item><item><title>Gene editing is being sold on the promise of healthier babies — but what are the ethical concerns?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/ethics-of-gene-editing-designer-babies/105496228</link><description>The race to advance gene editing tech continues, spurred on by starry-eyed Silicon Valley investors, entrepreneurs and even pronatalists. But it is still deeply controversial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">073c888cabd844776c0f78ddf6d9f91a</guid></item><item><title>Brownlow Medal 2025 — when is it, how to watch and who are the favourites for AFL's best-and-fairest award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-medal-2025-explainer-how-to-watch-who-might-win/105799236</link><description>The AFL's big night is here, as the league's best and fairest player is honoured with the Brownlow Medal. Here is everything you need to know about the big event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a533b478e86cba0a5d23c3da7fd118e4</guid></item><item><title>The government says its 2035 climate targets are achievable but mathematics suggests a different story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/climate-target-2035-2050-carbon-emissions-global-warming/105799080</link><description>The problem with an emissions reduction target is that its mere existence implies it is achievable and that if we do achieve it, we will be fine. The truth is more complex.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55dd3a3450e5da05cd2e7e786ef836f8</guid></item><item><title>In an Australian first, chip company recycles leftover cooking oil into packaging to reduce emissions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/chip-packet-oil-recycling-snackbrands-australia-viva-energy/105788230</link><description>Hundreds of litres of used cooking oil are disposed of every year as a by-product of making some of Australia's favourite snacks, like chips — but one company is trialling a method to reduce waste.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ff59f9aa179f301bfc7d9f1c6d8480c</guid></item><item><title>Dementia-linked protein lower in people reporting vigorous exercise, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/how-exercise-can-reduce-risk-of-developing-dementia/105783238</link><description>Scientists have, for the first time, linked exercise with a particular protein in the blood that is associated with brain health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1927e46b141094965051ff5e6c95b5c2</guid></item><item><title>Australia has been free of endemic measles since 2014. Could that change?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/measles-cases-on-the-rise-australia-explainer/105799284</link><description>So far this year, there have been 121 measles notifications across Australia — the highest number since 2019, when there were 284 notifications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cebd25abdddc63773dde66358f7395f</guid></item><item><title>Pensioners left 'waiting to die' in regional Victoria as specialist healthcare costs rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/pensioners-cant-afford-specialist-health-care-costs-victoria/105713416</link><description>Victorian pensioner Eddie Rushforth says he does not know whether his bowel cancer has returned because he cannot afford the cost of the scans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2bc72941774215310fee9627fe967a3</guid></item><item><title>Murray River flood may not be to blame for SA algal bloom, Senate inquiry hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/murray-river-flood-link-to-algal-bloom-questioned-senate-inquiry/105733848</link><description>Scientists have questioned the link between the 2022-23 floods and South Australia's ongoing harmful algal bloom, despite the state government listing it as one of the three primary causes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e88db31a70e241e8774222579aebebdc</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr earns a standing ovation in home game return as Chelsea defeats Leicester 1-0 in WSL</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/wsl-sam-kerr-returns-home-to-standing-ovation-in-chelsea/105800446</link><description>Chelsea fans stand and applaud Australian superstar Sam Kerr in her long-awaited return to Kingsmeadow in the WSL.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da70332495135e59ba3b6176d03d566d</guid></item><item><title>World leaders are meeting at the UN General Assembly this week. Here are four things to watch for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/united-nations-general-assembly-what-to-watch-for-in-new-york/105800440</link><description>World leaders are arriving in New York for the UN General Assembly — and for the first time, Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is among them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">761958b8abcd8c47c96a8d78d674b211</guid></item><item><title>Optus triple-0 outage investigation underway as minister warns of 'consequences'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/optus-investigation-triple-0-outage/105800556</link><description>The Australian Media and Communications Authority begins its investigation into the Optus triple-0 outage that has been linked to multiple deaths in South Australia and Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64e8d943c326b70c38e9b095d514da19</guid></item><item><title>Queensland CHO on state's measles outbreak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/queensland-cho-on-states-measles-outbreak/105801130</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">651d78f7433d688b560566682a3c8124</guid></item><item><title>Australians can't trust the triple-0 network after 13-hour Optus outage results in deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/optus-triple-0-failure-analysis/105800592</link><description>The Optus failure is shocking and no doubt a massive fine and other sanctions could be on the way, but experts say it raises further questions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2edd7465f8b9851c69c1b7efadb1f5f1</guid></item><item><title>Easy and healthy dinner recipes for spring</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/easy-healthy-recipes-for-spring-dinners/105660408</link><description>If you're looking for light dinner ideas as the weather warms up, we have plenty of easy options. Think veggie-filled frittatas and beef taco bowls with a few healthy swaps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c28e2a7be5345c5402fc685acca89162</guid></item><item><title>Shalom House drug rehab centre CEO Peter Lyndon-James to step down over immigration views</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/peter-lyndon-james-steps-down-shalom-house-ceo/105801198</link><description>The head of a controversial WA drug rehabilitation service says he will resign so he can speak out against "mass migration".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f37d78dd839c3af15e6c8564d4e771f2</guid></item><item><title>Is AI impacting your career or life plans? Has its rapid rise got you rethinking your future? The ABC wants to hear from you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/ai-artificial-intelligence-future-job-career-impact/105762606</link><description>Whether you’re a student halfway through a degree or a mid-career manager planning the next five years, artificial intelligence (AI) is reshaping lives across the country. If you've been feeling its effects, the ABC wants to hear from you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc9fb0b057b73e053ee1ce795957b20a</guid></item><item><title>Court hears details of final hours of murdered children as Hakyung Lee murder trial nears end</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/hakyung-lee-trial-week-three/105801212</link><description>Hakyung Lee admits killing her children but claims she is not guilty by reason of insanity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8bb6b299ff32e2539915e7831b1952d</guid></item><item><title>Nasal spray flu vaccine becomes available for young SA children next year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/nasal-spray-flu-vaccine-for-children-in-south-australia/105801696</link><description>Three-year-old Clive has a brain injury after contracting influenza B. His mother is urging others to be immunised as SA announces it will make a nasal spray vaccination available to young children next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3127ec54f20dbb0732907c3206a26170</guid></item><item><title>Paper Australia sues Victorian government for $402 million over timber supply failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/paper-australia-sues-victorian-government-timber-supply-failure/105666676</link><description>Paper Australia alleges the state government failed to provide enough raw materials for its Maryvale mill, causing substantial loss and damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3966e123ebc206895cb857b760514b64</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos undecided on halves combination ahead of prelim final against Penrith</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/hunt-on-for-broncos-as-mam-mind-games-begin/105803392</link><description>Brisbane coach Michael Maguire continues to experiment with his halves combinations on Monday as Ezra Mam takes another key step towards a return from injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94b206b4a39973e74852b877af401757</guid></item><item><title>Potato mop-top virus detected in Victoria for first time, industry says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/mop-top-potato-virus-detected-in-victoria/105802514</link><description>The infected potato seeds, transported from Tasmania to Victoria, were found in cold storage and none have been planted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0acc254b768995af9724c767cc070527</guid></item><item><title>Endangered Littlejohn's tree frog finally bred in captivity amid habitat threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/endangered-littlejohns-tree-frog-finally-bred-in-captivity/105799502</link><description>Scientists have achieved a breakthrough in their work to save the Littlejohn's tree frog species which only exists in three isolated regions in New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">242f7f349ef09c427b4a7b8724bf30e1</guid></item><item><title>Brownlow Medal 2025: All the best fashion looks from AFL's night of nights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-red-carpet-wrap/105802436</link><description>Just after the fashion from this evening's Brownlow Medal? We've got you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8922390581e8430e878c1aa384dd8e2d</guid></item><item><title>Matt Rowell wins 2025 Brownlow Medal as Gold Coast star beats out Nick Daicos and Bailey Smith</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-medal-2025-live-blog-daicos-smith-dawson-rowell/105798968</link><description>Matt Rowell becomes the second Gold Coast player to win the prestigious AFL award, as a questionable voting call regarding Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera leaves the room stunned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08247d0fedaa413c59c8aea7818c6570</guid></item><item><title>Leopard sharks recorded mating by researcher in rare event off New Caledonia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/leopard-sharks-mating-rare-event-new-caledonia/105803858</link><description>A Sunshine Coast marine biologist has captured unique footage of two male sharks mating with a female in waters off New Caledonia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d272a5e23486cc628261c514c7180fe</guid></item><item><title>Latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/latest-financial-news/105804002</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a2a0a2b0118f619ddf3cb8e2061e8e4</guid></item><item><title>Non-profit multiple sclerosis organisation MS Society SA &amp; NT in voluntary administration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/ms-society-sa-nt-voluntary-administration/105803788</link><description>Non-profit organisation MS Society SA &amp; NT, which supports almost 3,000 clients living with multiple sclerosis, has gone into voluntary administration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e24b724079885d2734e6959f8fc726da</guid></item><item><title>Ley writes to Republicans vowing to revoke Palestine recognition ahead of Albanese's UN address</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/albanese-un-palestine-address-ley-republican-letter/105803078</link><description>In an unorthodox move, Opposition Leader Sussan Ley writes to a group of Republicans reassuring the Coalition would withdraw recognition of Palestine, ahead of a major United Nations address to be delivered by the prime minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98f3481476a06e3c9782e1032f1893d8</guid></item><item><title>Multiple UK charities cut ties with Duchess of York over email to Jeffrey Epstein</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/uk-charity-dumps-sarah-duchess-of-york-epstein/105804606</link><description>The decisions come after British media reported that the Duchess had described the disgraced financier as a "steadfast, generous and supreme friend" in a 2011 letter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c20e28d80c8779c49ad3426a6872fc0</guid></item><item><title>Artificial intelligence to dominate Australia's future economy, but who will reap the benefits?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/australias-future-economy-will-be-dominated-by-ai/105802364</link><description>From robots to supercomputers, artificial intelligence is set to become an integral part of the Australian economy, with tens of billions in benefits to be gained … but for whom?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12e16358f1d06001f22c8315b12c996c</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar junta revoking citizenship of actors, singers and other celebrities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/myanmar-celebrities-left-stateless-after-criticising-junta/105787574</link><description>Myanmar's military junta is using citizenship as a weapon, targeting political opponents, activists and even celebrities who speak out against the regime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df5568a6e89118d9a0c2db08ec61854c</guid></item><item><title>Three Australians lay dead as investors of Optus's parent company Singtel were buying up its shares</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/three-australians-lay-dead-investors-buy-up-shares/105803922</link><description>The actions by Optus management in the hours following a series of failed attempts by its customers to call triple-0 raises questions about the telco's fitness to operate in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24e9f1bc9c2b8e3b2e1bdab5ae2ccb23</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: 'No doubt' Trump and Albanese will meet soon, acting PM says — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/federal-politics-live-sept-23/105803300</link><description>Richard Marles says he has no doubt the prime minister and US president will meet soon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2770399e32c9257f91ff03c40ec31e7</guid></item><item><title>Calls for long-term plan to address Tasmania's 'concerning' school attendance level</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/tasmania-school-attendance-level-concerns/105770010</link><description>Australia's school attendance levels have dropped since the pandemic but education experts are particularly concerned about Tasmania — a state with an already notoriously low literacy rate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81f75b3e7bbb3bc0d144997482f5d7c9</guid></item><item><title>The public hospital patients who ended up paying abortion clinics for miscarriage care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/qld-mater-miscarriage-care-catholic-hospital-abortion/105781022</link><description>Brisbane women have told the ABC they paid an abortion clinic for their chosen miscarriage care rather than getting it at their large public hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34accc25ffd487a2e3cb32cdcd8a582d</guid></item><item><title>Moment Matt Rowell announced as 2025 Brownlow medallist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/moment-matt-rowell-announced-as-2025-brownlow-medallist/105805032</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4336530cc59f3c10ad2c74d7b058cebe</guid></item><item><title>Matt Rowell delivers Brownlow Medal acceptance speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/matt-rowell-delivers-brownlow-medal-acceptance-speech/105805042</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2002bf4ac5caada0dc95c1432e61966</guid></item><item><title>Sustainable Timber Tasmania mistake 'compromised' arrests of logging protesters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/tasmanian-logging-company-mistake-compromised-arrests/105802784</link><description>New documents show some of the reasons why charges against a number of forest protesters were dropped in Tasmania, with police now assisting the company to stop it from happening in future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fab7148986a7bada52644003a03f11e</guid></item><item><title>Turtle strandings and soft-shell syndrome cases fall as seagrass beds recover</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/soft-shell-syndrome-in-turtles-decline-as-seagrass-beds-recover/105789276</link><description>Soft-shell syndrome had been devastating green sea turtle numbers since flood events began impacting their seagrass food source in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af2746d8c73bc7e2cae2f8fde2fd2c13</guid></item><item><title>Doctors concerned easily accessible illegal cigarettes are causing smoking rates to increase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/act-easy-access-to-illegal-cigarettes-seeing-high-smoking-rates/105803450</link><description>Doctors say smoking rates are at levels they haven't seen in a decade due to easy access to illegal cigarettes that are a "quarter of the price" of legal cigarettes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">150ad4af75b20ef2e67ba79a215e5c20</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel reinstated after hundreds of stars back free speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/jimmy-kimmel-back-on-air-disney-says/105805048</link><description>US comedian Jimmy Kimmel's late-night show will be reinstated after being taken off air, following remarks he made referencing right-wing activist Charlie Kirk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">868e8a8d3b8279fa34a833b46463ee3f</guid></item><item><title>Man Ray and Max Dupain's photography on display together for the first time in new Heide exhibition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/man-ray-max-dupain-photography-exhibition-heide-melbourne/105790024</link><description>Surrealist photographer Man Ray revolutionised 20th-century visual culture. In Australia, a local photographer was exploring similar territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">318bfee371103375fcc23430352eccfd</guid></item><item><title>Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera being robbed overshadowed Matt Rowell's Brownlow Medal win, and could change the voting process forever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/afl-matt-rowell-nasiah-moment-brownlow-medal-voting-analysis/105804320</link><description>It is not often that the AFL's night of nights gets hijacked by a moment not involving the winner of the Brownlow Medal. This is exactly what took place when Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera was seemingly robbed in broad daylight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dfdde5b406fc68132f52c264d89b4c9</guid></item><item><title>Experts say paracetamol safe for pregnancy, no proof for autism link made by Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/trump-administration-links-autism-to-paracetamol-tga-says-safe/105803566</link><description>Australia's medicines regulator says paracetamol remains safe to use during pregnancy despite Donald Trump's administration linking its use to an increased risk of autism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9575c0f36522e77b42eccc5329990b40</guid></item><item><title>Darwin dancer with dislocated knee left waiting for ambulance for six hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/darwin-dancer-left-waiting-for-ambulance-over-six-hours/105803840</link><description>A 20-year-old dancer was left waiting for an ambulance for more than six hours after dislocating her knee during a competition in the Darwin CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e282340089a62fe29ce12b5bbe0cdbb8</guid></item><item><title>Ousmane Dembélé wins men's Ballon d'Or as Aitana Bonmatí joins elite club featuring Lionel Messi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/football-ousmane-dembele-ballon-d-or-bonmati-salah-yamal/105805184</link><description>French forward Ousmane Dembélé caps off a dream season with football's most prestigious individual award as Spain's Aitana Bonmatí continues to add to her legacy as one of the best women's players of all time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e69e7f3a1af9871429f380161b57a49e</guid></item><item><title>Chronic pain sufferer donates knitted goods for babies in intensive care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/thousands-of-donated-knitted-items-for-premmie-babies/105762552</link><description>Knitting has become an outlet for Port Stephens woman Kim Franks, who is mostly housebound after a diagnosis of debilitating psoriasis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f81a9667430db32dc168a444fd30d209</guid></item><item><title>Deeming rates have increased after a five-year freeze. Here's how that could impact pension payments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/deeming-rate-freeze-ends-impact-on-pension-payments/105798966</link><description>The changes impact people on Centrelink payments who earn an income from financial assets, but pensioners are the biggest group to be affected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2a6081a58d1e888118022ad40f5fcfd</guid></item><item><title>As a doctor I'm choosing self-care over resilience</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/doctor-choosing-self-care-over-resilience/105728568</link><description>As a doctor who advocates for self-care, it took me a surprisingly long time to look after myself. Now I'm trying to be a good example for my patients and other doctors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96d1bd7d0cdf02ba7b181e19ec630701</guid></item><item><title>Childcare boss unsure if bonuses were docked over rise in safety breaches, inquiry told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/nsw-childcare-inquiry-ceo-questioned-over-bonuses/105805562</link><description>The CEO of Affinity Education Group appears at a state parliamentary inquiry into the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3ece1d8ebaeed33106cbc2f0f9066d1</guid></item><item><title>Experts say it is safe to use paracetamol during pregnancy and Trump's autism declaration is 'baseless'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/taking-paracetamol-during-pregnancy-does-not-cause-autism/105806092</link><description>Donald Trump's advice that pregnant women should limit the use of paracetamol in pregnancy has been criticised as "baseless". So what does it mean for you?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81c81571674ce6c676915af2ca81de9b</guid></item><item><title>Bill Gates pledges $US912 million to AIDS and malaria non-profit as US cuts funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/bill-gates-foundation-pleaged-millions-to-global-fund/105806406</link><description>The tech entrepreneur's announcement follows deep cuts from governments around the world, led by the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd0e8c660df290dadbcdf29a13957875</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Lions star Lachie Neale trains strongly and looks on track for a grand final spot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/neale-trains-as-lion-s-grand-final-return-hopes-gather-pace/105806698</link><description>The 31-year-old dual Brownlow medallist, who has been battling a calf injury, took part in training drills in front of 2,000 Brisbane fans at the team's Springfield home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c61b547c00f1a6df00fecccb68dde8b8</guid></item><item><title>ASIC accuses RACQ of misleading customers over insurance renewal notices in Federal Court action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/racq-insurance-premiums-regulator-action/105805622</link><description>The corporate watchdog alleges RACQ knowingly misled over 500,000 customers in insurance renewal notices since 2019.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f51ab0965ff2e6958953913e6360ca6b</guid></item><item><title>MS support agency MS Society SA &amp; NT outlines three-year losses, $2.5m debt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/ms-society-sa-nt-facing-millions-in-debt/105806282</link><description>Non-profit organisation MS Society SA &amp; NT, says it has debts of about $2.5 million and has been facing losses for three years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">170d075b7f4176d41d4a209cb5faf5bc</guid></item><item><title>Kevin Bacon on the importance of music, philanthropy and acting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/kevin-bacon-take-5-actor-music-philanthropy-interview/105793360</link><description>He's a prolific fixture on our screens who's famously six degrees from almost anyone. But Kevin Bacon is also a passionate musician and philanthropist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45104e05b24001759cca6f2985a81b97</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu plans to sign police deal with China while Nakamal pact with Australia is left hanging</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/china-vanuatu-police-agreement-equipment-training/105806934</link><description>Vanuatu declares it will sign a new policing agreement with China as the landmark Nakamal pact between Australia and the Pacific Island nation hangs in the balance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e015a5946bffafc3e5c33cd1d8fa895e</guid></item><item><title>Concerns 'off-brand' cigarettes easy to access and cheaper</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/concerns-off-brand-cigarettes-easy-to-access-and/105807734</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e1d889cc16fa1dfacac6368020592c5</guid></item><item><title>Optus triple-0 outage tragedy: What we know and how events unfolded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/timeline-on-optus-triple-0-outage-what-we-know/105805890</link><description>The first sign something was wrong came late on Friday afternoon. Now we have a clearer picture of how the triple-0 outage unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c548c42002e87e4dd015358e8d8279e9</guid></item><item><title>Unproven autism claims like Donald Trump's risk undoing decades of progress</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/trump-unproven-autism-claims-risk-undoing-decades-of-progress/105807344</link><description>The Trump administration's rhetoric only adds to the noise around autism and will make it harder for the community to feel understood and accepted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00fa47bf5ec49c44ed4dd1852e1689f4</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of bees swarm Wagga Wagga CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/thousands-of-bees-swarm-wagga-wagga-cbd/105808258</link><description>Thousands of bees appear without warning in the regional city, alarming locals and causing a commotion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27722e02bcf2c9eb1efacb7eed1b7299</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie's spray at 'muppet', 'coward' Liberal colleagues after post bemoaning loss of Aussie car making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/andrew-hastie-car-making-coward-muppet-liberals/105808280</link><description>Senior Liberal Andrew Hastie has taken aim at colleagues who questioned a social media post where he bemoaned the loss of Australian car making, calling them "nameless cowards" and "muppets".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa8f233e21c3cb087597a2e4648810dd</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm's Jahrome Hughes and Ryan Papenhuyzen return for NRL preliminary final against Cronulla</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/storm-jahrome-hughes-against-cronulla-broncos-panthers/105808480</link><description>Melbourne recall three big guns, led by star half Jahrome Hughes, as their NRL title hopes go on the line in Friday night's preliminary final against Cronulla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1926a9906773436f42474dc790c296f5</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105809052</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2291dde89e5f6f2e800c553bd2118818</guid></item><item><title>Hawthorn's Mabior Chol has three-match ban overturned at AFL tribunal as rough conduct charge dismissed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/hawthorn-mabior-chol-afl-tribunal-hearing/105808298</link><description>The AFL tribunal quashes Mabior Chol's three-match ban for rough conduct, finding he did not act unreasonably in his tackle which left Geelong's Tom Stewart concussed and out of this weekend's grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a927a04bec9e6ad920a7713d7f32bccf</guid></item><item><title>Denmark links drones at Copenhagen airport to hybrid attacks across Europe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/denmark-investigates-drone-activity-at-copenhagen-airport/105809166</link><description>Denmark links incident involving drones over its main airport to a series of recent suspected Russian drone incursions and other hybrid attacks across Europe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebee7e7802e9046c39907e2c6a3957b7</guid></item><item><title>Super Typhoon Ragasa lashes Taiwan, with at least 14 dead and 129 missing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/super-typhoon-ragasa-taiwan-dead-missing/105809264</link><description>The most powerful storm so far in 2025 is now heading towards the Chinese mainland, prompting widespread disruption and warnings of sea surges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e86c797982ae3107e7d7d8203132df06</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump uses United Nations speech to lay out the US's complaints with the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/united-nations-general-assembly-donald-trump-speech/105809190</link><description>Donald Trump uses a speech at the UN to criticise US allies' moves to recognise Palestine and chastise the international community over a range of other American grievances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">251d1ac533cc88fd01a9540772aff365</guid></item><item><title>Russia systematically torturing Ukrainian civilians, UN says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/russia-systematically-torturing-ukrainian-civilians-un-says/105809316</link><description>The report is based on detailed interviews with 215 former detainees captured since Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b3ec3854b230344943aa0ea9a1c50f</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese to meet Donald Trump in Washington next month, White House confirms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/trump-and-albanese-to-meet/105809460</link><description>The prime minister is expected to travel to Washington to hold talks with the US president on October 20.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c3bc2495519a8885ce870e5014596b8</guid></item><item><title>Incoming triple-0 reforms may not have helped prevent Optus failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/triple-0-reforms-may-not-have-helped-optus-failure/105807524</link><description>The federal government has yet to pass legislation to empower a new coordinator for the emergency services line, but experts say tougher conditions are needed on the telco itself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">196d665b157a51d6ce3440ca5be81bfc</guid></item><item><title>Record number of calls to poisons hotlines for children ingesting melatonin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/melatonin-poisons-hotline-kidshealth/105802406</link><description>The ABC has analysed data from poisons hotlines across the country, revealing almost 1,500 calls were made about children taking melatonin last year, a dramatic rise on previous figures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6379f1180fb83dd59536f7b7017c4f87</guid></item><item><title>Could artificial intelligence and a universal basic income eliminate 'meaningless jobs'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/will-we-need-a-universal-basic-income-to-deal-with-ai-job-losses/105747954</link><description>COVID showed just how "fragile" our economic security is. As artificial intelligence potentially takes jobs from humans, a universal basic income might be a solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5953e2ae7f84df41d0ff5021a284652b</guid></item><item><title>Ryan Routh faces life in prison after guilty verdict in Donald Trump assassination attempt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ryan-routh-guilty-of-donald-trump-assassination-attempt/105809490</link><description>A man accused of trying to assassinate Donald Trump at his Florida golf course last year has been found guilty on all charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0214a8b817cf4108f24678a4dba1f80a</guid></item><item><title>Australians are moving to Tasmania to escape climate change, but the island state is not immune</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/australians-moving-to-tasmania-to-escape-climate-change/105785996</link><description>Jack and Anna swapped the humidity of Queensland for chilly days in Tasmania, but is Tasmania really the climate refuge many think it is?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0ff7fbad477aed99626b4746b82c14c</guid></item><item><title>How climate change impacted the 2025 snow season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/climate-change-impacted-2025-snow-season/105808698</link><description>The general sentiment is Australia's ski resorts are coming to the end of a bumper snow season — but is this evaluation accurate, or just positive spin after the dismal 2023 and 2024 seasons?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d83586cda83a6d18a50afafa5ab2f844</guid></item><item><title>Dickie Bird, former English cricket umpire, dies aged 92</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/dickie-bird-former-english-cricket-umpire-dies-aged-92/105809586</link><description>One of international cricket's most recognised umpires is being remembered for his "fairness, humour and love of the game".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ea286fdda73733b0f123adaeb2b514e</guid></item><item><title>NT government open to subdividing purpose-built State Square Art Gallery in Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nt-government-open-to-state-square-art-gallery-subdivide-darwin/105807672</link><description>A leading figure in Australia's art world has criticised the Northern Territory government for considering splitting up the lease for a building designed as a major new art gallery, describing the plan as "pure madness".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cea270549341f3bb40e1fafe548161cf</guid></item><item><title>Video record of violence and racism at Purnim Bears, Noorat country football grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/violence-racism-of-80s-country-victoria-football-grand-final/105741080</link><description>The Purnim Bears were supposed to be the feel-good story of country football — a team uniting black and white communities. But their 1987 grand final was so violent it ended with their expulsion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">231bb9fc7a4848fb3114f306c75ce3e0</guid></item><item><title>England names squad to face Australia in men's Ashes series 2025/26</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/england-name-squad-to-face-australia-in-men-s-ashes-series/105809606</link><description>England will bring a strong pace bowling attack, but several members of the squad, including captain Ben Stokes, are under injury clouds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d0a0a9cfab837e21e9251c67e841c3</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine can win back all territory lost to Russia, Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ukraine-can-win-back-all-territory-lost-to-russia-trump-says/105809578</link><description>The US president criticised Russia on the sidelines of the UN General Assembly, saying it had been fighting "aimlessly" in a war that a "real military power" would have won in less than a week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51fff57c3ffcb071ce802513857b4a30</guid></item><item><title>Offshore wind pioneer Henrik Stiesdal says Australia can learn from Europe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/offshore-wind-pioneer-henrik-stiesdal-lessons-for-australia/105783010</link><description>A Danish clean energy pioneer says Australia is poised for success with offshore wind, but there are lessons it can learn from abroad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e8e43f8da41b1a8bb53cc06569e333e</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou 'excited' to defend his Europa League trophy with Nottingham Forest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ange-postecoglou-nottingham-forest-europa-league/105809674</link><description>Four months after leading Tottenham Hotspur to Europa League triumph in Bilbao, Ange Postecoglou has returned to Spain and UEFA's second-tier club competition with a new challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d7d5db2308c2c5b39a10ccc3cdf7870</guid></item><item><title>Unexplained lights in the sky sparks UAP chatter across much of Western Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/unexplained-uap-sightings-reported-across-midwest-wa/105803264</link><description>Perth Observatory says it has received reports of lights dancing in the sky across a significant part of WA's Midwest and Goldfields, with an explanation yet to be found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b4cb4ae36f5ab9e984491b519fa7152</guid></item><item><title>ASX falls ahead of inflation data, Optus to investigate triple-0 failure — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/asx-markets-business-live-news/105809708</link><description>Optus launches an independent review of last week's triple-0 failure, with chief executive Stephen Rue saying human error meant processes weren't followed during the outage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e7944a8068d04ed1894186577c1f7dc</guid></item><item><title>Purnim Bears and Noorat in the 1987 Grand Final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/lowres-hits-compile-purnim-bears/105809790</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">374e9b7e43683512d21efa87c2aa761e</guid></item><item><title>Australian speed skydiver hangs on to title of fastest woman in the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/natisha-dingle-wins-fai-world-cup-speed-skydiving-title/105805486</link><description>Jumping out of planes and freefalling at nearly 500 kilometres per hour is "addictive" for Queensland woman Natisha Dingle, who has just set a new Oceania speed record in the sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6dae41d360c4eeda58220eedaf6442a</guid></item><item><title>Queensland speed skydiver Natisha Dingle shows off her impressive skills.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/speed-skydiver-natisha-dingle-shows-off-her-impressive-skills/105807064</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c809122700c1bf91a2b261a16e110608</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's meeting with Trump matters for AUKUS and the role of the US in the Asia-Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/anthony-albanese-donald-trump-meeting/105801298</link><description>Trump clearly disagrees with Albanese on Palestine and the reality of climate change, but it's not on the scale of the beef he has with other countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1daf71c6599467c19439c0e23875de0e</guid></item><item><title>Warragul man knocks back dream job after NDIS funding for van rejected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ndis-rejects-van-man-needs-to-drive-to-dream-job/105762830</link><description>Josh Evans, who uses a wheelchair, had to turn down a job with the Bureau of Meteorology because he was unable to get NDIS funding for a vehicle to drive himself to work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21c25c4b57843d7697e914107db94243</guid></item><item><title>Artemis program on track to take astronauts around the Moon: NASA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nasa-artemis-program-on-track-to-take-people-to-the-moon/105809764</link><description>NASA's first crewed flight in its Artemis program — a trip around the Moon and back — is on track for launch in April 2026 and could potentially be moved up to February, the space agency says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87a63c967423b595bde610ff51e979b6</guid></item><item><title>Trump claims paracetamol link to autism. Five experts explain what's wrong with that statement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/what-the-experts-are-saying-about-paracetamol-use-lead-to-autism/105806230</link><description>Some leading Australian experts in medicine, autism research and obstetrics say the US president's claims are "a misreading of science," or at worst, "a misuse". Here's why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bffee58bd319bdb466db1eb8559f629b</guid></item><item><title>Why the legacy of the 2023 NRL grand final hangs over the Broncos and Panthers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/panthers-broncos-nrl-preliminary-final-grand-final-cleary/105809026</link><description>On Sunday, the Broncos and Panthers will face off in the finals for the first time since the 2023 grand final, but the memory of that night still hangs over both sides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad8624f8c74a64751af52bbcd1e11c56</guid></item><item><title>ABC ordered to pay $150,000 fine for unlawfully sacking journalist and presenter Antoinette Lattouf</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/antoinette-lattouf-costs-decision-in-abc-unlawful-termination/105810052</link><description>The judge ordered ABC to pay a fine of $150,000 for unlawfully sacking journalist and presenter Antoinette Lattouf for reasons including her political opinions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dad4cb7dec36a5f662b73fe15e33939</guid></item><item><title>Sandy Brondello axed by WNBA side New York Liberty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/sandy-brondello-axed-by-wnba-side-new-york-liberty/105810534</link><description>Australian basketball coach Sandy Brondello is let go by the New York Liberty after a disappointing first-round exit from the WNBA play-offs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a4504d3bbba4c100278133bdd4d6055</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann seeks funding to pay for legal representation over raids at his home in 2024</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/bruce-lehrmann-seeks-funds-for-legal-representation-over-raids/105809920</link><description>Former Liberal staffer Bruce Lehrmann launches Federal Court action seeking funding for legal representation at a National Anti-Corruption Commission hearing after raids on his home in June last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">749a230c4ad7fe395ea22940c47b8259</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fullback Andrew Kellaway ruled out of first Bledisloe Cup Test match against All Blacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/wallabies-andrew-kellaway-ruled-out-bledisloe-cup-all-blacks/105810670</link><description>Wallabies fullback Andrew Kellaway will miss Saturday's Bledisloe Cup Test match against the All Blacks in Auckland, ruled out with a calf strain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11b979e7ef790b13cc2880a8a193f4dd</guid></item><item><title>Canberra golf course redevelopments providing both much-needed housing and financial lifelines for struggling clubs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/golf-course-redevelopments-providing-housing-financial-lifelines/105799100</link><description>With the ACT government pushing for greater urban density, golf courses in inner Canberra suburbs are becoming attractive sites for redevelopment to provide much-needed housing and a way for struggling clubs to bolster their budgets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b488a99ab4311911d8fa6f87e596dc4c</guid></item><item><title>Denise Scott returns to new season of ABC show Mother and Son</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/denise-scott-returns-to-new-season-of-abc-show-mother-and-son/105810904</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e590ac7331c82e9d119b2a29cfa7bba9</guid></item><item><title>Gender-based violence services prepare for increased calls on AFL grand final weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/increased-rates-of-gender-based-violence-during-football-finals/105809996</link><description>Ahead of the AFL grand final, national violence prevention organisation Our Watch is calling for the sporting community to address the increased risk of violence facing women during football finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4d5c539ddee700b75c82661684fb340</guid></item><item><title>The forgotten Australian statesman who was key in the Israel-Palestine partition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/herbert-vere-evatt-and-the-israel-palestine-partition/105805464</link><description>Anthony Albanese formally recognised Palestinian statehood on the world stage this week, but about 78 years ago a lesser-known Australian was fighting for the creation of a Jewish state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0bebd1b1a8da5b3eef2af168ca318d3</guid></item><item><title>Optus parent company Singtel apologises for triple-0 outage linked to multiple deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/optus-singtel-apologises-for-triple-0-outage/105810296</link><description>Optus's parent company says it will "ensure a thorough investigation of this incident to prevent any future recurrence".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4603051f8c7a42c9b44e671ff971d0d</guid></item><item><title>Camp Mystic plans to reopen next summer, a year after floods killed 27</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/camp-mystic-plans-to-reopen-a-year-after-flood-deaths/105810114</link><description>Camp Mystic also announces plans for a memorial dedicated to "the lives of the campers and counsellors lost on July 4th".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">496ec39f957a1a61a68f959f6319b508</guid></item><item><title>Man behind iconic ABC TV programs, Graham White, dies aged 93</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/graham-white-abc-tv-and-radio-pioneer-dies-at-93/105806806</link><description>Graham White was a pioneer of Australian radio and television and played a key role in the creation of numerous television series, including A Big Country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54c9a84115c56f73f0923751c300a0e1</guid></item><item><title>When is the 2025 AFL grand final? Here's what time it starts and where to watch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/when-is-the-afl-grand-final-time-where-to-watch-explained/105809976</link><description>Wondering what time the AFL grand final starts and how you can watch it live? We've got you covered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b35be59cc10e4e0032348864c66bd1c7</guid></item><item><title>Despite past controversy, NSW Police commissioner Mal Lanyon has a strong backing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nsw-police-commissioner-mal-lanyon-premier-chris-minns-analysis/105810774</link><description>For newly-announced Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon, Wednesday morning would have been both one of his proudest moments, and his most uncomfortable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed72f9bcc7ce20d2d722b8b43d539719</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel returns, addressing Charlie Kirk and 'un-American' axing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/jimmy-kimmel-returns-thanking-supporters-speaks-to-free-speech/105808410</link><description>Despite the late-night host's return, several US ABC affiliates did not air the episode, excluding an estimated one-quarter of American households.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac8b78a8e557c0d2a91d42ed04e2eed</guid></item><item><title>Family suspects foul play in Noosa man Byron Dumschat's death in a Bali villa pool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/family-suspects-foul-play-in-bali-death-noosa-man-byron-dumschat/105809846</link><description>An Australian family is asking why Indonesian police allowed three Australian witnesses to return home without being interviewed after their 23-year-old son died on the Indonesian holiday resort island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4e8e32abe23c1a44f62c5e3f023e2a2</guid></item><item><title>Rape case against Bruce Lehrmann delayed after lawyer misses deadline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/bruce-lehrmann-rape-case-faces-more-delays-in-toowoomba/105811608</link><description>A judge says the process of a bid to stop a criminal rape case against former Liberal Party staffer Bruce Lehrmann proceeding has been "problematic" after his lawyer missed a key deadline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20b38956daedd1cd16f45a4769958aa6</guid></item><item><title>How #RedundancyDiaries are busting the stigma of being let go</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/busting-the-stigma-on-redundancy-by-sharing-online/105751880</link><description>Camille says being made redundant was hard, so she began sharing her experiences on TikTok hoping to help others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69e9a0930ebbcb9805519c817968e9ee</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's changed stance on Ukraine could be a challenge for Vladimir Putin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/donald-trump-ukraine-nato-comments-a-challenge-to-vladimir-putin/105810170</link><description>If Donald Trump actually means what he has just said — that NATO countries have a right to shoot down any Russian jets in their airspace — the US president may be contracting out a serious counteroffensive against Russian aggression to NATO countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c624737442bcb04137b18db123e6997</guid></item><item><title>Elon Musk's father, Errol Musk, accused of abusing five of his children over three decades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/errol-musk-elon-father-abuse-allegations/105810162</link><description>Multiple police reports, social workers and family members uncover the allegations against 79-year-old Errol Musk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b128f012c363aa69849c2a916828663b</guid></item><item><title>Mount Isa man charged with more than 70 child sex offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/mount-isa-man-charged-child-sex-offences/105811958</link><description>Police charge a 40-year-old man in Mount Isa and allege the offences occurred over 25 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f170f1084a78ce506347bb313d68dd8b</guid></item><item><title>Why did the UN escalator stop after Donald and Melania Trump stepped on it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/donald-melania-trump-escalator-teleprompter-un-marcon-call/105810256</link><description>Footage of the US president and his wife's reactions to the mishap was shared widely on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87fdb12fe7af401b7964018acf19bc5f</guid></item><item><title>Doctor who lost daughter to brain cancer receives grant in race to clinical trials</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/doctor-receives-grant-to-continue-brain-cancer-research/105810368</link><description>A professor who lost his daughter to brain cancer in 2018 is hopeful the research to find a cure in children is just five years away from clinical trials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc0272343034af8958b1ec9f51c4c20f</guid></item><item><title>Optus admits procedural failure before outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/optus-admits-procedural%C2%A0failure-before-outage%C2%A0/105811978</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b84c417046bbfc3acea16532e90a47cf</guid></item><item><title>What Hollywood gets wrong about music teachers on screen and how this impacts Australian teachers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/hollywood-portrayals-music-teachers-impact-australians/105803248</link><description>On-screen portrayals of music teachers like School Of Rock are full of cliches. Researchers say this might be stopping more Australians from taking up the profession.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9038906989bc595b89e85f5f95a323fd</guid></item><item><title>Optus to pay $100m fine, as crisis engulfing Australia's second biggest telco continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/optus-fined-100-million-for-sales-misconduct/105810174</link><description>In enforcing the fine today, the Federal Court's Justice Patrick O'Sullivan described the company's conduct as "extremely serious" and "appalling".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5b8ef086dc95c25b9efd2536b1850d6</guid></item><item><title>Tesla's self-driving technology is available in Australia, but road rules differ nationwide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/tesla-self-driving-technology-rules-differ-around-australia/105808104</link><description>Owners of late model Teslas can now access the company's self-driving technology. But the rules for how drivers can use it differ around the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">191d278dfe60ecd4ddb9b581b2e3730f</guid></item><item><title>AFL boss hints at Brownlow voting shake-up after Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/afl-boss-hits-at-brownlow-voting-shake-up-after-controversy/105812086</link><description>Voting for the Brownlow Medal has been a hot topic again in the wake of Monday night's count, with the AFL open to letting umpires have access to statistics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5d9c582b445942c6c11e6f1591db872</guid></item><item><title>Concerns Launceston City Council could give away Birchalls CBD site it bought for $8.8m</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/launceston-council-developer-plans-for-birchalls-building/105809796</link><description>Launceston City Council bought the historic Birchalls building for $8.8 million five years ago. A ratepayer association says it has learnt of a proposal to give it away "for nothing".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57bb6bb59e636d4105fd48c27dcdbaca</guid></item><item><title>Kindergarten cleaner who allegedly filmed children in bathroom faces more charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/kindergarten-cleaner-who-secretly-filmed-children-in-toilet/105811222</link><description>Prosecutors have flagged more potential charges for the Victorian kindergarten cleaner accused of secretly filming children in a bathroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a0e03375009bb4e55aea4b0a8b01d7e</guid></item><item><title>Missouri woman gets more than four years jail for trying to sell off Elvis' Graceland property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/missouri-woman-jailed-for-elvis-graceland-property-scam/105810930</link><description>A woman's attempt to sell off one of the most storied pieces of real estate in the US has come to naught. Here's how it happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87c9bf726b751fc3728cdd75266b9d0d</guid></item><item><title>Gambling participation and harm on the rise in Australia, new study reveals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/gambling-participation-harm-rising/105812048</link><description>New data reveals that around 3 million Australians are engaged in some form of harmful gambling, which is linked to financial stress, family violence and poor mental health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">582e5e06f9c5592583e96dc9e908fbf5</guid></item><item><title>Electric vehicle-to-grid trial in Exmouth generates promising results for state power distributor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/electric-vehicle-to-grid-v2g-trial-in-exmouth-promising/105811868</link><description>State distributor Horizon Power says a trial of bi-directional charging with electric vehicles to both supplement the grid and take up excess power, known as V2G, has proved a success.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c657879091e2ce95be5b33b932b29f12</guid></item><item><title>Hockeyroos legend Katrina Powell quits as coach after two Olympic campaigns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/hockeyroos-legend-katrina-powell-quits-as-coach/105812958</link><description>Hockeyroos great Katrina Powell has quit as coach of Australia's women's team after rebuilding a criticised culture in the elite program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3362fa20010b71b5d18e66dc93b4c83</guid></item><item><title>Christopher John Sullivan sentenced for stabbing partner Pauline Mountford in Gooseberry Hill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/christopher-john-sullivan-domestic-violence-sentencing/105812460</link><description>A 74-year-old man who slashed his partner's throat in their Perth Hills home is sentenced to 10 years in jail over the near-fatal attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b34ba7512fda4d4c878ff84234b915f6</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's gripe-filled United Nations speech unsurprising, Foreign Minister Penny Wong says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/penny-wong-responds-to-donald-trump-un-speech-albanese-meeting/105809070</link><description>Foreign Minister Penny Wong says the speech US President Donald Trump delivered at the UN is simply more of the same from him and "consistent" with his views and actions since being elected for a second term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d44f8f03841ac14753961232f5608cf4</guid></item><item><title>Former A-League footballers Clayton Lewis and Kearyn Baccus sentenced over betting scam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/a-league-betting-clayton-lewis-kearyn-baccus-sentencing/105811400</link><description>Both players were paid $10,000 each to intentionally get themselves yellow cards while playing for Macarthur FC against Sydney FC to influence overseas bets on the game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4d047a9369284c7941aaf5cccc0a654</guid></item><item><title>Farmer Sam Bailey, who worked to be the world's first quadriplegic helicopter pilot, dies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/quadriplegic-helicopter-pilot-sam-bailey-dies/105811530</link><description>A "true blue" farmer, pilot, and pioneer for accessibility in agriculture has been honoured after his sudden death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1022bcfec676038f6c3bd27cde15e24c</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast posts record tourism spend as mayor warns of public transport 'time bomb'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/record-gold-coast-tourism-spend-prompts-public-transport-warning/105811046</link><description>International tourists are spending more than ever on the Gold Coast, but mayor Tom Tate says the city faces a public transport "time bomb" that could ruin its reputation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c6df1c0bdc0bbebd9425d3678241991</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of Australians fighting 'cruel' battle for COVID vaccine injury compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/fight-for-compensation-for-covid-19-vaccination-injuries/105808630</link><description>Thousands of Australians who were injured by COVID vaccines say they are facing a 'cruel and complex' system to get compensation from the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc0182bdb4d37c0f24454edad8263808</guid></item><item><title>Productivity Commission to review state and territory GST deal, including $60b WA windfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/australia-gst-review-under-review-wa-gst-deal/105813372</link><description>Western Australia's GST deal, expected to cost the Commonwealth $60 billion by 2029, will form part of a review by the Australian Productivity Commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b22ae8ce5ff8afaa0d867d88f15dc4f0</guid></item><item><title>WorkSafe WA drops psychological harm case against justice department</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/worksafe-wa-bunbury-prison-psychological-harm-case-dropped/105811948</link><description>A former Bunbury prison officer who alleges she was sexually harassed at work says she is disappointed that WorkSafe WA has dropped legal action against the Department of Justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2990b5c45595069196146a3173be6cc1</guid></item><item><title>Australian War Memorial updates Ben Roberts-Smith display to mention recent High Court rejection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/war-memorial-updates-ben-roberts-smith-exhibit-again/105813004</link><description>The war memorial's revised display now mentions Ben Roberts-Smith's failed bid to appeal recent High Court findings against him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9edc3cc4a1fb29debf8f915faecacf6</guid></item><item><title>Former police officer Stephen Michael Calcutt pleads guilty to filming teenagers in shower and up skirt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/former-police-officer-pleads-guilty-filming-teenager/105812714</link><description>The former sergeant also filmed up another teenager's skirt and had a number of cartoons depicting children in sexual situations on a hard drive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d016f9d7ccabbb8651e7cb9fc607919e</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Lions trust Lachie Neale to make right call ahead of AFL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/brisbane-lions-lachie-neale-right-afl-grand-final-call/105813604</link><description>All eyes are on Lachie Neale's bid to make a remarkable grand final return from injury, and his teammates will back him to make the right call.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b33183c69e679601c3ad83c2c662b7b</guid></item><item><title>Uber ordered to pay lost wages in 'landmark' unfair deactivation case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/uber-unfair-deactivation-case/105812068</link><description>The Fair Work Commission has ordered Uber to repay lost wages to a driver it deemed was unfairly deactivated from the rideshare platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f3574450e42cae819f14881001f5399</guid></item></channel></rss>