<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 14:47:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Sport has a role to play in addressing harmful gender stereotypes, says Carlton defender</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/harriet-cordner-on-carlton-respects-and-violence-against-women/105923910</link><description>Carlton defender Harriet Cordner says sport has a key role to play in challenging gendered stereotypes in society, particularly given its reach within communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d204662d618f48e535520e14f7eff3a</guid></item><item><title>Temporary commercial and recreational fishing restrictions announced amid ongoing algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/fishing-restrictions-announced-amid-ongoing-algal-bloom/105926488</link><description>The SA government is placing temporary restrictions on fishing in the Gulf St Vincent and Spencer Gulf as results from fish stock monitoring show declining numbers of some species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf20fc4355e416dc49bd319eea97e9b3</guid></item><item><title>High speed camera captures how venomous snakes bite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/snake-bite-camera-3/105926212</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">608eec0bd7426e48ade3e4539f05f467</guid></item><item><title>High speed camera captures how venomous snakes bite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/viper-strike-high-speed-camera/105913278</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5221b3a3cef0e11c8f94fbe4d678b328</guid></item><item><title>High speed camera captures how venomous snakes bite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/elapid-snake-high-speed-camera/105913286</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8985fd9490ff9803e28a1a862fe8cf44</guid></item><item><title>High speed camera captures how venomous snakes bite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/snake-bite-camera-colubridae/105926354</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c64d98557d75c7464c1bd86149b88f11</guid></item><item><title>Phillip Mark Walton's family tell inquest of their heartbreak about his death in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/walton-inquest-day-4/105926812</link><description>The family of a man who died in police custody in northern New South Wales say they thought he had overcome his problems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07288cf36f87b9d44e29cc8e9b3fa714</guid></item><item><title>Chinese Communist Party body replaces 11 members amid corruption purge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/chinese-communist-party-replaces-11-members-at-key-congress/105927988</link><description>The personnel turnover is the highest since 2017 and shows Xi's determination to crack down on corruption, say analysts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0713d89fed50edcc77631eac414c2bd1</guid></item><item><title>Vodafone customer unable to ring triple-0 with Samsung phone says telco failed to help her fix problem</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/vodafone-customer-service-samsung-triple-0/105922288</link><description>A Vodafone customer who was repeatedly unable to ring triple-0 says the major telco failed to help her fix the problem for months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb45f4a15310e3076db7e65e77dc8aa5</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne crime prevention program provides mentoring for multicultural youth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/youth-crime-melbourne-centre-for-multicultural-youth-mentoring/105922620</link><description>Lueth Akue turned to crime during a childhood plagued by hardship. He is using his experience to help young offenders turn their lives around in Australia's "crime capital".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9b9568cadf6cfa0b86a159d9d6ca3f8</guid></item><item><title>Coalition's climate strategy could learn from the proverb about a dog returning to its vomit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/liberals-coalition-proverb-dog-vomit-climate-policy/105919794</link><description>The Liberals have faced an existential crisis over climate and energy twice in recent memory. The damage must live in the memory of today's parliamentarians, who face the prospect of another episode.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b4261ed35e4f4a9c014387726b12a75</guid></item><item><title>The Dish still helping unravel secrets of the cosmos 25 years after film's release</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/dish-movie-25th-anniversary-australia-role-in-moon-landing/105915320</link><description>The film The Dish helped reintroduce a new generation of Australians to the critical role the Parkes Observatory played in the Moon landing. Twenty-five years after its release, the film has had a lasting impact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d3e939b63051b8f008dee345b8474d8</guid></item><item><title>How to tell if a book is valuable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/what-makes-some-books-so-valuable/105924004</link><description>There are many factors that can determine the monetary value of a book, so what can make an edition worth tens of thousands of dollars?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">180abc4ea316320cff098bcae2fc6f5c</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's trade moves with China put South-East Asian countries in the crossfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/us-china-trade-shift-hits-south-east-asian-nations/105924246</link><description>As US President Donald Trump visits South-East Asia amid global trade tensions, Indonesian exporters worry the region could bear the brunt of his protectionist policies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ff0cb1575f3309d3297bacec596d92a</guid></item><item><title>Women push for flexible construction jobs amid building delays in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/nsw-women-builders-flexible-construction-jobs-delays/105921604</link><description>Experts say unlocking flexible hours, gender diversity and migrant workers could help Australia meet its housing targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebafd488245f8c16ee8d73adf614cb0c</guid></item><item><title>Australia is all in on AUKUS. In Donald Trump's America, it's more complicated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/us-aukus-commitment-welcomed-but-questions-remain/105928396</link><description>In Washington on Monday, Anthony Albanese made something clear once again: Australia is all-in on the trilateral defence pact. Clarifying what US powerbrokers think remains a multi-billion-dollar question.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2097e546d99243d4faca7eb0a1113d6</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners handed more than 900,000ha of Cape York land after 255 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/cape-york-land-returned-to-traditional-owners-native-title/105926650</link><description>A native title claim in the region where Captain James Cook made landfall after his ship crashed into the Great Barrier Reef in 1770 is among one of three to finally be settled by the Federal Court this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">628998917e10c5d82b1709ecf427d004</guid></item><item><title>Three men charged with murder of Bankstown woman Thi Kim Tran</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/three-men-charged-with-bankstown-murder-of-thi-kim-tran/105928608</link><description>Three men have been charged with murder after a Sydney woman was kidnapped and killed over her husband's drug debt earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a975243015b6297bb0cc8036144a60a</guid></item><item><title>NSW program helps mothers restore dignity, rebuild lives outside of prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/nsw-women-prison-program-from-now-wagec-mothers-homelessness/105787934</link><description>The program from the Women's and Girls' Emergency Centre helps pregnant women in, or at risk of incarceration find safe accommodation and keep families together.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">130f9d1b4ce2f26b7907dd3236ade820</guid></item><item><title>ASX closes Friday lower but hits second consecutive week of gains, Trump terminates trade talks with Canada — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/asx-markets-business-live-news-oct-24/105928654</link><description>The Australian share market finishes Friday lower but the week higher after Tuesday's record gains, as US President Donald Trump takes to social media to declare trade negotiations with Canada over.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d29e8b0481f79711586321434a587e57</guid></item><item><title>Sydney 2000 Paralympics changed everything for the Paralympic movement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/sydney-paralympics-changed-everything-elizabeth-wright/105872756</link><description>Sydney 2000 was a turning point — not just for me, but for the entire Paralympic movement, writes silver medallist Elizabeth Wright.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">092136bc1972dc772bb30f1718b69b4c</guid></item><item><title>NBA head coach Chauncey Billups, player Terry Rozier arrested over sports betting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/basketball-billups-rozier-arrested-nba-betting-poker-schemes/105928658</link><description>Portland coach Chauncey Billups and Miami Heat guard Terry Rozier are among more than 30 people arrested in two cases alleging sprawling criminal schemes to rake in millions by rigging sports bets and poker games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c1adda1a7bfd5e98d96964fe5622c73</guid></item><item><title>Innovators rethink bike seat design to combat cycling saddle pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/innovative-bike-seat-designs-to-combat-cycling-saddle-pain/105898628</link><description>"Saddle soreness" is a common complaint among cyclists. These innovators are looking at creative ways to prevent it by redesigning the bike seat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6022273d98d73660d31032c869b90541</guid></item><item><title>ADHD support groups help women in Geraldton navigate life after diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/adhd-support-groups-for-women-in-geraldton/105920570</link><description>Jessie Carrie could not find the support she needed after being diagnosed with ADHD as an adult, so she started groups to help others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22b713181dd93c35dad55fe09e8d7be2</guid></item><item><title>Mudgee's Regent Theatre bought by residents with big plans for grand revival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/movies-to-mudgee-regent-theatre-bought-by-residents/105926030</link><description>After sitting idle for two decades residents of the NSW town of Mudgee have purchased the iconic Regent Theatre, with plans to return it to its former glory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f751cc691c737c4a8150cf9a7ec5388a</guid></item><item><title>Construction sector taskforce investigate burglary at home of investigative journalist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/construction-alleged-extortion-arrests-melbourne/105928724</link><description>Victoria Police are investigating a burglary at the home of award-winning journalist Nick McKenzie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3132ed3d63e108d7dd1227d856d66d8f</guid></item><item><title>Dolphins frolic with sea sponges on heads in unique mating tactic off WA coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/humpback-dolphins-wear-wigs-of-sea-foam-to-attract-mate/105918014</link><description>Scientists observe male humpback dolphins parading sea sponges on their heads to impress females off Western Australia's northern coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4caf78cc79dddb901f74e7fb48aa7634</guid></item><item><title>Australia backs Pacific Islands facing China heat over Taiwan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/pacific-islands-forum-under-pressure-from-china-over-taiwan/105928036</link><description>Beijing reprimanded Pacific Island nation ambassadors for including Taiwan in the regional summit last month, but Australia and New Zealand have lent their support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9de69f4ef09294d85a96827432ef8a87</guid></item><item><title>Deadly H5 strain of bird flu suspected on sub-Antarctic Heard Island in the Southern Ocean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/bird-flu-suspected-remote-sub-antarctic-heard-island-nuyina/105928676</link><description>Suspected bird flu has reached Australia's sub-Antarctic Heard Island, with signs of the deadly H5 avian disease observed in elephant seals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">009928e6c16748c0cac1dfa1d8fb29c8</guid></item><item><title>A-League footballers' mental health and substance abuse concerns revealed in PFA report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/a-league-mental-health-concerns-revealed-in-new-report/105927872</link><description>Socceroos hero Andrew Redmayne sheds light on the stresses A-League players face after a report finds footballers are struggling with their mental health, substance abuse and job security issues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dba60209ba077b7518445fa02b5a66e</guid></item><item><title>US imposes more sanctions on Russia as Ukraine war continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/us-imposes-more-sanctions-on-russia-as-ukraine-war-continues/105928768</link><description>The Russian president acknowledged that the move to sanction two oil companies would have "certain consequences", but would not significantly impact the country's economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91e2f52a7f7565fea1f79fcd0a317a98</guid></item><item><title>Man charged over stabbing death of housemate on southern Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/man-charged-over-stabbing-death-on-southern-gold-coast/105928840</link><description>A 27-year-old man has faced court on the Gold Coast, charged with murder after his 57-year-old housemate was found dead with stab wounds at a unit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bda3c665cfbe619d676ea71be58b97e0</guid></item><item><title>India qualifies for Women's World Cup semifinal after double-century partnership from opening pair</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/cricket-smriti-mandhana-india-vs-new-zealand-world-cup-wrap/105928974</link><description>Smriti Mandhana scores her third century of the World Cup as a monster partnership with fellow opener Pratika Rawal delivers India a crucial win against New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fecc1046a1aaf0e7ce8821df9986c7e7</guid></item><item><title>Survivor calls for greater awareness of strokes in young people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/young-stroke-survivor-calls-greater-awareness/105920754</link><description>Despite one in four sufferers being under 65, experts say there is a common misconception that strokes only occur in older people. Mental well-being is key to recovery but is often more difficult for younger stroke survivors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e500e676e885fd882a544785e36d9e8</guid></item><item><title>First Nations women share healing stories to pave bright tourism future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/first-nations-cultural-women-tourism-growing-demand-australia/105894586</link><description>A growing number of women are entering the in-demand cultural tourism field in which First Nations guides share treasured knowledge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">651a9c18b262747919d1b4e1ad65533e</guid></item><item><title>Cranky crow forces visitors to Noosa's Hastings Street to duck for cover</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/cranky-crow-divebombs-noosa-visitors-prompting-warning/105918290</link><description>Noosa Council has received multiple reports of the crow swooping walkers, which experts say is unusual for the species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33643d00a64e72ebb959cfe74e0f6634</guid></item><item><title>Ex-employees accuse Kimberley service station of hygiene breaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/derby-fuels-service-station-food-allegations/105729068</link><description>Steve Pates has worked in kitchens all around Australia, but says what he witnessed at a business in WA's far north was beyond anything he had ever seen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5addf76fa5eb7356b14e448f41abf14f</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroo Nawaqanitawase will earn Wallabies recall in 2027, says Les Kiss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/kangaroo-nawaqanitawase-to-earn-wallabies-recall-2027-says-kiss/105929654</link><description>Wallabies coach-in-waiting Les Kiss is an admirer of Kangaroos debutant Mark Nawaqanitawase, who he says will return to union in 2027 wiser and a better player.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80a870d9bd80cd8a7e8054e329512588</guid></item><item><title>Staff in regional ACM newsrooms concerned about rollout of generative AI model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/generative-ai-newsroom-journalism-acm-media-journalists/105860896</link><description>Staff and a union say a generative AI model being tested in Australian Community Media's regional newspapers is misattributing facts and leaving some fearing for their jobs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52b0a8efbd397a63d6b496185d72f575</guid></item><item><title>Police warn wave of kill crew plots break 'no families' gangland code</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/nsw-tran-murder-gangs-code-families-sydney-bankstown/105929560</link><description>The alleged murder of a woman who was stripped naked, bound and gagged before she was killed shows a wider trend that Sydney's "guns for hire" are willing to break gangland code, a senior NSW detective says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b434841ca81ea8b0a89c19a8ea4eeba</guid></item><item><title>Mount Gibson announces 450 redundancies due to Koolan Island mine closure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/mount-gibson-koolan-island-collapse-closure/105930000</link><description>A rockfall prompts Mount Gibson Iron to wind down operations at its Koolan Island mine in WA's far north earlier than expected, with 450 workers made redundant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf5cbcf1950b4018709ddadb3c80ed06</guid></item><item><title>Suspected arson attack on Bega home, weeks after fatal stabbing on same street</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/bega-house-fire-arson-investigations-stabbing-death/105911350</link><description>A fire that destroyed a house on the NSW far south coast is being treated as suspicious, after a man was fatally stabbed on the same street earlier in the month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d371ed2e334ed528ad9afecb1f8aee05</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged with murder, arson over Gladstone house fire in central Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/woman-charged-with-murder-after-fatal-gladstone-house-fire/105930378</link><description>A woman has been charged with murder and arson after a house fire that took the lives of a woman and two young children in Gladstone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51582c9643baa6361572e9efafb2ba42</guid></item><item><title>Video appears to show Louvre jewel thieves escaping on ladder in broad daylight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/video-appears-to-show-louvre-thieves-escaping/105929650</link><description>Video shared widely on social media appears to show alleged Louvre jewellery thieves escaping on a crane near the Seine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc3ee68a92442faf5873cbe10dff28d3</guid></item><item><title>Louvre thieves descend on crane after robbery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/louvre-thieves-descend-on-crane-after-robbery/105930090</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f300126d928789f032c949bfeb2a619b</guid></item><item><title>Rare dinosaur mummies help scientists recreate what the prehistoric creatures may have looked like</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/rare-dinosaur-mummies-wyoming-america-duck-billed/105929888</link><description>The duck-billed dinosaur was only a few years old when it died. Scientists now believe the species had hooves on its feet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2902ec0732a0af00e2fc4f5f4bb38d0</guid></item><item><title>Police launch fresh search in cold case murder of Colleen Walker-Craig</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/fresh-search-for-missing-bowraville-murder-victim-colleen-walker/105928932</link><description>A search is underway on NSW Mid North Coast for the remains of Colleen Walker-Craig, who went missing within months of two other children in Bowraville.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab94d3c6b78437a27a9bdd74b9dc8791</guid></item><item><title>US faces a reckoning after blurring line between gambling and sport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/american-sports-betting-reckoning-/105929458</link><description>Seven years ago, the United States crossed a line that it once dared to never cross, leading to a string of arrests that threaten to tarnish sports in the country for generations to come.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aee14fa4bd13768c4f4fa7e4d89b53af</guid></item><item><title>Rough sleeping camps found burnt in Launceston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/tasmania-launceston-housing-camps-burnt-homelessness/105929238</link><description>Two homeless camps in Launceston were found burnt, and with the social housing waitlist growing and more people calling for help, advocates say the situation is at breaking point.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0ccc84bf11e8b6bdcb05feb85f54d02</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Forrest's $1b Clarke Creek Wind Farm opens in central Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/clarke-creek-windfarm-opens/105903672</link><description>After three years of construction, one of the biggest wind farms in the country has been switched on. The large-scale project has not been without controversy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9715ae9d6538b5f4d898c73301b4ce60</guid></item><item><title>Canada ready to resume US trade talks halted by Trump over TV ad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/donald-trump-ending-trade-talks-with-canada-tv-ad/105931518</link><description>The US president has used tariffs as leverage on many countries around the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65cb2dc0ead2547841d8a87da0abfdc6</guid></item><item><title>How these families organise cooking to make weeknight dinners easier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/how-these-families-make-mealtimes-easier/105895804</link><description>Precision meal planning is not for every household and these family cooks say there are other ways to make mealtimes easier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c83cf77d5785445fe47d0b092cd2f4e</guid></item><item><title>WA town of Kununurra in crime crisis with 17 juvenile arrests in 72 hours over car thefts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/kimberley-police-kununurra-juvenile-arrests/105930556</link><description>Children as young as 10 have been arrested as stolen vehicles are driven recklessly at police cars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7b6849daf86c1c8930c7eae98df6d65</guid></item><item><title>Satellite images show White House's East Wing has been demolished for Donald Trump's ballroom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/white-house-east-wing-demolished-trump-ballroom/105930582</link><description>The demolition has sparked angry backlash from Democrats and raised questions about whether the Trump administration followed proper protocols.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">255371e55eb05ee436c8c58fea90ce56</guid></item><item><title>Childcare workers charged after allegedly assaulting toddler at Little Zak's Academy in Western Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/nsw-sydney-zaks-academy-doonside-workers-charged-with-assault/105932014</link><description>Little Zak's Academy said it had "zero tolerance" for any conduct that compromised the wellbeing of a child.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c706a4cbb277ed685cc76f0b6188d2c</guid></item><item><title>Dolphin on the Pilbara coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/dolphin-on-pilbara-coast/104800612</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b832a330a814a05ce02203ec52f5da42</guid></item><item><title>Fish at Murujuga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/underwater-shot-of-fish-on-pilbara-coast/104800696</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">813401d97197421bac8f55bedee23920</guid></item><item><title>Australia's women on cusp of International Crown semifinals as Minjee Lee, Steph Kyriacou fight back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/australia-s-women-on-cusp-of-international-crown-semifinals/105932704</link><description>Minjee Lee and Steph Kyriacou edge a star-studded Team Australia closer to the semifinals at the prestigious International Crown in Seoul.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cff47a38f96c21b35cd3a8243a7f34d</guid></item><item><title>Woman extradited to Queensland over alleged Chinese authority and law enforcement impersonation scam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/woman-extradited-brisbane-chinese-authority-impersonation-scam/105932238</link><description>Police say they've been investigating reports about scammers impersonating Chinese police officers or authority figures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fe1f77dec3929af9ce9b8bcbd496556</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/friday-finance-with-david-chau/105932660</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8745ffaa73188726c7a8c1f98e249b4e</guid></item><item><title>WA company TLC Surface Treatment fined almost $1m over death of 16yo Hamiora Sharland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/tlc-surface-treatment-fined-almost-1m-over-workplace-death/105932674</link><description>A sandblasting and spray-painting business is fined more than $1 million over the death of a teenager who was critically injured at a Perth factory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff02690d12904ef34ebe55630b1d238c</guid></item><item><title>Graeme Samuel says he's "disappointed" with Sussan Ley.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/graeme-samuel-says-he-s-disappointed-with-sussan-ley/105932480</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf22d3899f867d02f2eed8814ff8a1d0</guid></item><item><title>Environment report author 'bitterly disappointed' by Coalition, Greens opposition to government's reforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/sussan-ley-graeme-samuel-environment-reforms/105932422</link><description>The man tasked with reviewing Australia's environment laws back when the opposition leader was minister, says he is "bitterly disappointed" she is pushing back on the reforms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bd16ad2b6592c95bea4c1309950bbaa</guid></item><item><title>Authorities identify homemade foods believed to be linked to Queensland rat poisoning cluster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/queensland-health-issues-alert-rat-poisoning-food-link/105933064</link><description>Queensland Health says three of the five people who presented to hospital with brodifacoum poisoning last week consumed two homemade dishes which later tested positive to the toxin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61e7f47e6382d140fab8c2727c93020c</guid></item><item><title>Indy Tahau breaks AFLW goal-kicking record as Port upsets Adelaide by seven points</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/aflw-port-adelaide-beats-adelaide-crows/105932808</link><description>Indy Tahau breaks the AFLW home-and-away season goal-kicking record in Port's breakthrough seven-point defeat of Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5537d4fa5b68b57e1a4c86c396cc0c3c</guid></item><item><title>US warns of more killings as it strikes another alleged drug-running boat in the Caribbean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/us-strike-in-caribbean-targets-alleged-drug-running-boat/105933266</link><description>The frequency of the strikes has increased from one every few weeks in September to three in one week now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">292dac06c111cc02cf816cdfbe1fea86</guid></item><item><title>Albanese heads to summit where Asia's response to Trump's tariffs is on full display</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/anthony-albanese-asean-china-trade-pacific/105919818</link><description>The unintended consequences of Donald Trump's tariffs may be the exact opposite of what was intended: closer links between ASEAN countries and China, and the creation of an even bigger manufacturing hub in south-east Asia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e71c8995888fd60e67f4c1563efe90da</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley is Labor's best bet on environmental laws as deal with Greens carries risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/sussan-ley-environment-law-murray-watt/105884246</link><description>If the Coalition is indeed the living corpse it so often resembles, Watt and his boss Anthony Albanese will have little choice but to sit down with the Greens, a party they often seem to loathe even more than the Liberals, and do a deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdbfa143d04f1406d46b8d2ec64372f4</guid></item><item><title>Hamas will disarm but only if a Palestinian state is promised, spokesperson says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/hamas-disarm-political-solution-palestinian-state/105912450</link><description>Hamas has quickly re-established de facto control of much of Gaza since the recent ceasefire. But a spokesperson says the militant group does not want to govern Gaza into the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a6a800f2e6eadd6f998ed01e69235c0</guid></item><item><title>Spring rain on the horizon for Australia's weather as La Niña battles Antarctic warming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/spring-rains-likely-for-australia-weather-as-la-nina-emerges/105931412</link><description>A predicted wetter-than-normal season has failed to materialise, and much of NSW, Queensland and the NT are sweating through their hottest October on record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6fa1af2d20018476147f00524ae110a</guid></item><item><title>OnlyFans 'sugar daddy' and his wife embroiled in $61 million tax mischief</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/onlyfans-sugar-daddy-and-wife-assets-frozen-61-million-tax-case/105918188</link><description>A Gold Coast house purchased for an OnlyFans creator by a small-town businessman is among 20 properties frozen by the Federal Court in a $61 million tax case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f5b115c4d26d798f9a7dff793513c42</guid></item><item><title>Our country's 50,000-year-old encyclopedia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/deep-time-murujuga-rock-art-gallery/104798598</link><description>There are more than 2 million artworks on the rocks at Murujuga, with more stories under the waves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d27335f38d49abce79572f86f211c403</guid></item><item><title>Why the 'Prince Andrew problem' is one King Charles 'has to confront'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/king-charles-dilemma-over-what-to-do-with-prince-andrew/105929300</link><description>In a week where King Charles said he hoped to project unity as a "bulwark against those promoting conflict, division and tyranny", his scandal-ridden brother reigned supreme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eff4681b45cb1d36a5f4539519b603f5</guid></item><item><title>Northern Australia warned to prepare as heatwave weekend tipped</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/heatwave-longreach-mt-isa-northern-australia-weather-deaths/105932230</link><description>As a "silent killer" blankets large parts of Australia's north this weekend, medical professionals urge people to plan ahead and stay hydrated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adea2e2c5a96109748f769e49b11739b</guid></item><item><title>The Hobart Clinic failed an audit before CEO was fired and board attempted to wind it up, documents show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/hobart-clinic-failed-audit-documents-show/105924822</link><description>Documents obtained by the ABC show a failed audit at Tasmania's only large-scale private mental health facility, claims that staff concerns were ignored, and the lead-up to the departure of its CEO.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ed91b190e97358e2a25012909291f67</guid></item><item><title>Analysts say gold chasing shares to record highs is eroding its crucial safe haven status</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/could-the-gold-price-double-in-the-long-term/105930178</link><description>A major investment bank says gold is following share markets higher. While the precious metal consistently pushes record highs, it suggests the gold price could continue to rise substantially. But what's really at stake?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f24fa53d0477d04ba16956cb1b4a195</guid></item><item><title>Food subsidies set to run dry as second-longest US government shutdown drags on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/trump-us-government-shutdown/105930350</link><description>The government shutdown is continuing in the US and some of the worst effects are yet to be felt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">028bbdf8fd65d40a6fcfa4f3cd7c5918</guid></item><item><title>ABC Quote Quiz: Gifts for Trump, unpopular royals, a new-look BOM site and helping skates mate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/abc-quote-quiz-october-25/105928776</link><description>They said it, we published it. Can you decipher it? See if you can work out who said what, and why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">540f581e25ff96a272e413a576b00a9a</guid></item><item><title>MS is not holding Lynda MacCallum back from staying in the saddle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/horse-trainer-lynda-maccallum-beating-multiple-sclerosis-odds/105887908</link><description>Told she would never ride again after a multiple sclerosis diagnosis, horse trainer Lynda MacCallum is still defying the odds seven years later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98f95237aa06db2059f75127ceb9df91</guid></item><item><title>Will Australia's $3bn critical minerals deal with Trump pay off?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/what-us-critical-minerals-deal-means-for-australia/105927100</link><description>Anthony Albanese and Donald Trump were all smiles as they inked a $3 billion critical minerals deal touted as a good deal for all. But has Australia drawn the short end of the stick?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d16458967e3dfdd99b1064dba7da04e</guid></item><item><title>The unexpected hurdle meaning a NSW musician is ineligible for a government grant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/singer-ineligible-nsw-government-grant-co-contribution-condition/105919048</link><description>Jennifer Hankin was hoping to apply for a NSW government grant program to support local recording artists so she could finally release her EP.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">893d650ed7143ff1693378b328d7974a</guid></item><item><title>AI robots enlisted in fight against sea urchin surge along Australia's east coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/mallacoota-sea-urchins-ai-artificial-intelligence/105802956</link><description>A hidden environmental crisis lurks beneath the crystal clear waters of Australia's east coast as long-spined sea urchins wreak havoc on the coast. Now scientists are trialling a new solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69d18a9aedb53e3a0be55835e43b7276</guid></item><item><title>How a billion-dollar dream blew up a friendship between financial advisor Jason Sourasis and AFL star Scott Pendlebury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/how-the-scott-pendlebury-jason-sourasis-lawsuit-unfolded/105932496</link><description>Former Magpies skipper Scott Pendlebury has hired one of Australia's most high-profile commercial lawyers to claim millions that he alleges his former confidant misappropriated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a93cf7ee0160fdbfe727070ebd3de230</guid></item><item><title>Nine candidates running for Townsville mayor at postal by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/nine-candidates-for-townsville-mayoral-by-election/105911262</link><description>Townsville residents will select from a field of nine candidates at a mayoral by-election next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3206cb66668d5116b32d85034a5d70d5</guid></item><item><title>Russian envoy says Trump, Putin meeting will likely happen 'at a later date'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/russian-enoy-trump-putin-meeting-later-date/105933554</link><description>A top Moscow official says he believes the US, Ukraine and Russia are close to a "diplomatic solution" on the conflict.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41b7e47edfc88fba084e614deabb2a19</guid></item><item><title>A jewellery heist story can feel like a guilt-free treat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/louvre-jewellery-heist-brooch-tiara/105920432</link><description>I bet you've never spent as much time in your entire life ruminating over a brooch as you have this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70357d4e38745bccdfbed26b2e6097b6</guid></item><item><title>Best books out in October, from Jane Harper, Kiran Desai, Bri Lee and more</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/best-books-what-to-read-october-jane-harper-kiran-desai-bri-lee/105915138</link><description>Wondering what to read? This month's best books include the latest from Jane Harper, Bri Lee and Booker Prize winner Kiran Desai.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10b0699202501075721adcc8ff9e71b4</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania remains free of H5 bird flu, but returning migratory birds could pose a risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/tas-bird-flu-fears-for-tasmania/105932858</link><description>With migratory birds returning to Tasmania during a period of increased bird flu, the chance of the virus affecting the state's coastal areas is on the rise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e402485fa51b43661822628f486c21d1</guid></item><item><title>How the star of lost silent film Jewelled Nights went from the limelight to selling sweets for cinemagoers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/tas-silent-film-louise-lovely-bjelke-petersen-jewelled-nights/105417108</link><description>Australia's first Hollywood star, a famous romance novel by Joh Bjelke-Petersen's aunt and a rare alloy mined from Tasmania's west coast put the island's wild places on the big screen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef0fd77808ed2c9dbcd21fa23b196c76</guid></item><item><title>Fire ant eradication program under scrutiny as woman left fighting infestation alone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/queensland-fire-ant-funding-calls-communication-errors/105888208</link><description>A Queensland woman says she has been left to fight a fire ant infestation with virtually no support, as experts warn funding gaps and slow responses risk wider spread.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db05075d077e0e0067b727fdb57e0980</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur beats Matteo Berrettini in Vienna, sets up Jannik Sinner clash for place in final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/i-m-always-ready-mate-demon-set-for-sinner-exam-in-vienna/105933604</link><description>Alex de Minaur reaches his 30th ATP tour semifinal in Vienna with a big win over Matteo Berrettini -- but he will have to get past his nemesis Jannik Sinner for a place in the final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4860e960e8a946da026f96e130c34054</guid></item><item><title>Nationwide Bug Hunt to capture Australia's insect, invertebrate underworld</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/australian-bug-hunt-announced/105926406</link><description>Australia's photographic natural database is about to get a big boost as citizen scientists are urged to join a national search.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0ca7159e6a29be7018f238949242eab</guid></item><item><title>'Castle Law' petition closes with record support in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/castle-law-petition-record-support-queensland/105923936</link><description>A second attempt to put "castle law" before Queensland parliament has generated record support, with some legal experts concerned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6861c40e3ccadd150b641bc22c1554a</guid></item><item><title>Trailblazing female mining engineer remembered as pioneering transgender woman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/transgender-mining-engineer-rebecca-norton/105904044</link><description>The mining industry is notoriously "bloke-centred". Rebecca Norton transitioned gender and kept going.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae28811392ff71f213c9b10197bfd2b0</guid></item><item><title>NSW seeks federal support for world-first mRNA foot and mouth disease vaccine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/mrna-foot-and-mouth-disease-vaccine-federal-support-needed/105931398</link><description>Scientists in NSW develop a potential world-first mRNA vaccine to protect cattle from foot and mouth disease.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd622ba9005c5b8cb3fd6a5045475ca9</guid></item><item><title>What does it mean if a deadly strain of bird flu has been found on Australia's Heard Island?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/bird-flu-h5n1-likely-present-in-heard-island-elephant-seals/105931840</link><description>Scientists suspect a deadly strain of bird flu, H5N1, has infected wildlife on Heard Island after observing a high mortality rate in elephant seals on the Australian territory in the sub-Antarctic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b7bdc89237fb02e04da24a97d2cc27b</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police arrest 'Balenciaga Bikie' after month-long manhunt.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/nsw-police-arrest-balenciaga-bikie-after-month-on-the-run/105933742</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e728238a13de824b2fadc38ae44dd211</guid></item><item><title>'Balenciaga Bikie' Tarek Zahed arrested in Sydney's north-west after month-long manhunt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/nsw-balenciaga-bikie-tarek-zahed-arrested-month-long-manhunt/105933646</link><description>Tarek Zahed was arrested at a property in Dundas Valley on Friday night, NSW Police said. Warrants for his apprehension had been issued in two states.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04370ca7cb1dcbf21c1a21358d858a6b</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr set for Matildas return against Wales after nearly two years out with injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/would-be-a-dream-come-true-sam-kerr-s-big-asian-cup-ambition/105933704</link><description>Sam Kerr is back with the Matildas and ready to start taking big steps towards a dream of lifting silverware with the current group of players.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32c7a2084439a095d98b3e94b72bb03a</guid></item><item><title>Trump sending US carrier to Latin America as war fears rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/trump-sending-us-carrier-to-latin-america-as-war-fears-rise/105933798</link><description>It is a major escalation in a US military build-up in the Caribbean, with Venezuela's leader warning the Trump administration is "fabricating a war".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1374689bd3ea21c2609a998cc2e4998e</guid></item><item><title>Menindee Lakes birdwatcher, the 'Birdman', has recorded 200-plus bird species</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/menindee-lakes-birdman-geoff-looney-photography-birds/105919896</link><description>For 50 years Geoff Looney has called the remote Indigenous community of Menindee in Far West New South Wales home. Thirty years ago he started recording information about birdlife in the region which has grown to more than 209 species recorded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f19372fb3d08c42ba70b8791eb513f48</guid></item><item><title>Perth Festival venues include vacant offices, bridges, secret locations in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/perth-festival-announces-2026-lineup/105927414</link><description>Perth Festival unveils a diverse program making use of unconventional event spaces, but large-scale opening and closing events are markedly missing this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ac3d662e7e0a00be0956db62010efe8</guid></item><item><title>New York Attorney-General Letitia James pleads not guilty in mortgage fraud case pushed by Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/letitia-james-pleads-not-guilty-mortgage-fraud-case-donald-trump/105933866</link><description>Speaking to supporters outside the court following brief arraignment, Letitia James said the Trump administration is using the justice system as a "vehicle of retribution".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfc8bdf98d1d6ed39d4a69725a16a9c4</guid></item><item><title>Thailand's Queen Mother Sirikit dies after blood infection, aged 93</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/thailand-former-queen-sirikit-dies-93/105933802</link><description>Sirikit, who succumbed to a blood infection, is remembered as a champion of the poor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df3a1027ff61c5fc4c09f55165fb9306</guid></item><item><title>Study tracks how foxes 'colonised' Australia and grew to a population of 1.7 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/first-fox-origins-mapping-introduced-to-australia-research/105903156</link><description>A nationwide program has traced how foxes spread from south-eastern Australia to as far away as the Pilbara in just 70 years, as part of efforts to revive native species populations decimated by the pest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6ec944a7b43d79e669b3062ac59eccc</guid></item><item><title>Surfing with the Mob connects Indigenous teens to country and language on NSW far south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/surfing-with-the-mob/105901276</link><description>It started with a surf lesson, but these these Indigenous teens found something far deeper in the ocean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">525be2b9d37d48b57cf3e2b3633f99d7</guid></item><item><title>Jon Bon Jovi uses football analogy to describe vocal surgery rehab — and meets the Kangaroos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/jon-bon-jovi-vocal-chord-surgery-kangroos-nrl-wembley-stadium/105933860</link><description>The US rocker says getting back to form after the surgical procedure was a long, slow process.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ded40ad1a8b7169ca63222c5e327eae</guid></item><item><title>Bon Jovi meets Australia's national rugby league team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/bon-jovi-meets-australia-s-national-rugby-league-team/105934108</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">602a664ed34ae313d5f62c186a861e4f</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos vs England, kick-off time and how to watch, Australia meets Bon Jovi at Wembley before Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/kangaroos-vs-england-kick-off-time-and-how-to-watch-bon-jovi/105933996</link><description>The countdown is on for the first Ashes series in 22 years, as the Kangaroos look to retain the title they have held since 1973.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df694b4c587c0f961ae403205dd86c5b</guid></item><item><title>Marking 40 years since the historic handback of Uluṟu-Kata Tjuṯa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/nt-uluru-handback-40th-anniversary-indigenous-land-rights/105927200</link><description>When you drive towards Uluṟu and see the stark, red monolith on the horizon, or stand at its base and look up at its striking, powerful enormity, time stands still.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c64ba3456cc462427185d5ab8b457e5</guid></item><item><title>Perth Zoo's Sumatran tiger Jaya dies of cancer, seven years after tumour removed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/perth-zoo-sumatran-tiger-jaya-dies-of-cancer/105934036</link><description>Perth Zoo's beloved Sumatran tiger Jaya dies, seven years after being diagnosed with cancer and nine years after his mother also died of the disease.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf8ee41326cfb3a782bdbc8102f7b07c</guid></item><item><title>Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma lead India to nine-wicket victory over Australia in third ODI</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/australia-india-third-odi-kohli-sharma/105934264</link><description>Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma conclude their Australian farewell tour with an unbeaten 169-run partnership in India's commanding nine-wicket victory at the Sydney Cricket Ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">525e153b4cf2743f9494e9dd27a0b1ed</guid></item><item><title>Mollie O'Callaghan breaks freestyle 200m short course world record for second time in one week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/mollie-ocallaghan-freestyle-200m-short-course-record/105934254</link><description>Mollie O'Callaghan caps a brilliant week at the swimming World Cup in Toronto, setting a new short-course world record in the 200-metre women's freestyle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e89fb93e4c22550d88a0159cd2327df1</guid></item><item><title>Popular podcasters are calling out Trump — will young men follow suit?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/popular-podcasters-calling-out-trump-male-listeners/105863690</link><description>Wildly popular podcasters such as Joe Rogan, Andrew Schulz and Theo Von have distanced themselves from the Trump administration in recent months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24ea41796bdf86658c15a4f8d5e0862f</guid></item><item><title>Community gathers in Gladstone for woman, two boys allegedly murdered in house fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/community-gathering-gladstone-house-fire-alleged-murder/105924080</link><description>A central Queensland community gathers to mourn a mum, her son and his best friend who died in a house fire. A woman has been charged with murder and arson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d9a75682928481f60847432488bb646</guid></item><item><title>Swans keep season alive with 17-point defeat of Eagles as Hawks, Lions and Dockers notch victories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/aflw-r11-swans-eagles-bombers-hawks-dockers-tigers-lions-demons/105933950</link><description>The Sydney Swans beat the West Coast Eagles by 17 points to keep their hopes of playing in this year's AFLW finals series alive, while Fremantle, Brisbane and Hawthorn also pick up wins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1da8e0a3afe22a5d565106104d79eb60</guid></item><item><title>Apartment construction scheme unveiled by SA government ahead of 2026 election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/sa-government-unveils-apartment-construction-election-policy/105933814</link><description>A scheme to increase housing supply by boosting confidence in apartment construction projects in Adelaide's CBD has been unveiled by the SA government as a major election commitment — but the opposition has questioned the affordability of the proposal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6234c51b86ceb4be5330a69cc0fdd726</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies defeat Eddie Jones's Brave Blossoms 19-15 in opening Test of spring tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/rugby-union-test-wallabies-japan-updates-live-blog/105934092</link><description>In the first stop on their spring tour, the Wallabies hold on for a gritty 19-15 victory over Japan in wet conditions at Tokyo's National Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97e83ba8a96107003311b8ef41b8215a</guid></item><item><title>Halloween toys fail safety tests, prompting warning to parents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/halloween-toys-products-fail-safety-tests/105934324</link><description>Authorities warn parents of the dangers of Halloween-themed toys bought online, after testing reveals 80 per cent fail to meet safety and information standards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">005617b9d2c2e706dc9377c19b39d222</guid></item><item><title>Trump says he ‘won’t forget’ Rudd’s negative comments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/trump-says-he-won-t-forget-rudd-s-negative-comments-/105934388</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cdf597aee25ce2963e02996ebf86787</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says he does not forget when people 'say bad' about him, in response to question about Kevin Rudd</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/trump-wont-forget-rudd-negative-comments/105934410</link><description>US President Donald Trump says he does not forget when people "say bad" things about him, in response to a question about Australia's ambassador, Kevin Rudd.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">890455bf963d16b6d198a12a4320febc</guid></item><item><title>Thunderstorms disrupt Harvest Rock and OzAsia festivals in Adelaide's CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/harvest-rock-and-oz-asia-festivals-disrupted-by-thunderstorms/105933816</link><description>A burst of stormy weather causes interruptions at Adelaide's Harvest Rock music event and the OzAsia Festival, amid more downpours in other parts of the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a149d9899be760b66ebcfe7c543b6088</guid></item><item><title>Cricket Australia says two Women's World Cup members were 'touched inappropriately' in India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/cricket-australia-women-touched-inappropriately-india/105934466</link><description>Cricket Australia says two members of the Australian Women's World Cup cricket team have been "touched inappropriately" in India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6a6e524625ac1911df42f9041afa364</guid></item><item><title>Worker dies at Merredin grain property owned by WA farmer John Nicoletti</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/worker-dies-at-john-nicoletti-grain-site-in-merredin/105934480</link><description>A man in his 60s died at a property owned by prominent farmer John Nicoletti in Western Australia's Wheatbelt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c86a792f3287abfd78b6bbf3ce1f660a</guid></item><item><title>Alana King spins Australia to crushing seven-wicket victory against South Africa in ODI World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/australia-crushes-south-africa-odi-world-cup/105934114</link><description>Alana King claims the best figures by an Australian woman in ODI history as Australia defeats South Africa by seven wickets to book a semi-final clash with India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e881d2580f2ee147a3a3fc57e5048a6c</guid></item><item><title>'Change is hard, but progress occurs': Albanese chats land rights on NT visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/prime-minister-anthony-albanese-40-years-since-uluru-handback-nt/105934262</link><description>Crowds gather to celebrate the anniversary of a pivotal moment in the Aboriginal land rights movements, as the prime minister speaks from Uluṟu for the first time since the failed referendum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18b697b66607d55d5b504df36f0d8c12</guid></item><item><title>Matildas beat Wales 2-1 in Cardiff as Sam Kerr makes successful return from injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/matildas-vs-wales-international-friendly-live-blog/105934608</link><description>Sam Kerr makes a successful return to action with the Matildas, starting and playing an hour in Australia's 2-1 win over Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a5995cae322115d167923932307ef82</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos crush England 26-6 to claim 1-0 series lead in rugby league Ashes series at Wembley stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/live-updates-england-vs-kangaroos-ashes-international-league/105919936</link><description>Reece Walsh scored two tries and saved two more as the Kangaroos belted England 26-6 in front of a record crowd at Wembley Stadium in London.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0094b724fa2404f30fb3ef62beb92d87</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese heads to Malaysia for ASEAN and East Asia Summit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/anthony-albanese-heading-to-asean-summit-malaysia/105934102</link><description>Speaking ahead of the trip, Mr Albanese said he would use the summits to discuss economic growth, security, and stability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78eb1fbe9a98a113d9782ca4e009a3dc</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar too low on agenda as regional leaders meet Trump for summit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/myanmar-asean-agenda-thailand-cambodia-donald-trump/105928700</link><description>Instead of talking about Myanmar, the US president and his regional counterparts will be congratulating themselves for helping Thailand and Cambodia strike a peace deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">357366ae6e37a136832fe715b04bfc85</guid></item><item><title>Year 12 exams have started for the Class of 2025 who began high school in COVID lockdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/school-year-12-exams-vce-hsc-sace-wace-tce/105895538</link><description>They started high school as the world went into lockdown, interrupting their young lives at a pivotal moment. Now they’re graduating year 12 and figuring out what to do next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4c148e0a37d6c84d59a43a5f0ac98ad</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew has been excised from the royal family. Should the monarchy do more?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/prince-andrew-titles-royal-family-monarchy-do-more/105929144</link><description>The Prince Andrew debacle is shameful for the monarchy — it's not a pile-on, it's alleged paedophilia. So should the royals do more, here?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c8f61b3baf2b8e37d799b8e8cc13b11</guid></item><item><title>Georgia's surrogacy clinics attract hundreds of Australians but ethical questions remain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/georgia-surrogacy-clinics-attract-hundreds-of-australians/105914082</link><description>The international surrogacy market attracts hundreds of Australians each year, but one country in particular has become a top destination for people wishing to start their families.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">470c148be55ed64980f822bf60de1b75</guid></item><item><title>West Bank community left reeling after Palestinian woman clubbed by masked Israeli settler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/settler-attacks-west-bank-rise-again-during-olive-picking-season/105927950</link><description>Settler violence against Palestinians in the West Bank ramps up every year during olive harvest, but a brazen attack caught on camera has left the community shaken.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6768ce196c29595e9f846d9f229293f</guid></item><item><title>Shooter Jennings releases unheard Waylon Jennings recordings on new album Songbird</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/waylon-jennings-songbird-shooter-jennings-interview/105922010</link><description>Shooter Jennings unearthed a treasure trove of unreleased recordings from his legendary father Waylon, revealing a tender, soulful side of the outlaw icon that history forgot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f34df56f1bb5d145aa4f89beffe0c977</guid></item><item><title>Amid anger over corruption and inequality, Asia's gen Z turns on political 'nepo babies'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/gen-z-turn-on-asia-political-nepo-babies-wealth-flaunting/105884288</link><description>Gen Zs in several Asian countries launch an online war against political "nepo babies" who flaunt their wealth on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7205896f2bcebb1e12718a8d6d807442</guid></item><item><title>DV victim and Brisbane Lions member calls for more privacy after alleged stalking incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/lions-support-on-being-found-at-gabba/105929960</link><description>Two years after she took out a domestic violence order against her ex-partner, Aurora realised he was working 10m from her reserved seat at the Gabba — she believes he accessed her details by calling the club’s membership line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c121a7391e20cbed8a19e4109a57f7e</guid></item><item><title>Trump says NYC primary winner Mamdani is 'a communist'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/trump-says-nyc-primary-winner-mamdani-is-a/105487470</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4341236c0f58b4fa2678934ad18eb786</guid></item><item><title>Zohran Mamdani may soon be NYC's first Muslim millennial mayor. It's part of his appeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/zohran-mamdani-new-york-success-is-more-than-social-media/105474246</link><description>If Zohran Mamdani wins, he will become New York's first Muslim and millennial mayor. It's something his campaign has been acutely aware of as he taps into new voting bases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35a5e3f32b70c2582fdc2e938ef186c2</guid></item><item><title>Child sex doll heads sold as model mannequins to harness loophole</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/temu-shein-shipping-child-sex-dolls-to-australia/105636720</link><description>Child sexual abuse doll heads are being sold on Temu as hairdressing model mannequins to harness a legal loophole, according to experts who say it is part of an "unhealthy culture".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71e80ed19552e65773831c678b45fa2f</guid></item><item><title>Farmers buy local pub to help foster connection in country NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/farmers-buy-bemboka-pub-to-foster-connection-in-country-town/105783916</link><description>Operating a pub is no mean feat, but try doing it while running a farm at the same time. That is exactly what farmers Karen and Rowan Alcock have done in their town of Bemboka on the New South Wales far south coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecdb848df7312b1db1240fbc07cbc3bb</guid></item><item><title>F1 Mexico qualifying: Oscar Piastri starts seventh, Lando Norris on pole, Max Verstappen fifth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/formula-1-qualifying-mexico-city-grand-prix-piastri-norris/105915880</link><description>Britain's Lando Norris has dominated qualifying in Mexico to take pole position for Monday morning's grand prix, putting championship leader Oscar Piastri under pressure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af1ff7e05bb6f56d6768c1c12f7ab9b0</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur loses to Jannik Sinner in Vienna Open semifinal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/alex-de-minaur-loses-to-jannik-sinner-in-vienna-open-semifinal/105935156</link><description>Alex de Minaur's Vienna Open ends at the semifinal stage, with the Australian falling to world number one Jannik Sinner for the 12th time in as many meetings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0623b189bf656dc23c1e6fceca311bf7</guid></item><item><title>Lauren Huxley's brutal attacker Robert Black Farmer is up for parole next year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/lauren-huxley-sydney-home-attack-random-robert-farmer-parole/105922226</link><description>It has been 20 years since Lauren Huxley was brutally attacked in her home as a teen in a crime that shocked Australia. She has built a life no-one thought possible, but now her hard-won peace could be tested.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e5b1aa00b99012139193c0a90f0b0d0</guid></item><item><title>Tens of thousands to pack stadium for Punjabi singer Diljit Dosanjh's Western Sydney show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/punjabi-artist-diljit-dosanj-australia-tour-parramatta-concert/105925932</link><description>The pop sensation has an army of fans all over the world who see him as an artist who bridges cultural gaps — Diljit Dosanjh's music loved by both Indians and non-Indians alike.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f080ffd3b321d209120aaeaaaaf3ca30</guid></item><item><title>Runner Sissy Austin reunited with paramedic who helped her after horrific assault near Ballarat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/sissy-austin-paramedic-reunite-ambulance-victoria-aboriginal/105927734</link><description>When Sissy Austin, a young Aboriginal woman, was left dizzied and bloodied by an unprovoked assault while running, a small gesture from an attending paramedic helped her feel safe. It's a lesson that underpins a small but significant change in how paramedics treat patients across Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2fcb5d91b52a701d678c0134b259015</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Convinced your losing streak is finally over? We'll see about that</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/105925868</link><description>We both know you're hoping for the best with this week's quiz. Just remember, hope will get you nowhere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac696c49dee64885c32f095f04de0cc5</guid></item><item><title>Ex-MP Troy Bell will spend time in prison, joining short list of jailed politicians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/troy-bell-joins-list-of-jailed-former-sa-politicians/105912672</link><description>Hard-working and charismatic former politician Troy Bell was so well liked, he was twice re-elected while awaiting trial for stealing public money. Now, he joins a short list of former SA politicians who have served time for crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e72966c961a8a5b5dc35b9be4c83fcaf</guid></item><item><title>Will the art of biography be lost when AI and algorithms control our data?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/biography-ai-algorithm-letters-diaries-digital-world/105923770</link><description>How will the work of biographers change as letters, diaries and photographs are replaced by emails, texts and snapshots on the cloud?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">583e972eb2e93006858183a75f1465e7</guid></item><item><title>Thai cave rescuer Richard Harris explores risk-taking in the film Deeper</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/richard-harris-deeper-jennifer-peedom-thai-cave-rescue-diving/105919694</link><description>A new documentary by director Jennifer Peedom delves deep into the attraction of cave diving, and why Richard Harris says risk-taking is crucial for resilience.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6649f5eb681c26f5b8bed4ac3324e77</guid></item><item><title>Logan City Council resident concerned about flood map accuracy as review draws to a close</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/qld-logan-flood-mapping-concerned-residents-plan-consultation/105930402</link><description>Concerns that draft flood maps don't reflect historical accounts from residents have informed some of the submissions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c123475a6473f72677873fc07b724e4f</guid></item><item><title>Trump punishes Canada with 10pc tariff increase over TV ad stoush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/trump-punishes-canada-with-10pc-tariff-increase-over-tv-ad/105935220</link><description>US President Donald Trump says he plans to hike tariffs on imports of Canadian goods by an extra 10 per cent because of an anti-tariff television ad aired by the province of Ontario.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd2d016acfef0c7fde752a37ddb8a4d0</guid></item><item><title>Staff at Tasmania's public hospitals say physical and verbal abuse a normalised part of the job</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/tasmania-public-hospital-staff-physical-and-verbal-abuse/105847902</link><description>Staff at Tasmania's public hospital emergency departments say they experience violence and aggression "all the time". Data released under right to information laws shows how often these incidents are occurring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc46341484b76d500c138a2c29f58ebf</guid></item><item><title>Walking netball adaptation helping players stay on the court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/walking-netball-masters-games-active-inclusive-sport/105934176</link><description>Before they take the court, the Magnolias strap on knee braces and tie bows in their hair. But don't be deceived, they're playing one of the 'most competitive games', and there may be elbows thrown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcba91251592e68fb53952910d872d63</guid></item><item><title>Return to traditional birthing practices brings joy to Bundjalung mothers, elders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/bright-future-for-jarjums-on-bundjalung-country/105719430</link><description>Bundjalung babies get the ceremonial treatment as proud elders welcome them to country for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9975841b4189ec090d99615b2aa486b8</guid></item><item><title>Man seriously injured in suspected machete brawl in Melbourne's Broadmeadows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/broadmeadows-machete-attack/105935216</link><description>Police are investigating a suspected machete brawl after a 19-year-old man was found with serious injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b40b750de3b8222d4a91aa157c30e579</guid></item><item><title>Ancient tree stumps showing sea level change exposed on popular Esperance beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/ancient-wetland-exposed-on-popular-esperance-beach/105898762</link><description>Harsh winter weather has exposed almost 100 preserved trees from an ancient wetland on an Esperance beach, but there are fears over protecting the site on a popular four-wheel drive stretch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59cc2762bc05a0b7434915fef286b795</guid></item><item><title>Winter weather exposes ancient tree stumps</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/ancient-tree-stumps-at-esperance-beach/105931462</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49efb669c70727f9322a3a615cac5bd5</guid></item><item><title>It's been 20 years since the Cronulla Riots. So what have we learned?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/20-years-on-from-the-cronulla-riots/105686104</link><description>It's been 20 years since violence erupted on the streets of Cronulla after thousands gathered in a public display to "reclaim their beach" from specific migrant communities. So, what has changed?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5291ffd93a63ad0e832d23653b8d0062</guid></item><item><title>Soccer program creates change for young people in remote communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/john-moriarty-football-program/105933040</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d65271ca42c78e74863ac54857fe9364</guid></item><item><title>Football program named after trailblazing Aboriginal soccer star John Moriarty creates change in remote communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/john-moriarty-football-for-change-aboriginal-soccer-program/105888794</link><description>Trailblazing Aboriginal soccer star and Yanyuwa man John Moriarty started a soccer program which has been driving change in remote communities across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3c522fc1f542a2654e05e576e0e804a</guid></item><item><title>Father and son grow delicate citrus blossoms for niche liqueur market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/father-and-son-grow-citrus-blossoms-to-make-boutique-drinks/105889538</link><description>Farmers and distillers collaborate to capture a delicate flower's flavour for the boutique drinks market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7019fd97ca776f07a2f552eb001335fe</guid></item><item><title>Eric Abetz's first budget for Tasmania is coming, with community organisations concerned over savings drive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/community-organisations-fear-abetz-budget-repair-hit/105933656</link><description>Eric Abetz's first budget for Tasmania is coming — and community organisations fear they'll bear the brunt of funding cuts to "repair" the budget.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83c83770df8d575c15236160f11486ae</guid></item><item><title>June Lockhart, beloved mother figure from Lassie and Lost In Space, dies aged 100</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/lassie-and-lost-in-space-star-june-lockhart-dies-aged-100/105935288</link><description>Lockhart died on Thursday of natural causes at her home in Santa Monica, a family spokesperson says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bf879243bbf38deb78596b01b91a445</guid></item><item><title>Albany woman wins international wildlife photography award for second time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/five-headed-caterpillar-wins-photo-award/105926608</link><description>An Albany photographer has won an international wildlife photo award for her image of a five-headed caterpillar that was in her backyard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d1b26042df7faa5d99f630e1842c0c1</guid></item><item><title>Driving simulator assists people with disabilities to get behind the wheel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/driving-simulator-assists-people-with-disabilities/105758844</link><description>More than 20 regional NDIS clients have gone on to get their L-plates since completing a course with a unique driving simulator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35670f40fc377e11843fed94a8063cb3</guid></item><item><title>Exoskeletons including high-tech glove trialled to reduce workplace injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/exoskeleton-trials-in-australian-workplaces/105924332</link><description>An ordinary worker puts on a power suit and gains extra strength. It sounds like the plot of a superhero film, but this is no work of fiction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4068d4c9455ba09f23412bfaa030dd2</guid></item><item><title>In the housing debate between NIMBYs and YIMBYs, a map of Sydney shows what's at stake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/nimbys-yimbys-housing-debate-heritage-conservation-area/105931706</link><description>In the debate about Sydney's housing situation and the protection of the city's heritage buildings and suburbs, there's a map that does the rounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c529c2b3eb11b7e242f53ab13eeac0ac</guid></item><item><title>Nationals' net zero review has not undertaken economic modelling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/nationals-net-zero-report-canavan/105935222</link><description>Nationals Senator Matt Canavan will present parts of his and Ross Cadell's net zero review to the party room when parliament resumes on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5cef9cefc44ebe8a33fdcf3382c1f96</guid></item><item><title>Mount Gambier's St Andrew's Uniting Church to be sold due to steeple repair cost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/mount-gambier-uniting-church-to-be-sold-steeple-repair-cost/105914782</link><description>The tallest church in Mount Gambier will be sold so the congregation and its pastor can focus on their Christian mission rather than paying to repair its 154-year-old building's rickety steeple.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">883ea8ecd2edefbbbb267344da25bc90</guid></item><item><title>Tiny home dream shattered for WA woman with epilepsy as council orders removal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/tiny-home-dream-shattered-for-woman-with-epilepsy-by-council/105922162</link><description>A tiny home which began as a dream for Kathryn Payne becomes little more than a $130,000 storage unit in her dad's front yard as a local council in Perth's north demands the structure be removed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62fa25b02950a65b0bfe678b039aeb06</guid></item><item><title>10yo boy holds toy train exhibition at local pub to raise funds for sick children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/boy-holds-toy-train-exhibition-to-raise-funds-for-sick-children/105899456</link><description>In the main room of a local pub in the western Victorian town of Natimuk, Brock Mewett shows off his toy trains to raise money for the Royal Children's Hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6168bf8c839b4871dd82d0c8958493b7</guid></item><item><title>Lani Pallister and Kaylee McKeown set world records at short course swimming World Cup in Toronto</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/lani-pallister-kaylee-mckeown-swimming-world-records/105935460</link><description>Lani Pallister and Kaylee McKeown have continued Australia's record breaking run at the short course swimming World Cup in Toronto.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55b1f867acef145ae1d0772f0a663ecf</guid></item><item><title>11yo boy from West Australia's Wheatbelt restores FJ45 LandCruiser</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/farm-boy-restores-vintage-toyota-landcruiser/105927368</link><description>After-school restoration fun wins 11-year-old Wheatbelt mini-mechanic Harry Strange best in show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f971f09312152b8f0fa8b92fe5dd71c</guid></item><item><title>Kamala Harris says she may run for US presidency again but hasn't made up her mind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/kamala-harris-may-run-us-president-interview/105935364</link><description>The former US vice-president won't commit to making another bid for the White House yet, but reiterates she's "not done" with public service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba1339fbbed7afd9a5a1b6ff8a8b53d8</guid></item><item><title>Meet the 2025 Agrifutures Rural Women's Award national finalists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/agrifutures-rural-womens-award-2025-finalist/105924530</link><description>Meet the national finalists in the running for the 2025 AgriFutures Rural Women's Award celebrating change-makers in rural, regional and remote Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb6ab8630d27b8886ca61c15ea6e605e</guid></item><item><title>Death of child trapped in fence at childcare centre ruled 'preventable'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/nt-toddler-childcare-death-ebony-thompson-inquest-findings/105935362</link><description>The family of a 22-month-old girl who died at a Northern Territory child care centre last year are calling on the government to ban the type of fencing that caused her death under the banner of "Ebony's Law".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c31dc6c6e76d16c0b8c042bf9edef08</guid></item><item><title>Reece Walsh hailed a 'freak of a player' after Kangaroos defeat England 26-6 in first Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/rugby-league-nrl-reece-walsh-kangaroos-england-ashes-first-test/105935528</link><description>Nathan Cleary and Cameron Munster heap praise on Kangaroos teammate Reece Walsh following his stunning Test debut against England at Wembley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d9fd164e0d9418dc85ecfe804ab91e3</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder over alleged stabbing of woman in Broome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/man-charged-murder-woman-death-broome-/105935516</link><description>A 56-year-old man is charged with murder over the death of a woman in Western Australia's far north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75eee24a2ffccff67e0cea59615a2384</guid></item><item><title>Electricity cut to hundreds on Yorke Peninsula when car hit Stobie pole</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/hundreds-left-without-power-when-car-hit-electricity-pole/105935476</link><description>An allegedly unlicensed driver will face court after he crashed into a Stobie pole at Minlaton on SA's Yorke Peninsula, cutting the power supply to surrounding areas, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27a1f7e6a5eb651c250142659bcf0d18</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese dismisses lingering questions about relationship between Donald Trump and Kevin Rudd</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/albanese-dismisses-trump-comment-fake-media/105935518</link><description>The prime minister batted away concerns over Kevin Rudd's future after Donald Trump said he does not forget when people "say bad" things about him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7131b2409407125a9860a46223b6310</guid></item><item><title>What you told us about receiving mail for a previous home owner or renter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/readers-share-frustration-responsibility-return-to-sender-mail/105375268</link><description>From feeling "harassed" to fraudulent activity, this is what you had to say about how receiving mail that is not yours has impacted your life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f761ea778900d1fd2394e24272fbbbe1</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump and Anthony Albanese arrive in Kuala Lumpur ahead of 47th ASEAN Summit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/donald-trump-lands-in-kuala-lumpur-ahead-of-asean-summit/105935552</link><description>US President Donald Trump and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese touch down in the Malaysian capital of Kuala Lumpur ahead of the annual summit of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">babf3ed90d28f7b682a87f0688f4cb1a</guid></item><item><title>Man trapped in truck rollover which spilt 20,000 litres of seafood liquid product into Putty Road creek bed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/nsw-hunter-putty-road-truck-rollover-fish-product-spilt/105935654</link><description>A man, believed to be in his 50s, was trapped for more than six hours after his truck rolled west of Cessnock in the NSW Hunter Valley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ac754b5d4f3690d771b04571ce6b47c</guid></item><item><title>Trump’s reception at Kuala Lumpur airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/trump-s-reception-at-kuala-lumpur-airport-/105935776</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fae9db5247ed8d0cc2e1d94c574b803</guid></item><item><title>Truck roll traps driver, spills 20,000 litres of fish product</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/truck-roll-traps-driver-spills-20-000-litres-of-fish-product-/105935930</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4bfca886797ee1257087b5b8e82fcb4</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Diamonds lose to New Zealand's Silver Ferns 61-52 in Constellation Cup third Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/netball-constellation-cup-third-test-diamonds-silver-ferns/105935836</link><description>Australia misses the chance of wrapping up the Constellation Cup in the third Test, with New Zealand recording a 61-52 victory in Hamilton.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ff4c810a230de46a3bee5f847361f90</guid></item><item><title>Trump speaks at the ceasefire signing between Cambodia and Thailand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/trump-speaks-at-the-ceasefire-signing/105935958</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af1286d87d4354883aa56a66532e6e70</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos equal winning record with 46-point Saints drubbing, Cats down Dogs, Pies and Blues notch wins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/kangaroos-saints-bulldogs-cats-blues-giants-pies-suns-aflw/105935848</link><description>North Melbourne equals the VFL/AFL record for consecutive wins and claims the AFLW minor premiership with a 46-point drubbing of St Kilda.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26cb9ad1bd1bdbbd858ee61573eb1549</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Jillaroos defeat Fetū Sāmoa 60-0 in Pacific Championships Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/rugby-league-pacific-championships-jillaroos-fetu-samoa/105935934</link><description>The Jillaroos show why they are world champions, recording a dominant 60-0 victory over Fetū Sāmoa in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48a9c9ce3d0ee976de3492e52b404528</guid></item><item><title>Ipswich lashed with severe thunder and hail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/ipswich-lashed-with-severe-thunder-and-hail/105936072</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">368839a3b83ab7ea7c014386b50254d0</guid></item><item><title>Large hail and strong winds as severe thunderstorm hits south-east Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/qld-severe-thunderstorm-warning-bureau-of-meteorology/105936082</link><description>South-east Queensland's energy network was "absolutely smashed" as severe thunderstorms brought large hail and strong winds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d39e61005245c82a9f0c0ff28a6882d</guid></item><item><title>Woodend, Ipswich hit with strong winds and hail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/woodend-ipswich-hit-with-strong-winds-and-hail/105936100</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d460a70347377110ebbd844863535a0</guid></item><item><title>Flooding in Newport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/flooding-in-newport/105936074</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f36216eabd5dd2776322ce024fd14fe0</guid></item><item><title>Rain on Flinders Street</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/rain-on-flinders-street/105936076</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3a054fae64d2c3c41a2f95719aab659</guid></item><item><title>Thousands left without power as severe thunderstorms hit Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/victoria-thunderstorm-damage-weather-rain/105936056</link><description>Tens of thousands of Victorians were left without power after a band of thunderstorms lashed the west of the state on Sunday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6be44d46feb8195bb0e246229d6bee9b</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese arrives at ASEAN summit in Malaysia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/anthony-albanese-arrives-at-asean-summit-in-malaysia-/105936144</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ade57c2adcbb46da92f51ae7092fbff</guid></item><item><title>Minjee Lee, Hannah Green and Steph Kyriacou lead Australia to International Crown glory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/lee-green-kyriacou-lead-australia-to-international-crown-glory/105936170</link><description>Minjee Lee and Hannah Green hold their nerves to guide Australia home against the USA in the final of the International Crown in South Korea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">955ac80a27d76f22a416a42f191179e7</guid></item><item><title>Suspects arrested over theft of crown jewels from Louvre heist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/louvre-suspects-arrested/105936180</link><description>One of the suspects was arrested at Charles de Gaulle Airport airport, with plans to fly to Algeria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6f973a602468cebd460ce670a357396</guid></item><item><title>Samoa defeats Tonga 34-6 to qualify for Pacific Cup final as lightning wreaks havoc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/samoa-overcomes-lightning-defeats-tonga/105936182</link><description>Samoa defeats Tonga 34-6 after a 95-minute lightning delay at Lang Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab66c45227d2bac734c63018e0fd3fb1</guid></item></channel></rss>