<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 04:47:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>South Australia declared free from brown rugose fruit virus after more than a year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/south-australia-tomato-virus-free-brown-rugose/105861964</link><description>More than a year since South Australia's $230 million tomato and capsicum sector was plunged into turmoil by the first discovery of the tomato brown rugose fruit virus in Australia, the state has been declared free of the exotic disease.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f9a128f54240cc9f99a036c7afaba14</guid></item><item><title>SA childcare centre closed for 90 days amid supervision concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/edge-early-learning-closure-extended-90-days/105862742</link><description>The Education Standards Board has closed Edge Early Learning Centre at Plympton for 90 days following an investigation into reports of "inadequate supervision" of children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecd91d4d6915aff8eca13d17480e9222</guid></item><item><title>Trade restrictions for Philippines banana imports to be reviewed by federal government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/australian-government-review-banana-imports-from-philippines/105863456</link><description>The federal government will review its quarantine rules after a formal request by the Philippines to import its bananas, but the industry is pushing back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3914bf6a6bd32339f4e721ddf4773ebe</guid></item><item><title>British man jailed in New York over $US99 million fine wine fraud scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/british-man-pleads-guilty-to-wine-fraud/105867228</link><description>The scheme ran from June 2017 to February 2019, and collapsed when interest payments stopped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">304f6da93469258db1ce9b623d7ddcbc</guid></item><item><title>Powerlifting champion aged 82 and ready to represent Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/powerlifting-champion-aged-82-and-ready-to/105868692</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e86a029c85c4645e6a5b1179ad310de</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr returns to Champions League in Chelsea's draw with Twente Enschede</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/sam-kerr-returns-to-champions-league-football/105869372</link><description>Australian striker Sam Kerr makes another appearance for Chelsea off the bench, getting 23 minutes of playing time but unable to break a 1-1 deadlock with their Dutch opponent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8be88f2cf245467da33d855cd83d496a</guid></item><item><title>Argentina-Puerto Rico football friendly moved from Chicago amid immigration crack down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/argentina-puerto-rico-game-moved-over-national-guard-in-chicago/105869564</link><description>An Argentine Football Association executive confirms an upcoming football match against Puerto Rico is moving from Chicago due to the National Guard being called in to quell immigration protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35a5e12e2ec1b8bc2ccbf801832e994b</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm grants Nelson Asofa-Solomona immediate release from NRL contract</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/nrl-melbourne-storm-nelson-asofa-solomona-contract-release/105874194</link><description>Melbourne will clear Nelson Asofa-Solomona's salary from its cap after the powerful front-rower was granted a release from the final two years of his deal with the club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b68459e3d2d56c43d3bea81b42409d1</guid></item><item><title>Deloitte caught out using AI in report for federal government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/deloitte-caught-out-using-ai-in-report-for-federal/105874634</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73a40e241a39295c35b76e8f87cb1de6</guid></item><item><title>About 40 Victorians held permission to work with children despite bans from childcare industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/victoria-childcare-working-with-children-check/105874410</link><description>The government says about 40 Victorian workers retained their Working with Children Check despite being deemed an unacceptable risk to children by the education department.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9236ded9d3d5db9116428de1aca16ef6</guid></item><item><title>Can you ever throw out a previous home owner or renter's mail?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/can-you-ever-throw-out-someone-elses-mail/105837974</link><description>Even years after moving in, you might still be receiving someone else’s bills and letters. Here’s what can you do about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bad6b718ab042dcb408f6ce3edd8d58c</guid></item><item><title>Genomic medicine could be huge but 5 million Australians may miss out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/genomic-medicine-could-be-huge-but-5-million/105878606</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ed6e2fb9d4d9d0324e237a7c8b62bfe</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government's BetStop scheme not working, former gambler says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/betstop-scheme-not-working-former-gambler-says/105878872</link><description>Diehard Richmond fan "Tiger Shaun" says he's watched on in horror as gambling advertising and sponsorships have come to dominate football — and become a constant reminder of the addiction he has struggled with.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6b9cac18f3f5518da8b3cd291770331</guid></item><item><title>Diane Keaton, star of Annie Hall, The Godfather films dies at 79</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/diane-keaton-dies/105881842</link><description>The unexpected news of Keaton's passing has been met with shock around the world, with stars remembering their time with the actor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">880393f1a8884001569183fb7e30b624</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Diamonds defeat South Africa's Proteas 65-42 in third netball Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/netball-test-australia-diamonds-defeat-south-africa-proteas/105882776</link><description>Australia warms up for the eagerly anticipated Constellation Cup with a convincing 65-42 victory over South Africa in the third and final Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f1ff5a0a480446ef675b46afe105c3f</guid></item><item><title>Carter Gordon rushed back into Wallabies squad after quitting NRL's Titans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/rugby-australia-queensland-reds-carter-gordon-quits-nrl-titans/105884978</link><description>The Wallabies waste no time in welcoming back fly half Carter Gordon to rugby union, less than two hours after it was announced he was leaving the NRL.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3aa32c62a9f0aa84542aa4fe59849c01</guid></item><item><title>How to tell if your Qantas personal data has hit the dark web and what you can do if it has</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/qantas-cyber-hack-has-my-data-been-leaked-what-should-i-do/105884604</link><description>Hackers have released Qantas customer data onto the dark web. Here's what experts say to look out for if you think your personal data may be caught up in the leak and what actions you can take.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0686253e2a0f07a77f7a19d16ef3924b</guid></item><item><title>Here's how Labor's revised super proposal would work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/labor-super-tax-changes-explained/105885434</link><description>Every prominent criticism of the tax has been addressed, with the result that it will apply to fewer people and raise less money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e8eac54b40c708087b8083935640a86</guid></item><item><title>Hamas releases all remaining Israeli hostages in Gaza, IDF confirms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/hamas-releases-all-remaining-israeli-hostages-in-gaza/105885332</link><description>Israel says Hamas has handed over all 20 living hostages in the first phase of the Israel-Gaza ceasefire agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1da4a5a9ff5c0b24b017021965f0b640</guid></item><item><title>Woodside North West Shelf gas project extension challenged in Federal Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/federal-court-appeals-over-woodside-north-west-shelf-extension/105884752</link><description>Two separate appeals are launched in the Federal Court in a bid to overturn Environment Minister Murray Watt's approval of Woodside's gas hub extension on the North West Shelf.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">342bee27bf9dff6d11dddd935c41d8df</guid></item><item><title>England provides the blueprint for 2029 Women's Rugby World Cup in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/rugby-world-cup-women-england-wallaroos/105874404</link><description>The recently concluded Women's Rugby World Cup in England took the game to new heights. But, as Alicia Lucas writes, Australia needs to take big strides to ensure its hosting of the tournament in 2029 continues to raise the bar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b19337aaae0b20b96cc6cd07fe6cffb7</guid></item><item><title>Why Santos is behind your soaring electricity and mortgage costs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/why-santos-is-behind-your-soaring-electricity-and-mortgage-costs/105885202</link><description>It was a primary force behind Australia’s inflationary surge, it’s forced businesses either to the wall or to shift offshore, undermined national industry policy and resulted in the loss of countless thousands of jobs. And it all hinged on one disastrous decision in an Adelaide boardroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">103585cee22276b5b682cf9cc4c3ec88</guid></item><item><title>Cape Verde qualifies for 2026 FIFA World Cup in United States, Canada and Mexico</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/cape-verde-qualifies-for-2026-fifa-world-cup/105887380</link><description>Cape Verde will play in the men's FIFA World Cup for the first time after beating Eswatini 3-0 to win its group in African qualifying for the 2026 showpiece.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a68c49530029934617e84ae8ecd3b5f</guid></item><item><title>Fresh doubts over plans to boost Perth's tree canopy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/fresh-doubts-over-plan-for-perth-tree-canopy/105886692</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eeff764a51281b1a24aecd32b078248f</guid></item><item><title>Generator trial to address mobile phone tower outages during WA emergencies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/mobile-phone-power-outages-during-emergencies-generator-trial-wa/105835910</link><description>Rural communities battling power cuts to mobile towers during natural disasters are being offered a temporary solution with a trial of community-operated generators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4ff5e0410778619fa307c454be94887</guid></item><item><title>Midnight Oil fans rally to keep Rob Hirst's drum kit 'in public hands' at charity auction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/midnight-oil-fans-secure-rob-hirsts-drum-kit-at-charity-auction/105887566</link><description>Midnight Oil drummer Rob Hirst auctions off the kit, which he has had since 1979, saying he can no longer play it because of his battle with pancreatic cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4b1a250f2c50ae072e79e344e2dc5fa</guid></item><item><title>Bridget Archer announces funding for Hobart Clinic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/bridget-archer-announces-funding-for-hobart-clinic/105890098</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb1b30d865a9a239f2642a4dd843222b</guid></item><item><title>Indie film producers tell SXSW Sydney about how to survive and thrive making horror</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/sxsw-sydney-indie-producers-on-how-to-survive-making-horror-film/105890988</link><description>Horror films can be a great training ground for filmmakers, but there is also a gritty reality, a panel of indie producers tells SXSW Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1c6edf129ce345474e049a6b56c5528</guid></item><item><title>WA's flu season exceeds 30,000 cases as authorities blame low vaccination rates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/wa-flu-season-worst-ever-poor-vaccination-rates/105891252</link><description>Western Australia records its worst flu season on record, with more than 30,000 influenza cases reported this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f1f2484096733debed58e21c7b6682</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105891880</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">653774c141b651a45c0a8cb8f098cded</guid></item><item><title>An embarrassing backflip by Chalmers on super or a strategic shift?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/was-chalmers-taught-a-lesson-in-his-fight-over-superannuation/105891400</link><description>After two years of refusing to reshape his superannuation shake-up, the treasurer abandons the idea of taxing unrealised gains while agreeing to index a key tax threshold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81f26bfccf07023bc6ed3051fab482c2</guid></item><item><title>Grammy-winning R&amp;B singer D'Angelo dies of cancer aged 51</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/grammy-winning-singer-dangelo-dies-aged-51/105892638</link><description>The Untitled (How Does It Feel) singer died after a long struggle with cancer, his family said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b3f3f79c82f23a9810f81db1f015302</guid></item><item><title>Dying mother loses life insurance after failing to declare UTI tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/dying-mother-loses-life-insurance-after-failing-to/105891944</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3a16fd23e92a2762fe66d3e28645c0c</guid></item><item><title>Illawarrra Academy of Sport holds open testing day for aspiring young athletes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/illawarrra-academy-of-sport-pen-testing-day-young-athletes/105878204</link><description>Young athletes wanting to be the next Emma McKeon or Jessica Hull have been put through high-performance testing to see if they have what it takes to be a professional.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15a018213f26351372e484eeb90ad629</guid></item><item><title>Japan makes history as Brazil records 'unacceptable' 3-2 loss in international friendly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/japan-beats-brazil-in-football-international-friendly/105893036</link><description>For the first time in 14 meetings, Japan defeats Brazil 3-2 in their international friendly at a sold-out Tokyo Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6454207cf8d9709c6caca8495b04511c</guid></item><item><title>The US has dropped out of the top 10 most powerful passports — but where does Australia rank?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/united-states-passport-drops-out-of-top-10-most-powerful/105893408</link><description>The US passport has fallen to 12th place, a five-spot decline from its previous ranking, tying with Malaysia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">210460eb5dcbc50a34d606ea70c1a796</guid></item><item><title>Conjoined boys born in PNG bound for Australia for medical treatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/png-conjoined-twins-braun-hospital-medical-treatment-sydney/105888942</link><description>The boys, who are only the second known case of conjoined twins born in PNG, are expected to come to Australia for medical treatment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">602984aa1a6e648bd1700a79bdd0ced0</guid></item><item><title>ARLC says NRL players face 10-year ban for joining rebel leagues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/nrl-players-face-10-year-ban-for-joining-rebel-leagues/105894992</link><description>The Australian Rugby League Commission has announced a 10-year ban for any NRL player who agrees to join a football competition it does not recognise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddb37f0928e43c1b5bbf5bd94cff1dfa</guid></item><item><title>Michael J Fox talks about life with Parkinson's disease</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/michael-j-fox-talks-about-death-and-parkinsons-disease/105894044</link><description>The Back to the Future star has been candid about life with the degenerative neurological condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb8da2122b00a39bed22e5f831e89528</guid></item><item><title>How long does it take to acclimatise to a new place when the weather is very different?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/how-to-adjust-different-climates/105887794</link><description>Do our bodies actually acclimatise when moving from one climate to another and can we do anything to smooth the transition?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7b51651bfb1e6f2f7657bf344b2ebee</guid></item><item><title>Federal government puts states, territories on notice over failure to close the gap for Indigenous people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/closing-the-gap-proposed-penalties/105894194</link><description>The federal Indigenous minister may impose penalties on states and territories that fail to meet critical targets for the National Agreement on Closing the Gap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db05c3e8b8aaf1109e2ab7a09d9a6061</guid></item><item><title>Historic Number 12 Squadron returns as Australia expands anti-submarine capability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/poseidon-12-squadron-defence-air-force-australia-us-china/105895342</link><description>The federal government has re-established the Number 12 Squadron in SA at the same time as Australia's anti-submarine capability is expanding with the arrival of new aircraft.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6176d289d3b4affa946abe70f4a0a0c</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period quick hits: Zach Merrett's agent fumes, clubs feud over Callum Ah Chee deal and Charlie Curnow gets his move</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/afl-trade-period-deadline-day-quick-hits-merrett-curnow/105897020</link><description>The AFL trade period's deadline day delivered more drama than ever — with a manager blowing up and a Hawks star suggesting Essendon is 'Alcatraz' on a social media post.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30e7d7c3c3877a4e5422e185ff4a2a02</guid></item><item><title>US wants to make rare earth deals with Australia but without China involved, expert says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/us-is-open-to-make-rare-earth-deals-with-australia/105895128</link><description>As rare earths re-emerge as a central battleground in the US-China trade war, Australian companies are already striking deals to supply America. A policy expert says talks at the White House next week could secure a national agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93a0c2c00f2f1e07783629d538ec8b4e</guid></item><item><title>Fifty years since the Balibo Five murders, families are still seeking justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/balibo-five-murders-50-years-indonesia-australia-timor-leste/105884316</link><description>On the 50th anniversary of the Balibo Five murders, families are still grieving the loss of their loved ones and remain committed to holding those responsible accountable for their actions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1314ae8328046a527aba9120658d2d1d</guid></item><item><title>What is Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder and how is it diagnosed? Unpacking questions about ADHD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/what-is-adhd-attention-deficit-hyperactivity-disorder-diagnosis/105843020</link><description>October marks Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) awareness month and the focus this year is on the many faces of the neurological condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">326c4e8c1519f7e7bdd9cf1c15fa5446</guid></item><item><title>Australians Ajla Tomljanović and James Duckworth reach WTA and ATP quarterfinals in Asia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/tennis-alja-tomljanovic-james-duckworth-ningbo-almaty-open/105897556</link><description>Australian duo Ajla Tomljanović and James Duckworth reach the quarterfinals at their respective events in China and Kazakhstan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">336d915e1efab8f376e17988ed3ec4ca</guid></item><item><title>Nikon Small World photomicroscopy competition's top 15 images of 2025 capture our tiniest signs of life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/nikon-small-world-photomicrography-competition-2025-winners/105880892</link><description>Extreme close-ups of rice weevil, pollen in a spider's web and a geometer moth laying eggs are among this year's Nikon Small World competition entries from thousands of scientists and artists across the globe. Here are the judges' favourites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">422146c134220b9daaeb85e97181786b</guid></item><item><title>Soldier killed in vehicle rollover during army training in north Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/army-soldier-killed-in-vehicle-rollover-while-training/105897572</link><description>The Department of Defence says an Australian soldier has died after a single-vehicle rollover during training at the Australian Army's Townsville Field Training Area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9064921280d2988c8f1986804181b2f4</guid></item><item><title>Cost of 'best practice' on emissions at leaking Darwin gas plant an 'intolerable risk' for Santos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/santos-darwin-lng-emissions-best-practice-intolerable-risk/105819802</link><description>Santos's Darwin gas plant is set for a new lease of life despite a major methane leak. The company told federal officials the risk it could be forced to meet best practice on carbon emissions was "intolerable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4185616f1eb4420fa8e0bb9f51a7a95</guid></item><item><title>R360 hits back at Australian Rugby League Commission's threat of 10-year bans for rebel players</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/arlc-nrl-r360-hits-back-at-ban-threats-for-players/105897732</link><description>The boss of R360 says threats of 10-year bans for NRL players who defect to the rebel competition are predictable, as the code war escalates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a507cb97abb406d1566b15b62aa13750</guid></item><item><title>Four-time Olympic champion Ariarne Titmus announces retirement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/swimming-ariarne-titmus-announces-retirement/105898036</link><description>Ariarne Titmus draws the curtain on a decorated career, in which she won eight medals across two Olympic Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b20c3d209eb66b297a235d75ac8ea914</guid></item><item><title>Madura Plains sheep station hits the market as wool and lamb prices soar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/historic-madura-plains-for-sale-wa-sheep-station/105894986</link><description>One of Australia's largest sheep stations is listed for sale as wool and lamb prices soar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdf5cb0f5e7c6d4612908253b324ec0b</guid></item><item><title>Ariarne Titmus's retirement ends years of sacrifice and allows her to at last savour her greatness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/ariarne-titmus-retirement-a-career-of-sacrifice-and-greatness/105898280</link><description>Ariarne Titmus has given her life to a dream. As she sets off on her next adventures, she can be in no doubt that her years of sacrifice and devotion were worth it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ace92f301f8bbd380cf4ea10e08f291</guid></item><item><title>Consumer groups, regulator concern as number of Australians accessing super to fix health surges again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/concern-over-accessing-super-for-medical-care-rises/105876384</link><description>Australians were allowed to withdraw $1.37 billion from their superannuation accounts for medical costs last financial year, in another jump from previous years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc6ab38204feeb436342c69f39e8b1a1</guid></item><item><title>Albanese dismisses lobby concerns, Chalmers takes one for the team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/anthony-albanese-jim-chalmers-good-oppositions/105884222</link><description>This week, the PM was not wasting any time on "this" issue, and the treasurer took one for the team as Brett Worthington signs off with his final political wrap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8caaca04017f6e10ef0a87a9a892f94f</guid></item><item><title>Former Ballarat dentist Ian Lomax suspended after alleged Neo-Nazi ties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/former-ballarat-dentist-suspended-after-alleged-neo-nazi-ties/105876992</link><description>Dental board suspends practitioner, who was allegedly photographed at a Neo-Nazi rally, while it investigates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">318fe292d66345273a778b72f5f069a7</guid></item><item><title>The Hobart Clinic rescue hinges on Monday shareholder meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/hobart-clinic-rescue-hinges-on-monday-meeting/105893386</link><description>Despite the offer of a $2 million lifeline to keep a private mental health clinic in Hobart open, last-minute wobbles could yet scupper the rescue bid, as the clinic's shareholders prepare to meet on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bc39e20ce0caab5b58da7fe6590d2ae</guid></item><item><title>Ariarne Titmus's greatest races, from Olympic golds, world records and surprise silvers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/ariarne-titmus-a-swimming-legend-races/105899372</link><description>The races that made Ariarne Titmus an Australian legend, from her maiden world championships appearance to her perfect Paris farewell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db607ccb521dd952dfad409a01b1c02e</guid></item><item><title>Diane Keaton's family releases cause of death, urging tributes to homelessness services and animal shelters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/diane-keaton-cause-of-death-released/105898904</link><description>The actor's family says the 79-year-old died of pneumonia, expressing gratitude for the "extraordinary messages of love and support" received following news of her passing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ad4d9062c3fd28201c61a47954bccd0</guid></item><item><title>Cohealth's closure of three Melbourne GP clinics to affect 12,500 patients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/melbourne-cohealth-gp-clinics-closing/105897006</link><description>Inner-city Melbourne community health service cohealth will be shuttering its GP services at the end of the year, citing escalating costs and aging infrastructure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">206d1831d09920250b9663ff89ae7f92</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/thursday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/105900826</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39251dff22abd93c574816fddff415b9</guid></item><item><title>Rugby Championship scrapped for 2026 due to Test calendar squeeze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/rugby-championship-scrapped-for-2026-test-season/105901714</link><description>The competition will not be played next year but will appear on the global calendar the following three years, including ahead of the 2027 Rugby World Cup, the organisers say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84c38b2c85ed36bf3a8054c41860989d</guid></item><item><title>Alyssa Healy scores second straight century as Australia qualifies for World Cup semis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/womens-world-cup-australia-beats-bangladesh-for-semifinal-berth/105899700</link><description>Australian captain Alyssa Healy scores her second straight century as her side maintains its unbeaten record at the cricket World Cup with a 10-wicket win over Bangladesh.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa8f9519f2a73e65f2eef48c11a9f988</guid></item><item><title>Government unveils a plan to combat South Australian algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/plan-to-combat-sa-algal-bloom/105900918</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb673ff2efdfdb07d4b825046c407370</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says Narendra Modi has pledged that India will stop buying Russian oil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/donald-trump-says-india-will-stop-buying-russian-oil/105901976</link><description>The US president says his Indian counterpart has made the pledge, as pressure continues to mount over the purchases that fund Moscow's war in Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfa3d657832c0a2a078b14f16d2fc9e8</guid></item><item><title>Calls for Australia to follow England's ban on supermarket junk food specials</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/calls-for-australia-to-follow-england-ban-on-junk-food-specials/105807974</link><description>Research finding supermarkets continue to offer discounts and multi-buy deals on junk food more frequently than healthy food prompts calls for Australia to follow England's lead and ban "buy one, get one free" deals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edbe2cd8f08f8c2fc9c6395f9edf30b7</guid></item><item><title>Jim Chalmers and Tony Burke are in a long race for prime position</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/jim-chalmers-tony-burke-leadership/105884226</link><description>There is general agreement in Labor that Jim Chalmers is the government's best communicator. But insiders watching this race know Tony Burke is the master tactician.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93f58dc170f3f37c70cca03a69e3a6f5</guid></item><item><title>Drunken motorcyclist crashes with daughter riding as passenger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/drunken-motorcyclist-crashes-with-daughter-passenger/105898498</link><description>A Mildura father-of-six avoids jail after drunkenly crashing his motorbike while carrying his young daughter as a passenger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b7dbbdb3b9ed775f287c7490a9599c8</guid></item><item><title>BHP vs China Inc: What the iron ore dispute says about Australia's present and future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/what-bhp-china-iron-ore-dispute-means-to-australia/105901692</link><description>The resolution of negotiations between Australian mining giant BHP and China's state-backed iron ore buyer China Mineral Resources Group could reshape not just the resources industry, but also international trade flows, global markets, and the relationship between China and the West.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f17745151acc39e0b5f38368c4928c68</guid></item><item><title>From cult web series to cinema: Nirvanna the Band the Show the Movie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/nirvanna-the-band-the-show-the-movie/105898756</link><description>Canada's cult web series heads to the big screen, after creators Matt Johnson and Jay McCarrol were told they could make any movie they liked after their success with BlackBerry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcab9960bf8462cac061bee2cf98745a</guid></item><item><title>Zach Merrett trade drama a reminder that deals can no longer be judged by amount of first-round picks involved</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/afl-trade-period-analysis-zach-merrett-first-round-pick-value/105898588</link><description>The AFL trade period offered three different test cases on just how much value a first-round pick holds during negotiations. Two stars got their moves, while one was left stranded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28e8bb8d5802a90c22f1d69d1a4727c3</guid></item><item><title>New research shows impact of lead poisoning on ancient humans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/new-research-shows-impact-lead-poisoning-ancient-humans/105899188</link><description>A new study claims lead might be the reason why Homo sapiens came to dominate the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12aa86f8c8828a99bbdb6054ea89c8c1</guid></item><item><title>Dangerous flammable cladding still not removed from dozens of NSW high-rise apartment buildings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/government-yet-to-fix-cladding-on-dozens-of-apartments-re-scheme/105900296</link><description>Dozens of high-rise apartment buildings across the state are still covered in flammable cladding as the NSW government's scheme has failed to fix them on schedule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">900570fd41fc7cafb3f056a176d7d52c</guid></item><item><title>How a 15yo autistic boy tinkering in his bedroom triggered WA's biggest ever data breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/joshua-unwittingly-triggered-major-wa-health-data-breach-autism/105455250</link><description>Joshua's "passion project" with a radio scanner led to one of WA's most significant public health data breaches. His story highlights the challenges confronting autistic people caught up in the legal system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13c71de037de480416dd879b9c6eab51</guid></item><item><title>McLaren's 'papaya rules' may be over as Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris battle for the F1 drivers' championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/mclaren-papaya-rules-oscar-piastri-lando-norris-f1/105855110</link><description>"Papaya rules" have dominated Formula 1 for two seasons, but with both McLaren drivers in the heat of a world championship battle, Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris may no longer prioritise what is best for the team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c1dd9f6429245aceb6baaa21e041d3e</guid></item><item><title>SA Education Department fined after teen fell from school playground swing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/sa-education-department-fined-playground-swing-fall/105900366</link><description>South Australia's Education Department has been fined $225,000 after a student at a special school fell from a swing which had not had a comprehensive safety inspection for eight years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cdc7ec760bf1e318791fcad162c615f</guid></item><item><title>Defence in talks to support Gaza peace plan but Australia says no request yet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/defence-in-talks-with-us-to-support-gaza-peace-plan/105902742</link><description>Australia's defence force has had discussions with the Unted States to provide support for its Gaza peace plan but the government says no formal request has been made yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd80619b996f35eb17de143a6b7e07dc</guid></item><item><title>Virtual emergency department a lifeline for patients in regional areas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/virtual-emergency-department-option-for-patients-remote-areas/105371852</link><description>A virtual emergency room app created during the pandemic could help bridge healthcare gaps in regional Victoria. But more patients need to dial-in and use the resource.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cce3e05039289d83c6bdbae0a5d4e7b</guid></item><item><title>'No doubt' Anthony Albanese and Donald Trump will discuss critical minerals: Chalmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/albanese-trump-chalmers-critical-minerals-deal/105903392</link><description>Anthony Albanese will "no doubt" use a meeting with Donald Trump next week to discuss critical minerals, the treasurer says as he dismisses a call for Australia to "decouple" with China over rare earth materials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fe4351ff10e966c7a84c8e260555fa8</guid></item><item><title>Pacific Championships set to start without Australia as strong Samoa and Tonga teams take on New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/pacific-championships-stars-embrace-their-island-heritage/105903826</link><description>Emerging superpowers Samoa and Tonga will field formidable teams loaded with NRL talent in the third edition of the Pacific Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07fb63cc9e9ec53c5f2664aaf516d600</guid></item><item><title>WA's insolvent Griffin Coal ramps up operations as taxpayer bailout deadline looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/insolvent-wa-griffin-coal-ramps-up-operations/105901120</link><description>The receiver of a WA coal mine says it is ramping up operations in a final attempt to trade out of insolvency before millions of dollars in taxpayer support dries up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2e888ffc914c66fe0fec7316e9144da</guid></item><item><title>Pet-friendly flights are taking off in Australia. Here's what to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/pet-friendly-flights-what-to-know/105903876</link><description>The first pet-friendly commercial flights have taken off in Australia this week. Here's what you need to know about the new service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4379a2d55c184d75fb0dbc167127d3db</guid></item><item><title>Cameron Green ruled out of Australia vs India ODI series, Marnus Labuschagne called into squad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/cameron-green-ruled-out-of-australia-vs-india-odi-series/105904798</link><description>Cameron Green has been ruled out of Australia's ODI series against India, just over a month out from the start of the Ashes series against England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfecd41bffae6db1aa484dbde8addcc6</guid></item><item><title>Ways to increase safety on a first date and red flags to watch for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/red-flags-on-first-date-safety-tips/105805388</link><description>Both people involved in a date are responsible for creating a safe environment, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f5f2638f6ee24d2f8b7347e8441dce8</guid></item><item><title>NT DPP confirms it will not appeal sentence for Alice Springs baby assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/man-sentenced-over-alice-springs-baby-assault-no-dpp-appeal/105904314</link><description>The NT Director of Public Prosecutions has confirmed it will not appeal the non-custodial sentence handed to a young man who fractured the skull of a nine-week-old baby in Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c925ab8c4fe58507e765dc17837dd6b</guid></item><item><title>Wayne Swan steps down as Labor president urging party to focus on membership boost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/wayne-swan-labor-president-leaves-role-politics/105905064</link><description>Labor party president Wayne Swan will step down next July and has warned the ALP must boost membership if it is to survive into the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75e127f2e28c7f78ce730de287d98398</guid></item><item><title>Wittenoom asbestos contamination prompts legal threat from Banjima traditional owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/wittenoom-asbestos-litigation-documentary/105886444</link><description>After decades of disconnection, the traditional owners of Wittenoom say they are prepared to take legal action to ensure the area is properly remediated so they can return to country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">713ee52afb0c4689f99c025841f00428</guid></item><item><title>Strict conditions imposed on future LIV Golf site at North Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/strict-conditions-on-north-adelaide-golf-course-redevelopment/105905844</link><description>South Australia's Aboriginal affairs minister has imposed 31 strict conditions on the government's planned redevelopment of the North Adelaide golf course.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc6d01343d110faca4bb8653ade74cc5</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/friday-finance-with-david-chau/105906178</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6b775f25a05cb343702a02cf5d8de47</guid></item><item><title>AFLW Round 10: Port Adelaide Power defeat Hawthorn Hawks, West Coast Eagles down Geelong Cats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/aflw-round-10-power-hawks-eagles-cats/105906400</link><description>Port Adelaide defeats Hawthorn to record its fourth win of the AFLW season, while West Coast moves closer to a maiden finals appearance with victory over Geelong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae0cbd52bca8dc6756cd2ffe42c3b8bd</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's Trump meeting comes amid global geopolitical circus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/gaza-ceasefire-deal-donald-trump-anthony-albanese-trade-tariff/105884238</link><description>All signs suggest Anthony Albanese will be sticking with Plan A in his meeting with the US president on Tuesday, rather than becoming a prop for the bigger global circus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7369e04e283103228bfcf69dddc12dd2</guid></item><item><title>Administrative Review Tribunal swamped by surging demand, more than 100 members short</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/administrative-review-tribunal-overwhelmed-surging-demand/105893728</link><description>The Administrative Review Tribunal was set up to resolve issues with its predecessor, but has struggled with staffing and long wait times over its first year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fd2f156e95340a969daa8b6003273f1</guid></item><item><title>Education department admits not enough done to stop Dubbo College Delroy aide harming children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/systemic-failure-to-investigate-nsw-dubbo-school-staff/105807290</link><description>The NSW government says it should have taken allegations of wrongdoing by a male school staff member more seriously. That failure left those who reported it so isolated their mental health spiralled and never fully recovered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c22f6955d77c23cb8f7c088405ad508</guid></item><item><title>Wall Street sell-off could mean hip-pocket relief for millions of Australians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/insurance-companies-caught-in-global-sector-sell-off/105906164</link><description>Australia's big insurance companies were sold off heavily on the share market on Friday after a wave of anxiety hit the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e35eee1242809cb384df7776dc560ebc</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's family reportedly made hundreds of millions from crypto after White House return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/how-trump-family-profits-from-cryptocurrencies/105445400</link><description>US President Donald Trump and his family have reportedly amassed hundreds of millions of dollars from cryptocurrencies. Here is what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d405316e27218a44724818a9f9ff772a</guid></item><item><title>Young people with chronic pain feel 'unheard', misunderstood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/young-people-living-with-chronic-pain/105898314</link><description>Chronic pain affects one in five Australian children. Two young people who experience it want more people to understand their conditions and better support for all children in pain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">946486ae5287caf11084ac18ee24e69e</guid></item><item><title>James Duckworth returns to ATP Tour semifinal four years after his last</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/james-duckworth-atp-tour-astana-open-semi-final/105907190</link><description>Four years since he last reached an ATP tournament semifinal in Kazakhstan, Australian James Duckworth is back in the last four at the Almaty Open</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dceb858841c1c847c349b2a7432508b3</guid></item><item><title>AI tech takes on one of NSW's deadliest rock fishing spots</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/ai-camera-trial-rock-fishing-safety-nsw/105902900</link><description>Surf Life Saving NSW is testing artificial intelligence cameras at Kiama Blowhole to detect when fishers are swept into the water and alert rescuers within seconds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">151eddbf0d62e8e7f4aeb5cec27a435d</guid></item><item><title>Hospital in the Home program helping young man with agoraphobia who 'cut himself off from the world'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/hospital-in-the-home-northwest-tasmania-mental-health/105789004</link><description>Tom French's agoraphobia meant he couldn't leave the house to access the mental health care he needed, but a Hospital in the Home program means the care is coming to him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1b964e8ba63ca42e36daf1af0d1b9c8</guid></item><item><title>Tool's Maynard James Keenan on touring Australia, making wine and martial arts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/tool-australia-tour-2025-maynard-james-keenan-interview/105865706</link><description>The alt-metal band's frontman is a world-class multi-tasker. He tells us how he balances it all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">501350518724f7dcac6393cd0c095da6</guid></item><item><title>Western Australia starts harvesting what could be a record-breaking grain crop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/western-australia-harvest-record-grain-crop-expected/105900332</link><description>Farmers in Western Australia have begun harvesting a grain crop that could set a new record. It is a different story on the other side of the Nullabor though.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a84a87f36461e65b587de7b1fd2f66c6</guid></item><item><title>Greek-inspired lamb kebabs with olive potatoes baked in the oven - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/easy-oven-baked-lamb-kebabs-with-olive-potatoes/105291672</link><description>The lamb is fuss-free and full of flavour. No barbecue needed — the oven takes care of everything.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97732d3bb23552f5f8a4e4e0fa75a14b</guid></item><item><title>From a Springsteen biopic to a doggy horror: here are the movies out in October</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/october-movie-wrap-what-to-watch/105893300</link><description>From the highly anticipated Bruce Springsteen biopic to a horror movie from the viewpoint of the family pup, here are the films filling up cinemas in October.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f217a9477d3de1211d4744ae2ba19bd8</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne's record-setting AFLW winning streak is clear in the numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/north-melbourne-setting-aflw-standards/105905842</link><description>Having developed the program layer by layer since joining the AFLW in 2019, North Melbourne's disciplined, professional style of footy is forcing the rest of the league to rise to their level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3f69ec228f1094f89b081dd9d305cb5</guid></item><item><title>Gulgong woman changes career to honour murder victim Michelle Bright</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/michelle-bright-murder-leads-abby-honeysett-on-forensic-career/105866588</link><description>The murder of Michelle Bright altered Abby-Lee Honeysett's childhood in Gulgong, New South Wales and guided her towards a career in forensic medicine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b220bc940fcd8f7c374cc9f9976a5291</guid></item><item><title>Gungahlin United Football Club to fold after losing NPL licence, leaving 2,000 grassroots players club-less</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/gungahlin-united-fc-fold-capital-football-licence-revoke/105907530</link><description>Just last year, the club won the league, and a former president was jailed for stealing $20k. Now they are going to fold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b94409bd3e5cff77f2199cae368e6fbf</guid></item><item><title>Who is Prince Andrew? Why is he giving up his royal title?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/why-prince-andrew-gives-up-royal-titles-duke-of-york/105907380</link><description>The third-born child of Queen Elizabeth II will still be referred to as a prince and is expected to continue living in his Windsor mansion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08536e709980d0a36f65e1774362c22d</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce hasn't quit the Nationals yet but he's got one foot out the door</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/speers-analysis-barnaby-joyce-has-not-quit-the-nationals-yet/105907744</link><description>In declaring he won't be recontesting his lower house seat and letting speculation run that he might jump ship for One Nation, Barnaby Joyce is declaring he's had enough with the Nationals under David Littleproud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f61bd6ea4984b1bc51fdcb3bae580b</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos defeat Crows by 40 points to move closer to winning record as Saints, Dockers and Demons notch victories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/aflw-demons-swans-kangaroos-crows-giants-dockers-blues-saints/105907762</link><description>North Melbourne moves one victory away from equalling the all-time VFL/AFL and AFLW winning record with a 40-point drubbing of Adelaide as St Kilda moves closer to a maiden finals appearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3036c640f5f12f4b89b3526d94476ea</guid></item><item><title>NT chief minister claims tough-on-crime approach has led to 'significant' crime drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/nt-chief-minister-claims-tough-on-crime-led-to-crime-drop/105906588</link><description>NT Chief Minister Lia Finocchiaro says the Country Liberal Party's tough-on-crime approach "is working". But after two teens broke into a play centre and left a trail of destruction, operator Steve Mason is not convinced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ceb1811e211ef03f608859e94141ede6</guid></item><item><title>Chinese Communist Party's Central Committee set for major shake-up at plenum meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/xi-inner-circle-major-shakeup-ccp-meeting-beijing/105885472</link><description>A key meeting of the Chinese Communist Party Central Committee is expected to include a major shake-up of President Xi Jinping's inner circle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41655c3a7bf399a2c8c3669a0f55d79b</guid></item><item><title>Collingwood cult hero Mason Cox not offered new contract for 2026 AFL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/mason-cox-leaves-collingwood-magpies/105907852</link><description>Mason Cox, the first American to become an AFL regular, confirms he will not be with the Magpies in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faaa19652e592fb7fd468bdd25c33d4d</guid></item><item><title>Nottingham Forest sack manager Ange Postecoglou immediately after loss to Chelsea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/ange-postecoglou-sacked-nottingham-forest/105908162</link><description>Nottingham Forest sacked the winless manager moments after their 3-0 defeat by Chelsea on Saturday local time, which left the club 17th in the standings and on the brink of slipping into the relegation zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57c551c6fd2ddff4af0d49de00cd0a77</guid></item><item><title>China's economic slowdown has become its diplomatic weapon in the Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/china-economy-pacific-australia-united-states/105884758</link><description>For Australia and the US, the Pacific is no longer a comfortable backyard — it's a battleground of credibility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2b0e48dd4fde1249a89b421640ef595</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew's decision to give up his titles may have been quietly orchestrated by members of his own family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/is-prince-andrews-decision-enough-to-stem-damage-to-monarchy/105907688</link><description>With the swirl of news around Prince Andrew this week, something had to be done; the question was whether he would do it himself or if his brother would be forced to show him the door.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b77456c907ef9b548850123a9b10fa3e</guid></item><item><title>Native mussel restoration project supported by Victor Harbor community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/mussel-bed-rebuilding-at-encounter-bay-after-algal-bloom/105887684</link><description>Victor Harbor was one of the first areas affected by SA's harmful algal bloom. Now its citizens are funding and supporting research into rebuilding native mussel populations as it looks to the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5482853b2341d466e8d2331ff929036a</guid></item><item><title>After Ukraine, Finland hopes it won't be Putin's next target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/inside-finlands-preparations-for-russian-invasion/105859992</link><description>Blasted into the bedrock, deep below the streets of Helsinki, these massive bunkers are currently used for recreation. Their primary function, however, is much more sinister: preparing for a Russian invasion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3896c79d12d96bc2c66108ed2320d926</guid></item><item><title>China's 'special forces'-style tourists packing big itineraries in small budgets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/china-hong-kong-special-forces-style-travel-sleep-mcdonalds/105902602</link><description>Young Chinese tourists with limited time and money are travelling 'special forces'-style — inspired by the efficiency, endurance, and intensity of military units.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecc8983a388385cd9855eaf49fa6fe2b</guid></item><item><title>How Mother Teresa helped Steve Waugh channel his 'power' for children in need</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/steve-waugh-on-meeting-mother-teresa/105671818</link><description>When Steve Waugh retired from cricket, he knew he wanted to use his influence to make a difference. It was meeting Mother Teresa that made him realise his new path.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f532c8e947e73fb6c25eb280850294d</guid></item><item><title>'No Kings' protest crowds gather across the US against Donald Trump's leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/no-kings-protests-across-us-against-donald-trump/105908510</link><description>Organisers say the rallies reflect frustration over the Trump administration's prosecutions of the president's perceived enemies, immigration raids and the sending of troops into US cities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">844c41c111bff92bc93ef28915c54a4f</guid></item><item><title>Cheap energy driven by rooftop solar means larger solar farms could be unviable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/cheap-solar-household-energy-pushing-solar-farms-out-of-market/105898336</link><description>Australia's renewable energy push has resulted in a surge in household solar power. But what does that mean for private solar farms?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36014b920dd1bc4459bb64a96d7ea4d1</guid></item><item><title>Sheffield Shield round two quick hits: Marnus Labuschagne confirms form ahead of Ashes, Scott Boland bullies and spinners offer reminder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/sheffield-shield-summary-marnus-labuschagne/105907142</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne's magical early season form continues with the bat, Scott Boland and a pair of spinners offer a reminder of their skill, while Sam Konstas turns on the flair at round two of the Sheffield Shield.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">054ff0d8e5945ea2d312a9468fd3278e</guid></item><item><title>Iconic house for sale for only second time in 193-year history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/iconic-house-for-sale-for-only-second-time-in-193-year-history/105838914</link><description>Classical musicians Richard and Suzy Miller count their circa-1832 home as one of their greatest creative achievements as they prepare to leave it for someone else to love.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0cb817277090afe4c3ee03c0a1fb2c2</guid></item><item><title>James Duckworth falls at Almaty Open semi-final stage against Daniil Medvedev</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/james-duckworth-falls-almati-open-semi-final-daniil-medvedev/105908658</link><description>Australian seed-slayer James Duckworth has finally met his match in Almaty, where Daniil Medvedev dug deep to beat him in three sets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0d127a1f537ae19f3d552f01bce600f</guid></item><item><title>It's been called Canberra's 'forever government' — but ACT Labor's brand is growing tired</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/act-canberra-forever-government-but-labor-brand-growing-tired/105904332</link><description>It's been a year since Canberrans re-elected an ACT Labor government for a seventh consecutive term — but as budget pressures bite, analysts say Labor's stocks are suffering from brand fatigue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ee3cbb31b12feb0dbf9a314f57eeb6d</guid></item><item><title>Social media promotion of raw milk 'misleading and dangerous'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/raw-milk-trend-worries-experts/105636166</link><description>A public health expert says social media content creators are undermining years of scientific research by promoting raw milk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be479a18a9b8b5bd2c9c5515b5b11008</guid></item><item><title>Dodo and iPrimus hack impacts more than 1,600 home internet, email and mobile customers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/dodo-hack-impacts-internet-email-and-mobile-customers/105908674</link><description>More than 1,600 Dodo and iPrimus home internet and mobile customers were impacted by a hack of the telco's email and mobile services, the company confirms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2023f6e78d453f5b1767f6b78873787c</guid></item><item><title>GPs with extra skills who want to work in Tasmania say there are no suitable jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/rural-generalists-tasmanian-health-service-say-no-suitable-jobs/105907346</link><description>Rural generalists are GPs with training in emergency care and one other advanced skill area. While Tasmania has a training program for rural generalists, doctors say their skills are not properly recognised by the Tasmanian Health Service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa38354b32d3f313d4fb620c7e2db87f</guid></item><item><title>Nationals leader wants Barnaby Joyce to 'stay', amid rumour of One Nation defection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/nationals-littleproud-barnaby-joyce-stay-party-one-nation/105908722</link><description>Announcing he would not re-contest his seat of New England for the Nationals, Barnaby Joyce cited an irreparable breakdown with his party leader David Littleproud. Mr Littleproud says he still wants Mr Joyce to stay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9848481613384650c56cadeda692b7be</guid></item><item><title>National Disruption Group to be established to crush tobacco black market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/national-distruption-group-tobacco-black-market/105908764</link><description>A new "National Disruption Group" will be convened to stamp out the exploding illicit tobacco market and other "converging" threats, the home affairs minister has announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cc3bdda511d1e9aa7bb583dee35ef1e</guid></item><item><title>Five suspected rat poison cases detected in south-east Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/qld-rat-poisoning-symptoms-reported-to-hospitals/105908798</link><description>Queensland Health is investigating after five people were hospitalised with symptoms of ingesting rat poison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17e5b91d5e833fa2e54a07c383a89f60</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou's Nottingham Forest stint a classic case of wrong place, wrong time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/ange-postecoglou-nottingham-forest-wrong-team-brian-clough/105908712</link><description>Ange Postecoglou was on a hiding to nothing at Nottingham Forest, his sacking the result of terrible recruitment and a knee-jerk appointment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0adc426b55b3caeb01dc1561cdfadbc</guid></item><item><title>'Green bans' saved Sydney's historic buildings and taught economists a lesson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/green-bans-sydney-1970s-unions-nimby-yimby-milton-friedman/105903850</link><description>The "green bans" in the 1970s saved many of Australia's historic buildings and our cities are richer for them. But a famous economist didn't like them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abdb337970b734f91db4e99387b96c1a</guid></item><item><title>Mollie O'Callaghan crushes 200m short course world record as post-Titmus era begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/mollie-o-callaghan-crushes-200m-short-course-world-record/105909080</link><description>Mollie O'Callghan breaks the women's short course 200m freestyle world record on day two of the World Aquatics Swimming World Cup second leg in Illinois.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6231da4c79de0162d4eb6b705e6680d</guid></item><item><title>How Claire's decision to be 'one and done' was rocked by divorce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/how-claire-feels-about-being-one-and-done-after-divorce/105870074</link><description>After a traumatic birth, followed by mental and physical health challenges, Claire was "one and done". But divorce made her think twice about her decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c4071ab0f2b41bc5ba8af85bdc44b4</guid></item><item><title>Tiger snake slides over passenger's foot during a drive on NSW far south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/tiger-snake-encounter-passenger-narooma-rescue/105909112</link><description>A passenger in a car has the fright of his life when a tiger snake slithers across his feet during a drive on the NSW far south coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2664ddc2ecf35a9e1c24c1ee8681b6ac</guid></item><item><title>Wadeye traditional owners say Yidiyi cultural festival brings community together as 'one family'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/wadeye-nt-yidiyi-festival-2025-brings-community-together/105908796</link><description>Traditional owners of the remote NT Aboriginal community of Wadeye say the community has been brought "together as one family" at this year's Yidiyi cultural festival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d233684dc20b0f2b15cd1d575b533874</guid></item><item><title>Bulldogs keep finals hopes alive with 66-point Suns trouncing, Lions and Tigers pick up wins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/aflw-bombers-lions-magpies-tigers-suns-bulldogs/105909452</link><description>The Western Bulldogs hammer Gold Coast by 66 points to keep their finals flame flickering, while Brisbane returns to the top four with victory over Essendon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">220f543ca713782ae1e2a21e7e2fa7c0</guid></item><item><title>Raúl Fernández wins Australian MotoGP as Jack Miller fails to finish</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/australian-motogp-raul-fernandez-wins-phillip-island/105909524</link><description>Raúl Fernández breaks through for his first MotoGP win, but Australian Jack Miller's race ends in agony at Phillip Island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c694a400ab3702b8a4fad7d55703dad</guid></item><item><title>If we're going cashless, why do we still pay card fees?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/if-we-re-going-cashless-why-do-we-still-pay-card-fees-/105909604</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99d81835be593f4489d729ef0cd5668f</guid></item><item><title>Possible space junk found near Western Australian mine site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/wa-space-debris-reentry-investigation/105909612</link><description>Suspected space debris is believed to have crashed near a WA mine site, with the Australian Transport Safety Bureau confirming the object was not from a commercial aircraft.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07160fd72846f9d8cf600d6423dfba11</guid></item><item><title>Trent Dalton's Boy Swallows Universe wins Radio National's Top 100 Books of the 21st century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/top-100-books-trent-dalton-boy-swallows-universe/105872764</link><description>The results are in — Trent Dalton's Boy Swallows Universe has won Radio National's inaugural Top 100 Books of the 21st Century.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cef78d8d8b4ac4e460acf0badccc758</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Matthew Hauser claims World Triathlon Championship Series crown with Wollongong victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/world-triathlon-championship-finals-matthew-hauser-wins/105909718</link><description>Australia's Matthew Hauser finishes on top of the men's World Triathlon Championship Series standings following his victory on home soil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ae60c8b144ff92de26c1543e5f8d92c</guid></item><item><title>Pope Leo XIV canonises Papua New Guinea's first Catholic saint Peter ToRot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/papua-new-guinea-first-catholic-saint-canonised/105908782</link><description>Peter ToRot, a Papua New Guinea man killed in prison in 1945 for standing up for monogamous marriage at a time when polygamy was practised has been canonised a saint.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b144cc28b792f0d2dfcd4dee91332e0a</guid></item><item><title>Australia cruises to seven-wicket victory over India in rain-shortened ODI</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/odi-australia-defeats-india-by-seven-wickets-perth/105909904</link><description>Surviving a series of rain delays in Perth, Australia records a seven-wicket win over India in the first of three men's ODI matches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bfda650a8c1f1f7cac905e46ef4fbd7</guid></item><item><title>F1 United States Grand Prix: Oscar Piastri's championship lead trimmed, Max Verstappen beats Lando Norris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/f1-live-united-states-grand-prix-oscar-piastri-lando-norris/105894158</link><description>Max Verstappen has dominated from pole position to claim his fifth grand prix win of the season, as Oscar Piastri's lead of the Formula 1 drivers' championship was trimmed for the fourth consecutive weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bcdd6bd358bd86dd0f6bfeea97ab54e</guid></item><item><title>If AI and crypto aren't bubbles, we could be in big trouble</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/ai-crypto-bubbles-speculative-mania/105884508</link><description>Speculative manias where the first investors win because there isn't a bust are rare occurrences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">283c30df2984a269ddf09fef3456e7d6</guid></item><item><title>Reused signature among string of issues as home owner left with unfinished build</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/reused-signature-among-string-of-failures-on-home-build/105792444</link><description>When Matthew Mapley questioned why the bank had paid his builder for unfinished works, it said it had his written authority — except he hadn't signed it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">145bbaf8d8739f0ee1789f78d179e3e6</guid></item><item><title>How much do you know about Australia's epic 65,000-year history?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/deep-time-first-nations-history-australia/105906578</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7068111e58813c1ec3717ff7a0ba5b0</guid></item><item><title>How much do you really know about Australia's epic 65,000-year history?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/deep-time-indigenous-history-introduction/105907302</link><description>First Nations people have survived and thrived through an ice age and massive landscape changes — as well as sharing the land with giant animals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fac48bc54ea66e8592dfbaf1bfce506</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce says One Nation 'not barking mad' on net zero, but will not reveal if he will defect</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/nationals-no-mass-defection-barnaby-joyce-one-nation/105909238</link><description>Barnaby Joyce says that, "unlike others", One Nation's approach to climate change is not "barking mad". But the Nationals MP says he remains with his party — for now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba1192292768a0257d6e65e047ca10d2</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese's meeting with Donald Trump could hardly be timed better</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/albanese-trump-meeting-timing-critical-minerals/105909072</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is about to set foot inside the gilded cage of the Oval Office — and the timing could hardly be better.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d20e6cfd5af8252e5277f8c4a4af005</guid></item><item><title>Most OECD countries get to work within 30 minutes. This is how Australia compares</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/australia-work-commute-times-compared/105888860</link><description>Over the past few years, daily commutes have changed with flexible work arrangements. Most OECD countries' commute times are about 30 minutes. So how does Australia compare?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a63582c54c385a16e1911ae416c9c620</guid></item><item><title>Olympic BMX champion Saya Sakakibara still fears racing after brother Kai's horrific crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/saya-sakakibara-bmx-champ-on-facing-her-fears/105873744</link><description>When Saya Sakakibara saw her brother nearly die in a BMX crash, fear took hold. It nearly broke the star siblings' Olympic dream.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdae19b5295afb8401bfc230766e6f52</guid></item><item><title>Over a dozen unis are using AI to catch AI — and getting it wrong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/universities-using-ai-to-detect-students-cheating/105905804</link><description>At least a dozen Australian universities are using AI to detect AI. But they're not always catching cheats. Instead, they're wrongly accusing students of academic misconduct.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5ac54c938944764d045af8b0b3883b9</guid></item><item><title>20 per cent HECS cut does not address 'underlying problems', uni students and graduates say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/20-per-cent-off-australian-hecs-debt-but-underlying-problems/105888952</link><description>A 20 per cent reduction on HECS debt is a welcomed relief for some 3 million Australians with a student loan. But those who paid their HECS early or are yet to rack up a debt will miss out on the support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b09ab14b2ad609ce96fc07e9706db7c3</guid></item><item><title>Teenager who died by suicide sent final message to Gold Coast health service, but it went unanswered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/neve-wright-gold-coast-health-service-death-calls-investigation/105902752</link><description>The ABC has uncovered the case as part of an examination of Gold Coast Hospital and Health Service's treatment of mental health patients and their suicides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80b94bbccc9715cedfe4fc21a97e430c</guid></item><item><title>Rabbit populations boom in parts of Australia as ideal conditions see pests return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/rabbit-populations-on-rise-in-southern-australia-after-rain/105903702</link><description>A resurgence of rabbit populations following recent rainfall is driving experts to urge for increased control measures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f0b63e3021992436e68289f3f87b2a2</guid></item><item><title>Daniil Medvedev wins Almaty Open, Elena Rybakina closes in on WTA Finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/atp-wta-tours-daniil-medvedev-elena-rybakina-win/105910582</link><description>Daniil Medvedev claims his first ATP Tour tournament win since 2023, while Elena Rybakina's push to reach the WTA Finals gathers momentum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d27928b89915e24efb9812cfeeed4e7</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: PM arrives in Washington DC, Nationals leader confirms he's spoken with Barnaby Joyce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/federal-politics-live-blog-october-20/105910558</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese lands in a wet and windy Washington DC ahead of his meeting with US President Donald Trump, saying "it's wonderful to be here". Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72bc8103d4f91ae0296dacb6042cd595</guid></item><item><title>All the numbers behind Radio National's Top 100 Books of the 21st century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/top-100-books-radio-national-trent-dalton-numbers/105876550</link><description>The winner for the Top 100 Books has been announced. What do the votes behind it say about us?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eceddbdf78c0567b7386f67a77686872</guid></item><item><title>Millions being spent as Australia prepares for deadly H5 strain of bird flu</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/australia-prepares-for-deadly-h5-strain-of-bird-flu/105906562</link><description>The bird flu outbreak that saw millions of chickens culled and a national shortage of eggs has been declared eradicated, but scientists warn a much deadlier strain of avian influenza could arrive this spring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e83ea2739e1cc6e0699c27dab01c0b6a</guid></item><item><title>Healthscope under fire over proposal to farm millions in employees' tax benefits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/healthscope-proposal-for-workers-tax-benefits-under-fire/105894910</link><description>In-receivership hospital group Healthscope is taking radical steps to stay alive, converting to a charity and proposing to take 90 per cent of a benefit intended to reduce workers' taxable income.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54fe6626e9683e97ff7c755dc0f3b158</guid></item><item><title>Israel says ceasefire and aid to resume after airstrikes kill 26 in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/israel-says-gaza-ceasefire-and-aid-to-resume/105910598</link><description>Israel says it has resumed enforcement of the Gaza ceasefire plan after it was "violated" by Hamas following a wave of Israeli strikes that killed 26 people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b15241284c0d7f497581843777ebda8</guid></item><item><title>Multiple sclerosis support group tries to fill gaps as Northern Territory services dwindle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/multiple-sclerosis-support-group-tries-fill-nt-service-gaps/105839144</link><description>Being diagnosed with multiple sclerosis can often be an isolating experience, and even more so for those in Darwin who lack access to on-the-ground supports. Despite these barriers, a group of local women have created a support group to help fill the service gap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14749aee6ee20b3feba95efcd80cf469</guid></item><item><title>Drone footage reveals Gaza City's destruction as people return home during ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/drone-footage-reveals-gaza-city-destruction/105906708</link><description>One week into the ceasefire in Gaza, Palestinians are returning to destroyed homes and trying to find shelter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3949b76fa29fedb2ce2ac2c7ac488821</guid></item><item><title>England records four-run Women's World Cup win over India to join Australia in semifinals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/cricket-world-cup-england-defeats-india-to-reach-semifinals/105910632</link><description>England secures its Women's World Cup semifinal spot with a tense four-run win over tournament co-host India at Indor's Holkar Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca127f26cc1b519429233a14a7576b44</guid></item><item><title>Tourism dollars roll into Carnamah a year after arrival of big tractor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/worlds-biggest-tractor-tourism-wa-midwest-town-carnamah/105893574</link><description>One year on from its opening, the orange icon has brought people from all over Australia — and the world — to WA's Midwest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e006f37718ddfa2b762776c7387048c2</guid></item><item><title>Police probing claims Prince Andrew tried to smear sexual assault accuser Virginia Giuffre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/police-looking-into-claims-prince-andrew-smear-virginia-giuffre/105910618</link><description>British police say they're probing claims that Prince Andrew asked an officer to dig up dirt for a smear campaign against his sexual assault accuser Virginia Giuffre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e42ba0d11b99fb0e6ffb5ef188a4743</guid></item><item><title>Caravans clog suburban streets sparking calls for new laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/caravan-street-parking-congestion-motion-put-forward-to-state/105905046</link><description>Queensland councils put forward a motion calling on the state government to implement strict laws on caravan street parking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43fef001bb1c8713271d0be4b79c9222</guid></item><item><title>India backs Virat Kohli to rebound after ODI duck against Australia in Perth series opener</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/cricket-odi-india-australia-virat-kohli-duck/105910756</link><description>Virat Kohli failed to score in the opening men's ODI in Perth. However, his India teammates expect their ex-skipper to quickly recapture his best form.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bc80acf1d0f546076475e758c726a92</guid></item><item><title>Holiday from Hospital virtual reality to transport patients to Australia's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/holiday-from-hospital-virtual-reality-program/105904452</link><description>A leukaemia survivor designs a VR program that will help patients travel to some of Australia's iconic locations from their hospital beds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86e927a78d6931f5a5bc765a1bd0349f</guid></item><item><title>Richmond is starting to play good footy. But in AFLW's short season there's no time left to build momentum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/richmond-aflw-short-season-limits-chance-to-build-momentum/105910676</link><description>After a 0-7 start to the season, Richmond are starting to notch wins on the board. But it's too late for much momentum to build in the short women's season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">069e771beb7b5a18b4ca2823e445cde9</guid></item><item><title>Some scientists challenge logic of Victoria's fuel reduction burns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/scientists-challenge-fuel-load-burns-victoria/105666680</link><description>Dry winter conditions have resulted in extra fuel reduction burns in regional Victoria ahead of the fire season. But some scientists are asking if fuel burns are the best way to reduce fire risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24063f01e48736dadc0cd1dc663f5536</guid></item><item><title>Severe winds and hail hit WA's Kimberley as wet season approaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/wild-weather-batters-far-north-wa-unusual-hailstorm/105909234</link><description>Wild weather hit the Kimberley over the weekend, with some residents witnessing hail falling on their lawns despite it being a 38-degree day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">759b0e13b14ba30ecea0dbed924de7c7</guid></item><item><title>Victorian police minister defends use of rubber bullets, pepper spray at Melbourne protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/police-minister-defends-use-of-force-at-melbourne-protest/105910874</link><description>Victoria's police minister backs the police response to protests in Melbourne's CBD on Sunday, when demonstrators were hit with rubber bullets and pepper spray.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26957d5a4aa63566b917429161520d6c</guid></item><item><title>F1 standings: Oscar Piastri says too early for McLaren to prioritise drivers as Max Verstappen continues charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/f1-championship-standings-2025-piastri-verstappen-norris/105910856</link><description>Formula 1 championship leader Oscar Piastri says McLaren does not need to prioritise one driver over the other, as four-time world champion Max Verstappen continues to narrow the deficit to both.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6b6dbcdc3ff000bf792dec04e4a387f</guid></item><item><title>New childcare centres might ease waitlists in regional Victoria, but worker shortages endure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/childcare-worker-shortages-regional-victoria/105861138</link><description>Hundreds of children in a regional Victorian city are on childcare waitlists, but centres say they cannot open to full capacity as they struggle to find qualified staff.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f8b17ce3da65fae957a913f9d8b696d</guid></item><item><title>Warning over rare but deadly virus after bat bites Pilbara woman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/pilbara-bat-bite-lyssavirus-treatment/105903464</link><description>A Pilbara resident says an attempt to save a small bat stuck in her house has resulted in painful treatment for a deadly virus that can be passed onto humans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7649b3e7c5d127072e9734a5e6389db2</guid></item><item><title>Melt Festival is giving queer artists a space to be themselves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/melt-at-pip-queer-arts-festival-stand-up-comedy/105876434</link><description>Brisbane's Melt Festival has rapidly expanded in the past decade, inviting numerous venues into the celebration of queer artistry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82f95541593c2dd6615f166a0fa29834</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr backed by Matildas coach Joe Montemurro to make impact in friendlies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/matildas-sam-kerr-joe-montemurro-wales-england-friendlies/105911490</link><description>Sam Kerr will return to the Matildas fold off the back of limited minutes at Chelsea, but coach Joe Montemurro is confident she will shine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55b775730bad08a65eaa25450f51842f</guid></item><item><title>Mossman sugarcane industry on its last legs as haulage deal ends</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/mossman-sugarcane-mulgrave-mill-transport-costs-too-high/105905656</link><description>A deal between Mossman sugarcane growers and a mill 100 kilometres away has been deemed unviable, leaving farmers without a place to send their product after this season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4f1c7e046b4e98aead821af1d28a44d</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the Louvre jewellery heist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/what-we-know-about-the-louvre-jewellery-heist/105910640</link><description>Here are the details on the items stolen in the Louvre heist that unfolded in broad daylight in Paris.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d269eaf9f556b0ba4f01c08707826645</guid></item><item><title>Vison broadcast on French TV appears to show Louvre thief</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/mobile-vision-purporting-to-show-louvre-thief-/105911652</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6728d820eb0c2de018ff21bbf736d48c</guid></item><item><title>Limp Bizkit bandmates pay tribute to bassist Sam Rivers after death at 48</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/limp-bizkit-bandmates-pay-tribute-to-bassist-sam-rivers/105911436</link><description>Fred Durst takes to social media to say he has shed "gallons of tears" since finding out about the death of his "truly wonderful" bandmate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1d63bc89303f861e3b31723c1277a98</guid></item><item><title>Cargo plane slides off runway at Hong Kong International Airport, two people dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/hong-kong-airport-cargo-plane-crash/105911458</link><description>The flight arriving from Dubai was landing at Hong Kong International Airport when it skidded off the runway, leading to the deaths of two men in a vehicle on the ground, according to police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">949790ffe37f5f7d2047c0e6ac8b0cee</guid></item><item><title>Australian Olympic champion Kaylee McKeown breaks world short course record</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/swimming-kaylee-mckeown-breaks-world-short-course-record/105912014</link><description>Australia's five-time Olympic gold medallist Kaylee McKeown sets a world short course record in the women's 200 metres backstroke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">402b6aa0b6c8c60ddfcda2c6439f5872</guid></item><item><title>Former Toowoomba Chronicle journalist Peter Hardwick sentenced over indecent treatment of child</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/qld-former-journalist-peter-hardwick-child-indecent-treatment/105911288</link><description>Peter Hardwick is sentenced after pleading guilty to two counts of indecent treatment of a child under the age of 12.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5215ec6b2a4623b1d02131cfd00d22d9</guid></item><item><title>Live: Deep Time, a story 65,000 years in the making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/deep-time-launch-live-blog/105911270</link><description>ABC's Story Lab team has created an interactive tool to help Australians better understand the ancient history of our continent and its First Nations peoples. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9204ef8f5d9eebc4f3e76e50be4721ac</guid></item><item><title>Shane Wanganeen pleads guilty to criminal neglect following son's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/shane-wanganeen-pleads-guilty-to-criminal-neglect/105911944</link><description>A South Australian father has pleaded guilty to the criminal neglect of his seven-year-old son, who died after not being treated for pneumonia in 2022. WARNING: Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander readers are advised this article contains the name of a person who has died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3dddd8946d0112422d50d9ca6f97346</guid></item><item><title>Black Swans rowing crew from WA records win at Head of the Charles Regatta in Boston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/black-swans-rowing-crew-posts-win-at-head-of-the-charles-regatta/105912280</link><description>A group of West Australian former high-level rowers are still in shock after claiming a win at the world's biggest and most famous rowing event — The Head of the Charles Regatta in Boston.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c9029515cc34eb9eab3a0a5e60e4e01</guid></item><item><title>Samoa down to 17 fit players after Pacific Championships loss to New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/samoa-to-call-in-replacements-after-brutal-kiwi-defeat/105912418</link><description>Samoa's brutal loss to New Zealand leaves them needing to call fresh troops into their squad, with the Pacific powerhouse down to just 17 fit players.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b4e1cb8410d3d6e41561f33c4befb1e</guid></item><item><title>Tatiana Dokhotaru told mum she was 'very afraid' of ex-partner before her death, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/nsw-danny-zayat-murder-trial-tatiana-dokhotaru-mother-olga/105911540</link><description>Danny Zayat has pleaded not guilty and is facing a Supreme Court trial over the alleged murder of Tatiana Dokhotaru in May 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ff4265f79917f345faf843c0c7d1395</guid></item><item><title>Central Land Council CEO Lesley Turner sues Senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price over defamation claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/nt-clc-lesley-turner-sues-senator-jacinta-nampijinpa-price-court/105911056</link><description>A seven-day Federal Court defamation case, alleging Senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price "trampled" the reputation of an NT land council leader, has begun in Darwin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8420ac7f16d0a99cba30c47990ca4485</guid></item><item><title>Has Australia just killed its cultural cringe?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/books-100-cultural-cringe-australian-literature/105911414</link><description>How wonderful for Australian writers to receive this recognition from the very people who consume their work, as part of ABC Radio National's Top 100 Books countdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6955af048b4c6e6460e149afd7da2d97</guid></item><item><title>Election campaign donation laws would have blocked $8m in Climate 200 funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/climate-200-donations-millions-blocked-election-reforms/105910960</link><description>Climate 200 would have been blocked from making $8.34 million in donations to independent candidates if new election donation laws were in place at the 2025 poll.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a105858ce5aba7b87125fcecf773b3e4</guid></item><item><title>New England voters divided by Barnaby Joyce's flirtation with One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/barnaby-joyce-future-uncertain-as-new-england-voters-react/105910950</link><description>Support for the politician remains strong in his electorate despite his apparent flirtation with One Nation, a party enjoying a surge in popularity in the seat of New England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5fd341f9bae412bf8bef068aa17b4f9</guid></item><item><title>Space junk found near WA mine linked to Chinese rocket launch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/space-junk-chinese-rocket-jielong-newman-bhp-iron-ore/105912162</link><description>Suspected space junk which crashed near an iron ore mine in remote WA has been linked to a Chinese rocket launch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24854cc69cdd74ae88771488846a683b</guid></item><item><title>Bonza's financial backer 777 Partners co-founder charged with fraud</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/bonza-us-financier-charged-500-million-alleged-fraud/105910734</link><description>The FBI investigation resulted in 777 Partners co-founder Joshua Wander being charged with stealing US$500 million from lenders and investors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e392cffcb519df7c5888daa3070bb23a</guid></item></channel></rss>