<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 02:37:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Frank Gehry, world-renowned architect who designed the Guggenheim Museum Bilbao, dies aged 96</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/frank-gehry-guggenheim-bilbao-dies-aged-96/106109892</link><description>Gehry's most memorable creations were either celebrated as works of genius or reviled as self-indulgent messes — but either way, people were looking, as he liked to say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecfb4aee4144b1097d9f9d29ef26c3fc</guid></item><item><title>Blue whales off Dunsborough</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/cow-and-calf-blue-whale/106106620</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2679d706e21deadabffe76fdbb7dce0</guid></item><item><title>Blue whale calf numbers rise after slow migration start along WA's south west coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/baby-blue-whale-numbers-wa-south-west-coast/106104766</link><description>Researchers are relieved as baby blue whale numbers increase after a slow start to the migration season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce2461b0ebf884ba690caf4fa73f245f</guid></item><item><title>Blue whale swimming off Busselton Jetty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/blue-whale-swimming-off-busselton-jetty/106105306</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d10be79b81cc7f5bcfab5c804d73069</guid></item><item><title>This tasty, veggie-filled omlette is a fast and satisfying meal - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/ejjeh-zucchini-omelette/106102824</link><description>Ejjeh is a traditional omelette made with eggs, herbs, spices and that soft zucchini flesh that would otherwise go to waste. It's simple, fresh and full of flavour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77fef1ae7c6da366ad1c89e922b140e5</guid></item><item><title>Roger Cook wants to change the rules on project approvals to avoid FOMO, but critics have their doubts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/concerns-as-roger-cook-seeks-to-speed-up-project-approvals/106100190</link><description>The WA premier is seeking wide-reaching powers to change the rules on approvals for "big, shiny, job-creating projects" — but it has prompted concern from the opposition, environmentalists and even lawyers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">457c6d34d10955987fa825d514bfdd0a</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos found in new Edith Cowan University campus in Perth CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/asbestos-found-in-new-ecu-campus-in-perth-cbd/106109070</link><description>WA's parliament is told asbestos has been discovered in fire doors at Edith Cowan University's flagship new campus in Perth's CBD, and it won't be removed until after the first semester next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59fb25929fe3469ce6ffd2b649633c6f</guid></item><item><title>The National Indigenous Art Triennial in Canberra reflects on legacy, rebirth and renewal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/national-indigenous-art-triennial-after-the-rain-tony-albert/106105020</link><description>Indigenous artists from across Australia, including Alair Pambegan and Grace Kemarre Robinya, feature as part of the National Indigenous Art Triennial in Canberra: After the Rain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">298d22642d30f831c89ee4391ea7cd3c</guid></item><item><title>Up to 16 homes lost in Bulahdelah and Koolewong fires in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/strong-winds-intense-heat-thunderstorms-nsw/106109226</link><description>More than 1,500 firefighters with 300 vehicles were deployed by the RFS across eastern and central NSW amid extreme heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97594e0790a4e0dbae88468a24108d86</guid></item><item><title>Bunbury Indigenous elders write children's book in Noongar language to preserve culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/noongar-kala-bunbury-aboriginal-elders-south-west-wa/106101058</link><description>Once forbidden from speaking their local language, a group of Indigenous elders in WA use it in a children's book, hoping to breathe life into a dying dialect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8c8164c0eeec9b3ba3ab586b29b8bad</guid></item><item><title>Residents still unable to return home as north-east Victoria bushfire continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/markwood-fire-recovery-houses-lost/106110100</link><description>North-east Victorian residents are still unable to return home as firefighters assess bushfire damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b13e50e22ebfcfa29edd47ab97b690b5</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate hikes increasingly likely in 2026 but a major event would produce the opposite result</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/interest-rates-2026/106106712</link><description>Inflation is a problem as 2025 comes to a close and it's set to remain that way. Without a swift rise in productivity or a financial markets meltdown, borrowers are facing several interest rate hikes next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d746d4688a4127389fb3a4b35770ed4</guid></item><item><title>Woman found dead after days outside NSW south coast police station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/dead-woman-found-after-days-in-nsw-police-station-car-park/106109896</link><description>A critical incident has been declared after a 48-year-old woman's body was found inside a car at a police station car park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd7b3a6dc0c9dc28cab1f12101df257e</guid></item><item><title>An RFS Chinook flies above the Bulahdelah fire on the Mid North Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/rfs-chinook-flies-above-the-bulahdelah-fire/106110314</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dad630d4115bb5b48c742b0992b7287e</guid></item><item><title>Controversial genetically modified mosquito release paused after backlash in Qld</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/controversial-gm-friendly-mosquito-release-paused-csiro-oxitec/106108190</link><description>An organisation that planned to sell "friendly" mosquitoes to reduce the spread of diseases like dengue withdraws its licence application after backlash from scientists and health experts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99c152b0ac25af67c26215182860c9d9</guid></item><item><title>Malaysian football in chaos after FIFA suspends national players from Argentina, Spain and Brazil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/player-naturalisation-scandal-rocks-malaysian-football/106095646</link><description>A football players' union says seven South American and European members of the Malaysian national team suspended over allegedly forged documents are "victims".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4856b0aaec28e11010c2f73e3c63280</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos far from a World Cup 'group of death' against United States, Paraguay and a European qualifier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/socceroos-world-cup-draw-analysis/106110310</link><description>Nothing can be guaranteed in a World Cup, but the Socceroos' draw alongside the United States, Paraguay and a European qualifier gives a solid shot at advancing, with the Australians avoiding most of the big names.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49c5d81bdd2e928aa1bc4fde8d7d5a0b</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025 updates: Mitchell Starc's all-round brilliance puts Australia on the verge of 2-0 series lead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/ashes-second-test-live-gabba-day-three-australia-vs-england/106110146</link><description>Mitchell Starc and Scott Boland torment England with both bat and ball as Australia puts itself on the verge of claiming a 2-0 series lead in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d64b4e80361f254db5f9a88be54a499e</guid></item><item><title>Whale researchers in Timor-Leste are calling for regulation of the whale watching industry following reports of operators piloting boats too close to mammals.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/whale-tourism-in-timor-leste/106108468</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">234a2971d877726ad7e5837065f4dfeb</guid></item><item><title>Critics choice nominations 2026: Sinners scores 17 nods, One Battle After Another earns 14</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/critics-choice-awards-nominations-sinner/106110372</link><description>The gothic vampire period drama Sinners has topped the Critics' Choice Movie Awards, securing 17 nods, followed by One Battle After Another with 14.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a30900a46808c056c75a85fb6601196e</guid></item><item><title>Escapee back in custody after running from Adelaide hospital, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/escapee-who-prompted-manhunt-back-in-custody-police-say/106110628</link><description>A 36-year-old who prompted a manhunt after allegedly escaping custody at Adelaide's Queen Elizabeth Hospital on Thursday night has been re-arrested and will face court on Monday, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfe9431ed7e5eb9fa6f90cfa81d97c38</guid></item><item><title>Geraldton community raises funds and thanks responders as juveniles charged with alleged arson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/juveniles-charged-with-alleged-arson-following-geraldton-fires/106110454</link><description>While police say the investigation is over, the local community is still trying to move forward from the devastation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4122eb9d5167b06fe6f887df21b32420</guid></item><item><title>Not all babies need a hepatitis B shot at birth, US vaccine advisers say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/us-vaccine-advisers-say-not-all-babies-need-a-hepatitis-b-shot/106110932</link><description>President Donald Trump is calling the vote a "very good decision" after US vaccine advisers recommended ending the universal hepatitis B shots at birth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df40efa82146c8a5f6816b5bc09ffc1b</guid></item><item><title>Archer's English pillow, Starc's top score and a couple of firsts for England — quick hits from day three of the Gabba Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/ashes-gabba-test-day-three-england-australia-quick-hits/106110492</link><description>A sleepy Jofra Archer cops a rinsing from Matthew Hayden, as the English finally make it through the first over of an innings. Here are the quick hits from day three of the Gabba Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c64f50b01ae250aec71536d3473f161</guid></item><item><title>Politicians in South-East Asia ignore climate change at their own political peril</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/floods-thailand-climate-leadership-monsoon-torrential-rain/106097870</link><description>Accused of incompetence and apathy in the aftermath of natural disasters, governments across Asia are facing increasing backlash as the impact of global warming intensifies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17caf11fe4eac45fbe9ce13a3ecbccb6</guid></item><item><title>Opposition to social media ban scores minor political points at best</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/social-media-age-ban-albanese-government-sussan-ley-opposition/106097916</link><description>Australia's social media age ban is one of the most significant attempts to rebalance the asymmetric power relationship between government and tech.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1c19bd7f93be3f2eab79e2f3c0e9566</guid></item><item><title>How pregnancy is being criminalised in post-Roe America</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/pregnancy-criminalisation-abortion-fetal-personhood-miscarriage/106097546</link><description>In the wake of widespread abortion bans, US prosecutors launch hundreds of cases charging people with crimes related to their pregnancy, miscarriage, stillbirth or birth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b40d723313a028093c154415c269b698</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: So, you think you're good at quizzes? It's time to play HARD!</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/106090792</link><description>Alright, show us what you've got. I'll keep my expectations low.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1614ab325a4465d488e9f23ca9b12335</guid></item><item><title>Gearing up for the school holidays? Here's how to survive them without social media</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/social-media-ban-school-holidays-parenting-children/106018636</link><description>These school holidays, children under 16 will find themselves with less social media access as a ban comes into place. We asked the experts how parents can best support their kids with the transition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df818395897eaf31c4423307fd9381fe</guid></item><item><title>What life's like when you're Deaf and blind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/a-deafblind-day-in-the-life/105789718</link><description>Living with vision impairment throws up many challenges. Being Deaf on top of that requires you to go to even greater lengths just to fit in with the modern world. This is how one Deafblind woman does it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a956beee6b8ee94b7a2d6c74a16d9d78</guid></item><item><title>Rare piece of Australia's Indigenous history captured on camera in the desert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/aboriginal-elders-historical-photo-of-first-contact-lost/106010316</link><description>In the 1960s, the last of the desert families were coming into contact with white people. For one woman, the moment was captured on camera.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7abee498779fc3abfdd1edf31be65f7a</guid></item><item><title>Republicans just won an election in Tennessee but it's still bad news for Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/tennessee-special-election-van-epps-behn/106106326</link><description>A Republican claimed a win at a by-election in Tennessee this week, but his party colleagues are sounding alarm bells.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd1c905795a22c1d914b665c6c9e82aa</guid></item><item><title>Australia senses Ashes kill as England and Bazball face day of reckoning at the Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/judgement-day-arrives-for-bazball-australia-moves-in-for-kill/106110882</link><description>Australia was patient, mature and ruthless on day three at the Gabba, widening the chasm between it and an England side now set for its day of reckoning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d6ade1bbdc1dcdabd936b05843d9f68</guid></item><item><title>Reedy Creek Reserve's Paperbark Forest Walk in Agnes Water closed after tourist and environment concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/agnes-water-reedy-creek-reserve-closed-paperbark-walk/106100738</link><description>Bush Heritage Australia says it is still considering how to safely reopen the walk, which prior to closure was being visited by 100,000 people a year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17e00acf204351a585a62c7e2fea5b8e</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne council responds to lunch-thieving seagulls knocking food from pedestrians' hands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/seagulls-learn-to-knock-food-from-peoples-hands/106043826</link><description>Pesky seagulls snatching food from unsuspecting members of the public has spurred a Melbourne council to start canine patrols of Federation Square.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7f4a5d7dbae1847da8ae3200e1e7d33</guid></item><item><title>'Less algal influence' seen in some SA waters, divers say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/divers-notice-improved-marine-conditions-algal-bloom/106090962</link><description>Open water divers say underwater visibility has improved and marine life is returning to some areas off South Australia's coast. Experts say it's a positive sign, but warn it's "way too early" to say the environment is recovering from the state's algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfad2cccdd7bf4dc93dddc21091b37d3</guid></item><item><title>Number of homes destroyed in NSW bushfires rises to at least 20 as recovery efforts begin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/sixteen-homes-lost-koolewong-central-coast-fire-but-maybe-more/106110700</link><description>Natural disasters are declared in six areas across NSW, as the number of homes destroyed rises to at least 20, with the majority concentrated on the Central Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f545b09a363eca4e348ed86afcb4cacf</guid></item><item><title>Criminals are trying new methods to get drugs into Australia but authorities say they are always watching</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/attempted-drug-imports-sea-australia-mothership-smuggling/106073102</link><description>The alleged use of an international livestock ship to smuggle drugs into Western Australia last month prompted a media storm, but one expert says it is just one among a "dizzying variety" of methods criminals are trying.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4191a2f6367c22bebf14314f40b9247</guid></item><item><title>Water leaks, electric shocks force 32yo breast cancer unit off road in Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/breast-cancer-screening-bus-pulled-after-staff-electric-shocks/106090358</link><description>Tasmania's health department was aware a 32-year-old breast cancer screening bus was unsafe for years, but continued operating it up until two staff suffered electric shocks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ff63e98eda12f40f8dbbd4beb2606a5</guid></item><item><title>Insurance doctor never spoke to traumatised former NSW Police officer before challenging his mental health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/nsw-police-officer-with-ptsd-wins-insurance-case-amid-battle/106093472</link><description>A former NSW Police officer with post-traumatic stress disorder had his mental health incorrectly challenged by a doctor who never consulted or examined him during a year-long battle with the force's insurer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d5e4694754c274d6be22a3bcd766afc</guid></item><item><title>Michael Neser takes two key England wickets with caught-and-bowleds as Australia in Ashes command</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/caught-and-bowled-king-neser-feared-his-test-career-was-over/106111568</link><description>Bowling all-rounder Michael Neser is back and taking vital wickets after beginning to think he had played his last Test match for Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34ca06f197f5d99c18fee149bc7f6cce</guid></item><item><title>QVMAG costs Launceston ratepayers millions of dollars every year, but there are fears reform has hit a wall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/qvmag-launceston-future-reform/106053812</link><description>More than three years after a Tasmanian council green-lit a plan to ease the financial burden of the Queen Victoria Museum and Art Gallery, stakeholders worry momentum has stalled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c2d4c946fd4053b35bac4240de05654</guid></item><item><title>Aged care in Australia under the microscope in new documentary Careless</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/careless-documentary-film-aged-care-australia-sue-thomson/106100558</link><description>Filmmaker Sue Thomson recently lost her mum. But before that, they made the beautiful documentary Careless together, which explores Australia's aged care system mess.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7eecf0bd88b748e1bbea443583c5e1e4</guid></item><item><title>Western Australia's Port Hedland marks 50th anniversary of Cyclone Joan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/cyclone-joan-remembered-50-years-on/106105218</link><description>Cyclone Joan made landfall near the WA mining town of Port Hedland a year after Cyclone Tracy flattened Darwin, and it was almost as powerful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07b2549729e7a97acaf7b3f01384c184</guid></item><item><title>Russian drone, missile attacks target Ukrainian railways and power infrastructure in overnight barrage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/russia-attacks-ukrainian-energy-infrastructure/106111570</link><description>A large-scale Russian drone and missile attack damages power facilities in eight Ukrainian regions, causing blackouts and forcing nuclear power plants to cut output.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9e28d3b538b262a66c7d54959ae2fe5</guid></item><item><title>Fire jumps a kilometre over water, disaster declared for NSW regions — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/heatwaves-fire-live-blog-december-6/106110894</link><description>NSW Premier Chris Minns says it has been a "difficult 24 hours", with more than 20 fires still uncontained across the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c18a4d1320eaa2ffec3079f7378c5589</guid></item><item><title>Researchers are teaching foxes not to eat freshwater turtle eggs, by making them feel sick</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/training-foxes-to-stop-killing-native-turtles-aversion-condition/106026320</link><description>Researchers in Victoria are using taste aversion conditioning to stop foxes eating native turtle eggs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">904402fb27dc1fd3146ccac2d254e7e0</guid></item><item><title>Questions raised about Gavin Morris's suitability as Yipirinya School principal after conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/questions-gavin-morris-yipirinya-school-principal-conviction/106106750</link><description>Former Yipirinya School principal Gavin Morris has been found guilty of aggravated assault against students, but questions have been raised about Morris's hiring and his suitability for the role.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dd85f356137ce6beb04f61f0ac4aed2</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos FIFA World Cup 2026 times, dates and locations set, with games in Vancouver, Seattle and Santa Clara</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/socceroos-set-for-wild-west-north-american-world-cup-adventure/106111662</link><description>Australia's North American west coast adventure at the World Cup is confirmed, with matches in Vancouver, Seattle and Santa Clara in California.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7aaff72b6b041c20050aa4cde13783c</guid></item><item><title>Australia's new land clearing, regrowth laws spark concern among farmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/farmer-concerns-as-australian-land-clearing-laws-tighten/106104878</link><description>Queensland producers say a blanket approach to environmental laws will restrict their ability to manage land sustainably and responsibly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbd94438aad374b26c5da2a12aabe40c</guid></item><item><title>Prime minister's office approved Anika Wells's almost-$100,000 flights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/pmo-approved-wells-flights/106111598</link><description>The furore over Communications Minister Anika Wells's expenses continues, with just three days until the government's much-anticipated social media ban for under 16s comes into force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee55c4ecfec6b883eecfce1559d5f1b5</guid></item><item><title>Iconic Lagoon restaurant lease ends after 40 colourful and controversial years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/wollongong-iconic-lagoon-restaurant-lease-ends/106077292</link><description>For four decades Lagoon Restaurant has been one of Wollongong's most iconic and controversial establishments, enjoying a prime seaside location and a close relationship with the city's political class.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43794c1266f909517717039f3c339315</guid></item><item><title>Surf Life Saving WA brings all-abilities nippers program to regions for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/regional-first-for-all-abilities-nippers-surf-lifesaving/106093904</link><description>Catering to children with autism spectrum disorders, it is the first of its kind in regional Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08a0fa804bc4bd0a70cb58c4f3aad91a</guid></item><item><title>Cleveland Dodd inquest findings expected to unpack dysfunction in WA's youth justice system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/coroner-to-hand-down-cleveland-dodd-inquest-findings-/106105718</link><description>The coroner investigating WA’s first recorded death in youth detention is expected to hand down wide-ranging findings and recommendations following the death of 16-year-old Cleveland Dodd in 2022. Here's everything you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47288d99a3815da2fad534c77f62d2f9</guid></item><item><title>Aerial view of bushfire destruction in northern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/aerial-view-of-bushfire-destruction-in-northern-nsw/106111894</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73a8f5b5ea93981b016a93ba7d568bdc</guid></item><item><title>Firefighting aircraft battle raging bushfires in northern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/firefighting-helicopters-battle-raging-bushfires-in-northern-nsw/106111892</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aacacb1a2f4512d4ae24f606b7415f35</guid></item><item><title>Bridget Murphy reports from fire ground in Redhead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/bridget-murphy-reports-from-fire-ground-in-redhead-/106111864</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53bd446aa3217d3c748c96da76357dc1</guid></item><item><title>Child of Stolen Generations in WA given her birth certificate after 88 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/stolen-generation-survivor-given-birth-certificate/106074930</link><description>Maisie Harkin was born on country in Western Australia's Great Victoria Desert. It has taken 88 years for her birth to be officially recognised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62e588a6410a278cd6b6455bf3e6e671</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters battle blaze in Redhead, Lake Macquarie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/firefighters-battle-blaze-in-redhead-lake-macquarie/106112010</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11fe15b5b4fe13e9b2f945014afb97dc</guid></item><item><title>Four arrested after food thrown at Crown Jewels display case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/four-arrested-after-food-thrown-at-crown-jewels-display/106111940</link><description>An organisation called Take Back Power, which describes itself as a civil resistance group, posted footage of the incident on social media and said two of its members had smothered the Imperial State Crown display case with apple crumble and custard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6548036014f4b677aeaddf17bdf3eeb</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025 updates: Steve Smith and Jofra Archer in fiery clash as Australia wins second Test against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/ashes-live-gabba-test-day-four-australia-vs-england/106111832</link><description>Australian captain Steve Smith lets his bat do the talking following a fiery exchange with Jofra Archer in an eight-wicket win in the second Test in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f1b74fe8e3fff6ef045a8fd32663c93</guid></item><item><title>The $108 billion Warner Bros and Netflix deal has sparked backlash — here's why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/what-the-netflix-warner-bros-merger-means-amid-controversy/106111948</link><description>A major deal between Netflix and Warner Bros has sent shock waves through Hollywood and sparked backlash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c5b49941b708628215a93a2b57a70ed</guid></item><item><title>Unpause and rewind: Cassette tapes are making a comeback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/cassette-tapes-are-making-a-comeback/106102136</link><description>For a supposedly obsolete music format, audio cassette sales seem to be set on fast forward at the moment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44b393e1bbc4bba401dd313c21117f0c</guid></item><item><title>South Australian distillers tap into trending thirst for limoncello</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/limoncello-tradition-trend-alcohol-south-australia/106077938</link><description>South Australian distillers are tapping into a growing global thirst for limoncello and finding a new market for lemons and grape spirit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eac2197d4c58b3bca193cfa97b9fc4c2</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania Fire Service confirms 19 homes destroyed and nearly 200 assets damaged in Dolphin Sands bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/dolphin-sands-residents-weigh-up-bushfire-risk/106111658</link><description>The Tasmania Fire Service confirms 19 homes have been claimed by a bushfire that ripped through Dolphin Sands this week, while nearly 200 assets have been damaged.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26ee56f15a04beadc995bbad8e91369f</guid></item><item><title>Albanese defends Anika Wells' weekend in Thredbo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/albanese-defends-anika-wells-weekend-in-thredbo-/106112252</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8727180d3e520acd8cf54da37f35175e</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters attend to smouldering homes in Koolewong, NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/firefighters-attend-to-smouldering-homes-in-koolewong-nsw/106112296</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4757ac3a3698c678aef8d64be2412a3c</guid></item><item><title>Record number of temporary residents in Australia - 7 December 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/record-number-of-temporary-residents-in-australia-/106112346</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c904f5b96f0f4a168bcaa5271462f0da</guid></item><item><title>Man smashes ambulance windscreen with head in Kalgoorlie-Boulder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/amulance-windscreen-smashed-by-community-member/106112330</link><description>A video circulated on social media shows a naked male using his head to smash the windscreen of a moving ambulance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33a142b37be9a826fb48feaf00b73ca2</guid></item><item><title>Birch by Romeo Lane nightclub fire in India's Goa state kills at least 25 people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/fire-goa-nightclub-kills-25/106112514</link><description>Local village council official Roshan Redkar tells a news agency that authorities had earlier issued a demolition notice for the club as it had no construction permit from the government, but higher officials rolled back the order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e744d8d981c5194ad55cdd71ee568c21</guid></item><item><title>Japan and Australia urge calm after Chinese radar locks onto Japanese jets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/australia-and-japan-urge-calm-after-chinese-radar-locks-jets/106112526</link><description>Japan formally protests the incident, calling it "an extremely regrettable" and dangerous act that "exceeded the scope necessary for safe aircraft operations".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27d322c26523ac3fb38305e86556e60e</guid></item><item><title>Smith fires up, Bazball leaves the building and a miraculous grab — quick hits from day four of the Gabba Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/ashes-day-four-quick-hits-smith-archer-stokes/106112152</link><description>Smith "champs" Archer, Bazball leaves the building and the Australian captain breaks the game open with a miraculous grab. Here are the quick hits from the fourth and final day of the Gabba Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6ba650280f3a6ceb3b2e2da4950a896</guid></item><item><title>Ben Stokes questions England's ability to handle Ashes pressure as Brendon McCullum warns of 'glass jaw'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/ben-stokes-brendon-mccullum-ashes-pressure-reaction/106110490</link><description>England's famed captain-coach duo aren't going to let their relationship fray in the face of the biggest test of their polarising tenure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c67b486eeeb03575c3b909dbdb4b94e</guid></item><item><title>Is it ever OK to leave a party or social event without saying goodbye?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/is-it-ever-ok-to-leave-party-social-event-without-saying-goodbye/106102146</link><description>We asked two experts for their advice on the etiquette of leaving a social gathering without notice and the best approaches to take if you do need to depart suddenly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f883ec7fc9efd90b556602eaec850898</guid></item><item><title>Australia and Steve Smith chase total Ashes domination as England pokes the bear in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/australia-is-out-for-ashes-domination-england-poked-the-bear/106112388</link><description>The snarl on Steve Smith's face proves conclusively that Australia doesn't just want to beat the English in this Ashes series. It wants to break them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8aad39a86986584da1d955db5d9d571f</guid></item><item><title>Have you been involved in a multi-level marketing business? Tell us your MLM story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/audience-callout-mlm-schemes-multi-level-marketing/106100604</link><description>Multi-level marketing networks have been around for decades. But their business models are changing, with consumer advocates warning that the industry is rife with predatory tactics. We want to hear about your experiences with MLMs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f2ac4367142e66fc108bd2b5bac5d47</guid></item><item><title>Australian MLM influencers are cashing in on the manosphere</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/multi-level-marketing-giant-enagic-accused-of-preadatory-tactics/105065260</link><description>A global multi-level-marketing business that sells expensive water ionisers is shifting its target audience to Aussie tradies, but critics say some of their predatory sales tactics are tantamount to a pyramid scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0e9050f1adfb8f45aafbb3485f5d0a3</guid></item><item><title>Devastated families grapple with ferocity of NSW Central Coast bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/nsw-central-coast-families-devasted-by-fierce-koolewong-bushfire/106111938</link><description>Residents on the NSW coast are coming to terms with property loss after bushfires swept through the region on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65624e96ff54c17f0c863108c3ebae98</guid></item><item><title>How Europe is gearing up to follow Australia's teen social media ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/how-europe-may-follow-australias-teen-social-media-ban/106035946</link><description>The European Union says it will learn from Australia's new laws to bar under-16s from social media, with steps to implement the world-first ban already underway and European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen praising Australia's "brave move".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55c8ac89d0b35b01d09cc1e297835546</guid></item><item><title>Communities harness the people power of co-ops to stave off privatisation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/castlemaine-cooperative-privatisation-economic-democracy/106103270</link><description>For its passionate members, saving a historic goldrush-era pub to protect their cooperative was about "economic democracy" and keeping the property out of developers' hands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ef75db79dadf3fd81685d34b6c2fb6e</guid></item><item><title>First-home buyers on government's MyHome scheme struggling to get sellers on board</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/buyers-purchasing-property-with-myhome-shared-equity-scheme/106009682</link><description>When Regan buys his first home, the government will own around 30 per cent of it. But he is fast realising that for that to even happen, a lot of things have to fall into place.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5feedf17c76acc7f38f85f248f101af4</guid></item><item><title>Russia increases recruitment of foreign fighters through targeted social media campaigns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/russia-recruitment-of-foreign-fighters-increases/106096108</link><description>Through a targeted social media campaign, Russia is offering citizenship and money to foreigners who join its fight in Ukraine, but experts say it is a desperate measure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4ee2dd53a43ee1b9f3a58ae1ab06442</guid></item><item><title>China's global technology and engineering ascendancy continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/china-us-technology-engineering-ai-plan-australia/106111696</link><description>China used to be trying to catch the West, specifically the US. Then it caught up. Now the West is trying to catch up to China, but likely can't.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73f515ced6456e40883658e372daaa99</guid></item><item><title>Exploitation fears over SA government aged care changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/elder-exploitation-fears-over-sa-aged-care-law-changes/106105940</link><description>The South Australian government is trying to speed up the transfer of hospital patients into aged care, but advocates say they are "trampling on the rights of older people" in the process.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40c41c3a15163c4ca5aec5bf5a984ef2</guid></item><item><title>Anika Wells's taxpayer-funded Thredbo ski trip a costly distraction for Labor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/anika-wells-travel-expenses-scandal-albanese-labor/106112088</link><description>What was meant to be a Sunday interview bookending a remarkable political year became an exercise in explaining the inexplicable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b8486cb5a97efe3b165f4060c2c7fa4</guid></item><item><title>Crops preferred to sheep in large parts of Australia's traditional mixed farming regions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/crops-preferred-to-sheep-in-traditional-mixed-farming-regions/106035940</link><description>Mixed farming, which involves growing crops and rearing livestock, used to be standard practice in Australia, but there are almost 100 million fewer sheep in Australia than there were 35 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3a750e588866118fa491cdd0f9f1d85</guid></item><item><title>Muster Dogs favourite Frank Finger makes final on-screen appearance with kelpie Annie in portrait show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/muster-dogs-frank-finger-annie-portrait-artist-of-the-year-tv/106073124</link><description>From hit series Muster Dogs to a new television show, Frank Finger and his beloved kelpie Annie's unbreakable bond steals the spotlight once again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa07300da9bf7b69d2501baa6ae26b21</guid></item><item><title>A year after the fall of Bashar Al-Assad, Syrians are scraping by</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/a-year-since-liberation-syrians-cautiously-celebrate-scrape-by/106112708</link><description>Today marks one year since the Assad dictatorship in Syria was toppled by Islamist rebels, bringing an end to nearly 14 years of civil war. Some are celebrating, while others continue to struggle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de06d898a7b2c881a7fbd7c1f302fb27</guid></item><item><title>Health regulator accused of failing to support patients amid complaints over doctors' conduct</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/ahpra-complaint-inappropriate-doctor-examination-queensland/106097566</link><description>Two women have told the ABC they believe the health regulator is failing to acknowledge the power imbalance between doctors and patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56c6fc8e1d4c1e7a8f7cb8a03ff94c4a</guid></item><item><title>Victoria Police apologises for misgendering trans woman after two-year legal battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/victoria-police-apologises-for-misgendering-trans-woman/106086058</link><description>Victoria Police fought a legal battle with a transgender woman for more than two years before admitting it incorrectly referred her to men's support services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8834dd29818387e55e6397c7c5652d0b</guid></item><item><title>Where Oscar Piastri lost the Formula 1 world championship, McLaren teammate Lando Norris claims ultimate prize</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/oscar-piastri-missed-f1-world-title-through-minor-moments/106113184</link><description>Oscar Piastri missed out on winning the Formula 1 drivers world championship by just 13 points to his teammate Lando Norris, the culmination of multiple small moments throughout the season that cost him dearly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb082e3701f1fe8b29d4db1328f26f4e</guid></item><item><title>Hotline claims to have identified more than 200 alleged historical child abuse offenders in secretive Christian sect</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/aus-hotline-identifies-200-alleged-offenders-in-christian-sect/106044742</link><description>Jillian Hishon has devoted hundreds of hours, listening to an estimated 280 victims of historical child sexual abuse from within the fundamentalist Christian church she grew up in.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">033e27e3826a7171cd062d10d7213252</guid></item><item><title>The US fired on survivors clinging to a 'drug boat' — who gave the order?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/pete-hegseth-venezuela-boat-strike/106101966</link><description>What happened in the lead-up to a second strike on a speedboat in the Caribbean — who knew what and when, and who gave what order — is now under scrutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e0a0ab2661d3088030ebb72d729a0eb</guid></item><item><title>Interstate clerical abuse survivors reflect on horrors and remember lives lost to suicide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/clerical-abuser-survivors-from-newcastle-and-ballarat-remember/106095424</link><description>Newcastle and Ballarat are 1,100 kilometres apart but share a dark bond — scores of suicide deaths linked to historical Catholic clergy abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">046b50681c789f56cfafc00265ea1770</guid></item><item><title>Murray-Darling Basin predicted to be hotter and drier by 2050 if nothing changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/murray-darling-basin-outlook-predicts-hotter-drier-by-2050/106091334</link><description>Water needs for river communities will be under increasing pressure over the next 25 years, according to predictions from the Murray-Darling Basin Authority.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ed309817c90e9e5c1a0070f6fa21fd3</guid></item><item><title>Protesters mount legal challenge to Victoria Police designated area declaration for Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/legal-challenge-police-designated-area-melbourne/106113444</link><description>A legal challenge is launched against a "designated area" declaration for Melbourne's CBD that gives police greater powers to search people without a warrant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c352fe0d6f210955fd459976e7ba2cc</guid></item><item><title>59yo NPWS firefighter killed by falling tree during bushfire prevention work at Nerong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/npws-firefighter-killed-by-falling-tree/106113538</link><description>A National Parks and Wildlife Service firefighter dies after being crushed by a tree during bushfire prevention work north of Newcastle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">561ad6d42df6b53a4d5d78d2893973dc</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Barnaby Joyce joins One Nation weeks after leaving Nationals — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/cph-pols-blog-dec-8/106113524</link><description>Former deputy prime minister Barnaby Joyce has joined One Nation after leaving the Nationals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0dda282736f165176cca4c3002e5f13</guid></item><item><title>Rory McIlroy did not win Australian Open but still completed one of his missions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/rory-mcilroy-restores-australian-open-prestige/106112750</link><description>Rory McIlroy's appearance at the Australian Open in Melbourne has gone a long way to restoring the prestige of the tournament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08480b9f91bf40b93667e71c6b206a6c</guid></item><item><title>New NT training program aims to attract and keep home tutors at remote stations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/training-program-aims-to-attract-and-keep-home-tutors/106096712</link><description>A course offered for the first time this year has upskilled home tutors working on remote central Australian cattle stations in a bid to ease education workforce shortages in the outback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0477d8345ddb6d66f02fe540b09a33f7</guid></item><item><title>WA economic regulator accuses power generators of overcharging utilities for wholesale electricity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/wa-power-producers-accused-overcharging-wholesale-electricity/106109294</link><description>The cost of electricity is being driven up by some Western Australian power producers breaking the rules and charging more than they're allowed, the state's economic watchdog alleges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">860ad6b80841060e4f6090269832620d</guid></item><item><title>Hitchhiking Pilbara mechanic Kevin Guiness recounts a lifetime on the road</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/hitchhiking-pilbara-mechanic-recounts-life-on-the-road/105845782</link><description>At 12 years old, Kevin Guiness was rebuilding engines on an outback cattle station. Now, after decades travelling the dusty roads in the Pilbara, the Yindjibarndi elder reflects on what kept him going.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63597aedacce7b26b6bd91fdc2853622</guid></item><item><title>How the internet reacted to Australia winning the second Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/how-the-internet-reacted-to-the-second-ashes-test/106102100</link><description>Mitchell Starc was the hero, again, as the English were comprehensively outplayed in Brisbane — but how did the internet react?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54a7ad441f6e075cb25a030091f327da</guid></item><item><title>Brendon McCullum says England 'over-prepared' ahead of Brisbane Test, as players head to Noosa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/ashes-2025-brendon-mccullum-says-england-trained-too-hard/106113606</link><description>England coach Brendon McCullum claims his team trained too hard for the Gabba Test, which ended in a bruising eight-wicket loss that leaves the tourists' Ashes hopes in tatters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a036f962842a5cadbc8e4bdc053a51b</guid></item><item><title>Kremlin praises Donald Trump's national security strategy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/russia-welcomes-donald-trumps-national-security-strategy/106113490</link><description>The strategy argues the US should revive the 19th century Monroe Doctrine, which declared the Western hemisphere to be Washington's zone of influence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">335c9f75f5b6876f832a8beac9835170</guid></item><item><title>'Everything destroyed' as Indonesia's Aceh grapples with disease after floods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/indonesia-aceh-grapples-with-disease-after-floods/106113542</link><description>Hit by deadly floods, Indonesians in the region around Aceh Tamiang are grappling with worsening diseases and a lack of medical care at the lone hospital in the area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3474ba744c45bf27f842c7d2d152ad4c</guid></item><item><title>City of Rockingham residents complain of maggots and flies after FOGO introduction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/perth-garbage-bins-leave-residents-unhappy/106112238</link><description>Perth residents say they are dealing with an "infestation of maggots" and stinking rubbish after the introduction of a third bin for food and garden waste. But the local council is adamant it will not be making any changes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">942d178ff66f8fa6776a5dfe4df5cdaf</guid></item><item><title>Jessica Stenson breaks Australian women's marathon record during Valencia race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/jessica-stenson-breaks-australian-womens-marathon-record/106113722</link><description>Jessica Stenson breaks the Australian marathon record before an emotional phone call to the former record holder, Sinead Diver.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a5a9164a7e8010a9906a27913e4be33</guid></item><item><title>How would your feed look if you got to control what you saw on social media?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/chanel-contos-teach-us-consent-fix-our-feed/106107546</link><description>Sexual violence prevention group Teach Us Consent is pushing for Australians to have the choice to "opt-in" to social media algorithms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5f4437d61b6c09b76d3d735425df36e</guid></item><item><title>Notorious paedophile Ashley Paul Griffith could have been 'detected and disrupted earlier', damning review finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/qld-ashley-paul-griffith-child-death-review-board/106113728</link><description>The Queensland government in January ordered a review into how one of the country's most notorious paedophiles was able to offend for so long.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3a6483979fe027797f823689ba2265a</guid></item><item><title>Benin President Patrice Talon says coup attempt thwarted with help from Nigerian military</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/benin-coup-attempt-thwarted/106114130</link><description>Patrice Talon says the West African nation's government will punish those responsible for a coup attempt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ea8421ac418ad9f8ca71e83b162b1df</guid></item><item><title>Cleveland Dodd's care in Unit 18 'inhumane', coroner examining youth detention death finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/cleveland-dodds-care-in-youth-detention-inhumane-coroner-finds/106112004</link><description>Western Australia's first recorded death in youth detention was predictable, a coroner finds, declaring the care of 16-year-old Cleveland Dodd was "inhumane" and "reminiscent of 19th century jails". WARNING: This story contains the name and image of an Indigenous person who has died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6ae9813e2e602a349029e2320971ce1</guid></item><item><title>Water leak at the Louvre museum damages hundreds of works</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/hunderds-of-works-damaged-in-water-leak-at-louvre-museum/106114116</link><description>The leak occurred after a valve was accidentally opened in a heating and ventilation system, allowing water to seep through the ceiling of the Mollien wing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcd11071a8244d998a994b13c1876405</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce joins One Nation, concluding defection from Nationals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/barnaby-joyce-joins-one-nation/106114758</link><description>Barnaby Joyce's defection gives One Nation its first lower house seat since 1998.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">278b33937863e280a5410062430ada30</guid></item><item><title>England's lack of Ashes depth highlighted as Australia A thumps Lions at Allan Border Field</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/australia-a-thumps-england-lions-to-highlight-ashes-problem/106114756</link><description>England's lack of Test depth is highlighted as Australia A beats the Lions by an innings and 127 runs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cb0896b3276dafa3d9d5ad9a03b7b6e</guid></item><item><title>Government will not extend energy bill relief</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/government-will-not-extend-energy-bill-relief/106114842</link><description>Jim Chalmers says the end to the "temporary" subsidy was a "hard" decision but recognises pressures on the budget.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55398d2d5d6a262e7d4a8cd38ce0ebd8</guid></item><item><title>Thailand launches air strikes amid new border clashes with Cambodia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/thailand-launches-air-strikes-on-cambodia-border-clashes/106114878</link><description>Thailand launches air strikes along its disputed border with Cambodia, after both countries accuse one another of breaching a ceasefire agreement brokered by US President Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fff6be86fabeb871f89a1632dbbb598f</guid></item><item><title>Men jailed for gang raping women at Newcastle bucks weekend have convictions quashed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/convictions-quashed-for-men-jailed-for-newcastle-gang-rape/106114374</link><description>Marius Hawell, his brother and a friend have had their convictions thrown out on grounds of appeal, after being handed jail sentences of between nine and 14 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">defbb35bad98e43fb9702ee6c0c45d1a</guid></item><item><title>One of PNG's rare conjoined twins dies after urgent surgery in Sydney, brother survives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/png-conjoined-twins-tom-sawong-surgery-sydney/106113822</link><description>Surgeons have separated a rare set of conjoined twins after they were urgently flown from Papua New Guinea to Australia, but only one of the boys has survived.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a079440a2938e807240cbf33338baccc</guid></item><item><title>Police charge 18-year-old man allegedly involved in fatal Ascot Vale stabbing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/police-lay-charges-over-alleged-ascot-vale-stabbing-melbourne/106114822</link><description>Police charge an 18-year-old man with offences including intentionally causing injury and affray, following the incident that claimed the life of a 40-year-old in Ascot Vale on Sunday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe81c4b31349b3ab20a88cd539f3afc7</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government facing fresh legal challenge over controversial puberty blocker ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/qld-puberty-blocker-ban-legal-action/106113504</link><description>The action is being taken on behalf of the same mother of a transgender teenager who previously successfully fought the state's first ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61e6a01e91c0d489e7a445db2a87bc97</guid></item><item><title>Coalition puts heat on Wells over trips to cricket and AFL with family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/coalition-anika-wells-cricket-expenses-travel/106113546</link><description>The Coalition is applying more heat to Sport Minister Anika Wells over flights she claimed for herself and her husband to attend two Boxing Day cricket test matches in recent years, and several AFL Grand Final events.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4275bb62ee4e0bc79aac67e67b200901</guid></item><item><title>Dolphin Sands resident 'frustrated' by official communication after bushfire destroys homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/tasmania-dolphin-sands-bushfire-community-dismayed/106113646</link><description>More questions have been raised about the official warnings ahead of a bushfire that destroyed 19 homes in a tiny Tasmanian seaside community where there is one road in and out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be856664e93eb4ff4b5a4acac5ddecad</guid></item><item><title>Lithium-ion battery suspected to have sparked Caroline Springs house fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/lithium-ion-battery-house-fire-caroline-springs-warning/106114446</link><description>Fire services are urging people to buy lithium-ion battery products from reputable suppliers ahead of Christmas after yet another house fire was suspected to have been caused by a lithium battery on the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">800cb01f4ed7114abcce14e86bc10fa4</guid></item><item><title>Perth man Adam Simon McGovern guilty of making 'upskirt' videos of women, girls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/adam-simon-mcgovern-guilty-upskirt-videos/106109500</link><description>A man who made 'upskirt' videos of women and girls in public places in Perth is found guilty of multiple charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e73ec0fd540f983efc3419f5592f39d4</guid></item><item><title>Toddler's septic tank death 'likely would have been prevented' with sufficient NT government maintenance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/nt-septic-tank-death-toddler-remote-community-coroners-report/106114688</link><description>A coroner's report has found there were multiple missed opportunities to improve or replace the public housing septic system, which the NT government had responsibility for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98d947177f624dd68d704b5339256202</guid></item><item><title>Australian Ashes openers Travis Head and Jake Weatherald praised as Usman Khawaja call looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/ashes-test-series-travis-head-jake-weatherald-usman-khawaja/106116580</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne says Australia's opening partnership is making the rest of the batting order improve, as selectors deliberate over Usman Khawaja's Test future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd19c84e600636615e42a245d0785fe1</guid></item><item><title>Should you go screen-free after giving birth? These mums share their stories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/mums-mental-health-online-postpartum/106086872</link><description>Readers share how they approached their online and social media use in the weeks immediately after giving birth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42d427354161a31e013bc51ecf3cbd12</guid></item><item><title>The 'missed details' that enabled childcare paedophile Ashley Paul Griffith to abuse dozens of children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/how-ashley-paul-griffith-could-have-been-stopped/106116080</link><description>A review has identified 18 points or "missed opportunities" where Ashley Paul Griffith's offending could have been disrupted or stopped, had a different action been taken.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">151fd06e0d843e05fc25d090a880300c</guid></item><item><title>Trump hosts Kennedy Center Honors in historic first</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/trump-makes-history-hosting-the-kennedy-center-honors/106115478</link><description>Donald Trump has made the Kennedy Center a touchstone in a broader attack against what he claims is "woke", anti-American culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1c346ecf0726a7d78fd03b0d4f5725b</guid></item><item><title>Rajwinder Singh found guilty of Toyah Cordingley's 2018 murder on Far North Queensland beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/rajwinder-singh-guilty-toyah-cordingley-murder/106102518</link><description>It took a jury in the Supreme Court in Cairns seven hours to reach the unanimous guilty verdict after an almost four-week retrial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86c525c4287096b2882fd5a6e52a2d18</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of raping elderly woman in NSW aged care home gives evidence at his trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/coffs-harbour-aged-care-home-sexual-assault-trial/106114170</link><description>Hayden Carl Skinner tells the District Court in Coffs Harbour that the open doors of the facility inspired a "spur of the moment" break-in to settle a drug debt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1d80f4c2537f29e425e29f3197794ea</guid></item><item><title>More than 30 zinc sunscreen brands using formula that failed preliminary SPF testing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/zinc-sunscreen-brands-spf-testing-lower-than-advertising/106050396</link><description>It's been almost two years since Craig Jones first ran preliminary tests on his zinc sunscreen. When he discovered it wasn't providing the SPF it was supposed to he threw it out and set out on a quest to find out why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4753ebb9b4860304072af5ef3e08466</guid></item><item><title>NSW man jailed over single-vehicle crash that killed three friends near Tarago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/act-driver-jailed-over-tarago-crash-that-killed-three-friends/106114392</link><description>A young driver who crashed his car near Tarago, killing his girlfriend and two friends, has been sentenced to more than six years in jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f885d2e9cb8f54393b2121ff122592b</guid></item><item><title>NRL proposes lengthy bans for Tonga officials following Eli Katoa head knocks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/nrl-tonga-officials-face-bans-over-eli-katoa-incident/106116872</link><description>Three Tonga team officials are facing two-year suspensions following the NRL's investigation into the incident that forced Eli Katoa out of the 2026 season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27f95fe22540f5745ec85088c7fcfb22</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106116270</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea3bba99a227f19b6ea86a8bd7bd1346</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder over death of Nikkita Azzopardi found not guilty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/man-charged-with-murder-of-nikkita-azzopardi-found-not-guilty/106116296</link><description>The family of a Melbourne woman who was brutally killed by her partner say they're distraught after the man was found not guilty due to mental impairment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58827c3667eb8e4d2a0cbfca8f90bfa0</guid></item><item><title>Australia braces for more threats from bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/australia-braces-for-more-threats-from-bushfires-/106117072</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">091a60684b81dc3b31373f5ebcc49a58</guid></item><item><title>Perth boy's death in Department of Communities care may have been accidental, inquest told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/inquest-examines-death-of-10-year-old-boy-in-state-care/106112324</link><description>An inquest hears the 2024 death of a 10-year-old Indigenous boy while he was under the care of the Department of Communities may have been an accident, not suicide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83ca7dea763d310cb801eb99d903a67c</guid></item><item><title>Clermont's only GP clinic closes after hospital doctor suspended</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/clermont-hospital-doctor-tim-lane-suspended-after-dispute/106113774</link><description>The suspension of Tim Lane leaves a Central Queensland town of 3,000 people with no permanent hospital doctor or GP.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d72146816b82719750eec96cfb2ce126</guid></item><item><title>Queensland primary school teacher jailed for child sexual abuse, exploitation material</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/cairns-teacher-sentenced-child-exploitation/106113986</link><description>A former Cairns state primary school teacher has been jailed for 17 years for dozens of child exploitation offences involving children from the school where he worked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fcd102994a16aaf2dc887acd5e38dce</guid></item><item><title>Ellenbrook Secondary School in lockdown after student stabbed in knife attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/ellenbrook-secondary-college-lockdown-after-stabbing/106117516</link><description>A teenage boy is taken to hospital after being stabbed in the arm in a "targeted" knife attack that saw a Perth high school go into lockdown on Monday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41a9621a94bd02d070cbdfef806f28e9</guid></item><item><title>Thailand-Cambodia border conflict reignites.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/thailand-cambodia-border-conflict-reignites/106117524</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71ed64bea61eb140d343da497cb72d80</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce likens One Nation to Reform UK party under Nigel Farage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/barnaby-joyce-joins-pauline-hanson-in-one-nation/106116240</link><description>In his first interview since formally joining One Nation, Barnaby Joyce says he sees comparisons between his new party and Britain's far-right Reform UK party under populist leader Nigel Farage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec46698bc1eba717753f4b4770c24910</guid></item><item><title>Renters need $300,000 more superannuation in retirement than home owners, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/renters-need-twice-more-super-than-home-owners-in-retirement/106104784</link><description>Rising rents mean older Australians who are not home owners will need twice as much superannuation to enjoy the same retirement lifestyle as those who are mortgage-free, according to a study by a leading advocacy group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f0e8be479137557c82638664cac88ce</guid></item><item><title>Magnitude-7.6 earthquake in Japan prompts tsunami warning and evacuation order for 90,000 people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/japan-earthquake-prompts-tsunami-warning/106117964</link><description>The quake has seen a tsunami warning issued for large parts of Japan's northern coastline and about 90,000 people ordered to evacuate to higher ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bb4b46720be5433eaa15872180e00ad</guid></item><item><title>Jacob Elordi, Rose Byrne and Joel Edgerton score Golden Globes nominations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/golden-globe-nominations-2025/106117782</link><description>Jacob Elordi is Australia's big hope at the Golden Globes after scoring two nominations overnight for the 83rd iteration of the film and television awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aebf576e95042edfa57508a1e792b2c0</guid></item><item><title>Australia's favourite political test depends on who is at the pub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/barnaby-joyce-annabel-crabb-expenses-one-nation-defection/106114804</link><description>The "pub test" tends to be applied when we've run out of avenues to pursue a public figure, but are still super annoyed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bb613641045e771ebed97e24f6e6ad9</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 9: How smallpox was eradicated after killing 300 million people in the 20th century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/smallpox-eradication-infectious-disease-ring-vaccination/105999388</link><description>The eradication of smallpox 46 years ago has been hailed as the greatest triumph of global public health. It has also been held up as a model for global cooperation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd95131d8068f6201274ad73e3783a82</guid></item><item><title>For some teenagers, 'life is better' without social media and they support the ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/teenagers-who-support-social-media-ban/106095948</link><description>Patrick, 15, does not use social media and hopes he never does. Nick, 15, had a flip phone for the first few years of high school. Here is why they support the social media ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11cd0cfc0070dd985225db4602176ddc</guid></item><item><title>Fluke discoveries of asbestos in children's sand strike twice decades apart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/fluke-discoveries-asbestos-children-play-sand-decades-apart/106056760</link><description>A doctor in the US who found asbestos in his son's sandpit tried in vain to get stronger regulations. Almost 40 years later he says he's "not surprised" the problem re-emerged in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">073011ed164029fa273c9d40b51498b2</guid></item><item><title>A logical gas exports policy could put the economy back on an even keel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/time-to-fix-gas-policy-to-ease-inflation-cost-of-living-pressure/106116030</link><description>For a decade, a disaster has unfolded. We've run short of gas through indecision and incompetence, and that's driving energy costs and inflation. We need a solution and an unlikely source may have one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">474f58cf1e220611fdd153145a49d0a9</guid></item><item><title>Domestic violence survivors using strength training for trauma recovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/west-project-domestic-violence-survivors-strength-training/106046732</link><description>In a suburban Canberra gym, no questions are asked. If you identify as a domestic violence survivor, you're in. The WEST Project is an innovative program helping women build themselves back up through powerlifting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19150622edf2f22115c32dd67228de96</guid></item><item><title>Wells spends thousands on Comcars to attend grand finals, but has plenty of company</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/wells-spends-thousands-on-comcars-for-grand-finals/106117742</link><description>The sports minister has endured scrutiny over her use of parliamentary expenses, but is one of dozens of MPs to have accumulated large Comcar bills.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">539e905664a43e0090610d9a8afe2e80</guid></item><item><title>Halfbrick Studios CEO Shainiel Deo on creating the first Bluey video game made in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/bluey-video-game-halfbrick-studios-brisbane/106113906</link><description>Halfbrick Studios, the company behind Fruit Ninja, has created the first ever Bluey video game made in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1957f4f6e0250e77e45f7285388a026</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy meets with European allies as Donald Trump accuses him of not reading US-led peace plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/zelenskyy-european-allies-downing-street-trump/106117756</link><description>European leaders express scepticism about US-led plans to end Russia's invasion, following peace talks between US and Ukrainian officials end without a breakthrough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a788d9da4a6464c4aa1a3f92e35c20a</guid></item><item><title>Moment magnitude-7.6 earthquake strikes near Japan’s coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/moment-magnitude-7-6-earthquake-strikes-near-japan-s-coast/106118186</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6c3f48e38de8a8b929215f4f8541fbf</guid></item><item><title>Penny Wong and Richard Marles meet US counterparts in Washington after AUKUS review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/marles-wong-hegseth-rubio-hold-ausmin-talks-aukus-defence/106118088</link><description>The recommendations made by the US's recent review of the AUKUS pact remain confidential after the talks in Washington, where the two nations have committed to the continued growth of the American military presence in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2ad9c9f6e38d4d71c90442aa95f7e80</guid></item><item><title>From a Barossa 'baronial' background, Ashton Hurn has risen to the SA Liberal leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/ashton-hurn-explainer-following-liberal-leadership/106111804</link><description>South Australia's new opposition leader Ashton Hurn has likened the task ahead of her to climbing a mountain, but she's taking inspiration from a family background that includes a former state cricketer and an AFL premiership captain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa54cf54be49af6d3ed9ac168f41e2f2</guid></item><item><title>Victorian government makes historic apology to Aboriginal people following signing of treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/government-apology-to-aboriginal-victorians-after-treaty/106116798</link><description>The Victorian government has made a historic apology to Aboriginal Victorians, in one of the first public acts to follow the signing of the state's treaty agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c287b141c7986bd0cde18ca5ae9b903f</guid></item><item><title>Paramount counters Netflix with hostile bid for Warner Bros Discovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/paramount-hostile-bid-warner-bros-netflix/106118082</link><description>The offer paves the way for a battle between Paramount — whose owner, Larry Ellison, is an ally of Donald Trump — and streaming behemoth Netflix to buy one of Hollywood's most storied studios.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25d82dd9ad8a74c2e91677b8cbc0028d</guid></item><item><title>Bulahdelah farmers count the cost after devastating bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/bulahdelah-farmers-count-the-cost-after-devastating-bushfire/106114632</link><description>Farmers and businesses on the Mid North Coast are reeling after a fire tore through the region, destroying homes and forcing families to evacuate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">468939875f6419fddbed642b64f925c5</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane City Council announces crackdown on short-stay accommodation in residential areas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/brisbane-council-short-stay-accommodation-crackdown-airbnb/106117338</link><description>Hundreds of properties in low and low-to-medium residential-zoned areas of Brisbane will have to seek development approval or be banned from acting as short-stay accommodation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63527c358de066bf43ebbacbc0f7730a</guid></item><item><title>Federal government deal sending non-citizens to Nauru faces critical High Court challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/high-court-interim-arrangement-non-citizens-send-nauru-challenge/106116480</link><description>An Iranian man facing removal to Nauru under a controversial agreement will ask the High Court to find the government's plans to deport him lack procedural fairness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e81f90955562a06f8615179633142390</guid></item><item><title>Some Israeli-backed anti-Hamas gang members surrender to group</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/some-israeli-backed-anti-hamas-gang-members-surrender-to-group/106117908</link><description>A handful of members of an Israeli-backed anti-Hamas gang in Gaza have surrendered to the militant group, days after their leader was killed in the strip.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edbd622b9355b843303b4233556f08a7</guid></item><item><title>Mitch Marsh to retire from Sheffield Shield but leaves door open for Test recall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/mitch-marsh-announces-retirement-from-sheffield-shield-cricket/106118274</link><description>Mitch Marsh tells his Western Australia teammates he is retiring, but keeps the door ajar for a Test recall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7aeffa9d95cb18c8b91fc44297d744e8</guid></item><item><title>RBA live updates: RBA tipped to keep rates on hold as market awaits clues to next move</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/asx-markets-business-live-news-rba-9-dec/106117048</link><description>The local share market is lower ahead of the Reserve Bank's final rates decision of 2025, with the cash rate expected to remain on hold at 3.6 per cent. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00fc7f6cac2262937ab97fb252298a06</guid></item><item><title>Families left in the lurch after Zone RV caravan manufacturer collapse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/zone-rv-customers-in-limbo-after-collapse/106098684</link><description>The sensational shutdown of the luxury caravan manufacturer has had a gut-wrenching impact on families from Australia and abroad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f30fe67994eba4db444803d85e6c20e</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: Joyce 'throwing the toys out of the cot' in move to One Nation, Canavan says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/federal-poltics-live-blog-dec-9/106115678</link><description>Nationals senator Matt Canavan says he thinks Barnaby Joyce's decision to join One Nation is a "dummy spit". Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d4831f888454f5f69cc1a8e0c33484e</guid></item><item><title>Farmers and innovators say there is potential in Australia's untapped biofuel sector</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/australia-biofuel-sector-has-untapped-potential-say-farmers/105802948</link><description>Fuels produced from waste and agricultural feedstock are tipped to play a role in cutting emissions, but a leading Victorian farmer says political will is required to seize the opportunity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3de76cd91935af910eb720c85fa0a201</guid></item><item><title>Farmsafe Australia issues warning after two serious hay bale incidents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/farmsafe-australia-warning-after-hay-bale-incidents/106115168</link><description>A woman has died and a man has been hospitalised in two separate incidents involving falling hay bales in southern Queensland. Farm safety advocates are calling for increased caution while manoeuvring hay bales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f235659ff20a96eb4a19df846d06f8d6</guid></item><item><title>NT police restart investigation into mysterious disappearance of Yolŋu clan leader Dhakiyarr Wirrpanda</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/nt-police-restarts-investigation-into-yolngu-leader/106116104</link><description>The announcement from NT police follows a months-long ABC investigation into the disappearance of a Yolŋu clan leader who vanished without a trace after being acquitted of murdering a police officer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df20398d6d11c7e4b745c78042fa3f2d</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur wins fourth Newcombe Medal as Maya Joint finishes runner-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/newcombe-medal-alex-de-minaur-wins-fourth-trophy/106118368</link><description>Alex de Minaur wins the Newcombe Medal for a fourth time, as Cruz Hewitt claims a junior award at Australian tennis's night of nights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b238379fbc44b34014ba11a6eeff9b7</guid></item><item><title>The Australian Christmas carols that should be on your playlist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/the-australian-christmas-carols-that-should-be-on-your-playlist/106105838</link><description>We've rounded up some Australian Christmas carols to enhance your festive mood, from W.G. James to Christine Anu.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87b21b60041e0e154a9475ba1ba8208c</guid></item><item><title>Alter Boy's NRG nominated for WA Music Award for Auslan performances</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/alter-boy-nrg-luke-eastman-auslan-wa-music-awards/106083818</link><description>Luke Eastman's interpretation work using Auslan in the band Alter Boy is recognised in this year's WA Music Awards, with a nomination for vocalist of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f40c0220a5ab8b708a0cacac4ee90e1</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged with murder after shooting in Slacks Creek, to Brisbane's south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/man-and-woman-charged-over-fatal-logan-shooting/106118352</link><description>Police charge a 28-year-old woman with murder over the shooting death of a 41-year-old in Slacks Creek last week. A 42-year-old man is also facing charges over the incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4f229e2d0bc51adea95944dc488aa19</guid></item><item><title>Search underway at Coffin Bay on SA Eyre Peninsula for man who reportedly fell off jetty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/coffin-bay-water-search-jetty/106118414</link><description>Emergency services are searching for a man in Coffin Bay on the state's Eyre Peninsula after the alarm was raised about 1am on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fcd30bb2a0ac47e47a84a1c4eca51a6</guid></item><item><title>Jakara Anthony, Matt Graham claim FIS moguls gold in Ruka, two months out from Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/jaraka-anthony-matt-graham-claim-moguls-gold/106118416</link><description>Olympic medallists Jakara Anthony and Matt Graham start their FIS World Cup seasons with a bang, claiming double gold in Ruka just two months out from the Milano-Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e985b0366cf0b0d0403a11107856bee</guid></item><item><title>WA food ambassador Don Hancey points chefs to other fish species in wake of demersal catch ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/wa-food-ambassador-demersal-fishing-ban/106109474</link><description>WA food ambassador Don Hancey says there are plenty of other local fish in WA waters as the government's ban on catching demersal varieties looms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a04b2d4d80d0246387ea0becae97bb3</guid></item><item><title>As the Cleveland Dodd inquest calls for a 'complete reset' in WA youth detention, what are the next steps?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/cleveland-dodd-inquest-analysis-next-steps-for-wa-youth-justice/106117732</link><description>The inquest findings into WA's first recorded death in youth detention, that of 16-year-old Cleveland Dodd, are a stark warning for the government — and vulnerable lives remain at stake. WARNING: This story contains the name and image of an Indigenous person who has died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">841065e8f15b724ea8b1c4ba434c0369</guid></item><item><title>Victims of paedophile Ashley Paul Griffith call for more action after review finds he could have been stopped</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/ashley-paul-griffith-victims-parents-speak-of-ongoing-trauma/106117326</link><description>The parent of one victim of childcare paedophile Ashley Paul Griffith says they're still dealing with ongoing trauma, as a Queensland review finds his offending could have been stopped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e7daeedbb7310a87eb8e68fbd9d1cab</guid></item><item><title>Jake Weatherald and Ben Stokes caught up in Ashes sledging after Jofra Archer and Steve Smith clash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/ashes-2025-jake-weatherald-and-ben-stokes-caught-up-in-sledging/106118556</link><description>Sledging between Jake Weatherald and Ben Stokes emerges after Jofra Archer and Steve Smith's fiery clash at the Gabba.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e00b33bef30b94b8d30a2fe9a69f9944</guid></item><item><title>WA regional air travel fare cap changes anger residents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/wa-regional-air-travel-fare-cap-changes-anger-residents/106081870</link><description>The WA government says it will continue to cap airfares for regional residents but from July next year they will be more expensive during peak holiday periods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dac5f0e779750c284965330b5dabb7de</guid></item><item><title>FIFA announces scheduled water breaks during all games at the 2026 World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/fifa-2026-world-cup-water-breaks-to-be-scheduled-for-all-games/106118696</link><description>FIFA announces three-minute water breaks in both halves of all games will be included in the 2026 World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0585b3d784e1cc9bbe779d339890911</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce's defection to One Nation — the view from his electorate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/barnaby-joyce-voters-nationals-reaction/106115442</link><description>Voters in the New England electorate share their feelings as they digest the news that local MP Barnaby Joyce has defected from the Nationals to One Nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">202e2b3d7841f8522ad173d1b8b99a8b</guid></item><item><title>Mackay riverfront under the microscope as community grapples with addiction and homelessness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/mackay-riverfront-grapples-with-addiction-and-homeless/106117362</link><description>The banks of the Pioneer River near Mackay's CBD are home to makeshift camps nestled among the trees, while others reside in picnic shelters by the wharves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07e12624fb72728b2861297dd7541855</guid></item><item><title>Why Kate chose to 'stay flat' after breast cancer surgery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/why-kate-chose-to-stay-flat-after-breast-cancer-surgery/106087348</link><description>After a cancer diagnosis, Kate Miller's doctor recommended a mastectomy on one side only. But Kate wanted both breasts gone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee9c5fda1e5f653e7df6819b46e1e433</guid></item><item><title>Dolphin Sands residents awaiting reopening of main road after a bushfire destroyed homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/bushfire-at-dolphin-sands-road-reopen-residents-access-damage/106114738</link><description>The one road into a bushfire-affected Tasmanian town will reopen at 1:30pm today, allowing many residents their first chance to assess their properties after a devastating blaze.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b570931a7774b6d1180b1bfa3e2a86c</guid></item><item><title>TPG Telecom boss says second person may have died due to Triple Zero failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/triple-zero-outage-senate-hearing-tpg-telecom-second-death-link/106118690</link><description>TPG Telecom chief executive Iñaki Berroeta flags another death possibly linked to a customer's inability to call Triple Zero (000) on their Samsung mobile phone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ca9a724d429ca8f7534afb45866024b</guid></item><item><title>Six teenagers charged after Ellenbrook Secondary College student allegedly stabbed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/teenagers-charged-after-ellenbrook-secondary-college-stabbing/106118992</link><description>Police charge six youths aged 13 to 16 with a string of offences over the stabbing of a 15-year-old boy at Ellenbrook Secondary College in Perth’s north-east on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fbfcc6dfb08cb04136ac4bf7e461263</guid></item><item><title>Canadian traditional owners fear Australian-style LNG development</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/canada-traditional-owners-in-australia-to-protest-against-gas/106111960</link><description>Canadian hereditary chief Na'Moks wanted to find out what a gas pipeline on his land would look like, so he flew to northern Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fec3762dac068c1104d6fbd8727431f5</guid></item><item><title>Inquest into death of tasered 95yo Clare Nowland to focus on dementia training</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/clare-nowland-death-examined-by-nsw-coroners-court/106113798</link><description>A court hears training of aged-care staff and first responders in dealing with people experiencing dementia will be the primary focus of an upcoming inquest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92ccec0c5f846cf198b92feea888ddd0</guid></item><item><title>Josh Hazlewood ruled out of remainder of the Ashes in injury blow to Australian attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/ashes-2025-josh-hazelwood-ruled-out-of-series-with-injury/106119372</link><description>Coach Andrew McDonald confirms Josh Hazlewood will not play in the Ashes due to ongoing injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">097860d022b48b46eb529bbc4ab183dc</guid></item><item><title>Travelling teacher Tina Greenfield brings instrumental music to regional schools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/travelling-instrumental-music-teacher-tina-greenfield/106107440</link><description>Tina Greenfield drives 350 kilometres each week to teach music to students at five schools in regional Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af0e9509f44753cea55e61d61c0fef55</guid></item><item><title>Four dead, one missing after powerful wave drags swimmers out to sea in Tenerife</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/powerful-wave-in-spanish-island-of-tenerife-kills-four/106118978</link><description>Local media reported that a weather advisory for rough seas was in effect when the swimmers were swept out to sea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79e49197f544ed3aaafe83edbdd961e4</guid></item><item><title>Kids in remote towns say social media ban will make isolation worse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/remote-kids-social-ban-isolation/106114026</link><description>Kids in remote and regional parts of Victoria say the social media ban will "cut off" their contact with friends and family, leading to further isolation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8d58e6ded7ee1eeeb07f1d9350f16a0</guid></item><item><title>University of Technology Sydney facing crisis amid union-led no-confidence vote in vice-chancellor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/university-of-technology-vote-of-no-confidence-vice-chancellor/106114890</link><description>The union-run vote comes as controversial, consultant-designed redundancies continue and politicians call for resignations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d99a7a07c10de436af442171b41740ba</guid></item><item><title>Toyah Cordingley's murderer Rajwinder Singh sentenced to life in prison for 'violent, brutal' attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/toyah-cordingley-murderer-rajwinder-singh-sentencing/106118664</link><description>Rajwinder Singh, 41, was found guilty of the Far North Queensland woman's 2018 murder on a secluded beach north of Cairns. He then fled to India, hiding out for about four years before his arrest and extradition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3369bf75e430709e015a7e767c53fc18</guid></item><item><title>Dolphins Sand resident Mark speaks ahead of the community being reopened after the bushfire emergency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/dolphin-sands-residents-speak/106119518</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3b2cb8c93d8f4334409436835d924b0</guid></item><item><title>Wellington North solar farm grass fire burns almost 100ha</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/wellington-solar-farm-fire/106113846</link><description>The cause of a grass fire that started on one of Australia's largest solar farms remains a mystery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c01c7027c20f76ec5ab2adb267a0fd3</guid></item></channel></rss>