<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:47:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Netflix workers walk out over Dave Chappelle special The Closer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2021-10-21/netflix-workers-walk-out-over-dave-chappelle-special-the-closer/100556538</link><description>About 100 people protest near Netflix HQ against the streaming pioneer's decision to release comedian Dave Chappelle's new special, which they say ridicules transgender people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00da6b5df3e9ee70c77f8032f353bb02</guid></item><item><title>Call for button battery redesign after new study reveals horrific injuries and fatalities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/button-battery-warning-danger-deaths-lithium-swallow/103986966</link><description>A new study reveals the horrific injuries suffered after swallowing or inserting button batteries but manufacturers aren't prioritising their redesign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46ab5f96ade65908ecf6b7be8673e61f</guid></item><item><title>The US election is about style more than substance. It's why Kamala Harris needs to nail her DNC speech in about eight seconds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/us-election-kamala-harris-dnc-speech-style-substance/104256162</link><description>When the Democrat presidential candidate Kamala Harris delivers her speech to the Democratic National Convention today, style will be almost everything.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bddf8093759d999153dfd749b90e144a</guid></item><item><title>The Strata Trap</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-09-09/the-strata-trap/104330248</link><description>Four Corners is the home of Australian investigative journalism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c59176a87691f5428c06580532e1a7e4</guid></item><item><title>Kayaker plucked from another sport joins new wave of Australian athletes eyeing Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-01-01/kayaker-next-generation-of-australian-athletes-eyeing-olympics/104569272</link><description>Just four years after hopping into a kayak, 19-year-old Sammy Lourey is a national champion and has her sights set on the Olympics. But her talent almost went undiscovered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec777b38c876548114951b5349c5f551</guid></item><item><title>Have Your Say: What was the issue, policy or event that decided your vote?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-02-26/federal-election-your-say/104788518</link><description>After a five-week campaign, the results are in with Labor returned to government. Is there a policy or issue that swayed your vote? Have Your Say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">320dfcbec9cd8fe02e449407ce78e618</guid></item><item><title>Voters tell ABC's Your Say they want politicians with a vision, not bickering</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-13/abc-your-say-federal-election-politicians-with-vision/105164874</link><description>Voters tell ABC's Your Say campaign they want courage and vision from politicians, not bickering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">033ddce5ad54070fbce620dc6760d9ba</guid></item><item><title>Push for seniors' dental scheme grows ahead of federal election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-13/aged-care-dental-scheme-australia-federal-election/105149782</link><description>Imagine living in aged care and not having your teeth or dentures properly cleaned and checked each day. That's a risk faced by elderly Australians, prompting calls for the next federal government to boost oral health training and services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36d312d336a36247fd1c01e78814112b</guid></item><item><title>Australians tell ABC's Your Say they are struggling more than ever with housing costs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-15/abc-your-say-federal-election-2025-housing-policies/105175180</link><description>Voters tell ABC's Your Say campaign they are struggling more than ever with housing costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54451646ec8e9f100cc2fe59fc9c08c5</guid></item><item><title>Australia's growing cohort of tenants fear they will rent forever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-16/australias-growing-tenant-cohort-fear-forever-renting/105127148</link><description>Home ownership rates in Australia have been falling for decades, and with rental vacancies at record lows and prices at historic highs, many fear their dream of owning a home may be out of reach. Some experts say rental caps could help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36f35fe439f533ac9522c679c7e37187</guid></item><item><title>Graduates in 'debt vortex' as HECS front and centre for first time in an election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-16/federal-election-2025-hecs-student-debt-policies/105177248</link><description>New research shows a sharp rise in HECS debts, despite graduate earning power declining, as student loans become a potent election issue for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48707ffafbe02c400b1200e6269fd40e</guid></item><item><title>Housing advocates seek federal funding election promise for co-op model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-17/housing-cooperative-solution-proposed-for-rental-crisis/105108816</link><description>Advocates admit co-operative housing models are not for everyone but say for the right residents, they offer more security and affordable pricing than traditional rentals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3608b0c1ae56f5a5b36968898f65df5e</guid></item><item><title>Next-generation voters call for better engagement ahead of federal election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-18/federal-election-rural-next-generation-voters/105173450</link><description>Young people in Albury say issues that directly affect them and their communities are not being addressed by major parties for the 2025 election campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ae182892b8c9591cd9ec35e6e57fcb9</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne seat of Calwell highlights Labor woes as Gaza pain galvanises Muslim voters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-20/calwell-labor-backlash-over-gaza-islamophobia/104850500</link><description>Dissatisfaction with the Albanese government's stance on Israel-Palestine among many Arab and Muslim voters threatens to unseat Labor MPs, in some places for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63e7f9854fee5bc20e54ee2f5bd136f4</guid></item><item><title>Cost of living, housing among key concerns in SA marginal seat of Boothby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-21/boothby-cost-of-living-federal-election-2025/105190262</link><description>At this year’s federal election, the South Australian seat of Boothby is one of the state’s two marginal seats. As part of the ABC’s “Your Say” campaign, we spoke to residents in the electorate about their biggest concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dfd66b0605d29b960082ff52f18c170</guid></item><item><title>Energy projects in South West WA threaten votes for major federal parties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-21/energy-projects-south-west-wa-federal-election-labor-liberals/105152524</link><description>Australia's two major parties have tied their federal election fates to controversial energy projects in WA's South West where the issues have polarised voters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8962a53de05f0293b3a104690022111a</guid></item><item><title>Tiwi Islanders eager to have their say as remote voting for the federal election begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-22/early-voting-starts-in-remote-communities-tiwi-islands-aec/105201318</link><description>Voters in the small remote community of Pirlangimpi on the Tiwi Islands, north of Darwin, have become some of the first to cast their votes for the federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0c419fe3ae44debe7edf27241c0e5c1</guid></item><item><title>Mobile coverage is an election issue in regional areas. What's been promised?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-23/telecommunications-mobile-coverage-federal-election-promises/105080674</link><description>For many regional and remote Australians, reliable mobile coverage can be life-saving. They are desperate for both sides of politics to take meaningful action towards eliminating black spots.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ceda72e552d98e5f293d3c037efeefa</guid></item><item><title>Health, climate and community sport: What older voters in the Tasmanian seat of Bass are talking about this election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-29/health-climate-sport-election-older-voters-bass-tasmania/105224138</link><description>The federal seat of Bass is held by a margin of just 1.4 per cent. For these older voters who live in the electorate, health, climate and community sport are the issues that will decide their vote.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a3579db910b5a7ee8e11d2618bf798f</guid></item><item><title>Nicole Kidman honoured at Cannes Film Festival for championing female directors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-19/nicole-kidman-wins-women-in-motion-award-cannes-film-festival/105309342</link><description>Nicole Kidman has received an award at the Cannes Film Festival honouring groundbreaking women both on and off the screen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ce581e38afcdf263c0df768dc04df81</guid></item><item><title>Sydney commuters warned further train delays possible on Wednesday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-20/sydney-commuters-warned-further-train-delays-possible-/105316518</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20fad6b8a0805178318f78fcf044bf7f</guid></item><item><title>Movie World cleared of wrongdoing after scalping injury on carousel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-21/movie-world-cleared-carousel-child-descalping-injury/105317156</link><description>A judge-only trial heard a 12-year-old boy was standing on the back of a carousel character when his head was caught in moving parts in the ride's ceiling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2922c5f0714e88c2b17cdcb1185fdb9</guid></item><item><title>Liberian-born rapper Youngmoze and art school help students break into film</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-06-15/liberian-born-rapper-youngmoze-music-video/105357072</link><description>A refugee-turned-rapper teams up with a school of fine art to give young people from the bush a chance to kickstart careers in filmmaking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c69f96fb92ea13f5b9096c1b72ae99c5</guid></item><item><title>WA Budget 2025: Rita Saffioti's second budget delivers $2.4 billion surplus as power credits axed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-06-19/rita-saffioti-hands-down-2025-budget-amid-another-surplus/105425832</link><description>This year's budget cements the state as the nation's economic engine room as West Australians brace for higher power bills amid rising global instability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5cff2156fc5517a158b2794bb3d9878</guid></item><item><title>Repeated Cape York ferry breakdowns leave tourists in kilometres-long queues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-06-27/jardine-ferry-breakdowns-strand-tourists-in-cape-york/105464932</link><description>Travellers wanting to reach the tip of Cape York Peninsula can only do so by crossing the Jardine River ferry. But it has broken down for the fourth time in as many weeks, stranding tourists and locals on both sides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1e086fe25eb035255060aba93a668ad</guid></item><item><title>Heather Ewart reflects on the tough road to Back Roads success</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-07-17/heather-ewart-farewells-back-roads-ten-year-anniversary/105425700</link><description>Heather Ewart was a powerhouse political reporter when she was asked to create a show about regional Australia. A decade later, and with her final season going to air, Ewart admits that getting the idea off the ground was no easy feat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">015b32b8ed1e8c3177e94f59c0a95456</guid></item><item><title>Taree small businesses ask minister for more flood recovery grants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-07-25/taree-small-businesses-meet-minister-flood-recovery-roundtable/105566492</link><description>Taree business owners say they urgently need larger flood relief grants, or they risk shutting their doors for good.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5025bf9bae4a0abab579f20a74b0f62f</guid></item><item><title>If the RBA cuts rates this week, expect property prices to rise (again)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-10/if-the-rba-cuts-rates-expect-property-prices-to-rise-again/105632180</link><description>When the RBA cuts rates, it drives property prices higher. What does it mean for housing affordability?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf87af7ec9947f68d427d05b79425f06</guid></item><item><title>RBA looks for way forward in the rear-view mirror as interest rates hinder economy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-12/rba-hold-or-cut-official-interest-rate-decision-today/105636830</link><description>Having dashed hopes for some much-needed respite from cost-of-living pressures three weeks ago, it would be a brave RBA that again denies households a rate cut today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57ecd0d5800270143ef4a6117b3f5805</guid></item><item><title>Donnell Wallam signs with Sunshine Coast Lightning, returning to Super Netball</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-12/donnell-wallam-signs-with-sunshine-coast-lightning-super-netball/105641812</link><description>Diamonds shooter Donnell Wallam is set to return to the Super Netball competition, signing with the Sunshine Coast Lightning for the 2026 season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09ca00a6d7425ec0d3d2e81166bbf5c4</guid></item><item><title>Four football netball clubs in axed Golden Rivers league approved to join new competition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-16/four-golden-rivers-clubs-to-transfer-to-central-murray-league/105657512</link><description>Four clubs from NSW and Victoria in a regional football netball league that is set to close are approved to move to a new competition by their board, which says clubs' intrinsic value to their communities was a factor in the decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">726816e012dc5424cc885d82a4f702bd</guid></item><item><title>Coloured wool from Polwarth sheep popular with crafters around the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-16/colourful-history-of-australias-first-breed-of-sheep-polwarth/105649748</link><description>Naturally coloured wool, the brainchild of a farmer in the 1970s, is used by craft enthusiasts around the world to be fashioned into all manner of things.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab74609e15ed9ecc6b2dcacc8af64b4a</guid></item><item><title>Investigation finds links between white nationalist views and March for Australia organisers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-28/who-is-behind-march-for-australia-anti-immigration-rallies/105657548</link><description>An ABC NEWS Verify investigation has found organisers linked to the March for Australia protests sharing white supremacy posts on social media and, in one case, pro-Nazi and pro-Hitler memes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29c13421c02495f9f56fcb3eb6fd011b</guid></item><item><title>How Taylor Swift's engagement collides with her discography of heartbreak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-29/taylor-swift-is-engaged-how-fans-will-relate-to-her-music/105709652</link><description>Now that Taylor Swift is entering her bridal era, is this the end of her vast swathes of relatable heartbreak songs that have sound-tracked the lives of her fans?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1488102ef5f4f66dc9e53a08a09eb5ea</guid></item><item><title>Australian film and TV industry calling on content quotas to revitalise struggling local scene</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-30/delays-to-content-quotas-for-streaming-services-hurting-industry/105680966</link><description>With promised local content requirements for streaming services delayed indefinitely, Australian filmmakers say the local industry is hurting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">019778c37b9cd599679ab9e29d9c24ab</guid></item><item><title>Home prices keep rising in 'seller's market' as new property listings below average</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-01/home-values-rise-interest-rates-low-property-listings-lift-price/105711442</link><description>Australian property prices have been pushed higher again in August as lower interest rates, rising real wages and buyer optimism collided with a shortage of homes for sale.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a9649212b9dc9ccba3a9a8e925b9796</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins battles back stress ahead of Ashes Test series agains England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-02/pat-cummins-battles-back-stress-ahead-of-ashes/105724754</link><description>Pat Cummins is no certainty to captain Australia in the first Ashes Test as he deals with stress in his back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db9f2fb6dd985499b66a54c3fca4ff30</guid></item><item><title>From movies to red carpets, these are some of Giorgio Armani's best dressed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/giorgio-armanis-best-looks-and-hollywood-friends/105738220</link><description>Giorgio Armani's name has become synonymous with the red carpet, thanks to his close relationship with the stars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cca9c1e241fcf01a390021f665ce5fd</guid></item><item><title>Carlos Alcaraz beats Jannik Sinner in US Open final, reclaims world number one ranking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/tennis-us-open-mens-final-sinner-vs-alcaraz-live-blog/105744794</link><description>Carlos Alcaraz wins the men's US Open, reclaiming his world number one ranking by defeating Jannik Sinner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3e38f0de65b1740196844af5d838f7a</guid></item><item><title>Runt by Craig Silvey comes to the stage in Belvoir St Theatre's 2026 season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/runt-craig-silvey-play-belvoir-st-theatre-2026-season/105747908</link><description>Runt earned a slew of awards for younger readers and was turned into a movie. Ahead of the release of the sequel, a theatre adaptation is in the works.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96dc8f32b957cc029d060b16262927de</guid></item><item><title>British YouTube creator Yung Filly to travel home to UK on bail for sexual assault charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/youtube-creator-yung-filly-allowed-to-fly-overseas-on-bail/105094220</link><description>British YouTube content creator Yung Filly, who's facing trial in Perth on sex assault charges, is granted permission to travel home to the UK for the first time since he was arrested.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c89f9603e811b96cf1412b9f341613a</guid></item><item><title>From Formula 1 to creating the 'world's best' croissant, how baking saved Lune founder Kate Reid's life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/cars-to-croissants-kate-reid-and-the-lune-empire/105750472</link><description>Kate Reid's Lune croissants have been called the world's best. But how did a young woman struggling with a near-fatal eating disorder end up perfecting pastry?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d09b350f758690100795053d1425df1</guid></item><item><title>Australia beats India in first of three ODIs before Women's Cricket World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/australia-beats-india-in-odi-world-cup-warm-up/105773182</link><description>Australia's Cricket World Cup preparations are in full swing as three batters score half-centuries in a big run chase in the first of three ODIs against India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a29f09f0be7bd9b554de11bd5f4906d1</guid></item><item><title>How is Australia affected by climate change? The National Climate Risk Assessment models the future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/national-climate-risk-assessment-and-why-it-matters-explained/105773936</link><description>For the first time, the government has modelled the threats from climate change on Australia's future. What's the point of a document like this, and can it help us avoid the worst-case scenarios?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ad84229da5de3e8a79b28e4eacc8cab</guid></item><item><title>V/Line train passenger suffers broken leg after falling on train tracks at Pyramid Hill station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/vline-passenger-falls-on-train-tracks-breaks-legs-as-no-platform/105775672</link><description>Daniel Kelly broke his leg after he stepped off a V/Line train only to discover the carriage had outrun the platform at his local station.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f45e5dd7f65e619f5a087f25ddf878b</guid></item><item><title>Nepal's protests estimated to have caused hundreds of millions of dollars in damage as families farewell those killed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/nepal-gen-z-protests-cause-millions-of-dollars-in-damage/105781578</link><description>As clean-up efforts continue and an interim government finds its feet, families have said farewell to loved ones killed in last week's violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1064109a46dbf7b37962228d9f172092</guid></item><item><title>Gardeners share the joys of turning dust to daisies in the Australian outback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/gardeners-share-the-joys-of-growing-flowers-in-the-outback/105761510</link><description>Flower farmer Suzanne Stanton says generations of outback women have taken comfort in their gardens, proof that life can survive in the harshest of climates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">983de27f94440a9ba1f44837800269ac</guid></item><item><title>Investigation of eye-maker's online presence reveals multiple red flags</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/jack-mcdonald-ocularist-website-warning-signs/105788574</link><description>A reverse-image search of ocularist Jack McDonald's website shows that receptionist "Nadia" also appears on a dentistry blog and is known as "Donna" on a self-help guru's site. It's just one of the red flags that ABC NEWS Verify spotted during its investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d081d56d6116ad09be5333b0e23b73bc</guid></item><item><title>Turtling tracking in Broome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/turtling-tracking-in-broome/105794988</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10cb5e530edb2253e9361a5ada40925c</guid></item><item><title>How skateboarding became a family affair for Townsville single dad Jay MacAskill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/qld-skateboarding-becomes-family-single-dad/105774582</link><description>For almost eight years, Jay MacAskill's skateboard was collecting dust at home — until his daughter found the skate park around the corner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ab26eabc2acb19d8f736401a36cb5d2</guid></item><item><title>World leaders are meeting at the UN General Assembly this week. Here are four things to watch for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/united-nations-general-assembly-what-to-watch-for-in-new-york/105800440</link><description>World leaders are arriving in New York for the UN General Assembly — and for the first time, Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is among them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">761958b8abcd8c47c96a8d78d674b211</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos undecided on halves combination ahead of prelim final against Penrith</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/hunt-on-for-broncos-as-mam-mind-games-begin/105803392</link><description>Brisbane coach Michael Maguire continues to experiment with his halves combinations on Monday as Ezra Mam takes another key step towards a return from injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94b206b4a39973e74852b877af401757</guid></item><item><title>Kevin Bacon on the importance of music, philanthropy and acting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/kevin-bacon-take-5-actor-music-philanthropy-interview/105793360</link><description>He's a prolific fixture on our screens who's famously six degrees from almost anyone. But Kevin Bacon is also a passionate musician and philanthropist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45104e05b24001759cca6f2985a81b97</guid></item><item><title>Incoming triple-0 reforms may not have helped prevent Optus failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/triple-0-reforms-may-not-have-helped-optus-failure/105807524</link><description>The federal government has yet to pass legislation to empower a new coordinator for the emergency services line, but experts say tougher conditions are needed on the telco itself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">196d665b157a51d6ce3440ca5be81bfc</guid></item><item><title>Rodeo attendees told to practise safe sex as STIs continue to rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sti-cases-continue-to-rise-indigenous-overrepresented-in-data/105809704</link><description>Health providers in outback Queensland are taking a light-hearted approach to promoting safe sex, as new data shows sexually transmitted infections are on the rise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a991448f6d24b7d59719d012fdc3e584</guid></item><item><title>Who is Samoa's new prime minister, Laaulialemalietoa Polataivao Fosi Schmidt?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/new-samoa-prime-minister-election/105789496</link><description>Supporters are fervent in their enthusiasm for Samoa's new prime minister, but voters who are more sceptical of Laaulialemalietoa Polataivao Fosi Schmidt, question his motives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">625c6497fc8280a6929fa5f29c6e97f3</guid></item><item><title>Nicho Hynes shrugs off personal barbs ahead of NRL preliminary final between Melbourne and Cronulla</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nicho-hynes-cronulla-sharks-nrl-preliminary-final/105815774</link><description>Accused by some of being too nice and not nice enough by others, polarising Cronulla star Nicho Hynes "doesn't give a rats" about criticism that comes his way anymore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab3262fd8438997bf3566bc3f3afd340</guid></item><item><title>Fourth NZYQ member issued Nauruan visa as Labor steams ahead with deportation plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/fourth-nauruan-visa-issued-to-nzyq/105817222</link><description>The former detainee was returned to immigration detention on Thursday and could be the first person transferred under the multi-billion-dollar deal inked with Nauru earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad0acd68e16e51eb3bff42b299e11dc0</guid></item><item><title>China aid and investment returns to Solomon Islands's Malaita province after ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/china-aid-solomon-islands-malaita-road-development/105789780</link><description>The Solomon Islands's province of Malaita made global headlines five years ago when it banned Chinese investment. But today, a new China-funded road project is on the way — and the people are all for it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aef86fbb6ca57b72f9ef6089dc9580e9</guid></item><item><title>'I am innocent,' says former FBI director James Comey after being indicted on two counts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/james-comey-former-fbi-director-indicted-swears-innocent/105814672</link><description>He was indicted on one count of making false statements and one count of obstruction of justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beacc8c1c93306cafeca910785eac6ab</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos face Penrith Panthers in preliminary final without key forward Pat Carrigan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/brisbane-broncos-must-fill-carrigan-void-or-perish/105820354</link><description>Brisbane's forward pack is on notice to do their jobs and a bit more against Penrith in the preliminary final to cover the absence of Pat Carrigan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f832375101d237ed86d9093fecd23395</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane hellbent on ending horror NRLW finals run ahead of preliminary final clash with Newcastle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/nrlw-finals-broncos-knights-brigginshaw-upton/105820672</link><description>The Broncos have been almost untouchable through the 2025 NRLW season but the club's poor finals record in recent years means they can not afford to get ahead of themselves leading into this week's preliminary final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d248af9a48662ba232728304794119fd</guid></item><item><title>Even without Trump's tariffs, Australian farmers are losing out on billions of dollars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/non-trade-barriers-trump-australian-farmers/105820528</link><description>Even without Trump's tariffs, Australian farmers and exporters of agricultural produce are already losing out on an estimated $4 billion of annual export trade each year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8da56250820715f66334662c60347158</guid></item><item><title>Why you might consider glass food containers over plastic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/are-glass-containers-better-for-food-storage/105814738</link><description>Compared to plastic containers, glass alternatives can reduce exposure to microplastics when used in the microwave and be easier to clean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62503c861f079a92f249f37bd31d4008</guid></item><item><title>Gulf states reevaluate US relationship as Israel replaces Iran as a threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/gulf-states-united-nations-general-assembly-donald-trump/105801292</link><description>The Gulf, along with Israel, will be wondering just how far Donald Trump really is prepared to push Benjamin Netanyahu.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e0e64a2d1db9bd1d64b2ebafe1d2ab8</guid></item><item><title>Australia's climate target doesn't eclipse today's tough questions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/climate-announcement-targets-emissions/105801294</link><description>As a nation, it's as if we're arguing about where to have a family holiday in 2035, and whether we fly economy or business. Meanwhile, nobody can agree on dinner tonight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4146131c7945d7a9befae50175a86f11</guid></item><item><title>Indians in Australia continue to face racist abuse one month on from anti-immigration protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/indians-racism-march-for-australia-protests-anti-immigration/105782222</link><description>Nearly a month after anti-immigration protests swept across Australia, some in the Indian diaspora say they are still facing racist abuse and constantly "looking over their shoulder".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50a690450fbc31f7c53d0d4ea03d629f</guid></item><item><title>Epstein files show flight with Prince Andrew and meetings with Elon Musk, Bill Gates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/epstein-files-six-pages-released/105823750</link><description>The documents include flight logs, massage messages and cash transactions in Jeffrey Epstein's ledger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f78ee953397b3a507669a6560c685081</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with performing Nazi salute at AFL semifinal was former political candidate with history of racist posts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/qld-man-charged-with-performing-nazi-salute-political-candidate/105815900</link><description>An ABC investigation reveals Tylere Baker-Pearce, a former political candidate who has posted a selfie smiling outside Auschwitz, was the man charged with performing a Nazi salute at an AFL game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30e54f094513d67b34962af67d4ac555</guid></item><item><title>Lawyer for Neo-Nazi leader Thomas Sewell shared racist, antisemitic posts on social media</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/national-socialist-network-thomas-sewell-matthew-hopkins-lawyer/105812392</link><description>Matthew Hopkins shared racist and antisemitic material from the Neo-Nazi group on social media and described Adolf Hitler's Mein Kampf as a "brilliant book" to his followers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19ffaba1e4c67dac0617eaac38822c4a</guid></item><item><title>Police reveal link between man and woman found dead in New South Wales home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/police-investigate-after-two-bodies-found-in-coffs-harbour/105823928</link><description>Police found the bodies of a man and woman in their 60s when doing a welfare check at a Coffs Harbour property on Friday evening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47e234f9b8ecd79651a27ee1302b040c</guid></item><item><title>For four years, Yuna and Minu Jo lay in a suitcase in a New Zealand storage unit. Now they have justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/nz-suitcase-deaths-aftermath/105811894</link><description>Minu and Yuna Jo's bodies lay in a storage unit for four years. They finally have justice after their mother was found guilty of their murders seven years after they were killed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c20fa9f4daa00b724ebbc96dbed5d5c6</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final 2025: Brisbane Lions thump Geelong Cats by 47 points, Will Ashcroft wins Norm Smith Medal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-grand-final-2025-geelong-vs-brisbane-live-blog/105822258</link><description>Brisbane secures its second straight AFL premiership, taking control in the final quarter of an otherwise gripping grand final against Geelong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14ca0c766669a84c1c64d308b07e389c</guid></item><item><title>Tourist dies at Tasmania's Cradle Mountain National Park after group becomes 'overwhelmed' by extreme weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/cradle-mountain-walker-dies-extreme-weather/105824188</link><description>A group of tourists who were unprepared for the extreme conditions at Cradle Mountain National Park is rescued, but one member of the group dies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c2bacc1d4008463c044ab40ec94a7ab</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous teenager teaches Paakantyi language to teachers at Menindee school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/aboriginal-paakantyi-language-teacher-outback-nsw-school/105815440</link><description>Jaz Fusi has been passionate about learning Paakantyi language for most of her life. Now, she teaches it to her local school's teachers and is eager to see other kids do the same.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffc9b2d6c78f4e662e2f96fe4e5bf8a9</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump will send troops to 'war-ravaged' Portland, in latest deployment to US cities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/trump-orders-deployment-of-troops-to-portland-ice-facilities/105825548</link><description>The military says it is ready to mobilise as Donald Trump authorises "full force" to protect federal immigration facilities from "domestic terrorists".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7bbd1ebd2ce3c0d838911445a763b29</guid></item><item><title>Woppaburra people welcome ancestor's return but face final hurdle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/woppaburra-peoples-fight-to-get-ancestor-home/105788102</link><description>More First Nations remains are being returned to Australia from international institutions, but these Woppaburra men say laying them to rest on country can prove a fresh challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f2752aea82ec37f1fac83229df02a1</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's coal royalty regime back in the spotlight after job cuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/qld-coal-mine-royalties-regime-questioned-after-job-cuts/105818488</link><description>Despite a change of government, Queensland's controversial coal royalty scheme remains in place and recent job cuts are prompting renewed discussion about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05fc998cc23e435b2b1e012ba6d8ab22</guid></item><item><title>Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov warns NATO, Europe that aggression will be met with a 'decisive response'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/russian-foreign-minister-sergey-lavrov-warns-nato-europe-at-unga/105825572</link><description>While Russia does not intend to attack Europe, its Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov has not ruled out action against NATO aggression.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0368cfa881bd50ea3b87763fb766242f</guid></item><item><title>Kununurra's Barra Bash barramundi competition underway as restocking solution sought</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/barramundi-stocking-concerns-at-barra-bash-in-kununurra/105815558</link><description>More than 1,000 fishers hope to reel in a winning catch at Lake Kununurra, where a restocking program and ideal conditions have grown record-size barramundi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">923bf257f99baf7de30b4c08ce60dcfd</guid></item><item><title>The benefits and risks of sleeping next to your dog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/the-benefits-and-risks-of-sleeping-next-to-our-dogs/105774468</link><description>While there are several benefits to keeping our pets close at night, there are a few minor risks to consider.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">932ca557de76cc1cae410a853cede833</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate death of man at Brisbane shopping centre in early hours of Sunday morning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/brisbane-man-found-dead-at-shopping-centre/105827860</link><description>Police were called to a suburban shopping centre in the early hours of Sunday morning where they declared the man in his 40s dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1f120a042247a986d3d85b34298ac38</guid></item><item><title>Adam Reynolds and Reece Walsh explain the Broncos' game-winning moment against Penrith Panthers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/adam-reynolds-reece-walsh-nrl-final-game-winning-moment/105828288</link><description>Adam Reynolds took the kicking tee from the Broncos' biggest star in the biggest moment of their season so far, and it paid off in the biggest way possible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">536642d6505adba508e3c36f170c355a</guid></item><item><title>Vietnam evacuates thousands as Typhoon Bualoi approaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/typhoon-bualoi-forces-thousands-to-evacuate-in-vietnam/105828376</link><description>As Typhoon Bualoi approaches Vietnam, thousands of people are seeking safer ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34ba155386d3628844b99b19c8e4efb0</guid></item><item><title>If China beats the US on fusion energy, its supremacy will be assured</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/fusion-energy-china-united-states-coal/105720436</link><description>China is driving hard to supplant the US in this new military industrial complex, and has already achieved leadership in electric vehicles, batteries, drones and renewable energy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f2ed6434035cb358c677b916343d8b7</guid></item><item><title>Anti-corruption chief Paul Brereton continued defence consulting after declaring he had resigned from role</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/nacc-chief-defence-consulting/105821158</link><description>The head of the national anti-corruption commission told a Senate inquiry he had resigned his role at the defence force's investigative arm. But the ABC has learned he continued consulting for them, and documents proving his resignation could not be identified.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2142fb25ce654eee8a08d853101c7865</guid></item><item><title>Funding deal for research program about Australia's polar security rejected by Tasmanian government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/funding-deal-for-research-into-polar-security-rejected/105817408</link><description>A funding bid to establish a polar security research program has been knocked back, despite the changing geopolitical dynamics in Antarctica and the Southern Ocean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7caffffe60fab33afc201a1dced4018</guid></item><item><title>These Australians are homeless with a house</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/remote-nt-housing-amid-rising-temperatures-climate-change/105421962</link><description>Many Aboriginal people in Tennant Creek live in overcrowded makeshift shelters with no running water or electricity as they wait up to a decade for a home. But experts say the social housing being built is not safe for today's climate, let alone the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6114aa8701c7c5addd04a9559938ee86</guid></item><item><title>New York City Mayor Eric Adams announces he is dropping his re-election bid after unpopular tenure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/eric-adams-drops-re-election-bid/105828948</link><description>Eric Adams announces he is dropping his re-election bid, but says he will "continue to fight for this city" until his term ends on January 1, 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e1a8b654c5ea5d1d7a7ff58bd246fdd</guid></item><item><title>Children's author Pamela Allen's work showcased in interactive exhibition at State Library of NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/children-author-illustrator-pamela-allen-exhibition/105816018</link><description>At 91, Pamela Allen has published more than 60 books. This exhibition brings her work off the page and invites children and adults to play as they read.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79ba1502bd70c825488eecfa0f939e60</guid></item><item><title>If you're looking to try out a career change, volunteering can give you a taste</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/volunteering-to-test-a-career-change/105788520</link><description>If you're considering a career change, or want a taste of a new industry, volunteering can be a great option.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8160f86239ba2807fc1b8d35ee83f8df</guid></item><item><title>Tufi Junior Tauese-Auelua jailed for five years over firebombing of Jordan Shanks' Bondi home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/man-jailed-for-five-years-over-bondi-friendlyjordies-arson/105830364</link><description>Described as "a little boy in a very large body", the man who lit the blaze at the home of the YouTube comedian in 2022 apologised and said he would "rather die" than go back to jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1f43ca56edac53669d0466e7605132d</guid></item><item><title>When is the 2025 NRL grand final? Here's how to watch and everything you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/when-are-the-2025-nrl-and-nrlw-grand-finals/105829220</link><description>The NRL and NRLW grand final teams have been finalised and are getting ready to face-off this weekend. Here's what you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83aee82f83ac81d24eb24f5d884f94e4</guid></item><item><title>Body scanner to be used in ACT courts after significantly reducing prison strip searches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/act-electronic-scanner-expansion-reduce-strip-searches-jail/105830654</link><description>The ACT government will expand the use of electronic body scanners to the courts after their use in Canberra's only prison saw a dramatic drop in the need to strip search prisoners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8593aef0310bd16a46c4fdad86864527</guid></item><item><title>At least 13 dead after Typhoon Bualoi makes landfall in Vietnam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/apn-bualoi-vietnam-landfall/105831514</link><description>At least 13 people have died after heavy rain and strong winds from the former Typhoon Bualoi flooded roads, knocked off roofs in central Vietnam, state media reported, with residents describing it as "one of the strongest".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a633befcd32cf7b9b0648dcd1307f2e</guid></item><item><title>Albanese invites Emirati retail giant Lulu Hypermarket to take on Coles and Woolworths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/albanese-invites-lulu-hypermarket-to-take-on-coles-woolworths/105832238</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has invited Emirati 'hypermarket' chain LuLu Group to set up shop on Australia's shores and take on supermarket giants Coles and Woolworths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dff2e97321eaa2a6005ab80c58f514cb</guid></item><item><title>Rick Morton's book about Robodebt, Mean Streak, among Prime Minister's Literary Award winners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/prime-ministers-literary-awards-rick-morton-mean-streak-robodebt/105808038</link><description>Journalist Rick Morton didn't want to write a book about Robodebt. Now that book, Mean Streak, has won the Prime Minister's Literary Award for non-fiction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5222686c405207b893f11605f1d249b6</guid></item><item><title>US to impose 100pc tariff on movies made outside the country, Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/us-to-impose-100-tariff-on-movies-made-outside-the-country/105832688</link><description>US President Donald Trump initially threatened to impose such levies earlier in May but offered few details, leading to confusion among entertainment industry executives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c6b83ec49a52515805a0e1a9b788860</guid></item><item><title>Private equity consortium offers to buy Electronic Arts for $80 billion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/consortium-buys-electronic-arts-for-55-billion-dollars/105832746</link><description>A consortium of private equity companies, including one backed by Donald Trump's son-in-law, Jared Kushner, is offering to take the video game giant private.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a06eae9e8baf8c4fc089531baf0884ed</guid></item><item><title>Inside Iran, a paranoid regime hunts for traitors and spies after its war with Israel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/iran-hunts-spies-and-traitors-after-israeli-spy-infiltration/105822466</link><description>For 12 days in June, the world watched as Iran and Israel traded blows. What came next was a brutal purge of spies and traitors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bd8ed2cd2c6a2db151383f80c45b3bf</guid></item><item><title>Will the Reserve Bank cut interest rates today? Only if hell freezes over</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/reserve-bank-set-to-keep-interest-rates-on-hold-at-sept-meeting/105830776</link><description>With markets pricing next to no chance of an interest rate cut today, what are the chances of another RBA move before year's end?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7391188e4fe7f994864ec7dc5831b5d4</guid></item><item><title>What could Thriving Kids, the NDIS alternative for some children, look like?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/thriving-kids-autism-developmental-delay-design/105793852</link><description>Despite the government wanting its Thriving Kids program for children with "mild to moderate" developmental delay and autism to start next year, the system is yet to be designed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11b6c263c5db7a26886a74772271eb7d</guid></item><item><title>Benjamin Netanyahu agrees to Donald Trump's 20-point Gaza peace plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/israel-gaza-peace-plan-white-house-announcement/105832816</link><description>Israel has agreed to a US proposal to end its war on Gaza, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and US President Donald Trump announce after holding talks at the White House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7a1f4e181a9cb0ff116cb25c804daf0</guid></item><item><title>Clock is ticking for Optus boss as triple-0 disaster escalates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/optus-triple-zero-disaster-means-clock-ticking-for-ceo-rue/105832282</link><description>Analysts say the Optus CEO should "leave quietly" now or risk a more public exit once the reviews into the company's recent outages are complete.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d065263a83281a11837869d86cf3d983</guid></item><item><title>Consultancy bill to review 'struggling' submarine agency blows out to $12.1 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/submarine-agency-consultant-review-blows-out-aukus/105831752</link><description>The agency responsible for delivering AUKUS has spent five times what it first planned for consultants to review its operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf24c34870572f0d84606c9ed22dfb92</guid></item><item><title>Pro-EU party wins majority in Moldova election in setback for Russia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/pro-eu-party-wins-majority-in-moldova-election/105832904</link><description>Moscow is accused of attempting to sway the election in favour of a pro-Russian party, but a majority of voters backed the pro-EU Party of Action and Solidarity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96ceb7f4e8448574865973b7d1624d57</guid></item><item><title>Tom Ballard's new show searches for the line between funny and offensive while pushing the comedy envelope</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/tom-ballard-jks-a-comedy-melbourne-fringe-festival/105829986</link><description>Comedian Tom Ballard is swapping a stand-up stage for a dramatic one as his new stage show asks, how do you remember a divisive figure?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8deace55743245b36e5fd8f6ad090d8</guid></item><item><title>Looming crisis for older Australian women who will retire into poverty if no urgent action taken, new report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/super-crisis-for-women-who-retire-in-poverty-new-report-says/105830680</link><description>Women's super balances are disproportionately impacted by events later in life, in addition to childcare duties, which could mean serious financial problems, research from Super Members Council (SMC) has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f10e93e0fbfcfdb37654ad8d0c08828</guid></item><item><title>Federal environment minister knew of rock art fears before granting Woodside North West Shelf extension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/murray-watt-murujuga-rock-art-woodside-extension/105831128</link><description>The federal environment minister was advised pollution from Woodside's Karratha Gas Plant may be causing irreversible changes to ancient rock art, before granting the company a 40-year extension with strict conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fe1024f68585a39e20b2ea2ecd5747f</guid></item><item><title>What is Donald Trump's peace plan for Gaza?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/what-is-donald-trump-peace-plan-for-gaza/105832748</link><description>US President Donald Trump has pitched a 20-point peace plan for Gaza, after meeting with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35d5e8dbb083b3be541952e63f593457</guid></item><item><title>Mitch Brown hits out at Bailey Smith and Patrick Dangerfield over 'homophobic' social media post from Geelong Mad Monday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/geelong-cats-mad-monday-mitch-brown-hits-out-at-smith/105833250</link><description>Mitch Brown, the first AFL player to reveal he is bisexual, hits out at Bailey Smith and Patrick Dangerfield over a social media post from Mad Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33be92e1e52ee7e5f5e0402c86508d43</guid></item><item><title>Reserve Bank keeps interest rates on hold, RBA governor says property market at 'difficult' point — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/rba-interest-rates-asx-markets-business-live-news-29-sept/105831264</link><description>The Reserve Bank left the cash rate steady at 3.6 per cent at its latest board meeting, as expectations of a November rate cut declined.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1586079bce949bf1d6b30c9934c9d44f</guid></item><item><title>Taliban imposes communication shutdown in Afghanistan after severing fibre optic connections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/afghanistan-taliban-imposes-communication-shutdown/105833300</link><description>Taliban authorities in Afghanistan have imposed a nationwide shutdown of communications, weeks after they began severing fibre optic connections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa47ca3794742304b50f8bf884b4e0e8</guid></item><item><title>YouTube to pay Trump $33.46m following January 6 Capitol riots ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/youtube-settles-with-donald-trump-in-capitol-riot-ban/105833406</link><description>Donald Trump sued parent company Alphabet and other social media companies after the platforms suspended his accounts in 2021.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d1bb644c6003414da83fd1b747251c4</guid></item><item><title>Southern Cross Media and Seven West Media announce merger, Kerry Stokes to step down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/southern-cross-austereo-and-seven-west-media-merge/105833848</link><description>Media magnate Kerry Stokes will stand down as chair of Seven West Media after the company announced plans to merge with Southern Cross Media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f614c97b8fbac30496e1c32a4483ab96</guid></item><item><title>Kane Cornes labels Geelong's Mad Monday antics 'disrespectful' and 'embarrassing'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/afl-community-react-to-geelongs-disrespectful-mad-monday/105834040</link><description>Kane Cornes labels Geelong's Mad Monday antics "disrespectful" and "embarrassing", after a slew of social media posts raises eyebrows across the AFL community, including one referencing his Seven colleague Caroline Wilson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e256b45f537f9f1f094c29befffe0edf</guid></item><item><title>Trump's peace plan shows Netanyahu has outmanoeuvred yet another American president</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/netanyahu-has-outmanoeuvred-yet-another-american-president/105833774</link><description>For all US President Donald Trump's boasts about ending wars and being a worthy candidate for a Nobel Peace Prize, he has failed to end the war in Gaza and build a sustainable future for both Israelis and Palestinians. At least for now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e4ef8c9191cf6f9517189aeae2286b1</guid></item><item><title>Why Bad Bunny is a controversial choice to headline Super Bowl half-time show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/why-bad-bunny-is-a-controversial-choice-for-super-bowl/105834094</link><description>Grammy-award winning rapper and singer Bad Bunny receives mixed reactions to the news he will headline the 2026 Super Bowl half-time show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f773b39eed99469859ef72baf7b22b5</guid></item><item><title>Police investigating deaths of mother and daughter at Kenmore Hills house listed on Airbnb</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/qld-police-investigating-death-mother-and-daughter-kenmore-hills/105833308</link><description>Police are investigating the sudden deaths of a mother and daughter whose bodies were found at a property in Kenmore Hills in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdb2e63bd212d8534f0611786f4dc53c</guid></item><item><title>Optus board expresses 'confidence' in CEO Stephen Rue to lead repair job</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/optus-anika-wells-meet-about-triple-0-outages/105833276</link><description>After it was initially unclear whether Optus and its Singaporean parent company, Singtel, had confidence in chief executive Stephen Rue, the board has confirmed in a statement its support for the embattled CEO to lead the task to restore confidence in Optus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffa091d24bdee9c5e49daa67768fabb7</guid></item><item><title>James Turner wins first gold medal for Australia at World Para Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/james-turner-gold-medal-world-para-athletics-championships/105834992</link><description>Paralympic champion James Turner wins Australia's first gold medal of the World Para Athletics Championships, saluting in the 400m T36 event in Delhi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8961ceea19af23e6792dc83d35ce6d61</guid></item><item><title>NSW government loses music festival strip search case as woman awarded $93,000 in damages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/nsw-government-loses-landmark-police-strip-search-festival-case/105833654</link><description>A Sydney woman subjected to an unlawful strip search at a music festival has been awarded $93,000 in damages, in a judgement that could see thousands of others also receive compensation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8731061ec317f2a8c3879d4163384bc7</guid></item><item><title>Lily Ridgeway found not guilty of Raymond Terrace manslaughter of Jason Adams</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/lily-ridgeway-not-guilty-manslaughter-jason-adams/105820526</link><description>Lily Ridgeway, 27, has been found not guilty of manslaughter over the 2020 death of Jason Adams in the NSW Hunter Valley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12bbe9e6705ff5c489b0b9f36a66e077</guid></item><item><title>How Brisbane's culture of empowerment has allowed its youngsters to be fearless on the AFL's biggest stage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/afl-brisbane-lions-empowerment-youngsters-grand-final/105833746</link><description>Brisbane's youngest players rise to the occasion on the biggest stage, led by its 21-year-old Norm Smith medallist Will Ashcroft. Here's how the two-time premiers allow their kids to thrive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c817f23b0eba7b31b09a29d4859ec37</guid></item><item><title>New Spirit of Tasmania vessels need hull upgrades in case of 'extreme' weather, TT-Line says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/tas-spirit-of-tasmania-hull-upgrade-needed/105833990</link><description>The new Bass Strait ferries have both been completed but new works are needed after an issue with the vessels' hull specifications was detected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49e5e91f617d0c86340eb3fb5eedbd93</guid></item><item><title>RBA holds interest rates in September, market bets on one more cut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/rba-leaves-interest-rates-on-hold-in-september/105835342</link><description>The Reserve Bank leaves interest rates on hold at 3.6 per cent, having cut them at its previous meeting in August, while market pricing for a November cut also fades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb931fecca858bfc78f61f8553caa441</guid></item><item><title>Calls for investigation after thousands of scans may not have been reviewed by doctors at Caboolture Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/qld-caboolture-hospital-thousands-scans-not-reviewed-review/105834958</link><description>Queensland's premier has called for an independent investigation into the problem, affecting up to 9,000 patients at Caboolture Hospital dating back to April 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e660e5b728d6683b4b992947bd86277c</guid></item><item><title>What is the Riyadh Comedy Festival? The Saudi Arabia event stirring controversy in Hollywood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/riyadh-comedy-festival-begins-with-pete-davidson-bill-burr/105833686</link><description>The Riyadh Comedy Festival stars A-list comedians like Peter Davidson, but despite its blockbuster acts, it has copped backlash for what one human rights organisation says is a "whitewashing" of a "brutal repression of free speech".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">781f8dbcd30903d7de8068b4d1880cbf</guid></item><item><title>Geelong is known for its accessibility on Mad Monday, but Bailey Smith's posts have unravelled years of goodwill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/geelong-mad-monday-analysis-goodwill-unravels/105833790</link><description>Geelong forged years of goodwill via its accessibility to Mad Monday — now the club faces a mess that it never saw coming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb01a53a558c07a149255170f2a7537a</guid></item><item><title>Man drowns in Moore River at Guilderton, four swimmers rescued</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/guilderton-drowning-reports-moore-river-perth/105835732</link><description>A man in his 30s dies after an incident on the banks of the Moore River in Guilderton, while four other swimmers are rescued by bystanders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a514bd7e6734a6ff51b2194cea940d3</guid></item><item><title>Missing boy's family releases statement as search continues in mid-north SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/missing-4yo-boy-family-release-statement/105834906</link><description>The devastated family of a missing four-year-old boy has released a statement saying it is holding on to hope "he will be found and returned safely" as authorities and community members continue the search in mid-north South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7906f16cd7afb2eb27bc054e9012f08b</guid></item><item><title>'Complex' brief of evidence after group charged with stealing crocodile eggs from Kakadu National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/nt-unauthorised-taking-crocodile-eggs-kakadu-national-park/105834370</link><description>Four men, including a pilot who survived a fatal chopper crash in 2022, are facing Commonwealth charges for allegedly stealing saltwater crocodile eggs from Kakadu National Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0304fdecbe772deca4891e4a06f31fe9</guid></item><item><title>Lorde on her Charli xcx collaboration and exposing vulnerabilities on Virgin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/lorde-charli-xcx-girl-so-confusing-virgin-take-5-zan-rowe/105640698</link><description>When Charli xcx released a song about her on the era-defining album Brat, Lorde didn't expect it to drag her onto a path that would redefine her trajectory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4539d82345ce00e473b297d1139e0848</guid></item><item><title>Stolen WWII ledger returned to St Luke's church in Toowoomba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/st-lukes-toowoomba-stolen-wwii-ledger-found/105831060</link><description>The historic ledger, which bears the names of Toowoomba locals who served in WWII, went missing a month ago, but now it is back in safe hands thanks to a string of unlikely coincidences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8961c39443bc027c4a2c1ae8b7abdd58</guid></item><item><title>Australia ready to defend Women's Cricket World Cup trophy in India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/australia-ready-to-defend-women-s-cricket-world-cup-india/105835898</link><description>Australia's all-conquering generation of women's cricketers has one last Cricket World Cup feat to tick off, setting their sights on defying almost 40 years of history to win back-to-back ODI tournaments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4f0edc1a54eab871471c231f8d5855d</guid></item><item><title>West Coast Eagles handed extra draft pick, four rookie list spots to help climb up ladder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/west-coast-eagles-priority-pick-afl-assistance-package/105836060</link><description>The West Coast Eagles are handed an extra first-round draft pick and four additional rookie list spots from the AFL, in a bid to help the ailing club return to competitiveness after four dismal years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9feff746910248fecc11a86219cb423d</guid></item><item><title>Australian film industry fears Donald Trump's movie tariff threatens jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/fears-trump-film-tariff-could-hurt-australian-film-industry/105834582</link><description>The multi-billion-dollar Australian film industry searches for details after the US president announced he would impose a 100 per cent tariff on movies made outside America.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">136a332733ca27fcd51ab79654e57f49</guid></item><item><title>Speaking to others without kids helped me find a future after IVF</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/sashi-perera-finding-joy-after-stopping-ivf/105735290</link><description>The more people I spoke to, the less frightened I felt of my future. I could shift my focus to what I can do because I don't have a kid, instead of what I was missing out on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b4f48fad02df065f9a736939478d498</guid></item><item><title>Former British PM Tony Blair named as part of Donald Trump's Gaza recovery authority</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/tony-blair-gaza-explained-donald-trump-peace-plan/105834250</link><description>US President Donald Trump has unveiled his proposed peace plan for Gaza — pitching the return of a former British prime minister as its coordinator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b1873e7206745885d315e67267ae7c0</guid></item><item><title>Teenage boy injured after falling from train in Sydney's south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/teen-boy-injured-falling-train-woolooware-carringbah-sydney/105835360</link><description>Transport authorities are warning of a recent spike in a dangerous social media craze after a teenager fell onto railways tracks while reportedly train surfing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a707eaf63827dd5669b1a32586bd32e</guid></item><item><title>Jessica Ann Walker among trio accused of murdering Jayden Selfe in Attadale</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/jessica-ann-walker-accused-murder-jayden-selfe/105831694</link><description>Pictured riding on a luxury boat and posing on the deck of a multi-million-dollar home with sweeping views of the Swan River, life appeared good for Jessica Ann Walker in 2022 — but just three years later she would be charged with murdering a man.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bee22e867fede4d5afda761e4fe5161b</guid></item><item><title>Man alleged to have performed Nazi salute minutes after leaving police custody, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/qld-nazi-salute-charges-tylere-baker-pearce-court-bail/105835866</link><description>Tylere Baker-Pearce, 39, was hit with two additional counts of the alleged offence on Monday after being arrested by counterterrorism police outside the Brisbane Magistrates Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51871ef683010138a43d57ff1c59e6d8</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm and Brisbane Broncos name NRL grand finals teams, NRLW teams announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/melbourne-storm-brisbane-broncos-nrl-grand-final-teams/105836192</link><description>Brisbane Broncos' mid-year recruit Ben Talty has been dropped for this Sunday's NRL grand final, making way for the returning Pat Carrigan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b139d1c93ffd07d1815afdf4c95d2f09</guid></item><item><title>Leaked council email angers Clarence Valley caravan owners facing eviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/council-email-featuring-wrecking-ball-sparks-caravan-owner-anger/105829224</link><description>A leaked council email that shows wrecking balls smashing caravans has angered caravan owners facing eviction from four council-run parks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">536790fcfd281a79885028452c59f28e</guid></item><item><title>Rescuers search for missing students a day after Indonesian boarding school collapses during prayers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/indonesia-boarding-school-collapse/105836328</link><description>Indonesian rescuers are scrambling to locate 38 people feared trapped under rubble after an Islamic boarding school collapsed in the East Java town of Sidoarjo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c1cfbda615a91084b0366ed6aef0151</guid></item><item><title>Kash Patel gave New Zealand officials 3D-printed guns illegal to possess under local laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/kash-patel-gave-new-zealand-officials-3d-printed-guns/105836578</link><description>On a visit to New Zealand in July, FBI Director Kash Patel presented three senior security officials with 3D-printed guns that were later destroyed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bf94ff62ee2982a0d805eadf8a4de47</guid></item><item><title>Noemie Fox in the mix for podium at ICF Canoe Slalom World Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/icf-canoe-slalom-world-championships/105836784</link><description>Noemie Fox is on track for a podium finish in the canoe event at the ICF Canoe Slalom World Championships in Sydney, provided the Australian star can clean up her errors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5ee07edc9228f3ebade0e8c0f4e4832</guid></item><item><title>Nicole Kidman and Keith Urban separate after 19 years of marriage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/nicole-kidman-and-keith-urban-separation/105833442</link><description>A source close to the couple tells the ABC the separation was not a mutual decision, saying it was Urban's decision to leave the relationship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e81cf0bb0bb7525617787a8a43998838</guid></item><item><title>Clean-up underway after 'devastating' industrial spill in Far North Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/clean-up-underway-after-boral-spill-at-smiths-creek-in-cairns/105835936</link><description>Building company Boral works to clean up thousands of litres of kerosene and bitumen from one of its plants that have spilled into a creek in Cairns, connecting to an inlet that leads to the Great Barrier Reef.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a973536937e2bf9984291a17c0344987</guid></item></channel></rss>