<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 20:50:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Inflation cools in November with consumer prices rising 3.4pc but still above the RBA's target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/inflation-abs-monthly-cpi-for-november/106205848</link><description>Inflation cooled in November, with the consumer price index rising 3.4 per cent over the year, down from 3.8 per cent a month earlier. Some economists continue to forecast a February rate hike, however.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f13348eb885b0fed864738fbce93301b</guid></item><item><title>Who is Nicolás Maduro Guerra, the son of Venezuela's deposed leader?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/who-is-nicol%C3%A1s-maduro-guerra-son-of-venezuelan-leader/106202664</link><description>Nicolás Maduro Guerra rose through the ranks of his father's government and remains in Caracas. It's uncertain for how long.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dabc89c15f5459e8a52d8629ce14dc1</guid></item><item><title>Ben Stokes limps off during fourth day of final Ashes Test at SCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/ben-stokes-limps-off-fifth-ashes-test-scg/106206318</link><description>Ben Stokes left the field during the first session of the fourth day at the SCG, with England confirming their skipper was being assessed for a right adductor injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0e602a309ffcc4c39cd0fb90e32f2ec</guid></item><item><title>Poland to face Australia in United Cup quarterfinals after Hubert Hurkacz wins singles against the Netherlands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/poland-to-play-australia-united-cup-quarterfinals/106206422</link><description>Poland will meet the host nation in the last eight of the mixed-teams event after in-form Hubert Hurkacz beat Tallon Griekspoor of the Netherlands in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64fe6cf10297ec2f374a68bff622d074</guid></item><item><title>How to avoid heatstroke and when to call Triple Zero in a heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/heatwave-illness-and-how-to-protect-yourself/106205872</link><description>Extreme heat forecast for the next few days has prompted warnings form health experts. Here's how to stay safe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">697d4b3b3f2b3f0a17e64bf6fd46fdc4</guid></item><item><title>Past works reimagined in Second Look — Legacy, the Australian Design Centre's final exhibition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/australian-design-centre-second-look-legacy-exhibition/106192528</link><description>Second Look — Legacy celebrates sustainable making while paying homage to one of the most influential figures in Australia craft and design.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6796a5ca7d920ad8561aac2789c84e6</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne tram enthusiasts join fight to save India's last tram network</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/melbourne-tram-enthusiasts-fight-to-save-kolkata-tram-network/106204938</link><description>Melbourne's iconic trams thrive in a car-centred world, but Asia's oldest tramway is now facing extinction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce54859611aa9ff045d5ded24b2b723c</guid></item><item><title>Why does Trump want Greenland and why is it so important?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/why-does-trump-want-greenland-and-why-is-it-so-important/106203650</link><description>Donald Trump's continued interest in Greenland is part of his "America First" agenda to dominate the Western Hemisphere and contain China's interests in the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe83050ed01b2f0d3c705e4286721003</guid></item><item><title>Council calls in diggers as big swells deposit masses of seaweed on Sydney beaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/diggers-called-in-as-seaweed-masses-on-sydney-beaches/106206160</link><description>Piles of kelp were removed from a popular Sydney beach, although some councils prefer to leave the seaweed for its environmental benefit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5637b05772499f34725d36a017b4e93c</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal artist Bobbi Lockyer in tears as Australia Post loses $4k painting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/auspost-loses-4000-dollar-bobbi-lockyer-artwork-before-xmas/106206356</link><description>Indigenous artist Bobbi Lockyer has been left frustrated after she sent a $4,000 custom artwork of the Pilbara to a buyer in Queensland, only for an empty cardboard sleeve to be delivered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9d27135931651e6a5ebc9706fc2eba9</guid></item><item><title>Prisoners charged over death of Shannon Daniel Norgate to face court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/prisoners-charged-over-death-of-shannon-daniel-norgate/106119896</link><description>Two men are set to face court over the alleged murder of another prisoner in a Queensland jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ad977be3d0d4048879d23297720c39c</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave conditions likely to bring increase of flies and maggots</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/how-to-reduce-flies-maggots-at-home/105941190</link><description>Forecast heatwave conditions across large parts of the country could mean flies and maggots are more prevalent. Here's how to deal with them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd44e594d644af51a17c967e875c59ba</guid></item><item><title>Kimberly Birrell, Olivia Gadecki, Emerson Jones record second-round losses at Brisbane International</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/aussie-emerson-jones-out-brisbane-international-gadecki/106207056</link><description>Australian players Kimberly Birrell and Olivia Gadecki have fallen in the second round of the Brisbane International, along with rising star Emerson Jones, who went out after a high-quality encounter with the world number 17.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b35e2c4b3e39d3d89b44578a759a1ad6</guid></item><item><title>Songs from the Hottest 100 of 2005 that should have been higher</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/songs-from-hottest-100-of-2005-should-have-been-higher/106145224</link><description>Arctic Monkeys were that low!? These are the tunes from triple j's Hottest 100 of 20. years ago that deserved to have placed higher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afe7a93ca4bda33c4967345c3488e4f4</guid></item><item><title>Staff at new Noarlunga mental health unit 'visibly distressed and crying', union says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/sasmoa-raises-concerns-staff-pressured-at-mental-health-unit/106206512</link><description>South Australia's doctors' union has raised concerns that clinicians were distressed when asked to admit more patients at a new mental health unit at Noarlunga Hospital when staffing levels were "not clinically safe".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18ada848b526514d9d9fdbfb12165814</guid></item><item><title>Cosmetic nurse banned for two years after injecting botox without consulting doctor or obtaining prescription</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/qld-cosmetic-injectables-nurse-banned-ahpra/106206780</link><description>An AHPRA investigation found Thia Sullivan injected a patient without doctor consultation or a script, falsified records, and urged patients not to co-operate with police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24ab7c914abb7698629cc451740e2e66</guid></item><item><title>Ex-CIA agent Aldrich Ames who sold US secrets to the Soviets dies in prison at 84</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/cia-turncoat-aldrich-ames-who-sold-us-secrets-to-the-soviets-die/106207464</link><description>Aldrich Ames, who was 84, betrayed Western intelligence assets to the Soviet Union and Russia in one of the most damaging intelligence breaches in US history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e3f840337e699cc44ea7256e63057d7</guid></item><item><title>Beau Webster sparks another English meltdown and Jacob Bethell brings tears — quick hits from day four of the SCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/ashes-quick-hits-day-four-scg-test/106205924</link><description>Beau Webster sparks a classic English meltdown as Jacob Bethell brings tears while Ben Stokes fails to finish another series. Here are your quick hits from day four of the SCG Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c2b6e11a4423ebcc8a55b02204c09a9</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/wednesday-finance-with-david-chau/106206784</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32abbb1c99e93571bc99a25151991c64</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2026: Jacob Bethell, England's biggest hope and biggest blunder, sets up Sydney finale</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/jacob-bethell-englands-hope-sets-up-sydney-finale-day-four-scg/106206644</link><description>Jacob Bethell's brilliant maiden Test century sets up an intriguing finish in Sydney, but leaves everyone bemused as to where this precocious young player has been all summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31da6c565da8a3ff2614cf41621bb413</guid></item><item><title>Maida Vale, High Wycombe fire extinguished after closing parts of Roe Highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/residents-in-city-of-kalamunda-urged-to-take-shelter-bushfire/106207782</link><description>Ground and aerial crews successfully control a bushfire that closed a section of Roe Highway and brought traffic to a standstill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09de7784b5375473f30d3a264f7b54b3</guid></item><item><title>Nestlé recalls select batches of Alfamino infant formula</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/nestl%C3%A9-recalls-select-batches-of-alfamino-infant-formula/106207844</link><description>The precautionary measure is over concerns that the product could contain a toxin that can cause food poisoning symptoms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5d3dc52ac89a785c547074fcbc7903b</guid></item><item><title>Fresh probe for answers on missing woman in NT</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/fresh-probe-for-answers-on-missing-woman-in-nt/106207612</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f04830b581e9dc47670b333f87db977</guid></item><item><title>US seizes more oil tankers as it lays out three-phase plan for Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/us-intercepts-bella-1-venezuelan-oil-tanker-russia-sub/106208100</link><description>Russia says one of the Venezuela-linked tankers is "our vessel" and demands the quick release of its citizens, as the US pledges to continue seizing ships and keep the pressure on Venezuela's interim leaders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29305b17e024b72cafa330d35ccb80e0</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios and Thanasi Kokkinakis's Brisbane International campaign ends in loss to French duo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/special-k-duo-kyrgios-kokkinakis-lose-at-brisbane-international/106208078</link><description>Nick Kyrgios and Thanasi Kokkinakis's doubles campaign at the Brisbane International has come to an end after an entertaining tiebreak decider against France.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f534806a03bfefb2c8c01436015d4bf6</guid></item><item><title>Property losses, warnings for bushfires across Victoria as firefighters prepare for 'catastrophic' conditions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/warnings-bushfire-victoria-longwood-mt-lawson-state-park/106207942</link><description>Emergency warnings remain in place as out-of-control blazes continue to burn in Victoria ahead of "catastrophic" fire conditions on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54310935b70c461d8a627f397c5eb0fe</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, January 8: 'El Chapo' recaptured in bloody raid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/today-in-history-january-8-el-chapo-recaptured/106192234</link><description>"Mission accomplished: we got him," began the triumphant tweet from Mexico's then-president Enrique Peña Nieto.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5827f4bceceda64381161c6f1f412626</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave breakdown state-by-state as breeze offers just a brief reprieve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/how-the-heatwave-will-play-out-in-each-state/106206670</link><description>A breeze will bring a brief reprieve for coastal areas of Victoria and South Australia today before the heat and fire danger ramps up again tomorrow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb45894b9a1eefc5d284f032f9b55958</guid></item><item><title>NATO faces unpredictable threat from Donald Trump as US eyes Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/natos-latest-threat-could-be-coming-from-within-donald-trump/106205214</link><description>Donald Trump has made it clear he's departing from decades of US foreign policy norms and once-close allies are now questioning what it could mean for them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f34a592f3deb295efe74b82e88ce4a5</guid></item><item><title>Organiser of Indigenous deaths in custody rally vows to defy NSW protest laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/nsw-first-nations-rally-organiser-protest-laws-david-dungay-jr/106207676</link><description>Paul Silva says he plans to defy NSW's new protest restrictions to rally against Indigenous deaths in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e56b69535dce50cdc4a24c01dd7f1aa5</guid></item><item><title>Labor fundraiser at centre of Minns donations allegations bigger than official records suggest, newspaper report shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/labor-fundraiser-reportedly-bigger-than-official-records-suggest/106206142</link><description>A decade-old Labor fundraiser at the centre of allegations that NSW Premier Chris Minns conspired to evade a state donations law was reported at the time as a much bigger event than official records suggest, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0730d1e104831103f68c68aaddd0cea</guid></item><item><title>Derailed freight train shuts part of key national railway line. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/train-derailment-affects-key-south-australian-rail-line/106205992</link><description>The derailment of a freight train on a key section of railway in South Australia is affecting all transcontinental train services as heatwave conditions in the area impact the pace of recovery works.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ec1ffc355f468cfacd7c593d01a860d</guid></item><item><title>More than 29,000 head of livestock dead or missing in north-west Qld, as BOM predicts potential cyclone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/cattle-deaths-north-west-queensland-floods-more-rain-to-come/106206592</link><description>The number of livestock found dead across north-west Queensland is expected to rise, but for already devastated producers, a potential cyclone brings the threat of more rain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97b61ee0ffac242cd75d19eb6e026735</guid></item><item><title>Should you exercise during hot weather? Experts weigh in as southern states swelter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/can-you-exercise-safely-in-a-heatwave-australia/106206302</link><description>Despite parts of Australia experiencing the worst heatwave conditions since the 2019-20 Black Summer, people can still be spotted braving the hot weather to go for a run. Should they be doing this?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2c9a65a4f90ad9a05ba00c7174ea0e6</guid></item><item><title>Two-time major winner Coco Gauff heaps praise on rising Australian star Maya Joint</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/united-cup-tennis-coco-gauff-maya-joint-australia-us/106208390</link><description>World number four Coco Gauff describes Maya Joint as a "great talent" ahead of a potential match-up against the 19-year-old Australian at the United Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c0575015d78e3407300f26a351994b0</guid></item><item><title>NT rangers capture croc a day in first week of new year, after more than 240 caught in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/nt-parks-and-wildlife-rangers-crocodile-capture-data-croc-risk/106206212</link><description>Rangers in the Northern Territory have caught an average of a crocodile per day in the first week of 2026, including one measuring 4.9 metres pulled from waters near a popular swimming spot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">575c9d4ba6f4778c96acb242536571a6</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Emerson Jones targeting rankings jump in 2026 after Brisbane International showing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/brisbane-international-emerson-jones-wants-to-reach-top-100/106208514</link><description>Emerson Jones gave a glimpse of her potential at the Brisbane International, with her 2026 season getting underway in promising fashion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">077a1b3047011e1af773f89ce733c29c</guid></item><item><title>What the 'I'm an American living in Australia' Instagram and TikTok trend reveals about both countries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/what-im-an-american-in-australia-trend-reveals-about-usa-and-us/106135242</link><description>Americans are posting sunny social media dispatches about their new lives in Australia, but there is something more revealing underneath.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ebbb3bb973e31d8db2e95e873ec2ffc</guid></item><item><title>Actor Awards nominations 2026: Australian stars Jacob Elordi, Sarah Snook and Rose Byrne among nominees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/sag-actor-award-nominations/106208668</link><description>Australian names are among the mix of nominees unveiled for Hollywood's Actor Awards, formerly known as the Screen Actors Guild Awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2da960f27bdebc5e7ba4cd8afcc9844</guid></item><item><title>Ollie Peake's last-ball six hands Renegades controversial BBL win over Scorchers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/bbl-ollie-peake-melbourne-renegades-perth-scorchers/106208704</link><description>Ollie Peake survives a contentious overturned catch to smash a six on the final delivery to seal a four-wicket win for the Melbourne Renegades in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e340c9416d62ddc933e2a89761b4936</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2026: Australia claims 4-1 series win after surviving nervy run chase to win Sydney Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/ashes-live-blog-day-five-scg/106208540</link><description>Australia chases down 160 with five wickets remaining in Sydney to round out the Ashes in style as Usman Khawaja bids farewell to Test cricket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">561f6e0d36232b22c3058b783d0b4529</guid></item><item><title>Algal bloom researcher 'deeply disturbed' by political interference claims, committee told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/claims-algal-bloom-cause-probe-delayed-until-after-sa-election/106208450</link><description>An inquiry into South Australia's harmful algal bloom has been rocked by claims from a prominent ecologist, who has raised allegations of government interference in scientific research into the bloom's causes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddbdc6a9b523b6c81afed0925ddeaa47</guid></item><item><title>Commercial fishers hit by Kimberley Marine Park left waiting five years for compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/commercial-fishers-still-waiting-compensation-kimberley-wa/106206918</link><description>Kimberley fishers impacted by the establishment of a marine park say the government has failed to deliver promised compensation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6002d73bf44564f51ba3d2a7fc29d97d</guid></item><item><title>Laura Peel boosts Australian Winter Olympics hopes with World Cup aerials victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/world-cup-laura-peel-win-gold-ahead-of-winter-olympics/106209106</link><description>After recently struggling for form, Australian star Laura Peel strikes gold at the aerials World Cup event in Canada in her best showing of the season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9ddfd3517b7db131eeb9468716932c3</guid></item><item><title>What the seizure of Maduro means for China, Venezuela's biggest oil buyer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/china-close-ties-with-venezuela-inaction-since-maduro-capture/106205836</link><description>Despite being one of the strongest critics of Donald Trump's move to capture Nicolás Maduro, Beijing has not moved beyond condemnation of Washington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f783c8e2d27f1fa5e3da5837c0681ffa</guid></item><item><title>Veteran Stan Wawrinka says Nick Kyrgios is an 'amazing player' amid wildcard debate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/wawrinka-on-kyrgios-australian-open-wildcard/106209186</link><description>Retiring veteran Stan Wawrinka was all class discussing the AO wildcard debate surrounding Nick Kyrgios, putting aside the pair's troubled history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32410a257a44771fc70bd7f1a788ca37</guid></item><item><title>Independent film collective Movie Juice launches inaugural summer film fest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/independent-film-collective-movie-juice-summer-film-festival/106207546</link><description>Summer has hit its stride with a heatwave across the country this week, providing the perfect backdrop to a new film festival that features beaches, surfing, young love, and that horrible feeling of holidays ebbing by.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c4265944145f44c4bd0a1e77ac10d99</guid></item><item><title>Grand Designs Transformations' Yasmine Ghoniem on living in her car, renovation mistakes and season two</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/grand-designs-transformations-yasmine-ghoniem-season-two/106199108</link><description>We chat with inimitable interior designer Yasmine Ghoniem ahead of Grand Designs Transformations series two to learn how she made it, her hot design takes, and what to expect from this season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0c60eebade36f183638f3ad12c09b98</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Test cricketer Damien Martyn returns home after waking from induced coma</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/cricket-damien-martyn-returns-home-after-induced-coma/106209598</link><description>Adam Gilchrist says his former Australia teammate Damien Martyn has been released from a Gold Coast hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49020d9667afff535b334516291f1145</guid></item><item><title>Kentbruck Green Energy Hub passes planning hurdle but report highlights environmental concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/kentbruck-wind-project-environmental-effects-approval/106206224</link><description>The Kentbruck Green Energy Hub would include wind turbines up to 270m tall, and be built inside active pine plantations, but its location has worried conservationists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3fb1208cb6857282d20eabaa766c4bf</guid></item><item><title>Reserve Bank deputy governor Andrew Hauser downplays easing inflation ahead of February meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/rba-deputy-andrew-hauser-inflation-interest-rates/106208716</link><description>The deputy governor of the Reserve Bank Andrew Hauser confirms the news mortgage borrowers would not have wanted to hear — interest rates are highly unlikely to head lower anytime soon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe254d1365e7c4696f8ec418bfb00e24</guid></item><item><title>No subscriptions? No problems. Here are the best movies and TV series you can watch for free</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/free-movies-free-tv-watch-online/106207308</link><description>From Academy Award-winning performances to classic Australian comedy, fill the last moments of your holidays with these free movies and TV series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ce170a90764ebd85c804dafd5fbfac9</guid></item><item><title>Boom time for active holiday tours attracting travellers with 'young energy'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/active-holidays-ocean-swimming-popular-on-turkish-lycian-coast/106173770</link><description>There is no lounging by the pool for these travellers, who are spending a week swimming the remote waters of the Turkish Lycian coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f50bd5e400dc329dbb870202b6788d7b</guid></item><item><title>PM's possible pick to lead Bondi royal commission sparks pushback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/bondi-attack-royal-commission-albanese-pick-pushback/106209204</link><description>Anthony Albanese has been in talks about calling a Commonwealth royal commission into last month's attack, signalling to colleagues he is preparing to renege on his opposition to the idea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42ef15f840ee4889890b49e87d097982</guid></item><item><title>Wild mountain gorilla gives birth to twins in Virunga National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/gorilla-twins-born-virunga-national-park-drc-congo/106209406</link><description>A mountain gorilla named Mafuko gives birth to twins, a "rare and remarkable event", in Virunga National Park in the Democratic Republic of Congo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">998b170e96d5631d89a0dcba5830c535</guid></item><item><title>Lachie Neale given Lions' 'blessing' if he wants to return to Perth at end of 2026 AFL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/brisbane-lions-lachie-neale-chris-fagan/106210014</link><description>The Brisbane Lions will not stand in the way of Lachie Neale if the club's former co-captain chooses to return to Perth at the end of the season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">265443ee944d4f0969e173229e5bcc74</guid></item><item><title>Minnesota ICE shooting takes life of a legal observer, according to local representatives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/minneapolis-ice-shooting-inside-the-legal-observer-networks/106209032</link><description>As Donald Trump's immigration crackdown escalates in Minneapolis, networks of local residents patrol the streets too, warning of incoming ICE raids, documenting what happens and offering legal advice to those targeted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cf336bfbdefd534a2fa8318e8d340b4</guid></item><item><title>Track the temperatures as southern Australian states face heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/southern-aus-heatwave-temperature-tracker/106207608</link><description>Use our tracker to keep an eye on temperatures as a heatwave moves through the southern states.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d8a181032d9a281810c93c1d37de5e5</guid></item><item><title>What led to an ICE agent fatally shooting a public observer in Minneapolis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/ice-shooting-minneapolis-minnesota-immigration-crackdown/106209128</link><description>The fatal shooting of a legal observer by an ICE agent in Minneapolis is the latest flashpoint in Donald Trump's crackdown on immigration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11849a2196d3508fa03e7f8c93c295ee</guid></item><item><title>Queensland man to be extradited from Armidale over alleged river murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/jordan-weribone-charged-with-brayden-thomas-thurston-murder/106210024</link><description>A Queensland man will be extradited from New South Wales over the alleged murder of a 24-year-old man in a border community late last month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">025aceb029ded06145c857187bc6fe81</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja's fitting farewell, DRS drama and Marnus Labuschagne keeps things interesting — quick hits from day five of the SCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/quick-hits-scg-day-five-ashes-khawaja-marnus-labuschagne-run-out/106208590</link><description>The SCG celebrates a retiring hero and a rising star, tempers flair after another DRS debacle and Marnus mourns a horror run-out. Here are the quick hits from the final day of the 2025-26 Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77ca3d9cc1cfdef04cb23ba77b921608</guid></item><item><title>Australia underlines its Ashes dominance of England to write its own story at the SCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/australia-underlines-ashes-dominance-to-write-its-own-story/106209390</link><description>A 4-1 scoreline can leave no doubt, this has been an Ashes summer of dominance for a resilient Australian side and a tour of errors and mismanagement for England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">606001ce9ef51ebfbcdb879075270f38</guid></item><item><title>Lifting ban on developer donations could increase corruption risk, Queensland watchdog says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/qld-political-donation-ban-property-developers/106210392</link><description>Queensland's corruption watchdog has warned lifting a ban on political donations from developers could increase the risk of "actual or perceived" corruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec8a36f9dc9f5bef9f5c83b607d43f0e</guid></item><item><title>Authors withdraw from Adelaide Writers' Week after Randa Abdel-Fattah axed for 'cultural sensitivity'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/randa-abdel-fattah-adelaide-writers-week-axed-authors-withdraw/106210464</link><description>After Randa Abdel-Fattah was dropped from Adelaide Writers' Week by the Adelaide Festival Board, a slew of authors, including Michelle de Kretser, have withdrawn from the event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbd24da619c619fbb5f6c152023696dd</guid></item><item><title>Former High Court justice Virginia Bell to lead Bondi royal commission</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/albanese-bell-royal-commission-antisemitism-bondi/106210052</link><description>A national royal commission into antisemitism and social cohesion has been called by Anthony Albanese after weeks of pressure to establish an inquiry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bafdd0d809232c7d5e25a141799792e</guid></item><item><title>Comiskey Group's 'eco-tourism' park approved for Coochin Creek</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/coochin-creek-tourist-park-approved/106209514</link><description>The state government approves a 150-site tourist park with 95 conditions despite ongoing environmental concerns from authorities and community groups.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5154da108b6229fb799dd8e46b791ef7</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka and Elena Rybakina march on to Brisbane International quarter-finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/sabalenka-rybakina-brisbane-international-third-round-pegula/106210594</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka and Elena Rybakina continue their 2026 campaigns in emphatic fashion with victories at the Brisbane International.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92ccba7ac40057a455324a9c01d15e3e</guid></item><item><title>Two-week chase ends in dramatic seizure of Russian-flagged oil tanker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/how-the-russia-flagged-marinera-oil-tanker-seizure-unfolded/106208808</link><description>When a US-sanctioned oil tanker originally bound for Venezuela abruptly changed course, it set off a dramatic chase at sea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f9641191277ec55bb68a88279d678a9</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: PM announces antisemitism royal commission after Bondi terror attack — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/live-blog-albanese-antisemitism-royal-commission/106205802</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has announced a royal commission into antisemitism after the Bondi Beach terrorist attack</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94310421a68e882725eeea301656e2d8</guid></item><item><title>Three options the US is considering to take Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/three-options-us-considering-to-take-greenland/106207610</link><description>At least three options have been floated for Donald Trump to achieve his goal of taking Greenland for the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3601b8c080e0918077e50115bc01c245</guid></item><item><title>Self defence or murder? What the videos of the Minnesota ICE shooting show us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/what-happened-in-minnesota-ice-shooting-abc-verify/106209188</link><description>ICE agents shot a woman in Minnesota. The president says it was self-defence while protesters claim it was murder. Here's what the vision shows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9039ec1dfeba5997c2b389a07fab6acf</guid></item><item><title>Ashes player ratings: England and Australia report card from 2025-26 Test series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/ashes-england-and-australia-player-report-card-grades-ratings/106208798</link><description>Here are the player ratings from a one-sided Ashes series with a few stand-outs and perhaps more flame-outs across the five Tests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">939d1f0d022317cea88e5225e6a8ace9</guid></item><item><title>New research finds keeping room temperature at 24 degrees or below could reduce sleep stress for older Australians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/study-room-temperature-24-degrees-reduces-sleep-stress-elderly/106210362</link><description>The study by Griffith University in Brisbane finds that a room temperature while sleeping of more than 24 degrees Celsius increases heart rate variability and physiological stress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b774992e996255b6e0f55a92360ad037</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106210068</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69e249fc81f420bec1c7f1dbb652f773</guid></item><item><title>What is a pyroCB, a fire-generated thunderstorm?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/what-is-a-pyrocb-a-fire-generated-thunderstorm/106210552</link><description>The fire burning in north-east Victoria near Walwa was so fierce it generated its own weather this afternoon, including a substantial pyrocumulonimbus cloud with lightning and thunder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5efce84e61a4f0c416252768757be9b7</guid></item><item><title>Police arrest suspects after armed heist at airport believed to be Vanuatu's first organised robbery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/vanuatu-robbery-port-vila-airport/106206412</link><description>A brazen heist at Port Vila International Airport has stunned Vanuatu and become the talk of a nation unused to such overtly public acts of crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c81aa2a1227df3ea9a7c5a1bee55281</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says US oversight of Venezuela could last for years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/trump-says-us-oversight-of-venezuela-could-last-for-years/106211978</link><description>Donald Trump has said that "only time will tell" how long the United States will maintain oversight of Venezuela.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">009a8a43f1559dbff27c6077658d7fa7</guid></item><item><title>England vice-captain Harry Brook apologises for incident at New Zealand nightclub ahead of Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/harry-brook-scuffle-with-bouncer-before-new-zealand-odi/106212164</link><description>Harry Brook was fined $60,000 and has apologised for bringing "embarrassment" to the English cricket team in a scuffle with a bouncer shortly before the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65a3318f02eab2896e6476d757307460</guid></item><item><title>Rinky Hijikata suffers three-set loss against Giovanni Mpetshi Perricard at Brisbane International</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/hijikata-mpetshi-perricard-brisbane-international-quarter-finals/106212468</link><description>Rinky Hijikata's three-set loss to big-serving Frenchman Giovanni Mpetshi Perricard means there are no Australians left in the Brisbane International singles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56035a169d6797e540a548b6b3663643</guid></item><item><title>On her 44th birthday, Princess Catherine is quietly reshaping royal life after cancer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/princess-catherine-wales-birthday-44-reset-normal-royal-life/106206914</link><description>Catherine turns 44 today as she resets royal life with fewer public appearances, tighter boundaries and a strong emphasis on family life — a choice shaped by loss, illness and the pressure of being next in line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3759ffc377b5207d302e17af450cd6f</guid></item><item><title>Three people missing in Longwood bushfire amid 'catastrophic' fire danger for Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/catastrophic-extreme-bushfire-warning-for-victoria/106211318</link><description>Three people, including a child, are missing after a house was destroyed by the out-of-control Longwood bushfire in central Victoria, according to police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10d03171fbffff94b09273cddafc14a5</guid></item><item><title>Victorians on edge as state experiences first catastrophic bushfire conditions since 2019</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/vic-catastrophic-fire-warning-bushfires-fri-walwa-longwood/106210230</link><description>Catastrophic fire danger warnings are in place across parts of Victoria's north and west today, with two significant fires already burning out of control and soaring temperatures forecast on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b31bf8a8081eb882e61131b27dd456c</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave and fire threat forecast for NSW, Victoria and SA as temperatures nudge all-time record highs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/heatwave-fire-threat-peaking-as-temps-hit-record-high/106211144</link><description>Southern states continue to sweat through one of the most intense heatwaves on record, and for many regions, including Melbourne and Sydney, the hottest weather is still to come.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcf6161ee66e70f17cefb19ef9dab4fa</guid></item><item><title>JD Vance defends Minnesota shooting as self-defence amid immigration crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/minneapolis-shooting-fbi-bca-blocked/106212576</link><description>US Vice-President JD Vance says the shooting was justified and that 37-year-old mother-of-three Renee Nicole Good was a "victim of left-wing ideology".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">937d425141ba4a896aa30c8a33c94d21</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's comments about Greenland were once seen as a joke. Greenlanders are no longer laughing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/donald-trump-greenland-denmark-nato-comments-worrying-island/106210090</link><description>The United States has a long history of wanting to acquire Greenland, but people living on the island say Donald Trump's latest comments about annexation feel different.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">780d9c1f5e1d18550bf80d207f6c5b10</guid></item><item><title>What landlords are obliged to do to cool your rental as temperatures rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/what-rental-landlords-are-obliged-to-do-to-cool-homes/106209220</link><description>With the nation gripped by a heatwave, renters will be looking at their rights for cooling their homes. Here's what they can do.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3c6800978649b78c60677ea43c2cc27</guid></item><item><title>How the internet reacted to the fifth Ashes Test at the SCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/how-the-internet-reacted-to-the-fifth-ashes-test/106198770</link><description>The internet went wild as Australia dominated with the bat, led by Travis Head and Steve Smith, and England crumbled in the dying embers of the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab73112ebb189dad0b2e311cb6ccdeb6</guid></item><item><title>Solar to the fore as grid sails through heatwave and record demand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/solar-powers-australia-through-heatwave-conditions/106211394</link><description>For so long, the pounding sunshine of an Australian heatwave was the grid's biggest threat. It has now become its greatest asset.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae701b0cb782c015f079002489ef8776</guid></item><item><title>US Senate votes to limit Trump's power to order strikes in Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/senate-votes-to-limit-trump-war-powers/106212508</link><description>The vote in the Republican-controlled chamber still needs to pass the US House, and has virtually no chance of becoming law due to Donald Trump's presidential veto.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a5427cd6d6d5921804e7ab4c06fb178</guid></item><item><title>Australian heatwave: Firefighters battling multiple out-of-control blazes across Victoria — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/fire-weather-heatwave-live-blog-victoria-sa-nsw/106212116</link><description>Multiple out-of-control bushfires threaten dozens of towns in central and north-eastern Victoria, with hot temperatures and strong winds resulting in "catastrophic" fire conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcbd0376d084f9e59fa8783cce3c308c</guid></item><item><title>Insect enthusiasts helping researchers keep an eye on bug populations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/qld-bug-hunt-insects-photos-research-citizen-scientists/106171252</link><description>Queensland insect enthusiasts are snapping photos of their backyard bugs to help researchers monitor native and invasive species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4f7610e986e7cd15889efebe22c7a82</guid></item><item><title>Locals, summer tourists swelter through heatwave in South Australia's Riverland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/sa-riverland-heatwave-hot-weather-peak-tourist-season/106205990</link><description>South Australia's Riverland will swelter through yet another day in the mid-to-high 40s on Friday and will have to wait until the weekend for a reprieve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">156f32643cce0f3fd5034709d9ff285a</guid></item><item><title>'High chance' of a tropical cyclone forming off Queensland's north-east coast bringing heavy rainfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/tropical-low-to-hit-far-north-queensland-late-friday/106211562</link><description>A tropical low off the Coral Coast could have the potential to become a tropical cyclone over the weekend, as residents across the far-north prepare for heavy rainfall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c9c9b6e59e8b4ac8d3a9d52215e0ad6</guid></item><item><title>Maya Joint gets Ash Barty's backing with teenager's Australian Open milestone confirmed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/joint-gets-barty-s-backing-ahead-of-aus-open-seeding/106212664</link><description>Teenage star Maya Joint will be the first home women's seed at the Australian Open since former world number one Ash Barty broke a 44-year title drought in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54395c014b677d61b32bba59eed839b6</guid></item><item><title>RBA plays the long game on inflation, so an interest rate rise could still be some way off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/rba-deputy-governor-andrew-hauser-interest-rates-inflation-janda/106210128</link><description>The Reserve Bank says inflation is "too high", but that doesn't mean it will necessarily rush to raise interest rates next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">822c83de4d34fdbaba8bbaad3b53d3a5</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan and foreign prisoners to be released following seizure of Nicolás Maduro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/venezuela-prisoners-to-be-freed-after-us-seizure-of-maduro/106212566</link><description>The president of the country's parliament says that Venezuelan and foreign prisoners will be released in the coming hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">162dbf5e6813226eb49bca2ac138a569</guid></item><item><title>Matildas and Arsenal star Kyra Cooney-Cross returns home in wake of mother's cancer diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/matildas-star-cooney-cross-returns-home-to-face-family-tragedy/106212710</link><description>Arsenal's Australia international Kyra Cooney-Cross flies back to Australia to be with her mother, who has been diagnosed with stage 4 cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">022d27429b844ff00f76299de5f2a1ab</guid></item><item><title>Dubbo woman Molly Croft raises $2 million after battling cancer twice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/molly-croft-raises-2m-and-helps-others-find-their-rainbow/106095998</link><description>This 19-year-old from western NSW, who has been diagnosed with cancer twice, is now helping others "find their rainbow".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7680560ded4679aff964bf9d7446d06</guid></item><item><title>NT pokies clubs report member perks, lavish upgrades as 'community' benefits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/nt-pokies-community-contributions-member-perks-renovations-foi/106084120</link><description>Previously secret documents released under Freedom of Information laws have revealed how the Northern Territory's pokies clubs' community contributions are really being spent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b956be26d539f0a576209395e5c2ce80</guid></item><item><title>Rio Tinto stock tumbles on Glencore merger talks, dragging down ASX — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/asx-markets-business-live-news-jan-2025-9/106212732</link><description>Glencore has confirmed media speculation that the company is back in merger talks with Rio Tinto. Follow updates live on our business and finance blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35335a243eed68ad82bd29a3257dc72c</guid></item><item><title>Top tips for learning a musical instrument or taking up singing at any age</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/top-tips-for-learning-a-musical-instrument-or-taking-up-singing/106206612</link><description>You can pick up an instrument or learn to sing at any age. Here are some helpful tips from experts and ABC Classic audience members to get you started.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b6a800c527cc85e14d26b021f88d536</guid></item><item><title>Inside Nicolás Maduro's complex network of alleged drug traffickers wanted by the US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/us-nicolas-maduro-indictment-associates-list/106209272</link><description>The deposed Venezuelan president allegedly oversaw a network of associates to facilitate the flow of illegal drugs into the US, aided by false passports, a guerilla training school, jets and grenade launchers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7659a5da2c9963426ef0ce8943ce144d</guid></item><item><title>Man in anaphylactic shock on Virgin flight to WA's Pilbara saved by crew, another passenger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/selfless-act-saves-man-anaphylactic-shock-on-wa-virgin-flight/106209770</link><description>Pilbara resident Andrew Rawle found himself 30,000 feet in the air, unable to breathe due to anaphylactic shock, but was saved by the crew and the selfless act of another passenger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07f2dd24254e8cf0a23a06e972a26c2e</guid></item><item><title>Angela Jones's history-making ride from country upbringing to top of Queensland's jockey ranks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/angela-jones-journey-to-becoming-number-one-jockey-in-queensland/106158424</link><description>Angela Jones became the number one jockey in Queensland in 2025. Now, the determined young woman, who grew up on a central Queensland cattle farm, wants Group 1 glory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61a9fab622749cc9f453903462200fc3</guid></item><item><title>How The Pitt lured ER star Noah Wyle back into the emergency department</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/the-pitt-noah-wyle-er-r-scott-gemmill-john-wells/106118716</link><description>ER launched Noah Wyle's career in 1994. Thirty years later he's back in the emergency room — and scooping awards season — as Dr Robby in The Pitt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93a195925d2de69fb82fd3317eb6f950</guid></item><item><title>NetBlocks reports internet blackout imposed in Iran amid nationwide protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/internet-blackout-imposed-in-iran-amid-nationwide-protests/106213246</link><description>Human rights groups say more than 40 people have been killed in protest-related violence since last month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd286bff3887cc0397c214ae6c0c3596</guid></item><item><title>Arsenal's Gabriel Martinelli apologises for 'disgraceful' act towards injured Liverpool player Conor Bradley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/martinelli-disgraceful-act-towards-injured-liverpool-player/106213400</link><description>Arsenal winger Gabriel Martinelli has apologised for shoving Liverpool's Conor Bradley, who was down with a serious knee injury, off the pitch during their Premier League clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">249ee65a474fdfd5395e9aa04686c802</guid></item><item><title>Rio Tinto in merger talks with Glencore, takeover could create world's biggest miner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/rio-tinto-in-talks-to-take-over-glencore-mega-miner-merger/106213252</link><description>Rio Tinto and Glencore are in takeover talks that could potentially lead to a combined mega-miner worth more than $US200 billion. Analysts are questioning whether Rio will be interested in Glencore's coal assets, having sold off its own in 2018.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">045687aff3f78cbc211b52c08acfbb59</guid></item><item><title>Diana Camacaro fled Venezuela when a friend close to Nicolás Maduro's regime texted her she was on a list to be arrested</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/nicolas-maduros-regime-came-for-these-women-who-fled-to-colombia/106207412</link><description>When a Telegram message landed on her phone, Diana knew she had to flee Venezuela. It was from someone close to Nicolás Maduro, and she says she would have been jailed, or worse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c98ade3c4b3047c53890d5f90ef7983</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios not seeking Australian Open wildcard, saying he is 'not quite ready' for grand slam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/kyrgios-says-he-will-not-be-seeking-an-aus-open-wildcard/106213610</link><description>Returning from injury, Nick Kyrgios has spoken with Australian Open organisers and made the call not to use a wildcard to play singles this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c307000e133452ec9eef5fba817b560</guid></item><item><title>What we know about Australian Teagan Croft who will play Rapunzel in Disney's Tangled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/teagan-croft-to-play-rapunzel-in-disney-live-action-tangled/106213672</link><description>Australian actress Teagan Croft will take on the lead role of Rapunzel in Disney's Tangled. The 21-year-old will star alongside Milo Manheim in the live-action remake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e23c5ae58eb08fde143d918add4210f3</guid></item><item><title>The Bondi royal commission will be a long-term test of Albanese's leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/bondi-royal-commission-test-albanese-leadership/106213854</link><description>The prime minister's critics feel he failed to meet the moment in the immediate aftermath of the Bondi attack, but with the royal commission he has a chance to get it right.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">916f58de1d1e77dad7bbbe9ffc85cf2e</guid></item><item><title>Australia's population forecast to reach 28 million in 2026 despite fall in overseas migrants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/australias-population-to-reach-28-million-in-2026/106213420</link><description>Australia's population is forecast to reach 28 million people in 2026 despite an easing of overseas arrivals following the post-COVID-19 migration peak.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f16364694bdcb7d5d4f01791e0da9534</guid></item><item><title>Total fire ban as extreme fire weather predicted for parts of eastern Tasmania this weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/total-fire-ban-east-coast-tasmania-danger/106213058</link><description>A total fire ban is in place for parts of Tasmania from Saturday, due to extreme fire weather predicted for the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0a5b1a9a096c99d5594002934f18fd4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump pulls US out of dozens of international organisations on environment and security</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/us-withdrawal-trump-united-nations-organisations/106210134</link><description>Protecting women and children, halting climate change and preventing acts of terrorism — these are the goals the White House now says go against America's goals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bb7426e5eb9ca8d42907119842b9ba5</guid></item><item><title>Eloise Worledge disappeared from her Beaumaris home in 1976.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/eloise-worledge-disappearence/106214226</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e68178b85ca8f5b6a8d6614bba5a915f</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian author seeks to be reinstated to Adelaide Writers' Week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/sa-palestinian-author-calls-for-apology-over-writers-week-axing/106212878</link><description>Palestinian author Randa Abdel-Fattah has called for her appearance at Adelaide Writers' Week to be reinstated after it was axed, but SA's Premier has continued to back the decision, as dozens of authors cancel their appearances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bc84d20ac7f6de4042f859ef7f45602</guid></item><item><title>Grass fire burning in Wagga Wagga's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/grass-fire-burning-in-wagga-wagga-s-north/106214436</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b8856016b4a7c28344bcad2ae7feab4</guid></item><item><title>Surge in heat-related illness as temperatures continue to soar across south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/heat-illness-emergency-presentations-surge-heatwave/106213074</link><description>Emergency departments, medical centres and first responders are dealing with a surge in heat-related illness across Australia's south-east as temperatures soar to near record levels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b871b12491bc4d2dc8eaf82577c10a1</guid></item><item><title>Senior SA government officials reject claims of political interference into algal bloom causes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/sa-department-heads-reject-interference-claims-in-algal-bloom/106213376</link><description>Four of the most senior public servants working on South Australia's algal bloom have rejected allegations that departmental staff had been instructed not to investigate the cause of the ecological disaster until after March's state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">870976f9925aebd0a33e7f1bc1020da3</guid></item><item><title>Violence against state school teachers and staff nearly quadruples in three years, new data shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/queensland-state-school-violence-against-teachers-quadruples/106214512</link><description>The data, tabled in Queensland Parliament, showed there were 20,833 occupational violence and aggression incidents reported by school-based employees last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">714d0649ede605b3bd45722cd4b4a92f</guid></item><item><title>Russia says it has fired its Oreshnik hypersonic missile at Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/russia-says-it-hit-ukraine-with-oreshnik-hypersonic-missile/106214842</link><description>A "massive" Russian night-time attack on Ukraine damaged 20 residential buildings in Kyiv and its suburbs, as well as Qatar's embassy, President Volodymyr Zelenskyy says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a8f4739db2dad29330326f7b3195830</guid></item><item><title>Ruffy residents describe devastation wrought by central Victoria's Longwood bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/ruffy-residents-describe-devastation-after-longwood-bushfire/106214024</link><description>During winter the trees and hills surrounding the small hamlet of Ruffy are beautiful and green, but now it has been "decimated" by an out-of-control bushfire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91f86b02b839c5bc83a16621b222b9da</guid></item><item><title>NSW premier 'cannot remember' fundraiser at centre of undeclared donation allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/nsw-chris-minns-responds-to-undeclared-donation-allegations/106213922</link><description>Premier Chris Minns did not dispute a report that 200 people attended a fundraiser dinner, but could not recall how an event of that size raised only about $6,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd496ac70a1c6e73ae9ad81456624a2d</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/fins-financefri-090126/106215310</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8160784fdd2d14e6759eba9d94f19c14</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters continue to battle multiple out-of-control blazes across Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/bushfires-victoria-homes-razed-people-missing/106214638</link><description>Three people who had been reported missing have been located and Victoria's premier has declared a state of disaster as fast-moving bushfires threaten dozens of towns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7d4864d07ae5d2799ef75cb49e29241</guid></item><item><title>Iranian leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei defiant amid growing nationwide protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/iranian-leader-defiant-amid-nationwide-protests/106215570</link><description>Iran's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has remained defiant amid nationwide protests, saying his regime would not back down in the "face of saboteurs."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7824ad9e3d4314266df80acbf92fb3f4</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, January 10: The Sopranos changes television forever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/the-sopranos-first-episode-aired-january-10/106184120</link><description>Restaurant owners in New York would eventually complain of "the Soprano effect" when they lost trade on Sunday nights as patrons headed home to watch the show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffcb2a4fb64b3420356a8e83d5d0d0e0</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump is reshaping American power and the threat to international order is alarming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/trump-power-venezuela-greenland-international-law-morality/106214406</link><description>There have been plenty of examples of the Trump administration's contempt for legalities, diplomacy and alliances, but this week Trump and his lieutenants went further.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c22187d11c5335ce0bf87ef3d56a102</guid></item><item><title>Elon Musk's AI bot says it is limiting its ability to 'undress' users. Australians want an opt-out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/grok-ai-undressing-australia-women-children/106213644</link><description>For more than a week, X's AI bot Grok has been generating sexual images of women and children at the request of other users, even when they ask it not to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22ff953eef024151d04f32634fee90bd</guid></item><item><title>Cautious hopes Beijing lifting soft ban on South Korean pop culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/china-ban-south-korean-pop-culture-could-lift-amid-warmer-ties/106205780</link><description>China has restricted access to South Korean pop culture since 2016, when Seoul received US anti-missile technology. Warmer bilateral ties are spurring optimism that will change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ba4fe5aa1d0f4321bc3f7f578639c8b</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave and extreme weather: Bushfire disaster in Vic; threat rises in NSW; cyclone forms in Qld — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/state-of-disaster-declared-bushfires-victoria/106215462</link><description>Out-of-control bushfires are continuing to rip through Victoria with at least 130 homes and buildings across the state lost and more than 300,000 hectares of land burned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4531b20bfb843f3cd9dc55a9cbfc4ffd</guid></item><item><title>Barmy Army turns Ashes defeat into Australian tourism win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/barmy-army-australia-cricket-england-ashes-tourism/106214260</link><description>The Barmy Army has continued the recent trend of UK travellers spending more time and money in Australia, despite a disappointing on-field performance from their side.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0e0cdaaf5650b5241200515e45b1db6</guid></item><item><title>A royal commission into the Bondi terror attack is going ahead. Here's what to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/nsw-bondi-beach-terror-attack-royal-commission-explainer/106214222</link><description>After growing calls for a royal commission into the Bondi terror attack, the prime minister has finally announced it would take place, saying it "was what Australia needs".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5c4db150b54ae496aa3b27cd3284f13</guid></item><item><title>NSW SES moves to embrace 'volunteers for a day' to boost members after May 2025 floods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/nsw-ses-embraces-spontaneous-volunteering-from-mud-armies/106148252</link><description>Experts say volunteering is not in decline, but it is becoming more spontaneous. The NSW disaster agency is moving to embrace this after seven women mobilised 1,200 people to volunteer for a day in record-breaking floods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ec15e7a123bbf5e95ce4ac5c8fcc385</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave in southern states one of the most intense on record as Queensland braces for cyclone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/australia-weather-weekend-fire-threat-nsw-possible-cyclone-qld/106214346</link><description>The heatwave, which has engulfed southern Australia this week, has become one of the most intense on record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58204e4bff379826f49c6ba8cd360331</guid></item><item><title>BOM declares Cyclone Koji as category two system off north Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/queensland-tropical-low-expected-to-intensify-into-cyclone-koji/106213662</link><description>North Queensland residents are readying themselves as a category two cyclone moves towards them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31ff50af30cc18bf007aa03d6532275f</guid></item><item><title>The daily struggle continues in Caracas as Venezuelans dare to hope for change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/inside-venezuela-daily-struggle-continues-in-caracas/106215776</link><description>The ABC hears from residents of Venezuela's capital, Caracas, about the struggles of daily life and their hopes and fears after American intervention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46481d872f8a29319917daa1f987ff21</guid></item><item><title>Japanese Elvis Tribute Artist takes centre stage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/japanese-elvis-tribute-artist-toyokazu-toki-takes-centre-stage/106214362</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7b15d70e23ac49a96cca25a50627edb</guid></item><item><title>The King of Rock and Roll transcends language and culture at the Parkes Elvis Festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/parkes-elvis-festival-toki-toyokazu-singing/106209036</link><description>Japanese tribute artist Toki Toyokazu is part of a growing international presence at the annual Parkes Elvis Festival, which also includes women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10fce8d3fb0882e55de283e43848800a</guid></item><item><title>Australia loses to Poland 2-1 in United Cup quarterfinals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/united-cup-australia-loses-to-poland-in-quarterfinals/106215862</link><description>Alex de Minaur produces a signature tenacious display, but it is not enough to send Australia through to the United Cup semifinals in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be2d9f482580407d8766b7a4a3016264</guid></item><item><title>Talc Alf's carved artworks attract tourists travelling the Strzelecki Track in outback SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/talf-alc-art-gallery-off-strzelecki-track-in-outback-sa/106215944</link><description>Off the Strzelecki Track in outback South Australia lies the gallery of Alf Talc, so named for the artworks he carves out of soft, powdery talc.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df41f2abeace4c13f0d72aa4071eaece</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka defeats Madison Keys in Australian Open final re-match at Brisbane International</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/brisbane-international-aryna-sabalenka-defeats-madison-keys/106215886</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka says she is no longer thinking about last year's Australian Open final loss to Madison Keys after defeating the US star at the Brisbane International.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8180e2dc6d360a3580a056c9b69885ba</guid></item><item><title>Wildlife ACT calls for more volunteers as demand soars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/behind-the-scenes-wildlife-carer-need-for-more-volunteers/106197866</link><description>There are about 40-50 active volunteer carers within ACT Wildlife, but the organisation says more are needed, especially as the temperature soars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f5a4332242278a963a96a5f5349515f</guid></item><item><title>Gladstone company taking centre stage in AI revolution, providing a critical mineral to cool computer chips</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/alpha-hpa-gladstone-high-purity-alumina-ai/106213676</link><description>The industrial hub is playing a key role in the AI industry as it pumps out a critical material needed to cool high-performance computer chips.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d9c1e88cea4d8966d5dcf9a4a5eddaa</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of alcohol products still without 'mandatory' pregnancy warnings, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/mums-drank-pregnancy-alcohol-warning-labels/106154908</link><description>New research shows thousands of alcohol products remain on Australian shelves without mandated pregnancy warning labels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4783e5564f11c66b51e1823883c1fc40</guid></item><item><title>Wall blocking Strahan waterfront views on Tasmania's west coast attracts ridicule</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/wall-blocking-views-on-strahan-waterfront-ridiculed/106209782</link><description>A concrete wall built on the picturesque waterfront of a small Tasmanian town has prompted confusion and concern from residents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15cbec567e8dd1d225fab9e0f9126558</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Island plastics pollution battle for turtles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/christmas-island-turtles-battle-plastic-pollution/106092234</link><description>A beach on a remote island, and home to nesting turtles, is annually overwhelmed by tonnes of plastic garbage. Christmas Island is doing what it can to help stem the never-ending tide of pollution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d3dcc3dcbe6121099810921fa255ce7</guid></item><item><title>NT town of Katherine home of Australia's best tasting tap water, nine years after PFAS detected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/katherine-pfas-australia-best-drinking-water/106184842</link><description>The tap water in the Northern Territory town of Katherine — which includes a "designer" mix of river water from the world-famous Nitmiluk National Park and mineral-rich groundwater — has been named Australia's best drop.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">261a9a94bd6f12376ce7733c8591bf93</guid></item><item><title>New video emerges of ICE agent shooting Renee Nicole Good in Minneapolis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/new-video-shows-renee-good-shooting-ice-agent/106216052</link><description>The new footage, reposted by the White House on social media, shows the recording made by the agent responsible for the shooting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82569c5ee3cb9b43c0d81e97092b0ab9</guid></item><item><title>Coronial inquest into death of Indigenous woman identifies 'chain of failures' at Royal Darwin Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/nt-inquest-indigenous-woman-died-at-royal-darwin-hospital-rdh/106214552</link><description>The Northern Territory coroner has determined a series of human errors contributed to the 2022 death of an Indigenous woman at Royal Darwin Hospital, in the weeks after she sought a routine surgery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f42a17b1714b5d0d3ff6fc9d137f0e5</guid></item><item><title>History made as first woman Erin Tassell in emergency management role in WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/erin-tassell-first-woman-in-fire-management-role/106214424</link><description>Behind every emergency in WA, from bushfires to whale rescues, a state duty officer is making critical decisions. New hire Erin Tassell is breaking new ground in a key government department.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6730a74e0ac97e410d1f9480fd22cfb</guid></item><item><title>Hollywood-backed Wrexham knocks Nottingham Forest out of FA Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/fa-cup-wrexham-beats-nottingham-forest-on-penalties/106216130</link><description>As actor and co-owner Ryan Reynolds watched on in the grandstand, Wrexham defeated Nottingham Forest on penalties to advance to the fourth round of the FA Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91bb5ae037795ce58b925a93a6f7f216</guid></item><item><title>Bushfires across Victoria wreak havoc on farmlands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/bushfires-across-victoria-wreak-havoc-on-farmlands/106216238</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c2ad5d2e8c4a88c6cd93b683f5f8d07</guid></item><item><title>Farmlands burn across Alexandra, Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/farmlands-burn-across-alexandra-victoria-/106216384</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b4b00b5df0c8569235cba051a3e411</guid></item><item><title>Sixth man charged after livestock carrier allegedly used for cocaine drop in WA waters off Lancelin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/sixth-man-charged-over-alleged-livestock-carrier-cocaine-plot/106216218</link><description>A sixth man is charged over an alleged plot to import half a tonne of cocaine into Western Australia using an international livestock carrier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b13f0fc413d246d59124f501cd43ee40</guid></item><item><title>Scaled-down race cars, a few nerves and a tight-knit community at Narrogin speedway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/young-people-get-behind-wheel-of-race-cars-at-narrogin-speedway/106188714</link><description>A long-running project in the WA town of Narrogin gives young people the opportunity to get behind the wheel of race cars. Organisers say it is about more than just racing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">461f71dc0cafdc6667532c6c3939b30b</guid></item><item><title>NSW bakes through temperatures above 40 degrees as fire crews successfully contain blazes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/fire-danger-heatwave-winds-expected-across-nsw/106215426</link><description>Scorching temperatures lingered late into Saturday across NSW with the hottest place in the state's far west recording 44.6 degrees Celsius.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b231cedc2fe401167227036f94b22b8e</guid></item><item><title>Switzerland holds national day of mourning for the 40 victims of the New Years Day ski bar fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/switerland-holds-national-day-of-mourning-bar-fire/106216232</link><description>Forty people died and 116 people were injured in the fire at the Swiss ski bar on January 1.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd5fe8c20d03f5897420f96311f3c38b</guid></item><item><title>Trump tells oil executives Venezuela is 'open for business'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/trump-tells-oil-executives-venezuela-is-open-for-business-/106216412</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">334da6ddf305874670f9f9f64ad542f0</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says oil executives will have 'total safety' if they invest in Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/donald-trump-calls-on-oil-executives-to-invest-in-venezuela/106216060</link><description>The US president has pivoted to portraying capturing former Venezuelan leader Nicolás Maduro as as a new-found economic opportunity for the US, seizing tankers carrying Venezuelan oil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dc2fcdae1c71862418dd85affd8a742</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's bushfires spread as two blazes burn out of control in Otways</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/bushfires-victoria-otways-harcourt-ravenswood-evacuation-orders/106216316</link><description>Fires in the Otway National Park are moving towards the town border of Colac, as firefighters continue to battle blazes across the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1eb719b39b488ae1230329f141585bab</guid></item><item><title>Marta Kostyuk crushes Jessica Pegula, Aryna Sabalenka powers past Karolína Muchová to reach Brisbane International final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/brisbane-international-semi-finals/106216472</link><description>Marta Kostyuk crushed world number six Jessica Pegula in less than an hour after Aryna Sabalenka powered past Karolína Muchová to reach a third consecutive Brisbane International final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e10e795e41fdde9877e558423899e1fc</guid></item><item><title>Australia will join G7 countries to discuss critical minerals in Washington next week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/australia-india-invited-to-g7-meeting-on-critical-minerals/106216434</link><description>India was also invited to attend the meeting, but it is unclear if it has accepted the invitation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5033c9e681d0a3e4dbd6b5122cd4832d</guid></item><item><title>Animals at Symbio Wildlife Park beating the heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/animals-at-symbio-wildlife-park-beating-the-heat/106216626</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dcbe6404c6ecf469ff1d372ddc74ebe</guid></item><item><title>Ravenswood local 'Catman' shares heartbreak after 'catastrophic' bushfire damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/ravenswood-bushfire-catman-damage/106216450</link><description>Approximately 50 structures have so far been destroyed in the Ravenswood and Harcourt bushfire, according to emergency services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1cab92c8e442ba1104092044e5fd339</guid></item><item><title>Video shows fire damage and spread in the Ravenswood-Harcourt fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/fire-damage-at-harcourt/106216668</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85ede2102be24b61a7ecac9f5c46a595</guid></item><item><title>Suspected copper thieves cut telecommunications to thousands in cyclone warning zone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/north-queensland-copper-thieves-cut-phone-internet-services/106216478</link><description>Thousands of North Queensland residents within a cyclone warning zone were without telecommunications services after suspected copper thieves cut cables.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc818474e3acca89ab765338c03368cc</guid></item><item><title>Former Adelaide Festival leaders pressure board to reinstate Palestinian author</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/adelaide-writers-week-board-letter/106216140</link><description>Nearly a dozen former leaders of the Adelaide Festival are calling for Randa Abdel-Fattah to be reinvited to Writers' Week, adding to a mounting crisis over the Palestinian-Australian author's exclusion from the literary festival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">419d86892f36312376cb6d948b7d5fd7</guid></item><item><title>Harcourt residents assessing damage after more than 50 structures lost in Ravenswood fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/harcourt-residents-assessing-fire-damage-50-structures-destroyed/106216128</link><description>Harcourt residents describe their devastation and gratitude in the wake of a massive blaze that swept through the town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41a20d508de1332022c43cad5ffab3d8</guid></item><item><title>Jakara Anthony wins gold, Matt Graham silver at Val Saint-Côme World Cup moguls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/jakara-anthony-wins-val-st-come-moguls-gold-matt-graham-silver/106216564</link><description>Jakara Anthony and Matt Graham both move to the top of the overall FIS Moguls World Cup standings with success at Val Saint-Côme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc6737a14624333a7254e0de0bc51b8c</guid></item><item><title>Scenes of destruction in Natimuk after Grass Flat fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/scenes-of-destruction-in-natimuk-after-grass-flat-fire/106216792</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8d99457fc813ac3e502a7f2e1f38727</guid></item><item><title>Vox pops with young smokers in 1964</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/smoking-vox-pops/106214428</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b599cb45f0ae4e0671abd61caf1aa98</guid></item><item><title>ABC journalist reports on Australia's tobacco industry in 1964</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/piece-to-camera/106214434</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77c4c451c5665f0e4b741c2ea74d0fe2</guid></item><item><title>A woman likens smoking to befriending a killer, during 1964 vox pop in Sydney.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/women-smoking-interview/106214426</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab041f7373861bff8fe53d7fb4600b5d</guid></item><item><title>1964 ABC News report about Australia's cigarette habit and efforts to curtail the hugely lucrative tobacco industry.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/abc-news-report/106214418</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fd470326da86f22844c2a7e437e47a2</guid></item><item><title>Nobel Laureate Sir Frank Macfarlane Burnet speaks to ABC News in 1964 about the dangers of smoking.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/burnet/106214420</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a2220457f2aed2e95fe86641384da2f</guid></item><item><title>A man on the streets of Sydney in 1964 tells an ABC reporter "let them smoke and die", in response to the growing anti-smoking campaigns.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/man-on-street/106214416</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca950d579d2921aeff1347e3f5f1c980</guid></item><item><title>RFS vision of bushfire burning at Brassknocker Firetrail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/rfs-vision-of-bushfire-burning-at-brassknocker-firetrail/106216834</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db8e70a5e4f29cb1266090a8566c5c8b</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Koji tracker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/tropical-cyclone-koji-tracker-north-queensland/106213640</link><description>Track the path of Tropical Cyclone Koji and monitor wind speeds as the system moves towards the coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e01cb181b9fdc2ab038764eefe8a0ef3</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja stars as Brisbane Heat beat Sydney Thunder in Big Bash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/bbl-brisbane-heat-beat-sydney-thunder-usman-khawaja-stars/106217066</link><description>Usman Khawaja's international career may be over, but he showed he is far from a spent force by stroking a fine 78 to help the Brisbane Heat to a BBL victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c207ff6a675044a194a5ef775cf96b0a</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open quiz: Can you get through this round in straight sets?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/australian-open-quiz/106213602</link><description>Take the covers off centre court! It's Australian Open time again. How well do you remember grand slams past?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a690bc29611ee04f1908e393963045b6</guid></item><item><title>Eloise Worledge was snatched from her bed. 50 years on her aunt is still looking for answers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/eloise-worledge-disappearance-50-anniversary-beaumaris/106207002</link><description>Fifty years after Beaumaris schoolgirl Eloise Worledge vanished, could new leads solve one of Australia's most haunting cold cases?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf4ad851f0d548a04588c6372c65d5a5</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, January 11: Smoking link to cancer announced in groundbreaking report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/today-in-history-january-11-smoking-cancer-link-/106185276</link><description>In 1964, a major scientific report laid bare the deadly risks of smoking, at a time when the tobacco industry had a stronghold on the public and government coffers. Delve into the ABC Archives to discover how Australians reacted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f3b760fbe172c75b58503d89275571c</guid></item><item><title>Natimuk community counting its losses from fast-moving Victorian fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/natimuk-township-loses-structures-homes-from-victoria-fire/106216288</link><description>Residents of the township of Natimuk, population 500, have returned to find homes and businesses gone, but say its community spirit will shine brighter than ever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">394f62682a9f1d62c5eb528f785db0e3</guid></item><item><title>Has Trump landed a dud with his Venezuelan oil play?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/has-trump-landed-a-dud-with-his-venezuelan-oil-play/106214900</link><description>While debate rages over the legality and the potential fallout from America's incursion, there's been a quiet acceptance that it is all about oil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c33d1561d445544b079145ddf3e5d257</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters continue to battle bushfires across Victoria as towns remain on edge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/bushfires-victoria-longwood-otways-walwa/106216856</link><description>Authorities say the Longwood fire in central Victoria and fires in the Otways in the state's south-west are of greatest concern to firefighters as blazes continue to burn across the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e3e9e246e6c576c1c48b9911fa8cd42</guid></item><item><title>Former members of Two by Twos call for financial transparency to access abuse compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/two-by-twos-christian-sect-child-sex-abuse-compensation-redress/106160220</link><description>Survivors of a secretive Christian sect, under investigation by the FBI, say it is hiding wealth through trusts, blocking access to abuse compensation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53db6860c0bfae7962745fe7350af472</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Koji expected to make landfall within hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/cyclone-koji-north-queensland-coast-warnings-flood/106216534</link><description>Tropical Cyclone Koji is expected to make landfall within hours between Ayr and Mackay, according to the weather bureau.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb9b746ab0173635b582a95ac5c4a288</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave live updates: Bushfire disaster in Victoria as Australia braces for more heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/bushfires-victoria-nsw-heatwave-live-coverage/106217152</link><description>Authorities are continuing to battle out-of-control bushfires across Victoria, which have already claimed dozens of properties. Meanwhile, extreme heatwave warnings remain in place for NSW, ACT and WA. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acb9c066d8210639d9c8ba8dd9319e36</guid></item><item><title>From Madonna to Metallica, these are the big albums turning 40 this year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/1986-albums-turning-40/106186462</link><description>Pop and MTV ruled supreme but 1986 was also a banner year for hip hop and metal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05306a3fa6e1d11e44c9247761024678</guid></item><item><title>Endangered animal populations bounce back on Kangaroo Island thanks to predator-proof fence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/kangaroo-island-native-animal-populations-bounce-back/106209894</link><description>Five years after feral cats were removed from inside the Western River Refuge on Kangaroo Island, populations of endangered species have boomed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ed4f14a274779c62d099d330ae29b52</guid></item><item><title>Fr Oche singing Lord's Prayer in church</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/fr-oche-singing-lord-s-prayer-in-church/106211280</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89b5f0a8167a901d2053f0a42db401a5</guid></item><item><title>Fr Oche Matutina, performing with rock band Yellowbelly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/fr-oche-matutina-performing-with-rock-band/106211472</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d5009401fa73845313d13739dbf3b83</guid></item><item><title>Catholic priest swaps sermons for rock 'n' roll guitar solos in the Australian outback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/indonesian-catholic-priest-swaps-sermons-for-rock-n-roll/106096618</link><description>An Indonesian priest brings a deep love of rock 'n' roll to his pastoral care in western NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d84d083c89e34414fa2cbae127dec1a1</guid></item><item><title>NSW community bands hit hard as association misses out on vital government funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/nsw-community-bands-lose-government-funding/106196730</link><description>Wollongong’s collective of brass and wind bands have been putting on a show for locals for almost a century, but it is one of dozens of community bands across the state that faces an uncertain future due to a recent loss of funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fa89331aaf2258eff5338749a99d08e</guid></item><item><title>Six dead, including a child, in Mississippi shootings, suspect charged</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/mississippi-shootings-leave-family-members-dead/106217418</link><description>A man is charged with murder after six people from the same family were killed in a series of shootings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5309a00fa4dc86c4e9ba2845bddc11bf</guid></item><item><title>The bombs in Afghanistan have stopped but its people now live under Taliban decrees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/life-for-women-and-girls-under-taliban-rule/106115402</link><description>Four years after the Taliban's return to power, security is no longer the defining issue in Afghanistan. Instead, one of the world's worst humanitarian crises is exacerbated by a series of overlapping disasters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d47b8de2f390cfaa84ce90c8187ccef</guid></item><item><title>How the 'Barbie' and 'ski-slope' nose trend is sweeping social media</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/barbie-nose-trend-social-media/105967608</link><description>Tiny, sloped rhinoplasties are dominating pop culture. But some plastic surgery experts say "trend-associated" procedures like these are a concern.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99bd0ab51f30db7ff059bbc4ff82acc9</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Bree Walker claims World Cup monobob victory ahead of Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/world-cup-monobob-bree-walker-australia-wins-gold/106217414</link><description>With the Winter Olympics on the horizon, Bree Walker proves she is among the medal favourites in the monobob with a World Cup victory in Switzerland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84e8862d0672515637f26584a6b46c59</guid></item></channel></rss>