<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 07:48:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Japan wants to hire more bear hunters after record number of people attacked</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/japan-hires-bear-hunters-after-record-number-of-attacks/105960706</link><description>In the past six months, there have been four times the number of people killed by bears compared with last year, and the Japanese government wants to hire hunters to help cull the animals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b94b0d493eff834ff8f63809da300887</guid></item><item><title>Monkey escape in Mississippi gives a glimpse into the secretive world of animal research</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/monkey-search-us-animal-research-questions/105960876</link><description>A truck carrying 21 research monkeys overturned in Mississippi, spilling wooden crates labelled "live monkeys" into the tall grass near the highway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">837b49eea6678d18176e391ed60579b7</guid></item><item><title>Australia criticises 'lost opportunity' for strengthened Antarctic conservation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/antarctic-conservation-krill-fishing-ccamlr/105958414</link><description>The Australian government says it's "disappointed" after an international conservation meeting in Hobart failed to reach agreement on improved protection measures in Antarctica.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b8e997fb574570c44cb438a1c4ea1b6</guid></item><item><title>NSW mental health nurse disqualified after intimate relationship with patient</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/mental-health-nurse-disqualified-intimate-patient-relationship/105960708</link><description>The NSW Civil and Administrative Tribunal has found a mental health nurse guilty of professional misconduct after she was observed hugging and kissing a patient.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24944a801043e0de150b7f3c3a619f28</guid></item><item><title>Eagles to make historic AFLW finals appearance after Swans fall to Bombers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/aflw-power-giants-tigers-suns-swans-bombers-cats-demons/105961268</link><description>Daisy Pearce's West Coast Eagles have reached the AFLW finals for the first time after the Sydney Swans blew their chance in a shock three-point loss to struggling Essendon at Coffs Harbour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8352fdea61b61a74d7d71d411279529b</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after woman's body found in home near Cessnock</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/police-make-arrest-after-womans-death-cessnnock/105960920</link><description>Police have charged a man in connection with the violent death of a 39-year-old woman in a home near Cessnock.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da28036e83cf08345f69ac738cde7e04</guid></item><item><title>Police charge teen after officers allegedly assaulted at Byford Halloween party</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/two-arrested-over-police-assault-at-byford-halloween-party/105961178</link><description>Two police officers were allegedly assaulted while shutting down an out-of-control Halloween party attended by hundreds of people in Perth's southern suburbs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97de9b08824a32ec2c7df8196e8c47af</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Cup 2025 field, horses, form guide and finishing order</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/melbourne-cup-2025-field-horses-form-guide-and-betting/105895400</link><description>Jamie Melham has landed a famous victory aboard Half Yours at Flemington, becoming the first female jockey to win both the Caulfield Cup and Melbourne Cup. Here is the complete finishing order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5c14042d610687b63933e018c602f35</guid></item><item><title>Tanzanian president Samia Suluhu Hassan wins disputed election with more than 97pc of vote, results show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/samia-suluhu-hassan-tanzania-election-results-disputed-win/105961496</link><description>The result is likely to amplify the concerns of critics, opposition groups and others who said the election was not a contest but a coronation, after the president's two main rivals were barred or prevented from running.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f882ddb778d8b55165f699bcfb9ca3f7</guid></item><item><title>Three players sin-binned as Australia win torrid second Test 14-4 over England to retain Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/rugby-league-ashes-live-updates-australia-england-second-test/105961660</link><description>Australia have won a tough physical battle in Liverpool to claim the second Test against England and ensure they will retain the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00cefecb9b09081da42f3e08f2474f9e</guid></item><item><title>England power past Wallabies 25-7 at Twickenham as Matt Dawson slams Australians as being 'woeful'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/live-updates-england-vs-wallabies-rugby-union-international/105950672</link><description>The Wallabies are overpowered by a disciplined and ruthless England team, which wins its eighth-straight international to claim victory at Twickenham.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a65e895909c012bbf81dead627b70dc</guid></item><item><title>Two more people charged over Louvre heist in Paris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/louvre-heist-suspect-released-without-charge/105961712</link><description>The man and woman deny any involvement in the heist as investigations continue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b684b03bddb0c65cf3adf01f8e0f665d</guid></item><item><title>Share your experience with the housing market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/audience-callout-housing-experiences/105958352</link><description>What's your experience looking to buy your first home, or find an affordable, stable rental? We want to hear from you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d2af351a2853732a55f711d6a86bdde</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew is leaving Windsor Estate. Why wasn't he given another property on the grounds?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/prince-andrew-windsor-estate-who-lives-where/105961082</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten Windsor's eviction from his mansion in Windsor Castle is the latest part of a reshuffle of royals around the estate's grounds. Here's where everyone lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40999d5b8081f180d9837a54afab649e</guid></item><item><title>Australians are being priced out of the property market and first home buyers schemes might not be helping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/real-estate-property-market-first-home-buyers-schemes/105941822</link><description>A recent auction for a three-bedroom townhouse in Brisbane has captured just how much property prices have skyrocketed in recent years, highlighting the nation’s fast-growing housing affordability crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b516c705020e5d11eef2fa6ae1e76d3</guid></item><item><title>When is the RBA meeting next? When will interest rates go down?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/reserve-bank-australia-rba-meeing-interest-rates-october/105942272</link><description>Many people paying off mortgages were hoping for a cash rate cut, but recent inflation data means that is highly unlikely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f329c2691a88d508e7837d35f646745</guid></item><item><title>Labor takes fight to Greens in key seats over environment laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/labor-takes-fight-to-greens-on-environmental-laws/105959854</link><description>As it negotiates with the Greens and the Coalition over its proposed overhaul of environment laws, Labor is preparing a campaign accusing the minor party of obstructing its agenda.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e24fd6f4bdadc2cf53792201d360334c</guid></item><item><title>New York's underbelly is thriving — this FBI case pulled back the curtain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/new-york-mafia-families-caught-running-complex-gambling-ring/105958744</link><description>The New York mafia is alive and an "historic" FBI bust has shown that underworld crime is still kicking across the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">262122226118c0158e14d96cee51a5d0</guid></item><item><title>Talking about aged care in multicultural families can be hard but these tips may help</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/talking-about-aged-care-in-multicultural-families/105938294</link><description>Discussing aged care in culturally diverse families can be a sensitive subject. Here's how some approached the conversation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2ac3beed4221115a2488574253ef35c</guid></item><item><title>Horse racing replays edited to remove falls and deaths as industry grapples with social licence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/horse-racing-disappearing-video-replay-ethical-concerns/105812252</link><description>For years, the racing industry has been quietly removing falls and deaths from its replays. Now, industry insiders are speaking out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60509cf475521db2072628c3e8b45285</guid></item><item><title>A game for the ages: Nan and teen granddaughter line up together in country netball</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/newstead-netball-game-for-the-ages-nan-and-teen/105944908</link><description>A grandmother and granddaughter played for their regional Victorian netball team, turning a secret plan into a moment of country sport history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95920eb90f08d84fbc57ca7f8a5ec5ad</guid></item><item><title>Copper theft costing Queensland taxpayers millions of dollars every year, as rate of crime increases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/copper-theft-costing-queensland-millions-crime-rates-increase/105943088</link><description>Experts say cost of living pressures, and the ability to make money quickly, is behind a surge in copper thefts which are leaving highways and sporting fields in the dark.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0f0ec08f1204c4a7360840a2b521d86</guid></item><item><title>Do the Queensland government’s claims about the surgical waiting list stack up?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/queensland-goverment-claims-surgicial-wait-times/105958488</link><description>Queensland's government declared victory on elective surgery wait times but thousands of patients are waiting longer than recommended — and specialists warn the fix is short-term at best.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1addc634e85cc415f058a6f711c9770</guid></item><item><title>From death masks to selfies: The history of our love-affair with portraits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/history-of-the-portrait/105915764</link><description>Whether it's an ancient death mask found on an Egyptian sarcophagus or the selfie you have just cropped on your phone, we have been creating portraits for centuries. So why do we love them so much?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e709c70c97458c7783289aaa7bc0da4</guid></item><item><title>How taxidermists are 'honouring the life' of extraordinary creatures through art and science</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/inside-the-role-of-taxidermists-and-nsw-rules-around-taxidermy/105858594</link><description>From a taxidermied mynah bird perched on a teacup to a mammoth leatherback turtle, here are the "extraordinary creatures" these taxidermists are preserving.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0ffe9b37d678fe031e628d33e163a35</guid></item><item><title>House prices have been climbing for a generation. Undoing the damage could take even longer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/house-prices-climbing-for-generation/105954416</link><description>It's an inconvenient truth that a housing crisis that took a generation to create cannot be fixed easily. The damage will likely take another generation to undo, unless the solution comes at the expense of those who already own their homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">029813aa2a3bd32b3760400b372935b2</guid></item><item><title>Australian number one Maya Joint loses in Hong Kong Open semis, Kim Birrell through to Chennai final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/hong-kong-open-semifinals-maya-joint-kim-birrell/105962042</link><description>Australian number one Maya Joint falls short of reaching the Hong Kong Open final, but compatriot Kimberly Birrell wins through to the tournament decider in Chennai.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88b411666705cb40a6cf868fe350d23a</guid></item><item><title>Think you've got what it takes to top this quiz? It's time to play ... HARD!</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia-tom-gleeson/105938854</link><description>Let's get it straight: you'll probably do badly on this quiz, and I'll judge you. It's time to play … HARD!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">466367d1bfc6da25874b17e1169c00f1</guid></item><item><title>Pitch invader stands with Kangaroos during national anthems before Ashes Test against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/pitch-invader-stands-with-kangaroos-at-ashes-test/105962104</link><description>A man is arrested by police after he lined up next to Cameron Munster before the Kangaroos' victory over England in the second Ashes Test in England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">659b8535fd83d29f6d57607dbfa2d552</guid></item><item><title>Rock climbers' defiance grows over Mount Arapiles cultural site requests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/arapiles-dyurrite-rock-climbers-defy-parks-victoria-requests/105950420</link><description>Rock climbers are publicly urging others to ignore Parks Victoria's requests to avoid culturally significant routes at Mount Arapiles Dyurrite in western Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f94931f9679aa559cb31740079bcf6c6</guid></item><item><title>Kirsha Kaechele banned men from MONA's Ladies Lounge — and won</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/mona-kirsha-kaechele-artist-curator-ladies-lounge-court-tasmania/105950618</link><description>No men are allowed at Kirsha Kaechele's Ladies Lounge and the Supreme Court agrees. The artist, curator and "missus" of MONA's owner knows how to cross boundaries, but can she solve Tasmania's thorniest dispute?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9eb89d5990fedbf1ad146e5a325a75f4</guid></item><item><title>Sting linked to AN0M encrypted app which brought down criminals around the world enters new phase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/operation-ironside-an0m-arrests-messages-new-phase-explained/105950980</link><description>An international covert sting linked to the encrypted AN0M platform which brought down hundreds of alleged criminals and netted cash, drugs and weapons has reached a new phase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c81f46b90927df3ed2f640543f7ceadd</guid></item><item><title>UK train stabbing leaves 10 in hospital, nine with life-threatening injuries, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/multiple-people-stabbed-on-uk-train-two-arrested/105962212</link><description>British police declare a "major incident", with counter-terrorism officers investigating a mass stabbing attack on a London-bound train.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a06b26a629b9fb1767a6f889a22afab</guid></item><item><title>Women's crisis shelter waits years to sub-lease vacant NT building</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/nt-galiwinku-womens-space-waits-years-to-lease-vacant-building/105947400</link><description>An Aboriginal-led domestic violence support service is demanding answers over stalled progress in establishing a women's shelter in remote Northern Territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c5519c7e21bec78ba2608589fe13d55</guid></item><item><title>Jockey Ethan Brown makes rise from from near-fatal fall to Melbourne Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/fall-and-rise-of-alice-springs-jockey-ethan-brown-melbourne-cup/105959830</link><description>Two years after a near-fatal fall, 25-year-old Alice Springs-born jockey has had a bumper season with 32 wins. Now he is riding in the Melbourne Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">119e82e58075acf4c274d207a8b07167</guid></item><item><title>Calls for road map for disability employment providers after Bedford's troubles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/advocates-call-for-road-map-for-disability-employment-sector/105952760</link><description>Some in the disability employment sector say they are operating in an increasingly complex and changing environment, and that there is a need for a clear way forward for organisations supporting people with complex needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1c23b56d2930c0a42e75b55696ab779</guid></item><item><title>There was a large police presence after reports of stabbings on a train in Cambridgeshire.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/large-police-presence-after-reports-of-stabbings-on-uk-train/105962274</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23f5eefc621d4af1bbe941ed925aee86</guid></item><item><title>Coalition won't back environment reforms without changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/coalition-wont-back-environment-reforms-without-change/105962194</link><description>The Coalition says it cannot support major reforms to Australia's environment laws in their current reform, setting a bar as they enter deep negotiations with the federal government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2234622f8159395c0c50b31e8b6a5e92</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Island shrew declared extinct after decades without a sighting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/christmas-island-shrew-declared-extinct/105949448</link><description>A researcher says the long-suspected extinction of the mouse-sized mammal is "another stain" on Australia's environmental record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5881e83cdbfcb4b8a03bf21dcfcc021</guid></item><item><title>Did a former Perth bikie order the public assassination of his one-time gang leader?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/david-pye-nick-martin-assassination-supreme-court-murder-trial/105946084</link><description>With all the hallmarks of a Hollywood blockbuster, the high-profile murder trial of ex-bikie David Pye in WA's Supreme Court was never going to be a pedestrian affair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dbdcfef0061b6ca8b57bb1f0884bfe5</guid></item><item><title>Southern NSW summer rice and cotton crops shrink amid water shortages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/nsw-rice-and-cotton-plantings-slashed-amid-water-shortage/105899914</link><description>Southern NSW rice and cotton growers are heading into one of their smallest summer cropping seasons in years, with tight water allocations forcing many to halve their plantings or sit the season out altogether.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb84268cc4e631402cd4bcac564e8480</guid></item><item><title>Spotlight on youth justice after dozens arrested in WA's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/community-government-split-on-how-to-manage-youth-crime/105960744</link><description>The political spotlight has once again turned to preventing and managing youth crime in Western Australia, but decision-makers are split on how best to tackle the issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e66797b37f7b947c54d8cfd5aefe6249</guid></item><item><title>Veteran credits his local RSL with helping to pull him out of darkness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/regional-rsl-helps-veteran-during-time-of-darkness/105945666</link><description>A veteran in Victoria says he found hope and solace in his local RSL that "had his back" when he felt overwhelmed by his wife's early onset dementia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e62e59e10ad6400b36d4782f5d0997a</guid></item><item><title>High demand for ambulances in Melbourne and Geelong as weather warms up on Cup weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/vic-ambulance-victoria-high-demand-in-melbourne-and-geelong/105962168</link><description>Victorians are being urged to only call triple-0 for critical cases as demand for an ambulance soars on the quasi-Melbourne Cup long weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ccec54418d7485d71cf4d6c80c677ec</guid></item><item><title>Critically endangered shrub on NSW Northern Tablelands could have prosperous future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/endangered-plant-grows-only-on-nsw-northern-tablelands/105924048</link><description>There are signs a critically endangered plant that grows on a rural property near Armidale could have a prosperous future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65eed854defe58937336b9a998c6ad1a</guid></item><item><title>The tensions inherent in Australia's housing crisis laid bare at Perth gallery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/need-for-housing-inspires-artist/105939626</link><description>In an exhibition exploring the fraught issue of finding a home, artist Alana Hunt is directly inviting owners of multiple properties to solve her own, personal housing crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1ede08335cf42653d92cae8ec5a73da</guid></item><item><title>Koalas found at Avonside in the NSW Snowy Mountains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/koalas-found-in-nsw-snowy-mountains/105951296</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fa344b8bed5c5e2a2839eba39c799c2</guid></item><item><title>Drones spot hidden koala population in NSW Snowy Mountains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/drones-spot-hidden-koala-population-in-nsw-snowy-mountains/105938022</link><description>A hidden group of koalas is found for the first time in a remote area of the New South Wales Snowy Mountains.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75fc1668ffcc40181a0b318a70f9f929</guid></item><item><title>Nationals formally abandon commitment to reach net zero emissions by 2050</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/nationals-formally-abandon-net-zero-by-2050/105962162</link><description>The Nationals have formally abandoned a commitment to reach net zero emissions by 2050, setting a challenge for Opposition leader Sussan Ley whether to follow or risk splitting the Coalition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46eb3da651430f25d065e42b19a4b4ec</guid></item><item><title>Female jockey Jamie Melham discusses riding Melbourne Cup favourite Half Yours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/jamie-melham-half-yours-melbourne-cup-2025/105962620</link><description>Jockey Jamie Melham says she will be doing a "rain dance" on Monday, ahead of riding Melbourne Cup favourite Half Yours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c470aa33d7806c624d07e1920957cc8</guid></item><item><title>Three generations tackle 12th annual Variety Postie Bike Dash at Nabiac</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/family-gathers-for-charity-postie-bike-dash/105951144</link><description>Brian leads three generations of his family in the annual Variety Postie Bike Dash, raising money for sick and disadvantaged kids.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4db43038f1692bc5604a07fbdae21032</guid></item><item><title>Christopher James McLoughney refused bail over alleged murder of Rhukaya Lake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/court-hearing-for-man-accused-of-murder-of-rhukaya-lake/105962286</link><description>A man charged with the domestic violence murder of 39-year-old Hunter woman Rhukaya Lake is remanded in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e02a89e9350dc3c1d31c5a2c1ded6326</guid></item><item><title>Police stop train at Huntingdon Station after mass stabbing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/police-stop-train-at-huntingdon-station-after-mass-stabbing/105962658</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fe2514f2e3fe196c8c30a4c2f2604f6</guid></item><item><title>AFLW round 12: Crows hold on to eliminate Dockers from finals contention, Lions finish third after beating Magpies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/aflw-round-12-collingwood-lions-st-kilda-bulldogs-crows-dockers/105962532</link><description>Adelaide has hung on for a thrilling 12-point win over Fremantle that secures its AFLW finals spot and ends the Dockers' season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e10849f6e5a398d9f4c6195ad557c31</guid></item><item><title>Easy low-alcohol cocktails and non-alcoholic drinks for summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/low-alcohol-cocktails-and-non-alcoholic-drinks-mocktails/105763344</link><description>Having a range of drinks on offer can help everyone feel included, especially at end-of-year gatherings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf0b38dd980309d44e125e1fc03ddb6b</guid></item><item><title>Eliesa Katoa fitted with oxygen mask during Tonga vs New Zealand Test match, Jillaroos defeat Kiwi Ferns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/australia-jillaroos-defeat-new-zealand-kiwi-ferns-10-4/105962804</link><description>Tongan forward Eliesa Katoa has been fitted with an oxygen mask during the Pacific Championship Test match against New Zealand, after copping multiple blows to the head.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c73a30eb3d2eb448a458821f369b445</guid></item><item><title>Inmate taken to hospital after alleged assault at SA's Yatala Labour Prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/inmate-taken-to-hospital-after-alleged-prison-assault/105962732</link><description>A prisoner was taken to the hospital after the second alleged violent assault in two weeks in the South Australian prison system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2f67da22d83a326dc19f70b0a9d48bf</guid></item><item><title>Australia's scandal-ridden childcare sector is a legacy of the 'golden age' of reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/australia-childcare-sector-scandal-golden-age-of-reform/105952006</link><description>The decision by past governments to push Australia's childcare industry in the direction of marketisation and corporatisation has left a lasting legacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1d56cc77ce2fe08cd4f6170ffaaaeeb</guid></item><item><title>India levels T20 series against Australia with impressive run chase in Hobart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/cricket-australia-india-third-t20i-hobart-live-scorecentre/105962480</link><description>India levels the Twenty20 series against Australia, sharing the blows with the bat for a five wicket win with nine balls to spare in Hobart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bd43953a9d2e34ceba1672873e920ea</guid></item><item><title>India defeats South Africa by 52 runs to claim maiden Women's ODI Cricket World Cup title</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/india-vs-south-africa-odi-world-cup-final-live-blog/105962972</link><description>All-round performances from Deepti Sharma and Shafali Verma have led India to a breakthrough World Cup triumph against South Africa in Navi Mumbai.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">491dce6762cbeeff4645783266a86c2c</guid></item><item><title>'Nothing to suggest' stabbing attack on train was a terrorist incident, UK police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/nothing-to-suggest-terrorist-attack-on-train-say-uk-police-/105963010</link><description>Police investigating a mass stabbing on a train bound for London on Saturday say there is nothing to suggest it was a terrorist attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9ecfd2362c9a76384f5e506470829e9</guid></item><item><title>Investors and first home buyers flock to property market, driving up prices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/investors-versus-first-home-buyers-flock-back-to-property-market/105943356</link><description>Australia's property market is seeing rising demand, with record auctions over spring and a rise in both first home buyers and investors pushing up house prices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0dc7ecf241d905d6c06b9d0a12ff2f49</guid></item><item><title>Calls for football clubs to divest from pokies with more than $110 million lost to machines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/afl-football-pokies-machines-gambling/105953142</link><description>There are calls for football teams to distance themselves from poker machines after data found more than $110 million was lost at venues owned by football clubs and leagues in the last financial year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdb126202dde835a7f847688b62cc9df</guid></item><item><title>Australia supplying China with critical mineral vital for hypersonic missiles and its nuclear program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/china-critical-mineral-nuclear-program-australia-supplying/105951072</link><description>Australia is supplying raw materials vital for China's military build-up, while at the same time signing up to be a partner of choice for the United States as it seeks to break Beijing's critical minerals stranglehold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e933fd3fd9f2a350a634f3b2db3b3986</guid></item><item><title>House prices are accelerating again and the housing crisis is back on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/house-prices-increase-again-mortgages-rba-interest-rate-decision/105962246</link><description>The nation has not yet embraced the idea that housing needs to be more affordable, or that it's the most important economic and social issue facing the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ba30d1a79581e1d53d207dd55298d74</guid></item><item><title>Prepaid electricity consumers sweltering under regular disconnections, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/first-nations-right-to-power/105941906</link><description>Communities on prepaid power meters face regular disconnections amid 40 degree-plus heat, meaning no aircon, food rotting in the fridge and long, hot walks to get reconnected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ef435fba593c2156d567a3d871dd4a3</guid></item><item><title>The Nationals dumping net zero is dangerous territory for the Coalition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/net-zero-nationals-coalition-climate-change/105962434</link><description>To borrow the words of former prime minister Tony Abbott, the net zero emissions by 2050 policy for the Coalition is now dead, buried and cremated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b330051db386938f13b08c23ad661075</guid></item><item><title>From England to Flemington — 20 years on from Makybe Diva's third Melbourne Cup victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/makybe-divas-third-melbourne-cup-20-years-on/105713334</link><description>From quiet beginnings, an unknown English filly came Down Under and changed Australia's racing history by achieving the impossible. This is how Makybe Diva won a historic third Melbourne Cup 20 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b00d87aee930c94249ed44e8122b286b</guid></item><item><title>Weightlifting empowers women of all ages to stop feeling 'invisible'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/women-weightlifting-no-longer-invisible-empowering-women-all-age/105945008</link><description>Teenager Mira Mohan, and Francee and Carolyn, both in their 60s, are changing the face of weightlifting, showing it is a sport for women at any stage of life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cf967ca9f315dc1aac5cb618c34b326</guid></item><item><title>Louvre heist suspects believed to be small-time criminals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/louvre-heist-suspects-believed-to-be-small-time-criminals/105963634</link><description>Four thieves raided the world's most-visited art museum last month, in broad daylight, taking just seven minutes to steal jewellery worth an estimated $150 million before fleeing on scooters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d7d21c2e3f32289b8a9be4f2f72931f</guid></item><item><title>ACT voluntary assisted dying scheme begins, allowing Canberrans to 'die with dignity'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/act-voluntary-assisted-dying-scheme-begins-die-with-dignity/105960688</link><description>From today Canberrans like Gail Ford will be able to apply for the ACT's new voluntary assisted dying scheme, which its advocates say gives dignity in death to applicants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cef55f218d79294ba609c758da3f26c9</guid></item><item><title>Granite Island's little penguin population climbs despite SA's algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/granite-island-penguin-population-climbs-despite-algal-threat/105920654</link><description>The small, fragile colony of surviving little penguins on South Australia's Granite Island records a "significant increase" in numbers amid the state's harmful algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92e580c7cc58e51567df7100b014ca56</guid></item><item><title>Former Prince Andrew set to be stripped of military rank by UK government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-to-be-stripped-of-uk-military-title/105963786</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten Windsor will be stripped of his last remaining military position as part of King Charles's decision to remove him from public life, according to the UK defence minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">186ca1d62c6cac740505a135890fa206</guid></item><item><title>Aftermath of mass stabbing on UK train</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/aftermath-of-mass-stabbing-on-uk-train/105963734</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8861ca23e346f8bceb631f4c77b0edc4</guid></item><item><title>Legal Services Board of Victoria warns lawyers about AI in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/legal-services-board-of-victoria-warns-lawyers-about-ai-in-court/105916628</link><description>The use of artificial intelligence to prepare court documents raises questions in the legal profession about its use and misuse in the industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11322fbec4ebb8c0fb7d75a1fd9addf2</guid></item><item><title>Funding health is one of the biggest challenges facing Tasmania, as Eric Abetz prepares to hand down his first budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/health-funding-budget-challenges-tasmania-eric-abetz/105962530</link><description>A peak health body is worried Tasmania's public health system won't receive enough support in Thursday's state budget to address ballooning demand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">023af7486079fa987a12ff634173e47c</guid></item><item><title>How hitchhiking 'suckerfish' reveal humpback whales' 'web of life'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/hitchhiking-suckerfish-reveal-humpback-whales-web-of-life/105950862</link><description>Suckerfish, the ocean's ultimate hitchhikers, cling to humpback whales for thousands of kilometres and reveal surprising insights into life on the whale highway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4897fceb3d1bc8314797d0f765a3d7b2</guid></item><item><title>Boy dies, man injured in mango farm quad bike crash south of Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/darwin-river-quad-bike-boy-11-death-mango-farm/105963960</link><description>An 11-year-old boy has died in a quad bike crash that also injured a 38-year-old man at a mango farm south of Darwin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8371782d854d497e54f01798c97d305</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Kimberly Birrell loses Chennai Open final but earns sportsmanship award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/tennis-kimberly-birrell-loses-chennai-open-final/105963952</link><description>Gold Coast tennis star Kimberly Birrell loses in the Chennai Open final but claims a sportsmanship award for touching moment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b050174d333d3fad08b33509268b994</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr and Ellie Carpenter score for Chelsea as manager praises impact of Matildas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/wsl-sam-kerr-scores-for-chelsea-as-ellie-carpenter-stars/105964142</link><description>Matildas Sam Kerr and Ellie Carpenter both score for Chelsea in an impressive performance from the Australian stars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b399797570ec89c343ac07e8138e3b3b</guid></item><item><title>Maternal health forum reveals gaps in NT system, families choosing to move interstate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/our-birth-our-voice-maternal-health-forum-mother-maternity/105962312</link><description>Women who have had traumatic birth experiences at Royal Darwin Hospital have gathered to share their stories and call for urgent action from the territory and federal governments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0c7f28022601c339568e89af3235be4</guid></item><item><title>Rescues on Bluff Knoll increase fourfold in one year as visitor numbers rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/bluff-knoll-hiker-rescues-increase-stirling-range/105957436</link><description>About 50,000 people climb Bluff Knoll in WA's Stirling Range each year, and emergency services say they are being called to more rescues as hikers underestimate the challenging track.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32734c6f058d18bc10fa2dc7af9d7dda</guid></item><item><title>South Hedland worker accommodation heads to final stage of approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/south-hedland-worker-accommodation-heads-to-final-stage-approval/105943730</link><description>A $500 million accommodation plan in the Pilbara gets the green light from the regional Development Assessment Panel and will now go to the Town of Port Hedland for approval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f54d9ff16fc59657cab9070178de7c28</guid></item><item><title>What time is the Melbourne Cup? How to watch and the weather forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/melbourne-cup-time-how-to-watch-weather-forecast/105964240</link><description>Rain in Melbourne is set to play a factor in Australia's most famous horse race, with Flemington Racecourse predicted to be rated a Soft 7 or Heavy 8 for Tuesday's Melbourne Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cae8d149b2d1975610eeb0ced6093cde</guid></item><item><title>NRL and RLPA to investigate Eli Katoa handling after Tonga star suffered 'seizure activity' during New Zealand Test match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/eli-katoa-undergoes-surgery-after-head-knocks/105964618</link><description>The Storm say Eli Katoa had surgery after suffering "seizure activity" following multiple head knocks in the Tonga and New Zealand clash, and the league and players' association are set to investigate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e73e2e6676e0caeba54a4615e22b408a</guid></item><item><title>Father of Molly Ticehurst frustrated by court delays in murder case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/daniel-billings-molly-ticehurst-court-delays/105074740</link><description>The father of murdered childcare worker Molly Ticehurst breaks down while expressing his frustration at the delays in the case against her alleged killer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d85f678d019d66080538c67931898225</guid></item><item><title>Mental health reform needed to stop children ending up in prison, doctors say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/experts-raise-alarm-over-nt-prison-mental-health-crisis/105964576</link><description>As incarceration rates continue to soar in the Northern Territory, experts say mental health reform in the justice system is crucial for improving community safety in the long term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c0cf2e9fb892f39645d934494cf0e9</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne hoping for chance to face undefeated North Melbourne in AFLW finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/melbourne-want-to-play-north-melbourne-aflw-2025-finals/105963086</link><description>North Melbourne may be undefeated for the second home and away season in a row, but a star Melbourne player says the short AFLW season means they haven't proven themselves against everyone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">593daee658710b712d3b31a8d7333c87</guid></item><item><title>Dark Mofo sees drop in interstate visitors despite return of full program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/dark-mofo-announces-2026-dates-interstate-visitor-numbers-drop/105964376</link><description>Tasmania's provocative midwinter festival Dark Mofo will return in 2026, as this year's festival reports fewer interstate visitors as "budgets are tightening" across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7592eeb31970369291e1fd1d07958fa</guid></item><item><title>Bathurst childcare worker sentenced over head injury to four-year-old</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/bathurst-childcare-worker-sentencing/105956356</link><description>The Bathurst childcare worker is said to have used "considerable force" on the child, resulting in his head needing medical adhesive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">881b637a3380f570bc2a0ebc764e3c1e</guid></item><item><title>Optus held 11 crisis meetings before telling government about triple-0 deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/stephen-rue-optus-senate-inquiry/105963860</link><description>A Senate grilling of Optus executives reveals the company sat on information about deaths resulting from its triple-0 outage for nearly a day before telling the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b21e83b6151f06a528993bfaa56fb5a</guid></item><item><title>Review of mass salmon mortalities in Tasmania points to litany of failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/tasmanian-government-salmon-mortality-report/105964772</link><description>The state's environment watchdog has released a debrief of lessons and reflections from a mass salmon mortality event in which dead fish washed up on Tasmanian beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9ca2922a14f04ffa535ac0a9c93a414</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs lashed by 'fierce' storm and wild wind, cutting power</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/fierce-storm-moves-lashes-central-australia/105964766</link><description>A severe thunderstorm brought down trees and cut power for several hours in Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">489e7a71a7046213a075a3ca36697ba7</guid></item><item><title>Alleged manslaughter victim resorted to eating from school bins, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/jenni-gaye-wilmott-criminal-neglect-manslaughter-trial/105964930</link><description>A girl who died, allegedly as a result of criminal neglect by her mother, had resorted to eating food out of bins at her school, a court has heard. Warning: This story includes references to child abuse and self-harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bbef5bcd61372c610efe3388118962d</guid></item><item><title>Jennifer Mui Len Chin avoids jail after stabbing daughter's boyfriend in her home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/jennifer-mui-len-chin-sentenced-for-stabbing-daughter-boyfriend/105729024</link><description>A Perth mother who stabbed her daughter's teenage boyfriend when she found him semi-naked in the family home avoids a prison sentence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">063cff8edce9a9e7ff9e75fd7461ce4f</guid></item><item><title>Brief of evidence in Pheobe Bishop murder case reissued due to server crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/pheobe-bishop-murder-accused-case-delayed-due-to-server-crash/105965760</link><description>Thousands of pages of evidence had to be reissued to defence team after it was lost in server crash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a663bff41ea244b253ec402335426338</guid></item><item><title>Your rights when it comes to breastfeeding and expressing at work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/your-rights-when-it-comes-to-breastfeeding-at-work/105885406</link><description>There are many ways to combine breastfeeding and paid work, for example expressing milk, breastfeeding during breaks, or working from home. Knowing your rights can help you feel more confident when negotiating what that looks like.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9bc5be5b34fd60252cd240bea55393e</guid></item><item><title>Ash Barty urges Australians to be patient with tennis young guns Emerson Jones and Maya Joint</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/tennis-ash-barty-emerson-ones-maya-joint-patience-fans/105965970</link><description>Australia's last women's singles grand slam champ is encouraged by the new crop of kids coming through, but has urged fans to remain patient with their progress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5473442a6386a6e6963a8c2fdd24ada1</guid></item><item><title>Former SA opposition leader David Speirs shares ideas for algal bloom recovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/david-speirs-writes-document-about-algal-bloom-recovery/105964388</link><description>Former South Australian opposition leader David Speirs says he will make a decision about his political future in the coming weeks as he launches his own plans for the algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">152096256b48251dcf5b836c9f15dcc9</guid></item><item><title>Outspoken Mexican mayor known for anti-crime stance killed during Day of the Dead festivities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/carlos-alberto-manzo-rodriguez-killed-during-festivities/105965498</link><description>In recent months Mayor Carlos Alberto Manzo Rodríguez had publicly appealed to the Mexican president for help to combat cartel violence and organised crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71067bc9dcf0697e95fb21e2c73e17c8</guid></item><item><title>Mid North Coast blueberry farmer counts losses after severe storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/blueberry-farmer-counts-losses-after-severe-nsw-storm/105964770</link><description>Stephen Thandi says a storm tore through his northern New South Wales blueberry farm "like a freight train" at the weekend, causing at least at least $300,000 worth of damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bc95aea2afdbdba268996de3d3870d9</guid></item><item><title>Labor pledged to ban nuclear weapons in opposition. In government it got a reality check</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/labor-retreats-from-nuclear-weapons-ban-pledge-four-corners/105959312</link><description>Anthony Albanese and Richard Marles once pledged Labor would sign a treaty to ban nuclear weapons. Why have they walked this back in government?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7b97f5dfd33f372d2e20a376341948d</guid></item><item><title>US judge ends Justin Baldoni lawsuit against Blake Lively for missing court deadline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/justin-baldoni-loses-lawsuit-against-blake-lively/105964392</link><description>The actor's lawsuit against his co-star Blake Lively ends after he missed a court deadline on October 17 to file an amended complaint.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d67cfbc085cd2577ee4a2e2aab8e657</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast Mayor Tom Tate calls for urgent e-transport law changes after deaths of two children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/e-bikes-gold-coast-mayor-legislation-police-parents-safety/105965460</link><description>Following the deaths of a 15-year-old and an eight-year-old in the space of less than two days, Gold Coast Mayor Tom Tate calls for urgent change to Queensland laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08a8c9380f4da24917de076c43271ed4</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate Sydney developer's brother's alleged kidnapping, claim $1 million ransom paid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/nsw-george-ayoub-belfield-kidnapping-ransom-charlie-developer/105964220</link><description>George Ayoub was allegedly taken and shoved into the back of a car while he was walking outside his Belfield home about 5am on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aafe92c1f3295450c142351348b3509c</guid></item><item><title>Hinchinbrook by-election a 'test' for Queensland LNP government as writs issued</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/hinchinbrook-by-election-test-for-lnp-government-as-writs-issued/105964322</link><description>One year after sweeping to power, Queensland's LNP government will face voters at the Hinchinbrook by-election, with the poll seen as a test for the premier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffb39a2372f3dd7130e26a17dfd9fb82</guid></item><item><title>Gorden Tallis and Matthew Johns join Gold Coast Titans ownership group under Frizelle family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/rugby-league-nrl-gorden-tallis-matthew-johns-titans-owners/105966490</link><description>Former Broncos captain Gorden Tallis joins interstate rivals as a part-owner alongside former Knights playmaker Matthew Johns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7199394dfc05ad97a23f69927e5fbccb</guid></item><item><title>Liberals shifting towards dumping net zero, despite moderate faction fears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/liberals-shifting-towards-dumping-net-zero-2050/105966032</link><description>The centre of debate inside the Liberals appears to be shifting towards dumping net zero, as a tumultuous debate unfolds following the Nationals' decision to formally abandon the 2050 target.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b9fc63959d7c9500d200678644eb8a2</guid></item><item><title>Trial begins for man charged with murder over alleged hit and run at Browns Plains in Logan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/browns-plains-alleged-hit-and-run-murder-trial-begins/105966476</link><description>Umar Al Enizi is charged with the murder of Troy Vandenberg in September 2021. The jury heard both men were "total strangers" who had been involved in an altercation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54aed34dbd3e42cbf6fa00df287384bc</guid></item><item><title>Teenager avoids conviction over 'racist' attack on security guard at Bendigo Marketplace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/teen-avoids-conviction-over-bendigo-marketplace-attack/105965024</link><description>A teenager involved in the violent attack on a security guard that forced a country Victorian shopping centre into lockdown avoids jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5957c3cafab69872dcfc6853254978cd</guid></item><item><title>6.3 earthquake damages Afghanistan's historic Blue Mosque</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/6-3-earthquake-damages-afghanistan-s-historic-blue-mosque/105966886</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fb07bb376838203237c6e9cef3ee9f4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says UK royals suffered 'terrible thing' with pressure over Jeffrey Epstein scandal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/trump-says-uk-royals-suffered-with-pressure-over-epstein-scandal/105966134</link><description>Donald Trump says he felt badly for the British royal family after King Charles stripped his brother Andrew Mountbatten Windsor of his title as prince amid mounting pressure over his ties to convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d370207082665fc3845970254d9582a</guid></item><item><title>Suspected meteor spotted in afternoon sky across Victoria's Gippsland region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/suspected-meteor-gippsland-sonic-boom-afternoon-sky/105964144</link><description>Victorians living in the state's Gippsland region say they saw a streak of light whizzing through the Sunday afternoon sky and heard a sonic boom, with many wondering if they saw space junk or a meteor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e9bed216b9650f760b92074d851e252</guid></item><item><title>Chinese ship spies on Australia, Philippines and the US in South China Sea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/chinese-ship-spies-on-australia-philippines-us-naval-exercise/105966362</link><description>A sophisticated Chinese spy ship monitors Australian, Philippines, United States and New Zealand naval forces as they conduct another round of joint exercises in the South China Sea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f50ebe538b32fabcc174dd6fada42689</guid></item><item><title>Champion trainer Chris Waller compares Buckaroo to 2021 Melbourne Cup champ Verry Elleegant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/melbourne-cup-horse-racing-waller-buckaroo-verry-elleegant/105967072</link><description>Buckaroo might have failed to get the job done at last year's Melbourne Cup and this year's Cox Plate, but trainer Chris Waller believes its build-up is tracking perfectly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e79d53022f0334e75d77be11f8c0d915</guid></item><item><title>The key takeaways from Anthony Albanese's time at ASEAN and APEC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/anthony-albanese-apec-asean-summits-key-moments/105966626</link><description>While Australia's relationship with China has improved, there is still growing unease about Beijing's military power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b3fc8fafd7b0d2699a5af5b3187d993</guid></item><item><title>Monday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/monday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/105966924</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ad6cfc9cbdeeb8601d746ca1d77c3c2</guid></item><item><title>Angel Seafood halts oyster relocation amid protesters' algal bloom fears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/angel-seafood-halts-oyster-relocation-after-blockade-algal-bloom/105966998</link><description>A blockade at a boat ramp to prevent oysters from entering an open fishing bay, over fears of spreading the algal bloom, leads to the destruction of nearly $70,000 worth of oysters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">312ff1f17c13dc66e91576d81bf0bbca</guid></item><item><title>O'Neil welcomes housing progress despite price surge, while Bragg says no to 'NIMBYs'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/oneil-welcomes-housing-progress-liberal-vows-to-ditch-nimby/105967310</link><description>As the government comes under pressure for rising house prices in the first month of its expanded home deposit guarantee, Clare O'Neil welcomes signs of progress on supply.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d615c45d8cbcf9247facb7fb761d60f1</guid></item><item><title>Erin Patterson lodges appeal request in attempt to fight mushroom murder convictions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/erin-patterson-mushroom-murder-appeal/105964152</link><description>The triple-murderer lodges documents in Victoria's Court of Appeal requesting an appeal against her convictions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bae0972bcb7f8344aef07b88621b35c3</guid></item><item><title>Suspected meteor lights up Gippsland afternoon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/suspected-meteor-lights-up-gippsland-afternoon-/105967540</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4750d5c5b5812e12c639053b39fa1700</guid></item><item><title>Sale of WA's Yeeda Pastoral Company near Broome completed, NT abattoir tipped to reopen in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/kimberley-yeeda-pastoral-company-sells-nt-abattoir-may-reopen/105966118</link><description>The sale of Yeeda Pastoral Company, including the Kimberley Meat Company, to TLP4 Australian Holdings is now complete.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a69121df3b6fe37235154873f254a5f</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man avoids jail sentence over part in violent home invasion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/act-canberra-man-avoids-jail-sentence-over-violent-home-invasion/105966702</link><description>Xiantao Shang went to an apartment seeking a woman who owed him money. When told she was not there, he and an accomplice forced their way in and assaulted the couple inside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7512d8ad9e3641601dd71f1628c2ea2d</guid></item><item><title>Students with disability isolated, unsupported in ACT public schools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/act-students-disability-isolated-unsupported-public-schools/105967090</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">066a3e3391a8532274683bb8634d750f</guid></item><item><title>UK train stabbing suspect also charged over incident at London Tube station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/uk-police-charge-train-stabbing-suspect/105967688</link><description>Police are investigating possible links between a man accused of a mass stabbing on an English train and a series of other incidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc5e2ce2990bdfc1fec9afb2bb8ce6e6</guid></item><item><title>Corrections officers placed spit hood on Wayne Hunt, stripped him naked after seizure, coroner hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/wayne-hunt-inquest-darwin-correctional-centre-death-seizure/105964646</link><description>A 56-year-old man was stripped naked, handcuffed and made to wear a spit hood after suffering a seizure inside prison, a coronial inquest into his death has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfbe155202a32163de63ee8ef7180e19</guid></item><item><title>Man who shot poodle in Central Coast caravan park robbery sentenced to eight years in prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/man-who-shot-poodle-during-robbery-sentenced-8-years-jail/105951672</link><description>A man who shot a dog in the face during a robbery on the Central Coast of New South Wales has been sentenced to eight years in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6d5c661df1e9fa1fd08a0c0a69f1702</guid></item><item><title>Australians to get three hours of free electricity every day under solar scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/energy-retailers-offer-free-power-three-hours-dmo/105965472</link><description>Saying there is enough solar power for everyone in the daytime, the federal government will direct retailers to provide three hours of free power every day to consumers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c85ae2b376f2fb89ba6bcad50685ee59</guid></item><item><title>Papua New Guinea conjoined twins should not be separated due to risk of death, hospital says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/hospital-updates-on-png-conjoined-twin-boys-/105967644</link><description>Conjoined twins are extraordinarily rare, accounting for fewer than every two in 100,000 births.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1c1ad8df2bfb45a76ee9dd9be681d6e</guid></item><item><title>'Just started erupting': Medieval tower near Colosseum in Rome collapses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/rome-tower-collapse/105967918</link><description>One worker has been critically injured and another was trapped for hours after the tower collapsed while undergoing renovations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d480989d5e661abb86f26beeab6af099</guid></item><item><title>France threatens to ban Shein if it resumes selling 'childlike' sex dolls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/france-threatens-to-ban-shein/105967908</link><description>France has threatened to ban Shein from accessing the country's market if the Chinese retailer ever resumed selling the dolls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e5c65a6b4be50169cd4ac26577461f4</guid></item><item><title>ICC warns atrocities by paramilitary group in Sudan may constitute war crimes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/icc-says-rsf-atrocities-in-sudan-may-constitute-war-crimes/105967920</link><description>Reports from the Sudanese city of El-Fasher of mass killings, rapes and other violence "may constitute war crimes and crimes against humanity", the International Criminal Court has warned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64691f8a0a3b064a80d5ffe7b421c28c</guid></item><item><title>'Good neighbours': China and Russia talk up trade and security ties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/china-talks-up-russia-pact/105968282</link><description>As Russian Prime Minister Mikhail Mishustin visits the country, Chinese Premier Li Qiang says the two countries "trust each other" and want to deepen their security and economic ties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1adeb7ee8400ad16b1673e7feea55270</guid></item><item><title>New environment laws could help or harm nature depending on the minister</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/new-environment-laws-could-help-or-hinder-nature/105963168</link><description>Ambiguous language in draft national environment laws means acting on scientific facts or not will come down to ministerial discretion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0cbae9dcf0cea368a4b70a16ecae783</guid></item><item><title>Housing supply lags behind demand in St Helens on Tasmania's east coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/east-coast-tasmania-housing-lagging-behind-demand/105964304</link><description>For some residents of Tasmania's east coast, it is either leave the region or risk being homeless as they grapple with a scarcity of long-term rentals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30812efe5a2ba88f57b4ddd9aaabfa90</guid></item><item><title>The Hobart stadium order has been tabled in parliament — here's what happens next</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/how-the-future-of-hobarts-stadium-will-be-decided/105965628</link><description>After years of talk, the process to decide the fate of the contentious $1.13 billion stadium at Macquarie Point is finally under way. Here's how it will all unfold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be1e48c1d4b77acc5158775f16bba4f8</guid></item><item><title>Wet, windy and cold as thousands flock to Flemington for the Melbourne Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/melbourne-cup-weather-fashion/105965732</link><description>The 165th running of the Melbourne Cup is set to be a soggy one, as rain drenches the city ahead of the race that stops a nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8cfd7d71c241c3d22b7b8dc0874393e</guid></item><item><title>Zohran Mamdani could be New York's next mayor. His path has been part Barack Obama, part Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/zohran-mamdani-path-to-new-york-mayors-office/105964234</link><description>Donald Trump has thrust the Democrats into the political wilderness but an uprising in the gritty streets of New York may be their future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34789b1586bd2ae6daa2e43cf220aae7</guid></item><item><title>How the arrest of an Israeli military lawyer has again shone light on shocking abuse of Palestinians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/israeli-military-lawyer-arrest-highlights-abuse-of-palestinians/105963704</link><description>Israel's top military lawyer is behind bars after leaking a video of shocking alleged abuse of a Palestinian man in a military jail. This is why the case has shaken politics and the military to the core.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ab6000e91e6db9b77356e98786585e7</guid></item><item><title>Climate change increasingly contributing to home insurance premium hikes, IAG warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/climate-change-plays-role-in-growing-home-insurance-iag-warns/105964560</link><description>A report from IAG and a scientific research centre finds escalating risk from severe weather events in south-east Queensland, New South Wales, and south-west Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc5a7b3e321500b2fbb76b021f6ed0c9</guid></item><item><title>Why Michele Bullock is relieved she is keeping rates on hold as markets continue to shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/why-michele-bullock-is-relieved-to-keep-rates-on-hold/105964738</link><description>Last week the RBA governor issued a blunt warning on the state of financial markets and as markets continue to shift from traditional valuation methods, plenty of cool heads are getting nervous.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9a61068ea39d826f7ec51ea2440d1a6</guid></item><item><title>Coalition to meet after Nationals lead charge to dump net zero</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/coalition-to-meet-after-nationals-lead-charge-to-dump-net-zero/105967106</link><description>The Coalition will gather this morning at a joint party room session as the issue of whether to keep or ditch its net zero commitment roils within the party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d6f3fc05b930ee9ac43289c33475ab2</guid></item><item><title>Mouse numbers on the rise, farmers told to be on alert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/mouse-numbers-on-the-rise-farmers-told-to-be-on-alert/105947934</link><description>The CSIRO is urging farmers to reduce opportunities for mice breeding this harvest season as the threat of a pest population boom looms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f996202fa6c43072b3d6d75cc3acde32</guid></item><item><title>Feral pigs devour 99 out of every 100 lambs on this Central West NSW farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/feral-pigs-eating-lambs/105835106</link><description>Neville Mattick says feral pigs are eating the lambs on his farm in the NSW Central West, with fewer than one in 100 surviving this season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f40a48ccdeac51885e04ccba65d4bce0</guid></item><item><title>The World Egg and Sperm Bank's proposed 'reward' scheme for IVF companies raises concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/the-world-egg-and-sperm-bank-proposed-ivf-reward-scheme/105966160</link><description>In an email seen by the ABC, a US-based egg bank told IVF clinics it was introducing its new "Client Success Reward Program in Australia".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cdc281283d90afe3e918cbb4234c0f6</guid></item><item><title>Damaged solar panels can be dangerous. Here's what to do if wild weather has impacted yours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/qld-solar-panel-damage-explainer-what-to-know/105966036</link><description>If solar panels at your property sustain hail damage, is there anything you can do to avoid further problems?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e30c58951f233f6cb855eabc5d5b8a84</guid></item><item><title>Inadequate funding, outdated class sizes among challenges for children with disability in ACT public schools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/challenges-for-children-with-disability-in-act-public-schools/105935316</link><description>Liam used to dread walking through the school gates. Now, he can't wait to learn — but it took leaving a system that made him feel ignored to get there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f465e029800c9f844ff4186493f69b0</guid></item><item><title>Sydney mum recounts 'panic' at discovering day care wrongly gave son to another person</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/mum-recounts-first-steps-bangor-gave-son-to-another-person/105961026</link><description>Sophie Tilley says she arrived at her son's child care to be told an "older man in shorts" had already collected him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">306a0a18fcf15f99d2fcee7d320efaba</guid></item><item><title>Dedicated radio station launched to help kids in custody get back on track</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/futures-radio-youth-justice-centre-giving-hope/105942784</link><description>A dedicated radio station launches at a Western Sydney juvenile justice facility, helping troubled teens share their stories and rewrite their futures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fbfe5924061846525fbf5312fdacf46</guid></item><item><title>RBA raises inflation forecasts but 'not hitting panic button just yet' — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/rba-asx-markets-business-live-news-interest-rates-4-nov/105966950</link><description>The Reserve Bank has left interest rates on hold at 3.6 per cent, as widely expected. The Australian share market finished lower. Here is a look back on how the trading day unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05336e776c01db56fd7432909e5f5c15</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Cup jockey Jamie Melham eyes off history on board Half Yours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/melbourne-cup-jockey-jamie-melham-half-yours-out-to-make-history/105968410</link><description>Star jockey Jamie Melham and her mount Half Yours will carry the weight of a nation as one of the Melbourne Cup favourites at a wet Flemington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d833c1ecf0db471280ee6eebfdd1ac40</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Sussan Ley accuses Labor of killing Christmas interest rate cut — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/federal-politics-live-blog-nov-4/105967096</link><description>The opposition leader accuses the government in Question Time of dashing any chances of an interest rate cut before Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55eee96426de1e6c54db5bac032b83e8</guid></item><item><title>Judge rejects plea deal for funeral home owners accused of dumping bodies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/us-funeral-home-owners-accused-of-dumping-bodies/105968376</link><description>A US judge rejects a plea deal granting shorter jail sentences to funeral home owners accused of stashing nearly 190 decaying bodies in a bug-infested building.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c52b1209f0a0e9629d92613a26454d</guid></item><item><title>Avalanche on Nepal's Yalung Ri mountain kills at least seven, officials say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/avalanche-on-nepal-mount-yalung-ri-kills-at-least-seven/105968456</link><description>An avalanche on Mount Yalung Ri has killed five foreign climbers, whose nationalities are yet to be confirmed, and two Nepali guides, while at least five others were injured at the mountain's base camp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9352b9d97460aa4b2cc3a6f1106e2658</guid></item><item><title>Stolen Generations survivors overlooked in aged care reform, advocates say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/aged-care-reforms-overlook-stolen-generations-elders/105966520</link><description>"Discriminatory" changes to means testing in aged care could leave Stolen Generations survivors having to pay high fees for basic everyday services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53ce69cebb8ca0c66941344be41502c6</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne enjoying best form in six years ahead of Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/ashes-cricket-marnus-labuschagne-australia-england-century/105968514</link><description>With the first men's Ashes Test starting in just over two weeks, Marnus Labuschagne reminds selectors of his ability with the bat after hitting another century for Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30ca1a99e99ce16e94904186272c0847</guid></item><item><title>Earthquake kills at least 20, damages Afghanistan's ancient Blue Mosque</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/afghanistan-earthquake-damages-blue-mosque/105968498</link><description>The centuries-old Blue Mosque site, one of Afghanistan's most revered religious landmarks, is a major gathering place during Islamic and cultural festivals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">051c17f7d467202c33a516952bcf249a</guid></item><item><title>Diane Ladd, three-time Oscar nominee, dies aged 89</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/diane-ladd-dies-aged-89-in-california/105968616</link><description>Diane Ladd, a three-time Academy Award nominee whose roles ranged from the brash waitress in Alice Doesn't Live Here Anymore to the protective mother in Wild at Heart, has died at 89.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85c73f3b8a392f6d186619f546226fc1</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Forrest's plan to alter sacred Ashburton River under fresh legal scrutiny</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/andrew-forrest-traditional-owners-in-sat-ashburton-river-plan/105966594</link><description>Mining billionaire Andrew Forrest's controversial plan to alter the natural river system on his large outback WA cattle station is under renewed legal scrutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">859de5c1125f5edc596b8a6f0861cdf3</guid></item><item><title>WA avocado growers eye record crop as export negotiations with China continue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/wa-avocado-growers-expect-record-crop-push-for-exports/105965972</link><description>WA growers say they are on track to "smash" the record season they enjoyed two years ago, but the volume of production means it is crucial to increase exports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8fa7a577913294e4b28aeffbd73b125</guid></item><item><title>Clean-up underway after stormy weather hits, 400 calls for help in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/nsw-weather-aftermath-storm-cell-sydney/105968348</link><description>A clean-up is underway after a fast-moving storm cell left a trail of destruction across parts of Sydney overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9758c83bccf35937a730c89b641b8fdf</guid></item><item><title>Liberals 'heading towards oblivion': Monique Ryan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/liberals-heading-towards-oblivion-monique-ryan/105968720</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9dd834fef7b90eb0a9a9f02fdc2def2</guid></item><item><title>Walking away from Paris Agreement would make Australia a 'pariah state': Bragg</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/walking-away-from-paris-agreement-would-make-australi/105968734</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32a9ce3926b53b411bdfda0f691603e4</guid></item><item><title>Thirteen arrested as pro-Palestinian protesters clash with police at defence expo in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/nsw-protesters-clash-with-police-at-sydney-defence-expo/105968392</link><description>Dozens of demonstrators from Palestine Action Group rallied outside the Sydney International Convention Centre on Tuesday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1415a4c84b6ddae08bc31a6338d99e8a</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Cup 2025: Half Yours wins, Jamie Melham becomes second female jockey to triumph</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/melbourne-cup-2025-live-updates-flemington/105965384</link><description>Jamie Melham has become the second female jockey to win the Melbourne Cup, riding Half Yours to a famous victory at Flemington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12d2aec921fc9fa95679da1e93ca5b8c</guid></item><item><title>China extends visa-free entry for 45 countries, including Australia, to end of 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/china-extends-visa-freee-policy-to-2026-australia-included/105968854</link><description>The extension, which is until the end of 2026, covers 32 European countries as well as Australia, New Zealand, Japan, South Korea and several nations in South America and the Gulf region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">374c0d903b43e0a657c68be58342bb67</guid></item><item><title>Darwin, Hobart and Canberra all set to have no queer bars or clubs by the end of 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/queer-spaces-disappearing-australian-nightlife/105958852</link><description>For the LGBTQIA+ community, queer pubs and clubs can be an oasis. But in some capital cities they are vanishing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3c82764a87e572720db22b75bb4169d</guid></item><item><title>Severe storms lash south-east Queensland for third day running</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/storms-smash-south-east-qld-three-days-running/105968692</link><description>Severe storms have again rolled through southern Queensland, smashing parts of the state still recovering from weekend weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de67b2c9412eeaec85fdc81a0b8e6285</guid></item><item><title>Mock crime scene workshop aims to drive more youth interest in regional careers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/crime-scene-workshop-aims-drive-youth-interest-regional-careers/105952156</link><description>When former police detective turned educator Luke Taylor swapped his badge and gun for a classroom, he realised his crime-solving skills could apply to multiple career pathways.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">258e1789d7b4a6ac8ce0cbcf530ff1f4</guid></item><item><title>World's oldest Olympic gold medallist, Charles Coste, dies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/worlds-oldest-olympic-gold-medallist-charles-coste-dies/105969014</link><description>Charles Coste, who won Olympic gold in track cycling's team pursuit in London in 1948, left behind a sporting legacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2da5473464f4f11976c3a35ea3b07f0f</guid></item><item><title>Larissa Behrendt's Boyer Lecture argues justice and imagination are an investment in democracy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/larissa-behrendt-boyer-lecture-justice-democracy/105965580</link><description>I want to reflect on what I have come to see, through my own experience, as both the illuminating strengths and the shadowed weaknesses of the Australian legal system and its role in our democracy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc27e73207c5aaced764f41b4f120e22</guid></item><item><title>Eli Katoa's 'scary' NRL concussion draws condemnation from ex-player Shaun Johnson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/eli-katoa-shaun-johnson-reaction-scary-incident/105969198</link><description>Former NRL star Shaun Johnson has called for heads to roll after the "scary" incidents that saw Eliesa Katoa requiring oxygen pitchside after suffering three head knocks in Tonga's clash with New Zealand at Eden Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9ca895cf75164e6b99eec2a7e0cdc12</guid></item><item><title>Worker dies after being rescued from Italian medieval tower collapse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/worker-rescued-from-torre-dei-conti-in-rome-dies/105969444</link><description>A Romanian worker who was trapped for hours under rubble in Rome after the partial collapse of a 787-year-old medieval tower near the Colosseum has died, according to local media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdcb3896726eb98264d3daefbc970c5c</guid></item><item><title>Lone survivor of Air India crash tells UK media 'God took all my happiness'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/air-india-crash-survivor-speaks-to-uk-media/105969152</link><description>A passenger who walked from a Boeing 787-8 Dreamliner crash that killed his brother soon after take-off tells UK media of the mental and physical anguish he has endured since.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">873f350d2b1f538b339d78ed222c43cd</guid></item><item><title>Man dies, five people injured in Kununurra crash in remote WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/kununurra-crash-ivanhoe-victoria-highway-fatal/105968910</link><description>One driver is dead and the injured have been flown to Perth and Darwin after the fatal two-vehicle collision in WA's far north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b797525837c6d550075cf5e18fac453</guid></item><item><title>Mount Gambier woman charged over damage to city's Cast in Blue sculpture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/mount-gambier-blue-blob-googly-eyes-vandalism-charge-court/105964692</link><description>A 19-year-old woman appears in court via telephone accused of damaging Mount Gambier's Cast in Blue sculpture, which has drawn criticism for its cost and appearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75b2be6a928e56949cb39dd8e9136db8</guid></item><item><title>How dirty are public toilet seats?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/how-dirty-are-public-toilet-seats/105894996</link><description>Public toilets are a "microbial soup" and there are things you should be doing to protect yourself — including not taking out your mobile phone and never hovering over the seat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">872963b29783bf2f551ddef61ab797c2</guid></item><item><title>Brett Lee says England must play both Jofra Archer and Mark Wood in Perth to win the Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/cricket-brett-lee-archer-wood-selection-perth-ashes-test/105970054</link><description>England is urged to play both Jofra Archer and Mark Wood to begin the Ashes in Perth despite durability concerns with both quicks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7aacfb41dd54e3d710232781a603a19d</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police, WA Police and AFP charge 18 people in Strike Force Bloomfield drug bust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/nsw-and-wa-police-charge-18-people-as-part-of-major-drug-bust/105969768</link><description>Police charge 18 people in Perth and Sydney and seize 268 kilograms of illicit drugs following a multi-agency investigation into a national crime syndicate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8a93680e5ed3262899b3b094cb1054f</guid></item><item><title>RBA keeps rates on hold in November at 3.6pc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/rba-keeps-rates-steady-in-november-2025/105969614</link><description>The Reserve Bank has kept interest rates on hold at 3.6pc after hotter-than-expected inflation in the September quarter squashed hopes of a rate cut.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97ed90e4cedb9eed7629cabb0eb6e8e2</guid></item><item><title>BHP offloads 3,700 hectares of land at Mt Arthur coal mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/bhp-mount-arthur-offloads-3700-hectares/105968394</link><description>BHP will transfer 3,700 hectares of land at the Mt Arthur coal mine to a neighbouring mining company looking to expand its operations, raising questions about its promise to close the mine by 2030.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78cec06fe6eda70ab0b88d877b06c682</guid></item><item><title>RBA forecasts suggest more cost-of-living pain and risk of no more interest rate cuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/rba-interest-rates-statement-on-monetary-policy-analysis/105969494</link><description>Will 3.6 per cent be as low as the Reserve Bank's cash rate gets? A majority of economists now believe so.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a49ecbfed42d168ca6196d7a4b67cac</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Cup 2025 finishing order from first to last, Jamie Melham wins on Half Yours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/melbourne-cup-2025-finishing-order-from-first-to-last/105966644</link><description>Check out the full finishing order from the 2025 Melbourne Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66b6ffd4f5af1a17a2a436a1e9fc3a11</guid></item><item><title>Eighteen have been charged the Strike Force Bloomfield drug bust.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/eighteen-charged-in-strike-force-bloomfield-drug-bust/105970644</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe28fe63f17b911872d6041c37a70d0a</guid></item><item><title>Some Australian states are set to get a free electricity period every day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/solar-sharer-free-energy-three-hours-outlier-states/105968998</link><description>The federal government says its new Solar Sharer scheme will also benefit Australians who aren't able to access it, but some experts are hesitant to agree.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ed74aea8c7ca1a5ed89fd3d67d343fa</guid></item><item><title>Regional WA travellers fear airfare price rise as cap scheme details unclear</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/wa-regional-airfare-price-rise-fears-as-cap-scheme-unclear/105967146</link><description>Regional West Australian residents booking flights to Perth beyond June 30 next year face a $400 jump in airfares, as uncertainty clouds the future of the state's price cap scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ad7e40fb44663283bde46c4b10f05e4</guid></item><item><title>Half Yours wins $10 million Melbourne Cup at Flemington, beating Goodie Two Shoes and Middle Earth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/melbourne-cup-wrap-half-yours-wins-at-flemington/105969044</link><description>Half Yours wins the 165th edition of the Melbourne Cup at Flemington, with jockey Jamie Melham making history as the first female jockey to win both the Melbourne and Caulfield Cups.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4146c0a445122ebed8d609b3f62efabd</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley almost certain to face challenge next year, detractors say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/sussan-ley-almost-certain-to-be-challenged/105970786</link><description>While conservatives are waiting for the net zero issue to be resolved, those who support Andrew Hastie or Angus Taylor for the leadership say her leadership will likely be threatened after the summer break.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f28a7dd365e917dcf51154d1b2cbdd1d</guid></item><item><title>Sorry seems to be the hardest word for ACT Transport Minister Chris Steel after bungled MyWay+ rollout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/sorry-the-hardest-word-for-act-transport-minister-chris-steel/105969026</link><description>Five days after being censured in the ACT's Legislative Assembly for the bungled rollout of the territory's MyWay+ network, Transport Minister Chris Steel has issued a statement to "apologise to anyone impacted by the transition to the new service".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e37c545d0d688068102d25ea466764bd</guid></item><item><title>Interim vice-chancellor says ANU's financial position is improving, but they still need to be 'very careful'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/act-australian-national-university-financial-position-improving/105969384</link><description>The Australian National University's dire financial situation is "improving", and interim vice-chancellor Rebekah Brown says the university has now set a new target of delivering a surplus next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5c4bdd27542b53f2d17709aa2e1d528</guid></item><item><title>Hektoria Glacier reconnaissance flight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/hektoria-glacier-reconnaissance-flight/105969902</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a59b4f7f003d29b434300abbfa5859d7</guid></item><item><title>Timelapse of Hektoria Glacier from November 2021 to July 2025.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/timelapse-of-hektoria-glacier/105969802</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0a776c54a1dcc2593ccf7d8c6ffeb6c</guid></item><item><title>Hektoria Glacier in Antarctica shrinks at fastest rate recorded in modern history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/hektoria-glacier-antarctica-retreats-fastest-pace-recorded/105968782</link><description>Antarctic scientists have documented the fastest retreat of a glacier in modern history, after it lost eight kilometres of ice in just two months, according to a new report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d7a7558133afee244b380a294b75313</guid></item><item><title>Streaming services to be made to produce Australian content</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/streaming-services-to-be-made-to-produce-australian-content/105970910</link><description>The federal government puts laws requiring streaming services to produce Australian content back on the table after a hiatus following the US election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcc02221f7eedf3c50ecac05c253f945</guid></item><item><title>Multi-generational housing could be a solution to housing shortage, NSW inquiry hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/nsw-housing-crisis-rural-land-zoning-secondary-dwelling-reforms/105970220</link><description>Communal living was once common in regional Australia. Now an investigation is underway into whether it could help ease the housing crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bb1fb4a807d14b85440e9bfac0f885c</guid></item><item><title>Woman convicted of starving ballerina daughter denied bail ahead of appeal hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/ballerina-starvation-trial-mother-denied-bail-appeal/105971136</link><description>A Perth mother jailed for starving her only child to the point of severe malnutrition is denied bail after arguing she should be released because she had not been given a fair trial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ade1bcda1fbf909d0978e59c72c5258</guid></item><item><title>Mother had 'callous disregard' for deteriorating health of dying six-year-old daughter, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/crystal-hanley-criminal-neglect-daugther-charlie-death/105968420</link><description>A court has heard harrowing accounts from emergency services and the siblings of a young girl who died after her mother criminally neglected her. Warning: Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander readers are advised this article contains the first name and image of a person who has died. Readers are also advised this story contains content which may be distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62bd92f2d569de80172b7c7dcef2adb5</guid></item><item><title>Fugitives could be stripped of welfare payments, but critics say it denies 'natural justice'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/fears-fugitive-welfare-cut-off-will-capture-innocent-people/105971100</link><description>Fugitives wanted for some of the most serious crimes and sexual offences could soon be stripped of their welfare payments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad32719dd40599eb4ea863faadf6c79a</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Cup five quick hits: Melham magic, Blake Shinn falls, and concern over blood from Half Yours's mouth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/melbourne-cup-2025-five-quick-hits-fashion-injuries/105969686</link><description>History was made at the Melbourne Cup as Jamie Melham claimed victory, but there were serious concerns for hurts horses and an injured jockey, while the fashions took over Flemington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4816bd091795ed8e4ccba3c2a9b3f1f4</guid></item><item><title>Jillaroos boosted by return of Tamika Upton for Pacific Championships final against New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/rugby-league-jillaroos-tamika-upton-return-pacific-champs-final/105971642</link><description>Australia's hopes of claiming the Pacific Championships are handed a major boost with star fullback Tamika Upton ruled fit to play after recovering from a calf injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ce3694d85d94b2ec998942b37dc9e9a</guid></item></channel></rss>