<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:49:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dozens of shark heads dumped outside WA Fisheries minister's office as demersal fishing ban looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/shark-heads-dumped-outside-jackie-jarvis-office-fisheries/106184674</link><description>Hundreds of kilograms of shark heads have been left dumped outside the WA Fisheries minister's office in Margaret River, just three days before a permanent commercial demersal fishing ban comes into effect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52da2612172243bdd59c8424d34d39b0</guid></item><item><title>Remembering the celebrities and public figures who died in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/celebrities-public-figures-who-died-2025-obituaries/105869472</link><description>From actors and designers to a Holocaust survivor and a broadcaster, these people made their mark.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8ff6e8e6521b3764b05e9eb7af0051d</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 30: Beatles star George Harrison stabbed at home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/today-in-history-december-30-george-harrison-stabbed/106171844</link><description>Unlike his former bandmate John Lennon, George Harrison survived an attack by a fan, but the musician's friends and family speculated it hastened his death less than two years later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5de21d23cf56392fd7ed419a58dc08c2</guid></item><item><title>What happened when we tested a 'safe' AI mental health chatbot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/safe-mental-health-artificial-intelligence-chatgpt/106136202</link><description>Is it possible to make a "safe" AI therapy bot? We tested the limits of a new Australian-designed chatbot that's been carefully designed not to hallucinate or be your best friend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">845b6e5b1edf763fd5784d8b8777cd9e</guid></item><item><title>Household battery uptake booms on back of 'game-changer' rebate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/home-battery-uptake-soars-due-to-government-subsidy/106120730</link><description>Battery uptake is booming since the federal government rebate came into effect in July. Here's what you need to know if you are thinking of joining the thousands of Australians adding a battery to their home solar systems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30708c31c5d2c6ad77f5cc6b6d8e3c4c</guid></item><item><title>Josh Burns on juggling politics and fatherhood and being a Jewish MP</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/josh-burns-baby-federal-parliament-georgie-purcell-antisemitism/106162418</link><description>In a broad-ranging interview for the Politics Now podcast, the rising Labor star reveals he plans to take extended leave to care for his baby daughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79bb53732ced6ee8fa0288579b707fca</guid></item><item><title>Vision appears to show attempted carjacking in Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/vision-appears-to-show-attempted-carjacking-in-melbourne/106186022</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9049f7aaa79bd452778e836be32f0bee</guid></item><item><title>Police search for alleged carjacker who was fought off by bystanders in inner Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/vic-police-investigate-carjack-attempt-richmond/106185972</link><description>Police are looking for a man who allegedly tried to steal a woman's car in Richmond earlier this year but was foiled by bystanders, including one person wielding a golf club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26e5e8466580c32f89d01a9fa9f34ac5</guid></item><item><title>Transforming soft plastics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/transforming-soft-plastics/106185050</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6094f402939257049978e2d7b4f55c9d</guid></item><item><title>Soft plastics recycling is back in Australia. How does it work and where does it go?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/soft-plastics-recycling-is-back-in-australia-how-does-it-work-/105912070</link><description>Australia's first large-scale soft plastics recycling facility is processing huge loads each day, turning waste into a useful raw material.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d37c808f6bf403492a2a2b8dc150e76</guid></item><item><title>South-east Queensland's largest dam is 'full'. What does it mean?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/qld-how-wivenhoe-dam-works/106166620</link><description>South-east Queensland's largest water reservoir provides drinking water and protection from flooding. So, how does it all work?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f007ea1b086bd4b4b1ac973bbf0b4df</guid></item><item><title>Hiker Stella Thurbon leads herd of goats on trek through Victoria's High Country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/victorian-high-country-hiking-with-a-herd-of-goats/106119216</link><description>With bells tinkling, tails flicking, and panniers packed to the brim, adventurer Stella Thurbon has spent 26 days winding through the Victorian High Country with nine goats trotting faithfully behind her.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6002a583dc507156847c083070b68f08</guid></item><item><title>Noongar elders say WA prescribed burn went ahead despite warnings of cultural heritage sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/noongar-elders-say-sacred-site-warnings-were-ignored-before-burn/106086072</link><description>Elders on WA's south coast say they tried to warn the state government about unregistered cultural sites in the path of a prescribed burn, but the burn went ahead anyway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c864bc1e20cca2ab1cdd845af6e7a45e</guid></item><item><title>Flooding, heavy rain and damaging winds hit north Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/flooding-north-queensland-weather-rainfall-severe/106184268</link><description>North-west Queensland is on alert as flooding is expected to increase across northern parts of the state. The SES is sending additional crews to the outback amid flood rescues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ef3825a52aeb74cb98779082589dd97</guid></item><item><title>Victoria Police make more than 100 arrests, seize 30 weapons during first weeks of shopping centre operations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/vic-police-shopping-centre-arrests/106186088</link><description>A 15-year-old carrying a hunting knife was among more than 100 arrests during the first few weeks of a police operation at four of Melbourne's biggest shopping centres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eebe5b8532f4619245d8ae290a1bd689</guid></item><item><title>Charles Darwin University researchers leading the way in fight to protect globally threatened rays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/rapid-decline-rhino-ray-indonesia-northern-australia/106168084</link><description>Researchers from Charles Darwin University are leading the way in the fight to protect a group of globally threatened fish species, which look like "a shark and ray joined together".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d46b9b263f05e0812c8e68978b30e6a</guid></item><item><title>Deaf people saying no to cochlear implants choosing 'different way of seeing the world'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/cochlear-implants-debate-in-the-deaf-community/106044156</link><description>Cochlear implants can be a life-changing tool for people with hearing loss, but some Deaf people argue their use risks compromising their community's identity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c2c83166ba67cdac1d4df501e80252f</guid></item><item><title>Daria Kasatkina set for Brisbane International and Australian Open after mental health break</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/crowds-will-love-her-kasatkina-s-landmark-home-australian-open/106186126</link><description>Daria Kasatkina is being backed to return from her mental health break and quickly become a fan favourite at her new home grand slam, the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b501ed752fb06314d115d319194d988b</guid></item><item><title>The importance of preparing for death and creating an end-of-life health care plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/preparing-for-death-and-creating-an-end-of-life-health-care-plan/105886810</link><description>Dying in sudden, unexpected circumstances is not something people often consider, but there are plenty of reasons to create an end-of-life plan. So why do so few people have one?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5cd6645b8bb831142f96e95a26be9b7</guid></item><item><title>Small businesses struggle as tourists look elsewhere after WA fishing ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/recreational-fishing-ban-impacts-small-businesses-midwest-coast/106181870</link><description>Businesses on the midwest coast say they are already feeling the impact of new fishing restrictions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2242b7e416158e7f4c1b26410111c320</guid></item><item><title>NSW Parliament powerless to force witnesses to front inquiries after 19th-century laws struck down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/nsw-parliament-powerless-to-force-witnesses-to-front-inquiries/106185518</link><description>The president of the NSW Legislative Council says he will not try to overturn a decision to strike down laws that purportedly allowed witnesses to be arrested for failing to appear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6d3dc528483abdb73cf850c25e53967</guid></item><item><title>It's backed by Maggie Beer and researchers alike, so why don't we eat more offal?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/eating-offal-and-why-we-should-eat-more/106093422</link><description>Despite becoming less popular in recent years, advocates like Maggie Beer say offal can be a delicacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46c988bca4e62653baff9eaa39fa9cbb</guid></item><item><title>Record number of NSW Police officers to patrol New Year's Eve events after Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/nsw-police-increase-presence-at-new-years-eve-post-bondi-attack/106185980</link><description>More than 2,500 police officers will be out in force at New Year's Eve celebrations in Sydney in a bid to bolster revellers' confidence in the wake of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86ecb30515d3b6e2eea71ed64622d3aa</guid></item><item><title>China hasn't said it wants war in 2026. But it's showing the world it's ready for one</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/chinas-military-drills-around-taiwan-a-message-to-united-states/106186794</link><description>While Donald Trump was distracted, China launched its strongest-ever challenge against Taiwan. Beijing is showing it is ready for war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2396db44fea5a52c39bd09e3d8eb8a9c</guid></item><item><title>Ambulance Victoria reports increase in violence against paramedics over Christmas holiday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/violent-attacks-paramedics-christmas-period-ambulance-victoria/106186398</link><description>Ambulance Victoria says paramedics were assaulted, spat on and sexually harassed in a series of serious incidents over the festive period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6c96067a3fa4ada8769d73de5d41e88</guid></item><item><title>Shoppers spending billions on post-Christmas sales, but small retailers feel forgotten</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/spending-billions-post-christmas-sales-small-retailers-forgotten/106186838</link><description>Outlet centres around Australia were bustling on Boxing Day, but just down the road, some small retailers were feeling the sting. It's a trend that could shape the future of the Boxing Day sales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b88a27e6af003388ee98622e92bcc03e</guid></item><item><title>Nick Offerman hopes The Pout-Pout Fish delights tough child critics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/nick-offerman-hopes-the-pout-pout-fish-will-delight-children/106185350</link><description>This Australian animation stars an international and local voice cast led by Nick Offerman and Nina Oyama, who can't wait for children to see the film.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0020d02c138202fc048dfeb5e6b91b11</guid></item><item><title>Gold, silver and palladium prices pull back sharply, worrying some economists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/precious-metals-gold-silver-palladium-crash/106187288</link><description>The price of palladium — used in electronics — tumbles from recent highs while the prices of other precious metals, including gold and silver, have also sharply declined in recent days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09492488be8fcdcec44fb283fd56f0fb</guid></item><item><title>NT Environment Protection Authority orders Santos, Inpex licence conditions review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/nt-epa-santos-inpex-licence-review-emissions-error/106185488</link><description>The Northern Territory environment regulator will re-examine the licence conditions of major gas facilities in Darwin, after one of its biggest operators admitted to under-reporting potentially toxic emissions at its Ichthys LNG plant on Darwin Harbour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">366601fe83aede9fa18c4a99b62dc8eb</guid></item><item><title>Australian laws changed in six important ways in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/australian-laws-change-ubereats-pets-sovereign-citizens/106187302</link><description>From food delivery to sovereign citizens, Australia's laws underwent some important changes this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a18d0b9e12e643b0d2c323088a0972dd</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide public transport, stations and interchanges join list of declared public precincts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/adelaide-public-transport-join-list-of-declared-public-precincts/106187762</link><description>Police have been given expanded powers to search people for weapons on every public bus, train and tram in the Adelaide metropolitan area ahead of New Year Eve's celebrations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">152f1e795e6672267dd0734ad7fde0a8</guid></item><item><title>Australian people smuggling operation laid bare in NT Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/nt-darwin-chef-sentenced-over-people-smuggling-operation/106186976</link><description>A brazen example of people smuggling has been recounted in the Northern Territory Supreme Court, after three Chinese nationals made it into Darwin Harbour on a small wooden fishing boat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d6907e5b5546ba8dd42b51c5a50e4b6</guid></item><item><title>Here's what we know about the Coral Adventurer, the cruise ship that ran aground in PNG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/coral-adventurer-ran-aground-papua-new-guinea-explainer/106187276</link><description>The Coral Adventurer was carrying 80 tourists into the remote reaches of Papua New Guinea when it came to an abrupt halt on a reef off the Pacific nation's coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c0becda7da09f9389e9cdce6adf9424</guid></item><item><title>Bizzi Lavelle uncovers the hidden history of Blak burlesque in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/blak-burlesque-bizzi-body-lavelle/106148190</link><description>Bizzi Lavelle, a Queer Wakka Wakka and Arrernte writer and burlesque dancer known in the scene as Bizzi Body, is reclaiming the hidden legacy of this art-form one tassel twirl at a time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c77f27ecf9f0afac3611eda7ff1d27f</guid></item><item><title>Man in his 70s dies in floodwaters in Normanton in north-west Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/qld-flood-death-normanton-/106188576</link><description>Police were called to a vehicle submerged in floodwaters near Normanton where they found the man aged in his 70s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a0152c1b443946285be0b6d361c8392</guid></item><item><title>South Korea bans bear bile farming with jail for those who breach the law</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/south-korea-bans-bear-bile-farming/106188716</link><description>South Korea is one of the few countries that allow farming to extract bile from bears, for traditional medicine or food believed to promote vitality and stamina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0a7ab9247aa9d1b35313e29e81bf61f</guid></item><item><title>Christmas cruise ends in chaos as Coral Adventurer passengers return home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/christmas-cruise-png-passengers-return-coral-adventurer/106186660</link><description>About 80 passengers on the Coral Adventurer are flown home after the cruise ship ran aground on a reef off Papua New Guinea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a12b92f399d1d29cd366ffaec633591</guid></item><item><title>Kakadu traditional owner says nature has long warned us about rising sea levels</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/nt-kakadu-sea-level-rise-climate-change-saltwater-intrusion/105752820</link><description>In wet season, Jonathan and his family have to drive, boat and drive again if they want to reach town. The remote NT traditional owner says nature has long been warning us about climate change, "but nobody's listening".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c61221d7a7e419755ea7ae07c0f7c52c</guid></item><item><title>Crowd-funding business campaigns falter, despite demand for tipple</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/gluten-free-craft-beer-a-healthier-option-for-drinks-investors-/106175338</link><description>Brewer Richard Jeffares's Victorian company raised about $2.5 million from 993 investors in a matter of days through a method called crowd-sourced funding, also known as equity crowdfunding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77f4b9ad49108a481dfc9b7c3a62283e</guid></item><item><title>Sportsbet pressured key watchdog into 'watering down' enforcement announcement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/sportsbet-pressure-acma-enforcement-announcement/106137264</link><description>Gambling giant Sportsbet pressured the Australian Communications and Media Authority into "watering down" enforcement announcement, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e01de2479c7e314611904a13ca22f4dd</guid></item><item><title>Human-operated Tokyo robot venture allows housebound people to work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/tokyo-robot-tourism-business-cafe-housebound-workers/106177054</link><description>Ory Yoshifuji's Tokyo business employs housebound individuals to operate robots as waitstaff at a cafe and as personal tour guides in the city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee5510266f87235181771f4e5e3fa9b7</guid></item><item><title>What should you do during a violent mass attack?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/what-should-you-do-violent-mass-attack/106179978</link><description>The mass shooting in Bondi and other incidents of mass violence around the world have highlighted that violence can strike anywhere. Here are some expert tips on how to escape, hide, and stay safe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c0de6bec2b16cb24966fa699f71bc8d</guid></item><item><title>Denmark becomes first country in world to end letter delivery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/denmark-postal-service-ends-letter-delivery/106188988</link><description>After 401 years, the Danish postal service has ended letter deliveries as the country fully embraces the digital age.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">527b1a7416978fbdc459d389b139e4a2</guid></item><item><title>Robbers steal $52 million from vault of German savings bank</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/robbers-steal-cash-jewellery-from-vault-of-german-savings-bank/106189018</link><description>According to police, the robbers drilled their way into the underground vault room of the savings bank from a parking garage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7000310909990d0892876846e48a929c</guid></item><item><title>For many South Australians, 2025 could be summarised as the year of searching for answers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/sa-2025-year-in-review-and-search-for-answers/106124586</link><description>As 2025 draws to a close and we look back at the stories that made headlines, for South Australians the year could be summarised as one where we searched for answers, with little results.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b594d8b07c4ab5c74b725ddbde48dc15</guid></item><item><title>Mechanic shortage driving Queensland businesses to look overseas for qualified workers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/qld-mechanic-shortages/106146022</link><description>The automotive repair industry says it is dealing with a major labour and skills shortage, and some mechanics are looking overseas for workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">677120ce168a39db717bbf44351334a6</guid></item><item><title>ASX ends 'stressful' year with gold and lithium stocks surging despite Trump's trade war threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/asx-ends-stressful-year-with-gold-and-lithium-stocks-surging/106188730</link><description>Several gold, lithium and other mining stocks have seen their share price double, and even triple, in 2025 as Australia's share market has had a much better than expected year despite tariffs, economic uncertainty and Donald Trump's ongoing unpredictability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d40112e062ed5ea83214da84bcdd4bb8</guid></item><item><title>Tatiana Schlossberg, granddaughter of John F Kennedy, dies aged 35</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/jfk-granddaughter-tatiana-schlossberg-dies-aged-35/106189118</link><description>Tatiana Schlossberg revealed in an essay published in November that she had a rare form of terminal leukaemia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">176bba8f13d8b78546e3a13fb3b4b903</guid></item><item><title>Flocks of tourists dubbed the 'koala paparazzi' putting animals at risk in Byron Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/tourist-put-byron-bay-koalas-at-risk/106183054</link><description>Large crowds of tourists gather daily at the bottom of trees home to koalas in Byron Bay, leaving the animals stressed and their habitat trampled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb3d6a084b9bc480d26fa3ad7329d0bf</guid></item><item><title>Record year for Australian beef exports despite Donald Trump's tariffs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/record-year-for-aussie-beef-despite-trump-tariffs/106188120</link><description>When Donald Trump enforced a 10 per cent tariff on Australian beef, there were some concerns it would impact trade. But the opposite happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9906a7cbfa515375f6e8f5ee77ad5126</guid></item><item><title>Calls for tighter regulations after Woodside knowingly shed plastic into ocean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/woodside-knowingly-sheds-plastic-into-ocean/106184338</link><description>Documents reveal one of Australia's biggest oil and gas companies knowingly shed plastic into the ocean for two months before notifying the offshore regulator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62d064ab98b320241c481f7d14c044db</guid></item><item><title>Flooding claims a life as deluge cuts north-west Queensland roads, isolates towns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/major-flood-warnings-in-north-west-queensland-towns-isolated/106186966</link><description>Police have renewed warnings about driving in floodwaters after a tragedy in Queensland's Gulf Country as the region endures a fourth day of drenching rain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe978e32493bddcc48a21b19b4ff485e</guid></item><item><title>What are the new rules in 2026? Here's what's changing from New Year's Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/2026-new-rules-laws-regulations-come-into-effect/106186738</link><description>New Year's Day brings a host of new laws, regulations and guidelines into effect. Here's a quick breakdown of some of the changes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a403392408ee586524631c7c64585ec2</guid></item><item><title>AI technology gives swimming pool lifeguards an extra set of eyes this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/ai-system-to-help-lifeguards-in-pools-swim-safety/106172140</link><description>An AI system used in 120 public pools across Australia analyses swimmers' movements and sends an alert to a lifeguard's smartwatch if it detects someone in trouble.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4981359265166fe70bf2f7d449ec0d3b</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill gardeners chop down trees in battle with Queensland fruit fly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/fruit-fly-war-in-broken-hill/106179748</link><description>There was no fruit fly to be found in Broken Hill 20 years ago, but now gardeners are facing an uphill battle trying to rid themselves of the pest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce1af482ebd6c6b880eb979a75966489</guid></item><item><title>Calls for national strategy to tackle apprentice hazing and protect workers’ mental health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/tradie-apprentice-workplace-hazing-mental-health-advocates/106173610</link><description>TV presenter and former builder Barry Du Bois is lobbying Canberra for change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f8c43af3c57b7d491903a3ea007e37a</guid></item><item><title>Former Australian Test batsman Damien Martyn in an induced coma with meningitis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/former-australian-cricketer-damien-martyn-in-induced-coma/106189352</link><description>Former Australian Test and limited overs batsman Damien Martyn is in hospital in Queensland in an induced coma after falling ill this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">000eccb538931e74b5a025d77acd4b72</guid></item><item><title>Promise of bumper coffee crop in 2026 fuelled by explosion of white flowers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/australian-coffee-growers-hope-for-bumper-2026-crop/106177198</link><description>Australian coffee growers are hoping for a bumper 2026 season to meet increased demand for homegrown beans following a prolific flowering season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbc7154a6a59404143386fbf87463625</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Alex Hartley responds to criticism for talking about period on BBC commentary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/alex-hartley-period-chat-bbc-cricket-ashes-commentary/106189540</link><description>Alex Hartley says she was stunned by the reaction to her talking about her period during the BBC's radio commentary of the third Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da608c2e7fa4ac5a89d0568184e22de6</guid></item><item><title>'White Australia' flyer letterbox drop in Newcastle sparks police investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/racist-pamphlets-spark-police-investigation/106189416</link><description>NSW Premier Chris Minns said police would "throw the book" at anyone behind flyers distributed to inner-city Newcastle letterboxes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e058794461c7b877b4797f33d91d706</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos striker Martin Boyle in injury blow for Hibernian</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/socceroos-striker-martin-boyle-in-injury-blow-for-hibs/106190128</link><description>Martin Boyle, no stranger to the heartache of missing major tournaments with the Socceroos, was taken off after injuring his hamstring for Hibernian in the Scottish Premiership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">555f74d5c866789a8613eb2631799bd4</guid></item><item><title>Australia's top glassmakers are the focus of the exhibition Glass Chrysalis II</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/chrysalis-glassmaking-wagga-art-gallery-exhibition/105938918</link><description>The art of glassblowing was popularised in a recent reality TV series, but these Australian artists are forging their own paths in the creative process of sculpting this tricky medium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f5563b4d86d0813f53f80d3286c4f6f</guid></item><item><title>Sunshine Coast live music venue The Station to shut down as event bookings drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/sunshine-coast-live-music-venue-the-station-to-shut-down/106189286</link><description>The Sunshine Coast's largest live music venue is shutting down, with the owners stating that they need double the number of bookings to stay afloat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ea077bcc6921d955c042e0e909479a4</guid></item><item><title>Driver in hit and run that killed woman on Darwin's Bagot road remains at large</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/darwin-hit-and-run-nt-police-investigation-continues/106190254</link><description>The search for a hit-and-run driver who allegedly struck and killed a 27-year-old Indigenous woman on one of Darwin's busiest main roads continues into its fifth day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16412ac2271ea486d0598b6b384b161b</guid></item><item><title>Pet owner's warning as dogs fall ill after beach visit amid algal bloom crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/dogs-fall-ill-ater-visiting-adelaide-beach-algal-bloom/106189458</link><description>Within 20 minutes of leaving an Adelaide beach dogs Lucy and Ella began breathing rapidly and fell "terribly sick", prompting their owner to issue a warning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6cf99b006e293aeae1a112225b2e336</guid></item><item><title>Man drowns and boy missing after boat capsizes at Palm Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/man-drowns-at-palm-beach-sydney-new-years-eve/106190220</link><description>Police confirmed one man has drowned and a 14-year-old boy is missing after their boat capsized at Palm Beach on Sydney's Northern Beaches, with a search and rescue helicopter continuing to search the area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fbf5c54becdf54104160c141ae98e91</guid></item><item><title>Felix Auger-Aliassime hopes for deep Australian Open run after career-best year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/felix-auger-aliassime-united-cup-australian-open/106190574</link><description>After his best year on tour, Canadian star Felix Auger-Aliassime is looking to keep his hot streak running in the United Cup and at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df826417b7ef14f9689a9f9bbaa440aa</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday Finance with Dan Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/wednesday-finance-with-dan-ziffer/106190736</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de67f028c9f77fb97d0d9c7d55d8191b</guid></item><item><title>Previously secret cabinet documents reveal Howard government tried to mitigate 'homegrown' terrorist threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/revelations-from-previously-secret-2005-cabinet-documents/106150758</link><description>From expectations of a trade union backlash against controversial industrial relations reform, to concerns about "homegrown" extremism in Australia, here are what previously unseen cabinet documents tell us about Australian politics in 2005.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1386303f4de0972e24cc5594c2097e71</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, January 1: Evonne Goolagong wins her first Australian Open title</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/spotlight-evonne-goolagong-wins-first-aus-open-1974/106180298</link><description>After an extended break and a shower, Goolagong changed tactics in the deciding set to sail to victory over American Chris Evert back in 1974.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c0c3483d732ec021918d1c074dbf814</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate hikes, an AI bubble and other as-yet-unanswerable 2026 problems</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/australia-2026-economy-predictions-and-questions/106187042</link><description>Australia’s top economists talk interest rate hikes and market movements.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e627973792e1f8843cac029b60d10423</guid></item><item><title>How running helped Darwin entertainer Shalom Kaa overcome substance abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/how-running-helped-shalom-overcome-substance-abuse/106150666</link><description>Shalom Kaa used to think running was something other people did. But after a series of events that left him at his lowest, running became a big part of his recovery following years of substance abuse with crystal methamphetamines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49a738868cba6d5035490a50b6743278</guid></item><item><title>Countries adopting 'new year's resolutions' with health, economy and internet laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/new-year-new-laws-government-social-media-currency-tax/106175364</link><description>From currency changes to cleaner toilets, here's what is changing around the world in the new year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2e880078f59643f418dbd37dedc4406</guid></item><item><title>What ABC journalists will be closely watching in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/2026-geopolitics-foreign-affairs-ukraine-gaza-china-bangladesh/106156684</link><description>Disruptions to the world trade system courtesy of Donald Trump and a reshaping of historic alliances as multiple wars drag on have set the stage for a precarious year in global affairs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f73d25420c43a9cd6d2b02dfa81ebf1</guid></item><item><title>Double stabbing in popular dining strip in Carlton leaves two men in hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/vic-double-stabbing-in-carlton/106191316</link><description>Two men were taken to hospital with serious injuries after being stabbed in Carlton shortly before midnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61922543ff664e1e8cd526db60fc0121</guid></item><item><title>Two people charged after police find explosive devices at a property in Bendigo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/vic-bendigo-firearms-explosives-arrest/106191330</link><description>A man and a woman will face court charged with numerous offences, including manufacturing unauthorised explosive devices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d3159db90fde9d3079a61c836000b7b</guid></item><item><title>Floodwaters to linger in north-west Queensland for weeks with heavy rain forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/floodwaters-north-west-queensland-rainfall-weather-new-years/106189794</link><description>Outback towns remain cut off, and floodwaters are expected to linger in the north-west for weeks. Graziers have started to assess their properties and count stock losses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71ac83feee2c563cf465f57ac98bf41e</guid></item><item><title>Around the world people celebrate new year and hope 2026 brings peace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/people-celebrate-new-years-eve-around-world/106191346</link><description>Cities around the world have rung in the new year in spectacular style, with fireworks lighting up famous landmarks from the London Eye to Egypt's pyramids.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b74c10eb721bba25dec16e8718bcdda5</guid></item><item><title>High-dose MDMA warning for revellers attending Sydney's Field Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/nsw-holder-nyd-music-festival-drug-warning/106190504</link><description>A pill testing trial has been expanded to Sydney's Field Day music festival, but authorities are urging partygoers not to be complacent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d13e73e39cd565120be97de8219ca974</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Roar coach Michael Valkanis's send-off sparks half-time clash with Central Coast Mariners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/police-called-in-roar-mariners-a-league-half-time-tunnel-clash/106191366</link><description>The fallout from Brisbane Roar's spiteful A-League clash with Central Coast continues, with the Roar "considering all options" after comments from Mariners coach Warren Moon following a send-off for Brisbane coach Michael Valkanis that prompted a half-time confrontation in Gosford.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2199dd7748597e9436c444e1885ef8c3</guid></item><item><title>Jurassic Park fan fulfils childhood dream of recreating Jeep</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/jurassic-park-fan-fulfils-dream-of-building-jeep-in-film/106127626</link><description>Zakary Weyer's obsession with Jurassic Park drove him to learn different skills to build a replica of the Jeep that appears in the iconic blockbuster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbb924050916e9eae4b5101cb3ed8759</guid></item><item><title>The nudists baring it all to address misconceptions about naked beach culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/nude-beach-naturism-decline-australia/106123544</link><description>Half a century after the first nude beach opened in Australia, these naturists say they are still fighting to keep beaches open and misconceptions at bay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e2261d54bc8210798ccae948700b720</guid></item><item><title>Chris Lynn wins Adelaide Strikers' New Year's Eve BBL game against Brisbane Heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/chris-lynn-adelaide-strikers-beat-brisbane-heat-in-bbl/106191468</link><description>Former Brisbane star Chris Lynn clobbers the Adelaide Strikers to an easy victory over the Heat in the New Year's Eve Big Bash League clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56be196a0a2a8ee63d3cbd369e5efdae</guid></item><item><title>Handwritten letters among items in the unsealed case file of hanged murderer Jean Lee</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/last-woman-executed-in-australia-jean-lee-melbourne/106186652</link><description>Jean Lee and her two co-accused were executed for murder in 1950. Handwritten letters from the trio are among items publicly available for the first time since their trial captured the nation's attention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01afeaa2dc091c3b9be4a1f4e81ffb8f</guid></item><item><title>Four titan arum 'corpse flowers' to bloom in a week at Cairns Botanic Gardens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/four-titan-arums-simultaneously-flower-in-cairns-botanic-gardens/106190260</link><description>Renowned for their size and stench, blooming corpse flowers are a rare occurrence. But to have four flowering in a week is "something of a record".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb7d7cc23915ad1269387ece32f2c817</guid></item><item><title>Police happy with Victorian NYE revellers despite multiple arrests and illegal fireworks injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/police-happy-with-melbourne-new-years-eve-revellers/106191446</link><description>Police make 18 arrests and several people are taken to hospital for injuries related to illegal fireworks as Victorians see in the new year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02d7743728860292e8f187b030898c75</guid></item><item><title>Three drown, man and teenage boy missing in multiple coastal emergencies off NSW waters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/woman-dies-at-maroubra-beach-while-two-others-missing-in-sydney/106191480</link><description>A man and two women have died and two people are missing following four separate incidents on Sydney waters over the past 48 hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15f036013ff303c79a58b9e1f51234ac</guid></item><item><title>The Bloomfield River cod is the world's only tropical freshwater cod</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/bloomfield-river-cod-is-worlds-only-tropical-freshwater-cod/106097432</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9445f976b28e3803a50943256b0efde</guid></item><item><title>Rare freshwater Bloomfield River cod surviving amid environmental threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/rare-freshwater-fish-bloomfield-river-cod-research/106091448</link><description>The Bloomfield River cod, found in a far north Queensland river catchment, is the world's only tropical freshwater cod, and scientists are working to have it officially protected amid threats from the climate and introduced species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00b5b370eec6e80cd550610dddb90088</guid></item><item><title>Permanent commercial demersal fishing ban begins for large part of WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/permanent-commercial-demersal-fishing-ban-begins-for-part-of-wa/106182868</link><description>From today, commercial demersal fishing is banned along hundreds of kilometres of the WA coastline in an effort to recover fish species numbers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2b9a6a2246d889c750fc2d0dcfefe13</guid></item><item><title>Farmer restores and puts vintage harvester to work 95 years after its first season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/95-year-old-vintage-harvester-restored-wild-horse-plains/106186626</link><description>While most farmers search for the newest technology to help with harvest, Leigh Baker has worked to bring a 95-year-old piece of equipment back to life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a96f456a44fb08b6bce263b2de1b4b92</guid></item><item><title>Lorin's father, satirist John Clarke, had a story to tell so she recorded their conversations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/capturing-memories-on-tape/106043904</link><description>When Lorin Clarke asked her father, satirist John Clarke, if she could start recording their conversations, she thought it would just be for them. But when he tragically died aged 68, one year after the recordings began, Lorin felt his story belonged to more than just her.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f795731f7aa749acc76bbe61db22fc0e</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins, Josh Hazlewood and Tim David named in Australia's T20 World Cup squad despite injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/pat-cummins-josh-hazlewood-in-australia-t20-world-cup-squad/106191918</link><description>Pat Cummins, Josh Hazlewood and Tim David are all included in Australia's 15-player squad for next month's men's Twenty20 World Cup in Sri Lanka and India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb632060256cd1ba342303369a50676e</guid></item><item><title>Australian meat industry warns China's new beef tariff impact will be 'severe'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/china-hits-australian-beef-industry-with-tariff/106191726</link><description>Meat Industry Council says it is "extremely disappointed" as China imposes a tariff on Australian beef imports that could cost $1 billion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b621256dd48d3d4b69ad87156798c3e3</guid></item><item><title>Beaches closed amid search for missing swimmer, teenager.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/beaches-closed-amid-search-for-missing-swimmer-teenager/106192130</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c95759a0f79ecd556f1cf9438e88c7d5</guid></item><item><title>Rescue authorities search for missing man on Coogee Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/rescue-authorities-search-for-missing-man-on-coogee-beach/106192206</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cc9b918142f8b19e81963fc1cfb8b9f</guid></item><item><title>Boy, 15, dies in e-bike crash in Tasmania's north on New Year's Eve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/teen-72yo-killed-in-separate-new-years-eve-crashes/106191780</link><description>A 15-year-old boy has died in an e-bike crash on New Year's Eve, described by Tasmanian police as "tragic" and prompting a call for riders to comply with the law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">161ceddb5bbca6b8089d434c7b4f0c36</guid></item><item><title>Boxer Anthony Joshua discharged from hospital after car crash in Nigeria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/boxing-champion-anthony-joshua-discharged-hospital-crash/106192240</link><description>British former world heavyweight boxing champion Anthony Joshua is discharged from hospital days after a car accident that killed two of his close friends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08b751e022153430fd5153e760395f3e</guid></item><item><title>Amyl and the Sniffers singer Amy Taylor files lawsuit against photographer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/amyl-and-the-sniffers-photos-lawsuit/106191940</link><description>Punk rock frontwoman of Amyl and the Sniffers Amy Taylor has filed a lawsuit against an American photographer alleging that photos taken for a magazine photo shoot are being sold against her wishes and without her permission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a2b281bb73710fe99dc7b3ff37257b4</guid></item><item><title>SA Police arrest 72 people over New Year's Eve celebrations, including three teens over alleged stabbing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/three-teens-arrested-after-12yo-girl-allegedly-stabbed-adelaide/106191974</link><description>SA Police say 72 people were arrested and 10 were reported for offences overnight as the state rang in the new year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1976527ab77b8921c852afb65805921</guid></item><item><title>The strategic plays that may have driven Israel's recognition of Somaliland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/israel-recognition-of-somaliland-comes-amid-tension-in-yemen/106189542</link><description>Israel, suffering international isolation, has recognised a small territory desperate for international attention. Here's why it has caused an enormous stir.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a49565f6d00a30653a30444fc34edd1b</guid></item><item><title>In Dear Life, Brooke Satchwell connects with the recipients of her late fiance's organs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/brooke-satchwell-dear-life-robyn-butler-wayne-hope/106118712</link><description>New Aussie drama Dear Life, from the creators of Upper Middle Bogan, looks at the strange and destructive ways people grieve — and how they live on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1243d86743abf674e8fbfbffb31ef0b</guid></item><item><title>Irish man, 35, drowns at Whitehaven Beach on New Year's Eve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/irish-man-whitehaven-beach-drowning-new-years-eve/106192666</link><description>Police are preparing a report for the coroner as authorities urge holiday-makers to follow safety advice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa793babfb44b038b895e4a91162b792</guid></item><item><title>Divers help free critically endangered grey nurse sharks from fishing gear</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/grey-nurse-shark-rescue-project-teams-divers-and-seaworld/106189440</link><description>The Sea World Foundation teams up with divers to locate, catch and release tangled grey nurse sharks — often referred to as the "labradors of the sea", despite their toothy appearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c1d420873d46fda4dfd18ae6eeec822</guid></item><item><title>Grey nurse shark rescue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/grey-nurse-shark-rescue/106190362</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4978cfeeedf89c7c5b98a8a5fe7b097d</guid></item><item><title>Millennium Falcon the last boat to finish the 80th Sydney to Hobart yacht race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/banged-up-millennium-falcon-last-in-sydney-to-hobart/106192678</link><description>A boat named after a Star Wars spacecraft is the final entry to finish the Sydney to Hobart yacht race, after facing a range of issues at sea and extremely rough weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbafe774d380dd851795fdbe8d388325</guid></item><item><title>Zohran Mamdani sworn in as NYC mayor with midnight subway oath</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/zohran-mamdani-sworn-in-as-nyc-mayor-with-midnight-subway-oath/106192224</link><description>Zohran Mamdani is officially sworn in as major of New York City in a midnight, underground ceremony, with a more public affair to take place in hours time on the steps of City Hall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6014b207fdfdf1b13807a2bb5a8552b</guid></item><item><title>Australian Winter Olympian Tess Coady fully fit for Milan-Cortina Games, after Beijing bronze medal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/aussie-coady-fit-and-firing-in-time-for-italy-winter-olympics/106192850</link><description>Fully-fit Australian snowboard medallist Tess Coady is looking forward to competing in the Winter Olympics next month in Italy after a torrid run with injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fb070f921f451b8f6b2e9bd695d9f99</guid></item><item><title>Father and daughter walk 13km after escape from flooded car in outback Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/police-rescue-father-daughter-from-queensland-floods-at-boulia/106192770</link><description>Two people from Victoria are rescued after climbing through the window of their car as it was washed away by floodwaters in the Queensland outback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f318fb8ee674a6bffcf4671ab13afa65</guid></item><item><title>CCTV footage captured a group of men armed with knives and machetes attacking two individuals on Lygon Street.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/cctv-captures-violent-knife-attack-in-carton/106193122</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afe4ade51e3fd71f1ef7a792b3e0f0d5</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka defends 'Battle of the Sexes' exhibition, wants to play Nick Kyrgios again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/i-need-revenge-sabalenka-targets-kyrgios-rematch/106193082</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka does not want her "Battle of the Sexes" clash with Nick Kyrgios to be the last and insists exhibitions have a vital role to play in tennis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edeffac013109e9ec2af9346d1b39ff6</guid></item><item><title>WA police searching for snorkeller missing off Ledge Point Beach, north of Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/police-searching-for-snorkeller-missing-off-ledge-point/106193204</link><description>Authorities step up their search for a 32-year-old snorkeller missing since yesterday afternoon in the ocean off Ledge Point Beach, north of Perth, after he disappeared while diving for crayfish.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">375f7873595de23bb39c9b6238003bbd</guid></item><item><title>Sydney and Melbourne property markets go backwards as national values hit speed bump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/national-house-price-hit-speed-bump-property-market/106185196</link><description>The red-hot Australian housing market is showing the first signs of easing since interest rates started rising in May 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecc800966e5f0b96cd673ff8c7a5685f</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne's Victoria Street has been on a downward slide, but a brighter future may be beckoning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/victoria-street-richmond-long-term-decline-solutions/106051394</link><description>Richmond's Victoria Street, once a buzzing area home to dozens of restaurants and grocers, has seen better days. What can be done to bring it back to its bustling best?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">828e3ea64293c180e8586ad71248a690</guid></item><item><title>Day in History, January 2: The Yorkshire Ripper's reign of terror ended in a sudden confession</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/yorkshire-ripper-reign-of-terror-ended-in-a-striking-confession/106185092</link><description>The Yorkshire Ripper's reign of terror began in the 70s and lasted for six years. In the end, he was caught by chance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0def5521fdced317ac5db0e4e8c9ad81</guid></item><item><title>The massive partially-quarried Te Tokanga Moai</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/the-massive-partially-quarried-te-tokanga-moai-/106164074</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8facadcc2a3673dc46890084111dd99</guid></item><item><title>Walking with Moai: Unlocking the mysteries of Easter Island stone statues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/rapa-nui-easter-island-moai-creation-and-movement-explained/106077706</link><description>A study using 11,600 aerial drone photos to map a mountainous quarry in 3D reveals more about how the island's famed stone sentinels were created and moved to their final resting places.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b3f8cc1b4e5b43b191888dd05803527</guid></item><item><title>Focus apps claim to improve your productivity. Do they actually work?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/focus-apps-productivity-distraction-smartphone-addiction-timer/106191902</link><description>To understand whether these apps are worth our while, we first need to consider why staying focused is so difficult in the first place.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecc1c656e8f350a1cec6644b16ddaac9</guid></item><item><title>Crans-Montana ski resort fire survivors say they were 'trapped' as Australian confirmed as being among injured</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/crans-montana-bar-fire-survivors-speak-amid-police-probe/106193662</link><description>Swiss authorities say "a large number of young people" are among the casualties from a fire at the Crans-Montana ski resort, as work continues to identify "dozens" of bodies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07157ddee4421fbe7b538c153271c673</guid></item><item><title>Authorities inspect scene of fire at Swiss ski resort of Crans-Montana</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/authorities-inspect-scene-of-fire-at-swiss/106193716</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c2cb13b4c191a4531098e12b20315ae</guid></item><item><title>Two MPs, two legal cases and one region left bewildered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/south-east-politicians-in-custody-analysis/106189724</link><description>The lower house of South Australia's parliament has two representatives from the Limestone Coast. Both are now in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9227dd4c4472299937ecffe98493570d</guid></item><item><title>Inside the massive protests sweeping Iran</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/iran-economic-crisis-sparks-large-protests-against-regime/106192000</link><description>Protests spread from the capital Tehran to other cities and across demographics, with people demanding Iran's leaders end the country's clerical rule and hold free elections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">244b1965f764041be2b54a588e923642</guid></item><item><title>South Australian emergency services kept busy as hot weather causes trees to drop limbs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/hot-weather-causes-trees-to-fall-and-drop-limbs/106187484</link><description>Hot weather has caused stressed trees to drop limbs, damaging property across South Australia and injuring one person so far this summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a75a80b197494567c0c21be1ccf5c757</guid></item><item><title>Why weather conditions in the Darling Downs create the perfect atmosphere for super cells</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/bom-forecast-storm-formation-rain-darling-downs-brisbane/106152296</link><description>Queensland's Darling Downs has recorded more severe storm warning days than any other region this season — and meteorologists say it is no coincidence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">081cd2ebf809a656e2804d0546b64a04</guid></item><item><title>Hit the road in 2026 and catch some of Australia's colourful regional festivals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/great-regional-festivals-in-australia/105752036</link><description>From pint-sized penny farthings to tuna tosses, a beer can regatta to the Running of the Sheep, there's a regional festival for everyone's interests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3df78f8ee6e61516607960f449727a5d</guid></item><item><title>Damien Martyn showing 'encouraging signs' during meningitis treatment, Adam Gilchrist says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/damien-martyn-meningitis-health-update-adam-gilchrist/106193746</link><description>Adam Gilchrist says there are "positive signs" from recent tests on former state and national teammate Damien Martyn, who is in hospital due to meningitis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07c3c452f3535d0a99575bf143c9c341</guid></item><item><title>Flood disaster taking toll on graziers in north-west Queensland, more rain forecast for tropical coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/flood-disaster-taking-toll-on-north-west-qld-more-rain-forecast/106192984</link><description>Rain has hit saturation point in parts of northern Queensland as communities remain isolated and cattle are lost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e749767c157c459501f02dc96f0e146</guid></item><item><title>Major retrospective of ceramic artist Pippin Drysdale opens in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/retrospective-ceramic-artist-pippin-drysdale-agwa/106158010</link><description>The first retrospective of the ceramic artist's work has gone on show in Perth at the state gallery, telling the story of an extraordinary career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cf75ba5ea1935e46c0fbdce0703cf83</guid></item><item><title>Artist Piiij Goodrem used honest self-portraits and therapy to heal from childhood trauma</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/piiij-art-therapy-childhood-trauma/106096230</link><description>The process of creating detailed self-portraits, inspired by tropical landscapes, helped Piiij Goodrem deal with past trauma and addiction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">672bcb420593ffd676f81f31cb65462e</guid></item><item><title>Could modular and prefabricated homes be the key to solving the ACT's housing crisis?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/are-modular-homes-the-key-to-solving-the-acts-housing-crisis/106170130</link><description>Fast to build, eco-friendly and affordable: modular and pre-fabricated homes have been touted as a possible solution to Australia's housing crisis, but manufacturers and suppliers say changes are needed to reduce costs and meet demand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fd79171175902a5b972cccae88eb9af</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja takes aim at 'racial stereotypes' during retirement announcement ahead of fifth Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/usman-khawaja-to-retire-after-scg-ashes-test/106193812</link><description>Australia batter Usman Khawaja takes aim at his critics one last time as he announces his retirement from international cricket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dad1fab02c02e3fc877030f0aa828415</guid></item><item><title>Unique whale behaviour attracts intrigued visitors to regional Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/unique-whale-behaviour-attracts-intrigued-visitors/106135932</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dcec1c05f8131299fa3512b1c166ebc</guid></item><item><title>Unique 'mugging' behaviour attracts intrigued whale watchers to Queensland hotspot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/humpback-whales-mugging-hervey-bay-qld/106126770</link><description>People normally try to avoid getting mugged, but when it comes to being mugged by humpback whales, sightseers are travelling to Queensland's whale-watching capital to witness this special event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3282eaec233651a17432b7f9aa8ca9f0</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja says he hopes he's inspired others in retirement announcement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/usman-khawaja-says-he-hopes-he-s-inspired-others/106194058</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4c8b8999bfd0014db81da5073972a1c</guid></item><item><title>Around 40 killed in Crans-Montana ski resort fire in Switzerland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/around-40-killed-in-crans-montana-ski-resort-fire-in-switzerland/106193796</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5514b0ba0699e7dfce77b2dd6538cd09</guid></item><item><title>Zohran Mamdani vows to protect people of NYC at swearing-in ceremony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/zohran-mamdani-vows-to-protect-people-of-nyc/106193942</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9378dbf342cbb415bc3f0a88afebf5f</guid></item><item><title>As Zohran Mamdani becomes New York's mayor, what are his chances of success?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/zohran-mamdani-inaugurated-as-new-york-mayor/106193766</link><description>New York's new mayor, Zohran Mamdani, has vowed not to water down his ambitious agenda during an impassioned inauguration address outside City Hall. But is his vision achievable?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67da1892dc576e4bb3743a4a18ac7b7d</guid></item><item><title>Sydney mother Melissa Austin identified as one of four NSW drowning victims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/nsw-sydney-beaches-search-missing-teenager-resumes-rescue/106193732</link><description>The identity of one of four people who died in a cluster of drownings on the New South Wales coast in recent days has been confirmed as a Sydney hairdresser and mother.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dfe617468b6038dff391fd793be6774</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja did it all his own way and retires a modern day Australian cricket great</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/usman-khawaja-retirement-cricket-career-legacy-analysis/106092620</link><description>Before his debut in 2011, Australia had never seen a cricketer like Usman Khawaja and, thanks to his work on and off the field, he'll be followed by plenty more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c9a76af7db0042009b315a2619a074c</guid></item><item><title>Tennant Creek mother who died in police watch house described as well-respected and bubbly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/nt-tennant-creek-death-in-custody-aboriginal-mother-autopsy/106184290</link><description>A remote outback town is searching for answers about why a “respectful, friendly and bubbly” Aboriginal mother died in the police watch house, more than 24 hours after her Christmas Day arrest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5738a60bc1f6caebad8e443f99a46a4c</guid></item><item><title>Lachie Neale steps down as Brisbane Lions co-captain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/qld-lachie-neale-steps-down-as-brisbane-lions-co-captain/106194176</link><description>The club said the 32-year-old had made the decision following a "challenging personal period".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">786a557007fbe0bc14c28e09b78783eb</guid></item><item><title>Clark MP Helen Burnet quits Greens to become a Tasmanian independent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/clark-mp-helen-burnet-quits-tasmanian-greens/106194134</link><description>The Clark MP says she knows the decision "will be disappointing for some," but it is necessary for her to be "effective" in parliament — a move that has "blindsided" her former colleagues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4034df2661d219da16b0b6841708443b</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: Ravenous ladybirds, a grumpy seal and a unique home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/weekly-news-quiz-january-2/106194248</link><description>As we start the new year, take some time out to explore some of the other stories you might have missed this holiday period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8399f93982f8cf387ebcb7e2037d649</guid></item><item><title>China's beef tariffs aren't personal as economy slows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/china-beef-import-tariffs-australian-trade-industry-economy/106192982</link><description>Beijing's new measures are aimed at trying to rein in an Australian surge and manage local growth, rather than a direct target on Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0adbd0ff03eaa4f3b1b25c350d5abca4</guid></item><item><title>Research ties China's smog clean-up to hotter and drier conditions in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/china-smog-cleanup-affects-global-warming-australian-rain-heat/106177394</link><description>As China caps off a historic clean-up of its smog and air pollution, the clearer air is helping temperatures rise to new records. Now, researchers are linking that change to hotter and drier conditions in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a199564d4f1ce691f7476ce33ac37099</guid></item><item><title>Alleged bikie granted bail after 'calculated hit' inside Queanbeyan hair salon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/bikie-stabbing-queanbeyan-hairdresser-granted-bail/106194238</link><description>In just four minutes, two men were stabbed in the chest and customers inside the Queanbeyan hair salon were left shaken.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b647deea177f7adfd50480c79377331</guid></item><item><title>NT to introduce Voluntary Assisted Dying legislation in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/nt-vouluntary-assisted-dying-legislation-introduced-2026/106194574</link><description>The Northern Territory government says it will introduce Voluntary Assisted Dying legislation to parliament this year, nearly two decades after the Commonwealth vetoed the NT’s world-first euthanasia legislation in 1997.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b2ba34e82f70d6dd5d2bb3438f371c2</guid></item><item><title>Venus Williams to become oldest ever Australian Open participant after receiving wildcard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/tennis-venus-williams-oldest-australian-open-player-wildcard/106194896</link><description>Venus Williams will play in the main draw of the Australian Open for the first time since 2021, 28 years after she first graced Melbourne Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">383c70fac8ec31cd0081f57a6d081c9d</guid></item><item><title>Man faces court after alleged crime spree, police pursuit in Latrobe Valley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/man-faces-court-after-alleged-crime-spree-in-latrobe-valley/106194974</link><description>A 34-year-old man has been remanded in custody after allegedly going on a multi-day crime spree across Victoria's south-east involving carjackings, burglaries and a police pursuit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1399ad0101654482f076800cadeee6f9</guid></item><item><title>Man who kidnapped boy from Moora home given eight-year prison sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/man-who-kidnapped-boy-from-moora-home-jailed-for-eight-years/106194254</link><description>A man who abducted a boy from his bed in regional WA after sniffing butane and having delusions about aliens is sentenced to eight years in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d838d36694a1ba7bcb5f596722cc3e5</guid></item><item><title>Queensland housing market continues to rise as national growth slows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/qld-home-values-cotality-rent/106194242</link><description>Brisbane's housing market remains one of the strongest in the nation, with prices up 1.6 per cent in December even as Sydney and Melbourne see some growth moderation in property valuations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92796b5f28217e1302dacb33b85d4577</guid></item><item><title>Crans-Montana ski resort fire witnesses recall how the tragic blaze unfolded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/how-crans-montana-ski-resort-fire-unfolded/106194322</link><description>As the resort town of Crans-Montana reels from the news of a tragic fire at a New Year's Eve party, a witness recalls hearing screams and seeing people covered in blood in the aftermath of the bar blaze.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1da6fdd72b683b6fa9d038315b8a72e</guid></item><item><title>Are modular homes the key to solving the ACT's housing crisis?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/are-modular-homes-the-key-to-solving-the-housing-crisis/106195194</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8df33e064533241b2bb3c2e047af6dd3</guid></item><item><title>Boddington family watches heritage cottage filled with antiques go up in flames on Christmas Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/boddington-fire-heritage-family-house-burnt-christmas-day/106185508</link><description>Two heritage homes and thousands of hectares of land were lost in a Christmas Day bushfire in Boddington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfc414b6e60e3ef86dd407eb61ea1511</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump gave a wide-ranging interview about his health. Here's what we learned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/donald-trumps-health-key-points-from-wsj-interview/106194812</link><description>US President Donald Trump says he regrets undergoing advanced imagery on his heart and abdomen because of the "ammunition" it handed his critics, but has once more defended his "perfect" health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45795f8f18432352bfd8576c1750a81f</guid></item><item><title>Todd Murphy in line for Ashes return as SCG curator allays fears over pitch's green exterior</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/todd-murphy-sydney-comeback-green-pitch-concerns-scg/106194954</link><description>Todd Murphy could play his first Test match on Australian soil as the curator of the SCG allays fears over the pitch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6afb840ee8e9c9cf26094b2c13f3912c</guid></item><item><title>Another e-bike death sparks renewed calls for consistency around laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/renewed-calls-for-consistency-around-e-bike-laws/106194008</link><description>Police believe a 15-year-old boy is the first person to die in Tasmania riding an e-bike, raising questions about what laws exist to regulate e-bike safety in the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77d632dfc18a7fe138571bfd7157f497</guid></item><item><title>Maya Joint hit with illness ahead of Australia's United Cup opener against Norway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/tennis-maya-joint-illness-australia-united-cup-vs-norway/106195416</link><description>Australia's teen sensation is forced to lay low, with team captain Lleyton Hewitt hoping it is just a 24-hour thing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">767bcd062b8c2aa011eed6fd7e4382d3</guid></item><item><title>Mother wallaby death sparks animal cruelty investigation in far north Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/wallaby-death-leads-to-animal-cruelty-complaints/106185200</link><description>Wildlife carers have lodged formal complaints with police and environment officials after stumbling across a scene involving a dead mother wallaby tied to a signpost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c90d255c025ebf1e2f29e236fa840a3</guid></item><item><title>Northern Territory town of Jabiru facing rolling blackouts since New Year's Eve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/jabiru-power-rolling-blackouts-new-years-eve/106195350</link><description>The remote Northern Territory town of Jabiru has faced rolling blackouts since New Year's Eve, with no clear indication of when power will be properly restored.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb00e31477b9b52b56c51f096ac6922b</guid></item><item><title>One man missing, another in hospital after collapse at Curragh Coal Mine in Central Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/qld-curragh-mine-incident-rshq/106195452</link><description>One man is in hospital and another is missing following an incident at a Central Queensland coal mine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">372e4a13946d341ab7a1528c3b403480</guid></item><item><title>Emergency services downgrade bushfire warning for Mundaring residents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/mundaring-residents-urged-to-leave-as-fire-close-to-homes/106195648</link><description>Authorities say the bushfire is moving in a north-easterly direction but is currently stationary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8556b9c03d9c98b1df1ca6391ead154</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says US will 'come to their rescue' if Iran kills protesters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/trump-says-us-will-come-to-their-rescue-if-iran-kills-protesters/106195678</link><description>President Donald Trump says the United States is "locked and loaded" to respond if Iran kills protesters, prompting Tehran to warn that intervention would destabilise the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3d44eb30adce12ba9b8fee18a1bc3b0</guid></item><item><title>Kim Jong Un's daughter makes public visit to state mausoleum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/kim-jong-un-daughter-visit-state-mausoleum/106195780</link><description>The North Korean leader's daughter, reportedly named Kim Ju Ae, has been making increasingly prominent appearances in state media, fuelling speculation she may be in line to be the country's fourth-generation leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cb58d10aaee154d499a5861b3c70ac4</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy names spy chief Kyrylo Budanov as new top aide, after ex-advisor quit over corruption probe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/volodymyr-zelenskyy-names-kyrylo-budanov-as-top-aide/106195996</link><description>Ukraine's president has named Kyrylo Budanov, a legendary intelligence leader in the country, as the new head of his presidential office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3adcf6f1ab7de0a90be5825e8bf3d6a8</guid></item><item><title>China-Taiwan-US triangle held together by assumptions and one dangerous lie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/taiwan-china-united-states-military-triangle-lies/106189394</link><description>The US has no intention of abandoning Taiwan. But it also has no intention of binding itself to an automatic war commitment on a timeline it does not control.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec0387ed2f1a234d6444e54f05dd6c27</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government can expect economic and political pressure in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/2026-labor-government-albanese-inflation-housing-chalmers/106156690</link><description>What are you watching in Australian politics in 2026? That's the question we put to the ABC's political journalists and columnists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1f99661621e9d02561489076f9ba6e3</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, January 3: Steve Waugh secures a last-ball century to complete his perfect day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/today-in-history-steve-waughs-last-ball-century-scg-ashes/106192024</link><description>With one ball remaining on day two of the fifth Ashes Test in 2003, Steve Waugh stared down a century and his own cricketing mortality before securing one of the most famous centuries of his storied career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05d0aba10e39cfec8283ebaa6d085d05</guid></item><item><title>Are reading goals helpful or performative? How to read more in the new year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/how-to-read-more-in-the-new-year/105977668</link><description>While some people might find goal setting motivating — such as reading X number of books each year or pages each day — there is a risk of turning what is supposed to be a pleasurable activity into a chore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10a698c1ed7e84a78515524c2f5bf576</guid></item><item><title>ABC 50/50 quiz: This week we're testing your knowledge of Kylie Minogue, Greek gods and card games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/abc-50-50-quiz-january-3/106157448</link><description>Every question has only two options: one is right and the other is wrong. You have an even chance of guessing correctly each time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b1191022abdeaac1fec317f882f4e6b</guid></item><item><title>Crans-Montana ski resort fire probe raises questions about sparklers, safety compliance at Le Constellation bar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/crans-montana-le-constellation-fire-safety-probe-continues/106195680</link><description>The prevalence of sparklers at a Swiss ski resort bar where dozens of people died in a fire this week has been branded "irresponsible", as authorities probe potential compliance issues there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b80455aa1638f38aebd977cfa10ee904</guid></item><item><title>World-first as Australian donates organs after self-administering assisted dying medication</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/australian-donates-organs-after-self-administering-vad/106086648</link><description>An Australian woman is believed to have become the first person in the world to donate organs after self-administering oral voluntary assisted dying medication.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">771245fd34fb60755bbd5d86c319d888</guid></item><item><title>Red and yellow flags can be dangerously confusing. Is it time to change them?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/red-yellow-flags-drowning-rescue-lifeguards-rip/106195120</link><description>Every summer, millions of Australians head to the beach and every year thousands are rescued by lifeguards or surf life savers, and even surfers or other bystanders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">474042795045b3c3e3237f3a864461e6</guid></item><item><title>Anastasia Golubeva set for 2026 Winter Olympics debut with Australia after citizenship change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/citizenship-change-keeps-figure-skaters-olympic-dream-alive/106194338</link><description>Figure skater Anastasia Golubeva becomes an Australian citizen, just six weeks out from the Milano-Cortina Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d0afd2ba4b8d8ddf86d2b3237f2bf1</guid></item><item><title>The moon will loom extra large tonight — but it's not a supermoon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/how-to-see-wolf-moon-2026/106194794</link><description>Stargazers will be treated with a supersized wolf moon for the first weekend of the year. Here's what to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12bba61f673a8ba85ac4295e8b36f0f0</guid></item><item><title>Confronting the man who followed the ABC while reporting on Myanmar's elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/confronting-the-man-who-followed-the-abc-myanmar/106190494</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c246f059eff67229015b952b1f6dfe76</guid></item><item><title>The parts of Myanmar the military junta doesn't want you to see</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/inside-myanmar-during-military-junta-sham-election-voting/106190364</link><description>Myanmar's military is holding its first elections since overthrowing a democratically elected government in 2021. But as it aims to portray a sense of normality, signs of the junta's menacing presence are everywhere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">948d3c6bb8238924022179a27bbdcb98</guid></item><item><title>Cattle walking through floodwaters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/cattle-in-floodwaters/106195478</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a4c2f7125a6ab275b841cc1f878d207</guid></item><item><title>Scrammy Gorge in Bladensburg National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/scrammy-gorge-in-winton/106195480</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7a613c0252146e93681cc6f27e15eb4</guid></item><item><title>Flooded outback Queensland graziers to get $2m government package for fodder drops</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/outback-queensland-flood-funding-announced-graziers/106194300</link><description>Floodwaters remain in outback Queensland as graziers start to tally up livestock losses. Major flooding is possible in the north-west, with king tides forecast on the east coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6be062a8ba3d66a5ef9d894cfa376139</guid></item><item><title>From a Facebook appreciation group to viral TikTok reviews: Australia's love for bánh mì</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/sydneys-banh-mi-obsession-bakeries-go-viral-on-social-media/105884842</link><description>A humble bánh mì appreciation group created by a Sydneysider has played a pivotal role in reinvigorating Australia's love for Vietnamese baguettes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b3308fe0fca82ab03b009e0efd4f43b</guid></item><item><title>FBI says it thwarted ISIS-inspired New Year's Eve attack in North Carolina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/fbi-foils-isis-inspired-plot-north-carolina/106196040</link><description>The US Attorney for the Western District of North Carolina claims the 18-year-old suspect had planned to attack a grocery store and fast food restaurant in his hometown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94007e2a50b07dbc56d071e34aaf0d9f</guid></item><item><title>Mid North Coast brumby program rehomes 160 wild horses across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/brumby-rehoming-program-gives-wild-horses-second-chance/106085286</link><description>About a third of the brumby population on the NSW Mid North Coast has been rehomed through a program designed to give wild horses a second chance as pets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ece383d3daeacd448a3de2d057214f0</guid></item><item><title>Naomi Osaka loses United Cup match to Maria Sakkari ahead of Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/united-cup-naomi-osaka-maria-sakkari-australian-open/106196062</link><description>Just over two weeks from the season-opening major, former world number one Naomi Osaka reveals she is not at full health after contracting a viral illness over the Christmas period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">512763bd96b8fdd1d3013fa3d2190ff2</guid></item><item><title>Housing program for pregnant homeless women faces high demand as expert calls for accurate data</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/homeless-pregnant-women-cornelia-melbourne-serivce/106169764</link><description>While the exact number of pregnant women who are homeless in Victoria is unknown, experts say the outsized demand for specialty support services indicates more can be done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca88c30c1930c6f0e97b5b166e7784bf</guid></item><item><title>Tesla loses title of bestselling EV company to BYD as sales drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/tesla-loses-title-bestselling-ev-to-byd/106196066</link><description>Tesla sales have declined for the second consecutive year, with Chinese rival BYD surpassing it as the world's largest electric vehicle maker.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c10f01312156bde84a15adaabb610cff</guid></item><item><title>Police hunt for offenders after shooting in Melbourne's inner north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/fitzroy-shooting-police-crime/106196082</link><description>A man was treated by paramedics but died at the scene following a shooting in Fitzroy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">558108aa6fbd3604a2fedf660c062bb4</guid></item><item><title>Barbecue explosion prompts safety warning after Qld beautician's burns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/mums-bbq-warning-after-explosion-on-christmas-eve/106195412</link><description>Rachel Dear has a serious warning for anyone using a gas barbecue after she suffered significant face and body burns while cooking on Christmas Eve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb1ca2b13267460bbd659d5184771082</guid></item><item><title>Coffee pods generate thousands of tonnes of waste in Australia. Here's what is being done about it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/qld-australia-coffee-pod-waste-upcycled-schemes-recycling/106149492</link><description>Between 10 and 20 per cent of the 3 million coffee pods Australians consume daily are actually recycled. Here's what's being done to change that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e00615d7dff72de8460ca30c668e1baa</guid></item><item><title>Photographs of Men in Love exhibition reveals public glimpses of forbidden love</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/photographs-of-men-in-love-exhibition-same-sex-couples-canberra/106164254</link><description>What started as a chance discovery of an old photo at a Dallas antique store has spawned a collection of more than 4,000 images of male couples, more than 100 of which are now on display in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">342bd9008f4a6040aef96519ae23b8f6</guid></item><item><title>Helen Burnet has defected from the Greens but voters may still be wondering exactly why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/helen-burnet-quits-greens-questions-remain-over-why/106195524</link><description>Helen Burnet fronted the cameras on Friday to announce she was quitting the party she's been a member of for more than 20 years, but it's still not clear exactly why she's made the move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">045c12b602cf0bd78e6fdcfc284e48f1</guid></item><item><title>WA's Pilbara region shares a human and shorebird FIFO population</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/migratory-shorebirds-land-in-the-pilbara-for-summer/106039306</link><description>Dozens of shorebird species flock to northern WA for summer during their global migration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ff35fe466eef14512e81d2afaf6106e</guid></item><item><title>Searches called off for 14-year-old boy and man missing off Palm Beach and Coogee Beach in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/nsw-police-suspend-search-for-teenager-man-at-coogee-palm-beach/106196102</link><description>Authorities suspend their searches for a 14-year-old boy and a man in his 20s who went missing off the Sydney coastline this week, following a horror week of drownings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6e3a10b25e5a870ee1705545a524f38</guid></item><item><title>Middle Percy Island is a 'haven' for sailors, displaying scores of memorabilia from bygone days</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/percy-island-attracts-yachties-from-across-world/105385704</link><description>Middle Percy Island is a rare gem where boaties can come ashore and wander through thousands of mementos left by travellers from across the globe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1746a1ce94f0eacb5cef7b4153c7f3b5</guid></item><item><title>Woman killed in suspected mountain lion attack on Colorado trail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/woman-killed-by-mountain-lion-in-colorado/106196130</link><description>The woman was found unresponsive by other hikers with injuries consistent with a mountain lion attack, authorities say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">589f9435ec17c1c8a5e5a671ab6681cc</guid></item><item><title>Former Darwin councillor's ex-partner speaks out after guilty domestic violence verdict</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/ex-partner-darwin-councillor-speaks-out-after-guilty-dv-verdict/106170776</link><description>Former Darwin councillor Paul Arnold was found guilty of domestic violence after a years-long court battle, with his ex-partner refusing to be scared into silence. She said the case was "stressful and deeply humiliating", but fronting her abuser had been empowering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4c243120a1fef30a2f8354e4ef212a0</guid></item><item><title>Red sprites erupt in the Kimberley sky.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/red-sprites-erupt-in-kimberley-sky-/106195070</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0c3f0d3710e04c31770e700478c1a58</guid></item><item><title>Storm chaser captures rare red sprites across Kimberley sky</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/red-sprites-storm-chaser-kimberley-sky/106192812</link><description>A storm chaser says he "screamed" when he captured an elusive natural phenomenon, known as red sprites, on video.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f1f2816c594f555f58c60bc969eeff4</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police riot squad to carry long-arm firearms at Sydney Ashes series following Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/nsw-police-riot-squad-carry-long-arm-firearms-sydney-ashes-/106196098</link><description>Officers will carry long-arm firearms as part of a bolstered police presence at the Ashes series in Sydney in the wake of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6877b2907f2f985901c51db094f90f7d</guid></item><item><title>Premium beef producers expect to be the main casualty of China's new 55 per cent tariff</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/wagyu-angus-casualty-of-china-tariffs-on-australian-beef/106194112</link><description>Australian cattle farmers producing wagyu and Angus beef are likely to be among the hardest hit by China's 55 per cent tariff on exports exceeding a 205,000-tonne quota.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">228dfb545460ba76f36dbd3ab6992df6</guid></item></channel></rss>