<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 18:59:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How 'snakeheads' are redirecting illegal migration from China toward Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/chinese-nationals-walking-the-routes-to-australia-boat-explained/106124082</link><description>Recent boat arrivals in Western Australia offer a glimpse into how routes through South-East Asia, particularly Indonesia, are being used to reach Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96570f64d21f4ef9f4cbcb03f5bb70d6</guid></item><item><title>Why the football Dylan Brown showed for New Zealand can make his record-breaking move to Newcastle pay off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/dylan-brown-golden-boot-newcastle-knights-contract/106126952</link><description>The football Dylan Brown played for New Zealand should have won him the Golden Boot but it could also be the key to his record-breaking move to Newcastle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b66459bac729932c38199a2ed35baba1</guid></item><item><title>Australian rare earth processing plant to be ready for use in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/rare-earth-processing-facility-mining-south-australia/106123882</link><description>The processing market is dominated by China, but Australia is building its capabilities in an attempt to boost the domestic industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76cd3cd1ea5800ec9707c1a72f6776cd</guid></item><item><title>States and territories reject Commonwealth public hospital funding offer — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/federal-politics-live-blog-dec-12/106134352</link><description>States and territories have rejected a public hospital funding offer from the federal government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e473ad0ef6aac29b4fbaefd35a9388e1</guid></item><item><title>Police Commissioner Grant Stevens appointed to Adelaide Football Club board</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/police-commissioner-grant-stevens-joins-adelaide-crows-board/106133692</link><description>South Australia's top cop has taken on an extra role, joining the Adelaide Football Club's board of directors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09e93f9c48e604eb3ccb6fcdbd02e0c3</guid></item><item><title>Trusted Mildura accountant facing longer prison sentence after defrauding clients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/trusted-mildura-accountant-philip-shugg-facing-longer-sentence/106129286</link><description>Philip Shugg, a prominent accountant from Victoria's north-west, is facing an even lengthier prison sentence after pleading guilty to defrauding his clients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57faad4e4c13ed7944513432f6053354</guid></item><item><title>Perth Scorchers into WBBL final as Beth Mooney continues sparkling form to down Sydney Sixers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/cricket-beth-mooney-stars-scorchers-into-wbbl-final/106134414</link><description>Sydney Sixers keeper Alyssa Healy misses a glorious chance to dismiss Beth Mooney, and the Aussie left-hander makes her pay big-time with a sparkling innings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f23135c1ee0b7703fe9b9e8aea71299</guid></item><item><title>Markets live update: ANZ to defend legal action by former boss over $13.5m in lost bonuses, ASX rises — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/asx-markets-business-live-news-dec-12/106134504</link><description>Former ANZ chief executive Shayne Elliott is suing the bank for stripping him of $13.5 million in bonuses. Local stocks rallied on Friday after the Dow hit new records in a mixed session for Wall Street overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22dd22fa432152c61a1dc4190fa94df3</guid></item><item><title>Independent wholesaler cautiously welcomes review into outback food subsidy scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/outback-food-subsidy-scheme-review-cautiously-welcomed/106090748</link><description>A wholesaler hopes a review of a controversial outback food subsidy scheme will be independent and transparent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec8ea28f6aa649b62bc6717d5ff7ee0c</guid></item><item><title>After 40 years of plot twists and drama, Neighbours wraps up for the last time — again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/neighbours-finale-recap/106133684</link><description>Relive the highlights, such as they were, in the final episode of Neighbours, which went to air last night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66d77596370f9dcb56e3473c4c20e070</guid></item><item><title>Demersal fishing ban leaves industry 'drowning' as mental health concerns rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/fishing-industry-drowning-in-emotional-toll-of-dermersal-ban/106109302</link><description>WA fishers are raising concerns about a lack of mental health support as the commercial industry comes to terms with a ban on demersal fishing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">780356866a5457fda1599f1fb8e408ed</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says land strikes on Venezuela drug shipments coming soon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/us-ready-to-seize-ships-venezuelan-oil-tankers/106134498</link><description>Donald Trump says the US will soon strike drug shipments making their way from Venezuela on land, amid a large-scale military build-up in the southern Caribbean to increase pressure on Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3988de499dfa17007965f95e974b24e4</guid></item><item><title>Record-breaking crocodile Cassius taxidermied for Green Island exhibit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/world-record-crocodile-cassius-taxidermied-new-exhibit/106131178</link><description>The world's largest crocodile in captivity until its death last year is going on display in Far North Queensland, as more findings are revealed about its cause of death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">733169fd9a429b9ff1e0b26e8fc099d4</guid></item><item><title>Hailstorm batters western NSW as homes destroyed in bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/storm-fire-cause-damage-nsw/106134570</link><description>Hailstorms have damaged homes in parts of western NSW as the cost of nearby bushfires continues to mount.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07dafe09ecc5e0e93c29e90d78c2a495</guid></item><item><title>Community rallies around family of farmer Mark Mudie after bushfire death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/community-support-wa-farmer-family-after-bushfire-death/106130238</link><description>In the wake of the tragic loss of farmer Mark Mudie while fighting a bushfire, the community has rallied to help his family finish harvesting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29225b57eeac8a3e9bddf250890cea9b</guid></item><item><title>Matilda Bay and Applecross ferry terminals approved in Swan River Metronet plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/swan-river-matilda-bay-applecross-ferry-terminals-approved/106130810</link><description>WA's planning authorities approve the construction of two new ferry terminals at Applecross and Matilda Bay as part of the state government's expansion of Swan River ferry services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">263609e9363897531936e450b7d42c1d</guid></item><item><title>Eurovision winner Nemo returns trophy in protest over Israel's participation in competition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/nemo-returns-eurovision-trophy-over-israels-participation/106134594</link><description>Swiss singer Nemo says they will return the trophy they won in 2024 over the EBU's decision to let Israel participate in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cb716762728053bb6ac34183a1719bf</guid></item><item><title>Reddit files legal challenge against social media ban for under-16s</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/reddit-social-media-ban-under-16-court-challenge/106134994</link><description>Reddit has filed a High Court challenge alleging that Australia's social media restrictions are being applied to the company inaccurately.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">198bf1486fb398a261f42203fd377f5a</guid></item><item><title>Career counselling lacking as students try to predict AI impact on jobs of the future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/ai-jobs-student-anxiety-vce-university-atar-employment/106123826</link><description>A Victorian Parliamentary Inquiry report finds youth career support is "severely lacking" as students fear AI is threatening white-collar industries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5781af3b1fbb37853c9b606b2ddad516</guid></item><item><title>Treasurer Jim Chalmers gives green light to Hanwha's double stake in shipbuilder Austal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/hanwha-austal-bid-approve-jim-chalmers/106134860</link><description>Jim Chalmers said there will be "strict conditions" on the South Korean defence conglomerate's stake in the strategic shipbuilder, in a nod to the diplomatic and security sensitivities surrounding the bid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110810108c4d6e185f96e797e7f4a857</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos-containing wind turbine brake pad shipment docked at Geelong port</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/asbestos-wind-turbine-brake-pads-worksafe-cfmeu-vestas/106131948</link><description>A cargo ship containing asbestos products is docked at the port of Geelong in Victoria's south-west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29a5b677e898bfcc7b394bfb1ef0a5e3</guid></item><item><title>French game Clair Obscur breaks records with Game of the Year 2025 win — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/game-awards-2025-live-coverage/106102718</link><description>The biggest night in gaming is getting underway in the heart of downtown Los Angeles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8d73ac44f3cef79d117d2e04e651b49</guid></item><item><title>Hollywood director Carl Rinsch convicted of scamming Netflix out of $16.5m</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/hollywood-director-convicted-of-scamming-16-million-aud-netflix/106135428</link><description>Carl Erik Rinsch is convicted on charges that he scammed Netflix out of $US11 million for a show that never materialised, instead using the cash for purchases including luxury cars and homewares.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9e8489bf4a398903633591b2660742f</guid></item><item><title>New SA Liberal leader Ashton Hurn unveils 'streamlined' shadow cabinet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/new-sa-liberal-leader-unveils-shadow-cabinet/106135116</link><description>South Australia's new Liberal leader Ashton Hurn unveils a "streamlined" shadow cabinet, just 99 days out from the next state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1951d24f5aa21dc00e9d0d2831cd4cb9</guid></item><item><title>How long does it take to fix an underperforming school?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/boonah-high-agriculture-education-turnaround/105983794</link><description>A Queensland high school has re-engaged students by embedding agriculture into the curriculum and building strong local industry ties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b4dcb5993bb0060e638f96fbbe9c04</guid></item><item><title>PM says he has asked independent watchdog for advice on politician entitlement rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/parliamentary-expenses-rules-review/106135370</link><description>Sports and Communications Minister Anika Wells referred her claims to the Independent Parliamentary Expenses Authority for review after a stream of questions over her spending earlier this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bef836fe52d78ae8131a7227fe19a13</guid></item><item><title>Surfers find 'earthquake wave' off Western Australia's remote south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/decade-long-search-for-unique-wa-big-wave/106133082</link><description>A natural phenomenon leaves surfers in awe of the "earthquake" wave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04596bfe87994ec9243bbca950c9b61b</guid></item><item><title>Surfers capture weird wave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/surfers-film-wild-wave/106133580</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a965f9627b6775da38a95dd70e718e7c</guid></item><item><title>Dicky Bill salad farm's $10m debt shock as creditors try to claw back millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/dicky-bill-salad-farm-10m-debt-blow/105904126</link><description>Administrators for failed Australian salad farm company Dicky Bill reveal its business debts to hundreds of staff and suppliers could exceed $10 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8e5be403ca29b045c30bc879c4ed016</guid></item><item><title>Emergency declaration lifted after police fail to find reportedly armed man in Marsden, south of Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/qld-police-issue-emergency-declaration-marsden/106136130</link><description>Queensland Police said they gained access to a home where they believed an armed man to be, but found no-one inside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91fb72fd52f04d81d8ae32e7b8cd23fe</guid></item><item><title>Court awards $54,000 to protester for Victoria Police's use of capsicum spray</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/court-awards-damages-to-protester-victoria-police-capsicum-spray/106136220</link><description>A Supreme Court judge awards $54,000 in damages to a protester who sued Victoria Police after officers used pepper spray at a protest in 2019 outside the Melbourne Exhibition Centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79b906d4e128deb26383226c7edd2dd6</guid></item><item><title>Brittany Higgins declared bankrupt amid Linda Reynolds court saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/brittany-higgins-declared-bankrupt-linda-reynolds/106136120</link><description>Former senator Linda Reynolds's bid to have Brittany Higgins declared bankrupt has succeeded in a federal court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f9de42f4bde5dc6b81841920cd36d48</guid></item><item><title>Tom Silvagni's victim tells pre-sentence hearing she is haunted by rape 'every single day'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/tom-silvagni-rape-conviction-victim-speaks-in-court/106134992</link><description>The young woman raped by Tom Silvagni, whose father is AFL great Stephen Silvagni, has described the horror of the night it happened and the lasting impact it has had on her life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6a78813bca7c02fedc257b38783e906</guid></item><item><title>Government deal to ensure Tomago Aluminium smelter remains open beyond 2028</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/tomago-aluminium-secures-government-deal/106135134</link><description>A deal is being finalised between Tomago Aluminium and the state and federal governments to keep the smelter open beyond 2028.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">344a7ea744602f32b11358244f0ec706</guid></item><item><title>Strict bail conditions for suspended police officer facing child abuse material charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/tylar-shepheard-strict-bail-conditions/106136090</link><description>Suspended NSW police officer Tylar Shepheard, charged with possessing child abuse material among other charges, has had strict conditions placed on him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14f0cc454169b974fb85f46b1c17a9d2</guid></item><item><title>UK backpacker Alicia Kemp sentenced over e-scooter death of Thanh Phan in Perth CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/english-backpacker-sentenced-over-escooter-death-/106135496</link><description>Alicia Kemp is sentenced to four years behind bars after the 25-year-old English backpacker hit and killed Thanh Phan as she rode an e-scooter while drunk in Perth's CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db6d181185033240337530be95bca41e</guid></item><item><title>Port Fairy residents demand answers after council abruptly closes only all-abilities pool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/belfast-aquatics-community-pool-abruptly-closes/106135078</link><description>The south-west Victorian community of Port Fairy is demanding answers after an abrupt announcement from its council that it has closed the town's only pool.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2475053435283faa9f963d9cc4a5eb3d</guid></item><item><title>Courtnee Vine in video portrait of the Matildas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/courtnee-vine-in-video-portrait-of-the-matildas/106136690</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d77dabc04c9ce29fe4d285c0c8e9cc5</guid></item><item><title>National Portrait Gallery unveils video portrait of Matildas honouring their contribution to sport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/new-video-portrait-of-matildas-pays-tribute-to-their-legacy/106136190</link><description>The 23-minute video portrait of the Matildas 2023 World Cup squad cost $400,000, in what the National Portrait Gallery describes as its most ambitious commission ever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b67ac0ff5d6ccb3e375135e07013ed8</guid></item><item><title>Former ANZ chief executive Shayne Elliott sues banking giant after losing $13.5m in bonuses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/former-anz-ceo-shayne-elliott-sues-bank/106136712</link><description>Shayne Elliott says he has been left with "no alternative" but to launch legal action against the bank over its decision to slash $13.5 million from his bonus payments after he retired.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7d863795f4422aa214a07f5703eaf25</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man sentenced to 30 years' jail for murdering co-worker at National Zoo and Aquarium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/act-man-jailed-30-yeras-for-murdering-co-worker-at-canberra-zoo/106136236</link><description>Jude Wijesinghe is sentenced to 30 years' jail for stabbing his Canberra zoo colleague Tshewang Choden to death in the storeroom of the kitchen area where they both worked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab2490ec14baa45da257236eb78c7194</guid></item><item><title>New concessional loans for drought-affected farmers and algae-impacted fishers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/government-ric-review-new-loan-program-farmers-fishers-drought/106134810</link><description>The federal government is introducing new low-interest loans for drought-affected farmers and algae-impacted fishers, but some are worried it doesn't go far enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">637d56e286835d468cfe8a39ac049e83</guid></item><item><title>Our 10 best Christmas recipes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/easy-christmas-recipes-mains-desserts/105721782</link><description>Christmas is around the corner and we have plenty of delicious ideas whether you're hosting or bringing dessert.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4744c3fde22d977ef3646b0be11dd87a</guid></item><item><title>The Thai Navy released footage of a Cambodian casino on the Thai border being shelled.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/thai-navy-bombing-building/106135828</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bb0f0a95c492be2839fd96581edb46e</guid></item><item><title>Thailand's bombing of Cambodian casinos could be putting trafficking victims at risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/thailand-bombs-cambodian-casinos-and-scam-centres/106125824</link><description>An expert says the Thai military's strikes on Cambodian casinos and suspected scam centres could be putting the lives of civilians and human trafficking victims at risk and may be considered war crimes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c044830d17205d2026f93fd522896c7a</guid></item><item><title>Celebrity crocodile wrangler Matt Wright sentenced to 10 months in prison, suspended after five months</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/crocodile-wrangler-matt-wright-sentencing-nt-supreme-court/106127504</link><description>Celebrity crocodile wrangler Matt Wright has been sentenced to 10 months in prison, suspended after five months, for attempting to interfere with an investigation into a fatal helicopter accident three years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ce1bef24766a0c434377874c4d84c74</guid></item><item><title>Kai Fursey pleads guilty to crash in stolen car that killed rideshare passenger Ryan Grafton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/kai-fursey-guilty-wacol-hit-run-ryan-grafton/106136654</link><description>Ryan Grafton, 30, was killed and two other people were seriously injured when Kai Colin Matthew Fursey crashed a stolen car into their Uber rideshare in May, 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0bc0f358d81dc5657120699d90be4cd</guid></item><item><title>Victims tell court of 'trauma' inflicted by Adelaide massage therapist Sumit Satish Rastogi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/massage-therapist-sumit-rastogi-victim-impact-statements/106137272</link><description>An unqualified massage therapist who sexually abused more than 60 women left his victims with "trauma" and "severe psychological harm", a court has heard. Warning: This story contains descriptions of sexual abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf24817650dee7534baeb0596d7c99d5</guid></item><item><title>Court hears Dreaming story not 'trump card' to halt Regis Resources' McPhillamys Gold Project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/court-told-dreaming-story-not-trump-card-to-stop-gold-mine/106135486</link><description>An elders' group has told a Federal Court in Sydney that the Blue Banded Bee Dreaming story was not being kept "up its sleeve" three years after a protection bid was first made to the Commonwealth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a40abe62a175d5b6f25efd398ee39997</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106137824</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ec17792ba04e87136ec7434373520ed</guid></item><item><title>Man jailed for not stopping to help 3yo hit by car in Geraldton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/geraldton-man-sentenced-hit-and-run-young-child/106135848</link><description>The boy was dragged under a car for more than 100 metres, with the judge saying she does not know how he survived.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bd7f61e8707e8c652c007a46ad18dfd</guid></item><item><title>Adult content creator 'Bonnie Blue' leaving a Bali court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/adult-content-creator-bonnie-blue-leaving-a-bali-court-/106137870</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">366cc6f24c711d807db94a02fc595df2</guid></item><item><title>British porn star Bonnie Blue deported from Bali after 'Bang Bus' case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/bonnie-blue-faces-bali-court-after-studio-raid/106137670</link><description>The controversial adult content creator has faced court for flouting the resort island's road rules.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8222c1e101256089be61bc436435f9d8</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested over Anika Wells alleged death threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/man-arrested-over-anika-wells-alleged-death-threats/106138216</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c75251c7df71bd19c42225bcf48a770</guid></item><item><title>Bunbury masseur Anthony Brain guilty of sexually assaulting clients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/anthony-brain-guilty-sexually-assaulting-massage-clients/105877236</link><description>A WA masseur who described himself as a nudist and provided "internal" massages without consent is found guilty of multiple sex charges after a trial that ran for more than two months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e565f667d28927f6c1fddffcd4f3027</guid></item><item><title>Horse owners urged to vaccinate animals after bat tests positive to Hendra virus in the NT</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/hendra-virus-found-in-the-northern-territory-darwin-bat/106135238</link><description>Horse owners in the Northern Territory are being encouraged to vaccinate their animals after a bat tested positive for Hendra virus, in the territory's first confirmed case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47cf55f810d41349e77a2a2323137bb2</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's historic treaty formally commences with cultural celebration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/victorias-historic-treaty-formally-begins/106137848</link><description>Victoria's statewide treaty has officially launched with a day of cultural celebrations in Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9af5d95067bab0db07b1bdad72cf6ac</guid></item><item><title>Americans sceptical of Trump on Epstein, as poll finds just 23pc approve of how he's handled crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/brk-polling-on-trump-handling-epstein-files/106138506</link><description>Most Americans believe Trump's administration is covering up Epstein information, with 62 per cent believing the government is hiding information about Epstein's death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18cc07d2d9e4c3f207ce4eb84ac7f679</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan Nobel laureate María Corina Machado says she's aiming for peaceful transition after Maduro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/maria-corina-machado-says-maduro-will-leave-power/106138770</link><description>Nobel laureate María Corina Machado says she's focused on achieving a peaceful transition of power, adding that she's confident the majority of Venezuela's armed forces and police will follow orders from a duly elected government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a7110091a7e4b0f6a72aa8ff86473ac</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump fails to secure ceasefire between Thailand and Cambodia as border conflict continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/trump-call-fails-to-secure-peace-between-thailand-and-cambodia/106138772</link><description>The US president spoke with his Thai counterpart on Friday after indicating he would intervene to reinstate peace between the neighbouring countries, who are attacking each other at the border.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce98813723ed159e7eb490bc6defb7e7</guid></item><item><title>Aged care reforms leave elderly Australians and their loved ones in the lurch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/aged-care-package-reform-worse-off-confusion-despair-waitlist/106136364</link><description>The reforms have unleashed a wave of confusion and despair amongst hundreds of thousands of elderly Australians, from those wanting care to those who already have it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bccf44fd0309fdda714dc96ed3d5cde5</guid></item><item><title>Trump's quietly released national security document didn't escape Europe's attention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/donald-trump-foreign-policy-national-security-strategy-europe/106136354</link><description>When the White House quietly released its national security strategy late one night last week, it instead seemed to get lost in other news. Except, perhaps, in Europe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a638ba1f7a2b1556fc4a3782ee5651f1</guid></item><item><title>How a grieving mother's letter helped Australia's world-first social media ban come into being</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/how-australia-developed-social-media-ban-under-16s/106137700</link><description>Key players including Anthony Albanese, Peter Dutton, Peter Malinauskas and Julie Inman-Grant tell the inside story of how an unprecedented ban came to be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a518d11646c795b19b3f686350ae927</guid></item><item><title>Battery subsidy scheme set for 'urgent' overhaul as costs run out of control</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/battery-subsidy-scheme-faces-urgent-overhaul-as-costs-spiral/106138464</link><description>Federal Energy Minister Chris Bowen announces big changes to the government's battery subsidy scheme amid claims most of its $2.3 billion budget has been spent in just six months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddcb2c850af156986007371f07ab8125</guid></item><item><title>Warner Bros Discovery battle draws in billionaires, celebrities and Trump's son-in-law</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/warner-bros-discovery-paramount-skydance-netflix-battle/106126968</link><description>The dramatic escalation in the fight for Warner Bros is one of the biggest in recent corporate memory, drawing an unlikely cast of celebrities and business figures including Jared Kushner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1412d0a2b8f61f8e6f279b4a1e8d252c</guid></item><item><title>When can politicians put sport or family trips on the 'company card'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/when-can-sport-be-charged-to-taxpayers/106128390</link><description>A spotlight on sports minister Anika Wells prompts fresh scrutiny of the rules about the expenses politicians can claim, including to attend big-ticket sporting events and concerts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fe77984fac9fd83754193d222751701</guid></item><item><title>Partygoers using walking sticks after ketamine, drug use at music festivals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/partygoers-using-walking-sticks-after-drug-use/106125022</link><description>Australian partygoers are using walking aids to support their ketamine habit at music festivals across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">261b99de3f1a68de6536bd5e8840d45b</guid></item><item><title>Best books of 2025, by Hannah Kent, Arundhati Roy, Charlotte McConaghy and more</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/best-books-2025-hannah-kent-arundhati-roy-charlotte-mcconaghy/106131106</link><description>An exciting Australian debut, a bevvy of award-winning literary fiction and more than one heart-wrenching memoir are among our critics' favourite reads of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7a47e37b2c20cf9e65c12b0b5f5610b</guid></item><item><title>Matildas midfielder Tameka Yallop requires surgery, all but ruling her out of home AFC Asian Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/matildas-midfielder-tameka-yallop-out-of-asian-cup/106138960</link><description>Matildas veteran Tameka Yallop will require surgery on a serious hamstring injury, all but ending her hopes of playing at the Women's Asian Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9891e03aaac924ec2a7ebb8aedf1419e</guid></item><item><title>50 years ago, Patti Smith’s Horses fused poetry and punk, rewriting rock's rule book</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/patti-smith-horses-50-years-anniversary-punk-poetry-rock-classic/106125110</link><description>The power and importance of Horses, the seminal debut of punk-poet Patti Smith, still lingers five decades after its release.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb54679b32daf54876ce47e32191e9fa</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 13: Box-office hit Sense and Sensibility hits US cinemas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/sense-and-sensibility-released-in-us-cinemas-30-years-ago-today/106127910</link><description>Sense and Sensibility was marketed "chick flick". But this 90s re-imagining of Sense and Sensibility starring British powerhouse Emma Thompson was more than just a bubbly romance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d6d813b6850c55992c00eb46f6b7b0c</guid></item><item><title>From devastation to wonder as Kangaroo Island bushfires lead to cave discoveries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/more-than-150-caves-discovered-in-ki-after-devastating-bushfires/106095942</link><description>It was an adventure into the unknown. From the surface all that could be seen was a small opening. The ABC has been given exclusive access to newly-discovered caves on South Australia's Kangaroo Island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc388cc62031e7ced86dc36fdeb23d3e</guid></item><item><title>Meet the fleet: The helicopters and planes protecting you this bushfire season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/victoria-firefighting-air-fleet-helicopters-aircraft-planes-fire/106130296</link><description>They are an eclectic mix but this diverse fleet of helicopters, water bombers and planes is ready to protect south-eastern Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd08d6e255b4c21288305aa9323d9bbc</guid></item><item><title>West Gate Tunnel project is set to open after delays and cost blow outs pushed onto road users</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/west-gate-tunnel-set-to-open-after-delays-and-cost-blowouts/106137268</link><description>The long-awaited West Gate Tunnel project will open on Sunday, with Labor hoping it's enough to win voters back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf91745cc022d88d7e89031bbf02b1bc</guid></item><item><title>Koolewong resident wins stand-off with insurer Budget Direct over bushfire claim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/bushfire-insurance-claim-rejection-koolewong/106134988</link><description>Gordon Plath thought he was one of the lucky ones when he escaped a bushfire that swept through Koolewong on the New South Wales Central Coast last weekend — but then he found himself in a stand-off with his insurer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c4844facdf469f8e193eeffe0ca0d0f</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous community feels 'forgotten' in nation's capital after two decades of Labor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/aboriginal-canberrans-feel-forgotten-failure-close-the-gap/106112204</link><description>After 24 years of Labor government, First Nations people in Australia's capital are frustrated and exhausted by a lack of meaningful progress to close the gap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4500ab690127d5eece816a53bb22af25</guid></item><item><title>Illicit vaping, cigarette raids create game of 'whack-a-mole' but health campaign urges patience</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/illicit-vaping-cigarette-raids-create-game-of-whack-a-mole/106120236</link><description>Despite a record $15.7 million nicotine seizure, experts say Australia's multi-billion-dollar illicit tobacco and vape market continues to thrive, exposing the limits of raids and crackdowns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26c5c6e9b33a21cf459c67553f43b018</guid></item><item><title>Changes to Queensland's political donation laws could increase corruption risks, experts say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/queensland-political-donations-property-developers/106135566</link><description>A ban on political donations by developers, introduced by the former Qld Labor Government, will be lifted by the LNP.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d622effc6640efe205ef4fafbe6ecae8</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill community fundraises for mental health in wake of tragic loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/mental-health-fundraiser-in-memory-of-alice-wilkinson/106032394</link><description>Alice Wilkinson loved music and was the life of the party. Her death has prompted her family to help others who might be struggling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9948ad96b75034e1c1748aa31157b822</guid></item><item><title>Australia's social media ban reminds us of the power of a loving boundary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/social-media-ban-teens-roblox-son-boundary-safety/106131786</link><description>This is where we parents should remind ourselves of the power of the loving boundary: not to bind and constrain, but to properly demonstrate that we hold our kids and their safety in our mind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b63e161e0d7b0716938ae584d3056917</guid></item><item><title>New generations take to bird watching</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/bird-watching-for-everyone/106138172</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be3cd15eb3f374029864ad60e0572480</guid></item><item><title>Gen Z drawn to bird watching after growing up on Pokemon GO</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/gen-z-drawn-to-bird-watching-after-growing-up-on-pokemon-go/106136816</link><description>Raised on Pokemon GO, generation Z is finding the hobby of birding just the ticket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57a5e8f5b4102873e2ea387eb135bd1c</guid></item><item><title>Matcha's popularity a boon for Japanese farmers but counterfeits a problem</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/counterfeit-matcha-is-flooding-the-market-to-meet-demand/106115334</link><description>As Japanese matcha producers struggle with the surge in demand, the industry is facing another problem — counterfeit matcha.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b338d270f01bd62218b06c26a1978a6</guid></item><item><title>Grassroots First Nations organisation flags concern for at-risk youth under social media ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/nt-social-media-ban-indigenous-teens-darwin-aunties-place/106133746</link><description>Social media can help at-risk youth connect with support services, so what impact will the federal government's under-16s ban have on those community hubs?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">090b6a9b3a1c75a2d5531cc8512af193</guid></item><item><title>Swimming's newest revolution is here, as Australia vs The World lights up The Valley Pool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/australia-vs-the-world-the-valley-pool/106139000</link><description>Swimming stepped out of its tried and trusted format in a novelty, multi-event competition in Brisbane on Friday night. And judging by the response, it was an enormous success.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91ddf945b27cbfcf23ec214074e940c2</guid></item><item><title>King Charles provides an update on his cancer treatment.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/king-charles-provide-update-on-his-cancer-treatment-/106139150</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">061ed64074dbb78ce57cac813f7f596a</guid></item><item><title>Tim Tszyu camp accused of sabotaging opponent Anthony Velazquez ahead of do-or-die Sydney fight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/tim-tszyu-camp-accused-of-sabotaging-opponent-anthony-velazquez/106139156</link><description>The stage is set for Tim Tszyu's make-or-break showdown against Anthony Velazquez, with the Australian superstar's team accused of sabotage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4139be0c5966454c571deb4aab5a71a9</guid></item><item><title>Record gold prices drive investment in exploration across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/record-gold-prices-drive-investment-in-exploration-australia/106121424</link><description>The money being spent on drilling for gold has increased 45 per cent in the past 12 months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d69ff758de9fcfef8c74baabbe66e46</guid></item><item><title>Migrant workers raise concerns at modern slavery inquiry in Coffs Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/modern-slavery-migrant-hearings-in-nsw/106130342</link><description>Witnesses have told an inquiry into modern slavery that migrant workers are being exploited in the nation's blueberry capital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad5a183a10a9cc947ab7eba5cea3574c</guid></item><item><title>What is the EU's 'reparation loan' plan for Ukraine using Russian funds?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/what-is-the-eu-reparation-loan-plan-for-ukraine/106138652</link><description>Its proposed "reparations loan" for Ukraine would see frozen Russian assets used to prop up Kyiv's ailing economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e79db11d885e0b6d4a5f0e77b2142c4f</guid></item><item><title>Public housing residents in Roebourne swelter through heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/public-housing-residents-in-roebourne-swelter-through-heatwave/106129428</link><description>WA's Pilbara has already endured a seven-day heatwave this month, but many in the town of Roebourne have little more than a hose and wet sheets to keep them cool as temperatures top 45 degrees Celsius.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd37452858bfa7de9710ef2891b41309</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire survivor calls for better emergency planning in the suburbs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/how-to-prepare-for-summer-bushfire-season-perth-wa/106120466</link><description>After a fast-moving bushfire reached the front door of her home in 2023, Kay Douglas is now better prepared in case it happens again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81bd001f98f7b1e53f812e5c94b138b1</guid></item><item><title>Underwater microphone records humpback whale sounds off NSW south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/underwater-microphone-records-humpback-whale-sounds/106129670</link><description>Underwater microphones off the NSW south coast capture consistent humpback whale sounds throughout the 2024 migration season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cc82218726405dc2f124c6cb8f59615</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne lawyer Dean Hadjina sentenced to prison for stealing from grieving widow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/melbourne-lawyer-dean-hadjina-prison-sentence-stealing-widow/106139262</link><description>Dean Hadjina is sentenced to prison for stealing $482,154 from a vulnerable widow who spoke little English as she sought compensation payouts after her husband's workplace death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b4d1bb774295f2d85cb6eceb1c2956</guid></item><item><title>18-year-old man in critical condition after Gold Coast assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/qld-serious-assault-gold-coast/106139282</link><description>An 18-year-old man is in hospital in a critical condition after being assaulted on the Gold Coast on Friday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c56049f475d1eb150165a6fdc757cdfa</guid></item><item><title>Croc wrangler Matt Wright's prison sentence a stark warning after years-long court saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/matt-wright-sentencing-fallout-for-helicopter-industry/106136470</link><description>Crocodile wrangler Matt Wright built a television and tourism empire in the Northern Territory, but that's all come crashing down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68ab8e1dd2c64631e9d79719aeb78b86</guid></item><item><title>Federal police release nine images to help identify online child sex abuse victims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/afp-releases-images-to-identify-child-sex-abuse-victims/106139222</link><description>These photographs might look like everyday objects, but the AFP-led Australian Centre to Counter Child Exploitation (ACCCE) believe they could help identify victims of online child sexual exploitation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2c17177c4b6be426a3ba95050bff1ff</guid></item><item><title>Perth's queer nightclub, Connections, celebrates 50 years of dancing and difference</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/perth-queer-nightclub-connections-celebrates-50-years/106137800</link><description>Founded in 1975, when homosexuality was still illegal in Western Australia, Connections nightclub has seen waves of social change and kept the party going.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbfccd7dc10d5ba74db21e7a1c43fba5</guid></item><item><title>Google to build undersea cables in Papua New Guinea under Australia defence treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/google-building-undersea-cables-in-png/106139500</link><description>PNG says the measure will provide a key upgrade to its digital backbone and link the north and south of the nation with high-capacity cables.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bdcdd335abbb5327aeebb352b5456bf</guid></item><item><title>Government-formed agency recommends against NSW coal industry expansion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/independent-agency-recommends-against-nsw-coal-expansion/106139270</link><description>Coal mining extensions and expansions will continue, the New South Wales premier says, despite a government-appointed agency finding further approvals were not consistent with emissions targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9daf0baa045cb5bb4ef13da04acdb8b6</guid></item><item><title>The ice hockey rink at the Milan-Cortina Winter Olympic Games is too small. The NHL is not happy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/winter-olympics-ice-hockey-rink-too-small-nhl/106139152</link><description>Ice hockey players from the NHL are due to compete in the Winter Olympics tournament for the first time in 12 years at Milan-Cortina. But the league is holding its breath over a rink that has is smaller than expected — and isn't even complete yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2192df130742278e9adc04d1853847e</guid></item><item><title>Australian fans among most active in searching for FIFA World Cup tickets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/australian-fans-search-for-fifa-world-cup-tickets/106139824</link><description>Australia are among the countries with the most ticket requests for next year's World Cup, which is bound to please Socceroos coach Tony Popovic and his team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">316d9995db7dddc4dbd80b9b4e357dbc</guid></item><item><title>What you should know about 'Bali belly' and how to avoid it before it ruins your holiday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/what-do-you-need-to-know-about-bali-belly-and-how-to-avoid-it/106133990</link><description>Every year about 1.5 million Australians travel to Bali. Chances are either you or someone you know has caught a stomach bug after travelling to the popular Indonesian destination. So what can you do to avoid it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e5d649d03f0cad3ea98b4b637b0d8ae</guid></item><item><title>Children 'traumatised' as wheel flies off speedway car into crowd at Avalon Raceway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/fireball-derby-racecar-wheel-hits-spectators/106139478</link><description>Race spectators were metres away from a flying wheel that tore through a fence after detaching from a sprint car at the Fireball Derby last night near Geelong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94755ec2877c2480598a57d57ec79593</guid></item><item><title>Desert Fireball Network students find fist-sized meteorite in outback WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/desert-fireball-network-students-find-meteorite-outback-wa/106139512</link><description>PhD students from Curtin University have found a 300-gram meteorite after a five-day search in remote bushland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a00682db69e225e1eeff0b8b54a44fd</guid></item><item><title>United Nations delegation warns of Australia's treatment of prisoners, detainees and breach in human rights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/united-nations-warn-australia-prison-detention-human-rights/106136950</link><description>A delegation of United Nations inspectors have raised the alarm about Australia's detention facilities and a breach of human rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">075a06b44f92126c2bd0015a8827c776</guid></item><item><title>Teenage skier Indra Brown claims maiden FIS Freestyle halfpipe World Cup medal in Secret Garden</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/indra-brown-wins-world-cup-freeski-halfpipe-bronze/106139934</link><description>Indra Brown has been on the radar of Australian snow sport aficionados for a number of years and, in her first ever World Cup event, she has secured a stunning bronze medal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1009bde3fc565f54cdccf459c7b4edf</guid></item><item><title>Severe heatwave cancels event, closes popular abalone fishing spot as season begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/severe-heatwave-as-wa-abalone-season-begins/106139888</link><description>Perth is in the grip of its hottest spell so far this summer, forcing the closure of a popular tourist attraction as abalone fishing season got underway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e379757217715ba153713c1409b032d</guid></item><item><title>Jailed Myanmar leader Aung San Suu Kyi's supporters rally in Sydney to protest junta elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/aung-san-suu-kyi-supporters-rally-sydney-myanmar-junta-election/106139074</link><description>Aung San Suu Kyi's son leads a rally of supporters in Sydney as part of global demonstrations trying to increase international pressure on Myanmar's ruling military junta.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7882d7a6e0844c1867f57f204dfb409d</guid></item><item><title>Roger Rasheed slams 'battle of the sexes' tennis clash between Nick Kyrgios and Aryna Sabalenka</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/roger-rasheed-nick-kyrgios-aryna-sabalenk-battle-of-the-sexes/106140068</link><description>High-profile Australian tennis coach Roger Rasheed has questioned the value of the upcoming "battle of the sexes"-style exhibition match between Nick Kyrgios and Aryna Sabalenka.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44c26b0beab1855f4660c042d1252f87</guid></item><item><title>China Coast Guard fires water cannon at Philippine fishing vessels in South China Sea, Manila says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/south-china-sea-chinese-water-cannon-philippine-coast-guard/106140098</link><description>Manila's coastguard says nearly two dozen Philippine fishing boats near Sabina Shoal were targeted with water cannon and blocking manoeuvres on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bb328352925a9ae0fcc01bbc0e0e037</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja open to middle order role for third Ashes Test in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/khawaja-open-to-middle-order-ashes-2025/106140150</link><description>Australia batter Usman Khawaja is feeling 100 per cent fit and is open to a return to the middle order for the third Ashes Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de5665c9e9bc10d34d2ac7d2c9d8c0c7</guid></item><item><title>Lizelle Lee stars as Hobart Hurricanes claim maiden WBBL title</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/hurricanes-claim-maiden-wbbl-title/106140180</link><description>Hurricanes opener Lizelle Lee hits an unbeaten 77 as her side claims its first WBBL title with a dominant eight-wicket win over the Scorchers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdfc4baf4edce297b59ca622e0b895a6</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 14: Journalist throws shoes at George W Bush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/journalist-throws-shoe-iraq-george-w-bush/106124532</link><description>It has been 17 years since Iraqi journalist Muntadhar al-Zaidi hurled his shoes at then-United States president George W Bush at a press conference in Baghdad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e48474660f00ee3d28fb7efbb41771d5</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: It's the season of giving so I'm gifting you a chance at redemption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/106130212</link><description>Your track record doesn't leave me hopeful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">693aef896cb1373b315facefcd53f061</guid></item><item><title>'I was tricked': African athlete lured to Russia for work, ends up on front lines of Ukraine war</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/athlete-says-russia-lured-him-for-work-then-sent-him-to-war/106122770</link><description>Vladimir Putin says Russia has "no need" to recruit foreign fighters to bolster its invasion of Ukraine, but inside this prisoner of war camp, people have a very different story.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0f54e990b1e6ae1e6cd660235034b18</guid></item><item><title>Sanction-skirting 'shadow fleets' in Trump's sights. Here's how they work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/what-are-shadow-fleets/106137346</link><description>Tensions between the US and Venezuela are soaring after American forces seized an oil tanker in the Caribbean Sea. So why is US President Donald Trump targeting so-called "shadow fleets"?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28967e6fabbd1b6edbe8e8daa824b124</guid></item><item><title>How Benjamin Netanyahu's corruption trial became a struggle for Israel itself</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/israel-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-corruption-trial-and-deep-state/106124242</link><description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's backers view his corruption trial as a witch hunt — but his detractors argue it is the system finally catching up to a ruthless political operative who is prepared to do anything to hold on to power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">868ab4d48d09c7dddeca77bf4f254be5</guid></item><item><title>Demerit point return scheme to be made permanent in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/nsw-demerit-point-return-program-to-be-made-permanent/106139942</link><description>Since the trial to return demerit points began almost two years ago, more than 1.7 million licence holders have benefited from their safe driving.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c9e80d6336ddf3b36d69a57b53d362e</guid></item><item><title>Two US troops killed in Syria ambush along with one American civilian</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/us-service-members-killed-in-syria/106140654</link><description>Two US service members and one American civilian are killed in an ambush in central Syria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63bd2995922c21f9ffbaed628e6b75e2</guid></item><item><title>After tragedies and rescues, Tasmanian bushwalkers urged to 'be prepared' for all conditions this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/tasmania-cradle-mountain-rescues-hiking-prep-for-summer/106028884</link><description>It has been a busy year for search and rescue operations in the Tasmanian high country. Authorities say a concerning number of visitors to the state's famous national parks are ill-prepared for the fickle weather — even during summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">366e2bd207b3ac5db65be6ca27b9bd08</guid></item><item><title>Iron deficiency is a challenge for many female athletes, like Super Netball's Zara Walters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/zara-walters-victorian-institute-of-sport-iron-deficiency/106108280</link><description>Zara Walters felt tired, dizzy and unable to recover from training sessions — then she found out she was low in iron. It's a condition that often goes undiagnosed, especially in female athletes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ee03bad452a9f38b43e0a5a4d93185d</guid></item><item><title>An Australian warplane disappeared 82 years ago. Now, it's been found</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/missing-raaf-ww2-fighters-found-plane-wreckage-png-rainforest/106126682</link><description>After more than eight decades, James Burrowes had just about given up hope of ever knowing what truly happened to his uncle Tom, an Air Force crew member who disappeared in World War II.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">578ae613c2db9b6869f3e2c69b2972ab</guid></item><item><title>Gippsland teenager Ethan Monck celebrates first job after a lifetime battling cancer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/ethan-monck-gets-his-first-job-fast-food-chain-mcdonalds/106001356</link><description>Ethan Monck's health problems began the day he was born. Now aged 17, he's celebrating after starting his first job and the freedom it gives him to pursue his hobbies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d8cd975bcb08a3e9ad54c598b450043</guid></item><item><title>Bree Walker seals IBSF World Cup monobob gold in Lillehammer, Josie Baff, Adam Lambert and 16yo Ally Hickman claim snowboard bronzes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/bree-walker-wins-monobob-gold-in-lillehammer/106140660</link><description>Bree Walker's superb sliding season continues with a third World Cup victory in a row on the Lillehammer sliding track in Norway, putting her into second place in the overall IBSF standings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81178ae79fe9afbcdb4132b5077f5a4c</guid></item><item><title>Earthquake due 'in foreseeable future' after 70 years of Adelaide tremors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/is-adelaide-due-for-another-big-earthquake/106126974</link><description>Adelaide sits on the most active seismic zone in Australia and has more than its fair share of tremors below magnitude-4, but it's been 71 years since it was rocked by a serious earthquake. Now, it's a matter of if, not when, it gets another one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">547eb51b5fce33d426720340f3261fa1</guid></item><item><title>The Kaurna cultural program inspiring students in Adelaide's south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/sa-students-find-connection-through-kaurna-program/106136626</link><description>Kanyanyapilla means "place of many eagles", and it's where Indigenous students in Adelaide are coming to connect with Kaurna culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2cc1db9b6981d4c5f9aed4bf8c5c018</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Sweeney transformed herself to play Christy Martin in a biopic as Hollywood struggles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/how-sydney-sweeney-transformed-herself-to-play-a-boxer/106132482</link><description>Sydney Sweeney changed a lot about herself to play Christy Martin in a biopic about the boxer. She says it was a role she had to take.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51771885fbf1fdd5558fa08cca2331b1</guid></item><item><title>Lionel Messi's India tour begins in chaos, seats ripped out in Kolkata</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/lionel-messi-india-tour-chaos-seats-ripped-out/106140692</link><description>Indian football fans ripped up seats and invaded the pitch in Kolkata as Lionel Messi's first appearance in India took a chaotic and dangerous turn.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6942144dbdac54fd6b55f6ac85693f8</guid></item><item><title>Medical groups push for consequences for freebirth 'birthkeepers' posing as medical professionals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/inside-the-freebirth-birthkeeper-movement/106137044</link><description>A number of recent deaths linked to freebirths — where a pregnant woman chooses to give birth with no registered medical professional present — is prompting health groups to speak out about rising levels of misinformation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16095bdb783bfd370331e86386a64607</guid></item><item><title>Israel says Hamas commander Raed Saed was among five killed in Gaza City attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/israel-kills-senior-hamas-commander/106140722</link><description>It was the highest-profile assassination of a senior Hamas figure since a Gaza ceasefire deal came into effect in October.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9511c3513952beac1daba85cc2926e6</guid></item><item><title>Alpha Bakery making famous pies again with family support after dementia diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/alpha-bakery-making-pies-again-family-supports-brother-dementia/106050182</link><description>Christopher Tilse has worked from dawn to dusk in a bakery most of his life. Dementia made that a challenge, but thanks to family support, he is still baking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef9efe3534ff9ae6f4fdc06349c272fd</guid></item><item><title>Three quarters of Canberra's suburbs see reduction in tree canopy despite government's 2045 goal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/decline-tree-coverage-bush-capital-canberra/106139714</link><description>It's called the 'bush capital', but three quarters of Canberra's suburbs have recorded a decline in tree coverage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a1e07b3043c41eef341fae603953e04</guid></item><item><title>UK police won't probe claim former prince Andrew asked bodyguard to investigate Virginia Roberts Giuffre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/uk-police-wont-probe-andrew-claim/106140752</link><description>London's police force says it will not take further action over claims that former prince Andrew asked his protection officer to carry out checks on Virginia Roberts Giuffre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">804859bb33197ef5054bd889c0dbd03a</guid></item><item><title>Two-thirds of women escaping violence in Broome cannot access help</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/hundreds-turned-away-from-broome-domestic-violence-refuge/106057354</link><description>In a region with Western Australia's highest rates of family and domestic violence, a Kimberley service provider says it can only help one-third of women who need it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">337b73f0f8756ae11e894af3cf8dbae2</guid></item><item><title>Pulp Fiction, The Mask actor Peter Greene dies aged 60</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/pulp-fiction-the-mask-actor-peter-greene-dies-aged-60/106140816</link><description>Peter Greene, a character actor best known for his role as the iconic villain, Zed in Pulp Fiction, has died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36ad8509e456fcf6d30148f22f003c23</guid></item><item><title>Brown University shooting in US leaves two students dead and nine injured</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/active-shooter-brown-university/106140822</link><description>Police detain a "person of interest" in connection with the Brown University shooting that left two students dead and another nine people wounded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2eefee872256923a130ecd2adf6c1ab</guid></item><item><title>Conservationist uses invasive fox fur to make ethical clothing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/conservationist-clothing-maker-turns-fox-pelts-to-coats/106049382</link><description>In six months, Emma Sinclair went from not knowing how to sew to launching her own fashion label based around fox fur.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be15a03e36974b98c27cb9abdac073ef</guid></item><item><title>Teenager dies after falling from cliff while taking photographs at Moffat Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/moffat-beach-death-teenager/106140832</link><description>Emergency services were called about 6:40pm following reports a teenager had fallen from a cliff.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdda3328cdcdf7147a0a4a0af2391f83</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after car allegedly hits pedestrians in Maroochydore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/man-in-custody-maroochydore-hit-and-run/106140854</link><description>Police say a vehicle struck a group of pedestrians on Saturday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77c0691b55acebc8671bd396734da9a8</guid></item><item><title>Two students killed, nine injured in shooting at Brown University — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/brown-university-active-shooting-live-blog/106140862</link><description>Two students have been killed and nine other people have been injured after a gunman entered an engineering building during final exams at Brown University in the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a993b5dc81abdc518e58657733134887</guid></item><item><title>Attorney-General Michelle Rowland to repay family travel expenses after independent review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/michelle-rowland-to-repay-expenses-claim/106140868</link><description>Attorney-General Michelle Rowland is told to repay a portion of travel expenses she claimed for a 2023 family trip to Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f97d3490b9622ca1c57d638e075a94ba</guid></item><item><title>There was a strong police presence after the mass shooting at Brown University.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/strong-police-presence-after-mass-shooting-at-brown-university/106140892</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">243703d6d861a8c4e4a0449c8a982aa9</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous Rap</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/indigenous-rap/106132094</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74433913880de1812460ededc410f8d7</guid></item><item><title>Budding musicians on NSW far south coast create songs about First Nations culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/first-nations-musicians-mentored-by-band-to-create-songs/106113948</link><description>With sounds recorded in a makeshift studio, this group of high school students produced music about First Nations culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d20d7fec8bae421ad705bc5fc8033d39</guid></item><item><title>The Providence mayor gives an update on the mass shooting at Brown University.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/providence-mayor-grieves-mass-shooting-at-brown-university/106140972</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a74da4f5ab1a69999a11b374da617f9</guid></item><item><title>Searching for treasure in the Aussie bush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/searching-for-treasure-in-the-aussie-bush/106109214</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca8167284f0f87b8b3d3de1ba0cc8a2b</guid></item><item><title>Orchid enthusiasts call for greater protection for native species facing habitat threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/new-orchids-discovered-habitat-threat-mount-wedge/106072786</link><description>Two centuries after orchids were first documented in South Australia, photographers are still discovering new plants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d238655dc5d75962a61dc09df9c50031</guid></item><item><title>Ashleigh Gentle shares 'incredibly isolating' miscarriage news before competing in T100 Qatar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/ashleigh-gentle-t100-qatar-miscarriage/106140914</link><description>Australian triathlete Ashleigh Gentle reveals she suffered a miscarriage just days before competing in the season-ending T100 event in Qatar, earning significant praise for her bravery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f78297feb0f2276cd51a9cfa1f4a5b3c</guid></item><item><title>School traffic wardens in WA call for body-worn cameras amid escalating abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/school-traffic-wardens-abused-in-wa/106132436</link><description>School traffic wardens are retiring because of escalating levels of physical and verbal abuse by passing motorists. They say their employer, WA Police, is not providing enough support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccaa7ea3efea78ea35722ca1c89f1527</guid></item><item><title>Households without power after Russian attack on Ukraine's power grid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/russian-attack-ukraine-power-grid/106141006</link><description>Five people were left wounded from the attack that Volodymyr Zelenskyy said consisted of more than 450 drones and 30 missiles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afcae4c642b6e6aeab8e1c46ac60f297</guid></item><item><title>$5 Coffee Club charity raises money and spirits at Laurieton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/coffee-catch-ups-promote-social-connection/106119808</link><description>Graham Lee is behind a charity raising thousands of dollars through people sacrificing one takeaway coffee a week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91d36d970ba41481de5ec8c1485a7610</guid></item><item><title>Brett Lee backs current Australian bowling attack as greatest ever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/brett-lee-backs-current-australian-bowling-attack-as-greatest/106141014</link><description>Brett Lee ranks Australia's bowling attack as better than the one he was part of, which featured the likes of Glenn McGrath and Shane Warne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6e1aa66b31fbbd1ea5a920c9345b872</guid></item><item><title>A bird's eye view of the Brown University shooting crime scene.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/an-bird-s-eye-view-of-brown-university-shooting-crime-scene-/106141092</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c559aed998dc5b6c8d8382708d6d5482</guid></item><item><title>Books reflecting remote Indigenous lifestyles and culture 'key' to students' reading success</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/improving-indigenous-students-reading-skills-with-relevant-books/106056534</link><description>An educator says books that reflect remote Indigenous cultures and lifestyles are "the key to success" in improving reading outcomes for First Nations students.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7add03b17810e2b90d8dc3cd234850c0</guid></item><item><title>Virtual fencing is now legal in NSW. This is what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/virtual-fencing-legalised-nsw/106128536</link><description>NSW farmers have been given the green light to use virtual fencing, providing an option over traditional posts and wires. Here is how it works.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e9f8e8bdd44e4f16106cd6fd01eb862</guid></item><item><title>Coles and Woolworths hit back at government's price gouging ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/coles-woolworths-hit-back-at-price-gouging-ban/106141094</link><description>Lower grocery bills are being promised within this new ban on price gouging, but giant retailers say they are the ones feeling the pinch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b22d07967f57eba637ea6d9f424f96a9</guid></item><item><title>I’m heading overseas. Do I really need travel vaccines?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/i-m-heading-overseas-do-i-really-need-travel-vaccines-/106139094</link><description>Australia is in its busiest month for short-term overseas travel. And there are so many things to consider when planning your trip. Unfortunately, it's easy to overlook the importance of pre-travel vaccinations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3487138a302c170a64988aa991484502</guid></item><item><title>Northern Territory Stolen Generations survivor William Tilmouth wins top honour at 2025 Human Rights Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/nt-stolen-generations-survivor-wins-top-2025-human-rights-awards/106137354</link><description>The Northern Territory has won big at this year's Australian Human Rights Awards, winning three out of the five categories including the top honour which was awarded to Arrernte man, William Tilmouth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d10b238aedc792761dd5a094e9021d1f</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania Police to formally join renewed search for missing Belgian tourist Celine Cremer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/tasmania-police-to-join-celine-cremer-search/106141072</link><description>Tasmania Police says it will formally join the independent search for missing Belgian woman Celine Cremer, after her mobile phone was found by a private search party on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dac486f0c443f93340ee046205bd222</guid></item><item><title>Up to 30 shots fired at a home in Guildford West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/up-to-30-shots-fired-at-a-home-in-guildford-west/106141204</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7faec1d85f7e25b17c3ac6fee6c2c720</guid></item><item><title>Police condemn 'outrageous' Guildford West shooting as vision shows 30 bullets fired into home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/hunt-street-guildford-shooting-video/106141186</link><description>The vision shows the moment a gunman sprayed an underworld associate's home with up to 30 rounds while two women and a child were inside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e1081f69550a94e14b27afd0d282eed</guid></item><item><title>Video of person of interest in Brown University shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/video-of-person-of-interest-in-brown-university-shooting/106141312</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd5a94ee16f783520e8f503ad851fa05</guid></item><item><title>'It's cooked': Big Brother contestant quit so she could afford the dentist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/abiola-big-brother-prize-money-dentist/106135150</link><description>Data obtained by the ABC shows people are waiting months, if not years, for dental care in every Australian state and territory due to the cost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">062c6c7e609df623f810eb7822b805f4</guid></item><item><title>Australians open to dealing with AI on a Triple Zero emergency call, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/triple-zero-000-call-service-needs-ai-tech-upgrade-survey-finds/106120258</link><description>Could artificial intelligence speed up emergency responses by receiving a caller's video or smartwatch data and capturing words like "knife" and "collision"? Most people think so and welcome the technology's potential, a survey finds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9bee4df8d38455408afb5df240c0fcf</guid></item><item><title>WA government to roll out six more high-tech cameras to capture driver bad behaviour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/wa-road-safety-cameras-government-announcement/106141226</link><description>The road safety cameras will be installed across the state and include six new high-tech devices to capture driver bad behaviour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25ece4270b417c5c7fbdb8d356c201fd</guid></item><item><title>Researchers call for water safety to be part of English education for migrants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/call-for-water-safety-to-be-incorporated-into-english-learning/106119112</link><description>As the country heads into the summer holidays, experts are again warning Australians to be aware of swim safety at beaches, pools and other waterways.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4390c5ccee6eff142d214ab84533e218</guid></item><item><title>Brendon McCullum vows against 'knee-jerk reactions' for third Ashes Test in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/mccullum-kneejerk-reactions-ashes-test-adelaide/106141442</link><description>England coach Brendon McCullum confirms his side's batting line-up will be unchanged for its must-win third Ashes Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6b4eae7c4f8a17c2ac9e7248c34c94d</guid></item><item><title>Short-form videos could be harming young minds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/how-short-form-videos-could-be-harming-young-minds/106139042</link><description>Online short-form video has shifted from a light distraction to a constant backdrop in many children's lives. But they were never built with children in mind, although many children use them daily.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0673a03803caca19c88a5d008e4686de</guid></item><item><title>Matt Wright's character references from famous singer, high-powered business person, media heavyweight released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/matt-wright-character-references-lee-kernaghan-mick-burns-/106141232</link><description>Country music star Lee Kernaghan, powerful business person Mick Burns, traditional owner Brian Tipungwuti and media heavyweight Nick Fordham all provided character references for celebrity crocodile wrangler Matt Wright ahead of his sentencing, court documents show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">278dc76daef3e70967b88f3de9193549</guid></item><item><title>At least 12 people dead as Bondi Beach attack declared act of terrorism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/shooter-at-nsw-bondi-beach-sydney-eastern-suburbs/106141572</link><description>At least 12 people, including one shooter, have been killed in an attack at Sydney's Bondi Beach on Sunday evening, NSW Police have confirmed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c50a2046c5fb607b28383e9daec01365</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting: 12 people confirmed dead and several injured in terrorist attack on Jewish community event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/bondi-beach-shooting-terrorist-attack-12-dead/106141580</link><description>Twelve people are confirmed dead and dozens are injured in a terrorist attack on the Chanukah by the Sea celebration at Sydney's Bondi Beach. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f3bc227b08c78d8902dea436fb15458</guid></item><item><title>Sean Tarek Goodwin describes the scene of Bondi Beach shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/sean-tarek-goodwin-describes-the-scene-of-bondi-beach-shooting/106141630</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">879ddfa3ca6e7a9261739b981f4dcfe5</guid></item><item><title>ABC Reporter Digby Werthmuller is at a police cordon at North Bondi.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/police-command-north-bondi/106141642</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e755c51742f8d576e639d894e1b6bf3a</guid></item><item><title>Gunman tackled by member of the public at Bondi Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/gunman-tackled-by-member-of-the-public-at-bondi-beach/106141666</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccc71cef55c177451db89c51abb0d939</guid></item><item><title>Gunmen opening fire at Bondi Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/gunmen-opening-fire-at-bondi-beach/106141686</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a44b2bc491b91dbfb1794ba8e9fc8ffd</guid></item><item><title>Man tackles gunman at Bondi Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/man-tackles-gunman-at-bondi-beach/106141700</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46318f800fa9bcef25b4d4549c358a50</guid></item><item><title>Gunmen on the ground, one detained at Bondi Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/gunmen-on-the-ground-one-detained-at-bondi-beach/106141732</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dc1fb6703b7762f191ef2fa64756fdd</guid></item><item><title>NOLs_BridgeArrestBlurs_1412 (1)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/nols-bridgearrestblurs-1412-1-/106141742</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3919e8eefc5d2e87a25abb56b1161e23</guid></item><item><title>French tourist describes what he witnessed at Bondi Beach.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/tourist-french-bondi-beach/106141752</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0836769ac4df66f77ed2b7025d8d67d2</guid></item><item><title>What we know so far about the Bondi Beach shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/what-we-know-bondi-beach-shooting/106141672</link><description>Twelve people are dead after two gunmen fired dozens of shots into crowds of people at Bondi Beach. Here's what we know so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26901ced8b258ae6960177c46c930cd3</guid></item><item><title>Drone vision shows shooter on a footbridge at Bondi Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/drone-vision-shows-shooter-on-a-footbridge-at-bondi-beach/106141712</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1ffca5036927679cb2fb3416ec1e042</guid></item><item><title>Law enforcement source identifies Bondi gunman as Sydney man Naveed Akram</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/law-enforcement-source-identifies-bondi-gunman-as-naveed-akram/106141750</link><description>A law enforcement official has told the ABC that police have raided one of the alleged gunman's house in Sydney's south-west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c27975b9fb669ae4eaf99f4ad3e6223</guid></item><item><title>Chris Minns calls the Bondi shooting a 'horrifying' and 'evil' terror attack.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/bondi-shooting-chris-minns/106141796</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae972118a83e00b6ef8317441b9cbe67</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting witnesses recall running for their lives as attack unfolded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/nsw-bondi-beach-shooting-witnesses-sydney-attack/106141716</link><description>Bondi Beach has been described as "hell on earth" by witnesses who were at the scene as gunshots rang out just after 6:30pm on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd5b205a5a2a992861d6bfa9c26f664b</guid></item><item><title>Fmr Israeli PM blames Bondi attack on government's lack of 'moral courage'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/fmr-israeli-pm-blames-bondi-attack/106141880</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">093ca8a55e31d2700fe4f56edf08da3c</guid></item><item><title>How the gunmen positioned themselves above Bondi Beach and opened fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/bondi-mass-shooting-/106141652</link><description>Videos and witness accounts from Bondi Beach have been shared widely. This is what they tell us about how the shooting unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95cdd8e99ecd7d8dbc0e73142876c667</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police Commissioner asks for calm following Bondi Beach terror attack.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/bondi-junction-nsw-police-commissioner/106141882</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6747a84526575dd6ea32b3802dd702bd</guid></item><item><title>Moment Bondi shooter tackled and disarmed by man in civilian clothes caught on camera</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/bondi-shooter-tackled-and-disarmed-by-possible-civilian/106141690</link><description>Dramatic footage shows a man, wearing a light blue shirt and black pants, crouching behind a parked vehicle near one of the Bondi Beach gunmen before disarming him during the terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab2602ba86af28c27b8e903ac7a50125</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine drops ambitions to join NATO ahead of peace talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/ukraine-drops-nato-ambitions-ahead-of-peace-talks/106141924</link><description>Ukraine relinquishes its ambition of joining the NATO military alliance in exchange for Western security guarantees as a compromise to end the war with Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24e2902f4acc583e3cebf3bfa496308b</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese condemns Bondi Beach terror attack as 'act of evil antisemitism'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/albanese-political-leaders-respond-to-bondi-beach-terror-attack/106142036</link><description>Anthony Albanese condemns the Bondi beach terror attack as an "act of evil antisemitism" targeting Australia's Jewish community, declaring the nation will never submit to "division, violence or hatred".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cedc87d4ab4b665da5e59ba25a648db</guid></item><item><title>One of the Bondi gunmen shoots at police officer.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-gunman-shoots-at-police-officer-behind-a-car/106141866</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93a3649924ec0a28d0b5115f2c75f36d</guid></item><item><title>Rabbi Eli Schlanger killed in Bondi Beach terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/rabbi-eli-schlanger-killed-in-bondi-attack/106142362</link><description>The rabbi's family has confirmed he was among those killed in the terror attack at Bondi Beach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31bf98870d168fe614efcc9be86af9cf</guid></item><item><title>Australia's medicinal cannabis situation leaves government in a bind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/australia-s-medicinal-cannabis-bind-is-a-political-hot-potato/106140878</link><description>There doesn't seem to be much political mileage for the government to do anything at all — whether that is cracking down and forcing cannabis users back onto the black market or fully legalising the substance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">351d59353e06489323dfd13cb834bafa</guid></item><item><title>Brain research centre The Florey sues executive, allegeing he stole and erased files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/the-florey-brain-research-centre-files-claims-against-executive/106135388</link><description>Australia's biggest brain research centre sues one of its executives, alleging he deleted troves of commercially sensitive information during a midnight incursion at its Melbourne laboratory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8345d1270fa7ecf8c2167fcfa10b7f08</guid></item><item><title>Photographing penguins in Antarctica</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/leila-jeffreys-photographing-penguins-antarctica/106136800</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f292e504bf8faabeea539a3c5e5b979c</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic Arts Fellowship allows artists to develop works on the ice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/australian-antarctic-arts-fellowship/106139246</link><description>Over the past four decades, the Australian Antarctic Arts Fellowship has given creatives the opportunity to travel south and develop works on the icy continent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">574f0d2516ef3270e6679d6ed8e90ea9</guid></item><item><title>Retiring captain Elyse Villani says Hurricanes' WBBL win shows team's potential</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/hurricanes-captain-elyse-villani-retires-after-wbbl-win/106141334</link><description>Elyse Villani has described the Hurricanes' win as a "fairy tale" ending to her WBBL career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">111f91f49499824a5d1f69e7c6e6f83c</guid></item><item><title>This week in history quiz, December 15: Do you remember the first Simpsons episode?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/this-week-in-history-quiz-december-15/105877268</link><description>Do you have the answers for our This Week in History quiz?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2da6e529ed31b18eee47527e77124283</guid></item><item><title>Superannuation funds accused of delaying disability insurance claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/super-funds-accused-of-poor-handling-of-tpd-insurance-claims/106050046</link><description>The regulator has found that while some superannuation funds have improved insurance claims response times, others are still falling short, with long delays in relation to mental health claims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed72917ef5a3d4a0f3e4254687d92da</guid></item></channel></rss>