<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 23:04:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>McLaren unveils livery for MCL40 ahead of 2026 F1 season, Piastri and Norris excited about new challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/mclaren-unveil-livery-for-mcl40-ahead-of-2026-f1-season/106324952</link><description>McLaren has unveiled its livery for the 2026 Formula 1 championship season, retaining the design that helped it win championships in the previous two seasons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c712cf8881dedcdae7919ab9fe84ee12</guid></item><item><title>Jake and Chris Waterman relishing prospect of AFL Origin as Perth prepares for Victorian invasion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/jake-waterman-chris-waterman-relishing-state-of-origin/106323028</link><description>WA's last State of Origin captain Chris Waterman is relishing the prospect of the concept's reboot — and can't wait to see his son Jake donning the famous black swan for the clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4e7c9262ce711480d0a666d35fb1e5a</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce taps into rural anger as One Nation eyes Coalition seats at the Victorian election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/barnaby-joyce-one-nation-eyeing-victorian-election-seats/106322072</link><description>The right-wing party's prized recruit, Barnaby Joyce, made a key appearance deep in National Party territory as the 2026 Victorian election campaign began to take shape, Richard Willingham writes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a46ca39f0081cb28359ae1fd139fc030</guid></item><item><title>Catherine O'Hara's cause of death revealed as pulmonary embolism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/catherine-ohara-cause-of-death-announced/106324996</link><description>Award-winning actress Catherine O'Hara died from a pulmonary embolism, according to her death certificate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0db2f6d1caf958e134132f56ca8ef189</guid></item><item><title>Lindsey Vonn set for multiple surgeries but denies torn ACL contributed to Winter Olympic crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/lindsey-vonn-tibia-fracture-multiple-surgeries-winter-olympics/106325232</link><description>American ski great Lindsey Vonn will "require multiple surgeries" after sustaining a tibia fracture, but denies that her previously ruptured ACL was the cause of the crash that ended her Winter Olympic Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ab4072a808dc472c68c186a6da6811b</guid></item><item><title>Licensed program to kill native animals 'weak' and 'outdated' inquiry told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/licences-to-harm-native-animals-inquiry/106320826</link><description>Animal welfare groups are calling for a major overhaul into the system that allows native animals to be killed in NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93d7971e8816215b902c8e022b64e384</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 4, Tuesday, February 10</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-day-4matt-graham-jakara-anthony/106320694</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c39e879c6be4500d56c80aa209f85717</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth asks to meet Roblox following reports of child grooming. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/commonwealth-roblox-reports-of-child-grooming/106323242</link><description>Roblox has been called to an urgent meeting with the federal government in the wake of reports that children are being groomed by predators and exposed to sexually explicit material on the popular online gaming platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8186dce135dbe17f29c38ae0b2e5a4fb</guid></item><item><title>Exploitation claims have been levelled against cruise ship company Carnival. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/carnival-cruise-exploitation-claims-what-we-know/106325788</link><description>A major cruise ship has been investigated by the maritime safety regulator for claims around poor working conditions. A spokesperson for The Carnival Cruise Line says it has "nothing to hide" and welcomes AMSA's oversight. Here's what we know so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fb766396c9c7d4da6c405ce6634ae51</guid></item><item><title>Mackay MP Nigel Dalton crosses the floor to oppose LNP ban on abortion debate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nigel-dalton-crosses-floor-opposing-lnp-abortion-debate-ban/106327032</link><description>First-term Liberal National Party MP Nigel Dalton votes to overturn a ban on debating abortion — in defiance of his party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c85acc349c94f7e5ef78c2f5a8611f2</guid></item><item><title>Grace Tame criticised for leading intifada chants at Sydney protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/grace-tame-criticised-for-sydney-protest-intifada-chant/106326896</link><description>Grace Tame accuses Australia of being "a so-called democracy" that punishes peaceful protesters, before chanting "from Gadigal to Gaza, globalise the intifada!"</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9dc912a9d76603ba103ace6885715f4</guid></item><item><title>Deadline looms for Warren Tredrea to pay Nine's legal costs after failed appeal against unfair dismissal case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/warren-treadrea-deadline-to-pay-legal-costs-to-nine/106326298</link><description>Former footballer Warren Tredrea has an imminent deadline to pay $149,000 to his former employer, Channel Nine, following a failed appeal against an unfair dismissal case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8204048fc3858d5ea8943a955cc6d4ba</guid></item><item><title>At school, I was my brother's protector. But I needed more support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/support-i-wish-i-had-at-school-while-caring-for-my-brother/106279156</link><description>I was my brother's protector at school, but the education system could have done more to support us both.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8737a14dea75637ab0e525bab21121a9</guid></item><item><title>Global Athlete accuses IOC of 'kowtowing' to Russia by including AIN athletes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/russian-winter-olympic-athletes-milan-cortina/106327282</link><description>Advocacy group Global Athlete has accused the IOC of enabling Russia by allowing 13 Russian and seven Belarusian athletes to compete at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c9a39c00f74fc512b507557d2b1ac8f</guid></item><item><title>Craig Goodwin's World Cup hopes cop hammer blow after groin injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/craig-goodwin-s-world-cup-hopes-dashed/106327940</link><description>He was one of the Socceroos best in Qatar but now Craig Goodwin will need a minor miracle to make this year's World Cup after the veteran suffered a groin injury for Adelaide United that will sideline him for some time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">832f24e225d388d7831d181361338c99</guid></item><item><title>Shark filmed in deep Antarctic waters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/shark-filmed-in-deep-antarctic-waters/106321640</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4eb3f0f8027a13b7cb77a572c9acacff</guid></item><item><title>Tahmoor Coal placed into administration as court hears creditor winding-up bid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/tahmoor-coal-mine-placed-into-voluntary-administration/106326534</link><description>Tahmoor Coal has been placed into voluntary administration just as the Supreme Court was set to hear a creditor's winding-up application.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">953d7d3b73b007feb1525c6e38b10dea</guid></item><item><title>Raymond Reddington murder trial hears Sharon Fulton seemed scared in hours before 1986 disappearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/sharon-fulton-murder-trial-raymond-reddington-woman-was-scared/106327376</link><description>A close friend of a woman allegedly murdered by her husband in Perth 40 years ago tells a Perth court she seemed frightened in the hours before her disappearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78ffe88ad62d326c893e3ac20446550a</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106326714</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f1e6a5abe89487f45e90e88fb30e856</guid></item><item><title>Cam Bolton fractures neck as training falls rule two Aussies out of Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/winter-olympics-2026-live-milano-cortina-moguls-ice-hockey/106326694</link><description>Australia's Cam Bolton and Misaki Vaughan are ruled out of the Games after training falls, while reigning Olympic gold medallist Jakara Anthony advances to the women's moguls final at the Milano Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf10d0c49b40e45eace54bd9ee12cefa</guid></item><item><title>Australian government puts pressure on Lao authorities over methanol poisoning deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/methanol-poisoning-holly-bowles-bianca-morton-jones-laos/106328530</link><description>The Australian government calls in the Lao ambassador in Canberra, amid criticism of the country's response to a fatal methanol poisoning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc5e186c3bcd06980d9bd00b9b489bd6</guid></item><item><title>Former NT police officer James Kirstenfeldt sentenced on drink driving, weapons offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nt-james-kirstenfeldt-sentenced-drink-driving-weapons-charges/106313314</link><description>A former Northern Territory police officer has been ordered to pay almost $5,000 in fines and undergo supervised treatment for post-traumatic stress disorder after drunkenly crashing his car outside his suburban Darwin home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94f3ae08a6978aeffd227f1b28acd709</guid></item><item><title>Health warnings about ultra-processed foods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/health-warnings-about-ultra-processed-foods/106328288</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52af8963f7db51a368846c06aa60a304</guid></item><item><title>Bulk-billing rates rebound on back of government's multi-billion-dollar policy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/bulk-billing-rates-rebound-after-multi-billion-dollar-investment/106327456</link><description>Bulk-billing rates have rebounded in the first clear measure of the impact of the government's multi-billion-dollar pledge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d77c00d7ce459a8883fdcf39108f49f</guid></item><item><title>The desperate toll of Australia's 2026 Winter Olympic Games injury chaos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/australian-injury-hell-at-2026-winter-olympic-games/106329260</link><description>Games-ending injuries to Cam Bolton and Misaki Vaughan have emphasised the dangers of winter sport as the Australian team copes with issues early in the Milano Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f1a5314017e313b221ef7737afe9b23</guid></item><item><title>Israel tightens grip over West Bank while Herzog visits Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/isaac-herzog-visit-protest-police-west-bank-annexation/106325902</link><description>While Israeli President Isaac Herzog visited Sydney, his government was taking concrete actions in the West Bank designed to "continue to kill the idea of a Palestinian state".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">728001663fca5f0a0371d55a7b3d1249</guid></item><item><title>Protesters were punched, pushed, and arrested but were NSW Police actions excessive?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/verify-police-use-of-force-town-hall-protest/106328358</link><description>What is reasonable? It's a question being asked by some after footage of clashes in Sydney's CBD, during a rally against Israeli President Isaac Herzog's visit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc032833c827cf116d697c6b10faca22</guid></item><item><title>The Epstein files are shaking Britain, but Donald Trump could still have 3 million reasons to worry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/epstein-files-shake-uk-but-white-house-could-still-be-worried/106324788</link><description>Donald Trump's enemies made no secret of their hopes the documents would contain something explosive enough to bring the president down, but right now the Epstein spotlight is on Britain's politicians and palaces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd62bb34a29f437c14df3ee1992e6c76</guid></item><item><title>Uber quietly agrees to external review after woman sues over guide dog refusals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/uber-agrees-to-review-after-guide-dog-refusal-case/106307858</link><description>Uber quietly agrees to an external review of its Australian operations after settling a Federal Court case brought by a woman refused more than 30 rides while travelling with a guide dog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7dae27423705f7913b0c26f0c1f43a5</guid></item><item><title>Jakara Anthony picture perfect, Matt Graham with room to improve at 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games moguls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/jakara-anthony-matt-graham-pressure-moguls-qualifiers/106324214</link><description>Jakara Anthony will do anything aside from thinking about moguls skiing after qualifying number one for Wednesday's 2026 Winter Olympics final, taking to Lego, a puzzle and Grey's Anatomy instead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c5b1f5d3da4862fb201d76474dc2318</guid></item><item><title>Food ministers move closer to mandating Health Star Ratings on packaged food</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/move-to-mandate-health-star-ratings-on-food-and-drink/106231700</link><description>The nation's food ministers will this week take a crucial step towards mandating the Health Star Rating scheme on packaged food products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d49aa89b821cfcbaa27037bef0288134</guid></item><item><title>How to reduce loneliness while working remotely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/how-to-reduce-loneliness-while-working-remotely/106286338</link><description>Working remotely can be a lonely experience. Here's what you can do about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07ee38b05fb1af72edee6be374ac35ed</guid></item><item><title>Hume City Council wants action over thousands of tyres dumped in Melbourne's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/illegal-tyre-dumping-and-hume-council-action/106328912</link><description>A council in Melbourne's north wants the federal government to establish a free tyre recycling scheme to stop thousands of tyres being dumped, causing a potential environmental hazard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1abf383c1d01a41e7eb877b26adf62af</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor resigns from Liberal frontbench ahead of expected leadership spill — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/federal-politics-estimates-albanese-ley-herzog/106328310</link><description>Angus Taylor has resigned from the shadow frontbench ahead of an expected Liberal leadership spill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9652a4c3a8e2cd737e83d0b30398df6</guid></item><item><title>Australian T20 World Cup squad looks different but do not count it out, Mitch Marsh says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/injury-hit-australia-open-t20-world-cup-campaign-against-ireland/106329438</link><description>Despite a slew of key injuries leaving the Australian team unrecognisable, captain Mitch Marsh is confident about the experience left in the side.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e7e79b7afbfde0a033b919098cc0b12</guid></item><item><title>Limestone Coast hospital's staff shortage in spotlight after former administrator's fall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/limestone-coast-hospital-staff-shortage/106318896</link><description>David Walshaw spent 20 years looking after the Limestone Coast's hospitals, but a fall made him realise the system was failing patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63b01408b05a077885b47352dd28bbdc</guid></item><item><title>Citizen scientists work on 100-million-year-old ichthyosaur fossil in Winton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/ichthyosaur-winton-australian-age-of-dinosaurs-fossil/106310754</link><description>Participants from across Australia and the world travelled to outback Queensland to clean up the near-complete ichthyosaur fossil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af8a6ea34ab1f32371b167c057d77dd9</guid></item><item><title>Trump told police chief 'everyone' knew about Epstein, FBI document says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/trump-commerce-chief-claims-no-relationship-with-epstein/106329468</link><description>Donald Trump allegedly told police in 2006 that people in New York knew about Epstein, a newly uncovered FBI interview shows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3c205dcd4860dd580cc592880560660</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Stunning cheating admission overshadows medal win as Naumov brings tears with tribute — quick hits from day four</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/sport-quick-hits-winter-olympics-day-four-cheating-nauov-tribute/106329142</link><description>A Norwegian's first-ever medal is overshadowed by a stunning admission to reporters as Maxim Naumov pays tribute to his parents in the most beautiful way. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4ddae6dcef41de86448ed66a84d4881</guid></item><item><title>Fateful wrong turn, quiet cancer battle possible factors in missing prospector's suspected death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/barry-podmore-inquest-potential-wrong-turn/106328254</link><description>An inquest into Barry Podmore's disappearance in WA's remote Wheatbelt hears the 73-year-old was waging a private battle with cancer and may have become lost in bushland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70fd4d4de62cfa6ad418be560e1027f2</guid></item><item><title>What 30 years on the domestic violence front line taught police negotiator Vincent Hurley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/conversations-vince-hurley-domestic-violence-hostage-negotiation/106224980</link><description>Years on the front line of domestic violence surfaced in a frustration-filled moment on national television for Vincent Hurley. He explains what motivates him to keep fighting for change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bbd7954a3ffef22e74026708d401305</guid></item><item><title>Race against bulldozers to save ancient grass trees in WA's South West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/race-to-save-grass-trees-south-west-wa/106323778</link><description>Some of WA's oldest grass trees are being rescued from land clearing and development amid a population and property boom, preserving a unique part of the South West's natural heritage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c035d16240b39fbe758a3a7788f5176</guid></item><item><title>Queensland records first outbreak of Mimosa pigra — giant sensitive tree — in 25 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/giant-sensitive-tree-mimosa-pigra-detected-in-qld/106327380</link><description>A giant sensitive tree infestation has been detected near a lake near Brisbane and authorities say they have "no idea" how it got there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d606b67f355e1baa958386464d8e8d19</guid></item><item><title>Dungeons and Dragons-inspired game breaks down social barriers for neurodivergent kids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/dungeons-and-dragons-inspired-game-for-neurodivergent-kids/106321560</link><description>An Adelaide clinical psychologist creates a simplified version of Dungeons and Dragons to help neurodivergent children and young people learn social skills and develop peer connections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6f190df99526fce8245046efec4cbf7</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos striker Mo Toure scores hat-trick on starting debut in English Championship for Norwich</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/socceroos-striker-mohamed-toure-hat-trick-debut-norwich/106330220</link><description>Mohamed Toure moved to England recently on a $5 million deal and it is already looking like a great decision for the 21-year-old forward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ecfd2aa16103898748a1ab83e8c75e7</guid></item><item><title>Perth Festival opens with outdoor music, light sculptures and stories shared via old red telephone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/perth-festival-opens/106328574</link><description>Australia's longest running arts event, the Perth Festival, began on the weekend with Humans of New York-style videos in which locals tell their stories using an old red telephone on a bridge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">471448dd08cd988b876b0d8d841cb742</guid></item><item><title>Former Gidarjil CEO Kerry Blackman to face trial on five charges of sexual assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/kerry-blackman-to-stand-trial-on-sexual-assault-charges/106327292</link><description>Kerry Blackman will face trial in the Bundaberg District Court in June, charged with five counts of sexual assault.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7deebe3550be4f8148a82c0beb111e66</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 5, Wednesday, February 11</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide/106325628</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4808821c5d5c5ad794f816a30958d89</guid></item><item><title>DPP apologises after office 'dropped the ball' over police officer assault case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/sa-police-grant-stevens-concerned-about-police-assault/106329878</link><description>A court decision in which a woman who assaulted a South Australian police officer with a glass bottle was spared jail prompts an extraordinary concession from the Director of Public Prosecutions (DPP).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8f6d35fb3085ec7867365bd29fc6a55</guid></item><item><title>Police say there was 'serious, imminent risk' of child kidnapping in Perth by Jason William Forbes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/baldivis-child-kidnapper-jason-william-forbes-update/106327906</link><description>WA Police say "something terrible" could have happened if there was a delay in intercepting a Baldivis man who planned to abduct and sexually abuse a child in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9cb2e1663474710cf734cdb38d48828</guid></item><item><title>Formula 1 2026: New engines and no DRS headline major changes in grand prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/formula-1-2026-new-engines-regulations-sprint-races/106325942</link><description>New engines, new regulations and an 11-team grid are just some of the changes in Formula 1 this season. Get up to speed with what is new in F1 ahead of the Australian Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fce942eea4fa4616a149450aa1c7158</guid></item><item><title>Doongmabulla Springs decision leaves Qld government to weigh appeal or face trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/doongmabulla-springs-qld-government-appeal-or-face-trial/106305714</link><description>Wangan and Jagalingou peoples await the state government's next move after a win in their fight to have alleged damage to a sacred site near a mine in Central Queensland investigated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">409498e1a5333e429fc6fc92646dec77</guid></item><item><title>Two more Chinese nationals accused of foreign interference after allegedly gathering information in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/chinese-nationals-accused-foreign-interference-canberra/106331328</link><description>A task force investigated the alleged covert collection of information about a Canberra Buddhist association.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a1ec680cbea7b7a88f62860b8627475</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia readies up to 8,000 troops for Board of Peace efforts in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/indonesia-to-send-8000-troops-to-gaza-idf-peacekeeping/106330718</link><description>The move makes Indonesia the first country to clearly commit troops to a multinational peacekeeping effort in the war-torn enclave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb09709ab6a43276c0ef5777b42146b8</guid></item><item><title>No body-worn video evidence available for inquest into Krista Kach's death, coroner hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/krista-kach-inquest-no-body-worn-camera-evidence/106330358</link><description>A court hears a NSW inquest will need to rely on eyewitness accounts of the 2023 death of Krista Kach, who was shot with a beanbag round following a 10-hour stand-off with police in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e1eb69fc8206627f42ed509806f3904</guid></item><item><title>What to watch in February, from puppy love to Muppet hijinks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/what-to-watch-the-muppets-scrubs/106325818</link><description>Kermit, Miss Piggy and the rest of the crew are back to celebrate their 50th birthday with a one-off special that has the potential to turn into a whole new series for the beloved characters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09b335d5b372e0742b8c096839af2dff</guid></item><item><title>Dinosaur dig on Victoria's Bass Coast uncovers more than 60 bones and fossils</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/dinosaur-dig-at-inverloch-finds-bones-and-fossils/105904132</link><description>A collection of more than 60 dinosaur bones and fossils are unearthed from rocks at the site of a fossil dig in Victoria's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d67f1ab883871846b55d6387f0f8bd4a</guid></item><item><title>Perth brothers Nezir and Enver Ibrahimovic avoid jail for assault at Scarborough bar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/bouncers-avoid-jail-scarborough-bar-assault/106331266</link><description>Two brothers working as bouncers when they assaulted a man at a Scarborough bar avoid jail after a magistrate recognised the trauma they suffered in the Bosnian war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78455998eac3b4222b694f47d3f06d7a</guid></item><item><title>Mother of teenager allegedly assaulted by NSW Police at Sydney protest to press charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/nsw-police-protest-allegedly-assaulted-teenager-mother-claims/106329674</link><description>The mother of a 16-year-old who alleges he was "pushed, kicked, dragged on the ground" by officers at a Sydney protest against the Israeli president's visit says she wants to press charges against police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30d0c8531d4d566ed060274bb1773187</guid></item><item><title>Cryptosporidium cluster at Waterworld leads to closure of Adelaide Aquatic Centre pools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/adelaide-aquatic-centres-close-after-cluster-of-gastro-cases/106330324</link><description>SA Health is urging people with gastroenteritis symptoms not to visit public swimming pools after eight cases at one swimming centre, including one child who was hospitalised and another who also visited the Adelaide Aquatic Centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">feaa7c2df6769e23acd9a68078708dfc</guid></item><item><title>Axed literary magazine Meanjin is resurrected by Queensland University of Technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/meanjin-magazine-finds-new-home-queensland-university-technology/106331850</link><description>The 85-year-old literary journal Meanjin will return to Brisbane, where it was first published, after it was controversially closed by Melbourne University Press last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8381f55200bc2cef76893ac168c73d93</guid></item><item><title>Telstra to axe up to 650 roles in mass redundancy round, some jobs to be outsourced to India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/telstra-axes-600-roles-in-redundancy-round-outsourcing-to-india/106331708</link><description>Telstra notifies staff of plans to outsource hundreds of jobs to an India-based technology company.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a54d2039d987947db967f7534c2af1d8</guid></item><item><title>Former Carlton legend Peter Dean hospitalised after serious assault in Albury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/former-carlton-legend-suffers-serious-assault-in-albury/106331586</link><description>Former AFL player Peter Dean is recovering in hospital after he sustained serious head and facial injuries in an alleged assault at Albury on the New South Wales Victorian border.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4ceb1d2b4738f0666d773a5bf7a2435</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide's own a medal contender for US in women's double luge at Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/winter-olympics-chevonne-forgan-womens-doubles-luge-adelaide/106331288</link><description>The driest state in the driest country of the world might seem the unlikeliest of places for a star in the Winter Olympics sport of luge to emerge, but Chevonne Forgan will be a medal contender tonight — albeit for Team USA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8190dc66c1226686cb38afb044c221c4</guid></item><item><title>Supersized fatberg clogging Sydney sewer blamed for mysterious debris balls on beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/supersized-fatberg-clogging-sydney-sewer-debris-balls/106309658</link><description>The debris balls that have washed up on NSW beaches in recent years are likely to continue as Sydney Water admits a massive fatberg it cannot reach is clogging sewers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e47536114404d9c787ba564b5b869472</guid></item><item><title>NSW soccer coach Tullio 'Tony' Giacomo Cigana jailed over child abuse material</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/nsw-soccer-coach-jailed-over-child-abuse-material/106332804</link><description>A once well-regarded soccer coach has been handed a 12 month jail sentence for possessing child abuse material, after a Sydney court heard he has been disowned by family members.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46189d96dae7bf43bc8498eec2003538</guid></item><item><title>Israeli President Isaac Herzog welcomes 'new beginning' in meeting with Anthony Albanese</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/protesters-rally-as-mps-skip-question-time-for-herzog-visit/106331226</link><description>Israeli President Isaac Herzog meets with the prime minister at Parliament House in Canberra, saying his visit to Australia has been "very emotional".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">579de49026fcdc60f86649be3a4bb35f</guid></item><item><title>Australian dollar reaches '40-year high' against Japan's yen, as cheap holidays fuel tourism surge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/australian-dollar-japanese-yen-currency-exchange-rate-tourism/106332346</link><description>Australia's exchange rate with Japan has grown increasingly favourable to tourists, which have surged to record numbers and topped more than one million visitors in 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7abbc35d9096aae897d046e36ccf9990</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds treated for e-bike injuries in 2025 at Sydney St Vincent Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/ebike-injuries-double-at-sydney-hospital/106332460</link><description>More than 200 people were treated for e-bike related injuries at a single Sydney hospital last year, with one medical professor describing the trend as an "epidemic".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51176d07eca703bb7654923149b12871</guid></item><item><title>RBA deputy governor defends central bank from critics, wonders if Australia is more inflation-prone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/rba-deputy-governor-says-rba-not-criticise-government-policy/106331502</link><description>RBA deputy governor Andrew Hauser says central banks should not criticise normal government spending choices, but he wonders if Australia's economy is more inflation-prone because it is so finely balanced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f806f14f928362b28b219b82a640327b</guid></item><item><title>Australian fans miss out on World Cup tickets as prices skyrocket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/world-cup-ticket-prices-aussie-fans-miss-out/106332736</link><description>A host of Australian fans will be denied the chance to watch the Socceroos World Cup campaign amid accusations of price gouging by FIFA as tickets to the tournament soar to astronomical prices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cb80105f0eeb0984e8c6d7afad7d449</guid></item><item><title>Labor tries again on super taxes, but yet to secure Greens support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/labor-tries-again-on-super-taxes/106331524</link><description>A second attempt to raise taxes on high super balances has been presented to parliament, but will require the support of the Greens to secure Senate passage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a466ab31df35bf825a2dc9c0feee1d03</guid></item><item><title>US bars Palau senate president and former Marshall Islands mayor over alleged corruption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/us-bars-palau-marshall-islands-officials-for-alleged-corruption/106329288</link><description>A senior Palau politician rejects accusations from the United States Department of State that he accepted bribes from "government, business, and criminal interests from China".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4c5d3311f093881fd48b21aa27d5d56</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106332300</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b1ea351c35c93ca1ce9d6966ef4ae9d</guid></item><item><title>Kane Dallow sentenced to two years in prison on fraud and other charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/tasmanian-man-kane-dallow-jailed-for-28-offences/106227598</link><description>A Tasmanian man who impersonated the Launceston Magistrates Court has been convicted on 28 crimes relating to fraud, forgery and perverting justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a46ce2b2cf467d06b9f88e5ba53d770b</guid></item><item><title>Chinese flotilla sailed to edge of Australia's waters, ADF chief reveals at Senate estimates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/chinese-flotilla-edge-australian-exclusive-economic-zone/106333020</link><description>Under questioning in Senate estimates, the chief of the Australian Defence Force reveals that a Chinese flotilla sailed within seven nautical miles of Australia's 200 nautical mile exclusive economic zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54162e69e9611e52a37af7ad332cce70</guid></item><item><title>NSW Parliament backs Cheryl Grimmer's family after 56-year quest for justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/cheryl-grimmer-parliament-motion-buckingham/106332722</link><description>Decades after three-year-old Cheryl Grimmer vanished from Fairy Meadow Beach, NSW MPs move to support her family's fight for justice, as Jeremy Buckingham directly addressed the alleged perpetrator under parliamentary privilege.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9f2d8b7e5889008ddc973077711f317</guid></item><item><title>Surveillance devices captured accused talking about alleged murder of Geoffrey McLean, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/court-hears-evidence-over-alleged-murder-of-geoffrey-mclean/106333170</link><description>An SA Supreme Court trial hears listening devices captured alleged murderer Mark Murphy admitting to his role in killing Geoffrey McLean in 2022. Warning: This story contains details that some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dee7af032cb8fec1ac1248900b766e93</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor resigns from front bench ahead of expected leadership challenge to Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/angus-taylor-resigns-from-frontbench-sussan-ley-leadership/106332492</link><description>Angus Taylor says the Liberals are at their weakest point since the party was formed as he announces his resignation from the front bench.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">719ec35aae82fd4ae16e34d338c37aa1</guid></item><item><title>Australia cruises to victory over Ireland in T20 World Cup opener</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/cricket-t20-world-cup-australia-ireland-blog-scores-stats/106330266</link><description>Australia beats Ireland by 67 runs to win its first game at the T20 World Cup, after captain Mitch Marsh was a late out due to testicular bleeding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f10653e8e126254d5fa9b92b8b0d7bf</guid></item><item><title>Channel Nine says Warren Tredrea has now paid costs over long-running legal battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/channel-nine-says-warren-tredrea-has-paid-legal-costs/106333410</link><description>Channel Nine has confirmed it has received legal costs from former AFL player and sports presenter Warren Tredrea, who was ordered to pay $149,000 to his ex-employer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f2d55f17d07ae474e5568f1f5fecbde</guid></item><item><title>PM condemns 'white supremacy ideology' behind alleged Invasion Day terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/prime-minister-closing-the-gap-speech/106332998</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has condemned the "racism and hatred" and "white supremacy ideology" behind the alleged terrorist attack on the Invasion Day rally in Borloo/Perth last month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e3643c30243d9459a9602b299a97cc4</guid></item><item><title>Britney Spears sells rights to music catalogue in reported $281m deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/britney-sells-rights-music-catalogue-primary-wave/106333696</link><description>Spears is the latest music star to sell the rights to their work, a decade after the release of her ninth and last studio album.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46d37ff06c7881b67f6362f876d81145</guid></item><item><title>Jakara Anthony misses medals at 2026 Winter Olympic Games in Milano Cortina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/jakara-anthony-2026-winter-olympics-moguls-final-wilson/106333690</link><description>The Australian spectators in Livigno are stunned as defending champion Jakara Anthony crashes out of contention in the women's moguls final at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a060f999a428f2c8f193deb043d835a1</guid></item><item><title>Xi Jinping says China's army has undergone 'revolutionary tempering' in corruption crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/xi-jinping-acknowledges-army-corruption-crackdown/106333834</link><description>Xi Jinping's comments were the first public admission of issues in China's armed forces since an investigation was launched into senior members of the body that overseas the country's military.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c77d72b3b87ccaf57b6cca7a5238b8a</guid></item><item><title>Jakara Anthony may not have won Winter Olympics moguls gold, but winning is not always measured in medals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/jakara-anthony-2026-winter-olympics-moguls/106333208</link><description>Disaster stared Jakara Anthony in the face and meted out the cruellest of injustices as she missed out on a moguls medal at the 2026 Winter Olympic Games. But her response showed us the character that should make Australia proud regardless.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e7220da0752d7dbb33f88021143e2b1</guid></item><item><title>Crack found in new $786m Bridgewater Bridge, RTI documents reveal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/concrete-cracks-in-bridgewater-bridge-rti-documents-reveal/106326476</link><description>Days before the official opening, the Tasmanian government's largest-ever infrastructure project hit a hurdle, with a large crack picked up in one of the Bridgewater Bridge's piers detected and fixed, documents show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dedb596ad7690da3fa77fd190349acb0</guid></item><item><title>Kath &amp; Kim is back on ABC iview. Test your Fountain Lakes fan credentials with our quiz. It's noice, it's different, it's _____</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/kath-and-kim-quiz/106286470</link><description>It's an Aussie classic, but do you know who delivered these iconic lines in Kath &amp; Kim? Put down your cardonnay and footy franks and show us what you've got.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b67dba22afc919812a6491878f676fa7</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor is moving to challenge Sussan Ley — but not on his terms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/angus-taylor-sussan-ley-leadership-timing-not-wanted/106331132</link><description>Angus Taylor was holidaying in Europe when his colleagues began manoeuvring to topple Sussan Ley. A leadership spill this week wasn't what he or Sussan Ley wanted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32d6f00ceb18364ee804ea3ff647cbdf</guid></item><item><title>Transparency concerns as Bougainville's Panguna mine that sparked civil war on path to reopen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/bougainville-signs-secretive-deal-to-reopen-panguna-mine/106331778</link><description>The Autonomous Bougainville Government signs a secretive deal to reopen the huge Panguna gold and copper mine that sparked a catastrophic civil war three decades ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7a5ff00e0503cc102c30c6e22dae858</guid></item><item><title>Australia's toxic legacy at Wilkes Station in Antarctica</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/wilkes-station-in-antarctica-a-toxic-legacy/106281888</link><description>The ABC has been given rare access to an abandoned Australian base in Antarctica that continues to pose a threat to the environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86fbd4ded36d272a381c32bb0d71bd55</guid></item><item><title>Old Bureau of Meteorology website still getting thousands of clicks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/old-bom-website-drawing-traffic-months-after-new-page-launch/106326812</link><description>The new BOM website is still drawing criticism, with 400,000 users turning to the old site, despite $1.15 million in recent updates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6571b8e0e99bb64c79240519d9e09619</guid></item><item><title>The weekend Adelaide becomes a Saudi Arabian sports utopia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/sa-how-adelaide-became-shining-light-for-liv-golf/106330622</link><description>Saudi Arabia’s LIV Golf project is facing plenty of problems across the world, but you would not read about it when the circus flies into Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff1f35542fe0cac1fbe33fb295905553</guid></item><item><title>Australia Diamonds defeat Jamaica 80-33 in third netball Test to claim 3-0 series win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/australia-diamonds-defeat-jamaica-80-33-in-third-test/106333890</link><description>Coach Stacey Marinkovich believes a refreshed Diamonds squad has found its "identity" ahead of attempting to become the first Australian netball team to defend Commonwealth Games gold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">572f0f2c0fcd545047cd50c575ce4950</guid></item><item><title>A look at the ballistic missile program Iran refuses to negotiate on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/iran-ballistic-missile-program-weapons-us-talks-trump/106307798</link><description>Iran has spent decades building the largest and most diverse ballistic missile stockpile in the Middle East and is refusing US demands to put limits on the weapons program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43b81c86e32420037a6e9d60aa99108f</guid></item><item><title>Thirty people stranded by floods in outback NT angry at police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/people-stranded-in-nt-flood-angry-at-police-response/106326132</link><description>A day trip to the Tjoritja/West MacDonnell National Park became a 24-hour ordeal for almost 30 people when the Hugh River unexpectedly cut off Namatjira Drive, 50 kilometres from Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">120c5f850f4631f4a3c7d5f0c1c42567</guid></item><item><title>Animal abuse charge takes one year as RSPCA prosecutions in Queensland drastically decline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/queensland-rspca-drop-in-prosecutions-animal-cruelty/106277220</link><description>A man has been charged with animal cruelty a year after neighbours first made a complaint to the RSPCA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cd8515cd059d1ed39c4f1b8f6e3e75d</guid></item><item><title>Lando Norris quickest on day one of F1 preseason test, Oscar Piastri drives well and Max Verstappen impresses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/f1-preseason-test-bahrain-norris-piastri-verstappen/106333906</link><description>McLaren's Formula 1 world champion Lando Norris was fastest on the first day of preseason testing in Bahrain, but Max Verstappen and Red Bull caught the attention with pace and plenty of laps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba0e6f82ba0e8d4236049cdf992c4cb9</guid></item><item><title>Baker Boy talks new album Djandjay, Riverboats festival and family legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/baker-boy-djandjay-album-riverboats-festival-racism-fresh-prince/106321578</link><description>The Yolŋu artist known as the Fresh Prince of Arnhem Land is the king of feel-good bilingual bangers. But heavy is the crown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a7e4fe54da381b9b3169df148ff7976</guid></item><item><title>James Van Der Beek, star of Dawson's Creek, dies aged 48 after colorectal cancer diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/james-van-der-beek-dawsons-creek-star-obituary/105821848</link><description>The American actor was best known for his starring role as Dawson Leery in Dawson's Creek from 1998 to 2003.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0a7efc4b90b9a094e5d4af5773abbca</guid></item><item><title>Canada school shooter 18-year-old Jesse Van Rootselaar acted alone, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/canadian-shooter-identified-in-school-attack/106333992</link><description>Police identify the person who carried out a school massacre in a remote Canadian community as an 18-year-old woman with mental health issues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3aa7b080fb4f452119e946dd95e8524</guid></item><item><title>Liberal frontbench resignations snowball as Ley backer resigns — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/federal-politics-live-blog-sussan-ley/106333952</link><description>Angus Taylor has confirmed he will challenge Opposition Leader Sussan Ley for the leadership at the meeting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c870442734b3073dc8ba7593b59edcb</guid></item><item><title>Pam Bondi grilled over Epstein files as survivors express fury over redactions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/pam-bondi-faces-congress-questions-over-epstein-files/106329688</link><description>US Attorney-General Pam Bondi faces furious questions over the censorship of names in the Epstein files at a heated hearing before a committee of Congress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f6370664d2895327e9152794883f228</guid></item><item><title>RBA concedes 'our forecasts are often wrong'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/asx-markets-business-news-feb12-2026/106334054</link><description>Asked by a journalist, "Was it perhaps overenthusiastic to cut interest rates three times?" The RBA's chief economist responded, "Forecasting is really difficult business, our forecasts are often wrong ... it is what it is."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0416d5b9ac46a1dd16ff15863726771f</guid></item><item><title>Australians feel divided as Albanese asks to 'turn the temperature down'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/social-cohesion-anthony-albanese-isaac-herzog/106294752</link><description>Most Australians want greater social cohesion here, even if they don't see much of it right now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa28ba119db2dd3922f89dee680cc738</guid></item><item><title>Carers WA struggling to cope with unprecedented demand for support services</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/carers-wa-unprecedented-demand-support-services/106328164</link><description>An organisation that helps people caring for vulnerable family members in WA is experiencing unprecedented demand, with services unable to keep up with the community's needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec18c3068cc8e2883c0431ac89a4d61c</guid></item><item><title>Authorities warn Alice Springs flash flooding threat isn't over, more Central Australian rain predicted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/nt-alice-springs-flooding-wet-weather-emergency-rain/106334186</link><description>Authorities are warning Alice Springs could face further flooding overnight, with forecasts of more wet weather posing a threat to slowly receding water levels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f0111c3d67d09aaf04530f675a2283b</guid></item><item><title>South Africa beats Afghanistan at Twenty20 World Cup after two super overs at Narendra Modi Stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/south-africa-afghanistan-t20-world-cup-double-super-over/106334290</link><description>South Africa wins the most dramatic T20 World Cup group stage clash with Afghanistan, featuring two super overs and countless twists of fortune.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb1593268b4f75b9895b6ade64f0c231</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Lindsey Vonn has successful surgery as Vladyslav Heraskevych wears his banned helmet — quick hits from day five</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/winter-olympics-2026-day-five-quick-hits-vonn-helmet/106334002</link><description>A Ukrainian athlete is refusing to back down over a controversial helmet featuring the dead, Lindsey Vonn has a third surgery, and maple syrup has powered Ryan Cochran-Siegle to another medal. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">881eb2ab6d01f7591d27959795e07f03</guid></item><item><title>Declining birth rates in southern right whales alarm researchers in new study</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/climate-change-driving-down-southern-right-whale-calving-numbers/106332214</link><description>New research on the birth rates of southern right whales – once touted as a global conservation success story – has revealed an alarming decline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5d80284251a8c0cd3713b5fe505730a</guid></item><item><title>Greens call for parliamentary inquiry into paedophile former Tasmanian police officer Paul Reynolds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/tasmanian-greens-paul-reynolds-parliamentary-inquiry-call/106332474</link><description>The Greens will push for Tasmania's parliament to scrutinise how police handled child abuse allegations against former officer Paul Reynolds, and why it was decided to give him a full police funeral.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f7f501ebb062cec9e3826f249c2421e</guid></item><item><title>Muslim leader urges public apology over police 'manhandling' at Sydney protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/muslims-nsw-police-public-apology-sydney-protest-cronulla/106333996</link><description>The Lebanese Muslim Association's secretary says the community's relationship with police could be fractured following the Sydney protest despite spending "nearly 20 years repairing" the damage caused by the Cronulla Riot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d02612f12f38a0ec4573ea3b1e9dc4e</guid></item><item><title>Mackay MP who crossed floor to oppose LNP ban on abortion debate defends actions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/nigel-dalton-crosses-floor-abortion-debate/106334698</link><description>Mackay MP Nigel Dalton crossed the floor on Tuesday to vote with Katter's Australian Party to end a parliamentary ban on abortion debate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7af1877d708465b9f166d5233952c8b6</guid></item><item><title>Public DNA databases lead to arrest over historical NSW sexual assault cases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/dna-technology-leads-to-arrest-nsw-sexual-assault-cold-cases/106334110</link><description>A 77-year-old man is arrested in connection with a string of alleged sexual assaults in NSW dating back to the 1990s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">957f7d3970b9923c7d95cd14199fbfad</guid></item><item><title>Albemarle's lithium refinery in WA's South West placed on care and maintenance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/albemarle-kemerton-lithium-refinery-shut-down/106334822</link><description>A multi-billion-dollar lithium refinery in WA's South West has been shut down, affecting about 275 workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5062fb4ce50ee697f9ff892aa55a778c</guid></item><item><title>Scotty James and Valentino Guseli raise their level at 'unbelievable' snowboard halfpipe qualifier at Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/scotty-james-valentino-guseli-snowboard-halfpipe-qualification/106333268</link><description>Scotty James is the man to beat in the snowboard halfpipe at the 2026 Winter Olympics, but a stunning qualifying competition proves that the final is going to be on another level entirely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84595f7c496f7dbad48fe23b81679130</guid></item><item><title>UK police to decide on Andrew Mounbatten-Windsor Epstein trade document investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-police-epstein-files-investigation/106334742</link><description>British police say they are "making progress as quickly as possible" on whether to launch a full investigation into allegations that Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor shared confidential trade documents with late financier and sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70f896e77bb48c2fb240d5bc44cccee3</guid></item><item><title>Three arrested by CFMEU corruption taskforce as premier insists she took appropriate action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/three-arrested-taskforce-hawk-cfmeu-corruption-investigation/106334256</link><description>The arrests were made hours before Premier Jacinta Allan faced reporters over separate allegations detailed in a new report that $15 billion in taxpayer dollars had made its way into the hands of criminals who had infiltrated the union.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc02ad89e79207293943a68d6da5adee</guid></item><item><title>Chris Minns has cracked down on protests. Will it pay off?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/chris-minns-protest-laws-herzog-visit-police/106331440</link><description>By expanding police powers and allowing bans on authorised public assemblies the Minns government has made restricting protest a defining feature of its first term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">527083f33675311c91fad837565911cc</guid></item><item><title>5,000 cannabis plants seized on rural NSW property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/5-000-cannabis-plants-seized-on-rural-nsw-property/106334568</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51853416fd6d3685a6d065d7635bcf34</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 6</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-matt-graham/106330602</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e7755738441e4486f4c3fbb99fe3561</guid></item><item><title>Plotters, kingmakers and dark horses — the Liberals vying for control</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/the-liberals-vying-for-control-of-party/106335554</link><description>Parliament House has entered the spill zone, where politics is at its most primal. Here are the Liberals jostling for control of their much-reduced party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01251844a95201cce2e0e2a131bfd5f3</guid></item><item><title>Reo Te Whetu Marama Marsh pleads guilty to murdering Mary Benedito on Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/marybenedito-murder-former-partner-pleads-guilty-southport/106335664</link><description>The 25-year-old mother was found unresponsive in a Southport apartment in 2021 and later died of her injuries in hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41675660826075c3b3cef1da1d9a7876</guid></item><item><title>Labor releases audio of Liberal MP backtracking on $495 million cost of living policy at industry event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/labor-releases-audio-of-liberal-backtrack/106334676</link><description>South Australia's Treasurer says the Liberal Party has secretly dumped its major $495 million policy less than six weeks out from the state election, with the Opposition arguing it has to wind back Labor's tax due to state budget blowouts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41c94a52edb47ae2f974cc0fddf1c2cb</guid></item><item><title>Camels dying from dehydration descend on APY Lands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/apy-lands-feral-camels-dying-drought-sa/106321572</link><description>Large mobs of camels wreak havoc in remote Indigenous communities as they desperately search for water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c807cb91079deb6ab0c14e1cb642ee2</guid></item><item><title>James Van Der Beek was synonymous with his character. How he embraced it with humour will be his legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/james-van-der-beek-dawsons-creek-character-legacy/106335718</link><description>James Van Der Beek's death prompts wide-ranging tributes from co-stars and friends who have praised his kindness and humour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a76d007b4e1dd749503740e00c13fea9</guid></item><item><title>RBA governor accused by senator of 'gaslighting' Australians on economy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/rba-governor-accused-of-gaslighting-australians-on-economy/106335332</link><description>Reserve Bank governor Michele Bullock fires back at Nationals senator Matt Canavan after he accused her of "gaslighting" Australians over the state of the Australian economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3d3abbc8ab57a6e74180c9d88ef4dae</guid></item><item><title>Ex-police officer Kritan Kutti jailed for arson and possession of bestiality videos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/former-nsw-police-officer-kritan-kutti-jailed/106329584</link><description>A former NSW police officer is jailed for multiple offences, including arson and possession of bestiality videos, while stationed at a rural border post.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b60e70d23fd8c282aad6b8a419d10ebc</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: 'Pindemonium' sweeps Milano Cortina as collectors go treasure hunting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/pindemonium-sweeps-winter-olympics-milano-cortina/106336996</link><description>For Olympic pin hunters, Milano Cortina 2026 is proving to be a thrilling treasure hunt, one that is taking them to corners of the world they may never have otherwise visited.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">133f5a34145c7cffb3fff053a69b8dff</guid></item><item><title>Man faces Mackay court accused of buying boat for drug smuggling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/man-accused-buying-boat-facilitate-import-illegal-drugs/106336250</link><description>Police allege the owner of a recently set up fishing company purchased a vessel with illicit funds to facilitate the importation of illegal drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a0b73226052d169923a9a7b5bfd9b8e</guid></item><item><title>Support firms for Angus Taylor to win Liberal leadership, though Ley expected to achieve 'good result'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/angus-taylor-liberal-leadership-support-firms/106334120</link><description>Support is firming for Angus Taylor to topple Opposition Leader Sussan Ley, though her supporters still expect her to achieve a "good result".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ec143f5904383374cfda9bd081918e1</guid></item><item><title>Mother of autistic man starved to death in Gold Coast hospital 'satisfied' with damning investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/ombudsman-investigation-robina-hospital-death/106334338</link><description>Queensland’s health watchdog finds Stewart Kelly's 2022 hospital death was the result of systemic failures in care, particularly around responding to his complex needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f21ac0cb928bb63b34bd2332709076bd</guid></item><item><title>Chocolate recipes to share some love with the people in your life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/valentines-day-recipes-love-chocolate/106325802</link><description>Whether you are into Valentine's Day or not, these chocolate recipes are perfect for sharing some love.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4882faeefbbf9e3310ba059823c6008</guid></item><item><title>Julian Assange's brother backs exiled former ASIO spy Marcus amid Bondi Beach gunman radicalisation claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/julian-assange-s-brother-supporting-former-spy-living-in-exile/106334144</link><description>Former undercover agent Marcus says he shared intelligence with ASIO about Bondi gunmen Naveed and Sajid Akram's alleged terrorism associations as far back as 2019.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d342528c0b8c306cae08cb9c3c5a0d35</guid></item><item><title>Liberals' leadership machinations dominate the political week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/liberals-leadership-spill-angus-taylor-sussan-ley/106325872</link><description>The Liberals have spent the week embroiled in leadership woes as the party braces for a spill on Friday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">874320a6b150dbbf66b077e9b0f5d9b5</guid></item><item><title>Gas exploration seismic testing project rejected in south-west Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/regia-3d-mss-project-seismic-testing-rejected-gas-exploration/106334294</link><description>A controversial seismic testing proposal off Victoria's south-west coast has been rejected in a "rare" move from the offshore regulator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f07ea3447a079671409f13da47906a8b</guid></item><item><title>Two Chinese nationals accused of foreign interference granted bail in ACT Magistrates Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/act-two-chinese-nationals-accused-foreign-interference-bail/106335336</link><description>Police allege the two Chinese nationals, who are charged with reckless foreign interference for alleged spying on the Canberra branch of a Buddhist association, are linked to a woman arrested on the same charge last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8ffcbf499d3b6e411f85857ee4a6971</guid></item><item><title>Severe thunderstorm, heavy rainfall warnings issued for Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/thunderstorms-severe-weather-warnings-south-east-queensland/106337566</link><description>Severe thunderstorms are likely to produce heavy rainfall that may lead to flash flooding across parts of Queensland tonight, according to the weather bureau.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0e82342c3647b805eed1dc7a1817a34</guid></item><item><title>Fatal Queensland house fire inquiry hears father was 'pretty abusive'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/queensland-fatal-house-fire-inquiry/106336740</link><description>The mother of a young boy killed in a house fire in 2017 has given emotional evidence at an inquest into his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e821f83fd67d3541967e14a7c326eb70</guid></item><item><title>New video shows violent arrest of Australian filmmaker James Ricketson at Sydney's anti-Herzog protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/video-shows-arrest-filmmaker-james-ricketson-sydney-protest/106337470</link><description>New video obtained by ABC NEWS Verify shows in vivid detail the arrest of a 76-year-old man, who was later released without charge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e8b85f342914cc4a1db8e8f827b072c</guid></item><item><title>Barbeques Galore enters receivership as debt burns into bottom line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/barbeques-galore-enters-receivership/106337962</link><description>Barbeques Galore has plunged into receivership, leaving question marks for nearly 100 stores that employ about 500 staff.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69523934e505732dbc33d0c34030742d</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106337290</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d261cc973fdb20ab56fe51470b7d321c</guid></item><item><title>Cars submerged, trees torn down, roads inundated: Alice Springs flooding in pictures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/nt-alice-springs-flooding-in-pictures-floodwaters-damage/106336102</link><description>Overnight thunderstorms left Central Australian rivers inundated on Thursday, with rapidly rising floodwaters submerging cars, ripping up trees and leaving multiple people stranded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e025807245504400521b8ef8f7040fd1</guid></item><item><title>Toowoomba Hospital maternity unit to implement recommendations for workplace culture overhaul</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/toowoomba-hospital-maternity-unit-workplace-culture-findings/106338238</link><description>Staff at the Toowoomba Hospital maternity unit will be implementing recommended changes to their workplace culture following an independent review.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fffb7e8031442fc89790d85b110ac64c</guid></item><item><title>Teen bounces back from nasty crash to snatch gold from American great</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/winter-olympics-2026-live-milano-cortina-cooper-woods/106338490</link><description>Two-time Winter Olympic champion Chloe Kim is pipped for first place by 17-year-old Gaon Choi late in the women's snowboard halfpipe final at the Milano Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77fd8c878e9a3a73529932cf9fb473c2</guid></item><item><title>Children prescribed puberty blockers without proper assessment at Cairns health service, review finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/qld-puberty-blockers-cairns-health-service/106336756</link><description>The review of the Cairns paediatric gender health service found that children as young as 12 were given puberty blockers inconsistently and without formal consent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">239aa031616658a4122734a07b49c2df</guid></item><item><title>Father finds family's bones in rubble of Gaza house destroyed in air strikes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/gaza-father-searches-for-family-bones-in-house-rubble/106335798</link><description>Mahmoud Hammad believes he has found his family's remains in the rubble of his house, which was destroyed more than two years ago in air strikes, killing his pregnant wife and their five children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c72e878a5950523e5fef0914825cd59a</guid></item><item><title>Nightcliff by-election set for March 7, Greens and Labor announce candidates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/nt-nightcliff-byelection-candidates-greens-labor-kat-mcnamara/106335938</link><description>The Greens and Labor have announced their candidates for the Nightcliff by-election, set for March 7, after the resignation of Greens MLA Kat McNamara earlier this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bb26b69187d156e3509e605e9c38389</guid></item><item><title>IOC disqualifies Ukrainian skeleton racer Vladyslav Heraskevych over helmet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/olympics-ukrainian-vladyslav-heraskevych-disqualified-helmet/106338586</link><description>Vladyslav Heraskevych is disqualified over his customised helmet featuring the faces of Ukrainian athletes and coaches killed in the Russia-Ukraine war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fccc878b54f516f48ad6edf96316efba</guid></item><item><title>Margot Robbie and Jacob Elordi dazzle fans at Wuthering Heights premiere in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/margot-robbie-jacob-elordi-at-wuthering-heights-sydney-premiere/106337298</link><description>Margot Robbie and Jacob Elordi were all smiles on the red carpet ahead of the Australian premiere of Wuthering Heights at the State Theatre in Sydney. They later surprised a sold-out audience gathered to watch the film at the OpenAir cinema on Sydney Harbour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fc5eafc61474e187ee527fb39a70bb7</guid></item><item><title>Muslim men had permission to pray before officers removed them from Sydney protest, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/muslim-men-had-permission-to-pray-at-sydney-protest/106338734</link><description>A group of Muslim men had already received police permission to worship during a Sydney protest before they were disrupted mid-prayer by officers, NSW Police Force confirms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96634ee0fdc26c6f60ce7edf1fb81c08</guid></item><item><title>Cooper Woods wins Australia's first gold of 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/cooper-woods-wins-winter-olympic-gold-moguls/106338772</link><description>Cooper Woods has stunned the moguls field to win a maiden career title at the 2026 Winter Olympic Games at Milano Cortina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b63e0dd3c0b2886d37f6baecb4e90bc</guid></item><item><title>Multiple people stabbed outside Coorparoo's Easts Leagues Club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/multiple-people-stabbed-easts-leagues-club-disturbance/106338794</link><description>A 33-year-old man has been arrested after the incident at Coorparoo's Easts Leagues Club on Thursday evening, which left two people in hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c59f0508e5e2d8715e345b2d4079ca1</guid></item><item><title>Cooper Woods welcomed to the Winter Olympic 'gold medal club' by Alisa Camplin-Warner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/cooper-woods-gold-medal-club-alisa-camplin/106338996</link><description>Only seven Australian athletes have ever felt the weight of a Winter Olympic gold medal being hung around their necks. And one of the first, Alisa Camplin-Warner, was thrilled to welcome the most recent, Cooper Woods, to the club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00bcbc79601b776b4d7b20f266d65169</guid></item><item><title>Judge sets trial date for Donald Trump's defamation case against BBC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/trial-date-set-donald-trump-defamation-case-bbc/106339012</link><description>A US District Judge has also rejected the BBC's application to halt the discovery phase of the $US10 billion ($15.1 billion) lawsuit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1afeba3aded5a954bd2d352ec1d9ae39</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's border tsar Tom Homan announces ICE withdrawal from Minnesota</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/ice-withdrawal-minnesota-homan-trump-tsar/106339228</link><description>An immigration crackdown in the Midwestern state has been marred by protests and public anger after the shooting of two US citizens by federal agents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebad345af8d5ae5ca9b449aeb32b47bb</guid></item><item><title>What living in a multigenerational home with one of your parents is really like</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/multigenerational-home-grand-designs-transformations-reality/106331396</link><description>Kay and her daughter, Cat, moved back in together a year ago — along with Cat's husband and their three kids. This is the reality of what it's like living with three generations under one roof.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3af29ad48f8e5edb33eee4096469d8b3</guid></item><item><title>Liberal Party poised to dump first female federal leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/liberal-party-poised-to-dump-first-female-leader/106338452</link><description>The Liberal Party is poised to dump its first federal female leader, with Sussan Ley's supporters acknowledging her rival, Angus Taylor, is in the "ascendancy".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6149b17b767527046bc7170e8b43226a</guid></item><item><title>3,100 aged care patients stranded in hospitals as states again press Commonwealth for action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/aged-care-hospital-funding-bed-block/106336820</link><description>With the ink still wet on a new hospital deal, state and territory health ministers will today use a meeting with their federal counterpart to call for urgent action on stranded patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db2af93a0e38f039ffeb1e1ccf5f3042</guid></item><item><title>Water utility 'confident' Hobart drinking water is antibiotic-free after salmon disease outbreak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/salmon-disease-outbreak-antibiotics-river-derwent/106330724</link><description>Tasmania's water provider says there is no risk of antibiotics entering Hobart's water supply, following Huon Aquaculture's use of oxytetracycline in the River Derwent to treat a disease outbreak.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1dee99594bcccdd9569ae25d5806d21</guid></item><item><title>Men face drug cultivation charges after $10 million cannabis bust in Victoria's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/men-face-commercial-drug-cultivation-charges-after-cannabis-bust/106338128</link><description>Police allege a drug bust in Victoria's north-west has uncovered 10 large grow houses cultivating $10 million worth of illegal cannabis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7d9fee7539b4a4ea68bd8031cfeac2b</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: A leadership spill, a ghost barge and mysterious balls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/weekly-news-quiz-february-13/106336680</link><description>Have you been paying attention to the headlines this week? Test yourself here.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8661fd8f3afb21c5f2bd8d2ebafdb227</guid></item><item><title>Italy wins first T20 Cricket World Cup match as Australian-born players shine in 10-wicket win over Nepal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/italy-wins-first-t20-cricket-world-cup-match/106339406</link><description>Sydney-born brothers Justin and Anthony Mosca have guided T20 World Cup debutants Italy to their first win in the tournament, as their unbeaten half-centuries secured a dominant 10-wicket victory over Nepal on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3c6d0fe17105b65b0990f4c481c3845</guid></item><item><title>Cooper Woods, Australia's unexpected Winter Olympic champion, finds his purpose</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/cooper-woods-australias-unexpected-champion-winter-olympics/106339106</link><description>Cooper Woods came into the 2026 Winter Olympic Games ranked 22nd in the World Cup rankings in moguls. But in finding his purpose, he roared to a glorious gold medal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ca54a379cdb065db55986946103d8e3</guid></item><item><title>ASX boss to depart as another controversy unfolds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/asx-boss-to-depart-as-another-controversy-unfolds/106336322</link><description>A decade of technology failures, unplanned outages, management upheaval, irate investors and the torching of hundreds of millions of dollars has left the ASX's reputation in shreds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d1cb6399c00e87f8a119dacdf9976aa</guid></item><item><title>Epstein victims stand up during House Judiciary Committee hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/epstein-victims-stand-up-during-house-judiciary-committee/106336132</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9715195d155fadad84500e2798d0720</guid></item><item><title>Epstein survivor says release of files was 're-traumatising' and falls short of transparency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/epstein-survivor-says-release-of-files-retraumatising/106317616</link><description>Lisa Phillips says the publication of the "Epstein" files was meant to deliver long-promised transparency but has instead exposed victims, deepened trauma and continued to shield powerful men.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">702d35e388b86c7214a684bca057a62f</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor wants to be the new leader of the Liberal Party. Who is he?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/who-is-liberal-party-leader-hopeful-angus-taylor/105268090</link><description>Angus Taylor will challenge Sussan Ley for the leadership of the Liberal Party, saying he no longer has faith that she can lead the party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da8415b8432271ddc8217b42ad3a877c</guid></item><item><title>Economist Bruce Preston appointed to RBA Board</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/economist-bruce-preston-appointed-to-rba-board/106337708</link><description>The economics professor is the second academic economist added to the board since a review recommended boosting its expertise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c0edb3495c53e1eb1dd6f353acd5bef</guid></item><item><title>The Christchurch terrorist changed New Zealand, now he is testing its legal system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/christchurch-terrorst-testing-nz-legal-system/106336320</link><description>It may be months before New Zealand finds out if the Christchurch terrorist will be granted an application to have his guilty pleas vacated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ffbd3cb1612c1e71fa5e4924f4f9071</guid></item><item><title>Lake Cargelligo residents live in fear as Julian Ingram clocks up three weeks on the run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/lake-cargelligo-struggles-as-julian-ingram-search-continues/106329894</link><description>As alleged triple-murderer Julian Ingram notches up three weeks on the run, residents in the small town are struggling to heal from shootings that rocked the community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dddd0fec0d64e1564639a60814b2225</guid></item><item><title>More than 100 Stolen Generations survivors gather for apology anniversary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/largest-gathering-of-stolen-generations-survivors-for-apology/106322950</link><description>More than 100 Stolen Generations survivors have gathered in Canberra for the apology anniversary. The government is pledging new money to help them heal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c81bef72da28cb61fb66cddb9bf13666</guid></item><item><title>Marine biologists fight to save endangered seagrass species in Sydney Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/science-key-to-saving-endangered-seagrass-population/106337120</link><description>A centuries-old nautical technique is being redesigned within a small Sydney cove in a bid to save a tiny remnant population of a dying species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c23125b58cdf591c3340528784e5fcd</guid></item><item><title>Intense rainfall risk for south-east Queensland as whole state set for 'wet and stormy' weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/intense-rainfall-south-east-qld-wet-condtions-queensland/106331410</link><description>South-east Queensland is being told to brace for an intense soaking from today, with up to 200 millimetres to fall in some coastal areas, with rainfall all weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">554feef4458ed64818b6a117e26a1463</guid></item><item><title>The 'farm-fluencers' taking agriculture online to bridge the rural divide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/farmer-influencers-sharing-rural-lives-online-content-creators/106326048</link><description>Farmers and agricultural workers are taking to social media to educate a new audience while building a community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed4626a80b6a8b07114590acfaf1a595</guid></item><item><title>Queensland police given greater powers to pursue animal abusers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/queensland-police-given-greater-powers-to-pursue-animal-abusers/106338042</link><description>Queensland police will be able to pursue animal abusers without seeking permission from a government department after regulation change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f16d1b253b7407790bb6843d7ac0cd0f</guid></item><item><title>Cost-of-living crisis sees more young women neglecting health and basic needs, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/young-women-cost-of-living-crisis-basic-needs/106300314</link><description>A study from Deakin University has found many young women admit skipping meals or forgoing medical attention to save money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5cd45054bcabb5c8fa618e72defa4a5</guid></item><item><title>Openly gay men in elite sport are rare, leaving women to lead the way for queer inclusion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/queer-lgbtiqa-inclusion-womens-sport-anneli-maley-wnbl-pride-cup/106149906</link><description>While high profile instances of homophobia in elite men's sport continue, leading female athletes are hoping to help create more inclusive spaces for all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70321d6613ab8607cbaea120ca706e88</guid></item><item><title>Four charged after $10 million cannabis crop busted in Victoria's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/four-charged-after-10-million-cannabis-crop-busted-/106339512</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b696f2667e1fc6727a09310d1c0869ee</guid></item><item><title>Consumers back call for country-of-origin labels on timber sold in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/calls-for-timber-wood-product-country-origin-labels/106335698</link><description>Consumer advocates and the wood products industry say it is time the origin of timber was made clear, as imports grow year-on-year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e45cbaa92971f939d0856d9c106483b</guid></item><item><title>What a 566yo coolabah tree in the Gwydir Wetlands could tell us about climate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/gwydir-wetlands-566-year-old-coolabah-tree-climate-history/106325412</link><description>New research shows some of the coolabahs and river red gums in the Gwydir Wetlands, New South Wales are hundreds of years old, and hold important climate history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a88c850ac8f236466b63627c9ffafc9e</guid></item><item><title>Live: Angus Taylor overwhelmingly wins Liberal leadership, Jane Hume voted deputy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/federal-politics-live-blog-liberal-spill/106339480</link><description>Angus Taylor has been chosen as the new Liberal leader after defeating Sussan Ley 34 votes to 17, with Jane Hume elected deputy. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e54c956be73e4b8996ca621b91910220</guid></item><item><title>Kim Jong Un set to pick daughter Kim Ju Ae to lead North Korea, South Korean intelligence says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/kim-jong-un-to-pick-kim-ju-ae-as-next-leader-south-korea-says/106339110</link><description>South Korea's spy agency says that Kim Jong Un is set to choose his daughter as his heir, extending his family's rule into a fourth generation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37569486a4575609470e58b928b30b7e</guid></item><item><title>Max Verstappen critical of new Formula 1 cars as preseason testing continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/max-verstappen-critical-of-new-formula-1-cars/106339508</link><description>Four-time Formula 1 world champion Max Verstappen says the 2026 cars are "not so fun", claiming the increasing energy management demands on drivers are "just not Formula 1".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">950bfbf36871e9c9d62401075e1fd446</guid></item><item><title>NT Australian of the Year Felix Ho volunteers thousands of hours to the community each year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/nt-australian-of-year-dr-felix-ho-thousands-of-volunteer-hours/106329556</link><description>Finding time to volunteer can be a stretch for most people, but for Darwin doctor Felix Ho, who volunteers thousands of hours every year, it's his "full-time hobby".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b99c4561a769bc93eea33549024a298</guid></item><item><title>Live: ASX headed for Friday 13th curse as AI fears stoke market downturn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/asx-markets-business-live-news-feb-13-2026/106339608</link><description>Meanwhile, the Webjet and Helloworld merger has fallen through, and Westpac is the latest Big Four bank to report rising profits. Follow the day's events and insights as they happen with our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18fef90dc73d15c4a2fdb264a54d455d</guid></item><item><title>Thai raid finds Cambodian scam centre had personal details of 300 Australians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/australians-targeted-by-cambodian-scam-compound/106335866</link><description>Australia's National Anti-Scam Centre says documents seized in a raid on a Cambodian scam compound contained the phone numbers, names and addresses of 300 Australians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08f7a75e42a1578ec6ae98632dc8210b</guid></item><item><title>Why do some regional councils charge for car parking in country towns, while others don't?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/paid-parking-council-in-victoria-parking-meters-fines-cost/106314960</link><description>Parking meters have been ripped out in some country towns, while in others, motorists are still being slugged, and retailers are feeling the pinch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bee258382b42dba9b9634ad0cdab2b36</guid></item><item><title>From new life to grief, Ella Macens's music for the Melbourne Symphony Orchestra is rooted in love</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/music-by-australian-ella-macens-premiered-by-melbourne-symphony/106323262</link><description>After experiencing the Bondi terror attack in December, this composer's new music grew to encompass love's power to heal us from hate and harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bbfdad77654f3b7445bd689a1085326</guid></item><item><title>The key factor that will define your NRL team's chances in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/2026-nrl-season-preview-key-stats/106334724</link><description>With the preseason challenge well underway and the season-opening matches in Las Vegas on the horizon, find out the key numbers that will make or break your team's NRL chances for 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdbd63c61f95bb7099a8f344adfd200e</guid></item><item><title>Raymond Reddington blamed wife Sharon Fulton's disappearance on serial killers David and Catherine Birnie, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/raymond-reddington-blamed-serial-killer-birnies-for-missing-wife/106336720</link><description>Notorious Perth serial killers David and Catherine Birnie could not be ruled out as suspects in the alleged murder of a woman who vanished in the same year they killed four young women, the detective who arrested them tells a court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2bbe9165743f94c76dde41edb99743d</guid></item><item><title>Trump repeals power to regulate climate, axes vehicle emissions rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/trump-revokes-basis-of-us-climate-regulation-ends-vehicle-emissi/106339598</link><description>President Donald Trump's administration has revoked a scientific finding that has been the central basis for US action to fight climate change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14587c3b8bd37c5943c0d33c136fd2f9</guid></item><item><title>Keen to declutter this year? Here’s how to start</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/simple-ways-to-start-decluttering-at-home/106300708</link><description>Experts say you don’t need to pull out the entire contents of a cupboard, beginning with one bag is best.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a8e041b72c037976f8eb5cb64a4f2a3</guid></item><item><title>Albemarle lithium refinery closure gives WA government a critical minerals reality check</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/kemerton-lithium-closure-wa-processing-challenges/106336122</link><description>It was once hoped WA would be in the "box seat" to process critical minerals like lithium. So why are processors like Albemarle pulling the pin?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebccfda86e0d4862543de2b4952b4ff5</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Breezy Johnson gets engaged at the Games, Snoop Dogg shows plenty of support — quick hits from day six</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/sport-winter-olympics-quick-hits-day-six/106339098</link><description>Breezy Johnson's pain of crashing was washed away by the euphoria of love, while Snoop Dogg showed his support with a magnificent snow jacket. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59bf59903ae0317ba477a60054f1e33f</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor becomes Liberal leader, defeating Sussan Ley 34-17</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/angus-taylor-becomes-liberal-leader/106339798</link><description>Sussan Ley, the first female leader of the Liberal Party, has been replaced by Angus Taylor after nine months in the role.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fa7d372d6cff076b3d6fe902ba524d0</guid></item><item><title>Former Tottenham manager Ange Postecoglou says Spurs 'not a big club' in wake of Thomas Frank sacking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/former-tottenham-manager-ange-postecoglou-on-club-issues/106339490</link><description>Tottenham Hotspur are "not a big club" because of their policy in the transfer market, former manager Ange Postecoglou has said in the wake of the London club's sacking of head coach Thomas Frank on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ce56a4955c12cf141f86e6540834b3a</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with stalking Israeli President Isaac Herzog during Sydney visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/man-allegedly-stalked-israeli-president-isaac-herzog-sydney/106339786</link><description>Police also allege the 45-year-old man stopped outside a school at Bondi Junction and filmed a security guard while using offensive language.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff670e1d1d3c662da8553512a71dae6c</guid></item><item><title>Family push for Sunshine Coast neurosurgery unit after shock brain cancer diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/family-push-for-neurosurgery-sunshine-coast-hospital/106321492</link><description>Despite living in one of Queensland's most populated areas, Sunshine Coast residents are still travelling to Brisbane to access life-saving neurosurgery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca9ad85102b860a2aa548084e02b8a5a</guid></item><item><title>Cooper Woods' mum reacts after stunning gold medal win in Men’'s Moguls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/cooper-woods-mum-reacts-after-stunning-gold-medal-win-/106339924</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9330246f2d9b13f2b20e5765e9270dc4</guid></item></channel></rss>