<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 17:44:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Populist billionaire Andrej Babiš wins Czech Republic parliamentary election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/andrej-babis-ano-wins-czech-republic-parliamentary-election/105853348</link><description>The party of billionaire and self-declared "Trumpist" Andrej Babiš wins the Czech Republic's parliamentary election, near-final results show, which could steer the country away from supporting Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebf46c1ca99f4a6100682da1f8980f37</guid></item><item><title>How the Tallis Scholars opened the world of sacred choral music to new audiences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/how-the-tallis-scholars-opened-the-world-of-sacred-choral-music/105849010</link><description>This English vocal group took centuries-old church music from the archives and became a hit. They're back in Australia sharing this music with local audiences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfc9ac542d3a1aa952c8f8d59dcfbf8c</guid></item><item><title>Economics rather than environmental concerns could sink Woodside's proposed Browse gas project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/economic-doubts-over-browse-gas-project/105838392</link><description>The Browse gas project is staring down the full weight of Australia's climate movement. Analysts say that is the least of its worries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecf5fc2ff00cdd38128ff1bdcd14da3a</guid></item><item><title>One Battle After Another, Paul Thomas Anderson's latest film, already eyed for Oscar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/one-battle-after-another-paul-thomas-anderson-film/105838240</link><description>One Battle After Another, starring Leonardo DiCaprio, uses the ever-turning wheel of political violence as a backdrop for a screwball adventure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e9722e5be393220e3ef6d51a097c812</guid></item><item><title>Australia was champion of the world three years ago, but now softball teams are struggling to find players</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/softball-decline-struggle-young-players-exposure-olympics/105851876</link><description>It was a schoolyard sport so common it once rivalled cricket as the most popular in Australia. But now grassroots teams are struggling to fill a team sheet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c27d12acae797957e866d7008cdb6895</guid></item><item><title>Some South Australian farmers facing long road to drought recovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/farmers-begin-long-recovery-after-year-long-sa-drought/105850610</link><description>Some South Australian farmers say they are still feeling the strain of drought after inconsistent winter rains left little room for recovery before the coming summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17b9cb9e734d8bd60eb0db15cbdbb695</guid></item><item><title>Alex De Minaur hits career-best mark with win at Shanghai Masters as ATP Finals loom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/de-minaur-hits-career-best-mark-with-win-at-shanghai-masters/105853398</link><description>Alex de Minaur sets a new personal record for wins in a year with a comfortable victory over Camilo Ugo Carabelli at the Shanghai Masters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc0f8ea3048522dab91e7a69c9ce7eed</guid></item><item><title>Prospecting mates who found Ming Dynasty Buddha urge prime minister to help repatriate it to China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/buddha-found-in-shark-bay-urged-to-be-repatriated/105831250</link><description>A Ming Dynasty Buddha statue found on a roadside in Western Australia's Shark Bay region seven years ago could soon be repatriated to the largest Buddhist population in the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b1dda99c49d71b70e55094f4a9bda4f</guid></item><item><title>Jahrome Hughes says he 'used to hate' the Storm as he prepares for grand final battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/melbourne-storm-grand-final-jahrome-hughes/105853438</link><description>Jahrome Hughes admits to once being sick of watching Melbourne win, but now the Kiwi can help lead them to another premiership in the NRL grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb3575fddded9eff46b74687c29f66c2</guid></item><item><title>Line dancing helps Queensland community connect and keep moving</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/line-dancing-popularity-helps-queensland-community-connect-move/105815880</link><description>Organisers behind line dancing events say more people are coming to their evenings, and social media is driving its popularity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47723861c4ac72827fe3eb93195e70de</guid></item><item><title>Health workers say NT leading the nation in hepatitis B care, as diagnoses jump but mortality rates plummet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nt-hepatitis-b-diagnoses-rising-as-mortality-rates-decrease/105840336</link><description>Health workers say new data showing hepatitis B cases have almost tripled in the NT reflects better access to care, with the territory also leading the nation in reducing mortality rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5fdc774928dc47194833017cc4f13b2</guid></item><item><title>Babe's 30th anniversary celebrated in Robertson where film was shot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/robertson-celebrates-30-years-since-babe-was-shot-in-the-town/105847244</link><description>Decades after hosting film crews making a children's movie about a loveable piglet, the town of Robertson in New South Wales is transformed into a country fair in tribute.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ee021ffad919f20582293d03868a10f</guid></item><item><title>UK police hold four people on suspicion of terror offences over Manchester synagogue attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/uk-police-questioning-suspects-over-manchester-synagogue-attack/105853442</link><description>UK police are continuing to question four people arrested on suspicion of terror offences after an attack on a Manchester synagogue on Thursday that left two people dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f504af9ec1ed1ca1c5c9be82bfde77ae</guid></item><item><title>Greens leader Larissa Waters 'doesn't know very much' about wind farm opposed by colleagues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/greens-leader-larissa-waters-unsure-about-tasmanian-wind-farm/105853456</link><description>Larissa Waters says she will be looking closely at the Robbins Island wind farm, which the Greens's two Tasmanian senators say will threaten several endangered species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04a1ed328b028d7562d776de27573de1</guid></item><item><title>Make-ahead dinners for busy weeknights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/easy-make-ahead-meal-prep-dinners-for-busy-weeknights/105668174</link><description>Don't have time to cook most nights? These easy meals serve up to eight people and can get you through the week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9395351dbe146c8ee8681dfb00636a06</guid></item><item><title>Community saves endangered tropical sea turtle that washed up on Esperance beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/esperance-tropical-green-turtle-visitor-north-west-wa/105839222</link><description>A community has sprung into action to nurse a juvenile tropical turtle back to health as wildlife carers question how it found its way to WA's south coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4ac34391201416c37af31bac8b03de5</guid></item><item><title>Harry Lush is handing out alpine plants to form a large-scale urban climate refuge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/harry-lush-director-of-gondwana-project/105853556</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc052d43324e94b02a9758439e00028f</guid></item><item><title>English springer spaniels Kelly and Milo helping fight dieback in Western Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/dieback-dogs-helping-fight-deadly-plant-disease/105849444</link><description>Two dogs join the fight against one of the biggest threats to Australia's native plants, making dieback detection possible in minutes rather than weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba971c766d020d17dfa85d059b2edf3b</guid></item><item><title>I got an unexpected afternoon tea invitation, and it told me a lot about Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/analysis-on-alexander-stubb-and-donald-trump-relationship/105851222</link><description>An afternoon tea meeting with a president is not the sort of invitation you get every day as a foreign correspondent, but when I met Finland's Alexander Stubb in Helsinki, it taught me a lot about another world leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e77bd18c49c780231a41cb654add893</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged with murder of man believed to be her partner, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/woman-charged-with-port-pirie-south-death/105853574</link><description>A woman has been charged with murder after a man was reported unconscious in South Australia's mid-north on Friday and could not be revived.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">195d8cc77414e8fdb07fdc21853e9c01</guid></item><item><title>Homicide Squad investigating 'suspicious' death of 84yo woman in Sydney suburb of Melonba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nsw-body-of-84yo-woman-in-her-melonba-home/105853626</link><description>The Homicide Squad is investigating the circumstances surrounding the death of an 84-year-old woman, who was found in her bedroom about midday Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b4f04ad76b564efa423012267ca9387</guid></item><item><title>Trump authorises deployment of 300 National Guard troops to Chicago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/trump-deploys-300-national-guard-troops-chicago/105853704</link><description>US President Donald Trump has deployed 300 Illinois National Guard troops to Chicago after Governor JB Pritzker refused to do so.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e09d2adca78710fda0a973cf63b4970</guid></item><item><title>Who is Sanae Takaichi, set to be Japan's first female PM?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/sanae-takaichi-japan-ldp-leadership-prime-minister/105853536</link><description>Sanae Takaichi has won Japan's Liberal Democratic Party's leadership contest and is likely to become the country's first female PM. Here's what we know about her.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">168ace564993b12a633f0b1f582bf714</guid></item><item><title>US Treasury unveils draft design for $1 Trump coin to mark 250th independence celebrations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/trump-coil-revealed/105853576</link><description>In 2020, the US Congress passed a law that allows the Treasury Secretary to mint $1 coins in 2026 "with designs emblematic of the US semi-quincentennial".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf499095bc04f4aa61baf295fc27ca60</guid></item><item><title>Mark Latham's ex-girlfriend Nathalie Matthews charged with sharing intimate images</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nathalie-matthews-charged-with-sharing-intimate-image/105853710</link><description>Nathalie Matthews, 38, was arrested after arriving into Sydney on a flight from Dubai this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df15eecd1f673f45c221819524098f94</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos beat Melbourne Storm in epic NRL grand final, Adam Reynolds injured, Brisbane ends Roosters' NRLW streak in decider</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nrl-grand-final-live-blog-melbourne-storm-brisbane-broncos/105847434</link><description>The Brisbane Broncos beat the Melbourne Storm 26-22 in the NRL grand final despite losing both halves to injury in the second half.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7354e645e2773f7438e3a91beca5cf8b</guid></item><item><title>More than 100 guns seized in WA Police raids targeting 'sovereign citizens'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/guns-seized-in-wa-police-sovereign-citizen-raid/105853620</link><description>More than 100 firearms are seized in a WA Police operation targeting 'sovereign citizens' in the wake of the fatal shooting of two Victorian officers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2549afbffbbe684a4f55011bd86c5acd</guid></item><item><title>Mega-team of heavy horses sets world record at Good Old Days Festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/record-breaking-feat-for-mega-team-of-heavy-horses/105853716</link><description>Scores of heavy horses have been harnessed together at a heritage festival in southern New South Wales in what organisers say is a world record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82701463d0333bf75c6cf5d657e9b923</guid></item><item><title>European Space Agency launches second space antenna in New Norcia, north of Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/space-agency-opens-second-deep-space-antenna-new-norcia/105849820</link><description>A second deep space antenna opened in a tiny monastic town in Western Australia could help unlock the secrets of the universe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">897e2da31ddeaef33af502525555b9b4</guid></item><item><title>Mass civil wedding in Paraguay's capital sees more than 600 couples say 'I do' in unison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/mass-civil-wedding-paraguay/105853878</link><description>The event was part of a government campaign aiming to make civil weddings more accessible across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f3c3cca78b4fbbc1b5508b945213e55</guid></item><item><title>Tigers end AFLW drought in shock 11-point win over Crows as Blues and Eagles enjoy victories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/aflw-tigers-crows-cats-blues-eagles-magpies-round-eight/105854110</link><description>Richmond's dismal losing streak is over, with midfielder Monique Conti playing a starring role in a shock win over competition heavyweights Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebb6f06da858950421d033911c808ba2</guid></item><item><title>Authorities will investigate campfire that sparked major Moreton Island blaze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/campfire-moreton-island-bushfire-alert/105853820</link><description>A "careless" campfire lit during a fire ban sparked a rapidly moving blaze that has now burnt hundreds of hectares on Moreton Island, according to authorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce8c6a567bd717f2cc696fa8de3e838f</guid></item><item><title>Liberty Bell Bay smelter receives first shipment of ore since flagging financial woes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/liberty-bay-bell-smelter-receives-first-ore-shipment/105853550</link><description>A $20 million loan from the Tasmanian government to keep smelter Liberty Bell Bay afloat after it flagged financial woes earlier this year has led to the first shipment of ore being delivered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">091231e8b6fe5383bb688542b2c8f6b2</guid></item><item><title>Police seize 135 firearms in sovereign citizen raids across WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/police-seize-135-firearms-in-sovereign-citizen/105854230</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dcf4833c0e8d17a4c1871b43ee48f52</guid></item><item><title>Mele Hufanga's NRLW premiership-winning try now an unsolvable mystery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nrlw-grand-final-broncos-roosters-hufanga-try-decision-analysis/105854160</link><description>Brisbane and the Roosters played one of the greatest games in NRLW history, but the controversial winning try to Mele Hufanga shapes as a football mystery that might never be solved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43c47d417ebdd6d90d15557efded717f</guid></item><item><title>Man in critical condition after shooting in Sydney's Croydon Park as police arrest alleged gunman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/man-arrested-after-shooting-in-sydney-croydon-park/105854454</link><description>NSW Police say the alleged gunman had been "firing indiscriminately at passing vehicles including police vehicles".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f80a42b7620b731f82ec58637dfdb05</guid></item><item><title>Reece Walsh wins Clive Churchill Medal to ice Broncos' NRL premiership success</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nrl-grand-final-reece-walsh-wins-clive-churchill-medal-broncos/105854358</link><description>In one of the greatest individual performances in grand final history, Brisbane Broncos star Reece Walsh was judged player of the match after inspiring his side to their victory over the Melbourne Storm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4da114fbdd73820852f227f68040d6f</guid></item><item><title>NRL grand final quick hits: Reece Walsh rushes to catch a concussed Ben Hunt and Broncos overcome injury toll</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nrl-grand-final-quick-hits-walsh-sin-bin-hunt-reynolds-injuries/105854254</link><description>Reece Walsh put in an NRL grand final performance for the ages after an early stroke of luck as the Brisbane Broncos survived the loss of both Ben Hunt and Adam Reynolds to end a 19-year premiership drought.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa2378f6001893fa3c85d8ab5c40ad05</guid></item><item><title>How the internet reacted to Brisbane Broncos winning the NRL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/internet-reacted-nrl-grand-final-reece-walsh-brisbane-broncos/105854070</link><description>The internet could barely believe what was happening as Brisbane, fuelled by Reece Walsh's brilliance, came from behind to win the NRL grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a773abe9892dbaf9421d194401021d35</guid></item><item><title>Why Brisbane Broncos's NRL premiership win is more about blood than gold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nrl-broncos-grand-final-win-reece-walsh-analysis/105854570</link><description>The Brisbane Broncos are flash and have never made apologies for it but, with their premiership win, they've proven they also have the true steel of champions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6201902fe26b76b27ebc4fd091ddb55</guid></item><item><title>Australia's de facto online betting regulator accused of being too close to gambling industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/nt-betting-regulator-accused-close-industry-four-corners/105848692</link><description>Four Corners has uncovered allegations of conflicts of interest and pro-industry bias at the country's part-time regulator responsible for Australia's biggest betting companies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95e49d8f6b396c0b6df1586a0c5a3614</guid></item><item><title>Inside the mission to rescue dachshund Valerie from wild 529-day Kangaroo Island ordeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/how-valerie-became-the-worlds-most-notorious-sausage-dog/105832548</link><description>Valerie's disappearance on South Australia's Kangaroo Island unleashed a 529-day hunt. She dodged rescue attempts and traps and had some wondering whether the sausage dog was mocking them and having the time of her life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98688fa4bd2992085d88df58549d292f</guid></item><item><title>Documents reveal Australia's F-35 fighter jet export details 'quietly' disappeared</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/f-35-jet-fighter-supply-chain-israel-gaza-weapons-transfers/105783858</link><description>Department of Defence emails show that a website dedicated to Australia's role in the global F-35 supply chain used by Israel to maintain its fighter jets was removed at the start of the war in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6c999b923749d4e0235e817b0cee3d7</guid></item><item><title>Housing supply without controlling demand suggests National Housing Accord won't fix affordability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/house-affordability-density-accord-first-home-buyer-cgt-student/105853500</link><description>The national project to fix housing affordability is off to a slow start but, from deposit schemes and negative gearing to immigration and construction delays, the reasons are complex.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f17886ca0bcb641add48e0a7f3cfd6e</guid></item><item><title>Russia launches drone and missile strikes on Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/russia-launches-drone-and-missile-strikes-on-ukraine/105854890</link><description>Authorities say nine regions across Ukraine were targeted by Russian night-time drone, missile and aerial bomb strikes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f563c2b2939092915726701d0a52f84</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm's new normal falls short in NRL grand finals and they're running out of chances</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/melbourne-storm-lose-second-straight-nrl-grand-final/105854346</link><description>The new and infinitely more exciting Melbourne Storm are finding out just how hard it is to play their exciting brand of footy when the tension is at its peak.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcc664b062ddc697654eb02247e6160e</guid></item><item><title>SA seafood demand still down as algal bloom safety message struggles to break through</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/sa-seafood-downturn-amid-algal-bloom/105838042</link><description>While industry and government tell consumers South Australian seafood is safe, consumer demand is still down amid the algal bloom, with businesses concerned they may not survive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f24ed267df69707658f158333dbd9ab</guid></item><item><title>SA foster care providers working to bring more culturally and linguistically diverse carers into the system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/culturally-and-linguistically-diverse-foster-carers/105755058</link><description>Masooma came to Adelaide as a refugee from Afghanistan in 2016, and has become the carer of a young girl from a similar cultural background. Experts say it is important carers reflected the diversity of children in care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad4334b7c6f485a97c49e24582a7b6f8</guid></item><item><title>The Sydney street workers helping get young people's lives back on track</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/youth-workers-break-barriers-with-young-people-in-sydney/105815280</link><description>Some of Sydney's vulnerable young people are being steered away from a life of crime, addiction and homelessness by a pair of youth workers who have had their own share of hardships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f11fa1e0d849012711a85134f7fad152</guid></item><item><title>Decades-old 'conversion therapy' resurfaces in today's trans youth healthcare debate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/conversion-therapy-trans-paper-pushed-decades-later/105850280</link><description>A decades-old psychiatric study is influencing current debates over transgender youth health care. But a new analysis led by a survivor says the findings were deeply harmful and dangerously misleading.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e95b828d4654c4252282ff2e665291d0</guid></item><item><title>Older Territorians say they still feel unsafe as residents' homes targeted by armed thugs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/calls-for-nt-ban-on-machetes-and-crossbows/105747486</link><description>There are growing calls for the NT government to ban machetes and crossbows as older residents share horror stories of being targeted in their own homes by armed youths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98526e141c9a7f83758a60d5e4e60adc</guid></item><item><title>Ten years on from 2015, Ben Hunt wins the Broncos premiership he's waited for his whole life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/ben-hunt-wins-nrl-grand-final-with-brisbane-broncos/105854350</link><description>Defeat in the 2015 decider was so scarring, Hunt eventually felt the need to move away from the club he loves. Ten years later and back in his home colours, he's a 350-game, premiership-winning NRL player.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f8db8ef48ab55750750e26bd011f36b</guid></item><item><title>Calls to ban machetes as elderly Territorians terrorised in their own homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/stateline-nt-calls-ban-machetes-as-elderly-territorians-hurt/105855298</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50227819e4fb3d1211eb8ade2e674398</guid></item><item><title>Outback businesses raise concerns about Services Australia's Centrepay reforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/outback-wa-retailers-worried-about-centrepay-reforms/105844344</link><description>Business owners worry major changes to a buy now, pay later system used by about 500,000 social security recipients will cause a raft of issues when it begins next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df02be8a6f258116a4f810bdcb01fba1</guid></item><item><title>Griffin Coal failure sees WA taxpayers fork out millions to Indian bank, despite government promises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/taxpayer-dollars-leak-offshore-amid-griffin-coal-failure/105846232</link><description>The WA government is facing fresh questions over its bailout of Griffin Coal — a mine critical to the state's energy system — amid revelations taxpayer money is leaking offshore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f293a0b660fb2a630645a7606afe128</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, day one: Essendon firm on Zach Merrett as Carlton set to play hardball with Charlie Curnow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/afl-trade-period-day-one-live-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca/105853514</link><description>Essendon once again firmly states that captain Zach Merrett will not leave the Bombers as all 18 clubs begin the wheeling and dealing on the first day of the AFL's trade period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf92b2ca3ab4ca2c9aa8406b4938bc0c</guid></item><item><title>Three youths charged with arson after fire at Ashley Youth Detention Centre in northern Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/young-people-fire-ashley-youth-detention-centre/105855982</link><description>Police said they were called to the site on Sunday afternoon following reports of a disturbance involving three armed youths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aacbe521773d620d44778bcc8d5ca1c4</guid></item><item><title>The chicken and egg dilemma fuelling house prices – 6 October 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/the-chicken-and-egg-dilemma-fuelling-house-prices-/105856110</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af996de1ea6ee0eff39713353a3ab126</guid></item><item><title>Former NFL quarterback Mark Sanchez charged after being stabbed in altercation with truck driver</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/former-nfl-quarterback-mark-sanchez-stabbed-and-charged/105856006</link><description>Fox Sports analyst and former NFL player Mark Sanchez is charged after being stabbed multiple times in an altercation with a truck driver.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60123ea56faac692d81f8adb084b0967</guid></item><item><title>Defiant Ange Postecoglou says he will fight back as Nottingham Forest lose again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/ange-postecoglou-defiant-after-another-loss/105856146</link><description>Ange Postecoglou fires up in a post-match press conference after Nottingham Forest lose to Newcastle United 2-0.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">628a8faa39f11e61f1e59c5dc3df9228</guid></item><item><title>NSW flood victims' personal details loaded to ChatGPT in major data breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/data-breach-northern-rivers-resilient-homes-program-chatgpt/105855284</link><description>The NSW Reconstruction Authority says the breach occurred in March and involved the personal data of applicants to the Northern Rivers Resilient Homes Program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">969bbd087c4743bb4d0cd5d00a3aefeb</guid></item><item><title>Clients of Melbourne builder MJ Harris Group lose life savings as company goes bust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/melbourne-builder-mike-harris-under-investigation/105849496</link><description>More than a dozen customers of MJ Harris Group have told the ABC they have been left significantly out of pocket after the company went into liquidation this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46d68729bac68ea68b04eb0537f41503</guid></item><item><title>Judge blocks Trump from deploying National Guard troops to Oregon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/judge-blocks-donald-trump-from-deploying-national-guard-oregon/105855384</link><description>A federal judge temporarily blocks Donald Trump from deploying Californian National Guard troops to Portland, after earlier blocking the US President from mobilising local troops in Oregon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcc61c937e41ec58121335fd63529179</guid></item><item><title>Reece Walsh's NRL grand-final heroics with Broncos rewarded with Kangaroos call-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/nrl-kangaroos-squad-ashes-reece-walsh-broncos-grand-final/105856380</link><description>Recognition of Reece Walsh's breathtaking performance in the NRL grand final continues, with the Brisbane Broncos hero set to make his Test debut for Australia later this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8158c6162030b6da5ff5baca267e3263</guid></item><item><title>What is task paralysis and how do you overcome it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/what-is-task-paralysis-and-how-to-overcome-it/105816676</link><description>Experts say feeling stuck or frozen when trying to start or complete a task can be the body's response to overwhelm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">148760b52f8431484adce2b1a2fde63d</guid></item><item><title>Broncos great Ali Brigginshaw to co-captain Jillaroos after NRLW grand final victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/nrlw-australia-jillaroos-brisbane-broncos-ali-brigginshaw/105856578</link><description>Ali Brigginshaw is named as a Jillaroos co-captain after helping steer the Brisbane Broncos to their fourth NRLW premiership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf319e012e91eeee866e7fc0a592b128</guid></item><item><title>As the AFLW begins to even out, North Melbourne remains untouchable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/north-melbourne-aflw-untouchable-as-comp-evens-out/105856458</link><description>North Melbourne claims its 20th win in a row as it looks to go undefeated for another season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4eb6269951bcaae08f99f7462a32cef</guid></item><item><title>Broncos star Pat Carrigan says a wooden spoon from 2020 helped motivate him for the grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/pat-carrigan-on-wooden-spoon-motivating-2025-nrl-grand-final-win/105856516</link><description>Fans left wooden spoons on Brisbane's training ground in 2020 — it was a move that helped motivate Pat Carrigan to greatness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3da51a345783afff5c94b8cb122d1f73</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man allegedly 'stormed a home', threatened mother and son with taser and demanded prescription drugs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/act-man-allegedly-threatens-mother-and-son-with-taser-in-home/105856840</link><description>A man who allegedly "stormed a home" and threatened a mother and son with a taser while demanding prescription drugs and cash will remain in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e72e6178e715991086eb171f7ccf0ce</guid></item><item><title>Forensics scour Croydon Park shooting scene as NSW Police probe motive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/sydney-croydon-park-shooting-dozens-injured/105855200</link><description>A suburb in Sydney's inner west was plunged into lockdown overnight after the alleged gunman, Artemios Mintzas, opened fire on passing cars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a20d6987b342fd746c29eecb1a0fa82a</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand pays $5.3 million to Samoa after sinking navy ship Manawanui on pristine reef</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/new-zealand-pays-compensation-samoa-manawanui-spill/105856488</link><description>The New Zealand government says it has done "the right thing" in offering a $5.3 million compensation payout to the Samoan government after its navy sunk a ship on a pristine reef off the Pacific island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99f964ebb4c46ee11f26209f97fd7525</guid></item><item><title>How much are NRL and NRLW premiership rings worth? What do they look like?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/how-much-nrl-nrlw-premiership-rings-worth-what-do-the-look-like/105856106</link><description>The men's rings are valued at $15,000, while the women's rings have a price tag of $10,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63575b695f4173281ef2a75ac53c102b</guid></item><item><title>Nathalie Matthews granted bail after airport arrest over sharing intimate image charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/nsw-nathalie-matthews-granted-bail-after-sydney-airport-arrest/105856636</link><description>Nathalie Matthews, 38, was arrested on Sunday morning after arriving on a flight from Dubai at Sydney Airport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f7b99fef1350a22661f690e945948c4</guid></item><item><title>Perth obstetrician Rhys Bellinge admits to reckless, dangerous driving days before fatal crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/perth-obstetrician-rhys-bellinge-pleads-guilty-driving-charges/105679920</link><description>Perth obstetrician Rhys Bellinge pleads guilty to driving dangerously and recklessly in the days before he crashed his car in Dalkeith and left a 24-year-old woman dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26d32c644d91222401685a921c93977d</guid></item><item><title>Why Kangaroos coach Kevin Walters is looking to the past ahead of Ashes series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/kangaroo-squad-ashes-kevin-walters-reece-walsh/105857268</link><description>New Kangaroos coach Kevin Walters was part of an era where the green and gold jersey was the highest honour rugby league could offer and ahead of the return of the Ashes it's a legacy he's desperate to pass down to his players.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58a50a4f00610fe11bdd54dcdff1814e</guid></item><item><title>Roosters forward Aliyah Nasio sent to judiciary over NRLW grand final brawl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/nrlw-grand-final-aliyah-nasio-roosters-judiciary/105857520</link><description>Sydney Roosters forward Aliyah Nasio is facing a ban for throwing a punch in the brawl at the conclusion of the NRLW grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d859f0db5c7d1d85425a636873ed3736</guid></item><item><title>Homicide investigation underway after man's body found in Bega park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/police-investigation-mans-body-bega-park/105856676</link><description>Homicide detectives are investigating the discovery of a man's body on the New South Wales far south coast overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19943022f4650103adecc9c6730dabfd</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne hands Ashes selectors reminder with Sheffield Shield century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/marnus-labuschagne-sheffield-shield-scores/105857408</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne has hit his first century in red ball cricket for over a year just one month out from the first Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a176bd65e86e8cee22777c8998188414</guid></item><item><title>More Optus triple-0 call failures on new dates, customers reveal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/more-optus-triple-zero-fails-outside-of-confirmed-times/105856172</link><description>Optus customers have come forward to report more cases of triple-0 calls failing outside the embattled telcos previously admitted outages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4358d6f86eb6a37293922181877cd73e</guid></item><item><title>Trump deploys National Guard in city deeply scarred by military force</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/national-guard-chicago-1968-history/105740956</link><description>The National Guard was deployed to Chicago streets in 1968. It changed the city forever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5de315904cfb310941c0e5754b3c7116</guid></item><item><title>Homeschool registrations are rising and policy needs to catch up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/australians-homeschooling-registrations-growth-queensland/105857486</link><description>Primary school homeschooling registrations in Queensland grew by 110 per cent from 2021 to 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2da6ac568e30445c88402c2dd8b19cc</guid></item><item><title>Australia and Papua New Guinea sign landmark alliance vowing to defend each other in conflict</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/australia-png-sign-defence-treaty-of-mutual-alliance/105858244</link><description>PNG and Australia formally sign a landmark new defence treaty, elevating the bilateral relationship between the two countries to an alliance and agreeing to "act to meet the common danger" if the other is attacked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">614af408f76065f8117ef33a6b854264</guid></item><item><title>Broncos shares surge 40 per cent after Grand Final win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/broncos-shares-surge-40-after-grand-final-win/105858608</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb9f530fa3b53960f57deb774eadfed4</guid></item><item><title>Forensic pathologist unable to say how 19-year-old Melbourne woman Isla Bell died</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/isla-bell-murder-committal-death-court/105856086</link><description>The body of Melbourne woman Isla Bell was so badly damaged that forensic experts were unable to say how she died, a court has been told.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a77bfa1fcf1d9df6ad88ac7f0731821</guid></item><item><title>Embarrassing roadside antics can't halt Tadej Pogačar's continued assault on cycling history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/embarrassing-roadside-antics-tadej-pogacar-european-champs/105858228</link><description>A spectator pulled down his pants and bared his bottom towards two-time reigning world cycling champion Tadej Pogačar, while others slapped stickers on his back. But the Slovenian still won the European Championships road race.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9609baf9b32ea2859f5f97ad797d35ad</guid></item><item><title>York family honours late son with tractor museum to fund cancer research</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/oliver-crane-tractor-museum-raises-money-for-cancer-research/105848104</link><description>Oliver Crane was diagnosed with bone cancer and died at age 17. This week, his family opened a vintage tractor museum in his memory to help raise money for cancer research.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13789f2997dab8a6f7214155c926b1c1</guid></item><item><title>Hikaru Nakamura accused of disrespecting chess world champion with wild celebration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/chess-player-throws-piece-after-checkmating-world-champion/105857474</link><description>World number two Hikaru Nakamura has beaten the current world champion Gukesh Dommaraju and thrown his king to the cheering crowd, prompting the chess world to debate whether it was showmanship or disrespect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83f02773a09d25c2b8d69f34bb6008ac</guid></item><item><title>Timothy Hunt convicted of murdering Tony Rowe after month-long Supreme Court trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/nt-darwin-man-timothy-hunt-convicted-murder-tony-rowe/105842404</link><description>Darwin man Timothy Hunt has been convicted of murdering Tony Rowe, whose remains were found on the city's outskirts in May 2023, one year after he was reported missing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bca0b60fc6589bb7b45b48088fbc19a5</guid></item><item><title>Director of Public Prosecutions to appeal Erin Patterson's sentence over mushroom murders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/dpp-appeal-erin-patterson-mushroom-murder-sentence/105858980</link><description>Victoria's Director of Public Prosecutions will appeal the sentence handed down to convicted triple-murderer Erin Patterson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63e8bcd098608d6f67fa643fd0271893</guid></item><item><title>Team Australia wins back-to-back Motocross of Nations titles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/team-australia-go-back-to-back-in-motocross-of-nations/105856060</link><description>Queensland brothers Jett and Hunter Lawrence help secure Australia's second consecutive Motocross of Nations title in Indiana.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c01890fe6dc96d2122a816cdf583308a</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle Yowies' dual glory in 2025 Koori Knockout rugby league finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/yowies-win-2025-koori-knockout-rugby-league-competitions/105857270</link><description>Yowies playmaker Kyle Laybutt kicks a mammoth field goal to seal victory in the men's final, while the Yowies women keep a clean sheet in their grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d04374ba9775987a358b27b3e554bf57</guid></item><item><title>Former Perth teacher Rodney Neville Watkins on trial for alleged historical sexual abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/rodney-neville-watkins-trial-sexually-abusing-boys/105858570</link><description>WA's District Court hears historical allegations a Perth teacher sexually abused multiple boys along with his partner, who was also a teacher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d977a74502395f7542a70b224d7ef0c</guid></item><item><title>Woman bailed as murder charge downgraded over Port Pirie man's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/murder-charge-against-woman-downgraded-over-port-pirie-man-death/105859010</link><description>A Port Pirie woman has been bailed after police downgraded a murder charge laid over the death of a man to aggravated assault.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e23adaa48e62532ba5950aca7687893</guid></item><item><title>Singapore PM offers condolences to families of Australians who died in Optus outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/singapore-pm-offers-condolences-to-families-of-optus-victims/105844832</link><description>Singapore's Prime Minister, Lawrence Wong, offers his condolences to the families of four Australians who died during an Optus network technical failure last month, which impacted hundreds of triple-0 calls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92e4a1d3ba99f0f05ba90b8864e4e46b</guid></item><item><title>England's 2003 Rugby World Cup winner Lewis Moody reveals MND diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/england-rugby-world-cup-winner-lewis-moodey-mnd-diagnosis/105859128</link><description>Lewis Moody, a former England rugby captain who helped his side win the 2003 World Cup, has been diagnosed with Motor Neurone Disease.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0125bfc995e3b0a490581c1e722fb8f3</guid></item><item><title>Greta Thunberg deported as Australian flotilla activists detained by Israel allege physical abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/australian-flotilla-activists-allege-israeli-authorities-abuse/105858942</link><description>Climate campaigner Greta Thunberg and more than 100 activists from the Gaza aid flotilla have been deported to Greece and Slovakia, Israel says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b714cb3ea153979a61059537e52b1de6</guid></item><item><title>Macron gives French PM Sébastien Lecornu two days to salvage administration after snap resignation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/french-pm-sebastien-lecornu-resigns/105859512</link><description>The president's move comes following Sébastien Lecornu's resignation just 14 hours after his appointment, plunging France into another political crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c15c6fa5fac96cdd6f330be716e37ae</guid></item><item><title>Papua New Guinea may sit out potential conflict between Australia and China despite Pukpuk defence treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/png-may-sit-out-australia-china-conflict-despite-defence-pct/105859432</link><description>Papua New Guinea Prime Minister James Marape says there is a "high possibility" the country would not enter a conflict involving Australia and China, despite having signed a mutual defence treaty with its southern neighbour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59feb7c5420f2241d7bceb57053d4049</guid></item><item><title>Monday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105859530</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">506757f396e017cb4299581c67727f19</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after allegedly driving ute towards woman and baby in Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/man-allegedly-drives-ute-towards-woman-baby-in-alice-springs/105859450</link><description>A man has been charged with a string of offences after allegedly driving a ute towards a woman and baby outside a shop in Alice Springs on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53b09fcf435c97092b892ed91ecc41ce</guid></item><item><title>Perth Royal Show attendance slumps to eight-year low</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/perth-royal-show-attendance-slumps-to-10-year-low/105857262</link><description>Attendance at this year's Perth Royal Show has hit an eight-year low, as organisers blame "heavy downpours" amid complaints from vendors about a lack of support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4db393861a1dcdbd2e0e82e56471da9</guid></item><item><title>English author Jilly Cooper, writer of The Rutshire Chronicles, dies at age 88</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/author-jilly-cooper-dies-at-age-88/105859754</link><description>The author was best known for The Rutshire Chronicles, including the novel Rivals, which was recently adapted into a Disney+ series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e8674f08b263feb4ef22338f75cf54a</guid></item><item><title>Trio of scientists win Nobel Prize in Medicine for 'discoveries concerning peripheral immune tolerance'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/scientists-win-nobel-prize-medicine-for-immune-system-work/105859742</link><description>The Nobel Prize for Medicine has been given to three scientists for discovering how our immune systems protect us from microbes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9af5df2f41780faee103603c8684e8f8</guid></item><item><title>Alleged Croydon Park gunman Artemios Mintzas charged with 25 offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/alleged-croydon-park-sydney-inner-west-shooter-charged/105859136</link><description>Artemios Mintzas, 60, will appear in a Sydney court charged over an alleged shooting spree that shut down an inner-west suburb for about two hours on Sunday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">986f11a7f0eebec2fb0bf6977ae58fea</guid></item><item><title>At least 63 people killed in Indonesia school collapse disaster in Java</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/indonesia-school-collapse-kills-at-least-63-people/105859952</link><description>The number of people killed in the disaster could still rise, with some half a dozen children still unaccounted for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb0eaac458f1bcf709a21c7c72610701</guid></item><item><title>Supreme Court rejects appeal from Ghislaine Maxwell, imprisoned former girlfriend of Jeffrey Epstein</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/supreme-court-rejects-appeal-from-ghislaine-maxwell/105860158</link><description>The US Supreme Court declines to hear Ghislaine Maxwell's bid to overturn her conviction for helping the late financier and convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein sexually abuse teenage girls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d5b59aebdf4950f84d1fdd5f88e9eba</guid></item><item><title>Gisèle Pelicot will face one of her rapists once again in a French appeals case. Here's why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/gis%C3%A8le-pelicot-to-face-rapist-once-again-in-french-appeals-case/105859998</link><description>Less than a year after the landmark trial which shook the world, Gisèle Pelicot will once again brave a courtroom as one of her rapists appeals his sentence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0842838fb7ae8d253dc4d643711b09f</guid></item><item><title>Australians released from Israeli detention after alleged beatings, according to DFAT report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/australians-from-flotilla-to-gaza-reports-from-israel-prison/105860420</link><description>Seven Australian activists arrested while trying to break Israel's naval blockade of Gaza have been deported to Jordan, the ABC understands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7ccce7c2ca458f724e93bbdc6c6ee3d</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's prisoner numbers outpace population growth, expected to rise further, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/victorias-prison-population-surges-bail-laws/105859764</link><description>Victoria's prison population has surged by 62 per cent in the last 20 years as the number of accused held on remand triples.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f81d3bf3beeb8f76404d212da73bea31</guid></item><item><title>Two years since Gaza war began, some Israelis feel 'reckoning' is coming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/israel-gaza-war-impacts-on-society-after-two-years/105856702</link><description>After two years of war, a fractured but defiant Israel is struggling to assert itself at home and abroad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80339c0e16865d228ed71373da828c3b</guid></item><item><title>Wildfires more lethal, economically damaging than ever, researchers find</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/wildfires-more-lethal-economically-damaging-report-finds/105853650</link><description>New Australian research shows, globally, major bushfire events are becoming more frequent, fatal and economically damaging.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3c40b37880d19a25d6319cd54212edd</guid></item><item><title>New data shows Australia's extreme weather losses among highest in world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/ica-finds-australia-extreme-weather-loss-among-highest-in-world/105831772</link><description>Amid more extreme weather events, parametric insurance — described as a bet on the weather —is on the rise. It is now being touted as a possible solution for Australians, who have some of the highest insurance losses in the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9275227f9aab52ca7138cba5646e848b</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley cites trans offender case in argument for minimum jail terms for child exploitation crimes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/coalition-minimum-sentencing-child-abuse-trans-debate-maloney/105858528</link><description>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley raises the case of a trans child abuser as she seeks to pressure the Albanese government to create mandatory minimum jail terms for child exploitation offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55234471d2b5596a81b4a31577fdb22d</guid></item><item><title>Telcos face Canberra grilling as Triple Zero Custodian legislation is set to be introduced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/telcos-meet-anika-wells-as-triple-zero-custodian-enshrined/105859926</link><description>New legislation will be introduced to enshrine the powers of the Triple Zero Custodian into law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbd4f5a5b9e0d8c6adaec44f1d1c4ed5</guid></item><item><title>Sole survivor of Bochara fatal crash was behind the wheel, coroner rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/bochara-crash-coroners-report-four-dead/105857490</link><description>A coroner determines that the sole survivor of a crash that killed four people at Bochara was behind the wheel during the incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a161f6794eb7803f4c4104e51e7211a9</guid></item><item><title>What the future holds for Sydney's former psychiatric hospital sites with storied pasts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/future-for-sydney-former-psychiatric-hospital-sites-callan-park/105829904</link><description>The challenge of transforming a major piece of Sydney's public space from a former mental health hospital to an "iconic urban parkland" is a delicate dance for the state government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82ae7a0e643192e5b9a78433c9d0443f</guid></item><item><title>Victorian couple sues Barwon Health over delayed diagnosis of rare 'flesh-eating disease' necrotising fasciitis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/barwon-health-sued-after-victorian-man-loses-left-eye-infection/105858504</link><description>A young father who lost his eye after contracting a rare infection is suing the hospital that treated him, alleging it ignored his requests to investigate his condition properly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4cdc819daa534b4f6bc329ec4854437</guid></item><item><title>Songbird heard for first time since 1890s in WA park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/noisy-scrub-birds-return-to-west-cape-howe-national-park/105856064</link><description>The song of the noisy scrub-bird is being heard in WA's West Cape Howe National Park again, bringing joy to bird enthusiasts everywhere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f07fbc8949558b0b0002a157cdb1da49</guid></item><item><title>Bulk-billing rates remain low as GPs spend longer with patients, survey finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/bulk-billing-low-as-gps-spend-longer-with-patients-racgp/105856332</link><description>An industry survey finds GPs are managing conditions typically handled by specialists due to high costs and only 12 per cent can afford to bulk-bill all patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c55f5a7f1ee185ba2bc0949994701619</guid></item><item><title>Singapore PM Lawrence Wong signals 'shared interests' with Australia and desire to expand military ties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/singapore-wants-to-expand-its-military-ties-with-australia/105856094</link><description>Singapore wants to expand its military ties with Australia, including through a greater Australian troop presence in the island state as part of an upgraded trade and defence relationship, according to Prime Minister Lawrence Wong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2d4433b0af1b549d254f001a101dc03</guid></item><item><title>Drought conditions forcing kangaroo mobs to descend on farms, consuming scarce resources</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/drought-kangaroo-populations-impacting-farmers-eating-pastures/105833458</link><description>Farmers are calling for a cull of kangaroos, which they say are being forced onto farmland by drought and dry conditions and consuming what little feed and water they have.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">253309d270a15dbf6688f4cc91faa6e9</guid></item><item><title>Darwin ship lift project cost blowout rivalling Snowy 2.0, economist says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/nt-taxpayers-billion-dollar-ship-lift-pearling-giant-paspaley/105856034</link><description>It’s taken 10 years, blown out by hundreds of millions of dollars, and is still nowhere near becoming operational. Now there are calls for the Darwin ship lift project to be scrapped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c825f0a31c74d4890b2904a10fbbc5ed</guid></item><item><title>Wildlife photographer Rob Blakers pleads guilty to trespassing on Robbins Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/rob-blakers-pleads-guilty-to-trespassing-charges-robbins-island/105858916</link><description>Wildlife photographer Rob Blakers pleads guilty to trespassing after admitting he camped beyond the boundary line whilst visiting privately owned Robbins Island to observe migratory birds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac32173c8f90d3e50097440e350afff4</guid></item><item><title>Daria Kasatkina ends 2025 tennis season early, citing burnout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/daria-kasatkina-taking-a-break-from-tennis-burnout/105860646</link><description>Daria Kasatkina ends her 2025 WTA season early, citing the hectic schedule and a high-stress year after switching nationalities to Australia from Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad2aa1068b4f5295b51933f2a1be3daa</guid></item><item><title>Bayer announces Roundup alternative with rollout of new weedkiller in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/bayer-announces-plans-for-australian-rollout-of-new-weed-killer/105847166</link><description>We've been spraying it on our farms, gardens and roadsides for 50 years, but the world's most used weedkiller is starting to run out of steam.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a610bff358c01395fe7953663db9dcea</guid></item><item><title>New WA program aims to improve access to childcare for children with disabilities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/childcare-children-with-disability-pilot-program-trial-perth/105854018</link><description>An Australian-first pilot program gets underway in WA in the hope of not only giving the parents of children with complex needs a break, but helping them navigate the maze of different support systems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a8e1b30ed0de1380c55df9e7d995ea6</guid></item><item><title>Chicago and Illinois sue to stop Trump’s National Guard deployment plan after Portland ruling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/chicago-and-illinois-sue-trump-to-stop-national-guard-deployment/105860592</link><description>Illinois is suing to block Donald Trump’s troop deployment to Chicago in what will be the president's fourth legal challenge over federal use of National Guard in cities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d4184466130c609265d8eab9d725c6c</guid></item><item><title>Woman claiming to be Madeleine McCann on trial charged with stalking parents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/woman-claiming-to-be-madeleine-mccann-stalked-parents-uk-court/105860736</link><description>A 24-year-old woman who claims to be Madeleine McCann is on trial charged with stalking the missing child's parents over the past three years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd2c2d66d238b7d5f1bffa72b34f0719</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, day two updates: Rival clubs reportedly interested in luring Nick Daicos away from Collingwood, Carlton secure Liam Reidy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/afl-trade-period-day-two-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca-daicos/105859160</link><description>The reported attempts to lure Nick Daicos away from Collingwood have headlined the second day of the AFL trade period. Look back at how all the day's trade news unfolded in our blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f32b16fe2d281e076b88df5a731c49f0</guid></item><item><title>Kati Thanda-Lake Eyre has reached its peak and is beginning to evaporate, local pilot says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/kati-thanda-lake-eyre-fills-up-south-australia/105856956</link><description>The floodwaters that have created an expansive inland oasis on the usually arid salt beds of Kati Thanda-Lake Eyre have reached a peak, and are beginning to evaporate, a local pilot says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">027c65d1be7d0e6bf6878186f247cce2</guid></item><item><title>Israel Premier Tech cycling team changes its name amid protests and exclusion from events</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/israel-premier-tech-cycling-team-changes-name-amid-protests/105860878</link><description>Israel Premier Tech drops "Israel" from its name after ongoing protests and exclusion from cycling events.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd2bd626d87e69690d1b2bed4ed90399</guid></item><item><title>ASX slips as banks, miners, energy stocks sold off, gold hits record high — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/asx-markets-business-live-news-october-7/104980306</link><description>Australia's share market lost ground after financials, energy and mining stocks were sold off, while the gold price hit another record high. Catch up on the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">636e58b8da854c899f6805c4e43597d3</guid></item><item><title>With an all-Blak writing team, Erica Glynn brought Mystery Road: Origin's enigmatic detective Jay Swan to life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/mystery-road-first-nations-writing-room-erica-glynn/105803594</link><description>With the help of Mystery Road: Origin's steely detective Jay Swan, an all-Indigenous writing team tackles one of Australia's biggest issues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">937ea5a8466e8813c9dd7a63ef17711b</guid></item><item><title>'Deeply wrong' pro-Hamas graffiti condemned as Australian Jewish community marks October 7</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/october-7-commemorations-marred-by-antisemitic-graffiti/105860494</link><description>Political leaders have condemned the painting of a pro-Hamas slogan on a Melbourne billboard as Australia's Jewish community commemorates the October 7 terrorist attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9d834509cddd326a16a998d7c66b8c0</guid></item><item><title>Singaporean PM on tariffs, defence and Optus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/singaporean-pm-on-tariffs,-defence-and-optus/105861116</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b53a622ac0e8f7bedc60bc2eee37c1b</guid></item><item><title>Why has France gone through five prime ministers in two years, and what's next?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/france-political-chaos-explainer-fifth-pm-in-two-years/105860746</link><description>The sudden resignation of France's prime minister — the country's fifth in two years — has put President Emmanuel Macron in a bind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8c52d8ffc75143a4a0f51bd82eab2ad</guid></item><item><title>LeBron James teases 'Second Decision', prompting speculation over retirement or possible ad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/lebron-james-teases-second-decision-retirement-speculation/105860846</link><description>LeBron James throws the NBA world into a frenzy with a 10-second video that has people speculating about his retirement or a possible bait-and-switch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6981ed924d5f07f8d54e7245806e577e</guid></item><item><title>Ord Valley's northern food bowl 'pipe dream' struggles amid changing climate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/northern-food-bowl-dream-struggles-amid-climate-change/105847668</link><description>Farmers are close to abandoning the dream of a food bowl in northern Australia, as one expert warns the region is nearing its "thermal limits" for cropping and cattle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de905ee900f69caf5bfbca7617e3ef61</guid></item><item><title>AC Milan to host Serie A match in Perth in what UEFA says is a 'regrettable' situation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/ac-milan-to-play-in-perth-as-uefa-says-it-is-regrettable/105861238</link><description>AC Milan will host a Serie A match in Perth next year, as UEFA's hand appears to have been forced to allow the game to go ahead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a50cc225d0e7505d28aab63baed1c536</guid></item><item><title>Local WA governments frustrated with rate of cat law reforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/native-animals-die-local-government-cat-laws-thrown-out/105794048</link><description>Concerned carers in WA say roaming pet cats will kill thousands of native animals while the state government debates changes to cat laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02d9d8ce7ef28bfe0486e2bc87ca5913</guid></item><item><title>Neighbours fans rush to Melbourne op shops after TV soap props donated to charities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/neighbours-fans-rush-to-find-props-donated-to-melbourne-op-shops/105858078</link><description>Neighbours fans rush to Melbourne op shops after 40 years of props, furniture and Ramsay Street relics were donated to charities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca86ba85c4354b9297414068cc619a44</guid></item><item><title>'Significant' aerial search for four-year-old Gus conducted over the weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/significant-aerial-search-for-missing-boy-gus-police-say/105861608</link><description>Police say they have conducted a "significant" aerial search of a property in South Australia's mid-north, where a four-year-old boy went missing 10 days ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8e4d5f34f117b094e212c99cd94e8e6</guid></item><item><title>NT government to refer parents for income management if child repeatedly skips school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/nt-government-school-truancy-plan-backlash-education/105856318</link><description>Parents in the NT who frequently fail to send their children to school, without a valid reason, may have their income managed by the Commonwealth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12aae044282aa406d31b3ff38d42c37d</guid></item><item><title>In Trent Dalton's new book Gravity Let Me Go, the bestselling author interrogates himself</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/trent-dalton-new-book-gravity-let-me-go-boy-swallows-universe/105806326</link><description>In Gravity Let Me Go, a struggling crime journalist lands the scoop of a lifetime, to the detriment of his loved ones. That's something Trent Dalton understands intimately.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec2f3217c1674a6b89bedc7b6a6f7815</guid></item><item><title>Kimberley bushfire season sees flames burn area double the size of Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/kimberley-bushfires-millions-burnt-hectares/105835854</link><description>This year's northern bushfire season has been dubbed "one of the toughest on record", with blazes having burnt through about 2.7 million hectares of land in WA's Kimberley region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5ea9e4fb95931d39c8997044e1ccfd2</guid></item><item><title>Former transport official Ibrahim Helmy fronts ICAC over kickbacks investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/nsw-icac-ibrahim-helmy-cupboard-transport-police/105861674</link><description>Ibrahim Helmy, who vanished before an inquiry into transport kickbacks, watched the first day of the Independent Commission Against Corruption public hearings via live stream.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10ff784b1f7132e0f3328c0ab3a9a20a</guid></item><item><title>Mother of Australian arrested on Gaza flotilla pleads for government to 'stand up for my son'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/calls-to-bring-australians-from-gaza-flotilla-home-from-israel/105858482</link><description>Jacinta McEwan calls for the Australian government to help her son amid reports he has been physically abused after being arrested on a flotilla trying to break Israel's naval blockade of Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc25acfde943f0206b86f785d4285e97</guid></item><item><title>Russian court sentences Australian to jail in absentia for fighting in Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/australian-soldier-sentenced-russian-court-fighting-ukraine-jail/105861764</link><description>The Australian man is accused of breaching Russia's criminal code by participating as a mercenary in an armed conflict.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">240bc6c318fee714ae234406626a5cd1</guid></item><item><title>Fresh and fragrant strawberry and cinnamon torte - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/alison-alexander-s-strawberry-and-cinnamon-torte/105849766</link><description>Sweet strawberries pair with a subtle cinnamon spice in this irresistible torte.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f19db1f54abf4889c55a5e00aedebdc8</guid></item><item><title>Artemios Mintzas faces court for the first time on charges over Croydon Park shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/croydon-park-shooting-artemios-mintzas-faces-court/105861858</link><description>The 60-year-old accused of shooting at over a dozen random members of the public in suburban Sydney has faced a magistrate after two lawyers got into an argument over who was representing him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8931b090491cc613a8ed6675842b7d99</guid></item><item><title>Body recovered during search for missing 15-year-old swimmer in Tamworth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/body-found-in-search-for-swimmer-peel-river-tamworth/105860868</link><description>A multi-agency search of the Peel River began on Monday night after police were told the teen had entered the water and failed to resurface.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d85bd2ee7e6ecffb36d40da7111de352</guid></item><item><title>Rescuers pull children from the rubble of Indonesian boarding school collapse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/efforts-to-rescue-indonesian-students-buried-under-school/105857382</link><description>Rescue teams worked around the clock through narrow gaps in the rubble of Sidoarjo's Al Khoziny Islamic Boarding School while risking further collapse to reach anyone still alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90d52525da9c6640b908a582ebebfacd</guid></item><item><title>Falling over a leading cause of hospitalisation, Injury Matters report highlights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/high-rates-of-falls-for-older-people-injury-matters-report/105859552</link><description>Data shows one in three people aged over 65 will have a fall every year. But a Perth not-for-profit wants to send a message that falls are not an inevitable part of ageing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f07c5568557ea0a0e0da1f83a197f2d4</guid></item><item><title>ABC Sport cricket coverage announced for the Ashes 2025/26 as Australia hosts England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/abc-sport-cricket-coverage-25-26-announced/105862028</link><description>Darren Lehmann and Glenn McGrath will join a first-class line-up of cricket talent for ABC Sport's coverage of the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df2427801c044d12182a1c9b4b33fc27</guid></item><item><title>Planning can help save you money this festive season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/preparing-financially-for-christmas-and-holidays/105795388</link><description>Australians estimate Christmas costs them about $800 a year, on average, but planning ahead can reduce the financial burden.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">158e6acd232ffd0c3bea1632ef3d82e3</guid></item><item><title>Callide Power Station's life extended as Qld government delays move away from coal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/power-stations-extended-callide-energy-road-map-policy/105843616</link><description>In Biloela, locals have seen it all — from "coal is king" to renewables and a short-lived nuclear proposal. Now the Queensland government is extending coal-fired power, but how long will the reprieve last?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4b9a44308a1bb82b978014d86676675</guid></item><item><title>What the Health of the Nation report tells us about GP doctors by numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/health-of-the-nation-gp-report-by-numbers/105861118</link><description>These five charts give us a glimpse into what the current state of general practice looks like in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fab4fda08cc0d73f7ca73f5c43a01ec1</guid></item><item><title>Canberra boy who pleaded guilty to possessing violent extremist material driven by 'teenage bravado', court finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/teen-with-violent-extremist-material-driven-by-bravado-court/105861716</link><description>The 17-year-old was arrested when police found a large number of videos and messages on his phone and laptop depicting violent extremist acts, many of which were highly disturbing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97674a71ae8be1823d0f5fcfc2611dbe</guid></item><item><title>Venezuela thwarts 'false flag' terror attack threat against US embassy in Caracas, Maduro says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/venezuela-foils-terror-attack-threat-against-us-embassy/105861982</link><description>Venezuela has alerted the Trump administration of a foiled "false flag operation" threatening to target the United States embassy in Caracas with explosives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b6c618bfd0a7ea992f3b60ddb4b419e</guid></item><item><title>Helicopter crashes on freeway in Sacramento, California, critically injuring three people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/helicopter-crashes-on-sacramento-freeway/105862402</link><description>Three people have sustained critical injuries after a helicopter crashed on a Sacramento freeway in the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88832676fc18bea8f0257f452487cdd5</guid></item><item><title>WA Police Commissioner Col Blanch rules out further action against officer allegedly involved in road incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/wa-police-commissioner-rules-out-action-over-alleged-assault/105862216</link><description>WA's police commissioner rules out reopening a case in which a man alleges he was choked by an off-duty police officer, in front of his daughter, during a fight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d25dadb868cd3e500b0e8f4a0d963d33</guid></item><item><title>Copper prices to keep rising as demand grows and global production is hit by disruption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/copper-supply-shortage-global-production-disruption/105852214</link><description>Copper is an essential industrial metal, but a series of major supply disruptions this year and a lack of new mines coming online have analysts warning of shortages in coming years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cd7389b9a7dab4aaf3b848293671343</guid></item><item><title>South Australia declared free from brown rugose fruit virus after more than a year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/south-australia-tomato-virus-free-brown-rugose/105861964</link><description>More than a year since South Australia's $230 million tomato and capsicum sector was plunged into turmoil by the first discovery of the tomato brown rugose fruit virus in Australia, the state has been declared free of the exotic disease.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f9a128f54240cc9f99a036c7afaba14</guid></item><item><title>Hikers feared being buried by snow as blizzard hit Mount Everest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/everest-rescue-how-it-happened/105861220</link><description>Hundreds of hikers are still trapped at an elevation of more than 4,900 metres as rescuers work to clear deep snow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c0bd394cd0abfdd67297249dd45789f</guid></item><item><title>Jarvis Cocker on his wild wedding, Glastonbury, and Pulp's first album in 24 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/pulp-jarvis-cocker-love-songs-glastonbury-more-take-5-zan-rowe/105836540</link><description>Love was "always problematic" for Jarvis Cocker, who fronts Britpop icons Pulp. But after decades of cynical songs on the subject, he's beginning to change his tune on romance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40c3575aacc74b1ddbee13cf6e2dbb39</guid></item><item><title>Wilcannia Weir project relies on increased federal funding, NSW minister says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/wilcannia-weir-project-funding-issues-rose-jackson/105849134</link><description>After decades of lobbying and design controversy, the New South Wales government says it needs another $30–40 million to proceed with the Wilcannia Weir upgrade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58e66e347555f3ff3da55e931beb4da2</guid></item><item><title>Australian wins with a jaffle at World Porridge Making Championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/melbourne-woman-wins-porridge-making-championship-with-jaffle/105861480</link><description>An oatmeal-filled jaffle made by a Melbourne food stylist and flavoured with Bundaberg Rum and bananas wins over judges in Scotland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">166b409d3c84e96a4aaae8acce2b6d24</guid></item><item><title>Search continues for 76yo man missing in Tasmanian bushland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/search-continues-for-76yo-man-missing-in-tasmanian/105862878</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e89673e6391ef9a599f8ed24c488ca1</guid></item><item><title>Peabody and Anglo American enter arbitration over $5.7 billion Queensland mines sale</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/peabody-anglo-american-arbitration-begins-on-moranbah-north-mine/105862190</link><description>Peabody Energy demands Anglo American return its $113.6 million deposit more than a month after the collapse of a deal to buy five mine sites in Queensland's Bowen Basin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61cd4fc8b7a1d2d53449d7b2401c9588</guid></item><item><title>McKenzie calls for more action on driving instructor sexual assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/mckenzie-calls-for-more-action-on-driving/105862302</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">041f19884bd39adb3995751e4b5bbc34</guid></item><item><title>Nationals Senator Bridget McKenzie demands government action over allegations of hundreds of sexual assaults by driving instructors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/bridget-mckenzie-driving-instructor-assaults-catherine-king/105861268</link><description>Frustrated by what she sees as inaction over a 7.30 investigation into alleged sexual assaults made by driving instructors, Nationals Senator Bridget McKenzie demands action from the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a10a5a9f37c5e7ad97e2577c0ef1a54</guid></item><item><title>Man who allegedly performed Nazi salute at Brisbane rally likely to plead guilty, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/qld-man-charged-nazi-salute-caboolture-court/105862006</link><description>Matthew Daniel Whiteway was charged by Queensland Police over allegedly giving a Nazi salute in Brisbane in September.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d7b7cb16fdaa708751bb008cd1d778a</guid></item><item><title>SA Police Commissioner Grant Stevens cleared over 1990s firearm incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/sa-police-commissioner-cleared-over-firearms-incident/105862988</link><description>South Australia's corruption watchdog has cleared Police Commissioner Grant Stevens of a discipline breach for accidentally discharging his firearm during a house raid in the early 1990s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11b1d529aef3b13c3907006779d8dc1f</guid></item><item><title>SA childcare centre closed for 90 days amid supervision concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/edge-early-learning-closure-extended-90-days/105862742</link><description>The Education Standards Board has closed Edge Early Learning Centre at Plympton for 90 days following an investigation into reports of "inadequate supervision" of children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecd91d4d6915aff8eca13d17480e9222</guid></item><item><title>Trump is deploying more troops on home soil — here's where things stand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/trump-national-guard-deployments-us/105862330</link><description>US President Donald Trump is ramping up efforts to deploy the National Guard in more cities across the country to combat what he claims is a "war from within". Here's a quick rundown on where Mr Trump has stationed troops — and which cities might be next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81336c34b8947a268eb83228d6116265</guid></item><item><title>Gerard Community Council Aboriginal Corporation pleads guilty to failing to lodge reports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/gerard-community-council-aboriginal-corporation-guilty-riverland/105861718</link><description>The corporation has been fined $2,000 for failing to lodge reports to the Office of the Registrar of Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Corporations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">667cc72e63a68b60053f0faf8d783cbf</guid></item><item><title>Za'id Abdus Samad pleads not guilty to murdering uncle outside Kuraby home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/qld-kuraby-muder-trial-plea-not-guilty-zaid-abdus-samad/105862744</link><description>Restaurant owner and father-of-four Abdul Basith Mohammed was found dead outside his home in 2017 after going to investigate a power outage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e49e8a375f84eefab8eb3f241b893d37</guid></item><item><title>Suspects in Bega stabbing death still at large, as police rule out chainsaw injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/bega-murder-investigation-park-death-police/105860516</link><description>Authorities say they are still piecing together who was involved in a "violent altercation" that left a man fatally stabbed and another in hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7db04311e9317f536592263b17a60b7</guid></item><item><title>Australia confident in batting at Women's Cricket World Cup, as Pakistan match approaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/australia-able-to-break-records-with-cricket-world-cup-approach/105862918</link><description>Beth Mooney has predicted Australia's new approach to ODI cricket will pay off in the Women's Cricket World Cup, with a greater desire to take the game on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6676359c94593bc78b44ad4f5348aa3</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast mayor says Qld government hoarding cyclone recovery funds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/gold-coast-mayor-attacks-qld-government-cyclone-funding-delay/105862826</link><description>Gold Coast mayor Tom Tate is calling for the state government to hand over funding allocated to help cover the city's growing disaster recovery bill following Tropical Cyclone Alfred.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b7381e80a01b974d263f402f2cda200</guid></item><item><title>State of WA appeals $2.8 million compensation payment to Dion Barber for abuse in state care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/state-appeals-dion-barber-abuse-compensation-amount/105862254</link><description>The state of WA is appealing a record $2.8 million compensation payment awarded to Dion Barber, who suffered repeated sexual abuse while in state care during the 1980s and 1990s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e41686a64a06dc35c2c557558da4dcb</guid></item><item><title>Australia Kangaroos lose Xavier Coates and Zac Lomax ahead of rugby league Ashes in England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/kangaroos-lose-xavier-coates-zac-lomax-rugby-league-ashes/105863632</link><description>Australia suffers a double blow with Zac Lomax and Xavier Coates ruled out of the overseas tour through injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0d6fe219c5cfcc432c5c99a3e88b226</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105863898</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">250fa4d6f9e87b19ec96acde65af18af</guid></item><item><title>Man in hospital after shooting near Mackay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/mackay-shooting-man-in-hospital-homebush/105863356</link><description>A man is in hospital in a stable condition after being shot in the hip during an altercation at a cane farm south of Mackay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b054640d57556808efd84205ef41382a</guid></item><item><title>Police tactical operation in Revesby leaves cars with bullet holes, windows smashed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/revesby-condell-park-tactical-arrest-police-fire-shots-at-car/105863486</link><description>A major police operation has taken place in Sydney's south-west after tactical operations officers conducted a "high risk" arrest on a suburban street.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fabe83686895e90c930f9ad9092cc79</guid></item><item><title>Motorists capture moment armed police make an arrest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/motorists-capture-moment-armed-police-make-an/105863872</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84c3a62e6f0a293aa619852839f622a9</guid></item><item><title>Surfer bitten twice by shark chasing seal off Kangaroo Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/shark-attacks-man-seal-uses-as-decoy-kangaroo-island/105863812</link><description>A surfer has driven himself to hospital after being twice bitten a shark who was reportedly chasing a seal in waters off Kangaroo Island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1b369fa6480a966dd5e0a9d060721c6</guid></item><item><title>Sheffield Shield round one: Victoria and NSW register wins, Tasmania bats for a draw against Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/sheffield-shield-round-one-victoria-and-nsw-register-wins/105863840</link><description>Victoria has upset reigning Sheffield Shield holders South Australia at the Adelaide Oval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d87a196b1e0545296dee75c1390f932</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds looking to change things up in second netball Test against South Africa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/australia-diamonds-south-africa-netball-second-test/105863906</link><description>Australian coach Stacey Marinkovich says she needs to try different combinations ahead of the Test series against New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c866a0db7bc54576ae7d2689ff95490</guid></item><item><title>Patient loses an eye after hospital’s delayed diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/patient-loses-an-eye-after-hospital%E2%80%99s-delayed/105864042</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71f1a8130aef45f21d177afc2118a48c</guid></item><item><title>Two years on from the horrifying Hamas attacks on Israel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/two-years-on-from-the-horrifying-hamas-attacks-on/105864066</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">598285ba0507cece72aec38c2ce1fc39</guid></item><item><title>Huge electric vehicle uptake needed to hit emissions target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/huge-electric-vehicle-uptake-needed-to-hit/105864088</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33383fa1160486898c5075de4de0bf76</guid></item><item><title>Was non-compliance with construction regulations responsible for Indonesian school collapse?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/was-non-compliance-with-construction-regulations/105864098</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a45ddae20d464d9e4a55e029b0ae76ab</guid></item><item><title>Second inquest into homicide of three tourists shot dead Mount Isa in 1978 begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/qld-spear-creek-murder-cold-case-second-inquest-begins/105863768</link><description>Gordon Twaddle, Karen Edwards, and Tim Thomson were killed almost 50 years ago. A second inquest into their deaths hopes to deliver answers for their loved ones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b77536cbcd65a613c86d384c392f6b7b</guid></item><item><title>Robin Williams's daughter begs fans to stop making AI content of her father</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/zelda-williams-calls-out-ai-video-of-late-father-robin-williams/105863964</link><description>The daughter of the late actor Robin Williams has condemned AI-generated content featuring her father's likeness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffd2a5defe194f05995a766f5c162ef7</guid></item><item><title>Scientists win Nobel Prize in Physics for discoveries in quantum mechanics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/scientists-physics-nobel-prize-quantum-mechanics-discovery/105863766</link><description>Three scientists have won the 2025 Nobel Prize in Physics for "the discovery of macroscopic quantum mechanical tunnelling and energy quantisation in an electric circuit".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e33d892453da0aeb26e45b03f8612f75</guid></item><item><title>Top stories from ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/top-stories-from-abc-news/105864284</link><description>Listen to ABC News interviews and commentary and analysis from radio programs like AM, PM and The World Today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8a957b84f60c237776fc4ad1db288c7</guid></item><item><title>Emmanuel Macron urged by his first PM to resign in escalating French crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/macron-urged-by-first-pm-to-resign-in-escalating-french-crisis/105864272</link><description>Emmanuel Macron's first prime minister urges the cornered French head of state to resign in a shock call that compounded an escalating political crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a9bdac4b0b2a74c58b74f54d75495b5</guid></item><item><title>Recently-elected German mayor Iris Stalzer in critical condition after being stabbed outside home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/herdecke-mayor-iris-stalzer-stabbed-in-germany-/105864280</link><description>Iris Stalzer, a Social Democrat who was elected mayor of Herdecke in the Ruhr region a week ago, is reportedly suffered life-threatening injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">167b87894c38ff1cccc6dda664d52cc7</guid></item><item><title>Research shows females carry a much higher genetic risk for major depression than males</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/queensland-depression-genetic-link-research-females-males/105864472</link><description>In a study involving about 200,000 people diagnosed with depression, scientists have identified almost twice as many genetic red flags in the DNA of females compared with males.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">992adc88f4efa48c96375158189324b7</guid></item></channel></rss>