<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:18:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rodney Neville Watkins jailed for historic sexual abuse of four Perth schoolboys</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/predatory-perth-teacher-jailed-for-abuse-primary-school-students/106010050</link><description>A former Perth teacher who abused four schoolboys in the 1970s and 80s, in behaviour a District Court Judge described as "predatory", is jailed for 16 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d607af0a91dae07c460c9fafcef73f0d</guid></item><item><title>Free concert in Melbourne CBD cancelled after overcrowding and safety concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/fed-square-amyl-and-the-sniffers-concert-cancelled/106012558</link><description>A free concert scheduled in Melbourne's Fed Square was cancelled at the last minute on Friday night, with organisers citing overcrowding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b4dc17084f55f990ab61f1547ac1a9a</guid></item><item><title>More than 11,000 customers lose power as storms with spectacular lightning hit south-east Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/qld-severe-storms-see-thousands-lose-power-in-lightning-show/106012492</link><description>An intense storm cell with dramatic lightning moves over the Brisbane area, delaying Friday evening commuters with heavy rain, strong winds and large hail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">195124137eee398d85cdc218c7127fd9</guid></item><item><title>Court finds 'pollutant' BHP liable over deadly Brazilian dam collapse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/bhp-found-liable-over-deadly-mariana-dam-disaster-in-court/106012632</link><description>A British court has ruled mining giant BHP liable for a deadly dam collapse in Brazil a decade ago, which sparked one of the world's largest environmental disasters on record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dabafdf511f5264b8516546f774dec2f</guid></item><item><title>Russia pounds Ukraine with drones and missiles, killing eight and hitting energy sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/russian-strikes-kill-six-in-kyiv-ukraine-responds/106012714</link><description>Both Russia and Ukraine accused each other of striking civilian areas in these latest attacks despite both sides saying they were hitting military targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb94e20f2cd95996120685e70dbb44e3</guid></item><item><title>Bus crash in Sweden's capital Stockholm causes several casualties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/stockholm-bus-crash-causes-several-casualties/106013116</link><description>At least three people have died and another three have been injured after an empty double-decker bus crashed into a bus stop.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bedd0ae7538ec459ac7c3af898d229f</guid></item><item><title>Trump's BBC and Epstein sagas dominate attention as international relations are rewritten</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/trump-bb-epstein-sagas-international-relations-rewritten/106010438</link><description>As what's happening in Trump's America dominates our attention there is a lot going on, mostly involving everyone else around the world refashioning their politics in an environment that has never seemed more uncertain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f45432a716a9f37538c96711f649e0f9</guid></item><item><title>Hair loss drug finasteride causing psychological side effects in some men</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/users-of-hair-loss-drug-finasteride-report-mental-health-issues/105965428</link><description>A vocal minority of finasteride users speak out about the long-lasting mental side effects of the hair loss drug, as telehealth ads for the medication surge on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b5e9c82bbd5756915155eff34974ab7</guid></item><item><title>The Paris conundrum at the heart of the Coalition's net zero backflip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/the-conundrum-at-the-core-of-the-coalition-net-zero-backflip/106011598</link><description>Liberal shadow cabinet members landed on a plan that has left many inside and outside the party bewildered and confused.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fb746f31ca9dfde8afe0d6a5f5f623a</guid></item><item><title>Jeffrey Epstein emails show he kept tabs on Donald Trump for years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/epsteins-emails-shed-light-on-his-preoccupation-with-trump/106010802</link><description>A trove of Jeffrey Epstein emails released this week reveals his preoccupation with US President Donald Trump in the years before Epstein's death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3711a02a04a2c4302a0d272cc4ff759e</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Forrest is betting on renewable energy in Queensland's coal heartland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/andrew-twiggy-forrest-backing-renewable-energy-in-queensland/105957172</link><description>At a wind farm in central Queensland, the billionaire backer and the local boilermaker offer a glimpse into how the energy transition is reshaping regional communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95ee7ebbe1a095c0c5f23087afe1493f</guid></item><item><title>Financial markets meltdown fears spread as US interest rate cut hopes fade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/financial-market-meltdown-fears-as-hopes-of-rate-cut-fades/106010576</link><description>Markets are heading south over fears about the US economy and interest rates not falling. Analysts fear mortgage holders and superannuates are in the firing line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39645985fb483d777cf6a3cb45de0418</guid></item><item><title>Health star ratings likely to become mandatory as food industry misses 70pc target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/food-health-star-ratings-mandate-industry-misses-target/106005758</link><description>Health ministers will meet next year and decide whether or not to make the system mandatory for all packaged food, something public health experts say is overdue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">543820576370a9410e01510f65cc9320</guid></item><item><title>After tireless advocacy and a dark history, Australia has a treaty with its First Peoples</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/australia-signs-first-treaty-with-aboriginal-people-in-victoria/106009328</link><description>Aunty Thelma lived through the mission era, stolen children and forced assimilation. As she witnessed the signing of the country's first treaty, her thoughts were on those who came before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ecc8059bcea9399dd81f5be810c2709</guid></item><item><title>One millionth refugee milestone in Australia on horizon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/australia-one-million-refugees-since-wwii/106005488</link><description>Australia is set to issue its one millionth refugee visa since 1947 in the coming weeks, in a humanitarian program that grew directly out the ashes of World War II.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96fd971fa30c044ec1f872fddde7f4d5</guid></item><item><title>As the social media ban sets in, how do you decide what TV to let your kids watch?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/social-media-ban-decide-kids-watch-tv-mad-men/106010214</link><description>We have navigated this new path of "what to watch/what to censor/what to allow" with stumbling footsteps. I'd love to tell you we have been perfectly consistent. We have not.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">602dd0fed8a47a81410bef8a48886887</guid></item><item><title>Jannik Sinner wary of Alex de Minaur ahead of ATP Finals semis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/tennis-atp-finals-jannik-sinner-alex-de-minaur-semifinals/106013206</link><description>Reigning champion Jannik Sinner says he will need to produce his best tennis to get past Alex de Minaur in the semis at the season-ending ATP Finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de0096d987c9d969cd1f0f77b696a5f0</guid></item><item><title>Football coach Zia Younan found quietly playing in Melbourne suburbs despite FIFA ban for match-fixing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/banned-soccer-coach-zia-younan-found-playing-in-suburban-leagues/106009158</link><description>A corrupt coach who was banned for life by the world football governing body for match-fixing has been quietly playing for clubs in suburban Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c4a876cd451ed856b62d8e9dd1ad55d</guid></item><item><title>Ewens Ponds set to reopen for public snorkelling after environmental concerns prompted closure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/ewens-ponds-diving-reopened-after-water-concerns/105973720</link><description>A date is set for snorkellers to return Ewens Ponds on South Australia's Limestone Coast, after low water flows caused its closure to the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d938e4575624ca15d9252385ce1860a</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after pregnant woman struck by car and killed in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/pregnant-woman-killed-struck-by-car-hornsby/106013262</link><description>A 33-year-old woman and her unborn baby have died after being hit by a car that had been involved in a crash with another vehicle at the entrance of a car park in Hornsby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e57498c406f24299416c3c31ed36345</guid></item><item><title>England great James Anderson tips Australian Ashes win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/cricket-ashes-james-anderson-england-australia/106013276</link><description>Legendary England fast bowler James Anderson says Australia is favourite to win the men's Ashes series on home soil, but feels the hosts will field their "weakest" team in 15 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1df86a6d1f314790c2b88925d10671cd</guid></item><item><title>Dolly Parton heads to Australian desert in unique exhibit celebrating rising art star Kaylene Whiskey</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/act-super-kaylene-whiskey-exhibition-national-portrait-gallery/106012440</link><description>Dolly Parton has never stepped foot on the dry red dirt of Indulkana in remote South Australia, but she is a frequent visitor in the art of Kaylene Whisky, which celebrates sisterhood and strong women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a5888fbf2ada0a905258b072ec37c7d</guid></item><item><title>Guy Sebastian's new album looks back on remarkable career</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/guy-sebastian-reflects-on-his-remarkable-career/105978684</link><description>Guy Sebastian looks back on the good fortune he has enjoyed in his music career, with the release of his 10th studio album, 100 Times Around the Sun.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">716ac837cd4cf2e0b77d74ce9d85deb2</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump seeks probe of Epstein ties to JP Morgan, Bill Clinton and other prominent Democrats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/trump-orders-epstein-probe-into-clinton-jp-morgan-democrats/106013208</link><description>The request comes two days after thousands of documents were released that raised new questions about Mr Trump's relationship with Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a8d351cc456dd6524275933490310a0</guid></item><item><title>Nearly half of women enrolled in Queensland homebirth program transferred to hospital, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/qld-homebirth-program-public-funded-12-months-report/106009706</link><description>The homebirth program was launched at the Sunshine Coast University Hospital in July 2024, with 74 women enrolled in the service in its first 12 months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d499e9ee78c05de12bd3434b7036759</guid></item><item><title>Thieves steal 65 young pigs from farm at Cranbrook in WA's Great Southern</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/thieves-steal-65-young-pigs-from-cranbrook-property-in-wa/105996932</link><description>A Cranbrook farmer says he feels like "the stuffing has been knocked out" of him after dozens of young pigs had been stolen from his property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85462403fd90446239dd93a35b42958a</guid></item><item><title>Trial of Rajwinder Singh, charged with murder of Far North Queensland woman Toyah Cordingley, concludes first week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/rajwinder-singh-trial-charged-with-murder-/106012200</link><description>Former Innisfail nurse Rajwinder Singh, 41, is standing trial over the 24-year-old's 2018 murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30b7ac58957120dd95352da96f556b81</guid></item><item><title>The Veronicas and Katy Perry songs behind Carlton and Hawthorn's finals campaigns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/the-songs-behind-carlton-hawthorn-aflw-semi-final/106013354</link><description>Before each game, the sides will blast a song to get their energy up, each emblematic of their seasons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b80205dd3e04caba0adbe26af6b1e68a</guid></item><item><title>Liz Stringer raises money for housing charities on huge tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/liz-stringer-housing-tour-australia-dates-second-high/106007614</link><description>The renowned singer-songwriter is on the road in support of her eighth album. Now, more than ever, she knows how to focus on what matters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53bcc66ace90f8a59beae29b1b310173</guid></item><item><title>A Great Act of Love by Heather Rose delves into her family's convict history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/heather-rose-new-book-a-great-act-of-love/106005806</link><description>In A Great Act of Love, the award-winning author interweaves a surprising chapter of Tasmanian history with the story of her ancestor who was transported to Van Diemen's Land in the 1800s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf87a42c95961b9dc560d58e6df29f33</guid></item><item><title>Fuss-free sticky beef and noodles for busy weeknights - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/sticky-beef-with-noodles-mint/105981016</link><description>This tasty, nourishing dish requires minimal prep and is quick and easy to throw together.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8d3d74bee7933d43fc72fd320f634dc</guid></item><item><title>NT government flags new fines for owners whose pet crocodiles escape</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/nt-government-introduces-new-pet-crocodile-ownership-rules/106011808</link><description>Crocodile owners whose pets escape and have to be recaptured by rangers could soon face penalties starting at $300, plus another $100 for each hour the reptiles are on the loose.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83717d2c1421addc1ee177f8590b3373</guid></item><item><title>Mona has lost $408 million since it opened in Tasmania but founder David Walsh doesn't mind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/mona-founder-david-walsh-on-future-of-tasmanian-museum/105982838</link><description>Hobart's landmark Museum of Old and New Art has racked up a staggering amount in losses since it opened in 2011, but founder David Walsh is still building.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f86bad330747f23072b91fc98553bd2b</guid></item><item><title>Amyl and the Sniffers shout Melbourne live music venues $35k in free drinks after gig cancelled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/amyl-and-the-sniffers-massive-bar-tab-after-fed-square-cancel/106012954</link><description>After their homecoming Fed Square gig was cancelled over security fears, Amyl and the Sniffers put $5,000 behind the bar at seven live music venues around Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e21c519850c76a221fe6d3baeb5423a</guid></item><item><title>Here's how Japan's PM found herself in a diplomatic spat with China over Taiwan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/japan-pm-takaichi-sparks-diplomatic-spat-with-china-over-taiwan/106012856</link><description>Sanae Takaichi has been in the top job for less than a month, but her comments detailing what Japan could do if China invaded Taiwan has sparked a diplomatic war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aead0e5f158af4be0ca9cb53d2a901d3</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump signs order to drop tariffs on hundreds of foods, including beef</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/trump-agriculture-beef-tariff-exemptions/106013518</link><description>Hundreds of food products, including beef and oranges, are now exempted from US trade tariffs, according to an executive order signed by President Donald Trump on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94cc598b29d020c165df325514a14bac</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested following four-hour siege on NSW South Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/nowra-siege-man-arrested/106013528</link><description>A man has been arrested after allegedly holding three people hostage with an axe at a home on the NSW south coast. The siege lasted four hours before police stormed the home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">100d4b34da30232b43fb006d6a55a838</guid></item><item><title>Man jailed for stealing signed print of Banksy's Girl with Balloon painting worth $544,000</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/man-jailed-for-stealing-banksy-print-of-balloon-girl-painting/106013434</link><description>The Grove Gallery in London was showcasing a collection of 13 Banksy pieces worth about £1.5 million ($3 million) when the iconic print was stolen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e91d1bd99618b757d0f8562ed765240</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies vow to bounce back in Ireland Test as spring tour continues in Dublin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/rugby-union-wallabies-prepare-to-face-ireland/106013576</link><description>Hit hard by last weekend's loss to Italy, the Wallabies are desperate to rebound when they face Ireland in Dublin on Sunday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">226388cffe19ee43d4b7dcbd09b5ac86</guid></item><item><title>What Australia can learn from China to become the world's 'cleaner' rare earth refiner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/australia-refining-rare-earths-environmental-challenges/105969994</link><description>As Australia races to scale up refining of rare earths, a thorny question looms: where does all the toxic wastewater go?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06dc511b156215c9f67c047f0c944bd0</guid></item><item><title>More than a month into the Israel-Gaza ceasefire, here is what has changed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/israel-gaza-ceasefire-one-month-on-what-has-changed/106013388</link><description>The fragile ceasefire in Gaza has now been in place for five weeks. Here is what has changed, what has not, and where things currently stand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3ba832f0ed79f6adf4011d2be982fba</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos fall to disjointed 1-0 loss to Venezuela in Houston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/disjointed-socceroos-lose-to-venezuela/106012522</link><description>Australia's hopes of a favourable draw for next year's World Cup take a hit with a disappointing 1-0 loss to Venezuela in Texas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45bb2143c8c71278dfa97f6a2a52c4c7</guid></item><item><title>The 'gun' shearer still setting a cracking pace at 85</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/john-harris-shearing-legacy-glengower-victoria/106009312</link><description>Australian shearing legend John Harris has returned to a central Victorian woolshed for the 75th year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94520388e9fce12775284bb46066f5c7</guid></item><item><title>Queensland GPs to be able to diagnose adults with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder from December 1</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/qld-gps-to-diagnose-adhd-and-prescribe-medication/106013548</link><description>From December 1, specialist general practitioners will have the ability to diagnose adults with ADHD and prescribe medication, in an Australian first.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cbb6041c09f20d827857d6db6f779be</guid></item><item><title>Video games are not banned at this Japanese high school, they are part of the curriculum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/the-japan-tokyo-school-where-students-play-video-games/106004378</link><description>Japan's education system is renowned for its rigidity. But one school is providing an alternative, blending typical education classes with intensive video game training.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff35046d95a4ece3835e5c25b0bb30f9</guid></item><item><title>NT's high rates of diabetes and amputations highlighted by territory health professionals on World Diabetes Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/nt-high-rates-of-diabetes-flagged-world-diabetes-day/106009950</link><description>The Northern Territory has some of the highest rates of diabetes globally, with health professionals warning that the cost of living is making it harder for those living in remote communities to access a nutritious diet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bf24a2fe3e09179d2c47ed4dd74f2dc</guid></item><item><title>US President Donald Trump says he plans to sue BBC for up to $US5 billion over documentary edit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/donald-trump-will-sue-the-bbc-over-documentary-edit/106013634</link><description>The US president added that he also planned to raise the issue with British Prime Minister Keir Starmer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efd7bd0d8903063a76eb8e9ec8911535</guid></item><item><title>First school reopens as risk from asbestos exposure deemed 'extremely low'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/first-school-reopens-coloured-sand-asbestos-low-risk/106013676</link><description>Seventeen schools were shut down on Friday after concerns about asbestos exposure. The reopening of one of the schools has been fast-tracked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd8be227610ea56f20751499bf5bc9f9</guid></item><item><title>Cell Block Studios preserves history of Old Geraldton Gaol as a hub for local artists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/cell-block-studios-preserves-history-of-old-geraldton-gaol/105996344</link><description>Once a place of punishment, Old Geraldton Gaol is now a site of creativity after being saved from demolition by a group of local artists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8948073177833970a2075bb853454dff</guid></item><item><title>Urgent review of Federation Square security ordered after Amyl and the Sniffers concert cancelled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/amyl-sniffers-federation-square-security-review/106013698</link><description>The operators of Federation Square promise an urgent security review after locked-out attendees broke through fences at the free concert, but say the band's fan base is not to blame.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56b6b4702f7f6684adfea30bfc0c9473</guid></item><item><title>Coloured sand linked to asbestos contamination scare found at over 100 SA sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/sa-sites-have-sand-linked-to-asbestos-contamination-scare/106013536</link><description>Coloured sand products linked to an asbestos contamination scare have so far been identified at more than 100 sites in South Australia following checks at schools and preschools, the state's education department says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c5f99cd335d0c3e0c00060b8f7b2767</guid></item><item><title>Josh Hazlewood ruled out of Ashes opener in Perth in blow to Australia's hopes against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/hazlewood-out-of-ashes-opener-in-massive-blow-for-australia/106013902</link><description>Australian quick Josh Hazlewood is ruled out of the opening Ashes Test match against England in Perth with a hamstring injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57a8ac180885e0219f5805ad7ca82d87</guid></item><item><title>Police to patrol Melbourne shopping centres in 90-day youth crime prevention trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/victoria-police-melbourne-shopping-centres-psos-patrol-trial/106013658</link><description>Victoria's police chief commissioner says groups of protective services officers and police officers will start patrolling shopping precincts before Christmas in an effort to reduce crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">114cc57de1f9c2b523ba41ccecb6955f</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne comes back to beat Adelaide in AFLW semifinal, Carlton advances with Hawthorn demolition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/hore-leads-demons-in-comeback-semifinal-win-over-crows/106013944</link><description>Melbourne is through to the AFLW preliminary finals as Kate Hore inspires the Demons to a comeback win over Adelaide, while Carlton demolishes a depleted Hawthorn.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c12718b9f928a563915afc3f9529fe08</guid></item><item><title>Three NT residents charged with fraud over alleged $71 million Defence contract scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/afp-charge-three-nt-over-alleged-multi-million-fraud-scheme/106013768</link><description>The AFP has raided homes and businesses across Darwin after a tip-off that a Defence employee, his wife, and a director of a building firm were allegedly involved in a fraudulent scheme to steer multi-million-dollar Defence building contracts their way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f902ce406c177bbb63e2a5bdc98015b</guid></item><item><title>Astronaut Katherine Bennell-Pegg named SA's Australian of the Year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/astronaut-katherine-bennell-pegg-sa-australian-of-the-year/106012362</link><description>When Katherine Bennell-Pegg was growing up, she was "mesmerised by the stars" — an enthusiasm that motivated her to pursue astronaut training, and has now secured an honour of a different kind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9ed5d025c4ab1b48f1f1d28b5c944cf</guid></item><item><title>Explosion inside India-controlled Kashmir police station kills nine people, injures dozens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/kashmir-india-police-station-explosion-kills-eight-people/106013968</link><description>At least nine people are dead and dozens are injured after a cache of confiscated explosives detonates inside a police station in Indian-controlled Kashmir.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a3f58f20950c2fe48844c426405598b</guid></item><item><title>What France's famous cave replicas can teach Australia about rebuilding lost heritage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/juukan-gorge-replica-rebuild-rio-tinto-ppk-france-/106012544</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49ddd6f3b5399718cc88508e6a5e4ad6</guid></item><item><title>Former Katter's Australian Party MP Nick Dametto ahead in early count for Townsville mayoral by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/counting-begins-townsville-mayor-election/106009322</link><description>Eight candidates are vying for the top role, including the city's former mayor, Troy Thompson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b58350df332ace1e648294f18c50b1fb</guid></item><item><title>England completes sole Ashes warm-up match with flurry of runs to Ollie Pope, Joe Root</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/england-completes-sole-ashes-warm-up-match-pope-root/106014128</link><description>Ollie Pope tunes up for the first Ashes Test with hard-hitting knocks of 100 and 90 in England's only warm-up match at Lilac Hill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eb9ce0564421eda3a89be3065490ab1</guid></item><item><title>Democratic Republic of Congo and M23 rebel group sign new roadmap to peace in Qatar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/democratic-republic-congo-m23-sign-peace-roadmap/106014172</link><description>At the ceremony, Qatar's chief negotiator Mohammed Al-Khulaifi called the agreement "historic", adding that mediators would continue efforts to achieve peace on the ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95ceb80d6aae4e99bec5eb9602986746</guid></item><item><title>Pope Leo XIV urges Hollywood actors to resist algorithms and save neighbourhood cinemas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/pope-leo-meets-cate-blanchett-spike-lee-vatican-audience/106014170</link><description>Pope Leo XIV tells a group of leading Hollywood actors and filmmakers during an audience at the Vatican that more should be done to protect struggling neighbourhood cinemas, to preserve the shared experience of watching movies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39e96906d1f19ddde661905e92e4c716</guid></item><item><title>The old-school landline is having a cultural moment in a world of screens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/landline-rotary-phone-social-media-ban-family-connect/106010638</link><description>As smartphones swallow childhood, a growing movement of parents is reinstalling landlines, hoping an old-school corded phone can restore patience and connection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12eb6c09a56ba6c0d117f1b31fd62bfc</guid></item><item><title>Social media has changed how we get the news and politicians are capitalising on it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/annabel-crabb-civic-duty-social-media/106007956</link><description>When a delegation of "influencers" appeared at Canberra's budget lock-up this year, joining press gallery journalists in the increasingly arcane tradition of reading a complex document for a few quiet hours before bursting forth in analysis thereof, much comment was made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b63cf42732ea63c2e79f7c330eb395e</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur exits ATP Finals as Jannik Sinner reaches decider</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/atp-finals-alex-de-minaur-loses-to-jannik-sinner/106014668</link><description>Alex de Minaur falls to Jannik Sinner for the 13th straight time, as the Italian advances to the final of the season-ending championship for the third consecutive year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e230cee3c88b68baf48d8e9b27e2c161</guid></item><item><title>Survivors of Sudan's El-Fasher conquest say they were attacked while escaping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/survivors-of-sudan-el-fasher-conquest-attacked-while-escaping/106003668</link><description>With Sudan's El-Fasher captured by a militia accused of mass killings, those who escaped are suffering in a refugee camp and mourning the deaths of family and friends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e86b511cd97badb6d078ffe9838c5b86</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fall to record-breaking defeat against late-surging Ireland in Dublin, Mack Hansen scores hat-trick</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/live-updates-ireland-vs-wallabies-dublin/106010192</link><description>The Wallabies's losing run on their spring tour continues, as Ireland records a convincing 46-19 victory on home soil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c58c9c21b234d411d1f115c8675dc91</guid></item><item><title>Property investors say they're 'boosting rental supply', but it can be a rhetorical trick</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/property-investors-boosting-supply-of-rentals-or-dwellings/106012670</link><description>Are they boosting the supply of rental housing by financing the construction of new dwellings, or buying pre-existing owner-occupied homes and converting them to rentals?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6811cb40a36c52cabe97de6b5518a15a</guid></item><item><title>The infamous photo former prince Andrew can't outrun</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/photo-former-prince-andrew-virginia-giuffre/106009338</link><description>More than 20 years after this photo was purportedly taken, it continues to haunt Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac9147d2e1850deea3230203303529f9</guid></item><item><title>England confident Jofra Archer will fire against Australia in Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/ashes-series-england-australia-jofra-archer/106014680</link><description>Injury may have stalled his Test career, but Jofra Archer is showing signs he will be at his best when the men's Ashes series gets underway in Perth on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc054839dab06d6b62fb2ec2a0457e1a</guid></item><item><title>Forestry looks to carbon market in wake of Great Koala National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/great-koala-national-park-forestry-future-carbon-market/105954932</link><description>The Great Koala National Park was announced to protect koalas and forests in northern NSW, but the forestry industry has been left wondering how it can fill a shortfall in supply.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59b353918710affce02350d5b8df1756</guid></item><item><title>The other-worldly ecstasy of the Socceroos' penalty shootout against Uruguay, 20 years on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/socceroos-uruguay-world-cup-qualifier-20-year-anniversary/106010284</link><description>Nostalgia can be an intoxicating force, especially when it comes to the 20-year anniversary of the Socceroos' remarkable win over Uruguay on penalties, which remains an Australian cultural touchpoint.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47245075f2a8785886b932f62bc620e3</guid></item><item><title>Rebuilding Juukan Gorge: Traditional owners turn to France for restoration plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/juukan-gorge-replica-rebuild-rio-tinto-ppk-france-inspiration/105949740</link><description>Five years after Rio Tinto destroyed a 47,000-year-old sacred rock shelter to expand an iron ore mine, an ambitious rebuild is underway drawing inspiration all the way from France.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de9425a9476d7c3af156b6d7b2c1414b</guid></item><item><title>Sunbury residents fear waste-to-energy proposal risks health and environment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/sunbury-waste-to-energy-incinerator-hiq-bulla-landfill/106006600</link><description>Sunbury residents say they are tired of being the state's "dumping ground" after waste-to-energy facility proposed nearby a receives a cap license from Recycling Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6845e30ea7b6c660b6e21464de2ca732</guid></item><item><title>Legal experts, civil libertarians warn the NSW government is 'eroding' the right to protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/nsw-protest-laws-eroding-right-to-protest-say-legal-experts/106006324</link><description>When 60 neo-Nazis lined outside NSW parliament last week, the premier's response was swift and familiar — steadily tightening the state's protest laws in response to flashpoint events.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31ea4c2c9ef06864b01f04216911c228</guid></item><item><title>Endangered bandicoots given new home free of feral predators in regional NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/bandicoots-given-a-new-home-mallee-cliffs-national-park/105995106</link><description>Twenty endangered bandicoots are roaming south-west New South Wales in an effort to return bandicoots to the region after several species were wiped out in the late 1800s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c46dea045a97336604f93f035b9ad0b</guid></item><item><title>Sixers teenager Caoimhe Bray claims WBBL hat-trick in 24-run win over Thunder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/wbbl-sydney-sixers-thunder-caoimhe-bray-hat-trick/106014712</link><description>Sydney Sixers rising star Caoimhe Bray needed to be told she had taken a hat-trick, as the 16-year-old added another WBBL highlight in a thumping derby defeat of the Thunder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0d7e129714674d7783957c8ea49e2e2</guid></item><item><title>India and Pakistan have faced the deadliest terror attacks on their capitals in a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/india-pakistan-deadly-terror-attacks-in-delhi-islamabad/106013650</link><description>In just 48 hours, almost 30 people were killed and dozens more injured in the deadliest terrorist assaults on the capitals of both India and Pakistan in more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0e54e563cf82b482504d0bcfb5d5d51</guid></item><item><title>Survival camping isn't for everyone — so how would you go in the wilderness? Take the quiz to find out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/survival-camping-quiz-tasmanian-wilderness/105888688</link><description>For 18-year-old Rivi, knowing what gear to leave behind can be as important as knowing what to take with.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab49ce291cf03e60517a144569b2e9c7</guid></item><item><title>Rain brings relief across much of Victoria but the drought is 'certainly not over'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/victorian-drought-not-over-despite-relief-of-spring-rain/106004802</link><description>Dusty Victorian farms turn muddy as drenching rain brings much-needed relief.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87d1f24f3b4d20878cb22c831a1aa5d7</guid></item><item><title>Rose Byrne plays a mother on the edge in Mary Bronstein's If I Had Legs I'd Kick You</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/if-i-had-legs-i-kick-you-rose-byrne-movie-mary-bronstein/105977540</link><description>The Sydney-born movie star discusses how her creative partnership with If I had Legs I'd Kick You director Mary Bronstein has opened the Oscars conversation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a57ec37515d332a6074b6269009da5c4</guid></item><item><title>Sergey Lavrov was one of Vladimir Putin's top allies on the world stage. And then, he was gone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/mystery-surrounds-missing-russian-foreign-minister-sergey-lavrov/106008516</link><description>For more than two decades, Sergey Lavrov has been Russia's top foreign diplomat, representing the Kremlin's regime around the world, but late last month, he disappeared.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45f8c3cacfd91b10388d63f50b589d5b</guid></item><item><title>Thunderstorms and heavy rain forecast for parts of Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/queensland-sunday-storms-heavy-rain-river-warnings/106014806</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says parts of Queensland and New South Wales will likely see smaller pockets of severe thunderstorm activity on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e83a3e313c7dcee756dcedeb4f73d0a6</guid></item><item><title>Inspection of Weona Park horse stud found several serious animal welfare issues, just weeks before public outcry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/weona-horse-stud/106012012</link><description>Investigators warned the "situation" at a horse stud in the state's south "is likely to [be] the next welfare issue hitting the news".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff8f2c6eb64387a9de9b3397ae1d51b1</guid></item><item><title>Horned 'devil' bee found in remote Goldfields prompts call for further research</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/horned-lucifer-bee-discovery-goldfields/105997548</link><description>The discovery of a new "lucifer" bee with devil-like horns sparks concerns over land clearing regulations in WA's Goldfields region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae67dce636b1d6d9780e5a16b4b27f80</guid></item><item><title>Amid ongoing drought in South Australia, these women are redefining resilience</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/women-showing-up-for-community-during-drought/105926946</link><description>Dusty paddocks, with no grain crop to harvest, and scarce feed for the few animals left, is the reality of many South Australian farmers right now. Four women are redefining resilience and showing what it means to endure tough conditions despite it all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5497b2acddf11b8b1ea3f54f23673983</guid></item><item><title>Victorian farmer to auction father's vintage tractor collection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/victorian-farmer-to-auction-fathers-vintage-tractor-collection/105990840</link><description>Tony Forrest reflects on his father's love of old tractors as he prepares them for sale.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8c2f2f7c59d020c9c17b7e189a1935c</guid></item><item><title>Indonesian school kids poisoned by free school lunches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/indonesian-school-kids-poisoned-by-free-school-lunches/106010538</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61fbcb16360c16afdcf8e5c097d19b79</guid></item><item><title>Aldo Revaldo taken to hospital with suspected poisoning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/aldo-repaldo-taken-to-hospital-with-suspected-poisoning/106010560</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb1cad64e02ae52dcb0ae19ad430e102</guid></item><item><title>How free school meals gave thousands of children food poisoning in Indonesia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/indonesia-free-school-meals-program-for-kids-in-schools-problems/106009984</link><description>Despite thousands of cases of food poisoning, Indonesia's government intends to expand a controversial program giving schoolchildren free meals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d079a30ad4ea57b0a6fa6d30e61416a4</guid></item><item><title>Accusations of secrecy, abuse of power fly as WA Labor wades through third term</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/wa-government-accused-of-secrecy-abuse-of-power/106010294</link><description>Accusations of secrecy and abuse of process have been levelled at the Western Australian government this week on several fronts. Are they blips on the radar or signs WA Labor is under strain?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">641b8039ba4f80240938b1dff54fec01</guid></item><item><title>Fourth case of measles confirmed after Jelly Roll concert at Brisbane Entertainment Centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/fourth-measles-case-confirmed-after-jelly-roll-concert/106014898</link><description>Authorities say a case had been identified in the Logan region after three cases linked to the concert at the Brisbane Entertainment Centre on October 24 were confirmed on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc09641cf8ec80e2d65bf674da768f83</guid></item><item><title>Wong won't put price tag on COP31 as final host decision looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/cop31-price-penny-wong/106014762</link><description>Foreign Minister Penny Wong has refused to say how much it would cost Australia to hold the COP31 climate conference, as negotiations over hosting rights enter the final stages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a300239a7111e75ab0cafa979cd434c</guid></item><item><title>Car crashes into crowd at Walcha showground rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/car-crashes-into-crowd-at-walcha-showground-rally/106014990</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e59ec862f30aea2262d1ca9356891b5b</guid></item><item><title>More coloured sand recalls prompt ACT to close 70 schools over asbestos concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/more-coloured-sand-products-recalled-over-asbestos-fears/106014952</link><description>Kmart has recalled four coloured sand products over concerns of asbestos contamination, prompting the ACT education department to close dozens more schools.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0c60746dd4e3f1d8cbdf98f839bc448</guid></item><item><title>Bail denied to teen accused of causing crash that killed pregnant woman and unborn child</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/teenage-driver-in-court-over-fatal-hornsby-crash/106014038</link><description>The 19-year-old accused of causing a crash at Hornsby on Friday night that claimed the life of a pregnant woman and her unborn child is denied bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12deb9505e88a5004ae005814578d976</guid></item><item><title>Government considers dramatic intervention to save Tomago smelter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/government-considers-intervention-to-save-tomago-smelter/106015238</link><description>The federal government is considering a power-purchase agreement with Tomago to supply electricity at a stable price, after warnings the smelter may need to close because of rising power costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4939cc71d7e33335bf2c9f977ab8634a</guid></item><item><title>Former MP Nick Dametto declares victory in Townsville mayoral by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/townsville-mayoral-by-election-nick-dametto-declares-victory/106014032</link><description>Nick Dametto, a former Queensland MP, has won 61 per cent of the votes counted, succeeding in his campaign to become Townsville's next mayor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e93915c10ec838af548b5920da333d1b</guid></item><item><title>Coalition plans to strip climate from energy operator's objectives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/coalition-joint-net-zero-position-leaked-submission/106015290</link><description>Emissions reduction would no longer be an objective of Australia's energy operator under a Coalition plan endorsed by the Nationals and Liberals, prioritising affordability and reliability over climate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e121017def600970fa4dff5d9f2618b7</guid></item><item><title>Calls for federal government to help 'stranded Australians' waiting in hospital for aged care bed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/critical-shortage-of-aged-care-beds-calls-federal-government/106010318</link><description>About 1,000 people are waiting in Queensland public hospitals for more appropriate care, such as a place in aged care, with infrastructure failing to keep up with the need.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4e9d39ecc3bdbcdbe884b027e9e26c2</guid></item><item><title>More than 90 patients stuck in Tasmanian hospitals waiting for aged care or NDIS support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/tasmanian-hospitals-bed-block-aged-care-ndis-funding-agreement/106015236</link><description>More than 90 Tasmanians who have been medically cleared to leave hospital are not able to because they are waiting for an aged care place or NDIS support. Premier Jeremy Rockliff says it's "not good enough" and is calling on the federal government to increase hospital funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4395de959a9953c7649153fbb7277ff3</guid></item><item><title>ACT closes 70 schools as more sand products recalled amid asbestos concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/act-to-close-schools-after-coloured-sand-recall-over-asbestos/106015398</link><description>The ACT will close more schools after additional coloured sand products were recalled by Kmart and Target, while the schools that were shut on Friday will reopen on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9518404fe2157f394c68f2bfa67ac72</guid></item><item><title>From 'female Donald Trump' to 'Wacky' Marjorie — how Taylor Greene's alliance with the president crumbled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/donald-trump-marjorie-taylor-greene-alliance-erupts/106015394</link><description>Once considered one of Donald Trump's most loyal soldiers, Marjorie Taylor Greene has found herself an outcast of the MAGA firm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce47c00f288f5b76e52c94fe74013bf6</guid></item><item><title>Renegades down Stars by four wickets as Devine sends down stunner in Scorchers win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/renegades-down-stars-scorchers-defeat-strikers/106015666</link><description>The Renegades get the better of the Stars in the Melbourne derby, while Sophie Devine bowls one of the balls of the season in the Scorchers' defeat of the Strikers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ec6f32af3d9f60d49cdfd034530342e</guid></item><item><title>Zac Lomax released by Eels for 'opportunities outside NRL', fuelling speculation of R360 switch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/lomax-released-by-eels-fuelling-speculation-of-r360-switch/106015696</link><description>Parramatta star Zac Lomax is released from the final three years of his NRL contract, fuelling speculation of a move to breakaway rugby competition R360.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e096c75a6ce2bd66a948cea80f34803</guid></item><item><title>Energy chiefs say net zero 'irreversible' even though bills unlikely to fall 'for a decade'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/energy-ceos-say-transition-irreversible-despite-rocketing-costs/106015292</link><description>Amid swirling debate among conservative politicians over decarbonisation, energy bosses have warned against turning away from net zero despite cost pressures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30ce8fd67aeb676bb34fe21971b4fd65</guid></item><item><title>Ambulance response times sluggish despite Tasmanian ramping 'ban' promise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/tasmanian-ambulance-ramping-ban-no-impact-on-response-times/106013750</link><description>The Tasmanian government's "ban" on ambulance ramping was announced with much fanfare in 2024 — but there has been no effect on ambulance response times, and patients are still facing long waits in hospital emergency departments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8584855324c23e23803258f1744a5898</guid></item><item><title>Why 'not just living for the weekend' may be a social media trend for good</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/not-living-for-the-weekend-social-media-trend/105999240</link><description>Emma Dickeson says her "school night" adventures are about devoting time and attention to the things that energise you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42759f841e6bf8bfce2e2a4594556426</guid></item><item><title>Family demand justice for Ukrainian journalist tortured in Russia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/tortured-death-of-ukraine-journalist-viktoria-roshchyna/105976670</link><description>Family and former colleagues of a Ukrainian journalist who was captured by Russian forces and tortured are determined to do everything they can to ensure those who contributed to her death are held responsible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b8c425ceabf6609b62e208aa67db7f3</guid></item><item><title>Vang Vieng backpacker hostel implicated in Laos methanol deaths set to reopen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/laos-hostel-implicated-in-methanol-tragedy-set-to-reopen/105978414</link><description>The Laos hostel accused of serving alcohol contaminated with methanol that killed six people — including two young Australian women — last November is set to reopen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4a08d18a14a827e06668bbd131f50c9</guid></item><item><title>Laos methanol poisoning survivor 'turning grief into action'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/laos-methanol-poisoning-survivor-turning-grief-into-action/106007590</link><description>A survivor of last year's Laos mass methanol poisoning has started a campaign to educate travellers on the dangers of the toxic form of alcohol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5926b3d2a458b4519574ccc128a7360</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians fear 'nothing can be done' about Israeli military operation in West Bank refugee camps</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/displacement-in-the-west-bank-amid-rising-settler-violence/105995424</link><description>After Palestinians were expelled from three refugee camps in the Israeli occupied West Bank this year, some fear a new ceasefire in Gaza could prompt Israel to expand its operations in the area once more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f6ebe04392cc6a7f3b2d25cbbaa4002</guid></item><item><title>Tony Abbott admits he was fighting the urge to thump journalist in 2011 interview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/tony-abbott-addresses-stare-off/106010356</link><description>In 2011, Tony Abbott was questioned over his use of the phrase "shit happens" when discussing the death of an Australian soldier in Afghanistan. Instead of responding, he stared at the journalist, fighting the urge to thump him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c2aef2912e0cdefb0225e24ff2af31b</guid></item><item><title>The strange macho appeal of fossil fuels in a world struggling to reach net zero</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/macho-appeal-of-fossil-fuels-in-a-world-struggling-with-net-zero/106011600</link><description>The strange macho appeal of fossilised vegetation means that 30 years of annual United Nations meetings to stop the planet heating any more have been a bust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d07adbbaa77ec7a1ebd1bd5822d3206</guid></item><item><title>Indian counterterrorism agency arrests alleged co-conspirator in Red Fort suicide bombing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/man-arrested-over-deadly-delhi-red-fort-explosion/106016028</link><description>India's National Investigation Agency says two men behind last week's deadly car blast in Delhi were from Kashmir, a region that has been a source of tension between India and Pakistan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e53842f29d91924a30d3bdb5722563d5</guid></item><item><title>WA testing lab inundated by families' and retailers' concerns about asbestos-contaminated sand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/wa-hazard-testing-lab-overrun-with-asbestos-sand-requests/106015136</link><description>Concerned families and retailers are inundating a materials testing laboratory with enquiries, since news broke that asbestos had been detected in decorative and coloured sand for children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21052cae1747cefb9fccbf348f33cb3f</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley scrabbling to retain leadership after net zero capitulation puts one advantage at risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/ley-puts-one-advantage-at-risk-scrabbling-to-keep-leadership/106011602</link><description>It was only a week ago that the moderates in the Liberal Party were flexing their muscle privately (and some publicly), threatening a divorce with the Nationals and to walk the plank if net zero was dumped. Neither threat ever materialised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0db26107892679ddf443db6d1c4ef15c</guid></item><item><title>Operational dates for Northern Water project pushed out by several years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/northern-water-project-timeline-pushed-back/105995628</link><description>Completion of the South Australian government’s Northern Water desalination plant and water pipeline is now forecast to occur in 2032.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3321bf605b72948ab339039081d26fc</guid></item><item><title>Numbers suggest England's Ashes preparation does not make a difference</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/ashes-england-preparation-first-test-historical/106012450</link><description>Has England compromised its pre-Ashes preparation by playing only one three-day warm-up match against its own reserve team before the first Test in Perth? The numbers say no.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64090b0afb139b2e1d6c0f0cee876498</guid></item><item><title>Doorbell footage shows aftermath of Waterloo police death in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/doorbell-footage-shows-aftermath-of-waterloo-police-/105920758</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e184ab3c3060da415367dd412aa44871</guid></item><item><title>Police mental health unit under the spotlight after the deaths of 10 people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/nsw-police-mental-health-responses-criticism-from-coroners/105914846</link><description>An officer who headed the NSW Police unit training the force in mental health responses once committed misconduct in a case where a mentally ill man was fatally shot by police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12f3f7fd35e360033cf2335d8bb2a05f</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr rested as Chelsea drops Women's Super League points</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/sam-kerr-rested-chelsea-drops-wsl-points-arsenal-draw/106016282</link><description>English champs Chelsea decide to rest Sam Kerr for their WSL clash against Liverpool but appear to pay the price with a 1-1 slip-up at Liverpool.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43246472ac0ff91330de097de8b29e25</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Moderates rally behind Ley's leadership as Albanese labels Liberal energy policy 'nonsensical' — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/federal-politics-live-blog-nov-17/106011986</link><description>Sussan Ley says she is not worried her leadership is on the rocks after a bumpy week for the opposition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1edf4ee95bd1bd8bcca418a35172957b</guid></item><item><title>Police seize record number of bladed weapons amid knife crime concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/vic-police-seize-record-number-of-knives/106016252</link><description>Police have confiscated more than 15,000 bladed weapons this year amid heightened community concern over knife crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6be37f5517622fde62452efb39f973a</guid></item><item><title>Maya Joint's fighting qualities praised in Billie Jean King Cup win over Brazil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/maya-joint-s-fighting-qualifies-praised-in-bjk-cup-win/106016324</link><description>Australia advances to the qualifying stage of the Billie Jean King Cup after Maya Joint and Kimberly Birrell dug deep to defeat Brazil and top their group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c08e333a529694f7ed6bdb93ce9ab748</guid></item><item><title>ASX claws back early losses to end flat, CBA and BHP slide while energy and property stocks make gains — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-nov-17/106015770</link><description>The ASX recovered from early losses to end the day where it started.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">102402b877e5c334ae33fa1d8bbb4dd0</guid></item><item><title>Locals brace for timber industry job losses amid creation of Great Koala National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/job-losses-in-timber-industry-to-create-koala-park/106004814</link><description>A third of Herons Creek’s population on the NSW mid north coast faces possible redundancy as the timber mill struggles to survive the logging moratorium to create the Great Koala National Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9af06d114671af8f00a4cf766aa9abe</guid></item><item><title>Jannik Sinner beats Carlos Alcaraz in ATP Finals in latest Sincaraz rivalry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/jannik-sinner-beats-carlos-alcaraz-in-atp-finals/106016348</link><description>Jannik Sinner has defeated world number one Carlos Alcaraz 7-6 (4), 7-5 in the ATP Finals title decider, defending his crown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e22513592369347affdecc29fa48dd1</guid></item><item><title>Groote Eylandt's unique rehabilitation program offers alternative to NT prison system amid record incarceration rates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/groote-eylandt-nt-rehabilitation-program-nt-prison-crisis/106007976</link><description>As the NT's prison population soars to new highs, Anindilyakwa elders on Groote Eylandt are delivering a unique rehabilitation program that provides participants with physical and psycho-educational programs, as well as new skills and employment opportunities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c264b98767b14288601b3656e660f24</guid></item><item><title>Unique rehabilitation program offers alternative to prison system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/stateline-groote-eylandt-rehab-centre-alternative-to-prison/106015402</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">039031c507c111d5767aa5572109796c</guid></item><item><title>Esperance community fights for more change, a decade on from deadly bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/deadly-esperance-fires-10-year-anniversary/106011936</link><description>A decade on from bushfires that claimed four lives, this community says not enough has been done to ensure they are safe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26fef5c10f539bb8ef24c281e054fc28</guid></item><item><title>New York Jets NFL player Kris Boyd shot in Manhattan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/new-york-jets-nfl-player-kris-boyd-shot/106016502</link><description>New York Jets cornerback Kris Boyd has been critically injured in a shooting in mid-town Manhattan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">536c1eb11403e2519b622d685cc852a1</guid></item><item><title>Iran begins cloud seeding to induce rain as it faces worst drought in decades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/iran-cloud-seeding-worst-drought-in-decades/106016566</link><description>Cloud seeding involves spraying particles such as silver iodide and salt into clouds from aircraft to trigger rain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2ac4d6818d3c9412a85d4a3f80ca6df</guid></item><item><title>Calls for greater education as growers in WA's south-west brace for polyphagous shot-hole borer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/growers-brace-for-impact-of-polyphagous-shot-hole-borer/106015566</link><description>Growers in this major food bowl are nervous for their future, as the state focuses its shot-hole borer efforts on outer-Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50f4a3a5e7ce5cf47c88150724bea96c</guid></item><item><title>South Africa beat India by 30 runs in low-scoring first Test boilover</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/south-africa-beat-india-in-first-test-boilover/106016596</link><description>South Africa upsets India on a turning pitch at Eden Gardens, with spinner Simon Harmer taking eight wickets in a man-of-the-match performance for the World Test Champions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f15a3e3dceaa4fad6333648dc1958129</guid></item><item><title>These young men escaped restless boredom that led to chaos and crime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/from-youth-crime-to-mentoring-with-football-and-skateboarding/105895098</link><description>Nye was getting into trouble and making bad choices when he was handed a lifeline that helped him turn things around.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e607803765cf9a6e1b25808c6b5ddc53</guid></item><item><title>Two men allegedly run over during road-rage incident near Forster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/forster-road-rage-incident-leaves-three-hospitalised/106016444</link><description>Two men are in hospital with serious injuries after an alleged road-rage incident near Forster on the NSW Mid North Coast. A teenager travelling with the men was also injured when he tried to help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10337217fe577c9d50c84c1b4134e358</guid></item><item><title>Koala mapping near Mudgee discovers strong population and ideal habitat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/mudgee-koala-mapping-finds-critical-population/105977120</link><description>Scientists mapping koala habitat in the NSW central west find it is larger than previously thought, but concerns remain over expansion plans at a nearby coal mine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">084df53a2828bc45a1af61c81e23d553</guid></item><item><title>Ireland celebrates after Troy Parrott secures last-second World Cup qualifier victory over Hungary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/ireland-beats-hungary-in-last-second-of-world-cup-qualifiers/106016698</link><description>Ireland keeps its hopes alive of making the World Cup finals for the first time since 2002 with a stunning comeback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0fecaa98eb474ea98596755ff77fd05</guid></item><item><title>When is the 2025 AFL draft? Here's your guide to bidding, trades and the official pick order</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/afl-draft-2025-everything-you-need-to-know-guide/106017028</link><description>Another AFL draft has arrived, offering dozens of teenage footballers the chance to realise their dreams. Here is everything you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95c3159204fc6f2fc50d5996c5f009b6</guid></item><item><title>From Blue Poles to Gina Rinehart, the most controversial artworks in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/controversial-artworks-australia/105984714</link><description>Art can stir strong feelings in people, both good and bad. These artworks fell in the latter, provoking great controversy in Australia, and telling us a lot about who we are as a nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2c66a5a1b1ff5afbc408c2410615cc7</guid></item><item><title>Australian golfers qualify for LPGA Tour Championship as Swede Linn Grant wins The Annika</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/australia-lpga-tour-championship-linn-grant-wins-the-annika/106017048</link><description>Swede Linn Grant has won The Annika on the LPGA Tour, finishing the tournament 19 under par for a three-stroke victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1f6676bcd51e58e8b1b01acd7728bf4</guid></item><item><title>Protesters in Mexico City attacked police with stones, fireworks, sticks and chains.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/protesters-in-mexico-clash-with-riot-police/106017096</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3ae815e97b1433b4b5b5cf40b75bef2</guid></item><item><title>Gen Z protests in Mexico City brings thousands out against crime and corruption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/mexico-gen-z-protests-gain-momentum-against-crime-corruption/106016816</link><description>The demonstration was mostly peaceful but ended with some young people clashing with the police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d288f9b9c30370a39087f65efadb877f</guid></item><item><title>Sam Konstas picked to open for Prime Minister's XI against England in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/sam-konstas-picked-to-open-for-prime-minister-xi-england/106017212</link><description>Sam Konstas will return to the scene where he made his case for Test selection last summer, with the axed opener given a chance to face England with the Prime Minister's XI.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3473b1050834fe6d4191bbba1937ae0</guid></item><item><title>Paralympic gold medal winner Paige Greco dies, aged 28</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/paralympic-gold-medal-winner-paige-greco-dies-aged-28/106017286</link><description>Australian Paralympian Paige Greco, who won Australia's first gold medal of the 2020 Tokyo Paralympic Games, has died aged 28.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39fe1f64b531a269cb3986cf717522a6</guid></item><item><title>China's seafood import rules behind a partial closure of Tasmania's rock lobster fishery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/tasmania-rock-lobster-fishery-antibiotic-florfenicol-salmon/106016448</link><description>The Tasmanian government closed two zones within the state's rock lobster fishery just hours after the commercial season opened. The closure is in response to concerns about an antibiotic being used by salmon companies and the rock lobster industry's reputation in overseas markets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b69359e0def6b5ab9dacf255531f62d1</guid></item><item><title>Why the ACT has gone further than other jurisdictions in closing schools over coloured sand asbestos concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/why-the-act-has-closed-schools-over-asbestos-sand/106016514</link><description>The ACT has closed 70 schools over the coloured sand asbestos scare. Why is it the only jurisdiction to do so?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c01cfca034233367a3ea078fd54beb00</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann gets full forensic copy of Toowoomba rape accuser's phone after court order</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/bruce-lehrmann-gets-full-copy-toowoomba-rape-complainant-phone/106017160</link><description>A judge rules in favour of Mr Lehrmann, who has been seeking a full copy of the woman's phone for several months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d69499f6cb9e2c763c6a0e7d6cd62945</guid></item><item><title>US flagship aircraft carrier arrives in Caribbean as part of massive military build-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/us-aircraft-carrier-carribbean-venezuela/106016932</link><description>Following the arrival of a 100,000 tonne warship in the Caribbean, as part of a massive military build-up, President Donald Trump has hinted that the US "may be having some discussions" with Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">594992e9b8c375933e7230409adc2c58</guid></item><item><title>Mackay Base Hospital expansion paused as contractor withdraws from site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/mackay-base-hospital-expansion-paused/106016520</link><description>Brisbane contractor BESIX Watpac will leave the Mackay Base Hospital construction site in Queensland as a report finds the cost of a 128-bed expansion has more than doubled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcec71f0845df5a45558dc3a585ca88d</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump calls on Republicans to vote to release Epstein files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/trump-calls-epstein-vote/106018036</link><description>President Donald Trump has called on his fellow Republicans in Congress to vote for the release of files related to the late convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df4f580cc759e73761cec529a1b9db13</guid></item><item><title>Sky Sports dumps dedicated women's sport TikTok channel Halo days after launch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/sky-sports-removes-womens-sports-tiktok-account-halo/106015524</link><description>English broadcaster Sky Sports responds to widespread criticism of its new women-focused, pink-themed Sky Sports Halo TikTok channel by dumping it within days of its launch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">282f8b65b943e639c926324bab5c2a79</guid></item><item><title>Celebrated actor, author and historian Sir Tony Robinson on his iconic role as Baldrick</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/celebrated-actor-author-and-historian-sir-tony-robinson/106017488</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6fdb0636cf949ffc81e57e6eca8c63fb</guid></item><item><title>Victorian youth offenders allowed to leave state for Gold Coast trip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/victorian-youth-offenders-take-trip-to-gold-coast/106016812</link><description>Two violent youth offenders serving a community corrections order in Victoria have been allowed to travel interstate for a taxpayer-funded trip, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25757467b6df9c4b7a36eea296ea7f4a</guid></item><item><title>Sharing COP presidency with Türkiye 'not an option', says Albanese</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/albanese-sharing-cop-presidency-with-turkiye-not-an-option/106017904</link><description>As Chris Bowen lands in Belém with the clock ticking on a resolution, Anthony Albanese says the rules against co-presidency for the COP are clear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9794fb3c53b4519304b21822dc905b0b</guid></item><item><title>Rachel Griffiths explores the role of art in understanding our wars in new show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/rachel-griffiths-explores-the-role-of-art-in-understanding/106017622</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">661b5a620cdae966b4351857fd983f9d</guid></item><item><title>Should I kick my diet soft-drink habit? Where do I start?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/should-i-kick-my-diet-soft-drink-habit-where-do-i-start-/106007994</link><description>You don't have to give up diet soft drinks altogether. But being mindful of how much soft drink you drink, and how often, can help you make healthier choices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8ad2c096503d0bd2d35b8a08f58567a</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese writes to states, telling them to rein in public hospital spending</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/anthony-albanese-tells-states-to-rein-in-hospital-spending/106017654</link><description>Health ministers are furious with a letter from the prime minister demanding they rein in spending if they want a public hospital funding deal honoured.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84ca8710050bda5c8532914dceb9e7e4</guid></item><item><title>Mother of 15-yo victim addresses getaway vehicle driver involved in fatal crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/jaydon-chauveau-parliament-house-crash-victims-mother/106018240</link><description>The mother of the 15-year-old boy who died in a car crash near Parliament House last year has spoken to one of the perpetrators involved during a court sentencing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e4acca9f9c94b514a08d980a507acad</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government denies dingoes could be kept as pets under contentious reclassification</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/dingo-reclassification-biosecurity-regulations-queensland/106000986</link><description>Queensland is considering changes that would remove restrictions on keeping dingoes and while the government says that will not mean people can keep them as pets, experts fear it could be an unintended outcome.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4338424fa0fdeae0ef247600ca95736</guid></item><item><title>Police charge 750 people with DV offences in four-day blitz, as services call for funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/nsw-police-domestic-violence-arrest-blitz-services-need-funding/106016234</link><description>More than 750 people have been charged under Operation Amarok XII, though support services say they are desperate for funding to match this police response.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3a6e988937537bc47818d31a73c8279</guid></item><item><title>Caroline Flack: Search for the Truth raises questions about assault charges and British tabloid ethics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/caroline-flack-documentary-revelations-media-police/106018362</link><description>In a two-part series, the mother of television presenter Caroline Flack examines the final months of her daughter's life and what she believes to be the mishandling of the criminal case against her daughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a12a6552a4b1f5a4fd8d1f21aa0b176</guid></item><item><title>Late Yolŋu leader Paul Gurrumuruwuy Wunungmurra honoured with PhD for anthropology, filmmaking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/paul-gurrumuruwuy-wunungmurra-phd-for-original-research/106013740</link><description>World-renowned anthropologist, filmmaker and Arnhem Land Indigenous leader Paul Gurrumuruwuy Wunungmurra has become the first Yolŋu person to be honoured for his work with a PhD for original research.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b19ee00b267d8622be272dec4ca318ee</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos sand contamination also affecting New Zealand, after 70 Australian schools close</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/asbestos-sand-contamination-new-zealand-school-closure/106017844</link><description>After asbestos was found in a range of coloured sand, early childhood centres and schools in Australia and New Zealand are hurrying to dispose of potentially contaminated products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfa35953b42e65748b152a39baccd75a</guid></item><item><title>WA bikie Dayne Brajkovich fined $500 over Nazi swastika facial tattoo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/dayne-brajkovich-charged-over-modified-nazi-tattoo/106018884</link><description>A Western Australian bikie known for his distinctive facial tattoos is fined after tattooing a Nazi swastika on his chin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">affeccbcca1602af51398276256b7837</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian private mental health service The Hobart Clinic reopens after 17-day closure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/tasmanian-mental-health-hospital-hobart-clinic-reopens/106016912</link><description>A $2 million transitional funding injection from the Tasmanian government has allowed The Hobart Clinic to treat patients for six more months while it comes up with a sustainable business model.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fddd37d2b51ab0986ed2914f7d3cf0b</guid></item><item><title>Jury in trial of Rajwinder Singh, charged with murder of Toyah Cordingley, taken to beach where her body was found</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/qld-toyah-cordingley-trial-rajwinder-singh-cairns/106016662</link><description>The jury was taken by bus to Wangetti Beach, north of Cairns, where Ms Cordingley's body was found buried in a shallow sand grave in 2018.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4cf89665461f09e93ed8302da6a4ca7</guid></item><item><title>Arsonist sentenced to time served, community corrections order for synagogue attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/angelo-loras-synagogue-arsonist-court/106019188</link><description>Angelo Loras pleaded guilty to setting a fire to the East Melbourne Hebrew Congregation synagogue on July 5.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26ddc60f622e661b2ff3dc56add29a3f</guid></item><item><title>South African man who attended Neo-Nazi rally outside NSW parliament has visa cancelled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/verify-neo-nazi-rally-participant-visa-revoked/106018130</link><description>The federal government has revoked the visa of a man who attended the far-right National Socialist Network protest at NSW's parliament house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b76921ba7f888c119b8ec7bca1ab37b</guid></item><item><title>Australian beef producers welcome end to Donald Trump's import tariffs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/beef-producers-welcome-end-of-tariffs/106018228</link><description>Shoppers at home and abroad are unlikely to see any immediate change in the price of Australian beef as tariffs that did little to curb demand in the first place are lifted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c0295fa27b30c3d32c17b6c75d5199f</guid></item><item><title>Quick and easy summer dinners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/easy-healthy-summer-dinners/105822526</link><description>The busy end of year calls for simple dinners that are ready in 35 minutes or less.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c150e5b10f059167f94843c91f1d296</guid></item><item><title>Homes searched, knife found in Melissa Trussell, Rosemary Brown cold case probe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/melissa-trussell-rosemary-brown-suspects-homes-searched/106018670</link><description>Police search two homes linked to a suspect in the investigation into the murder of Adelaide woman Rosemary Brown and the disappearance of her 15-year-old daughter, Melissa Trussell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49277d0ab0c89ed8c7a1f87b5026936d</guid></item><item><title>Dozens of Canberra schools to reopen, 25 remain closed over coloured sand asbestos contamination concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/dozens-canberra-schools-remain-closed-coloured-sand-asbestos/106019038</link><description>Dozens of public schools in the ACT will reopen or partially open tomorrow, but 25 remain closed for all students.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">403edecc55dd3b941ebf562588a5450e</guid></item><item><title>Liberal Minister decided not to give football club 100k after it attended Labor presser</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/utas-stadium-funding-commitment-north-launceston-footbll-club/106018408</link><description>Tasmanian Sports Minister Nick Duigan has admitted he reneged on plans to give North Launceston Football Club $100,000 after the club's president did a media conference with Labor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14be4877e7cdaf0d18378f4851d202ac</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Liberal leader Brad Battin facing leadership challenge as soon as Tuesday morning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/victoria-brad-battin-liberal-leadership-challenge/106019530</link><description>The opposition leader was informed by a delegation of MPs that he had lost the support of the party room, less than 12 months into his tenure as leader and just over a year out from the state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe4dbfb2be9f670da14edcbe68247616</guid></item><item><title>Offenders 'targeting' elderly residents at home in series of assaults in Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/elderly-residents-attacked-at-home-in-alice-springs/106016890</link><description>Three elderly Alice Springs residents have been assaulted at their Sadadeen homes within a 10-day period this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">665e2c7aab825f76c7c849d34092d77b</guid></item><item><title>Black swan 'Jandal' released in Alice Springs after recovering from suspected dog attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/alice-springs-black-swan-released-after-dog-attack/105974208</link><description>An unlikely patient in Alice Springs is returned to the water treatment ponds two weeks after being found injured from a suspected dog attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ac67925c2602e1c59871b9efe0f6a00</guid></item><item><title>Man sentenced over 'disgusting' death threats to Senator Fatima Payman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/man-sentenced-over-fatima-payman-death-threats/106016600</link><description>A Victorian court has sentenced a man to a community corrections order after he sent death threats to Australian senator Fatima Payman via email.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">640101d01f3a096ee8a29760edfa8aaf</guid></item><item><title>Speared wobbegong shark latches onto fisher's arm in WA's South West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/wobbegong-bites-spear-fisher/106017506</link><description>A man spearfishing in the state's South West has been bitten by a wobbegong shark, with bystanders stabbing the fish multiple times to remove it from the man's arm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2ba95cee12d2716ba1cc23c1ce34044</guid></item><item><title>Queensland former rugby league player Trevor Gillmeister charged over alleged assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/trevor-gillmeister-charged-police-assault/106019636</link><description>The retired rugby league player was charged with public nuisance, assault and obstructing police after an incident in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f6f85b5bce2b6c43a1f9cf197be9752</guid></item><item><title>Brother of driver recounts Walcha Derby accident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/brother-of-driver-recounts-walcha-derby-accident/106019946</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c908e732bc608b171d3baed998390bb</guid></item><item><title>Walcha demolition derby crash puts sport under scrutiny as Safework NSW investigates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/walcha-demolition-derby-crash-to-damage-sport/106016564</link><description>New scrutiny is expected in the demolition derby industry after a crash that injured 13 people in northern NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">944149ce497f4ca8e44b10f13c3496f6</guid></item><item><title>Identities of three NT residents charged with fraud over alleged $71 million Defence contract scheme revealed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/three-face-darwin-local-court-afp-alleged-defence-contract-fraud/106017382</link><description>Three Northern Territory residents who were charged on Friday over allegations of a $71 million Defence contract fraud scheme have been granted bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09d5797db5f8c8a2f8f195ebb35d3c28</guid></item><item><title>New WA Corruption and Crime commissioner alters report by predecessor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/new-ccc-boss-edits-john-mckechnie-japan-rort-report/106019914</link><description>Western Australia's new Corruption and Crime Commissioner removes a section of a controversial report written by his predecessor about the state's former trade commissioner in Japan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57c25cbbf4e7e67597c6d3c5c3fae8f8</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106018274</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98779dd691f5cd97ed5db0d8fb719e54</guid></item><item><title>Man sentenced over 2024 drowning death of UTAS student Deepinderjeet Singh</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/sentencing-2024-hobart-waterfront-drowning-deepinderjeet-singh/105627554</link><description>A 19-year-old has been sentenced to four years in jail after pleading guilty to the 2024 drowning death of student Deepinderjeet Singh, after he pushed him into the river at Hobart's waterfront.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3f25a9516c5e08696038b56d31951a3</guid></item><item><title>Brendan Doggett poised for Test cricket debut in first Ashes Test against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/brendan-doggett-ashes-test-selection-perth/106020038</link><description>Fast bowler Brendan Doggett says he learned he could make a Test debut while waiting to bat in South Australia's Sheffield Shield run chase last week against Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8502ae382f2de6c019d1618216d6f0e</guid></item><item><title>Mary Fowler's resilience in face of mental health struggles hailed by Matildas coach Joe Montemurro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/mary-fowler-matildas-mental-health-joe-montemurro/106019580</link><description>Mary Fowler is unlikely to be back on the pitch with the Matildas until next year at the earliest, but coach Joe Montemurro is making sure to stay in close contact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4088e4edf783bb36f9dab8b7ce4f910a</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man denied bail over alleged car park sexual assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/lal-ro-puia-denied-bail-alleged-car-park-sexual-assault-canberra/106019956</link><description>A 30-year-old man is behind bars after prosecutors alleged he pursued a woman into an underground car park where he tried to sexually assault her.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e1b803cc93d12e0512551e191882c32</guid></item><item><title>Catholic Education Tasmania to close six schools, with three others partially closed, due to coloured sand recall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/tasmanian-catholic-schools-shut-tuesday-coloured-sand-recall/106020206</link><description>At least six Tasmanian Catholic Education schools will be closed and three others partially closed on Tuesday due to the national recall of coloured sand products over asbestos contamination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fbea7ca273f5cb2f2e20576efc392e4</guid></item><item><title>Foreign minister says Labor's 'landmark' agreements builds more stable Asia-Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/foreign-minister-wong-australia-architect-asia-pacific-stability/106019990</link><description>The foreign minister has used a major speech to celebrate the government's string of security agreements, saying Labor has helped build a region more stable and less deferential to authoritarian powers like Russia and China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f611ac9a7de4e30493da9c6d2bc83df9</guid></item><item><title>High chance of a cyclone forming off the NT coast this week, potentially impacting Darwin, BOM forecasts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/nt-cyclone-high-chance-of-forming-near-darwin-bom-forecast/106017076</link><description>The chance of a cyclone forming off the Northern Territory coast this week is now high, the Bureau of Meteorology is forecasting, with Darwin potentially impacted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32d729a1060a2c6721f7f34b552bdea8</guid></item><item><title>Bangladesh's ousted PM Sheikh Hasina sentenced to death for student crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-sentenced-to-death/106020478</link><description>A Bangladesh court has sentenced ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina to death after finding her guilty of crimes against humanity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">178548480ecd805a14632813c78b7a83</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins completes bowling session before first Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/pat-cummins-completes-bowling-session-before-first-ashes-test/106020424</link><description>Australia captain Pat Cummins completes a full bowling session at training just four days before the start of the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7efacbc1a9c820d6f1197e4a721fbc1</guid></item><item><title>Rio Tinto scraps $215m research centre and BioIron product after decade of development</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/rio-tinto-scraps-wa-green-steel-bioiron-product/106019692</link><description>Mining giant Rio Tinto scraps a $215 million research centre and green steel project touted last year as a key staging ground for the world's net zero transition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51ffe8af4b14a77380de2ca43c97d8d5</guid></item><item><title>Some Perth trains cancelled after carriage came off the tracks at Bayswater station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/perth-train-derailed-traffic-chaos-at-peak-hour/106020498</link><description>A number of Perth trains are cancelled, causing delays for passengers at peak travel time, after a train came off the tracks at Bayswater Station.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9ee77b1612b142bb157e585f6a7c5b9</guid></item><item><title>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley guarantees she will remain leader until next election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/opposition-leader-sussan-ley-guarantees-leadership/106020032</link><description>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley may be under siege, but says she has no doubts she will remain party leader until the next federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f004c86a7822636864959b0d1b52cdaf</guid></item><item><title>Couple reported as missing for four days in Finke Gorge National Park, near Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/nt-tourist-couples-reported-missing-four-days-finke-gorge/106020548</link><description>A couple travelling through Central Australia have been reported as missing for the past four days. The tourists were last seen at Finke Gorge National Park near Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1e4efdf54b2a7f4e50cfb9971fd2724</guid></item><item><title>Explosion on Polish railway line to Ukraine an act of sabotage, Polish PM says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/poland-railway-line-explosion-act-of-sabotage-donald-tusk-says/106020652</link><description>The track is a vital link for supplies to reach Ukraine, with the incident the latest in a wave of similar attacks across Europe since Russia's invasion began.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75b80ebec4b1bf4f4d88f3cf14306a45</guid></item></channel></rss>