<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 07:23:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Albanese government turns defence sights north, completing $355m upgrade to RAAF Base Tindal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/government-completes-upgrade-raaf-base-tindal/106275670</link><description>A Royal Australian Air Force base near Katherine in the NT is updated with purpose-built hangars and improved runways.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03a9ca4f5d5657c2442fa9549ffa67b7</guid></item><item><title>Australia's heatwave smashes temperature records with some places nearing 50C</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/australia-heatwave-smashes-temperature-records/106275472</link><description>The Australian Open is off to a cooler start today after parts of Melbourne buckled under 45-degree heat yesterday, in a heatwave setting historic temperature records across the country's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2b3c7b34ebf30cebc6c854b490efff0</guid></item><item><title>Search for alleged triple murderer Julian Ingram may be like 'finding a needle in a haystack'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/finding-julian-ingram-will-be-difficult-former-officer/106273608</link><description>A former deputy commissioner of police who was involved in the eight-year search for one of Australia's most notorious fugitives says finding alleged Lake Cargelligo triple murderer Julian Ingram will be difficult.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8fb5ed69d9b38c60f8f0d61f136388b</guid></item><item><title>Sydney's landfills are set to reach capacity by 2030 sparking controversial plans to take trash to the regions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/sydney-landfill-capacity-regional-communities-incinerator-plans/106250180</link><description>A proposal to build an incinerator in the regional town of Parkes could see 700,000 tonnes of Sydney's red bin rubbish transported there every year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5548469c3cacacaf0e4a89da25a9d128</guid></item><item><title>Andrew and Tristan Tate lose bid to sue Adelaide YouTuber, launch appeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/andrew-and-tristan-tate-lose-bid-to-sue-adelaide-youtuber/106119086</link><description>An Australian YouTuber who is being sued by Andrew and Tristan Tate in a Florida court has won a bid to have the case dismissed, a decision the self-described misogynist influencers are now appealing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4516cd7f63699d938c05baff6f6b69df</guid></item><item><title>Scientists warn microplastics testing could be overestimating extent in human body</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/researchers-call-for-more-rigour-in-microplastic-testing/106275540</link><description>Queensland researchers lead calls for a standardised approach to microplastics testing, amid growing concerns about the impact of the pollutants on the human body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed0812ca82338b0a7f8cee84109e3b4d</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur receives feedback from Carlos Alcaraz after Australian Open loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/australian-open-alex-de-minaur-carlos-alcaraz-quarterfinal/106276482</link><description>Alex de Minaur acknowledges he needs improvement in his game, as Carlos Alcaraz moves on to the Australian Open semifinals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d0772e15c4d94d9c16a531773bc618b</guid></item><item><title>Documents reveal widespread misconduct, complaints, at Busy Bees childcare centres in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/misconduct-at-busy-bees-childcare-revealed-canberra/106256286</link><description>Disturbing allegations of verbal and physical mistreatment of toddlers, poor supervision and repeated staffing failures have emerged in documents about Busy Bees childcare centres in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0b190fb93708f11306c512af0fc79a8</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Festival 2026: Our favourite shows from Lacrima to Wake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/sydney-festival-2026-program-lacrima-wake-nowhere-hot-chip/106270990</link><description>A debauched Irish wake, a three-hour French play about a royal wedding dress and British electro-pop band Hot Chip were some of the best of the festival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de22002a63df290695b1055c54a35581</guid></item><item><title>'Incredibly abnormal' temperatures 20C above average in parts of Australia — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/heatwave-south-east-australia-weather-victoria-bushfires/106276290</link><description>Towns in New South Wales and Queensland are sweltering today amid a record-breaking heatwave, as firefighters continue to battle multiple blazes in Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">932c094089c1c12c63c06f08aadf15d1</guid></item><item><title>Rado Vidisic, A-League title winning coach and Australian football figure, dies aged 64</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/a-league-title-winning-coach-rado-vidosic-dies-aged-64/106276864</link><description>Rado Vidosic, a highly-regarded Australian football figure and coach across a number of A-League clubs and teams, dies of cancer aged 64.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16da6dfa221a94bba24b8ebe472c71a4</guid></item><item><title>Carlos Alcaraz approaching 'unmatchable' level after mastering powers of concentration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/tennis-carlos-alcaraz-aus-open-quarterfinal-analysis/106276424</link><description>Twelve months ago, Carlos Alcaraz was outwitted by a hobbled Novak Djokovic. This time around, against a rampaging hometown hero, there would be no slipping up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c317e157bd5311c468f2727e6b9f3db</guid></item><item><title>Judge orders ICE head to face court as Trump shakes up Minnesota operation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/minnesota-judge-orders-ice-head-to-face-court/106276814</link><description>A Minnesota judge takes the extraordinary step of ordering the acting director of Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) to appear in person and explain why his agency keeps ignoring court orders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcd40a6959de93cd437f96e7023d6470</guid></item><item><title>Floor collapse at Toll warehouse causes statewide vaccine shortages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/floor-collapses-at-brisbane-toll-warehouse/106272588</link><description>A section of floor has caved-in at Queensland's only vaccine warehouse, causing statewide delays to childhood vaccination schedules.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fa19a94d76f73ef8ead7640a5186fab</guid></item><item><title>Busselton ratepayers set to foot $60 million bill after performing arts centre cost blowout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/cost-of-busselton-arts-centre-blows-out-and-delays/106273766</link><description>Residents demand answers after the cost of a performing arts centre in the state's South West more than tripled its original allocated budget.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68522bc97950a856821d1a5817ea21c9</guid></item><item><title>Meet the 2026 Trailblazers changing regional Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/heywire-26-trailblazers-changing-regional-australia/106154604</link><description>Jayden is helping youth go from feeling "lost, angry and unheard" to "proud strong and seen". He's one of our 2026 Trailblazers, announced today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07e1f1bd2e589d52d1a28389012efec4</guid></item><item><title>University of Southern Queensland astronomer discovers 'potentially habitable' planet candidate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/planet-hd-137010b-discovery-earth-mars-uni-southern-qld/106206380</link><description>An international team of astronomers led from regional Queensland finds an exoplanet 150 light-years away with a 50 per cent chance of having liquid water on its surface.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08c0d0deb5a4413d65c89960aafa3cea</guid></item><item><title>TikTok settles social media addiction lawsuit ahead of trial against Meta, YouTube</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/tiktok-settles-meta-youtube-face-trial-social-media-addiction/106277142</link><description>TikTok agrees to settle a landmark lawsuit on social media addiction, the same day the trial was due to start against Meta and YouTube.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02e95a83373c5f57af7b1483994b7a6a</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds call up Matilda Garrett for Jamaica series as Australia eyes Commonwealth Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/diamonds-name-squad-jamaica-series-commonwealth-games/106277330</link><description>Australia's netball hierarchy settles on a replacement for an injured defender ahead of the Diamonds' three-Test series against Jamaica.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea34a2ad33dfe767762071768385c113</guid></item><item><title>Liberal frontbencher says Morrison's proposal to register imams 'a worthwhile discussion'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/andrew-bragg-scott-morrison-proposal-register-imams/106277042</link><description>Liberal frontbencher Andrew Bragg says Australian Muslims need to take some responsibility for extremist incidents and that a proposal for a register of Islamic preachers is worth considering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea70856261162296ab47edaddfc35f25</guid></item><item><title>Tongans frustrated with Trump's 'collective punishment' of foreign nationals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/tonga-us-travel-restrictions-trump/106249526</link><description>The United States bars Tongans from short-term visits or travel for tourism and business purposes, saying too many are overstaying their visas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a03acab0309315a7358d58af38c4346</guid></item><item><title>Mount Lawley diamond jewellery shop targeted in suspected ram raid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/matusik-jewellers-mt-lawley-ram-raid/106277288</link><description>Thieves target a Mount Lawley jewellery store in an early morning ram raid, leaving empty cabinets and a trail of destruction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53cb0442dd1a11c690b5640c2aabb227</guid></item><item><title>Daylesford crash driver will be compelled to give evidence at inquest, coroner rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/daylesford-driver-deaths-inquest-evidence/106277860</link><description>A Victorian coroner has ruled that a driver with diabetes who ploughed into a crowd outside a regional pub, killing five people, will be compelled to give evidence at an inquest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86a31d07bebf7a53dcabc2985a02e706</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with hate speech Brandan Koschel had posted photos alongside Neo-Nazis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/brandan-koschel-social-media-neo-nazi-group-nsn-photos/106275476</link><description>Brandan Koschel had posted blurred images of himself standing next to prominent Neo-Nazis on a social media account earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dcfbfe7db40d2e04c5b2225f65ea1df</guid></item><item><title>Why haven't police labelled Perth's Invasion Day rally incident terrorism? Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/why-perth-invasion-day-rally-explosive-not-labelled-terrorism/106276450</link><description>Identifying ideological motivations behind attacks is critical to separating terrorism from other events just designed to cause fear, an extremism expert told the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1f022d205f7d1bbc82d23db48e936f8</guid></item><item><title>Tony Abbott intervenes in Liberal leadership battle calling on right to unite to oust Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/tony-abbott-calls-on-conservatives-to-unite-and-oust-sussan-ley-/106278112</link><description>Former prime minister Tony Abbott has intervened in the Liberal leadership race, urging conservatives to unite behind either Angus Taylor or Andrew Hastie in their bid to oust Sussan Ley from the top job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa601877d4070c743e6ce0b2fdba4094</guid></item><item><title>Coco Gauff backed by Iga Świątek after smashing racquet at Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/australian-open-coco-gauff-smashed-racquet/106278048</link><description>Iga Świątek defends Coco Gauff after footage was shown of the American smashing a racquet at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af66dc4c3e3fd53a512c464210db0cba</guid></item><item><title>Microplastics triple in Sydney's waterways in three years, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/microplastics-triple-in-sydney-waterways-report/106276988</link><description>Microplastic pollution on Sydney's beaches and harbour shorelines has tripled in the past three years, according to a report, much of it from sources of "preventable losses".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a427d023e69d8edbbc0a452d15231048</guid></item><item><title>Accidental 'crying horse' toy becomes Spring Festival bestseller in China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/accidental-crying-horse-toy-wins-hearts-china/106278170</link><description>A dour-faced toy horse — the result of a manufacturing error — has gone viral in China, with some workers saying its expression mirrors their long hours and workplace stress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beab4af9112875b363f4e340d6d82f4d</guid></item><item><title>Woman accused of paying secret kickbacks to surgeons to use medical devices at Brisbane hospital faces court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/medical-devices-kickbacks-scheme-queensland-court/106277080</link><description>The finance manager is one of four people who were charged last month, following an investigation involving the Crime and Corruption Commission and the Queensland Office of the Health Ombudsman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9a89f57c6e346ab77f6bc40c35a057b</guid></item><item><title>Hoodoo Gurus' Dave Faulkner lashes One Nation use of song at March for Australia Rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/hoodoo-gurus-dave-faulkner-lashes-one-nation/106278392</link><description>Faulkner says One Nation and its supporters can "take a running jump" after his band's song was used at an Australia Day rally held by the party, and he's not bothered by party supporters trolling him on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40a56fc63cba76fbf4666d4f44c005b7</guid></item><item><title>Cattle farmer rescues koala from bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/cattle-farmer-rescues-koala-from-bushfire/106278554</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cadefd18a63263de582a53521d3ff8ce</guid></item><item><title>Accessory to murder charges dropped in cold case of NSW mother Pauline Sowry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/charges-dropped-against-man-accused-pauline-sowry-cold-case/106277876</link><description>Leon Boeyen, who has been in prison since May on two charges relating to the 1993 disappearance of the NSW woman, wept as he learned he would be released.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cad606f9d9e7ef4baae49908dcee12bf</guid></item><item><title>Tourist mauled by snow leopard while trying to take photo, Chinese media reports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/snow-leopard-mauls-tourist-trying-to-take-photo/106277636</link><description>A female skier has been mauled by a snow leopard on her way back to her hotel in China after she attempted to get a selfie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d14593825e2af78a830b06aa31778ef0</guid></item><item><title>'Doomsday Clock' set to 85 seconds to midnight, closer than ever to catastrophe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/doomsday-clock-85-seconds-to-midnight-nuclear-threats/106261766</link><description>Atomic scientists set the Doomsday Clock to 85 seconds midnight, with threats such as nuclear weapons and conflicts pushing humanity closer than ever to the point of annihilation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b81ce68e6e053ed4255e01382385ac1d</guid></item><item><title>Leigh Geoffrey Sushames pleads guilty to murder of Tasmania Police Constable Keith Smith</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/leigh-geoffrey-sushames-pleads-guilty-keith-smith-murder/106277880</link><description>The man accused of fatally shooting Tasmania Police Constable Keith Smith pleads guilty to murder in a Devonport court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae32f8dbe71455075e0b5c4ae4c48b5e</guid></item><item><title>Mass wildlife rescue underway with flying foxes entangled at golf club driving range</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/wildlife-rescue-underway-following-noosa-bat-entanglement/106278136</link><description>A mass wildlife rescue is again underway at the Noosa Golf Club after dozens of flying foxes became trapped in netting at its driving range for the fourth time this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f671db969da43aaba079cd618b3c9cf</guid></item><item><title>Why UFC 325 is a collision between Alex Volkanovski's glorious past and uncertain future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/alex-volkanovski-ufc-325-diego-lopes-tai-tuivasa/106277692</link><description>An end of an era looms for Alex Volkanovski as he prepares for his first title defence on home soil, but ahead of UFC 325, Australia's greatest ever MMA fighter is still the nation's gold standard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20b26fceeb1144bfc4c05000db7fc987</guid></item><item><title>Littleproud open to Ley meeting after Nationals spill resolved</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/littleproud-open-to-ley-meeting-after-nationals-spill-resolved/105435280</link><description>Nationals Leader David Littleproud will stare down a leadership tilt from Queensland MP Colin Boyce, though colleagues say it is unlikely the challenger will secure enough votes for a spill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f63ed83de0bcd066a1bacea06b3fa66</guid></item><item><title>At least 16 structures lost in Otways fire with heatwave still impacting Victoria's north-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/victoria-bushfire-structures-destroyed-heatwave/106278038</link><description>At least 16 structures have been destroyed by the Carlisle River fire in Victoria's Otways, with a strong wind change late yesterday afternoon impacting another 1,000 hectares.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20824b3cbd1b2511be193ae182828262</guid></item><item><title>Remains found during search in Tasmanian bush for missing tourist Celine Cremer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/remains-found-during-search-for-missing-tourist-celine-cremer/106279500</link><description>The bushwalker who found human remains while searching for missing Belgian tourist Celine Cremer says he "went into shock" after coming across bones in dense Tasmanian forest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ff9b206f9bbac58e147276b4a1e3f56</guid></item><item><title>Off-contract Usman Khawaja keen to extend Big Bash career with Brisbane Heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/usman-khawaja-brisbane-heat-big-bash-league/106279266</link><description>In the aftermath of his international retirement, Usman Khawaja is keen to extend his Big Bash career, with his preference to strike a new deal with the Brisbane Heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07cbbb1d29b1103cf930a9e72459cfa3</guid></item><item><title>Wine Australia's export report for 2025 shows consumers sobering up as cost of living bites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/wine-australia-export-report-for-2025-global-market-decline-sa/106277572</link><description>Global demand for Australian wine is continuing to dwindle, with the latest Wine Australia export report showing an 8 per cent decrease in 2025 as consumers opt for alcohol-free trends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea608f774b9ac7ff068b1669d2fdaeb6</guid></item><item><title>Teenager accused of electric motorbike death in Perth's north pleads not guilty to manslaughter charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/boy-accused-of-e-bike-death-denies-manslaughter-charge/106278852</link><description>A teenage boy accused of killing a 59-year-old woman while riding an unlicensed high-powered electric motorbike in Perth's north has pleaded not guilty to manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27244f675dcca5226051f20e404ba7f4</guid></item><item><title>'One-off' literary festival, Constellations, to go ahead in lieu of Writers' Week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/alternate-literary-festival-constellations-in-adelaide/106279364</link><description>A community literary festival will go ahead in the wake of the cancellation of Adelaide Writers' Week, but those involved say it is not a replacement for the original event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef44bb2df86cdb6c803ede79ea9f26e4</guid></item><item><title>Counterfeit Botox still being imported into Australia, months after regulator first raised alarm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/counterfeit-botox-items-detected-by-tga-in-australia/106278732</link><description>Counterfeit Botox vials were packaged in branded boxes that appear like a genuine product, according to a renewed warning from the Therapeutic Goods Administration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">776747f9c945055009f9d210c84c6b7e</guid></item><item><title>Alert level downgraded for Bullsbrook bushfire that threatened homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/gnangara-landsdale-bullsbrook-emergency-bushfire-/106279716</link><description>The alert level for a blaze burning north of Perth is downgraded, after it threatened lives and homes on Wednesday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d188ff0ffeb80df51c38775a123ebe40</guid></item><item><title>Iranian doctor who fled to Australia after operating on massacre victims estimates death toll in tens of thousands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/doctor-operated-on-wounded-during-iran-massacre-protests/106277548</link><description>In one of the most harrowing accounts yet, a doctor who fled Iran for Australia recounts trying to save bullet-riddled victims of the government crackdown on protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16fae7ededa33199f7a195a02a8ea18e</guid></item><item><title>Rain has transformed the outback from parched to puddles.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/from-thirsty-camels-mud/106279410</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38a8b5daea7a9f23748c75a79557e4d4</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Tropical Cyclone Luana brings rain relief for remote WA inland cattle stations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/rain-relief-for-inland-pastoralists/106275402</link><description>Weather associated with a former cyclone has drenched parts of Western Australia's inland region, bringing relief for pastoralists who had received very little rain for the previous 12 months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">053e0134cc118a1a332a27b78aabbca0</guid></item><item><title>Jim Chalmers has rejected responsibility for high inflation but will have a tough sell if rates rise again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/chalmers-says-inflation-is-not-his-fault/106279808</link><description>Less than a year after the Reserve Bank started cutting rates, the prospect of a rate rise is a political nightmare for a treasurer hoping for clear air.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c548b41b8cc890d99129d352e74eaa6f</guid></item><item><title>Chinese ambassador hints at retaliation if Port of Darwin is returned to Australian control</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/chinese-ambassador-hints-at-retaliation-over-port-of-darwin/106279996</link><description>China's ambassador to Australia, Xiao Qian, questions the Albanese government's ethics in wanting to return the Port of Darwin to Australian hands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7e20f0806b7a98f43b02ecd05bc0e9f</guid></item><item><title>Former South Korean first lady Kim Keon Hee sentenced to 20 months in jail for corruption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/former-south-korean-first-lady-20-months-jail-for-corruption/106279794</link><description>Kim Keon Hee, the wife of jailed former South Korean president Yoon Suk Yeol, is sentenced to prison by a Seoul court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1bb53f35bcdb862033f3203348290f4</guid></item><item><title>Former member of National Socialist Network fights for return of weapons licence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/former-national-socialist-network-member-weapons-licence-appeal/106279468</link><description>A man, who was stripped of more than a dozen guns after police found multiple copies of Adolf Hitler's manifesto at his home, is fighting to have his weapons licence reinstated by a court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb80f484ffa0fbb8d33a0e771ae0749c</guid></item><item><title>Police say bones found at a Phillip Island house not linked to active missing persons case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/silverleaves-bones-found-police-speculation/106252278</link><description>Police say human remains found on Phillip Island are not linked to a missing persons investigation, amid community speculation about whether the bones might be linked to an historic cold case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89ec8aa7ed9af60ad5d5e72dfcd7d98a</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106280098</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcbcc22000a85ac613cdbde4d932e0fc</guid></item><item><title>Doctors failed to tell authorities of driver's vision impairment before fatal Adelaide crash, inquest hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/sa-inquest-into-doctors-conduct-before-crash-that-killed-woman/106278662</link><description>A coronial inquest will investigate why three doctors failed to alert relevant authorities that a man was unfit to drive due to vision impairment in the years before he caused a crash which killed a mother of four.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da7be28c4f70d432f4edbdb020b928da</guid></item><item><title>Chinese ambassador announces joint taskforce in hunt for man who threw hot coffee over Brisbane baby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/chinese-ambassador-taskforce-hunt-for-man-after-attack-on-baby/106280208</link><description>China's ambassador to Australia says authorities will travel to Brisbane as the search for the man who threw hot coffee on a baby continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91f987c854543d48fd9ae9dd3d4ab584</guid></item><item><title>The search for Celine Cremer, Belgian tourist who disappeared in the Tasmanian bush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/belgian-bushwalker-celine-cremer-search-explainer/106279718</link><description>The two-and-a-half year search for a missing Belgian tourist has led to the discovery of bones, which may mean closure is not far away.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c448696f43c190849b55df59ba622a14</guid></item><item><title>Gem hunter receives suspended prison sentence for illegally mining turquoise at NT sacred site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/gem-hunter-illegal-mined-turquoise-ore-nt-sacred-site-sentencing/106278496</link><description>A gemstone dealer has received a four-month suspended prison sentence for illegally mining more than 8 tonnes of turquoise ore at a Northern Territory sacred site.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f3a9d472c461f3385d63d0404569b85</guid></item><item><title>First Nations urge stronger response after alleged Invasion Day rally attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/first-nations-reactions-to-perth-rally/106278632</link><description>First Nations leaders have urged governments to take stronger action in response to the alleged attack at an Invasion Day rally in Perth on Monday. Social Justice Commissioner Katie Kiss says failing to do so "sends a message that Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander people do not matter".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d788783b2f2b1d9210b64763272a33fb</guid></item><item><title>Victorian man faces court over alleged assault in SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/police-charge-victorian-man-over-alleged-assault-in-sa/106280464</link><description>A Victorian man has faced court after allegedly stabbing a man before following him to an Adelaide hospital where he allegedly made threats toward paramedics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c613de2e822b75b0731caebcd5936a5</guid></item><item><title>Authorities investigate bomb allegedly thrown into Perth Invasion Day rally crowd as 'potential terrorist act'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/authorities-investigate-alleged-perth-bomb-as-terrorist-act/106280668</link><description>A joint statement by WA Police, the Australian Federal Police and domestic security agency ASIO say the agencies' investigations are ongoing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f67cb75199536da0fae24b70fd1f55b5</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic gets lucky break in Australian Open win over Lorenzo Musetti</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/australian-open-novak-djokovic-lorenzo-musetti-quarterfinal/106279982</link><description>As he trailed Lorenzo Musetti, 10-time champion Novak Djokovic knew he was on the ropes as he looked to keep his Australian Open campaign alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6989483c04e6e616d14a6022e57d9acd</guid></item><item><title>Concerns domestic tenants required to share excessive personal data to secure leases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/concerns-tenants-sharing-excessive-data-to-secure-lease-ahuri/106269564</link><description>Tenants are being forced to hand over excessive personal data when applying for rental properties, with new research warning that applicants' personal information could be at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">203f59b7aa7b6ce7128c5459c2aee8d1</guid></item><item><title>Amazon accidentally announces further 16,000 layoffs in AI pivot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/amazon-accidentally-announces-layoffs/106280800</link><description>A misfired internal email was the first time many employees found out about a second round of job cuts in just six months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86b1eaba850241fba6bf277d009edc28</guid></item><item><title>Otways bushfire in Victoria eases as heatwave conditions continue in state's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/victoria-bushfires-otways-carlisle-river-walwa-dargo-heatwave/106280362</link><description>Firefighting conditions have improved around the fire that burnt through properties near the town of Gellibrand in Victoria's south-west, but crews warn the blaze is still not under control.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">554afdc299cbe69c2dca6a8d6afd824f</guid></item><item><title>Line search of river planned for area where Celine Cremer went missing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/police-press-conference-potential-celine-cremer-remains/106279906</link><description>Police say forensic testing will be done to determine the identity of the remains, as officers prepare for a further search along a section of the Arthur River.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d52ac84e4445b8c251bb6ed7f5c5f84</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Greens MP Tim Read to retire from state politics to focus on cancer battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/brunswick-greens-mp-tim-read-reveals-cancer-diagnosis/106278032</link><description>Victorian Greens MP Tim Read reveals he will retire from politics at this year's election after he was diagnosed with metastatic cancer — but not before one last political fight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bd4bd27af283ebfca28c70c7e951c88</guid></item><item><title>The US wanted to ban TikTok over national security concerns. Does a deal with China fix that?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/what-does-china-tiktok-deal-mean-for-us-national-security/106270748</link><description>US politicians — both Republican and Democrat — had worried TikTok's Chinese ownership could mean American user data was vulnerable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">829a0db74e3349f33087c609ec8bdd2d</guid></item><item><title>Rate hike pain is on the way for Australian borrowers, but will they be able to tolerate it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/inflation-higher-than-expected-rba-now-likely-to-raise-cash-rate/106278844</link><description>The Reserve Bank cut interest rates three times last year, betting inflation would moderate. But that hasn't happened, and now a rate hike looks likely next month — and possibly another in May.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df000fb90ee59b24891f02660da6ab94</guid></item><item><title>As Jannik Sinner and Carlos Alcaraz dominate, straight-sets matches are skyrocketing at the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/tennis-sinner-alcaraz-aus-open-competitiveness-dominance/106280732</link><description>The gap between the top seeds and the rest of the players in both the men's and women's draws has resulted in another day filled with straight-sets wipeouts at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d69272a825653b32b8365f5533ec617c</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic disrespected as Serena Williams offers Coco Gauff racquet smashing tips — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/australian-open-day-11-quick-hits-coco-gauff-novak-djokovic/106277850</link><description>Serena Williams offers Coco Gauff some tips on how to smash a racquet properly, while Novak Djokovic gets a dose of luck on court and a little disrespect off it. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">697d054373a3857b053e1b782af5c2d7</guid></item><item><title>Agents involved in Alex Pretti killing put on leave as Trump says mayor 'playing with fire'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/brk-ice-officers-placed-on-leave/106281050</link><description>The Trump administration is trying to manage a national uproar over Alex Pretti's killing and officials' subsequent comments about the 37-year-old nurse, who they accused of "domestic terrorism".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3f81743e3bee2b10b5762c82ff79b7e</guid></item><item><title>Health courses the most popular area of study for Australian university students in 2026, as IT enrolments fall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/university-degrees-australian-students-picking-2026/106247426</link><description>Data from the country's tertiary admissions centres shows health courses are again the most popular area of study for university students in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">139a0ca6dd78a91330e6c5f3629e5bb4</guid></item><item><title>Music rights body says Australian artists are struggling to find streaming audiences at home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/australian-music-fighting-streaming-algorithm-apra-amcos-says/106249072</link><description>While this year's triple j Hottest 100 featured a significant number of Australian songs, local artists have suffered a shocking decline in online streaming figures over the past five years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df046aa975e2266052fa7e20806b22b3</guid></item><item><title>Missing records in ACT childcare documents prompt concerns about scale of issues in sector</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/missing-records-act-childcare-documents-prompt-concerns/106273400</link><description>An ABC investigation has found some parent complaints and incident reports were excluded from a major release of ACT childcare documents, raising concerns about the scale and severity of problems in the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c95c200a5a330934622e47dee782f4b</guid></item><item><title>Rising bike thefts inconveniencing the nation but police say it's 'opportunistic'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/rising-bike-thefts-affecting-the-nation/106275258</link><description>If it hasn't happened to you, you likely know several people who have had their bikes stolen, and it isn't just those that are worth a lot of money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6dc1484206db416c099441a5f468dd9</guid></item><item><title>Phoebe Litchfield out of WPL with injury, raising concerns for India multi-format series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/injured-litchfield-leaves-wpl-concern-for-home-india-series/106281146</link><description>Australian batting star Phoebe Litchfield has to abandon her Women's Premier League season because of injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0792bab34432b61c7a12dbc112228057</guid></item><item><title>How locals handle the heat in one of Queensland's hottest towns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/how-locals-handle-the-heat-in-thargomindah-qld/106280568</link><description>Outback Queenslanders are tough — this is how they handled a 48.5C day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d507267542b1079586122e4e4293bb66</guid></item><item><title>30,000 livestock killed in Victorian bushfires, NSW swelters in extreme heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/heatwave-south-east-australia-nsw-victoria-bushfire-weather/106279598</link><description>NSW has been on high alert for bushfires as towns across south-eastern Australia continue to swelter in the extreme heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff03fc14923185be2c1ba1e8b2905c25</guid></item><item><title>The Two Teabags bringing joy and connection to residents in aged care homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/two-teabags-bring-joy-and-connection-to-aged-care-residents/106189520</link><description>Former aged care workers Marina Lee-Warner and Julie Joy have created a live show tailored to older Australians, including those facing cognitive decline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">788bee98eb47096ea22ff0306404d812</guid></item><item><title>Two Teabags bringing joy and connection to aged-care residents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/two-teabags-bringing-joy-and-connection-to-aged-care-residents/106278704</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ecac7ffd26aa483d679b08a466272ab</guid></item><item><title>As Trump threatens Iran, a US naval strike group arrives in the Middle East</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/iran-us-navy-strike-group-donald-trump-middle-east/106276852</link><description>A US aircraft carrier, supporting warships, fighter jets and air-defence systems have arrived in the Middle East, as the world waits to see to what action — if any — Donald Trump will take against Iran.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72c7775fcee2488ef071234da78470a7</guid></item><item><title>Talison lithium mine blasts in regional WA ignite calls for home buyback scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/talison-lithium-mine-greenbushes-residents-want-home-buybacks/106262764</link><description>Home owners living beside the Greenbushes lithium mine in Western Australia are calling for a buyback or relocation scheme amid the mounting toll of blasting, dust and noise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c14dc3318797e8e1079726c364b0ca3</guid></item><item><title>Why some towns in regional Australia are hotter than others</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/hot-weather-record-temperatures-regional-victoria-mallee-renmark/106277472</link><description>Temperature records have fallen across Australia this week, but why is it always the same towns hitting these extremes?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef22a3be604fda8e6439bc9f6103f1f4</guid></item><item><title>Fire fighters from Malmsbury brigade return home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/four-fire-fighters-from-malmsbury-brigade-return-home/106281590</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fadd79c15ed437b6a4ff9bcd67146b5a</guid></item><item><title>What is India's Nipah virus outbreak, what are the symptoms of the illness and how can you protect yourself from it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/what-do-we-know-about-india-nipah-virus-outbreak/106280738</link><description>Two cases of the Nipah virus have been detected in India, prompting a raft of screening measures to be enacted in countries across Asia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1450cb0be69b0ff6f046cde421748e6</guid></item><item><title>Sophie Molineux named Australian cricket captain, succeeding Alyssa Healy ahead of India series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/molineux-named-healy-successor-as-australian-captain-cricket/106281600</link><description>Sophie Molineux becomes Australia's new multi-format captain, taking over from Alyssa Healy ahead of a home series against India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3c004078c58d9d0e5319eb299a36155</guid></item><item><title>Firm behind cryptocurrency Qoin fined $14m for 'misleading' and 'condemnable' conduct</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/cryptocurrency-qoin-company-fined-14m-misleading-conduct/106278720</link><description>The company behind the Gold Coast-based crypto token Qoin has been fined $14 million by the Federal Court following long-running legal action by the corporate watchdog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9d146e42d41f5066717f6f68e96b4a5</guid></item><item><title>Man convicted of London assault after Barron Trump witnessed attack on video call from US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/barron-trump-intervention-helps-convict-russian-man-of-assault/106281372</link><description>A Russian man who became jealous of a woman's friendship with the youngest son of US President Donald Trump has been found guilty of assaulting her by a London court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f7973448815ecf8425118beefc2065b</guid></item><item><title>Canberra woman faces court for allegedly assaulting stranger's newborn baby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/baby-allegedly-thrown-from-pram-by-stranger-in-canberra/106281532</link><description>A woman aged in her 50s has faced the ACT Magistrates Court over the incident. WARNING: This story contains distressing details about an alleged assault on a baby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9793a142556574294d48d0dbe72e45ba</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026: Aryna Sabalenka the familar face in women's singles semifinals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/sabalenka-has-single-focus-with-open-trophy-beckoning/106282116</link><description>The Australian Open has lost the regular women's grand slam heavyweights from the draw but world number one Aryna Sabalenka remains a Melbourne Park constant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">304d87b0efed370b633f496682ae96cb</guid></item><item><title>First Nations leaders welcome Perth Invasion Day rally terror probe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/first-nations-leaders-welcome-perth-invasion-day-terror-probe/106281330</link><description>First Nations leaders say WA Police's investigation of Monday's alleged Invasion Day rally attack as "a potential terrorist attack" is a step in the right direction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">569d29cfb9373ce563d6e6a1fa8b83d1</guid></item><item><title>Farmers want permanent solution after 200-tonne landslide closes Waterfall Way</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/farmers-call-long-term-solution-waterfall-way-landslide/106257220</link><description>The NSW government has announced a fresh assessment of a key transport route recently closed by a 200-tonne landslip, but residents say it has all been done before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82584941049f0bda9e1a83bec4d70df4</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania takes control of ore stockpile after Liberty Bell Bay defaults on $20 million loan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/liberty-bell-ball-loan-default-tas-to-take-ore-stockpile/106281912</link><description>The Tasmanian government appoints receivers and managers to protect the manganese ore stockpile paid for by taxpayers at the Liberty Bell Bay smelter in the state's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9b3c04fb5b2a166cf60f6125f2fa151</guid></item><item><title>Tears of pride for Aryna Sabalenka as she makes Australian Open history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/australian-open-day-12-live-blog-sabalenka-svitolina-rybakina/106282372</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka is into her fourth straight Australian Open final after beating Elina Svitolina in straight sets in their semifinal, where she will meet Elena Rybakina. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13a3254c51c4da4f38c73f93e6a5fdb4</guid></item><item><title>David Speirs sees 'pathway' to standing for election amid eligibility questions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/david-speirs-pathway-to-election-amid-eligibility-questions/106281982</link><description>Former South Australian Liberal leader David Speirs says there is a way he could stand for the upcoming state election — but is yet to declare whether he will — despite the electoral commission declaring he is ineligible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fae2aef5067464d9cc7ec98c01ec275</guid></item><item><title>Malaysian football executives resign over player naturalisation scandal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/malaysian-football-executives-resign-over-player-naturalisation-/106282446</link><description>A scandal in which foreign players were improperly granted citizenship to play for the national team leads to the "voluntary" resignation of the executive committee of Malaysian soccer's governing body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e02d9a276c2f62056f0ea9525e1dc247</guid></item><item><title>Why it took nearly half-an-hour for police to start evacuating Perth’s Invasion Day rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/wa-invasion-day-explosive-police-response-analysis/106280370</link><description>As police face criticism for their handling of Perth's Invasion Day rally bomb scare, a law enforcement expert says they faced a "no-win situation".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d01ca40c394e758ea661c68dbe75a21</guid></item><item><title>Former employee accused of defrauding three NSW local councils by more than $1 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/nsw-martin-dimec-accused-defrauding-three-local-councils/106282160</link><description>Martin Thomas Dimec is facing more than 40 charges of fraud after police allege he stole the money from Murrumbidgee, Shoalhaven and Goulburn councils across 12 years of employment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f04f54fbda6336f24a525726db0fb900</guid></item><item><title>Australian government fund to invest $75m in company producing material critical to AI supply chains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/75-million-investment-high-purity-alumina-ai-gladstone/106281688</link><description>An Australian government fund will invest $75 million in Alpha HPA, helping it build the world's largest single manufacturing facility for high-purity aluminium materials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68738f60c938ecaa61726eb30f9acdbd</guid></item><item><title>Police release CCTV as part of Lake Cargelligo shootings manhunt.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/police-release-cctv-lake-cargelligo-shootings-manhunt/106283512</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d86e277f924ee26bb63f482dcc3b2d4c</guid></item><item><title>Police release footage of triple murder suspect as commissioner calls DV a scourge on the community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/police-commissioner-domestic-violence-scourge-lake-cargelligo/106281242</link><description>The NSW Police commissioner says a surge in domestic violence attacks is a disgrace as police release footage of Julian Ingram, the main suspect wanted over the deadly Lake Cargelligo shooting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">946a1963558f64a302a30eef9f06fc0b</guid></item><item><title>Coalition chaos drags on ahead of first official sitting week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/coalition-pauline-hanson-liberals-nationals-one-nation/106278234</link><description>Former prime minister John Howard once observed that Pauline Hanson was an "electoral gift to the Labor Party". His words proved relevant this week as the Coalition's chaos dragged on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e55fe948ed9cac9dfbe249d4a750510</guid></item><item><title>Roland Griffiths handed life sentence for Kylie Sheahan's murder in 2022 house fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/roland-james-griffiths-life-sentence-murder-kylie-sheahan/106281606</link><description>A Victorian Supreme Court judge sentences Roland James Griffiths to 32 years in prison without parole for the "brutal" murder of wife, 35-year-old Kylie Sheahan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efb42b4268ccf4bed75015b3001f7b87</guid></item><item><title>Hastie and Taylor fail to agree on plan to oust Ley despite clandestine meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/hastie-and-taylor-fail-to-agree-who-should-challenge-sussan-ley/106283820</link><description>The two conservative men vying to replace Sussan Ley as leader of the Liberal Party met in Melbourne before attending a memorial service for their former colleague Katie Allen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48442b172bb5d4d73b9254f6ca7c0381</guid></item><item><title>United Nations special rapporteur seeks to join challenge to NSW government's protest restrictions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/un-expert-seeks-to-join-challenge-nsw-govt-protest-restrictions/106283462</link><description>A United Nations expert is seeking to join a constitutional challenge to the NSW government's protest restrictions brought in after the Bondi terrorist attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b18300f51ba0611dd1a38a500e33cb00</guid></item><item><title>Parramatta provided with emails from Zac Lomax's lawyer as contract drama plays out in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/zac-lomax-eels-contract-case-lawyer-agent-storm/106284054</link><description>Parramatta has been given nine emails sent by Zac Lomax's lawyer as the case between the former Eels winger and his former club prepares to hit the courtroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6fab00ca9fdf9b673ff2ad88952bce4b</guid></item><item><title>'Predatory' former Logan teacher jailed for child sex offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/predatory-teacher-jason-seung-hak-lee-logan-child-sex-offences/106283910</link><description>The former Logan teacher, 30, has been handed a 5-year sentence after pleading guilty to multiple child sex offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8da2c6ce2847559254b32f4c3916b7f</guid></item><item><title>How farmers help keep their livestock and produce alive during a heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/farming-through-a-heatwave-how-farmers-stay-cool/106281292</link><description>How farmers make sure their livestock — and produce — stay safe during a heatwave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aabaf9f0bf0f0b845aba873eaf89c73c</guid></item><item><title>Most AI assistants are feminine — and it's fuelling dangerous stereotypes and abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/ai-assistants-female-dangerous-stereotypes-abuse/106281652</link><description>The design choices behind AI technologies — female voices, deferential responses, playful deflections — create a permissive environment for gendered aggression.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52aba3fc8e780a3a444023a722041f1a</guid></item><item><title>Queensland farm cashing in on US wellness industry demand for camel milk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/farmers-celebrate-us-interest-in-queensland-camel-milk/106283200</link><description>Camel milk is in hot demand in the wellness industry, now one Queensland farmer is seizing the moment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">441b865e5599c229e2ffa3008cb77db4</guid></item><item><title>China executes online scam ringleaders from Myanmar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/china-executes-online-scam-ring-leaders-from-myanmar/106284248</link><description>China executes 11 people linked to Myanmar criminal gangs, including "key members" involved in online scam operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a76abd16aad858c6ca8150d5841334a</guid></item><item><title>Planning to breastfeed? Preparation can help you meet your goals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/what-to-know-about-breastfeeding-before-your-baby-arrives/106220406</link><description>While most mothers in Australia start breastfeeding, by the time babies are five months old, exclusive breastfeeding drops to 15 per cent. Knowing what to expect — before bub is born — can increase the chances of meeting your breastfeeding goals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74803b6ee63f792d44b8c092db9dbd1e</guid></item><item><title>Two arrested after allegedly stolen vehicle is driven at police in Geelong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/geelong-allegedly-stolen-vehicle-pursuit-bus-crash/106284388</link><description>Two arrests have been made after police shot at an allegedly stolen car that collided with a school bus before driving towards officers in Geelong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ef2cc3862ba12e80e598a7b1233b0f2</guid></item><item><title>Police shoot at allegedly stolen car during chase in Geelong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/police-shoot-at-allegedly-stolen-car-during-chase-in-geelong/106284648</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">360fae01305c75faeb1bdb5909dcce0a</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026: Tennis Australia boss Craig Tiley listening to Coco Gauff player privacy complaints</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/australian-open-2026-player-privacy-craig-tiley-coco-gauff/106284528</link><description>The Australian Open will listen to complaints from players like Coco Gauff about behind-the-scenes cameras but remain convinced of their value, Tennis Australia chief executive Craig Tiley says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbe1d3a7a95c6a69cf43b391f66f0cb6</guid></item><item><title>Canadian backpacker Piper James's family and friends to visit Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/backpacker-piper-james-family-to-visit-australia/106283172</link><description>The heartbroken parents of Canadian backpacker Piper James will travel to Australia next week to visit K'gari, the island where their beloved daughter lost her life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e079dad83b3f8d3cb0ffd9b2196ec944</guid></item><item><title>'Mayhem' as fast-moving bushfire engulfs backyards in suburban Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/ellenbrook-bushfire-emergency-perth-north/106284734</link><description>Between six and eight homes were damaged by a fast-moving bushfire in suburban Perth, the Department of Fire and Emergency Services (DFES) says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df0585e6fedc28359330cd70e86f9d43</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106284468</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8d8acf018ab6475c2015fa2a7d33813</guid></item><item><title>'Never seen magnitude' of foreign vessels in Far North Queensland, as government defends border security</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/island-residents-reject-gov-border-security-investment/106284502</link><description>Torres Strait Island leaders say federal government claims of strong border protections do not match what communities are seeing on their doorstep in Queensland's far north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2d2d7fac8c95f3b44ad51bf9aec3f0c</guid></item><item><title>Bluey tops streaming charts in US for second year running</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/bluey-tops-streaming-charts-in-us-second-year-running/106284782</link><description>Americans tuned in to watch 45.2 billion minutes of Bluey, Bingo, Bandit and Chilli last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">359b77f5544572ac6d4f3b8653a634d0</guid></item><item><title>Bushfires still raging across Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/bushfires-still-raging-across-victoria/106284446</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13a6718d8a3f29d000689f0c75891d18</guid></item><item><title>All eyes on the Australian Open tennis finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/all-eyes-on-the-australian-open-tennis-finals-/106284458</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d088caf20b01b562ac0fe5b1c71e64a</guid></item><item><title>Former senior Mackay police officer sentenced over child abuse material</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/former-police-officer-sentenced-over-child-abuse-material/106282896</link><description>The court heard Mark Andrew Lewer had created profiles on four 'dark net' websites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78aaf37e0af7a758214fcaf544ce1516</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka manages anger to book fourth consecutive Australian Open final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/aryna-sabalenka-books-aus-open-final-fourth-consecutive-year/106284842</link><description>World number one Aryna Sabalenka books her fourth consecutive Australian Open final, defeating Ukraine's Elina Svitolina in straight sets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57f2c93fd324f785507cbc9e507cf448</guid></item><item><title>Democrats strike funding deal with White House as Trump undercuts border tsar on Minnesota drawdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/border-tsar-tom-homan-speaks-in-minneapolis-minnesota/106285350</link><description>Donald Trump says he has struck a deal with Congressional Democrats to temporarily fund the Department of Homeland Security, heading off a political brawl that seemed inevitable after the Senate voted down the latest package of government spending bills.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f31c3c2125dcc02174fa3cfda2dbb834</guid></item><item><title>EU labels Iran's Revolutionary Guards a terrorist organisation in policy shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/eu-designates-iran-revolutionary-guard-a-terror-organisation/106285596</link><description>European Union foreign policy chief Kaja Kallas says "repression cannot go unanswered" as the bloc looks set to categorise the IRGC alongside Islamic State and Al Qaeda.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9a14f02b677056cb22457aff09b5981</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire threat eases as crews work to keep Victorian blazes contained</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/bushfire-threat-eases-as-vic-crews-work-to-keep-blazes-contained/106284786</link><description>Conditions have improved on the fireground in parts of Victoria, where more than a dozen structures have been destroyed by flames. But authorities remain on alert.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df5e3469fe9d81d4a3d9ddd2d0bce79b</guid></item><item><title>What could have happened to Celine Cremer, the Belgian tourist who went missing in Tasmania in 2023?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/celine-cremer-what-could-have-happened/106283120</link><description>Celine Cremer went missing in 2023 from a track in a remote part of Tasmania's north-west. With several recent discoveries in the area, these are the theories of what could have happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fa46b028409bdd47ade634a0a74b296</guid></item><item><title>Trump says Putin agrees not to fire on Kyiv for one week, as freezing cold grips Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/putin-agrees-not-to-attack-kyiv-for-one-week-trump-says/106285676</link><description>Ukrainians, including residents of the country's capital, are experiencing their toughest winter of the war as Russian attacks target electricity infrastructure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b95e6b9ba98482a847a4af1c52c81d6</guid></item><item><title>February interest rate rise will be a 'bitter pill' for those struggling with cost of living, advocates say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/interest-rate-hike-to-hurt-amid-cost-of-living-crisis-fca-says/106282550</link><description>Consumer advocates fear a rate hike when the RBA board meets next week could be the "straw that breaks the camel's back" for borrowers in mortgage stress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d8d8f6bfb26ee5e5a784163fc3fa2fb</guid></item><item><title>GPS trackers in e-waste from Australia reveal 'likely' illegal exports to South-East Asia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/gps-in-e-waste-from-australia-reveal-exports-to-south-east-asia/106196324</link><description>A not-for-profit environmental group put GPS devices in 35 e-waste items and dropped them off at recycling locations in four Australian capital cities. Here's what they found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aca5cebf2406f07e87dae8d61746ccda</guid></item><item><title>The curious case of Pritam Singh, Singapore's ousted opposition leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/singapore-opposition-leader-pritam-singh-deposed-by-pm/106271192</link><description>Even for a de facto one-party state, the ruling People's Action Party's decision to dictate who runs Singapore's opposition is remarkable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fa2f090a4baa201df980d8ba10a1641</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic feels disrespected ahead of Australian Open semi against Jannik Sinner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/australian-open-novak-djokovic-jannik-sinner-semifinal/106284616</link><description>Playing with a chip on his shoulder or feeling slighted is often when 10-time Australian Open champion Novak Djokovic produces his best results.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e4e42d306849efa5a2fc671b18e697a</guid></item><item><title>As Donald Trump weighs up actions, Iranians send the US a message to 'please help'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/iranians-begging-donald-trump-intervention/106278760</link><description>Protesters in Iran are begging US President Donald Trump to launch military action to help topple the Islamic regime. But could it happen?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0104644f2ea8023284ca1e0ce13e8e0</guid></item><item><title>Two aspirants who are unlikely to suit the times vie for Liberal leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/coalition-leadership-angus-taylor-andrew-hastie-sussan-ley/106252048</link><description>Andrew Hastie and Angus Taylor both want to run against Sussan Ley. But the two right-wingers cannot afford to split the conservative vote on which their tilts would rely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba51f7fb24d29cbbec7cd19701ea84b9</guid></item><item><title>Elena Rybakina takes the long road back into Australian Open final and best in the world conversation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/tennis-elena-rybakina-aus-open-final-analysis/106285234</link><description>After being the forgotten figure when it comes to conversations about elite women's players, Elena Rybakina has put her name back up in lights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">051e6d02ab7256e11d03f0982faada6d</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide median house price grows $50,000 in a quarter, reaching $925,000 according to Valuer-General data</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/median-adelaide-house-price-inches-closer-to-1-million/106247930</link><description>Experts are forecasting continued growth this year as Adelaide's metropolitan median house sale price inches closer to $1 million, according to Valuer-General data.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f5fc36214dede0fbcb20494fda824d7</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: BAFTA nominations, a new cricket captain and departing pandas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/weekly-news-quiz-january-30/106282664</link><description>Think you've been paying attention to the news cycle?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fda808678e7347ad9a8a5250a0565d7d</guid></item><item><title>Authorities warn NSW residents to stay vigilant as heatwave draws on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/high-temperatures-for-nsw-towns-urged-to-heed-weather-advice/106283602</link><description>As parts of western and south-western New South Wales enter their sixth day of temperatures above 40 degrees, authorities are urging people not to become complacent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79fbffe8f0a8813241709e4ac02457db</guid></item><item><title>The makers of AACTA-nominated movies and TV shows discuss the Australian screen industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/aacta-nominations-bring-her-back-kangaroo-apple-cider-vinegar/106274762</link><description>Ahead of next week's AACTA Awards, the makers of frontrunners Bring Her Back, Kangaroo and Apple Cider Vinegar share their thoughts on the state of the local screen industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bce16781a3b4a5eeb30978d95ccc0b3</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Police refuse to release report following review into treatment of women in State Emergency Service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/queensland-police-refuse-to-release-state-emergency-service/106281368</link><description>The ABC understands that some female volunteers aired allegations of sexism and discrimination as part of the review, which was undertaken in early 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f88aa72b099de2c9065ed62d71fcb921</guid></item><item><title>Steven Johnson to stand trial for alleged Victorian cold case murder of Christopher Jarvis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/steven-johnson-trial-alleged-murder-of-christopher-jarvis/106283412</link><description>A landlord has been ordered to stand trial over the cold case death of his tenant Christopher Jarvis, who disappeared from his home near Warrnambool 20 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">caa90199513892529dc287febc0c6eb8</guid></item><item><title>A mid-match coffee break, Aryna Sabalenka's hindrance and a finalist's flashback — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/australian-open-day-12-quick-hits-aryna-sabalenka/106284124</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka's abnormal sound is punished, an Aussie has a mid-match coffee break and a women's finalist has an unsettling flashback. Here are the quick hits from day 12 at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">377325548b4589d070e7dd6f71ee3896</guid></item><item><title>Shoppers remember 'old days' at grocery store that has operated since late 19th century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/shoppers-memories-at-maclean-grocery-store/106093338</link><description>A New South Wales grocery store has been operating since before there was refrigeration, electricity and even Vegemite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13022bd7c8867c23fb979d67f3523425</guid></item><item><title>Hastie says he doesn't have support to challenge for Liberal leadership — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/federal-politics-live/106282604</link><description>Andrew Hastie will not contest the Liberal leadership, clearing the way for a possible challenge to Sussan Ley from Angus Taylor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d21429c4a876b692acc686fb3842a875</guid></item><item><title>Trump tariffs could 'isolate' the US and create new trading blocs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/trump-tariffs-isolate-united-states-creating-new-trading-blocs/106279190</link><description>In the past fortnight, US President Donald Trump has threatened tariffs against at least 10 countries. Some experts say the Trump administration's tariff policy is leading to the creation of new trading blocs, and isolating the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d680083e4bdd5f1c248ec52b9f8477d2</guid></item><item><title>Gold, silver plummet ahead of Fed chair announcement — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/asx-markets-business-live-news-jan30-2026/106283750</link><description>The prices of gold and silver have plummeted in Asian trade as markets prepare for a surprise Federal Reserve announcement, and the ASX 200 has finished the week on a negative note. Look back on the day's finance news in our business blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b8022ddef8840fb50b933476c1e329d</guid></item><item><title>Former AIS athletes blast handling of documentary amid fears it could 'damage' historical abuse victims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/ais-documentary-channel-nine-abuse-allegations-canberra/106279640</link><description>Former AIS athletes who claim they were physically and psychologically abused while living at the AIS have urged Channel Nine to shutter a documentary about the history of the institute.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9de1c6bd71c97b2bbccefed68364173d</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of flying foxes die, hundreds rescued, amid record-breaking SA heatwaves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/thousands-of-bats-in-sa-killed-after-heatwaves/106283058</link><description>A deadly combination of heatwaves has all but decimated a colony of flying foxes in SA's south-east, with surviving bats taken in by conservationists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dc9d83483a1198cfab5c4f68d8ace11</guid></item><item><title>SA Arts Minister Andrea Michaels to quit politics after state election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/andrea-michaels-to-quit-politics-after-sa-election/106285782</link><description>Andrea Michaels will not recontest her seat of Enfield, in Adelaide's inner north, but will remain in the cabinet until the March election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e5816633168f19eb7900aaffb75bb37</guid></item><item><title>Inpex under investigation after suspected sulphur dioxide exposure leaves worker in hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/nt-worker-hospitalised-potential-sulphur-dioxide-exposure-inpex/106283830</link><description>The Australian Workers' Union has raised concerns after a worker at Inpex's Ichthys gas facility was allegedly exposed to sulphur dioxide and hospitalised, prompting an investigation by the NT workplace safety watchdog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb31e475b4a1845ff9a7e9b9a6bf5dcc</guid></item><item><title>Australian Defence Force member charged over army truck crash north-west of Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/driver-of-military-vehicle-charged-over-crash-with-civilian-car/106285838</link><description>Police charge the 25-year-old over the collision, which left a woman in hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55d384ae2b5efdff0c8d63fa8d4d70f6</guid></item><item><title>Celine Cremer searcher speaks of 'shock' at finding human remains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/celine-cremer-searcher-on-finding-human-remains/106285976</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afc7e05d50f944d93d9a824405dd1ea0</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan down Australia by 22 runs in first match of T20 World Cup warm up series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/australia-pakistan-t20-world-cup-zampa/106285786</link><description>Despite the best efforts of evergreen spinner Adam Zampa, Australia have suffered a 22-run defeat to Pakistan in the first T20 of their World Cup preparations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5b6797ab9e5e0e0753ce33df51981bf</guid></item><item><title>Queenslander launches petition to charge drivers for dangerous rescues amid wild flooding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/queensland-petition-flood-driver-swiftwater-rescues/106258426</link><description>A flood victim is leading a campaign to force drivers who knowingly enter floodwater to pay for their rescue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da8fc48f6130854fda8658eedcce7bd7</guid></item><item><title>Men flee four-wheel drive at flooded Cape York crossing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/men-flee-four-wheel-drive-at-flooded-cape-york-crossing/106284024</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba0f5aa5a6c6860752d4400e87f4980c</guid></item><item><title>From Bondi to Perth, questions are being raised about the safety of public events</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/could-perth-invasion-day-rally-incident-signal-new-normal/106284214</link><description>As the Invasion Day rally incident and Bondi terror attack shatter expectations that people should be able to gather peacefully in public places, Australians may be facing a new normal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">539e7ccf9d8939fd21e1cb916140fd5c</guid></item><item><title>WA heatwave causes almost $1 million in crop losses to Gascoyne fruitgrowers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/carnarvon-growers-mangoes-wiped-out-by-heatwave/106273574</link><description>Growers in WA's Gascoyne food bowl have lost an estimated $1 million of fruit, with another heatwave on the way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8f8570aede49cc27fffd82e86a4981d</guid></item><item><title>Genetically modified purple tomatoes bound for fruit shops after regulator approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/gm-purple-tomato-approved-for-australian-growth-and-sale/106262696</link><description>The purple tomato was altered to make it taste better and boost nutrition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5bd1ac2234b9c2c680495f600b02f6f</guid></item><item><title>Polar bear walks on ice with cubs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/polar-bear-walks-on-ice-with-cubs/106285916</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">821b321e4da3c5195e26ac0fa30cfeb5</guid></item><item><title>'Good news' for Norway's polar bears, which are growing fatter despite loss of sea ice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/fat-polar-bears-svalbard-norway-despite-loss-of-sea-ice/106285810</link><description>Polar bears of the Svalbard archipelago have surprised scientists by growing fatter, despite shrinking sea ice, with one theory that the bears are including reindeer and walrus in their diet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9286b0e2cae46a331f15a2787d19d49d</guid></item><item><title>Teenage bushwalker found dead in the Blue Gum Forest in Blue Mountains National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/teen-bushwalker-found-dead-in-blue-mountains/106285992</link><description>Police say the teen and his 17-year-old friend became separated after setting out on a three-day hike.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">345b04c4263a082572d2e37c27a95eb3</guid></item><item><title>Kevin Muscat's Shanghai Port one of nine Chinese Super League clubs hit with corruption sanctions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/kevin-muscat-shanghai-port-chinese-super-league-corruption/106286038</link><description>Kevin Muscat's chances of steering Shanghai Port to a third successive Chinese Super League title have taken a hit with the club to start the season on minus five points after the Chinese FA completed a wide-ranging investigation into corruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29a24b977d37515cfff1103f297ccadc</guid></item><item><title>Look back at historic V-Set passenger service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/look-back-at-historic-v-set-passenger-service/106285056</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5964ba6b411025766ad372cc45b4be7f</guid></item><item><title>Rare earths mine at centre of Trump-Albanese deal yet to materialise after years in the making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/trump-albanese-arafura-rare-earths-mine-facing-further-delays/106285164</link><description>It is the Central Australian mine promised to help upset China's dominance of the rare earths market worldwide, and bring hundreds of jobs to Australia. But where is it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76c503f1ba23d8a96c79b1c3396b51b5</guid></item><item><title>The US wants to control Venezuela's finances. These armed groups could make it difficult</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/venezuelan-armed-groups-could-challenge-us-recovery-plan/106207132</link><description>The US plan to "recover" Venezuela could spark a domestic backlash in a country that is already heavily divided among various armed groups that have political interests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e60395cd057395211a12f4e84aa39d3b</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump has Iran in his sights, but what is his endgame?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/donald-trump-poised-to-strike-iran/106275390</link><description>As the "massive armada" of the United States approaches Iran to be in place for a possible military attack, a key question remains: what can such firepower actually achieve?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b87d627b2e6226212e6ab3126fac4f59</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Lions coach Chris Fagan says Lachie Neale having his 'best pre-season in a long time'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/lachie-neale-brisbane-lions-pre-season-marriage-breakdown/106286732</link><description>Lachie Neale has been in the spotlight all summer after giving up the Brisbane co-captaincy amid his highly-publicised marriage breakdown but the Lions brass believe the premiership winner is physically in the midst of his best pre-season in some years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa8155609cd081098a4e996ae177fd39</guid></item><item><title>Live: Incensed Zverev hits back as Alcaraz hobbled by injury in semifinal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/australian-open-day-13-live-blog-alcaraz-zverev-djokovic/106286224</link><description>Carlos Alcaraz starts struggling with an apparent groin strain after taking control in his men's singles semifinal against Alexander Zverev, who hits back to win the third set. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c4b896e4b47fb27ee95df0a2b0dea4d</guid></item><item><title>Australia closely monitoring Nipah virus, no change to border control</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/nipah-virus-no-border-control-changes-australia/106286138</link><description>The federal government is closely monitoring an outbreak of Nipah virus in India but has not received any advice to tighten border controls at this stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b3834c00079c11cd5b5192636589a57</guid></item><item><title>Vision of a police shooting involving an alleged stolen car in Geelong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/geelong-police-shooting-vision/106287012</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe143a6a9ef9bf933d365f56a7140536</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley issues ultimatum to David Littleproud as she announces temporary shadow ministry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/sussan-ley-announces-acting-shadow-ministers/106287014</link><description>The under-fire Liberal leader has given seven existing frontbenchers carriage of the portfolios vacated by Nationals, with a threat to leader David Littleproud the arrangements could be made permanent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">495aa296e1f1293c4b1df88740ff1415</guid></item><item><title>Nine Radio sold for cut-price $56m to pub tycoon Arthur Laundy as it spends $850m on outdoor ad company QMS</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/nine-radio-sold-to-arthur-laundy-talk-radio-shrinking-audience/106286352</link><description>Arthur Laundy's Laundy Family Office acquires a network that includes Melbourne's top-rating talk station 3AW, Sydney's 2GB and outspoken conservative presenters such as Ben Fordham and Tom Elliott.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e00eed476a238801bf56a342da10e5b</guid></item><item><title>Katarapko fire in South Australia's Riverland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/katarapko-fire-in-south-australia-s-riverland/106286546</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d834a47cc40ea71c7f7e4de8551e1a4</guid></item><item><title>SA man arrested for allegedly lighting multiple fires during Riverland heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/multiple-riverland-south-australia-bushfires-heatwave/106286030</link><description>A 49-year-old South Australian man has been arrested for allegedly lighting multiple fires in the state's Riverland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77106a453774cdd4f20e9ea14092dd10</guid></item><item><title>Alex Pretti in a scuffle with immigration officers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/alex-pretti-in-a-scuffle-with-immigration-officers/106286476</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a1fb8aee6e02293ff0355d9eaf57bd2</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump shares video of Alex Pretti confrontation with agents 11 days before shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/trump-shares-video-of-alex-pretti-confrontation/106286246</link><description>United States President Donald Trump has shared a video on Truth Social showing Alex Pretti in a confrontation with federal immigration agents 11 days before the intensive care nurse was fatally shot during a separate encounter with Border Patrol agents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5757815551c408c0f12cded050106ea</guid></item><item><title>Police line search begins after human remains found in search for Celine Cremer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/line-search-for-celine-cremer-after-human-remains-found/106286024</link><description>Tasmania Police says six experts have been flown in via helicopter to conduct a line search of the Arthur River, where human remains were found this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">367bbf28105725194bb3b6b8371a2b04</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide Hills man completes 23-year steam locomotive build</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/adelaide-hills-man-completes-23-year-steam-locomotive-build/106284306</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49c54e955468672d703d64312892b926</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Springsteen releases anti-ICE protest song Streets of Minneapolis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/bruce-springsteen-ice-trump-protest-song-streets-of-minneapolis/106286788</link><description>The Boss has blasted the Trump administration and ICE agents in a new song responding to "the state terror being visited" on Minneapolis and dedicated to Renee Good and Alex Pretti.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">900ff7596a77bbcf1626fbb586bcf484</guid></item><item><title>Government lands last-minute hospital funding deal with states</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/albanese-government-deal-hospital-funding-states-territories/106282208</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has bowed to mounting pressure from the states, promising an extra $25 billion for public hospitals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a19c82d245f496322cebe40598b78f9</guid></item><item><title>Machine capable of making millions of illegal cigarettes seized in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/sydney-illegal-cigarette-operation-uncovered-by-abf/106286376</link><description>A machine which can produce millions of black market cigarettes has been seized in a raid in north-west Sydney, as the fight against the illegal tobacco trade heats up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f81cd8fd0d0362ae79d65dfb6d3c2379</guid></item><item><title>Cannington greyhound racing 'carnage' prompts phase out calls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/calls-to-end-greyhound-racing-after-cannington-carnage/106287412</link><description>Four dogs were injured and two euthanased after a greyhound racing event in Cannington this week, escalating calls to end the sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7562d7b386c0d7e42127924c7b652841</guid></item><item><title>'Devastating tragedy': Perth family dead in suspected murder-suicide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/mosman-park-murder-suicide-four-people-dead/106287630</link><description>WA Police are investigating a suspected murder-suicide in suburban Perth after finding two teenage boys and two adults dead in a home in Mosman Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c0026c695591fc80f5c70c3d863255f</guid></item><item><title>Charge laid after allegedly stolen vehicle crashes into Geelong school bus, officer opens fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/charge-laid-allegedly-stolen-vehicle-crash-police-shooting/106286358</link><description>A 43-year-old woman has been charged with handling stolen goods after a dramatic incident that saw police open fire at a vehicle that allegedly drove at officers after crashing into a bus on Thursday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc6465c8a964f47bc0d206bd1ed9d8c0</guid></item><item><title>Families frayed by NDIS cuts brace for more change ahead of defining 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/families-frayed-by-ndis-cuts-brace-for-more-change-in-2026/106269362</link><description>Families frayed by NDIS cuts are bracing for even more change ahead of a year that is set to reshape the scheme into something more sustainable, write Nas Campanella and Evan Young.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2050bfad4e5d8c7178bb64a2e3c25249</guid></item><item><title>Fugees, Weezer, Spiderbait's classic albums turn 30 in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/albums-1996-30-years-weezer-fugees-you-am-i-spiderbait/106126108</link><description>From Weezer's raw emotion to the Spice Girls's pop revolution, revisit 10 iconic albums that made 1996 a landmark year in music. Thirty years on, they still define the era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8077fe8e16e49d742fd093cbca15bb86</guid></item><item><title>Why your sunscreen application might be putting your good intentions to waste</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/how-often-should-you-be-reapplying-sunscreen-this-summer/106079324</link><description>This is what three experts had to say about how to get the best protection from your sunscreen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbf13c6aa015eb074cae6c36de35d329</guid></item><item><title>Canberra woman charged with murder after man found dead in her Braddon unit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/act-woman-charged-murder-braddon-unit-court/106286114</link><description>A 37-year-old woman from Canberra's inner north is charged with murder after the body of a 44-year-old man was found in her unit in December.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d77375ab44d27f619cd86da776c91ba</guid></item><item><title>FBI seizes Georgia ballots as Trump pursues 2020 election grievance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/fbi-seizure-fulton-county-election-ballots-explainer/106286198</link><description>Fulton County, which votes overwhelmingly Democratic, has been a target of President Donald Trump since he narrowly lost the 2020 presidential election in Georgia to Democrat Joe Biden.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9425b33668c5262e1537b345d487501b</guid></item><item><title>Man jailed for injecting girlfriend with meth 24 hours before she died</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/ethan-ross-jailed-for-giving-meth-to-girlfriend-amy-bowden/106286368</link><description>A man who injected his girlfriend with methamphetamine in the 24 hours before her sudden death has been jailed for just over nine months — but his sentence was backdated, meaning he will be eligible for release in May.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afc51ced00b73e89e597a72c663492e7</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand has refused to join Donald Trump's 'Board of Peace'. What about the rest of the world?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/nz-refuses-trump-invitation-board-of-peace-gaza/106286460</link><description>New Zealand has declined Donald Trump's invitation to join his Board of Peace and is calling for "clarity" over the proposal. Here's where other countries stand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3104f6ed696845404ac34be7ab22385e</guid></item><item><title>Hastie rules out challenge to Sussan Ley for Liberal Party leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/hastie-rules-out-challenge-to-sussan-ley/106287872</link><description>The West Australian backbencher had made no secret of his desire to lead the Liberal Party but says he will not run against Sussan Ley next week, a move which could pave the way for Angus Taylor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fbd66676329dfbdf22f30190cab58fe</guid></item><item><title>Tim Picton's brother says seeing CCTV would be 'scarring for me forever'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/tim-picton-wanted-to-become-organ-donor-brother-chris-says/106282500</link><description>In his first interview since the death of his brother Tim, SA's Health Minister Chris Picton reflects on the profound emotional impact of the loss on their family, his reluctance to watch the CCTV footage, and his brother's inability to become an organ donor "because of the coronial process".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dc4e7e3f42b15de05773fd8481d3ef2</guid></item><item><title>Man jailed over antisemitic graffiti spree in Sydney fails to have sentence overturned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/mohommed-farhat-to-stay-in-jail-antisemitic-graffiti-arson/106287870</link><description>Mohommed Farhat's lawyers were urging the court to overturn the sentence on appeal and replace it with an intensive correction order which could have seen him released.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04208019012c5ce98bcb3942c8df4375</guid></item><item><title>More than $370 million now allocated for Victorian bushfire recovery support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/bushfire-funding-albanese-allan/106288080</link><description>The state and federal governments will substantially increase financial support for 23 Victorian local government areas devastated by bushfires this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a10d4fbc334d4b4942a4f0a34da5abb</guid></item><item><title>Gold and silver prices drop ahead of announcement on new US Federal Reserve chair</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/gold-silver-prices-drop-us-federal-reserve-chair-announcement/106289302</link><description>Gold and silver prices fall sharply in Asian trade, sparked by reports US President Donald Trump is set to announce a new US Federal Reserve chair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4830e74ecebdb3c2571478a59c1104f5</guid></item></channel></rss>