<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:09:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>All top six seeds make quarterfinals for first time in the Open Era</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/australian-open-2026-live-jannik-sinner-maddison-inglis-swiatek/106268840</link><description>The 2026 Australian Open will be the first grand slam that all top six seeds in the men's and women's singles have reached the quarterfinals in the Open Era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41d1412692588185302d718d13f0421b</guid></item><item><title>18-year-old tennis player Iva Jović ready to face Australian Open favourite Aryna Sabalenka</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/australian-open-tennis-iva-jovic-aryna-sabalenka/106269176</link><description>Iva Jović refuses to be intimidated about facing two-time Australian Open champion Aryna Sabalenka in the quarterfinals at Melbourne Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a31e99569c9a387cdd1467265ea308ad</guid></item><item><title>What is life like in Delhi, one of the world's most polluted cities?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/delhi-india-air-pollution-residents-struggle-breathing/106085882</link><description>Poor air quality in Delhi has impacted nearly all aspects of life with residents saying they have lost many of the "simple joys" such as opening a window or going for a walk outside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">085920628afd6fe5b51edf17d431eec4</guid></item><item><title>Parents of missing Queensland man Jack McLennan hopeful after meeting with police minister</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/missing-man-jack-mclennan-queensland-police-minister-meeting/106269360</link><description>The parents of missing Jack McLennan say they have drawn some comfort from a meeting with Queensland Police Minister Dan Purdie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1041d64f6e35fa28848910e083b6790</guid></item><item><title>US citizens are becoming collateral damage in Donald Trump's quest to deport immigrants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/us-citizens-collateral-damage-in-trump-s-immigration-crackdown/106269166</link><description>Minneapolis has become the flashpoint of an aggressive immigration enforcement operation ordered by the Trump administration and pitched as a campaign against undocumented criminals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92f5c0d64fad223fd8349ad33fa967af</guid></item><item><title>Potential explosive device thrown into crowd at Perth Invasion Day rally, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/invasion-day-rallies-australia-january-26-australia-day/106267560</link><description>Police say they are investigating whether a device thrown into an Invasion Day rally crowd in Perth contained explosives, in addition to ball bearings and screws found inside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bad110f23151b55de241e4f1394db5bc</guid></item><item><title>Australia Day 2026 marked by citizenship ceremonies, traditional dances, fun runs and heatwave conditions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/australia-day-celebrations-across-country-community-events/106268794</link><description>Communities across the country are marking Australia Day with citizenship ceremonies, traditional dances, smoking ceremonies and fun runs, as the prime minister calls for "unity not division" during a speech in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89a297ebf30dbceba064bdca817744b6</guid></item><item><title>Police arrest man as part of investigation into alleged sexual assault at Yeppen Lagoon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/rockhampton-police-investigate-alleged-sexual-assault/106269804</link><description>Police have taken a 27-year-old man into custody as part of their investigations after a woman was allegedly attacked on a popular walkway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e99697e3dba98f26345668a9a99c8a4f</guid></item><item><title>Gold's record run rolls on with prices surging past $US5,000 as investors seek safety</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/gold-record-run-continues-price-surges-past-us-5000/106269850</link><description>Gold surges to a record high above $US5,000 an ounce, extending a historic rally as investors pile into the safe-haven asset amid rising geopolitical tensions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23bbc0ce16bea8c51eb3c1035a7cf312</guid></item><item><title>'Dog in driver's seat' of ute on Tasmanian beach sparks call for witnesses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/dog-in-driver-seat-of-ute-on-tasmanian-beach/106270074</link><description>Reports of a "dog in the driver's seat" of a ute driving on a Tasmanian beach have prompted police to ask for witnesses to come forward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64bd480c793c2afb08c97fdec71c00ce</guid></item><item><title>Police appeal for information after 54-year-old woman assaulted in Sale home invasion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/sale-ross-street-home-invasion-woman-assaulted-police/106123750</link><description>Wellington Crime Investigation detectives turn to the public for help as they continue to investigate a 2025 home invasion where they allege three men broke in and assaulted a woman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db32c2e589adaee9c0ec93a59c6659fb</guid></item><item><title>Australian of the Year Katherine Bennell-Pegg reflects on space, STEM and the launch pad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/australian-of-the-year-katherine-bennell-pegg-on-space-and-stem/106269082</link><description>The 2026 Australian of the Year — astronaut and space engineer Katherine Bennell-Pegg — is a strong advocate for STEM education, but fears too much talent is being left on the "launch pad".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edeb680b7a28ff90b1a912dad59944d3</guid></item><item><title>Animated movie Imagine invited 150 Indigenous kids to collaborate with stars like Taika Waititi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/imagine-movie-jack-manning-bancroft-aime-indigenous-mentoring/106256658</link><description>The beautifully animated, crowdsourced movie Imagine introduces a wealth of Indigenous knowledge to audiences in the funniest way possible and hopes to generate real change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84f5433c25ed7356c9db4fefe25232b8</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners heartbroken over decision to cull K'gari dingoes involved in Piper James's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/traditional-owners-heartbroken-at-decision-to-cull-kgari-dingoes/106269824</link><description>The Queensland government euthanises six dingoes involved in Piper James's death on K'gari, and is expected to cull more in the coming days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45eaa987e1113e0f5ecce3f19a4a2ad1</guid></item><item><title>Australia Day heat record for Adelaide, as mercury hits 49C in Ceduna</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/adelaide-records-australia-day-heat-record/106270456</link><description>As Adelaide sets a new record for its hottest Australia Day, other parts of SA are enduring conditions that are even more sweltering, with the mercury climbing above 49C in Ceduna.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d0724e16a5e1fce8b2130181191edf8</guid></item><item><title>Madison Keys's world hasn't ended now her Australian Open defence is over</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/australian-open-madison-keys-jessica-pegula-fourth-round/106270864</link><description>There were no tears or tantrums once Madison Keys left Rod Laver Arena, knowing her Australian Open title defence had come to an end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9d96112d66d107dbf2ddad031e238d4</guid></item><item><title>Quick and easy burger recipes for stress-free summer dinners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/quick-and-easy-burger-recipes-for-stress-free-summer-dinners/106136826</link><description>From chargrilled beef patties and beer-battered fish to vegetarian parmigiana and cheeseburger tray bake, we have burgers to suit all tastes and diets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80df8dd571c7b72bbde93a28fde82e65</guid></item><item><title>Call for memorial to Beaumont children, 60 years after they disappeared</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/beaumont-children-missing-60-years-today-memorial/106269224</link><description>Politician Frank Pangallo is calling for a permanent memorial to be installed at an Adelaide beach to acknowledge the disappearance of the Beaumont children in 1966.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d98522fb95c1cd0c87faa382485d057</guid></item><item><title>Worst heatwave in decades sending temperatures close to 50C over south-east Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/south-east-australia-weather-hit-close-to-50c-worst-heatwave/106270302</link><description>A record heatwave across south-east Australia will peak during the coming days, leading to extreme fire danger and temperatures close to 50 degrees Celsius in multiple states.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c04b7f382ab317c08fced4431d4891d</guid></item><item><title>Police confirm human remains found in north Queensland those of missing man Jayden Penno-Tompsett</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/jayden-penno-tompsett-remains-confirmed-north-queensland/105919904</link><description>Human remains found in north Queensland belong to a missing New South Wales man last seen eight years ago, according to police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7df045b9c4b25556bf901030951af32d</guid></item><item><title>Travellers stranded at Nullarbor roadhouses as bushfire shuts Eyre Highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/eyre-highway-closed-bushfire-travellers-stranded/106270912</link><description>A fire near Caiguna has blocked the major road link between Western Australia and the east coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fa28955bc0da7c8801fe5f2ad91544b</guid></item><item><title>Man dies after confrontation with police officers in Kalgoorlie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/south-kalgoorlie-death-in-custody-police-investigation/106271730</link><description>A 43-year-old man has died after an incident involving WA Police officers in South Kalgoorlie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5aab0c4b8db9531438d22ab1be5f0959</guid></item><item><title>Gunmen open fire at soccer field in central Mexico, killing 11</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/mexico-shooting-soccer-field-salamanca/106271736</link><description>Authorities say gunmen opened fire in the city of Salamanca, killing at least 11 people and wounding 12 at the end of a soccer match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1154ce725b04adfda7cea06aae17974d</guid></item><item><title>Government agency deliberately broke law for years, federal watchdog finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/services-australia-knowingly-broke-law-for-years/106261814</link><description>Services Australia has known it was not fully complying with new child support laws since 2019, according to a scathing report released by the Commonwealth Ombudsman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fd0aefb325b79e1cc94de522aa7f401</guid></item><item><title>Benjamin Netanyahu announces discovery of remains of last Israeli hostage in Gaza, Ran Gvili</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/remains-of-last-israeli-hostage-in-gaza-ran-gvili-found/106271998</link><description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu says the remains of Ran Gvili have been found and identified.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97407c51a7fd92648efee5a60e2b745e</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump sends 'border tsar' Tom Homan to Minnesota after shooting of nurse Alex Pretti</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/republicans-express-shock-over-minneapolis-shooting/106271792</link><description>An American citizen, Alex Pretti, was shot by federal agents during a continuing Trump administration immigration crackdown in the city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c571686af181bc1dd64b85b1fde3edb</guid></item><item><title>Russia, Ukraine and US plan further trilateral talks on ending war</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/major-challenges-ukraine-russia-kremlin/106272110</link><description>Volodymyr Zelenskyy says discussions between envoys from Ukraine, Russia and the US in Abu Dhabi last week aimed at ending Moscow's invasion have left some political issues unresolved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f43e81e7388e85393beb91099c9153c2</guid></item><item><title>Victoria on high alert amid extreme bushfire danger and soaring temperatures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/victoria-bushfires-otways-heatwave-soaring-temperatures/106270362</link><description>Firefighters warn a wind change is likely to worsen Otways blaze, while temperature records tumble across the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddb7930b7670149c1a6c26a54de34d55</guid></item><item><title>Hoping to start your finances afresh in 2026? These tips will help</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/how-to-set-new-year-financial-habits/106125752</link><description>It might be time to devote some of your energy and good intentions towards your finances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">408ff5b0fc52a8a653d2b98b79542e00</guid></item><item><title>Track temperatures live as heatwave hits multiple states</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/temperatures-heatwave-tracker-live/106270976</link><description>Use our tracker to keep an eye on temperatures as a heatwave moves across much of the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7cafeaafcd960c34697752bde0aaad5</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open quarterfinalist Alex de Minaur confident he can compete against Carlos Alcaraz</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/australian-open-alex-de-minaur-carlos-alcaraz-quarterfinal/106269964</link><description>World number one Carlos Alcaraz has defeated Alex de Minaur each time they have played, but the Australian is not overawed ahead of their quarterfinal clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a765ff60d9ebc9fc5c75e76a6d7b58bb</guid></item><item><title>China's aging population is saving its way towards economic stagnation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/chinas-aging-population-is-saving-towards-economic-stagnation/106270300</link><description>Unlike many Western economies, Chinese households stash away more than 40 per cent of their income. But the pressure to boost local consumption is mounting for Beijing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17328eb4588c52a344a99b946e249019</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide swelters through night as 'extreme' fire danger forecast across South Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/extreme-fire-danger-as-heatwave-persists-in-sa/106270164</link><description>Authorities are urging South Australians to be vigilant and "make good choices" as "extreme" fire danger is forecast for the southern half of the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">159e0ac2f571dd1593a6067e01ac5b1e</guid></item><item><title>Darderi's tantrum against Sinner, and Ostapenko nails opponent in the face — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/australian-open-day-nine-quick-hits/106269988</link><description>Sabalenka and Alcaraz denied fitness tracking devices, Darderi has a tantrum and Siegemund cops a tennis ball to the face. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1756688589db63ec5adb6449484e2872</guid></item><item><title>Travel quiz: How well do you know your way around the world?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/travel-quiz/106251022</link><description>Which food is thrown in the re-enactment of a medieval food fight? And which airport is the world's busiest?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab8888906986e0413725c8ff81dcf34d</guid></item><item><title>Maddison Inglis exits Australian Open after loss to Iga Świątek in fourth round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/australian-open-maddison-inglis-iga-swiatek-fourth-round/106271672</link><description>Maddison Inglis did not expect to reach the Australian Open fourth round, while she reveals the unusual items she wants to buy with her prize money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">384af1d3e041157ddd20ea5588e1ef8e</guid></item><item><title>TikTok account celebrating Bondi terrorist attack was active for a month before deletion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/nsw-tiktok-account-celebrates-bondi-attack-banned/106269032</link><description>The social media giant deleted the account and a host of other profiles promoting Islamic State and other violent ideology only after questioning by the ABC last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eba71bbc9f8774260019d91439916c88</guid></item><item><title>Vivienne Westwood and Rei Kawakubo's fashion designs bring punk, play and power to new exhibition at the NGV</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/westwood-kawakubo-ngv-exhibition/106244602</link><description>The revolutionary work of fashion designers Vivienne Westwood and Rei Kawakubo is celebrated with style, surprise and punk flair in this new exhibition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcbeeb22988bd13f5cdc64e0e654757a</guid></item><item><title>Hellyer lead and zinc mine's previous operator has gone into liquidation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/hellyer-gold-mine-tasmania-previous-operator-liquidation/106270634</link><description>Hellyer Metals, which until recently operated Tasmania's Hellyer lead and zinc mine, has gone into liquidation. But the company says the mine is unaffected because it is now operated by a different company.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dbe6355ab6b72b0ec290eca10e0ec87</guid></item><item><title>US criminal investigation in 'legal limbo' as wanted man sighted in Australian coastal towns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/texas-police-urge-izaak-michell-to-hand-himself-in/106259216</link><description>Texan authorities say an extradition order may be required to resolve the "legal limbo" involving Australian man Izaak Michell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7141b5f358e659361dacf9b11070f85c</guid></item><item><title>A peaceful gathering in Perth's CBD turns to chaos in a matter of seconds. So what really happened?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/wa-invasion-day-rally-what-we-know-security-threat-australia-day/106271624</link><description>Premier Roger Cook says the way an orderly protest was targeted "runs against the very heart of what it means to be Australian". So what really happened in Perth's CBD on Australia Day?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">901aa2c094123fd60e15ed02c0ce6972</guid></item><item><title>Getting ready for the first day of school looks very different across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/families-gear-up-to-return-to-school/106244460</link><description>Families across the country, from the coast to the outback, are gearing up to return to school after a long, hot summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">808c3853bc2a5278c06324f08b614e00</guid></item><item><title>Ley backer insists leadership speculation 'all sound and fury signifying nothing' — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/federal-politics-live-blog-ley-coalition-liberals-albanese/106272358</link><description>A backer of Sussan Ley has taken aim at the fevered speculation about a looming Liberal leadership challenge, dismissing it as "sound and fury signifying nothing".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6416763512e57211bddfe7cb91a36449</guid></item><item><title>Australian share market rallies to three-month high — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-tuesday-27-january/106272410</link><description>The ASX 200 closed at levels last seen in late October, trading higher as gold and silver surge in price. See how the day unfolded plus insights from our business reporters on the ABC News markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b08f913f9c2ba9bd1ea20448fae68cdf</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with rape and attempted murder after alleged attack at Yeppen Lagoon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/man-charged-rape-attempted-murder-after-attack-yeppen-lagoon/106272392</link><description>A 27-year-old man remains in custody after the alleged attack of a woman on a run in Rockhampton.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3980b752a74c1294be1c6ad961e13bd7</guid></item><item><title>Woman discovers Holocaust descendants through DNA testing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/australian-woman-dna-test-family-tree-jewish-holocaust/106252638</link><description>Adriana Turk grew up believing there were no survivors on her Jewish father's side after World War II, but a DNA test showed that was not the case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cff4f7c21a5e88d8d950ff7583a128cc</guid></item><item><title>Kumanjayi Dempsey's family speak out after 'devastating' Tennant Creek death in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/nt-family-of-kumanjayi-dempsey-speak-out-after-death-in-custody/106269408</link><description>The family of a woman who recently died inside an NT police watch house is calling for answers, asking why she wasn't checked by medical staff for nearly two days, and demanding immediate action to improve conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04a454b15e870ac3a3d0bb9308926f86</guid></item><item><title>Noosa houseboats forced off river as new maritime rules take effect</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/houseboat-owners-forced-off-noosa-river-as-crackdown-looms/106267124</link><description>A David and Goliath battle is playing out on the multi-million-dollar shores of the Noosa River, where dozens of houseboat residents say they are being forced out and potentially into financial ruin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4a6ba483f912ebdb7967e10a86a07c7</guid></item><item><title>Trump suggests he may rein in Minnesota ICE operation amid public outrage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/trump-may-rein-in-ice-crackdown-minneapolis-st-paul/106272218</link><description>The Trump administration indicates it could rein in its Minnesota immigration crackdown as public outrage intensifies after a federal agent killed a protester.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33eae7ba87f85190139ee795e7474ee0</guid></item><item><title>Emergency feed arrives for remote WA pastoralists amid worst drought in decades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/feed-relief-for-wa-pastoralists-in-drought/106263028</link><description>Volunteer truck drivers and farmers rally to deliver tonnes of hay, providing relief for livestock and pastoralists in a remote part of Western Australia quietly struggling with drought.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7137d9c825998844fc6b05f9fc31d0a3</guid></item><item><title>Sir Donald Bradman's baggy green fetches record price at auction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/bradman-baggy-green-fetches-record-price-at-auction/106272464</link><description>A baggy green cap worn by Don Bradman in the 1947-48 series against India has been sold for $460,000 at auction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">036acd8577f4a131a16ec733a996df82</guid></item><item><title>SA divers have close encounter with great white shark, as local sightings grow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/divers-close-encounter-with-great-white-shark/106269326</link><description>The sighting comes amid a spate of white shark reports in SA's south east, and after a tragic month of incidents in NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">631c9df9fb3793cdaa0c98824220622b</guid></item><item><title>Emergency warnings for Victorian fires, as heatwave sends temperatures soaring — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/heatwave-bushfires-south-east-australia-vic-nsw-sa/106269198</link><description>A record-breaking heatwave is impacting south-east Australia, with temperature records tumbling in parts of Victoria and South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">133d06b30fb92dbd1a54c23abebbc88b</guid></item><item><title>Overland Telegraph Line documentary features First Nations accounts of violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/central-australian-film-director-tells-story-overland-telegraph/106247528</link><description>Aboriginal filmmaker Kieran Satour's documentary tells of murders and massacres by settlers and First Nations people during construction of the Overland Telegraph Line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9daf27fcbcf7e0196b8d816270bddfb0</guid></item><item><title>Race to save 'zombie tree' as scientists fight to stop living species from dying out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/fight-to-save-zombie-tree-from-extinction/106269436</link><description>Scientists and nursery workers race to save a newly identified tree species in Queensland branded "living dead", after a fungal disease stopped it from growing or reproducing in the wild.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dd8109d7ab682b8823f934476e6f20a</guid></item><item><title>Another quarterfinal exit for de Minaur as Alcaraz wins in straight sets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/australian-open-2026-live-alex-de-minaur-alcaraz-sabalenka-gauff/106272422</link><description>Alex de Minaur has been knocked out of the quarterfinals by world number one Carlos Alcaraz in straight sets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6bb1e7749b86a8f55fbda8573f78678</guid></item><item><title>How the Perth Scorchers sit alone as Australia's greatest Big Bash League franchise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/perth-scorchers-dynasty-big-bash-league-greatest-team/106270210</link><description>Six titles in 15 seasons is an extraordinary record, but what is the secret of the Perth Scorchers' incredible success?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cd7f9b19a171993894a9d15386d5c7f</guid></item><item><title>Rescue dog used in central Queensland koala monitoring program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/rescue-dog-used-in-central-queensland-koala-monitoring-program/106187550</link><description>This scruffy pup has gone from the pound to being part of a scat detection dog team, helping save endangered koalas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d2a0c927c72d280718730a5dab46b11</guid></item><item><title>Kanye West takes out Wall Street Journal ad to apologise for antisemitism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/kanye-west-apologises-antisemitism-wall-street-journal-ad/106272660</link><description>Ye, the artist formerly known as Kanye West, has taken out a full-page ad in the Wall Street Journal to apologise for past behaviour, saying he had an undiagnosed brain injury and bipolar disorder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2402d8035defb932e16ea201965c4043</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with making explosives after Perth Invasion Day incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/man-charged-making-explosives-after-perth-invasion-day-rally/106272888</link><description>A 31-year-old man is charged with making explosives in suspicious circumstances after a device was allegedly thrown into a crowd of hundreds of people attending an Invasion Day rally in central Perth yesterday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57b0f6a55e8736586d811e15566e0e8d</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne boy Danny, 12, missing from Venus Bay beach presumed dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/venus-bay-missing-boy-danny-recovery-operation/106272792</link><description>A search for a 12-year-old boy missing at a South Gippsland beach has shifted to a recovery operation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdd541feb7965dd7667716156ecd941e</guid></item><item><title>Maddison and Teagan Levi opt out of NRLW switch to re-sign with Rugby Australia on two-year deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/levi-sisters-turn-down-nrlw-to-stick-with-rugby/106273314</link><description>Maddison and Teagan Levi have turned down a potential switch to the NRLW and re-signed with Rugby Australia in an effort to claim rugby sevens gold at the 2028 Los Angeles Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c039079440aeaa88dc30f2790f75997</guid></item><item><title>The school holidays are over, how's your bedtime routine looking?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/sleep-routine-screen-time-tips-children-back-to-school/106252794</link><description>Has your bedtime routine gone out the window over the school holidays? We've got you covered with these expert tips.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75f505d8d28992479685767114e00639</guid></item><item><title>Brandan Koschel denied bail over alleged hate speech at March for Australia rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/brandan-koschel-charged-with-inciting-hate-denied-bail/106273486</link><description>Brandan Koschel has been charged with publicly inciting hatred on the grounds of race causing fear after he made comments at an open mic session at the rally.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce25543ed4562dfb7b87914bafb74a79</guid></item><item><title>Japan says goodbye to its last pandas as relations with Beijing deteriorate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/china-panda-diplomacy-is-on-show-in-japan/106271088</link><description>The departure of the last pandas from Japan demonstrates a significant crisis in North-East Asian politics that has no resolution on the horizon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b275e0f14adb8e8ee893e7a660dcf622</guid></item><item><title>Former FIFA president Sepp Blatter joins calls to boycott men's World Cup games in US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/sepp-blatter-fifa-wc-boycott-games-in-us-trump/106273718</link><description>Former FIFA president Sepp Blatter is backing a proposed fan boycott of men's World Cup matches in the United States because of the conduct of President Donald Trump and his administration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fe62cf8b4c6778d273c11ba7597a8e9</guid></item><item><title>Should you leave the air con on for your pets?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/should-you-leave-the-air-conditioning-on-for-pets/106228034</link><description>Do you wonder what your pet gets up to at home when you're not there? With temperatures on the rise, we asked three experts about keeping them cool in the heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1e0096303687ced6756508842d5cec4</guid></item><item><title>Sink or Swim | Michael Klim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/sink-or-swim-michael-klim/106271460</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6c4390053ead445b7812d9ff8952667</guid></item><item><title>Sydney men granted bail after alleged attempt to smuggle 65 kilograms of heroin into Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/sydney-men-bail-alleged-heroin-import-brisbane-airport-smuggle/106273974</link><description>Police allege officers found an estimated 65 kilograms of white powder, which returned a positive result for heroin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">707ab4b7c1c708b7a9fc2733982c4165</guid></item><item><title>Mandurah teacher who had student's baby pleads guilty to sexual abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/mandurah-teacher-admits-sex-assuaulting-student/106273420</link><description>A WA teacher pleads guilty to sexually abusing a boy who police say fathered her baby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">204a7d537c2b73329c24ea0621ea5769</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump triggers a gold rush as investors flee the United States</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/donald-trump-triggers-a-gold-rush-as-investors-flee-us/106274200</link><description>While the surging gold price has been a surprise, the driving forces behind it are not. Investors are losing faith in the United States and its role as the standard-bearer for global capitalism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4924baf1c3914214363f96709514f830</guid></item><item><title>Victorian maximum temperature record broken as heatwave engulfs Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/heatwave-record-temperatures-victoria/106273034</link><description>Temperatures soar to record highs across Victoria's north-west, as a heatwave pushes town gauges beyond previous records.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c06d467493a802793afce9a2fb4343c5</guid></item><item><title>Charges withdrawn against seven men accused of illegally trafficking abalone on NSW South Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/abalone-trafficking-charges-dropped-nsw-south-coast/106213172</link><description>Seven Aboriginal men from the NSW South Coast, accused of illegally trafficking thousands of blacklip abalone, walk free after police prosecutors withdraw all charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f73546154ee0fac10a78dd558d430a35</guid></item><item><title>Riverland town rises above 49C in 'new all-time record' for Renmark</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/renmark-sets-new-record-amid-extreme-heat-49-degrees-celsius/106274980</link><description>Temperatures in Renmark soared above 49 degrees Celsius in what the weather bureau says is "a new all-time record" as the SA premier came to the aid of two boys who fainted during a media conference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">729dc3e554ecee9b2f1d3fa239595a7f</guid></item><item><title>Three families on how they manage multi-generational living</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/families-on-how-they-manage-multi-generational-living/105950572</link><description>Cost-of-living and housing affordability issues are bringing generations together under the same roof, but some families are doing it by choice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83e1027dbf0964146c07a68229901c7f</guid></item><item><title>Nowra man Joshua Stephen Davey arrested over alleged nitazines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/nowra-man-joshua-stephen-davey-arrested-over-alleged-nitazines/106274934</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a0c5fe5a4c7807164b87436627a7cb5</guid></item><item><title>Immigration was at the centre of Donald Trump's 2024 win, but it's now mired in controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/trumps-immigration-policy-mired-in-controversy/106273482</link><description>If there was one policy area that was at the centre of US President Donald Trump's election win in 2024, it was immigration. But it has now become mired in controversy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2b5c558594cf03b1bf7536eb59767e5</guid></item><item><title>Bodies of two rock fishermen found off Gerroa 48 hours apart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/second-body-found-search-missing-rock-fishermen-gerroa-nsw/106274892</link><description>A second body has been located during the search for two missing rock fishermen on the South Coast, after police received a missing persons report on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d660065eaa7425da7654cd8999db619</guid></item><item><title>Invasion Day 'explosive' device hidden inside Disney Frozen sock, witness says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/perth-invasion-day-device-in-disney-sock/106275126</link><description>A homemade "fragment bomb" thrown into a crowd at a Perth Invasion Day rally yesterday was hidden in a child's sock with a Disney character on it, a woman who picked it up tells the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cac91b8366ad496ffb7f6b2ff8a1cf9</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide man charged with Victor Harbor attempted murder denied bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/victor-harbor-attempted-murder-charge-court/106260658</link><description>A 20-year-old man remains in an induced coma after being stabbed "no less than 10 times" at a hotel in Victor Harbor, on South Australia's Fleurieu Peninsula. Warning: This story contains content some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ada181d49c43510340dbb000a2dd35ff</guid></item><item><title>Two boys rescued from weir amid wild weather in Townsville</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/two-boys-rescued-from-weir-amid-wild-weather-in-townsville/106274964</link><description>Two boys stranded in white water while fishing at a North Queensland weir are saved in a dramatic rescue by police and swiftwater crews.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">241cbd2c67c5114de503e4bd2efbaf93</guid></item><item><title>Young driver worked more than 18 hours for Yole harness racing stables before 2023 crash, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/ben-yole-workplace-safety-case-harness-racing-injury/106272772</link><description>A driver crashed a vehicle towing a horse float after working for more than 18 hours, a Tasmanian court has heard, in a case in which a prominent harness racing stable is accused of failing to comply with its workplace health and safety duty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60fc13187b83fab657ef3c1b4ecac030</guid></item><item><title>Footage captured by locals in the Torres Strait</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/footage-captured-by-locals-in-the-torres-strait/106271254</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">292241c1b2678eb3389ea3d04bae7c12</guid></item><item><title>CCTV footage from a resort on Roko Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/cctv-footage-from-a-resort-on-roko-island/106271252</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad6a11b87962097e7daf9c8360b10cd9</guid></item><item><title>Foreign fishermen enter Queensland island resort before border force intercept</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/cctv-of-foreign-fishermen-in-far-north-queensland/106271128</link><description>CCTV captures foreign fishermen landing on a Far North Queensland island resort and asking the bar for refreshments, before their boat is intercepted by the border force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7cb062b201268f1b2d7e39b2b4f1b4e</guid></item><item><title>Police release images of ute last seen being driven by Lake Cargelligo shooting suspect Julian Ingram</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/lake-cargelligo-julian-ingram-vehicle-picture-released-by-police/106275966</link><description>NSW Police have released images of a white ute which was last seen being driven by Julian Ingram, who is wanted in connection with the fatal shooting of three people in Lake Cargelligo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">462a1f30ec8e05b774d8ee642f48b1e2</guid></item><item><title>Independent probe on 'missed opportunities' for deadly NZ landslide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/independent-probe-into-nz-landslide-deaths/106275182</link><description>An independent probe will explore whether there was a "missed opportunity" to prevent six deaths caused by a landslide in New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d1a0f5846fa76660e0ae413b6d36e65</guid></item><item><title>Historic heatwave sets all-time records as temperatures exceed 49C</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/south-east-aus-heatwave-sets-record-temperatures-exceed-49c/106274644</link><description>The heatwave gripping south-east Australia reached day four on Tuesday and is now unprecedented in many regions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51c7178be9cd9e4d3836ec679df7b14a</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106274330</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9a40cd1cd5e2d2f12d2881cabb2eee0</guid></item><item><title>New South Wales man stands trial on multiple charges for indecently dealing with two WA girls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/nsw-man-trial-underway-for-alleged-sexual-touching-wa-girls/106275838</link><description>The trial of New South Wales man Gregory Carr, accused of indecently dealing with two girls aged 12 and 13, is underway at a West Australian District Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9fd3d8ba9767b9fc1b521f2df08dca4</guid></item><item><title>Video shows man throwing explosive device into Perth Invasion Day rally crowd</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/video-shows-man-throws-explosive-device-into-perth-rally/106276126</link><description>WA Police have released CCTV that shows a man, dressed in black and wearing a black face mask, running through the crowd after throwing an object from a shopping centre balcony.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb7291be6fddb54a94b42b7990b740f3</guid></item><item><title>Vision released by police of the Perth Invasion Day incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/perth-invasion-day-incident-cctv-police/106276320</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d973e7138a9dc1d67ef4e9fbd957251b</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese rules out blocking appointment of incoming NT administrator David Connolly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/pm-albanese-rules-out-blocking-nt-administrator-david-connolly/106275882</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese says he will not intervene to block the appointment of the NT's incoming administrator, after a series of his past social media posts surfaced in the media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">623d61e19d88fa887c8db1bf0cffa387</guid></item><item><title>Advocate believes system is broken after another death in custody in Kalgoorlie-Boulder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/kalgoorlie-death-in-custody-advocate-says-system-broken/106273634</link><description>WA Police Commissioner Col Blanch tells the ABC he understands the recent death of a man in police custody in Kalgoorlie-Boulder, 600 kilometres east of Perth, was a "self-harm" issue, but investigations are ongoing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70585c7d3dbcc50448ca6e42a72e0d21</guid></item><item><title>Homes feared lost in Otways bushfire amid extreme fire danger in Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/victoria-bushfires-otways-carlisle-river-lismore-heatwave/106275746</link><description>Firefighters have been working through the night to contain a major fire in Victoria's Otway Ranges that was "running hard and fast" after a wind change on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77c2db82ce97073a90e18aa3d535745b</guid></item><item><title>Coco Gauff calls for greater privacy at Australian Open after racquet smash clip goes viral</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/tennis-coco-gauff-racquet-smash-privacy-australian-open/106276462</link><description>Coco Gauff loses her cool in the tunnels of Melbourne Park, only for it to be broadcast around the world on live TV.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d3ecba215cce4a352e333f9e48d4024</guid></item><item><title>What is in the EU-India trade deal and what does it mean for global trade?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/what-is-in-the-eu-india-free-trade-deal/106276554</link><description>The agreement could impact nearly 2 billion people in both economies and comes amid an upheval in global trade stemming from Donald Trump's tariff policies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f243229a2ceb6ae21879426cd4b928a4</guid></item><item><title>BAFTAs nominations: Rose Byrne, Jacob Elordi lead the Aussie charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/bafta-nominees-list-film-awards/106274710</link><description>The Australian hopefuls are nominated in the acting categories, but One Battle After Another leads the field with fourteen nods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c694e99e61c456d7e180ed330e227fc1</guid></item><item><title>Trump administration sued by families over deadly Venezuelan boat strike</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/trump-administration-sued-over-venezuelan-boat-strike/106276738</link><description>Families of two men allege they were murdered in a US missile strike off Venezuela's coast while returning to the Caribbean island nation of Trinidad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">163896f67d0c4eac5db1e7589fa0f8a1</guid></item><item><title>Hottest 100 of 2025 — how well do you know this year's countdown?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/hottest-100-2025-quiz-winners-stats-trivia/106273792</link><description>The Hottest 100 is done for another year. Were you paying attention?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8f551fd18f18610018e9fa289449a0d</guid></item><item><title>Why time feels like it speeds up as we age</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/why-time-feels-like-it-speeds-up-as-we-age/106223834</link><description>The perception that time is flying by can sometimes make us feel stressed and anxious. So how do we slow it down?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a0daa65cbbf696213c3b66e4297bd5e</guid></item><item><title>Liberty Bell Bay looks for new use for manganese by-product, after environmental authority intervention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/liberty-bell-bay-manganese-slag-epa-george-town-council/106273216</link><description>Liberty Bell Bay is considering how to use a manganese by-product, after concerns were raised by Tasmania's Environment Protection Authority.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76c48df059030edb150d5eb5c54b5bb2</guid></item><item><title>National medicines database promised after telehealth 'doctor-shopping' leads to overdose</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/national-medicines-register-in-honour-of-erin/106273618</link><description>The tragic death of a young Melbourne woman who was stockpiling medication has prompted the federal health minister to move to change the way prescriptions are recorded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1493a1b5d5500a6493d4fc3c99d9a8da</guid></item><item><title>Police reject claim March for Australia organiser was bashed by Middle Eastern men</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/vfy-march-for-australia-bashing-claim-alternates/106275558</link><description>March for Australia claims one of its organisers was bashed by a group of Middle Eastern men the day before Australia Day, but police and an eyewitness account have cast doubt on its claim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">179434db7afd2d282582f036d2cb38b0</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government turns defence sights north, completing $355m upgrade to RAAF Base Tindal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/government-completes-upgrade-raaf-base-tindal/106275670</link><description>A Royal Australian Air Force base near Katherine in the NT is updated with purpose-built hangars and improved runways.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03a9ca4f5d5657c2442fa9549ffa67b7</guid></item><item><title>Australia's heatwave smashes temperature records with some places nearing 50C</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/australia-heatwave-smashes-temperature-records/106275472</link><description>The Australian Open is off to a cooler start today after parts of Melbourne buckled under 45-degree heat yesterday, in a heatwave setting historic temperature records across the country's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2b3c7b34ebf30cebc6c854b490efff0</guid></item><item><title>Search for alleged triple murderer Julian Ingram may be like 'finding a needle in a haystack'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/finding-julian-ingram-will-be-difficult-former-officer/106273608</link><description>A former deputy commissioner of police who was involved in the eight-year search for one of Australia's most notorious fugitives says finding alleged Lake Cargelligo triple murderer Julian Ingram will be difficult.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8fb5ed69d9b38c60f8f0d61f136388b</guid></item><item><title>Sydney's landfills are set to reach capacity by 2030 sparking controversial plans to take trash to the regions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/sydney-landfill-capacity-regional-communities-incinerator-plans/106250180</link><description>A proposal to build an incinerator in the regional town of Parkes could see 700,000 tonnes of Sydney's red bin rubbish transported there every year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5548469c3cacacaf0e4a89da25a9d128</guid></item><item><title>ICE deported a man charged over the 'largest jewellery heist in US history' before he could face trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/ice-deported-man-charged-over-us-jewellery-heist/106270648</link><description>An Ecuadorian man accused of aiding the theft of about $147 million worth of gold, gems and luxury watches was deported by the Immigration and Customs Enforcement agency before he could face trial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43daff2e01f9e2c44ea194ba766bd0ea</guid></item><item><title>Andrew and Tristan Tate lose bid to sue Adelaide YouTuber, launch appeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/andrew-and-tristan-tate-lose-bid-to-sue-adelaide-youtuber/106119086</link><description>An Australian YouTuber who is being sued by Andrew and Tristan Tate in a Florida court has won a bid to have the case dismissed, a decision the self-described misogynist influencers are now appealing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4516cd7f63699d938c05baff6f6b69df</guid></item><item><title>Fugitive property developer Jean Nassif subject of ICAC probe over former Parramatta council bribe claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/icac-investigates-jean-nassif-parramatta-council-bribe-claims/106273010</link><description>The New South Wales corruption watchdog is examining allegations fugitive property developer Jean Nassif sought to bribe members of a former Parramatta council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0879234b4094904b3cca8c73b3291c8</guid></item><item><title>Scientists warn microplastics testing could be overestimating extent in human body</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/researchers-call-for-more-rigour-in-microplastic-testing/106275540</link><description>Queensland researchers lead calls for a standardised approach to microplastics testing, amid growing concerns about the impact of the pollutants on the human body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed0812ca82338b0a7f8cee84109e3b4d</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur receives feedback from Carlos Alcaraz after Australian Open loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/australian-open-alex-de-minaur-carlos-alcaraz-quarterfinal/106276482</link><description>Alex de Minaur acknowledges he needs improvement in his game, as Carlos Alcaraz moves on to the Australian Open semifinals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d0772e15c4d94d9c16a531773bc618b</guid></item><item><title>Documents reveal widespread misconduct, complaints, at Busy Bees childcare centres in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/misconduct-at-busy-bees-childcare-revealed-canberra/106256286</link><description>Disturbing allegations of verbal and physical mistreatment of toddlers, poor supervision and repeated staffing failures have emerged in documents about Busy Bees childcare centres in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0b190fb93708f11306c512af0fc79a8</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka's weird ritual, Carlos Alcaraz shows off — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/australian-open-day-10-quick-hits/106273392</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka discussed why she writes on her coach's head before a match and Alexander Zverev shared an important message. Here are the quick hits from day 10 at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dc768f1219c06e41a489c4787432fb3</guid></item><item><title>Tropical low triggers flood evacuations in the north as extreme heat builds in Queensland's south‑west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/qld-major-flooding-in-the-north-extreme-heat-in-south-west/106275644</link><description>A tropical low has dumped hundreds of millimetres of rain across north Queensland, prompting evacuations in a remote part of the state, while the state's south-west braces for a heatwave to peak.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">146f19864f0b7e1892d80b1bda982c15</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Festival 2026: Our favourite shows from Lacrima to Wake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/sydney-festival-2026-program-lacrima-wake-nowhere-hot-chip/106270990</link><description>A debauched Irish wake, a three-hour French play about a royal wedding dress and British electro-pop band Hot Chip were some of the best of the festival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de22002a63df290695b1055c54a35581</guid></item><item><title>'Incredibly abnormal' temperatures 20C above average in parts of Australia — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/heatwave-south-east-australia-weather-victoria-bushfires/106276290</link><description>Towns in New South Wales and Queensland are sweltering today amid a record-breaking heatwave, as firefighters continue to battle multiple blazes in Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">932c094089c1c12c63c06f08aadf15d1</guid></item><item><title>PM commits to new fund ahead of address to Timor-Leste Parliament — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/federal-politics-live-albanese-ley-coaltion-morrison/106275490</link><description>Anthony Albanese has addressed the Timor-Leste Parliament after committing to an infrastructure fund.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f15dd9ea83fe1b1eae7a51621866ba6d</guid></item><item><title>Rado Vidisic, A-League title winning coach and Australian football figure, dies aged 64</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/a-league-title-winning-coach-rado-vidosic-dies-aged-64/106276864</link><description>Rado Vidosic, a highly-regarded Australian football figure and coach across a number of A-League clubs and teams, dies of cancer aged 64.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16da6dfa221a94bba24b8ebe472c71a4</guid></item><item><title>Carlos Alcaraz approaching 'unmatchable' level after mastering powers of concentration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/tennis-carlos-alcaraz-aus-open-quarterfinal-analysis/106276424</link><description>Twelve months ago, Carlos Alcaraz was outwitted by a hobbled Novak Djokovic. This time around, against a rampaging hometown hero, there would be no slipping up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c317e157bd5311c468f2727e6b9f3db</guid></item><item><title>Judge orders ICE head to face court as Trump shakes up Minnesota operation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/minnesota-judge-orders-ice-head-to-face-court/106276814</link><description>A Minnesota judge takes the extraordinary step of ordering the acting director of Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) to appear in person and explain why his agency keeps ignoring court orders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcd40a6959de93cd437f96e7023d6470</guid></item><item><title>Floor collapse at Toll warehouse causes statewide vaccine shortages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/floor-collapses-at-brisbane-toll-warehouse/106272588</link><description>A section of floor has caved-in at Queensland's only vaccine warehouse, causing statewide delays to childhood vaccination schedules.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fa19a94d76f73ef8ead7640a5186fab</guid></item><item><title>ASX falls on inflation data, Aussie dollar off three-year high — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/asx-markets-business-live-news/106276952</link><description>The ASX 200 has fallen slightly after disappointing news about Australia's inflation rate, while the dollar retreated fractionally below 70 cents to the greenback after hitting three-year highs earlier in the day. Look back on the trading day in our business blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73ac72dcaffb7f4d3a86cad17300ceb2</guid></item><item><title>Busselton ratepayers set to foot $60 million bill after performing arts centre cost blowout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/cost-of-busselton-arts-centre-blows-out-and-delays/106273766</link><description>Residents demand answers after the cost of a performing arts centre in the state's South West more than tripled its original allocated budget.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68522bc97950a856821d1a5817ea21c9</guid></item><item><title>Meet the 2026 Trailblazers changing regional Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/heywire-26-trailblazers-changing-regional-australia/106154604</link><description>Jayden is helping youth go from feeling "lost, angry and unheard" to "proud strong and seen". He's one of our 2026 Trailblazers, announced today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07e1f1bd2e589d52d1a28389012efec4</guid></item><item><title>Pilot in fatal Gold Coast plane crash identified as Greg Ackman as air safety experts assess scene</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/qld-gold-coast-plane-crash-pilot-greg-ackman-atsb/106277012</link><description>The aircraft came down shortly after take-off from the Jacobs Well Airstrip on Tuesday killing 73-year-old pilot Greg Ackman and his male passenger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf9fca7109425611692ce1576273435f</guid></item><item><title>University of Southern Queensland astronomer discovers 'potentially habitable' planet candidate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/planet-hd-137010b-discovery-earth-mars-uni-southern-qld/106206380</link><description>An international team of astronomers led from regional Queensland finds an exoplanet 150 light-years away with a 50 per cent chance of having liquid water on its surface.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08c0d0deb5a4413d65c89960aafa3cea</guid></item><item><title>TikTok settles social media addiction lawsuit ahead of trial against Meta, YouTube</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/tiktok-settles-meta-youtube-face-trial-social-media-addiction/106277142</link><description>TikTok agrees to settle a landmark lawsuit on social media addiction, the same day the trial was due to start against Meta and YouTube.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02e95a83373c5f57af7b1483994b7a6a</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds call up Matilda Garrett for Jamaica series as Australia eyes Commonwealth Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/diamonds-name-squad-jamaica-series-commonwealth-games/106277330</link><description>Australia's netball hierarchy settles on a replacement for an injured defender ahead of the Diamonds' three-Test series against Jamaica.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea34a2ad33dfe767762071768385c113</guid></item><item><title>Sinner defeats Shelton to power into another Australian Open semifinal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/australian-open-live-blog-day-11-%C5%9Bwi%C4%85tek-djokovic-sinner/106277086</link><description>Jannik Sinner dominates Ben Shelton after a wounded Novak Djokovic receives a ticket through to the Australian Open semifinals as Lorenzo Musetti withdraws from their quarterfinal injured while leading two sets to love.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65e7cc83f8234703f1fd94f4fc753fc0</guid></item><item><title>Liberal frontbencher says Morrison's proposal to register imams 'a worthwhile discussion'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/andrew-bragg-scott-morrison-proposal-register-imams/106277042</link><description>Liberal frontbencher Andrew Bragg says Australian Muslims need to take some responsibility for extremist incidents and that a proposal for a register of Islamic preachers is worth considering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea70856261162296ab47edaddfc35f25</guid></item><item><title>Tongans frustrated with Trump's 'collective punishment' of foreign nationals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/tonga-us-travel-restrictions-trump/106249526</link><description>The United States bars Tongans from short-term visits or travel for tourism and business purposes, saying too many are overstaying their visas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a03acab0309315a7358d58af38c4346</guid></item><item><title>Jay Vine won Tour Down Under with broken wrist after final-stage crash with kangaroo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/vine-won-tour-down-under-with-broken-wrist-after-kangaroo-crash/106277862</link><description>Tour Down Under champion Jay Vine won the event with a fractured wrist suffered in a crash with kangaroos, his team reveals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7547626faf6d8a57e6cba1b25246669d</guid></item><item><title>Inflation hotter than forecast at end of 2025, adding to rate hike expectations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/inflation-ahead-of-rba-rate-decision-december-quarter-cpi/106277748</link><description>Inflation rose at the end of 2025, picking up more than forecast. The Consumer Price Index rose 3.8 per cent annually in December, up from 3.4 per cent in the year to November, adding to rate hike expectations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4139fab676bb28062338f9c22095882</guid></item><item><title>Mount Lawley diamond jewellery shop targeted in suspected ram raid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/matusik-jewellers-mt-lawley-ram-raid/106277288</link><description>Thieves target a Mount Lawley jewellery store in an early morning ram raid, leaving empty cabinets and a trail of destruction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53cb0442dd1a11c690b5640c2aabb227</guid></item><item><title>Daylesford crash driver will be compelled to give evidence at inquest, coroner rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/daylesford-driver-deaths-inquest-evidence/106277860</link><description>A Victorian coroner has ruled that a driver with diabetes who ploughed into a crowd outside a regional pub, killing five people, will be compelled to give evidence at an inquest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86a31d07bebf7a53dcabc2985a02e706</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with hate speech Brandan Koschel had posted photos alongside Neo-Nazis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/brandan-koschel-social-media-neo-nazi-group-nsn-photos/106275476</link><description>Brandan Koschel had posted blurred images of himself standing next to prominent Neo-Nazis on a social media account earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dcfbfe7db40d2e04c5b2225f65ea1df</guid></item><item><title>City of Perth Lord Mayor Bruce Reynolds rejects no confidence motion in his leadership at meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/perth-lord-mayor-bruce-reynolds-quashes-no-confidence-motion/106273762</link><description>Perth Lord Mayor Bruce Reynolds rejects a ratepayer's motion of no confidence in his leadership, and flags Corruption and Crime Commission involvement over how a secret workplace culture report was leaked to media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e828b87333fb5b481944f24209bde10</guid></item><item><title>Why haven't police labelled Perth's Invasion Day rally incident terrorism? Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/why-perth-invasion-day-rally-explosive-not-labelled-terrorism/106276450</link><description>Identifying ideological motivations behind attacks is critical to separating terrorism from other events just designed to cause fear, an extremism expert told the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1f022d205f7d1bbc82d23db48e936f8</guid></item><item><title>Tony Abbott intervenes in Liberal leadership battle calling on right to unite to oust Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/tony-abbott-calls-on-conservatives-to-unite-and-oust-sussan-ley-/106278112</link><description>Former prime minister Tony Abbott has intervened in the Liberal leadership race, urging conservatives to unite behind either Angus Taylor or Andrew Hastie in their bid to oust Sussan Ley from the top job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa601877d4070c743e6ce0b2fdba4094</guid></item><item><title>Coco Gauff backed by Iga Świątek after smashing racquet at Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/australian-open-coco-gauff-smashed-racquet/106278048</link><description>Iga Świątek defends Coco Gauff after footage was shown of the American smashing a racquet at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af66dc4c3e3fd53a512c464210db0cba</guid></item><item><title>Microplastics triple in Sydney's waterways in three years, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/microplastics-triple-in-sydney-waterways-report/106276988</link><description>Microplastic pollution on Sydney's beaches and harbour shorelines has tripled in the past three years, according to a report, much of it from sources of "preventable losses".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a427d023e69d8edbbc0a452d15231048</guid></item><item><title>Accidental 'crying horse' toy becomes Spring Festival bestseller in China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/accidental-crying-horse-toy-wins-hearts-china/106278170</link><description>A dour-faced toy horse — the result of a manufacturing error — has gone viral in China, with some workers saying its expression mirrors their long hours and workplace stress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beab4af9112875b363f4e340d6d82f4d</guid></item><item><title>Woman accused of paying secret kickbacks to surgeons to use medical devices at Brisbane hospital faces court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/medical-devices-kickbacks-scheme-queensland-court/106277080</link><description>The finance manager is one of four people who were charged last month, following an investigation involving the Crime and Corruption Commission and the Queensland Office of the Health Ombudsman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9a89f57c6e346ab77f6bc40c35a057b</guid></item><item><title>Hoodoo Gurus' Dave Faulkner lashes One Nation use of song at March for Australia Rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/hoodoo-gurus-dave-faulkner-lashes-one-nation/106278392</link><description>Faulkner says One Nation and its supporters can "take a running jump" after his band's song was used at an Australia Day rally held by the party, and he's not bothered by party supporters trolling him on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40a56fc63cba76fbf4666d4f44c005b7</guid></item><item><title>Cattle farmer rescues koala from bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/cattle-farmer-rescues-koala-from-bushfire/106278554</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cadefd18a63263de582a53521d3ff8ce</guid></item><item><title>Accessory to murder charges dropped in cold case of NSW mother Pauline Sowry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/charges-dropped-against-man-accused-pauline-sowry-cold-case/106277876</link><description>Leon Boeyen, who has been in prison since May on two charges relating to the 1993 disappearance of the NSW woman, wept as he learned he would be released.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cad606f9d9e7ef4baae49908dcee12bf</guid></item><item><title>Why some places can feel much hotter than the official temperature</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/how-do-we-measure-heat-official-temperature/106277628</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology's temperatures differ from those that may be shown in your car or on your phone. Here's how the "official" temperature is measured.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cc54c0bddb35e2590d04016c20ad74c</guid></item><item><title>Tourist mauled by snow leopard while trying to take photo, Chinese media reports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/snow-leopard-mauls-tourist-trying-to-take-photo/106277636</link><description>A female skier has been mauled by a snow leopard on her way back to her hotel in China after she attempted to get a selfie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d14593825e2af78a830b06aa31778ef0</guid></item><item><title>'Doomsday Clock' set to 85 seconds to midnight, closer than ever to catastrophe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/doomsday-clock-85-seconds-to-midnight-nuclear-threats/106261766</link><description>Atomic scientists set the Doomsday Clock to 85 seconds midnight, with threats such as nuclear weapons and conflicts pushing humanity closer than ever to the point of annihilation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b81ce68e6e053ed4255e01382385ac1d</guid></item><item><title>Leigh Geoffrey Sushames pleads guilty to murder of Tasmania Police Constable Keith Smith</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/leigh-geoffrey-sushames-pleads-guilty-keith-smith-murder/106277880</link><description>The man accused of fatally shooting Tasmania Police Constable Keith Smith pleads guilty to murder in a Devonport court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae32f8dbe71455075e0b5c4ae4c48b5e</guid></item><item><title>Mass wildlife rescue underway with flying foxes entangled at golf club driving range</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/wildlife-rescue-underway-following-noosa-bat-entanglement/106278136</link><description>A mass wildlife rescue is again underway at the Noosa Golf Club after dozens of flying foxes became trapped in netting at its driving range for the fourth time this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f671db969da43aaba079cd618b3c9cf</guid></item><item><title>Why UFC 325 is a collision between Alex Volkanovski's glorious past and uncertain future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/alex-volkanovski-ufc-325-diego-lopes-tai-tuivasa/106277692</link><description>An end of an era looms for Alex Volkanovski as he prepares for his first title defence on home soil, but ahead of UFC 325, Australia's greatest ever MMA fighter is still the nation's gold standard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20b26fceeb1144bfc4c05000db7fc987</guid></item><item><title>Littleproud open to Ley meeting after Nationals spill resolved</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/littleproud-open-to-ley-meeting-after-nationals-spill-resolved/105435280</link><description>Nationals Leader David Littleproud will stare down a leadership tilt from Queensland MP Colin Boyce, though colleagues say it is unlikely the challenger will secure enough votes for a spill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f63ed83de0bcd066a1bacea06b3fa66</guid></item><item><title>At least 16 structures lost in Otways fire with heatwave still impacting Victoria's north-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/victoria-bushfire-structures-destroyed-heatwave/106278038</link><description>At least 16 structures have been destroyed by the Carlisle River fire in Victoria's Otways, with a strong wind change late yesterday afternoon impacting another 1,000 hectares.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20824b3cbd1b2511be193ae182828262</guid></item><item><title>Remains found during search in Tasmanian bush for missing tourist Celine Cremer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/remains-found-during-search-for-missing-tourist-celine-cremer/106279500</link><description>The bushwalker who found human remains while searching for missing Belgian tourist Celine Cremer says he "went into shock" after coming across bones in dense Tasmanian forest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ff9b206f9bbac58e147276b4a1e3f56</guid></item><item><title>Off-contract Usman Khawaja keen to extend Big Bash career with Brisbane Heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/usman-khawaja-brisbane-heat-big-bash-league/106279266</link><description>In the aftermath of his international retirement, Usman Khawaja is keen to extend his Big Bash career, with his preference to strike a new deal with the Brisbane Heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07cbbb1d29b1103cf930a9e72459cfa3</guid></item><item><title>Wine Australia's export report for 2025 shows consumers sobering up as cost of living bites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/wine-australia-export-report-for-2025-global-market-decline-sa/106277572</link><description>Global demand for Australian wine is continuing to dwindle, with the latest Wine Australia export report showing an 8 per cent decrease in 2025 as consumers opt for alcohol-free trends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea608f774b9ac7ff068b1669d2fdaeb6</guid></item><item><title>Emirates Wolgan Valley luxury hotel reopens despite lack of road access</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/emirates-wolgan-valley-hotel-reopening-/106277870</link><description>Guests at one of Australia's most luxurious resorts will travel on a four-wheel drive trail down the side of the Blue Mountains, with the owners committed to reopening three years after a landslide closed the only access road.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">488f726c170436a4bdafbdb684e330a8</guid></item><item><title>Teenager accused of electric motorbike death in Perth's north pleads not guilty to manslaughter charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/boy-accused-of-e-bike-death-denies-manslaughter-charge/106278852</link><description>A teenage boy accused of killing a 59-year-old woman while riding an unlicensed high-powered electric motorbike in Perth's north has pleaded not guilty to manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27244f675dcca5226051f20e404ba7f4</guid></item><item><title>'One-off' literary festival, Constellations, to go ahead in lieu of Writers' Week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/alternate-literary-festival-constellations-in-adelaide/106279364</link><description>A community literary festival will go ahead in the wake of the cancellation of Adelaide Writers' Week, but those involved say it is not a replacement for the original event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef44bb2df86cdb6c803ede79ea9f26e4</guid></item><item><title>Counterfeit Botox still being imported into Australia, months after regulator first raised alarm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/counterfeit-botox-items-detected-by-tga-in-australia/106278732</link><description>Counterfeit Botox vials were packaged in branded boxes that appear like a genuine product, according to a renewed warning from the Therapeutic Goods Administration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">776747f9c945055009f9d210c84c6b7e</guid></item><item><title>Emergency warnings issued for two bushfires in Perth's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/gnangara-landsdale-bullsbrook-emergency-bushfire-/106279716</link><description>There are unconfirmed reports of animals being impacted by the fire, and a shed being destroyed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d188ff0ffeb80df51c38775a123ebe40</guid></item><item><title>Security tackles heckler who approached Democratic congresswoman Ilhan Omar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/heckler-who-approached-democratic-congresswoman-ilhan-omar/106278862</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a39eab87ba319306028488bd288e863</guid></item><item><title>Man tackled at town hall after spraying unknown substance on Democratic congresswoman Ilhan Omar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/democratic-congresswoman-sprayed-with-unknown-substance/106278878</link><description>Minneapolis police say officers saw a man use a syringe to spray an unknown liquid at Ilhan Omar, the Democratic representative for Minnesota.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73fb7f954c82b531717bb4f49bd893aa</guid></item><item><title>Iranian doctor who fled to Australia after operating on massacre victims estimates death toll in tens of thousands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/doctor-operated-on-wounded-during-iran-massacre-protests/106277548</link><description>In one of the most harrowing accounts yet, a doctor who fled Iran for Australia recounts trying to save bullet-riddled victims of the government crackdown on protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16fae7ededa33199f7a195a02a8ea18e</guid></item><item><title>Rain has transformed the outback from parched to puddles.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/from-thirsty-camels-mud/106279410</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38a8b5daea7a9f23748c75a79557e4d4</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Tropical Cyclone Luana brings rain relief for remote WA inland cattle stations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/rain-relief-for-inland-pastoralists/106275402</link><description>Weather associated with a former cyclone has drenched parts of Western Australia's inland region, bringing relief for pastoralists who had received very little rain for the previous 12 months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">053e0134cc118a1a332a27b78aabbca0</guid></item><item><title>Jim Chalmers has rejected responsibility for high inflation but will have a tough sell if rates rise again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/chalmers-says-inflation-is-not-his-fault/106279808</link><description>Less than a year after the Reserve Bank started cutting rates, the prospect of a rate rise is a political nightmare for a treasurer hoping for clear air.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c548b41b8cc890d99129d352e74eaa6f</guid></item><item><title>Chinese ambassador hints at retaliation if Port of Darwin is returned to Australian control</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/chinese-ambassador-hints-at-retaliation-over-port-of-darwin/106279996</link><description>China's ambassador to Australia, Xiao Qian, questions the Albanese government's ethics in wanting to return the Port of Darwin to Australian hands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7e20f0806b7a98f43b02ecd05bc0e9f</guid></item><item><title>Former South Korean first lady Kim Keon Hee sentenced to 20 months in jail for corruption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/former-south-korean-first-lady-20-months-jail-for-corruption/106279794</link><description>Kim Keon Hee, the wife of jailed former South Korean president Yoon Suk Yeol, is sentenced to prison by a Seoul court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1bb53f35bcdb862033f3203348290f4</guid></item><item><title>Former member of National Socialist Network fights for return of weapons licence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/former-national-socialist-network-member-weapons-licence-appeal/106279468</link><description>A man, who was stripped of more than a dozen guns after police found multiple copies of Adolf Hitler's manifesto at his home, is fighting to have his weapons licence reinstated by a court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb80f484ffa0fbb8d33a0e771ae0749c</guid></item><item><title>Police say bones found at a Phillip Island house not linked to active missing persons case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/silverleaves-bones-found-police-speculation/106252278</link><description>Police say human remains found on Phillip Island are not linked to a missing persons investigation, amid community speculation about whether the bones might be linked to an historic cold case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89ec8aa7ed9af60ad5d5e72dfcd7d98a</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106280098</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcbcc22000a85ac613cdbde4d932e0fc</guid></item><item><title>Doctors failed to tell authorities of driver's vision impairment before fatal Adelaide crash, inquest hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/sa-inquest-into-doctors-conduct-before-crash-that-killed-woman/106278662</link><description>A coronial inquest will investigate why three doctors failed to alert relevant authorities that a man was unfit to drive due to vision impairment in the years before he caused a crash which killed a mother of four.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da7be28c4f70d432f4edbdb020b928da</guid></item><item><title>Great Southern residents praise WA firefighters who saved 30 homes from serious blaze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/wandering-residents-praise-wa-firefighters-30-homes-saved/106275646</link><description>Firefighters in the Great Southern region of WA are being praised for saving 30 homes after lightning caused a fire that burnt out of control for four days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">848c376330b2a6d01389f7b95c66bb63</guid></item><item><title>Western Queensland towns swelter through intense heatwave but fall short of state records</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/thargomindah-swelters-through-heatwave-western-queensland/106277226</link><description>One outback Queensland town has reached a temperature of 48.5 degrees Celsius, falling just shy of a state record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5839f46220d743398c736c3f880faa38</guid></item><item><title>ACT heatwave breaks records in Canberra's south as Tuggeranong hits 43.5C</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/act-canberra-heatwave-tuggeranong-breaks-records/106279884</link><description>Canberra's south has hit record-breaking heat with Tuggeranong reaching 43.5°C as the ACT swelters through its hottest day in years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd904c6cc4822876b2a6f10ebc38e034</guid></item><item><title>Chinese ambassador announces joint taskforce in hunt for man who threw hot coffee over Brisbane baby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/chinese-ambassador-taskforce-hunt-for-man-after-attack-on-baby/106280208</link><description>China's ambassador to Australia says authorities will travel to Brisbane as the search for the man who threw hot coffee on a baby continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91f987c854543d48fd9ae9dd3d4ab584</guid></item><item><title>The search for Celine Cremer, Belgian tourist who disappeared in the Tasmanian bush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/belgian-bushwalker-celine-cremer-search-explainer/106279718</link><description>The two-and-a-half year search for a missing Belgian tourist has led to the discovery of bones, which may mean closure is not far away.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c448696f43c190849b55df59ba622a14</guid></item><item><title>Gem hunter receives suspended prison sentence for illegally mining turquoise at NT sacred site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/gem-hunter-illegal-mined-turquoise-ore-nt-sacred-site-sentencing/106278496</link><description>A gemstone dealer has received a four-month suspended prison sentence for illegally mining more than 8 tonnes of turquoise ore at a Northern Territory sacred site.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f3a9d472c461f3385d63d0404569b85</guid></item><item><title>First Nations urge stronger response after alleged Invasion Day rally attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/first-nations-reactions-to-perth-rally/106278632</link><description>First Nations leaders have urged governments to take stronger action in response to the alleged attack at an Invasion Day rally in Perth on Monday. Social Justice Commissioner Katie Kiss says failing to do so "sends a message that Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander people do not matter".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d788783b2f2b1d9210b64763272a33fb</guid></item><item><title>Victorian man arrested after paramedics allegedly threatened at Adelaide hospital, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/man-arrested-after-paramedics-allegedly-threatened-at-rah/106280464</link><description>A Victorian man has been arrested after he allegedly threatened paramedics and another man with stab wounds while armed with a knife outside an Adelaide hospital, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e50ac90e4c2cac578371e6c726acf2c9</guid></item><item><title>Telstra warns older iPhones may be unable to connect to Triple Zero</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/telstra-warns-older-iphones-may-be-unable-to-connect-to-network/106280356</link><description>Customers are advised to delay software updates on affected devices and find alternative ways to communicate if needed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">589943817c6ec4510938208dbabcea27</guid></item><item><title>Authorities investigate bomb allegedly thrown into Perth Invasion Day rally crowd as 'potential terrorist act'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/authorities-investigate-alleged-perth-bomb-as-terrorist-act/106280668</link><description>A joint statement by WA Police, the Australian Federal Police and domestic security agency ASIO say the agencies' investigations are ongoing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f67cb75199536da0fae24b70fd1f55b5</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic gets lucky break in Australian Open win over Lorenzo Musetti</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/australian-open-novak-djokovic-lorenzo-musetti-quarterfinal/106279982</link><description>As he trailed Lorenzo Musetti, 10-time champion Novak Djokovic knew he was on the ropes as he looked to keep his Australian Open campaign alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6989483c04e6e616d14a6022e57d9acd</guid></item><item><title>DC mid-air collision that killed 67 was '100 per cent preventable': NTSB</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/ntsb-says-dc-mid-air-collision-that-killed-67-was-preventable/106280300</link><description>Investigators and families are calling for major reforms, with more than 30 safety recommendations issued to prevent a similar tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">006b4c4c70d3d7334ef583e17193d58a</guid></item><item><title>Concerns domestic tenants required to share excessive personal data to secure leases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/concerns-tenants-sharing-excessive-data-to-secure-lease-ahuri/106269564</link><description>Tenants are being forced to hand over excessive personal data when applying for rental properties, with new research warning that applicants' personal information could be at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">203f59b7aa7b6ce7128c5459c2aee8d1</guid></item><item><title>Trump threatens Iran with 'major destruction' as US fleet arrives in Gulf</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/us-donald-trump-threatens-iran-with-major-destruction/106280948</link><description>The US president says Tehran should make a deal or face military strikes as tensions between the two countries escalates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10e6c332f60229c131b7f3edac7e63e8</guid></item><item><title>Australia hits power demand record as renewables pass 50pc milestone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/australia-hits-power-demand-record-as-renewables-pass-50pc/106280246</link><description>Amid fits and starts, Australia's energy transition turned a big corner in 2025, as renewables shot past fossil fuels despite demand records.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4156002309bd45cc31dbeeff455a7379</guid></item><item><title>'Bring them home' answered at last as Israel buries final hostage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/final-israeli-hostage-laid-to-rest-after-843-days-in-gaza/106280912</link><description>Many people who turned out to Ran Gvili's funeral hope this will allow the country to start to move forward and heal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94eee45d930fe78188eb5a0e0451899e</guid></item><item><title>Amazon accidentally announces further 16,000 layoffs in AI pivot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/amazon-accidentally-announces-layoffs/106280800</link><description>A misfired internal email was the first time many employees found out about a second round of job cuts in just six months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86b1eaba850241fba6bf277d009edc28</guid></item><item><title>Otways bushfire in Victoria eases as heatwave conditions continue in state's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/victoria-bushfires-otways-carlisle-river-walwa-dargo-heatwave/106280362</link><description>Firefighting conditions have improved around the fire that burnt through properties near the town of Gellibrand in Victoria's south-west, but crews warn the blaze is still not under control.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">554afdc299cbe69c2dca6a8d6afd824f</guid></item><item><title>Jetstar twice violated own policy on fees for changing name of support worker for man with a disability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/jetstar-name-change-policy-for-disability-support-worker/106223360</link><description>The 22-year-old northern Tasmanian man with a disability was incorrectly told he'd have to pay a fee to change the name of his support worker on a ticket. After an apology and a refund, it happened again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd0d995aedd9d87911e0574090d06e46</guid></item><item><title>Police to detail potential discovery of Celine Cremer's remains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/police-press-conference-potential-celine-cremer-remains/106279906</link><description>A press conference is scheduled to be held in Tasmania today, following the shock discovery of human bones in the remote area where a Belgian backpacker went missing more than two years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d52ac84e4445b8c251bb6ed7f5c5f84</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Greens MP Tim Read to retire from state politics to focus on cancer battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/brunswick-greens-mp-tim-read-reveals-cancer-diagnosis/106278032</link><description>Victorian Greens MP Tim Read reveals he will retire from politics at this year's election after he was diagnosed with metastatic cancer — but not before one last political fight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bd4bd27af283ebfca28c70c7e951c88</guid></item><item><title>Back to school quiz: How well did you survive summer with the kids at home?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/back-to-school-quiz/106274270</link><description>We made it. The kids are returning to school. See how much you learned during the most recent, interminable school holiday period with our quiz.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7351cd7d2fae89a90f3c52dc0e2cb9fd</guid></item><item><title>The US wanted to ban TikTok over national security concerns. Does a deal with China fix that?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/what-does-china-tiktok-deal-mean-for-us-national-security/106270748</link><description>US politicians — both Republican and Democrat — had worried TikTok's Chinese ownership could mean American user data was vulnerable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">829a0db74e3349f33087c609ec8bdd2d</guid></item><item><title>Travel agents work through the night to help UK dual citizens navigate new passport rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/travel-agents-overwhelmed-by-new-uk-passport-rules/106265500</link><description>New passport rules for UK Australian dual citizens have customers in "tears", say travel agents who are working through the night to help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffd73aeb545603209ad6d2b07d56b26b</guid></item></channel></rss>