<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 13:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Back Roads meets the women taking on the open road for the adventure of solo van life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-04/women-taking-on-solo-van-life/105625140</link><description>There is a growing cohort of women taking up van life, breaking stereotypes by travelling solo and finding community along the way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b11478cec27af3a792db2abd9fa20394</guid></item><item><title>Dee Annear's family say they'll never forgive Rohen Hanson for her murder in Bulga Forest hut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/dee-annear-family-speak-at-rohen-james-hanson-sentence-hearing/105737012</link><description>The family of Dee Annear, a woman murdered by her partner in a remote forest cabin on the NSW Mid North Coast, say the lies of her killer will never be forgotten.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d1c894f26709b3187dcc3c623ec7a16</guid></item><item><title>Equity call on rare cancers costs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-01/equity-call-on-rare-cancers-costs/105720408</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19168c56e670facf6f9b8f3f411de956</guid></item><item><title>Astronomer Grote Reber's ashes are held in radio telescope locations around the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/pioneering-radio-astronomer-grote-reber-built-first-big-dish/105725764</link><description>Grote Reber helped spark decades of interest in radio astronomy in Tasmania when he decided to call the southern state home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9417f11c5baa5079e22009aea0722381</guid></item><item><title>What is the 'last touch' rule? AFL coaches not convinced they need it despite use in SANFL and AFLW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/afl-last-touch-rule-does-not-sit-well-with-coaches/105751286</link><description>It's a rule used in the SANFL and the AFLW, but coaches have suggested they will need more convincing of the merits of the AFL bringing in a "last touch" rule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7b84c64b362c62e21c694ae2ac7f3d1</guid></item><item><title>Netball Australia says it will do better after performer who pleaded guilty to domestic violence sings at grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-08/netball-australia-grand-final-siala-robson-performance/105627452</link><description>Netball's players association says its members are facing "genuine hurt" after an oversight from Netball Australia saw a performer who pleaded guilty to domestic violence singing at last weekend's grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a178d455c051e964e8f9105a0176edd9</guid></item><item><title>Banks to refund $60m of 'excessive' fees but CommBank withholds $270m</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-07-29/asic-bank-fee-refunds-millions-low-income-customers-australia/105562370</link><description>Hundreds of thousands of Australians slugged more than $60 million in excessive bank fees could soon get a refund, but Commonwealth Bank customers may not see a cent of $270 million in unfair charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">723aa943f9dc5b0fa484c71fe9c89f60</guid></item><item><title>Polish businessman steals kid's cap at US Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-02/polish-businessman-steals-kids-cap-at-us-open/105723688</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">502823e5ae3d506c5dbfedb22b8fcfc7</guid></item><item><title>South Korean workers return home after ICE raids at US Hyundai factory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/south-korean-workers-return-home-after-ice-raids-in-us/105769030</link><description>The workers arrived home to emotional scenes as many consider never returning to the US following the raids which have caused serious tension between the longstanding allies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3defe526b22894efc768a6dadf8e6556</guid></item><item><title>Tour de France Femmes 2025 hopes to recapture spell-binding 2024 edition, and continue to grow women's cycling from 'ugly' past</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-07-26/tour-de-france-femmes-2025/105560928</link><description>The Tour de France Femmes produced one of the closest finishes in cycling stage race history last year. But when the women's Tour was first revived, it was called "ugly".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">364d2bd1682848d427c455d2ee3211b7</guid></item><item><title>Western Arrernte's Charlie Maher makes history completing world marathon majors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-01/western-arrernte-man-makes-marathon-history/105720220</link><description>Charlie Maher has become the first Indigenous man to complete all seven major marathons in the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39a8da89cfb5ea21582ea336b7f8ef52</guid></item><item><title>Reading retreats the salve for modern women's burnout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-31/reading-retreats-help-women-deal-with-stress-and-burnout/105666670</link><description>As symptoms of burnout rise, an increasing number of women are turning to reading retreats as a salve for stress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2be64a35aa35dc4a7d7f5bb610d99e84</guid></item><item><title>Nepalese in Australia mourn youth killed in anti-government protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/australia-nepalese-community-vigil-anti-government-protest/105756944</link><description>The frustrations with Nepal's government spill beyond the country's borders, with the diaspora in Australia taking to the streets to express solidarity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c48729067cf15aa134374a49e4426741</guid></item><item><title>ABC Sport's Andrew Moore recounts 'miracle survival' after cardiac arrest that led to four operations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-07/andrew-moore-miracle-survival-from-heart-attack/105744078</link><description>ABC Sport commentator Andrew Moore says he does not know when he will be back on the radio, but is "oddly excited" about the recovery process after his heart attack last month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2787fba9d5b83ad2ac225ba0d5d7d77c</guid></item><item><title>France could hold snap elections again amid deadlock and calls for Emmanuel Macron's resignation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/france-could-hold-snap-elections-again-amid-deadlock/105764462</link><description>France is stuck in a cycle of political chaos, with no clear end in sight. It has sparked calls for President Emmanuel Macron's resignation and has become so dire that another round of snap legislative elections is considered possible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa0b21d4717bbe32a1065fa72b61ca30</guid></item><item><title>Report finds Sydney Water was too quick to claim no PFAS hotspots in drinking water catchments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/damning-report-into-handling-of-pfas-contamination-sydney-water/105763308</link><description>A report has found Sydney Water did not perform an "appropriate level of due diligence" before it claimed in June 2024 there were no known PFAS hotspots within its drinking water catchments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40812e800fdb9047cdc9ec261fe1db64</guid></item><item><title>After Charlie Kirk's assassination, a bitter blame game pushes the US towards the precipice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/charlie-kirk-assassination-test-for-donald-trump/105765246</link><description>In a country with more guns than people, an increasingly violent and threatening public discourse is creating serious dangers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0129cd60adc41a6dc5937ee3c86625d</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou returns to Premier League management with Nottingham Forest after Nuno Espírito Santo sacking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/ange-postecoglou-named-nottingham-forest-manager-epl/105752408</link><description>Australian's Ange Postecolgou has been named as new head coach of Premier League side Nottingham Forest after the sacking of Nuno Espírito Santo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46355041a5ea317ee2e9b572db53fbf3</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach pro-Palestinian and pro-Israel protesters clash condemned as police investigate 'scuffle'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/bondi-beach-pro-palestine-pro-israel-protest-scuffle/105747036</link><description>Chris Minns has condemned the scenes of protesters clashing at Bondi Beach on Sunday as police look into if anyone involved should face charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7a90788b9749f1693855eee294c361a</guid></item><item><title>'March for Australia' participants crowd Sydney’s CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-31/march-for-australia-participants-crowd-sydney%E2%80%99s-cbd/105717842</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa56bc0be0101810da0214c95f9c4915</guid></item><item><title>What I learnt from three months of slashing my screen time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/what-i-learnt-from-three-months-of-slashing-my-screen-time/105670916</link><description>For sometimes up to 12 hours a day, I was falling prey to rage bait and the comparison trap. I wondered what it would be like to live without that noise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f7dd1aac710d6ae6a62a8b76e0b0304</guid></item><item><title>Tarryn Aiken injures knee as Sydney Roosters win NRLW minor premiership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/tarryn-aiken-injures-knee-roosters-win-nrlw-minor-premiership/105765274</link><description>The undefeated Sydney Roosters lock up the minor premiership with another big win despite a slew of injuries, including an apparently serious knee issue for halfback Tarryn Aiken.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3d0ec8cc837f9f4c700dece4e69d2af</guid></item><item><title>Measles vaccination rates reach 14-year low</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2022-11-24/measles-vaccination-rates-reach-14-year-low/101694880</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">def54d69384e1311fb15c35c1377ec1b</guid></item><item><title>Canterbury Bulldogs recall Toby Sexton, axe Reed Mahoney for NRL finals against Melbourne Storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/canterbury-bulldogs-axe-reed-mahoney-for-toby-sexton/105762352</link><description>Canterbury coach Cameron Ciraldo has confirmed the bold selection call to axe Reed Mahoney from the qualifying final squad to face Melbourne and recall Toby Sexton.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8299dd0d00e67f343a66f7cde293f42</guid></item><item><title>BIGSOUND illustrates Australian music's depth amid challenging times</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-06/bigsound-2025-highlights-music-charts-mariae-cassandra-drizzz/104290550</link><description>A couple of hundred eager emerging artists just proved that neither quality nor quantity are at the heart of Australia's music industry woes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0e883d53684a9430df3ced0cab24102</guid></item><item><title>Australia names 15-strong squad for ICC Women's Cricket World Cup, led by captain Alyssa Healy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/australia-names-squad-for-icc-women-s-cricket-world-cup/105698780</link><description>Australia names a 15-strong squad for the upcoming ICC Women's Cricket World Cup in India and Sri Lanka, as the team prepares to defend the title it won in New Zealand three years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd1c568c90937b651a88f3f5cb6c3c86</guid></item><item><title>NT police union raises alarm over death in custody risk in watch houses</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-07-15/nt-police-union-warns-of-death-custody-in-watch-house-conditions/105534016</link><description>The Northern Territory's police union is warning a death or serious incident in custody is only a matter of time under dangerous conditions in police watch houses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06d4f64574cb7e7c0f8d04aaa74b99d2</guid></item><item><title>Men's shed volunteers craft simple gifts to make young hearts skip with joy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/wagga-mens-shed-skipping-ropes-for-children-in-need-overseas/105739052</link><description>Retired farmer John's foray into woodworking has led to mateship, connections with kids in need around the world — and quite a few skipping rope handles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd8bc83565302e9b62ded0ed0f29564b</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of protesters face off in opposing rallies against racism and mass migration — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/rallies-blog-live-australia-marches/105769856</link><description>Thousands of protesters from across the political spectrum converged on Australia's capital cities, marching and facing off with police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab385b5fcee479d43d6aedc5d7466594</guid></item><item><title>Tobruk Fig Tree cutting planted in Port Lincoln to honour Eyre Peninsula's Rats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/rats-of-tobruk-honoured-fig-tree-port-lincoln/105761000</link><description>Many of the Rats of Tobruk hailed from the Eyre Peninsula and, after years of work, their legacy has been commemorated by a very special tree taking root.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80e75f73cf2637b214b67aec22e1a5c3</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's Papua New Guinean community celebrates 50 years of independence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/queensland-marks-50-years-of-papua-new-guinea-independence/105770082</link><description>Thousands of people from Queensland's Papua New Guinean community celebrate half a century of the country's independence with traditional music, dancing, art, and food.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21b437b4635536bc1b7540b1760056b1</guid></item><item><title>Bush band tells Aboriginal people's side of the Maralinga nuclear weapon tests story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/bush-band-song-tells-story-of-maralinga-atomic-bomb-tests/105765452</link><description>For Liam Tunkin, making music is about continuing his late father's legacy and sharing a dark part of Australia's history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b898813878aa4745672fc29e28ce560b</guid></item><item><title>Elderly Porepunkah woman left without in-home care as Freeman manhunt continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/alleged-police-killer-manhunt-disrupts-elderly-in-home-care/105761728</link><description>Elderly residents of Porepunkah have had their home nurse visits cancelled as alleged police killer Dezi Freeman remains at large.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">507302c0595171195289e7be5a84ab6f</guid></item><item><title>How the Jeffrey Epstein saga spread to British politics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/mandelson-how-epstein-scandal-spread-to-the-uk-starmer/105764932</link><description>After dogging the US president for months, evidence of a connection to Jeffrey Epstein has claimed a senior scalp within the British government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b90733943995ade4f20f3bb500f68ab</guid></item><item><title>Regulator with oversight of gas leak 'scandal' had paid role with industry lobbyist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/nt-regulator-oversight-gas-leak-scandal-paid-role-lobbyist/105752490</link><description>The man in charge of the Northern Territory government's handling of a major methane leak at a Santos gas plant was working with a lobbyist for the project's co-owner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b8811b14516374a1aa847b275d1f80a</guid></item><item><title>Islamophobia envoy calls for religious discrimination laws, review of approach to counter-terrorism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/islamophobia-envoy-wants-religious-discrimination-laws/105767918</link><description>In a landmark report, newly-appointed Aftab Malik also calls for counter-terrorism laws and approaches to be reviewed, and for national inquiries into Islamophobia and anti-Palestinian racism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc9a9f371e9e7f0d19902747f4cfb1dd</guid></item><item><title>Rare good news for critically endangered east coast grey nurse sharks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/critically-endangered-grey-nurse-shark-numbers-on-the-rise/105765674</link><description>Scientists say increasing numbers of east coast grey nurse sharks is rare good conservation news for the critically endangered species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10548b61892e77ded2ac12afc8405a87</guid></item><item><title>Air strikes kill at least 32 in Gaza City as Israel ramps up its offensive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/israeli-strikes-kill-at-least-32-across-gaza-city/105770758</link><description>Israel in recent days has intensified strikes across Gaza City, destroying multiple high-rise buildings and accusing Hamas of putting surveillance equipment in them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a19cccd4d36d16c4736f44ec0be6998</guid></item><item><title>Australia and Fiji to press ahead with security treaty talks as Vanuatu deal goes unsigned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/pacific-islands-forum-australia-fiji-security-treaty-talks/105757640</link><description>The government is still racing to expand ties with Pacific nations — particularly the current governments in Fiji and Papua New Guinea — despite a diplomatic setback with Vanuatu.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df82cbc9032e24ef1b1739da332a6e21</guid></item><item><title>Inside the world of Jeffrey Epstein's friends, associates and alleged co-conspirators</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/jeffrey-epstein-friends-associates-over-the-years/105593832</link><description>Convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein intentionally sought out some of the world's most powerful people. Here's how they have responded to his disgraced reputation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d86bdfe45629edff6870e5bdbfae31a</guid></item><item><title>Heavy police presence monitors thousands of protesters across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/protesters-across-political-spectrum-rally-across-australia/105769960</link><description>Rallies against racism and in support of Indigenous sovereignty coincide with mixed anti-government protests in major cities around the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">114f96de2b5f61b5df11c8299f73fdb6</guid></item><item><title>US golfer John Daly takes a record 19 shots to play a par-5 on the PGA Tour Champions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/john-daly-makes-wrong-kind-of-golfing-history-with-19-on-a-par-5/105770020</link><description>John Daly is known as "Wild Thing" for his big-hitting, swashbuckling play, but the US golfer's round went right off the rails on the PGA Tour Champions, hitting the water seven times on a par-5.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b97b8101604fb31617977361f0fd2839</guid></item><item><title>Migrants from Dubai, Philippines breathe new life into Edenhope</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/edenhope-home-to-new-migrants-from-philippines-dubai/105562718</link><description>When Nausheen Hashmi moved to a south-west Victorian farming town, she wondered how the locals would greet her and her children. She need not have worried.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a9fc72b4e6305c0db77bafe91a1bedf</guid></item><item><title>NATO announces operation 'Eastern Sentry' in response to Russian drone incursion in Poland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/nato-strengthens-eastern-defences-as-russian-drones-enter-poland/105769642</link><description>NATO announces plans to beef up the defence of Europe's eastern flank two days after Poland shot down Russian drones that had violated its airspace.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">623f8c161fe97637e26ccdb050a2363f</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane far too good for Gold Coast in QClash semifinal, setting up Collingwood prelim date</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/afl-finals-brisbane-lions-gold-coast-suns-live-blog/105768034</link><description>Brisbane's finals experience has come to the fore in a commanding and comfortable 53-point semifinal win over the Suns at the Gabba.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35fd90e486aa2532889961cd9ae474b8</guid></item><item><title>Nourishing and easy sweet potato and lentil bowls - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/easy-roasted-sweet-potato-and-lentil-bowl/105643934</link><description>This jazzy little bowl is made from simple ingredients. The sweet potato is roasted gently with spices and tinned lentils are roasted until crisp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f14ee49334cef10b8f95233d1889d9e</guid></item><item><title>Supreme Court gives Queensland hospital permission to terminate 12yo girl's pregnancy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/qld-hospital-gets-court-permission-for-abortion-on-12yo-girl/105770196</link><description>A 12-year-old girl in residential care in Queensland should be allowed to have an abortion, a court rules, after a judge found she was not capable of making the decision herself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86cd5589ba9855a3f68a146a74e238ad</guid></item><item><title>Australians tell ABC's Your Say they are struggling more than ever with housing costs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-15/abc-your-say-federal-election-2025-housing-policies/105175180</link><description>Voters tell ABC's Your Say campaign they are struggling more than ever with housing costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54451646ec8e9f100cc2fe59fc9c08c5</guid></item><item><title>Right-wing activist and Trump ally Charlie Kirk shot dead at Utah university</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/charlie-kirk-shot-utah-university-event/105418226</link><description>Donald Trump confirms Charlie Kirk has been shot dead in front of a crowd of horrified students, with the US president describing the conservative activist as a "tremendous person" and a "very good friend".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ea200333d2037582fb4799f0fc34d4d</guid></item><item><title>Who is Larry Ellison and how did he overtake Elon Musk to briefly become the richest person in the world?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/larry-ellison-overtakes-elon-musk-world-richest-person/105761394</link><description>The switch in the ranking comes after a blockbuster earnings report from Oracle, powered by multi-billion-dollar orders from customers as the AI race heats up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0730b98607c60787120f4e7ae4674d8</guid></item><item><title>Live updates: World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo, Day 1</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-2025-in-tokyo-day-1/105770190</link><description>The 2025 World Athletics Championships get underway in Tokyo, with 14 Aussies in action on night one. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1fd0acc71517e138058f6992507918f</guid></item><item><title>At least 190 people reported dead after two boat capsizes in DRC Congo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/over-190-killed-in-congo-boat-accidents/105769772</link><description>Hundreds of people have died and scores are missing from separate boat accidents this week in north-western Congo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ff5aa672c8f2783b21e64160ea828cc</guid></item><item><title>The US election is about style more than substance. It's why Kamala Harris needs to nail her DNC speech in about eight seconds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/us-election-kamala-harris-dnc-speech-style-substance/104256162</link><description>When the Democrat presidential candidate Kamala Harris delivers her speech to the Democratic National Convention today, style will be almost everything.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bddf8093759d999153dfd749b90e144a</guid></item><item><title>Growing group of Labor MPs urge 2035 emissions target above Climate Authority's floor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/labor-mps-urge-2035-target-within-climate-authority-advice/105762592</link><description>A growing cross-factional group within Labor is privately urging for Australia's next major climate target to respect the advice of the Climate Change Authority, which will hand its opinion on a 2035 target to government any day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">366f414d754ce8a4269105ca01955ee0</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu warns Australia that expanding Woodside's North West Shelf gas project could breach international ruling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/vanuatu-warns-australia-about-expansion-of-woodside-gas-project/105759934</link><description>Australia's move to expand Woodside's North West Shelf gas project has not been welcomed in the Pacific, which is fighting the most dramatic effects of climate change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">112f08872918df84094b125b428478cd</guid></item><item><title>Push for seniors' dental scheme grows ahead of federal election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-13/aged-care-dental-scheme-australia-federal-election/105149782</link><description>Imagine living in aged care and not having your teeth or dentures properly cleaned and checked each day. That's a risk faced by elderly Australians, prompting calls for the next federal government to boost oral health training and services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36d312d336a36247fd1c01e78814112b</guid></item><item><title>Former minister Greg Hunt works for Brethren company whose owners made millions on COVID contracts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/greg-hunt-plymouth-brethren-liberal-party-four-corners/105767402</link><description>The Sydney-based church has been described by former members and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese as a "cult".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4328a557e1520bd5030668231cb9ac20</guid></item><item><title>Wallaroos primed for Rugby World Cup quarterfinal against Canada</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/rugby-world-cup-australia-wallaroos-canada/105769754</link><description>Considered underdogs against the world number two, the Wallaroos are urged to be bold in their sudden-death encounter in Bristol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00a664df1e40e5f48d4be15d391193dc</guid></item><item><title>Government assessor finds Townsville Mayor Troy Thompson breached code of conduct</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/troy-thompson-mayor-townsville-conduct-breach/105769890</link><description>The Office of the Independent Assessor found Mr Thompson breached conduct rules when circulating an email criticising another council worker's delays in responding to his request for legal funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">874e80c88283317aa2a40af66fe6107b</guid></item><item><title>Update your ABC News homepage for more local stories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2020-09-03/update-to-abc-news-homepage/12579988</link><description>We've got an ABC News homepage for you. Adjust your settings for the right mix of local and national news.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">146f1699ce6b1b7420a91b6bb80d0309</guid></item><item><title>Murdochs resolve succession saga but family's hold on empire is vulnerable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/murdoch-money-trust/105753004</link><description>Rupert Murdoch's family has always been close. But if you really want to trace the extent of filial and sibling affection, you need to follow the money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05772215b7594bca0b62e72680c673b5</guid></item><item><title>ABC Quote Quiz: Birthday cards, bucket lists and (briefly) Banksy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/abc-quote-quiz-sept-13/105765946</link><description>See if you can work out who said it, and what they were talking about.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a2877e43e9ea593141eb7e2d26494b5</guid></item><item><title>Australia on alert to shot-hole borer threat as WA pivots to tree canopy rehabilitation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/shot-hole-borer-tree-threat-australia/105740250</link><description>It's barely the size of a sesame seed, but the shot-hole borer has quickly devastated Western Australia's tree canopy. Experts are warning other states and territories to take action now to avoid a similar fate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aea657a36513f410d730aac2a0066292</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government pours $12 billion into expanding AUKUS defence facility near Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/albanese-announces-aukus-12-billion-dollar-defence-spend-perth/105770188</link><description>The Albanese government will spend $12 billion on building a submarine and naval shipbuilding facility south of Perth under AUKUS, as doubts linger over the agreement's future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">420e959c71ffce19abd7eac4b8f6483e</guid></item><item><title>In their Melbourne Fringe Show, First Trimester, performer Krishna Istha is seeking a sperm donor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/first-trimester-melbourne-fringe-krisha-istha-sperm-donor/105650028</link><description>Krishna Istha has made a habit of turning to performance to solve a problem. So when they needed help to find a sperm donor, the solution was obvious.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cca559ebaead97189e3624cdb196df95</guid></item><item><title>The simple system I use for composting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/simple-system-use-for-composting/105648580</link><description>Koren Helbig has devised an easy and effective method of turning her food waste and plant trimmings into a nutrient-rich compost for her Adelaide/Tarntanya food gardens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79967d2cf242f317c83d0a075a76ca87</guid></item><item><title>Advocates call for action on brain health as AIHW reveals dementia is leading cause of death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/australians-dying-from-dementia-more-than-any-other-cause/105768682</link><description>Advocates warn the number of people with the condition could exceed 1 million without government intervention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b35bf8bb29f6390428b007c4fc10877</guid></item><item><title>Graduates in 'debt vortex' as HECS front and centre for first time in an election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-16/federal-election-2025-hecs-student-debt-policies/105177248</link><description>New research shows a sharp rise in HECS debts, despite graduate earning power declining, as student loans become a potent election issue for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48707ffafbe02c400b1200e6269fd40e</guid></item><item><title>Construction workers are at higher risk of suicide. Here's how to look out for them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/supporting-loved-ones-who-work-in-construction/105724124</link><description>Construction workers are nearly twice as likely to take their own lives as other employed Australian men of the same age. Understanding the risks can help us better support those we know in the industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d30f05b9ecbefa716057acb813bf159</guid></item><item><title>Homebuyers turn to shared ownership in expensive Wollongong market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/homebuyers-turn-to-shared-ownership-in-property-market/105719548</link><description>Friends Gem and Renata have saved money buying a home together with their respective families in Wollongong, and say the pay-off goes much further.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12de675050396e817010850d0aa22cf0</guid></item><item><title>A journey through 35 years of Canberra's history since the Raiders last won a minor premiership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/the-35-years-since-canberra-raiders-last-won-a-minor-premiership/105768944</link><description>Two weeks ago, the Canberra Raiders won the NRL's 2025 minor premiership by beating the Wests Tigers. It is their first minor premiership since 1990, and a lot has changed since then.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6c07216269a150c362150bb1c36ed05</guid></item><item><title>Armani drama beyond the grave as will instructs heirs to sell or list on stock market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/giorgio-armani-will-sell-company-or-list-on-stock-market/105768872</link><description>Giorgio Armani's will has surprised fashion watchers as it contains instructions to gradually sell off his company to a luxury brand or seek a listing on the stock market, in seeming contrast to his fiercely independent stance throughout his career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53e94498a98d7b4b3828f43dae15498d</guid></item><item><title>Who was Charlie Kirk, the MAGA podcaster and Trump ally shot dead in Utah?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/charlie-kirk-who-helped-build-support-for-donald-trump-dies/105760300</link><description>Charlie Kirk rose from a teenage conservative campus activist to a top podcaster, culture warrior and ally of US President Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cb5074e50db73965f4aeed9b76eb196</guid></item><item><title>Islamophobia has been 'persistent' and 'ignored', envoy says — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/federal-politics-live-sept-12/105765250</link><description>A long-awaited report into Islamophobia in Australia has been handed down, with the special envoy finding it has been "persistent" and "ignored".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2ef5426aa13af6f04a2b80bf14d5cab</guid></item><item><title>Cost of living, housing among key concerns in SA marginal seat of Boothby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-21/boothby-cost-of-living-federal-election-2025/105190262</link><description>At this year’s federal election, the South Australian seat of Boothby is one of the state’s two marginal seats. As part of the ABC’s “Your Say” campaign, we spoke to residents in the electorate about their biggest concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dfd66b0605d29b960082ff52f18c170</guid></item><item><title>Energy projects in South West WA threaten votes for major federal parties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-21/energy-projects-south-west-wa-federal-election-labor-liberals/105152524</link><description>Australia's two major parties have tied their federal election fates to controversial energy projects in WA's South West where the issues have polarised voters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8962a53de05f0293b3a104690022111a</guid></item><item><title>Labor win Kiama by-election as voters replace disgraced MP Gareth Ward</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/kiama-byelection-polls-close-votes-counting/105770414</link><description>The NSW Premier said Kiama now has the ear of the government after it claimed victory in the by-election triggered by the resignation of convicted rapist Gareth Ward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f8148eb8e329e6cf74190c6118a0a8f</guid></item><item><title>Israel's air strike campaign levelling Gaza City's remaining buildings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/israel-idf-destroys-apartment-blocks-in-gaza-city/105748728</link><description>Israel has dramatically ramped up its attacks in Gaza City in the past week with a targeted campaign to strike its high-rises. Hundreds of structures have been destroyed, forcing thousands of already displaced Palestinians to flee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50cf5012172274f369cca0a629feb384</guid></item><item><title>'Bubble curtain' ready to protect cuttlefish as algal bloom persists in SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/algal-bloom-bubble-curtain-ready-as-asthma-advice-defended/105761978</link><description>A "bubble curtain" is set for activation as part of South Australia's fight against the ongoing algal bloom, as the state government defends its handling of health advice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c99d09af36c76bdbcccd8ef52874b9da</guid></item><item><title>Limestone Coast is a food bowl and forestry powerhouse, but its water supply is under threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/limestone-coast-concerns-for-groundwater-shortage/105619362</link><description>South Australia's Limestone Coast is home to lush terrain in Australia's driest state, but its groundwater supplies are slowly in decline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ec057a3e3cf5d831d87672bdf6c9094</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fall to 28-26 defeat against Argentina in The Rugby Championship in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/live-updates-wallabies-vs-argentina-the-rugby-championship/105753320</link><description>The Wallabies have fallen just short of a magical comeback against Argentina, losing 28-26 in a thrilling Rugby Championship Test in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac9963693b81c061d5a7137f7874121c</guid></item><item><title>Erika Kirk makes first public statement after assassination of husband Charlie Kirk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/erika-kirk-pays-tribute-to-late-husband-charlie-kirk/105770008</link><description>Charlie Kirk's widow, Erika, delivers her first public remarks since the fatal shooting of her influencer husband.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a3e797f573f130d4cdaa37fc918652a</guid></item><item><title>'Low levels of satisfaction' with healthcare in Canberra for endometriosis, menopause, identified in Women's Health Matters survey</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/women-health-canberra-survey-access-affordability-not-serious/105748894</link><description>A survey of women in Canberra about the state of their wellbeing and health reveals large gaps in access and affordability, as well as the staggering statistic that almost half of respondents felt doctors weren't taking them seriously.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">124301288b396763dfdb1ac672cdfeb3</guid></item><item><title>Call for button battery redesign after new study reveals horrific injuries and fatalities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/button-battery-warning-danger-deaths-lithium-swallow/103986966</link><description>A new study reveals the horrific injuries suffered after swallowing or inserting button batteries but manufacturers aren't prioritising their redesign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46ab5f96ade65908ecf6b7be8673e61f</guid></item><item><title>Suns coach Damien Hardwick praised ahead of historic finals clash against Lions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/afl-suns-lions-damien-hardwick-alastair-lynch/105769862</link><description>Brisbane Lions great Alastair Lynch hails the impact of Damien Hardwick at the Gold Coast Suns as they look to continue their run in the finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">325e308ff45d50af4c7b44030c5cb081</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump and his 'good man' Anthony Albanese share some common ground</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/donald-trump-anthony-albanese-common/105756898</link><description>The MAGA president's grip on the Republican party is near total while Albanese holds a sway over his left-leaning caucus like few of his Labor predecessors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88bb570d5f115243764edac358fd6925</guid></item><item><title>An Ozzy Osbourne tribute, a Mayhem Ball and a Mariah Carey medley delight fans at the 2025 MTV VMAs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/key-moments-from-the-2025-vmas/105746958</link><description>Ariana Grande and Lady Gaga took home the biggest awards at this year's MTV VMAs with several nineties stars honoured for their musical legacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7aac3df4ab0753ac617e05bcf866036a</guid></item><item><title>Toni Jordan spent her childhood at the greyhound track, inspiring her new novel Tenderfoot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/toni-jordan-books-tenderfoot-interview/105754310</link><description>The acclaimed author's father was a greyhound trainer and her mother ran a TAB. Her unconventional childhood inspired her eighth book, Tenderfoot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19370cb777b009a92f1855e8361e9d09</guid></item><item><title>Is the pink soap scum in my bathroom mould, or something else?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/why-is-the-soap-scum-in-my-bathroom-pink-and-orange-/105721212</link><description>Have you ever noticed a pink or orange-coloured substance in the tile grout or around taps in your bathroom? In most cases, it's one of two things.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9deb3308036c00d500826ba08d50f062</guid></item><item><title>Australia's growing cohort of tenants fear they will rent forever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-16/australias-growing-tenant-cohort-fear-forever-renting/105127148</link><description>Home ownership rates in Australia have been falling for decades, and with rental vacancies at record lows and prices at historic highs, many fear their dream of owning a home may be out of reach. Some experts say rental caps could help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36f35fe439f533ac9522c679c7e37187</guid></item><item><title>More than a dozen women complain about Brisbane doctor accused of performing 'sexually motivated' checks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/complaints-against-brisbane-doctor-accused-unnecessary-checks/105761406</link><description>Dr Stan Theodoros is facing disciplinary proceedings, lodged by Queensland's health ombudsman, in the Queensland Civil and Administrative Tribunal (QCAT).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">741e87aaa3667ced3bea58af9748de48</guid></item><item><title>ASX higher on US rate cut expectations, but markets underestimating inflation risk — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/asx-markets-business-live-news-sept-12/105765376</link><description>The ASX rises, as do Virgin shares, as the airline reveals the exit pay of its former CEO. Westpac's economics team, led by former RBA assistant governor Luci Ellis, say they think markets are underpricing the risk of a renewed inflation breakout in the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9e5b59041ffdcd6b6304cf4b5301d79</guid></item><item><title>Nepal's gen Z protesters are continuing the fight for their future even after picking a new prime minister</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/nepal-gen-z-protesters-on-fight-for-future/105765704</link><description>A calm has fallen on Nepal's streets after days of violence and chaos. But leaders of the gen Z protest movement say the work's not done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b37bb71a46bc744a9f38b66a4eed75af</guid></item><item><title>Artists and users boycotting Spotify over AI use and CEO's military tech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/spotify-boycott-daniel-ek-ai-music-military-tech-fenn-wilson/105765846</link><description>A growing number of artists and users are leaving Spotify. What's changed with the streaming giant? And what comes next?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dce4c940b969890ecfdfb4e37ad98c9</guid></item><item><title>'Clone' websites catch out Australian customers as online shopping scams become 'alarmingly' common</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/clone-websites-retailers-catch-out-online-shoppers-scam/105736854</link><description>Online shopping scams are now one of the most frequently reported scam types and experts say they are alarmingly common, impersonating well-known brands and being promoted in search engine advertisements.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d6cf1bf94f1b9a65d30881e571ce779</guid></item><item><title>Voters tell ABC's Your Say they want politicians with a vision, not bickering</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-13/abc-your-say-federal-election-politicians-with-vision/105164874</link><description>Voters tell ABC's Your Say campaign they want courage and vision from politicians, not bickering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">033ddce5ad54070fbce620dc6760d9ba</guid></item><item><title>Reserve Bank restructure closer to reality after Treasurer Jim Chalmers offers olive branch to Angus Taylor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/reserve-bank-restructure-closer-to-reality/104260250</link><description>The Reserve Bank of Australia is a step closer to its biggest restructure in three decades after the treasurer offers an assurance to his Coalition counterpart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e920ec5b24583b8f74962ecc7f9c2585</guid></item><item><title>Australians watched the moment of Charlie Kirk's assassination on social media with no warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/young-australians-watched-charlie-kirk-murder-social-media/105766060</link><description>Young Australians say they are seeing graphic video of US commentator Charlie Kirk being shot dead pop up in their social media algorithms without warning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9340dfaeb79e8ebb902319c5caea2078</guid></item><item><title>NRLW wrap: Brisbane Broncos thrash the Cowboys 50-4, Gold Coast grab last finals spot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/upton-hat-trick-leads-broncos-to-big-nrlw-win-over-cowboys/105770416</link><description>It's a big day for Queensland sides in the NRLW, as the Broncos — led by skipper Tamika Upton — are far too good for the third-placed Cowboys, while the Titans clinch the last finals spot with a win over Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0af6a0f9bdb8ae75a28c6c7e963ce856</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand fugitive Tom Phillips killed in shootout with police after four years on the run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/nz-fugitive-tom-phillips-shot-dead/105746874</link><description>Tom Phillips is killed during a shootout with police during a burglary in New Zealand's Waikato region, his sister says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e302078e2d9bb555278551a94b40cfd3</guid></item><item><title>Have Your Say: What was the issue, policy or event that decided your vote?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-02-26/federal-election-your-say/104788518</link><description>After a five-week campaign, the results are in with Labor returned to government. Is there a policy or issue that swayed your vote? Have Your Say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">320dfcbec9cd8fe02e449407ce78e618</guid></item><item><title>Next-generation voters call for better engagement ahead of federal election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-18/federal-election-rural-next-generation-voters/105173450</link><description>Young people in Albury say issues that directly affect them and their communities are not being addressed by major parties for the 2025 election campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ae182892b8c9591cd9ec35e6e57fcb9</guid></item><item><title>Sushila Karki sworn in as Nepal's new prime minister after gen Z protests prompt political change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/sushila-karki-nepals-new-prime-minister-after-gen-z-protests/105769388</link><description>Sushila Karki garnered widespread support from many young Nepalese people who took to the streets in anger over government corruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b14068c37ad26302453e199b0b0960b7</guid></item><item><title>Penrith Panthers, Cronulla Sharks win NRL elimination finals against Warriors, Sydney Roosters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/nrl-finals-live-warriors-panthers-sharks-roosters/105770330</link><description>The Sharks end the Roosters' NRL season in the second NRL elimination final after Penrith took down the Warriors 24-8 in Auckland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8453f95a136416a45ec4efe167c5d81f</guid></item><item><title>WA Health issues measles warning as two more cases linked to Bali travel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/two-more-measles-cases-in-wa-linked-to-bali-travel/105770492</link><description>West Australians planning to visit South-East Asia are being urged to get vaccinated against measles, with two more cases linked with travel to Bali.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1897bbaf4493022b86af465fcc949ac6</guid></item><item><title>What's next for the far-right political movement in Australia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/what-next-for-far-right-john-macgowan/105735032</link><description>Australia's far-right movement has been buoyed by a wave of recent protests against mass immigration, with some saying the rallies were the "biggest thing that's happened in conservative and nationalist politics for a hundred years".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07e149ee4aff2602783cd21b0afe8328</guid></item><item><title>Adrianne Lenker on Big Thief's evolution and the making of Double Infinity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/big-thief-double-infinity-adrianne-lenker-new-album-interview/105754728</link><description>At the peak of their success, Big Thief faced a major emotional rupture that reshaped the group from the inside out. Now, they've returned with their sixth album, shaped by deep creative trust and a renewed commitment to collaboration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c838f7561646302e00adf2a4fa4ff7b4</guid></item><item><title>Tiwi Islanders eager to have their say as remote voting for the federal election begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-22/early-voting-starts-in-remote-communities-tiwi-islands-aec/105201318</link><description>Voters in the small remote community of Pirlangimpi on the Tiwi Islands, north of Darwin, have become some of the first to cast their votes for the federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0c419fe3ae44debe7edf27241c0e5c1</guid></item><item><title>Health, climate and community sport: What older voters in the Tasmanian seat of Bass are talking about this election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-29/health-climate-sport-election-older-voters-bass-tasmania/105224138</link><description>The federal seat of Bass is held by a margin of just 1.4 per cent. For these older voters who live in the electorate, health, climate and community sport are the issues that will decide their vote.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a3579db910b5a7ee8e11d2618bf798f</guid></item><item><title>When does Gout Gout run in the 200m at the 2025 World Athletics Championships in Tokyo, and other key events</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/when-does-gout-gout-run-at-the-world-athletics-championships/105748430</link><description>The 2025 World Athletics Championships in Tokyo sees Australia's largest-ever team tackle the best athletes on the planet. Here are the key events you won't want to miss.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed7a4e602de605c0371a42019cfce15a</guid></item><item><title>Australian-funded PALM scheme liaison workers say they went months without pay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/country-liaison-officers-allege-underpayment-pacific/105694912</link><description>Pacific Islanders supporting PALM workers say they have had to go to great lengths — including flying to their home countries — to chase money owed to them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8170a75dc62bc775f286f334b5115dc4</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne seat of Calwell highlights Labor woes as Gaza pain galvanises Muslim voters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-20/calwell-labor-backlash-over-gaza-islamophobia/104850500</link><description>Dissatisfaction with the Albanese government's stance on Israel-Palestine among many Arab and Muslim voters threatens to unseat Labor MPs, in some places for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63e7f9854fee5bc20e54ee2f5bd136f4</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne's Royal Children's Hospital cancels children in war discussion citing staff safety</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/royal-childrens-hospital-children-in-war-event-cancelled/105768998</link><description>Melbourne's Royal Children's Hospital says a symposium on the effect of war on children has been cancelled due to safety fears, but some doctors say pressure from a group opposing antisemitism is to blame.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fccbb42b0ca2b5ba0a4d9a7fdb9a9816</guid></item><item><title>Who is Tyler Robinson, the accused killer of Charlie Kirk?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/tyler-robinson-charlie-kirks-alleged-killer/105769710</link><description>After his father encouraged Tyler Robinson to turn himself in, people close to the 22-year-old provided investigators with crucial insights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeb2177456349534e747aeb65ed554d9</guid></item><item><title>AFLW wrap: Collingwood ends Sydney's unbeaten run, Carlton thumps Gold Coast, the Power beats the Demons</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/swans-perfect-start-ends-as-magpies-stun-at-home/105770154</link><description>Collingwood, wooden spooners last season, keep Sydney goalless for more than three quarters at home on Saturday for an upset win, as Port Adelaide beat another unbeaten side in Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">112f93d3f5b081beaf0d54247ad5c93a</guid></item><item><title>NSW government to roll out capped taxi fares from Sydney Airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/nsw-sydney-airport-to-cap-taxi-fees-in-fare-crackdown/105769768</link><description>A New York-style approach to taxi fees will roll out at Sydney Airport in a bid to put an end to fare rip-offs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2552ed679b01d6ed028827768a374b6</guid></item><item><title>What happens to your data when you trade or recycle your device?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/what-happens-to-data-when-disposing-of-old-devices-in-ewaste/105681804</link><description>A cybercrime expert says trading or recycling electronics may not completely erase personal data and users should adopt a "risk-adjusted strategy" when disposing of devices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a43950c96dbc6efda59bd57a5459809</guid></item><item><title>Mobile coverage is an election issue in regional areas. What's been promised?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-23/telecommunications-mobile-coverage-federal-election-promises/105080674</link><description>For many regional and remote Australians, reliable mobile coverage can be life-saving. They are desperate for both sides of politics to take meaningful action towards eliminating black spots.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ceda72e552d98e5f293d3c037efeefa</guid></item><item><title>Evidence points to remains found in Vietnam cave being South-East Asia's earliest known homicide victim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/vietnam-remains-earliest-known-homicide-victim-cold-case/105741956</link><description>It was on a sweltering morning in 2018 in a cave in northern Vietnam when Chris Stimpson and his team uncovered what may be the oldest cold case murder in South-East Asia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34f92776d6167c167af22a4b170f6648</guid></item><item><title>Housing advocates seek federal funding election promise for co-op model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-17/housing-cooperative-solution-proposed-for-rental-crisis/105108816</link><description>Advocates admit co-operative housing models are not for everyone but say for the right residents, they offer more security and affordable pricing than traditional rentals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3608b0c1ae56f5a5b36968898f65df5e</guid></item></channel></rss>