<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 07:06:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Sabrina Carpenter slams White House for using her music in ICE video</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/sabrina-carpenter-slams-white-house-donald-trump-for-using-music/106094936</link><description>Two-time Grammy winner Sabrina Carpenter slams the White House for using her song in a social media post about ICE raids, telling the Trump administration to never involve her in its "inhumane agenda".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8f7bdbb2cd0918ab4dc555b58041df2</guid></item><item><title>Football presenter Laura Woods collapses during scary on-air moment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/laura-woods-collapses-during-scary-on-air-moment/106095356</link><description>Laura Woods says she is doing 'OK' after collapsing on-air during an England match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9afae0442b5bf4dbdb650da6154d8516</guid></item><item><title>Report shows violent attacks and street abuse 'the norm' for Australian Jews, peak body says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/nsw-anti-jewish-incidents-report-2025-antisemitism-australia/106095142</link><description>Executive Council of Australian Jewry Alex Ryvchin said the data showed antisemitism remained at "deeply troubling levels".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0363a3480b2abf2d21da4defcd546451</guid></item><item><title>Victorian government relaxes car parking rules around well-connected residential developments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/allan-government-relaxes-car-parking-rules-homes-transport-links/106095118</link><description>The Victorian government vows to overhaul "outdated" car parking requirements for new residential developments in areas that are well-serviced by public transport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbd853c1855a14f011ecbb83f424873f</guid></item><item><title>Humanitarian migrants in US fear being deported into danger following shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/humanitarian-migrants-fear-deportation-following-shooting/106079920</link><description>The Trump administration's escalating restrictions on humanitarian migration are leaving some of the United States's most vulnerable diaspora communities terrified for their futures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8565c833d32189c41ff928dd4eda97f</guid></item><item><title>Data centre spending spree and housing boom drive economic growth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/september-quarter-gdp-2025-shows-economy-growing/106094160</link><description>Australia's economy grew by 0.4 per cent in the September quarter, driven by data centre spending spree and housing boom</description><guid isPermaLink="false">028c5d2dcb4ba055610adff5fba5b79d</guid></item><item><title>Hopes remain for return of eagles to relocated nest at Bundaberg Hospital site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/wedge-tailed-eagle-nest-relocation-bundaberg-hospital/106091190</link><description>A wedge-tailed eagle's nest was moved in an operation costing about $100,000 involving a 60-tonne crane, a specialist arborist and a carefully engineered basket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44f4ee129a4a56a8978a10e15f65edcf</guid></item><item><title>Peter Scammell charged with murder, extradited over 2020 death of nurse Katrina Hawker in Palmerston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/peter-scammell-charged-with-murder-over-katrina-hawker-death/106095606</link><description>A 44-year-old man has been charged with murder over the death of his partner near Darwin, and has been extradited from Victoria ahead of his first appearance in the Darwin Local Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5c7039d078e6825087f1be22888c869</guid></item><item><title>Crystal Fabergé egg shatters record, fetching $46m at auction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/crystal-faberg%C3%A9-egg-crafted-for-russian-royalty-shatters-record/106095312</link><description>The Winter Egg is made from finely carved rock crystal, covered in a delicate snowflake motif wrought in platinum with 4,500 tiny diamonds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa8c9f575b3950461f5671df857d7dd8</guid></item><item><title>Council says warnings ignored about tree removal in Central West Orana REZ</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/renewable-tree-destruction-council-criticism/106091996</link><description>The NSW government is being accused of wilfully ignoring warnings about the destruction of hundreds of native trees as part of a renewables project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c96e7e487df6855f57961c9b19f8335</guid></item><item><title>Demersal fishing ban announced for commercial, recreational fishers in Perth and WA amid scarce fish stocks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/perth-wa-strict-fishing-ban-commercial-recreational-fishers/106095814</link><description>Strict bans limiting commercial and recreational fishing in Perth and WA are announced in an effort to save some under-threat fish species from the brink of collapse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e453fcaba88e452b2844efd665762060</guid></item><item><title>Hugh Jackman and Kate Hudson surprise patrons with impromptu performance at Aussie pub in NYC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/hugh-jackman-kate-hudson-old-mates-pub-sweet-caroline/106095716</link><description>Hugh Jackman sung the crowd-pleaser Sweet Caroline and even climbed onto the top of the bar counter for the performance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b533f89ca790e766808a38268893eac8</guid></item><item><title>What time does the Gabba Test start? How to watch the Ashes, and Brisbane weather forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/ashes-2025-what-time-does-the-gabba-test-start/106095876</link><description>The second Ashes Test is upon us and we have fingers crossed it will last more than two days. Here's everything you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5877ff31536d915fc1044634dafee1f7</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins eyeing early return from injury in Gabba Test with Josh Inglis poised for Ashes debut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/josh-inglis-pat-cummins-ashes-brisbane-gabba/106096640</link><description>Australian skipper Pat Cummins is pushing for an early return from injury in the second Test in Brisbane while Josh Inglis will be making his Ashes debut.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17fed6f87907ecb612b4497bead483e4</guid></item><item><title>What happened to Lisa Lynn? The untold story of Greg Lynn's first marriage and his wife's sudden death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/unravel-huntsman-what-happened-to-lisa-lynn/104591040</link><description>Long before Greg Lynn was convicted of murder in Victoria's High Country, his estranged wife died suddenly at home in Mount Macedon. Now, some of those closest to Lisa Lynn are pushing for the coroner to re-examine her death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d05853d821bab6cebb3660faa1636d5</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann loses appeal against failed rape defamation case as lawyer hints at High Court challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/bruce-lehrmann-loses-appeal-of-finding-raped-brittany-higgins/106096496</link><description>Bruce Lehrmann has lost his appeal against a Federal Court ruling that found on the balance of probabilities he raped his then-colleague Brittany Higgins in 2019.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57e5db8864dc3cc122fbb3a1a6649b13</guid></item><item><title>Government considers offloading retiring Tiger helicopters to Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/government-considers-tiger-helicopters-to-ukraine/106097120</link><description>As the United States attempts to broker a peace deal at the Kremlin in Moscow, it is expected a significant funding boost from Canberra to aid Ukraine's war efforts is imminent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d5df644b3bb02e84a4c678130b237d</guid></item><item><title>Parents left with PTSD after son's death question post-operative care for people with disabilities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/perth-parents-question-post-operative-care-sons-sudden-death/106093640</link><description>The parents of a young man with a neuromuscular disease who died seven days after spinal surgery say they have serious concerns about the post-operative care he was provided at Royal Perth Hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d45fd7926a327736d402f80be50d3fa</guid></item><item><title>Search for missing flight MH370 to resume this month, Malaysia says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/search-for-missing-flight-mh370-to-resume/106097466</link><description>The search for missing Malaysia Airlines Flight MH370 will resume at the end of December, more than a decade after the Beijing-bound flight disappeared.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3739bbb1d5d8abfbc7527199c51e06f</guid></item><item><title>Why dating your therapist is almost never OK</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/why-dating-your-therapist-is-never-ok/106086500</link><description>A new code of conduct for for Australian psychologists provides updated guidance that it's almost never OK to date someone who is or has been a client, even if that was years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9c38271f27c7d67f982ad95f6bafac4</guid></item><item><title>Woman dies after being struck by hay bale at Roma Saleyards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/woman-dies-after-being-struck-by-hay-bale-roma-saleyards/106096236</link><description>Police and emergency services were called to the Roma Saleyards this morning after reports a hay bale had fallen on a woman. She died at the scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e2c59f3bd9f424726fcd71727495ec9</guid></item><item><title>Is it better to sleep naked or wear pyjamas in summer?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/is-it-better-to-sleep-naked-or-wear-pyjamas/106022700</link><description>What you wear to bed can affect the quality of your sleep. And if that's nothing at all, there are a few things to consider.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d379ee8e077de4c450e19dbddaa8427</guid></item><item><title>How to prepare yourself and your child for the social media ban on December 10</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/social-media-ban-pocket-guide-december-10/105938784</link><description>From December 10, young people will lose access to part of their online world. Here's how to support them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">778f718b5f3382e1a2ff7745675b7836</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's local and state governments to pay $650,000 for Foo Fighters concert in Launceston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/tas-to-pay-650000-for-foo-fighters-concert-in-launceston/106096094</link><description>Tasmania's "biggest concert ever" will take place at Launceston's York Park next month when American rock band Foo Fighters play their only Australian show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf968a5fd5a8aa81d76d97a55f862ebd</guid></item><item><title>Man killed, two others injured in northern NSW shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/northern-nsw-shooting-two-hospital-police/106098328</link><description>A man has died and two others injured following a shooting on a property in Murwillumbah in northern NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51ab5f45097fc9549a966da49bd3d843</guid></item><item><title>Algal bloom inquiry quizzes health chief about respiratory illness concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/public-health-chief-nicola-spurrier-fronts-algal-bloom-committee/106096360</link><description>South Australia's public health chief says there is a need for more data analysis to determine whether there has been an increase in respiratory illness linked to the state's algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1684af84be28c71b9ddb8b5f866a5837</guid></item><item><title>What the latest GDP numbers mean for interest rates and the economy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/gdp-figures-interest-rates-australian-economy-what-it-means/106095708</link><description>Australia's latest economic growth numbers show an economy in generally rude health, but that might result in a rude shock for mortgage borrowers earlier rather than later in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99a08905a8b035ded471a1c7886962df</guid></item><item><title>Ryan Papenhuyzen unsure if he'll ever return to professional sport after Melbourne Storm exit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/ryan-papenhuyzen-melbourne-storm-r360-future/106098004</link><description>Former Melbourne fullback Ryan Papenhuyzen says his future is a "blank canvas" ahead of a break from professional sport that he admits could end up being permanent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6707a3ee0371a85a20e3496d08c53bf</guid></item><item><title>'Extreme fire danger' forecast across South Australia for Thursday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/extreme-fire-weather-forecast-across-south-australia/106097370</link><description>The CFS is warning of high fire risk tomorrow with hot and windy conditions forecast, while the BOM has issued a fire weather warning with 'extreme fire danger' for parts of the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a5842876968e1f8a2cf4d8bda48fc5c</guid></item><item><title>Coalition has 'no confidence' social media ban will work under Labor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/coalition-has-no-confidence-in-social-media-ban/106098732</link><description>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley says Australia's social media ban will not work under Labor, as the federal government rejects YouTube's claim it will make kids "less safe".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afca70cdf1bf6407005b94a05df72a36</guid></item><item><title>First community-designed, culture-led home from new outback housing initiative arrives in Tennant Creek</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/tennant-creek-first-wilya-janta-culture-led-homes-arrives/106090624</link><description>A one-of-a-kind home, designed with the input of Tennant Creek families, has rolled up the Stuart Highway from Adelaide on a convoy of trucks. It is part of a new initiative aiming to transform housing in remote First Nations communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1245d00b9a5564e52777b7a81c103d3</guid></item><item><title>Jodie Hill denies involvement in alleged murder of 72-year-old Dimboola man John Hunter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/jodie-hill-dimboola-murder-supreme-court-crime/106097744</link><description>A woman on trial for the alleged murder of 72-year-old Victorian man John Hunter tells the Supreme Court she was present when he was attacked but another person was responsible for his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eef245144a5b7185d3fbcd25811e3cbf</guid></item><item><title>Footballer sacked, youth worker charged after 'last-minute' intel leads to drug drop police sting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/footballer-youth-worker-drug-bust/106097862</link><description>A regional Victorian footballer and youth worker are facing drug trafficking charges after being caught with a package allegedly containing illegal drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38e52f4cb62113f362aec8387ad7abe5</guid></item><item><title>Hobart's AFL stadium vote to pass Tasmania's upper house, but at what cost?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/hobart-afl-stadium-to-pass-tasmania-upper-house/106098582</link><description>A stadium on Hobart's waterfront has gained enough support to pass parliament, after key independents declared on Wednesday they would support the contentious project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76f6a7db96ff59b5758f389b96324df7</guid></item><item><title>Man with alleged links to 'Afghan crew' accused of lying to get home loan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/sydney-man-bail-allegedly-lied-to-get-million-dollar-home-loan/106098492</link><description>Ali Jundi was arrested as part of an investigation into the Alameddine crime family, with police alleging he was part of the "Afghan crew".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cf938216b8ce0d9a3c9537db01d3e14</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106098532</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b07e28ef2886eb3ca1e3b96068117042</guid></item><item><title>Australia's oil refineries will need government support to avoid a reliance on fuel imports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/australias-oil-refineries-need-government-support-to-compete/106095796</link><description>With just two refineries left and 80 per cent of liquid fuel being imported, experts are warning Australia is increasingly vulnerable to global supply shocks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e76fbb39a0d9416aa8d22c00cfdec98</guid></item><item><title>Treasurer hopeful Fremantle Traffic Bridge shutdown will be less than a year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/fremantle-traffic-bridge-closing-date/106098860</link><description>The WA government could consider limiting truck movements across the Stirling Bridge at peak hour to limit traffic congestion when the Fremantle Traffic Bridge closes, the deputy premier says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19da2dbff7943980f6d9ba0c6ad5c786</guid></item><item><title>Australia to provide Ukraine with $95m funding boost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/australia-to-provide-ukraine-with-95m-funding-boost/106098710</link><description>Australia will provide an additional $95 million in military assistance to Ukraine and slap a fresh round of sanctions on ships believed to be part of Moscow's so-called "shadow fleet".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e325db491fb1443122547e4bbc6d0b5</guid></item><item><title>WA's surrogacy and IVF laws overhauled as legislation passes state parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/wa-surrogacy-ivf-laws-overhauled-after-years-of-debate/106055640</link><description>Same-sex couples, single people, transgender and intersex West Australians will be able to access assisted reproductive technology and surrogacy, almost a decade after reforms were first promised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f44918d7e495555142326d3ca7386226</guid></item><item><title>Three issues reveal Albanese government's record on trust and integrity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/albanese-trust-jobs-for-mates-social-media-ban-transparency/106088008</link><description>Despite holding a commanding position, Anthony Albanese knows the global trend of sliding trust in government isn't one to be taken lightly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec30e2f45902d9cbc45411469bdc3e38</guid></item><item><title>New police investigation into Lisa Lynn’s death stalls over bill for expert report, family says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/new-lisa-lynn-police-investigation-stalls-over-expert-report/106089854</link><description>The family of the late first wife of High Country killer Greg Lynn says a fresh investigation into her death has stalled because police will not pay for an expert report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fa2d52decd1defbb0eb923844e95973</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Barnes: The story behind Working Class Man and his American dream</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/jimmy-barnes-working-class-man-interview-40-years/106088240</link><description>Cold Chisel was over. America beckoned. And Jimmy Barnes was terrified. This is the story of the album that made him, and the song that saved him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6b683513940f3ea59d642826a0e9d3f</guid></item><item><title>Energy watchdog flags 5 per cent fall in power prices amid renewables surge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/aemc-flags-fall-in-power-prices-as-renewable-energy-surges/106098392</link><description>An energy watchdog says more renewable energy is projected to lower prices, but others warn the promise is illusory and more pain is coming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3167cac147f6b9a1b77db85dbab5f83</guid></item><item><title>One player's case against the world's biggest crypto casino</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/case-against-the-worlds-biggest-crypto-casino-stake-vip-host/105884760</link><description>Chat logs and gambling data show the tactics used by Australian-run online casino Stake to keep one user hooked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e509f307e4a257bfe74d3a546597ee94</guid></item><item><title>Spotify Wrapped 2025: Bad Bunny takes global top artist spot for fourth time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/spotify-wrapped-2025-bad-bunny-takes-top-spot-wiggles-australia/106098954</link><description>Spotify Wrapped is back for 2025, with Bad Bunny taking the top spot for global artist for a fourth time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">486a29b95aff8226e12fcecbb0acc59a</guid></item><item><title>Survivors of child sexual abuse face growing National Redress Scheme wait times</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/national-redress-scheme-wait-times-growing/106095996</link><description>An independent audit of the National Redress Scheme has found wait times are increasing and causing significant distress to survivors of child sexual abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">779e18eb3e262e1d9462f06f245a54cf</guid></item><item><title>NSW council votes to stop flying Indigenous flags and enforce permissions for Welcome to Country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/aboriginal-torres-strait-islander-flags-federation-council/106090716</link><description>A mayor in southern NSW says removing the Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander flags from council meeting chambers will "promote civic neutrality".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26969c1b10c251548facab2ddd0db10b</guid></item><item><title>Australia's teen social media ban has unofficially begun. Here's what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/when-is-the-teen-social-media-ban-what-apps-are-banned/106086152</link><description>December 4 marked the unofficial start of the teen social media ban. Here's everything you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92055cd8f8b6664d761c0582f88b1c76</guid></item><item><title>Most renters avoid heating and cooling homes due to costs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/renters-energy-costs-report/106079190</link><description>A new report finds that about 70 per cent of renters were avoiding heating and cooling their homes to save money. Some experts and advocates are calling for stronger minimum energy standards across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9ee397f67be2d044da6702933e1bb56</guid></item><item><title>Parents, cancer patients say lack of proton therapy in Australia is 'an embarrassment'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/cancer-patients-say-lack-of-proton-therapy-is-embarrassing/106099062</link><description>When seven-month-old Evelyn was diagnosed with a rare cancer, her mother was told proton beam therapy would be her daughter's best chance for survival. But the treatment was not available in Australia and still is not three years later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7618a755932871cd58fc40ef994c4f8</guid></item><item><title>Superstar Twiggy on the documentary of her storied life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/twiggy-interview-sadie-frost-documentary/106085568</link><description>For the first time, the much-loved English model, actress and singer tells her own story in a new documentary by Sadie Frost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69ede7f405562c37563819191cd8818e</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast beaches eroded by Cyclone Alfred all open in time for summer holidays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/gold-coast-beaches-reopen-after-cyclone-alfred/106097888</link><description>Severe erosion caused by Cyclone Alfred forced the closure of several beaches in March. Now, extra lifeguards are being recruited as they anticipate a busy summer period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edb25a2af80d5486baec7f99c79a78d6</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann is running out of courts after losing his defamation appeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/bruce-lehrmann-running-out-of-courts-defamation-case/106097988</link><description>With his defamation appeal dismissed and legal costs rising, Bruce Lehrmann is almost out of options. A High Court bid is possible, but what would it take to get there?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">952bc5625baab2e37bca594593752cba</guid></item><item><title>Maddy sees the world through a 'glitter jar' but has still become a national tennis champion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/maddy-kelly-blind-low-vision-tennis-stargardt-disease/106091058</link><description>Victorian teenager Maddy Kelly was 11 years old when she started losing her sight. Two years later, she's a national tennis champion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de14bd29081988e1574d5e120dd4d92e</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith says adaptability is Australia's focus heading into the second Ashes Test at the Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/steve-smith-on-adaptability-heading-into-second-ashes-test/106099612</link><description>Steve Smith reveals the mindset Australia is taking into the second Test as the Aussies look to go up 2–0 in the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10898752092de46072fa6e796c3eda38</guid></item><item><title>Homegrown trainee Darrenia Carr helps fill recruitment gap in Tennant Creek art centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/barkly-regional-arts-training-filling-recruitment-gap-locally/106086734</link><description>An apprenticeship program in a remote Northern Territory town is helping businesses find skilled workers by connecting homegrown teens to local employment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10c61922907728d9fe670f60ee92389d</guid></item><item><title>Aged home care package changes set off cash conflict between providers and suppliers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/home-care-package-kickbacks-row-between-providers-suppliers/106095962</link><description>Care providers are trying to strongarm cash from suppliers of equipment, including wheelchairs, a month after the federal government reformed home care packages for senior Australians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e55de2b95201e71f552d7c77f3667f03</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder over Eungella shooting as another faces extradition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/man-charged-with-murder-over-shooting-at-eungella/106099646</link><description>A man charged with murder is refused bail as another faces extradition over a shooting on the NSW North Coast that left one man dead and two others injured.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cee90383f9f549f653a271fa90690021</guid></item><item><title>Richard Marles says he is 'working through' AUKUS review from the US – as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/federal-politics-live-december-4/106098384</link><description>The acting prime minister says the United States is fully supportive of AUKUS and has thanked it for providing a review.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e28bf601f3b2f015528a984d64fe244</guid></item><item><title>Video of Jeffrey Epstein's private island released by US Democrats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/video-from-jeffrey-epstein-s-private-island/106099640</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18459054eb6028846cbae91e26ff160c</guid></item><item><title>Fourth person arrested over Elizabeth shopping centre stabbing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/fourth-person-arrested-over-adelaide-shopping-centre-stabbing/106099642</link><description>The Elizabeth City Centre shopping centre was placed in lockdown with shoppers evacuated on Friday afternoon after an alleged fight that left two males with "critical" and "life-threatening" injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04ddca072ad4913507344368ab7a9e28</guid></item><item><title>Doctor in Matthew Perry overdose case sentenced to two and a half years in prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/doctor-in-matthew-perry-overdose-case-sentenced/106099756</link><description>A California doctor is imprisoned for illegally supplying Friends sitcom star Matthew Perry with ketamine, the powerful sedative that caused the actor's drug overdose death in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17d3409f980efc7b50604974340e50d8</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies and All Blacks drawn into same group for first time at 2027 Rugby World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/wallabies-and-all-blacks-drawn-into-same-world-cup-group/106099738</link><description>Wallabies coach Joe Schmidt says he is unlikely to be coaching the All Blacks at the World Cup, as Australia and New Zealand are drawn into the same group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c57be47b673feaaf8d94d81f316c9ca</guid></item><item><title>Increasing wait times for mammograms could have 'potentially tragic' consequences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/up-to-nine-month-wait-for-diagnostic-mammograms/106092334</link><description>A Medicare funding freeze and high cost of training new students has left a shortage of workers and blown out wait times of critical diagnostic services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">010130b4e8ae7c75d997cc1a3237e030</guid></item><item><title>Remote community in WA's Pilbara saves $400k of food after truck breaks down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/remote-community-rescues-400k-food-delivery/106090818</link><description>A mammoth effort by community members saves $400,000 worth of food for the Punmu remote community, but the incident reignites the debate about the condition of WA's most remote roads.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">249659075efb94f6e6dac94931adddd3</guid></item><item><title>Multiple charges laid after fatal shooting of man at Logan, south of Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/queensland-logan-fatal-shooting-charges-laid-police/106099958</link><description>A 22-year-old Beenleigh man has been charged with four offences as police investigate a fatal shooting in a Logan park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d4c42270f75bbf5011748172835dded</guid></item><item><title>Raccoon goes on drunken rampage in US liquor store</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/raccoon-goes-on-drunken-rampage-in-us-liquor-store/106099888</link><description>The suspect broke into a liquor store in the US state of Virginia, ransacked several shelves and ended up face down in the bathroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50d530a309b6a1b48f0063a161194a83</guid></item><item><title>Western Australia's Payarri people celebrate state's 150th native title determination after 30-year journey</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/150th-native-title-determination-wa-after-claimants-wait-30y/106087088</link><description>It was 1994 when Ngalia man Kado Muir first sat down with two of his elders and a lawyer to discuss lodging a native title claim for his ancestral country, Payarri. Today, the Federal Court will make an on-country determination of that claim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d464b121e26d8133c6fa619d7a32bddb</guid></item><item><title>Cricket fan's mission to crisscross Australia on his yellow Vespa to attend every Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/cricket-fan-scott-stokes-vespa-roadtrip-ashes-tests/106092912</link><description>One man, one little yellow Vespa and a 12,000-kilometre road trip to attend every Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08904e1ddbf6249d0b35e2061d1915eb</guid></item><item><title>Broome man who killed non-biological brother not guilty of murder due to mental impairment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/ian-ralph-brooke-broome-murder-not-guilty/106099188</link><description>A special proceedings hearing in the Supreme Court in Broome heard that Ian Ralph Brooke was suffering from an acute psychotic disorder when he fatally stabbed a 27-year-old in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4cc6389176a2c81087d7968e13af5f7</guid></item><item><title>Alleged childcare paedophile Joshua Dale Brown hit with more than 80 additional charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/police-more-charges-alleged-childcare-paedophile-joshua-brown/106100140</link><description>Detectives have issued an additional 83 charges against Joshua Dale Brown, a former childcare worker who was charged with more than 70 offences earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e7aa0842c1dc25269edefc994152801</guid></item><item><title>Opal mining to continue on land cut out from new Qld national park, formerly Vergemont Station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/opal-miners-continue-operations-vergemont-station-national-park/106095772</link><description>The Queensland government's purchase of Vergemont Station last year led to months of uncertainty for miners with tenures inside the former cattle station, which is larger than the Australian Capital Territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44d9c36f105074c8a972c2e3b68b1439</guid></item><item><title>Man who allegedly lied about theft of Arnie the dog facing additional charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/arnie-dog-owner-new-charges/106100342</link><description>A man who allegedly misled police over the theft of his vehicle and family pet has been charged with driving offences and obstructing police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a731900e7c083ed6bf6260ace6742a68</guid></item><item><title>Indonesian environmentalists blame rapid forest loss in Sumatra for severity of deadly floods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/why-is-indonesia-the-most-severly-affected-by-cyclone-senyar/106095614</link><description>Indonesia's government says it will summon eight companies over their suspected role in worsening the scale of floods and landslides that have killed more than 700 people. But environmental groups say authorities are hypocritical and partly to blame for the destruction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec49dde56210883e48d652a6074d6480</guid></item><item><title>Former NT administrator, musician and author Ted Egan dies aged 93</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/ted-egan-former-nt-administrator-musician-dies-aged-93/106100878</link><description>Folk music legend, author and former Northern Territory administrator Ted Egan has died aged 93.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6daba67379b08c7ea64857ac472194c</guid></item><item><title>Steve Cropper, legendary guitarist for Booker T and the MG's, dies aged 84</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/steve-cropper-dies-aged-84/106100460</link><description>Steve Cropper, was best known as the guitarist for Booker T and the MG's, but also co-wrote the classics Green Onions, and In the Midnight Hour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">950d40493d57fa69fd217c90cce415a2</guid></item><item><title>Anti-bullying review recommends making kids 'upstanders'. Does it work?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/upstanders-bullying-schools-research-jason-clare/106088358</link><description>Research suggests that actively encouraging students to be 'upstanders' to bullying may even be counterproductive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46c591942c7744cdc3303a13a113f9f0</guid></item><item><title>Global drug syndicate leader Tse Chi Lop sentenced to 16 years in prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/tse-chi-lop-sentence-drug-syndicate-leader/106100496</link><description>An international drug kingpin once described as "Asia's El Chapo" is sentenced after an "unusual" deal between a former Australian attorney-general and Dutch authorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8491997f43116a5fecdeea67280e3804</guid></item><item><title>Beer box musician, land rights champion and NT administrator Ted Egan's 'big and generous life'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/remembering-ted-egan-nt-musician-activist-bureaucrat/103438310</link><description>A former Government House occupant and a prolific author and historian, Ted Egan will also be remembered as the man who reinvented the beer box as a musical instrument.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc82942f2340d9245f3388bff950f0b5</guid></item><item><title>Why former Melbourne enforcer Nelson Asofa-Solomona chose boxing over rugby league</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/nelson-asofa-solomona-switch-from-nrl-to-boxing/106101478</link><description>Former Melbourne enforcer Nelson Asofa-Solomona reveals how he fell out of love with rugby league and turned down lucrative contract offers to pursue a career in boxing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">788ad09086ea947381aa73ead96fb640</guid></item><item><title>SA CFS volunteer sentenced for intentionally starting bushfire near Naracoorte</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/cfs-volunteer-sentenced-for-starting-naracoorte-bushfire/105665876</link><description>An 18-year-old who had been a cadet captain in the Country Fire Service admits deliberately lighting a bushfire near Naracoorte, but mental health conditions lower the sentence he might otherwise have been given.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87abb35d9a810672d5e9e1e2e928fefc</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025 updates: Australia vs England, Joe Root scores century, Mitchell Starc takes six wickets on day one of the second Test in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/ashes-second-test-live-gabba-day-one-australia-vs-england/106100550</link><description>Joe Root scores the first Ashes century of his career on Australian soil, as Mitchell Starc's 6-71 enlivens a thrilling day of Test cricket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15fdeb226de9240e8ee39f29f9f09c88</guid></item><item><title>Police offer $500k reward for information on toddler Jordan Thompson's overdose death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/reward-boosted-for-information-nsw-toddler-death-cold-case/106099936</link><description>NSW police are urging anyone with information about toddler Jordan Thompson's 2005 death to come forward as they increase the reward on offer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4479f4a0dbebcaba1ff4266c2ee6b03d</guid></item><item><title>Father of the baby bonus Peter Costello wants falling fertility rate 'back on the agenda'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/peter-costello-urges-government-to-consider-new-baby-bonus/106101512</link><description>With Australia's fertility rate at a new low and concerns about its economic impact on the future, the former treasurer behind the early 2000s baby boom says all options should be on the table to encourage more children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e14be90dc741e2d5d9a3588325c7fb1</guid></item><item><title>Government will not say if further Australian family members of Islamic State fighters on track to return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/questions-raised-over-is-family-members-return/106101260</link><description>The Coalition seizes on meeting notes from June to claim the government is working to return Australian children and partners of Islamic State fighters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d12e2cb84e15476f3a143189a3fab5a4</guid></item><item><title>Judge in trial of Rajwinder Singh, accused of Toyah Cordingley's 2018 murder, giving jury final instructions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/qld-toyah-cordingley-murder-judge-summing-up-case/106101952</link><description>The judge presiding over the trial of Rajwinder Singh, accused of the 2018 murder of Toyah Cordingley, is summing up the case before the jury goes out to deliberate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea6e21a75cfb088014fe8fed838e033f</guid></item><item><title>Confusion over when gas review will be released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/marles-reveals-the-east-coast-gas-review/106102084</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2adcde5cb3f7c4b7f6224c105a848399</guid></item><item><title>Cost of living remains a sore point for voters as political year wraps</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/anthony-albanese-election-coalition-cost-of-living-anika-wells/106087960</link><description>A mammoth year in politics ended with a focus on what is worrying most Australians ahead of Christmas: the cost of living.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3d580f2783d85343577bf467e6eefd8</guid></item><item><title>Gangster Mejid Hamzy's enemies and 'torture plot' revealed as alleged gangland assassins found not guilty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/mejid-hamzy-murder-trial-verdict/105760778</link><description>Mejid Hamzy's murder sparked Sydney's deadliest gangland war in a generation. For two years what led to his demise has been a secret.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6385b4327704482e20fa6723c3865d76</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man Michael O'Connell sentenced to 10 years in jail for manslaughter of partner Danielle Jordan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/act-michael-oconnell-jailed-for-10-years-jail-for-manslaughter/106101404</link><description>A Canberra man is sentenced to 10 years in jail for manslaughter, after the ACT Court of Appeal overturned his murder conviction for the death of his partner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2187c51bcd433d9b9008c693793aef9f</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian minister censured for withdrawing footy club funding after it attended opposition's media event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/tasmanian-minister-censured-for-withdrawing-footy-club-funding/106102352</link><description>Tasmanian parliamentarians have censured a minister for breaking his word to a local football club after it attended an election campaign media event with the opposition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a50f89df04db440581624e46b075fed5</guid></item><item><title>Behind the Lines political cartooning exhibition opens in Canberra, awarding Matt Golding the top prize</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/political-cartooning-exhibition-behind-lines-canberra/106100850</link><description>The annual showcase of the year's top political cartoons has opened at Old Parliament House in Canberra, depicting the biggest national and global events with satire and wit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c23e3a21067ae38b03c044883df0cd28</guid></item><item><title>Marles 'going through' Trump AUKUS review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/marles-going-through-trump-aukus-review/104750696</link><description>Richard Marles says the government has received the Pentagon's much-anticipated review into the $368 billion AUKUS submarine pact, reiterating Washington has been "fully supportive" of the deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7305e90130d4a320fcf796a1a72a54f0</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann sentenced in Tasmanian court for using car without consent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/bruce-lehrmann-sentenced-in-hobart-court-car-use/106101470</link><description>Bruce Lehrmann has changed his plea to guilty and been sentenced for one count of using a vehicle without the consent of the owner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecb618956a971a46261ebc510efb0805</guid></item><item><title>Calls to reinstate organ donation driver's licence scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/calls-to-reinstate-organ-donation-drivers-licence-scheme/106102290</link><description>As the Victorian government moves to bring back the driver's licence donor registration scheme, DonateLife wants it to be nationwide, saying there is clear evidence it leads to an increase in organ donors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45c70374278a437a49de2da048cec8c4</guid></item><item><title>Rare PNG conjoined twins en route to Australia as case reaches 'critical' point</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/rare-png-conjoined-twins-flown-to-australia/106096930</link><description>A rare set of conjoined twins are being urgently airlifted from Papua New Guinea to Australia, with doctors recommending they be separated as soon as possible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">284b1ab17f3fe2186516c76dd057ac88</guid></item><item><title>Brendan Kantilla sentenced to life in prison for murder of Bangladeshi student in Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/brendan-kantilla-sentenced-to-life-in-prison-for-student-murder/106099814</link><description>A Tiwi Islands man who murdered 23-year-old Bangladeshi student Md Isfaqur Rahman during a Darwin home invasion in 2023 has been sentenced to life behind bars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23cfd6be51acab0282fcad774caed4c9</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106103238</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b3e8330e565fccb72fbfead3b252309</guid></item><item><title>Alleged manslaughter victim told classmate she was 'treated like a slave' at home, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/jenni-wilmott-trial-former-classmate-gives-evidence/106102618</link><description>A girl who was allegedly criminally neglected at the hands of her mother before she died told a friend she was "treated like a slave" and was "scared to go back home", a court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">774be67b70155fe11280835620341d73</guid></item><item><title>High Court agrees to hear teenagers' challenge to under 16s social media ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/court-agrees-hear-teens-challenge-to-under-16-social-media-ban/106103338</link><description>The High Court of Australia agrees to hear a special case brought by two teenagers challenging the federal government's upcoming social media ban for Australians under 16.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01429325cf547c452cdd2ca176db7057</guid></item><item><title>Woman dies after dog attack in South Australia's upper Spencer Gulf</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/sa-woman-dies-after-dog-attack-in-whyalla/106103542</link><description>South Australian police say a woman has died after a dog attack at Whyalla in South Australia's upper Spencer Gulf region this afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e53a20862d35b0a6d3d300bb875fefa2</guid></item><item><title>Hobart’s new stadium likely go ahead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/hobart-s-new-stadium-likely-go-ahead/106103056</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de92cf69a05874e40648ad091328ed8f</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Nathan Lyon's axing leaves Australia struggling on docile Gabba pitch in second Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/nathan-lyon-axing-second-ashes-test-gabba/106103444</link><description>Australia leaves Nathan Lyon out of its XI for the second Ashes Test at the Gabba, marking an almost 14-year first.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a047be68f52e82cf4da3a71a299e58f</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with partner's murder granted bail in Darwin court, a day after extradition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/murder-accused-peter-scammell-receives-bail-darwin-local-court/106103562</link><description>Peter Scammell, who is facing a murder charge over the death of his partner Katrina Hawker five years ago, was granted bail just over 24 hours after being extradited from Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad959eba552a2c6b5ff831e97d61ab28</guid></item><item><title>Root notches century despite stunning run-out, non-Starc seamers struggle without Lyon — five quick hits from Ashes second Test day one</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/ashes-second-test-day-one-quick-hits-joe-root-run-out/106101422</link><description>Joe Root overcomes a horror mix-up to notch a long-awaited first Test century in Australia, while Australia's seamers largely struggle without the dropped Nathan Lyon. Here are the quick hits from the first day of the pink-ball Ashes Test in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a24f895f2e6e991ca803f11ce6c93550</guid></item><item><title>Hobart stadium at Macquarie Point gets final approval in parliament's upper house</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/tas-parliament-vote-approves-afl-stadium-for-tasmania/106103886</link><description>A $1.13 billion stadium on the edge of the Hobart CBD has been approved by Tasmania's upper house, satisfying a key condition for the state's AFL licence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c881f50449274ddd97789fe9d382154b</guid></item><item><title>Putin bears 'moral responsibility' for 2018 poisoning of UK woman, inquiry finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/uk-inquiry-findings-woman-2018-novichok-poisoning/106103644</link><description>A UK public inquiry concludes that Russian President Vladimir Putin "must have" ordered the Novichok nerve agent attack on Russian double agent Sergei Skripal in 2018.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ef9cac28206ecd99b86c43edee379e1</guid></item><item><title>Value of private health insurance 'eroding' as doctors urge reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/private-health-insurance-eroding-as-doctors-urge-reform/106095198</link><description>A new report from Australia's peak doctors' body says private health insurance is increasingly failing to deliver value to the roughly 15 million Australians who hold a policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">506ed9de17cafac299e52fb7051726a7</guid></item><item><title>FBI arrests suspect over pipe bombs planted ahead of January 6, 2021, US Capitol riot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/suspect-plant-pipe-bombs-eve-january-6-riot/106104160</link><description>The arrest marks the first time investigators have settled on a suspect in an act that had long vexed law enforcement and spawned a multitude of conspiracy theories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3564e38900d23b7cbe291e5bc5ab2c8e</guid></item><item><title>What does Vladimir Putin want from his state visit to India and his meeting with Narendra Modi?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/what-does-vladimir-putin-want-from-state-visit-to-india/106104162</link><description>The Russian leader's first state visit to India in nearly four years is expected to focus heavily on trade amid a backdrop of international sanctions and Donald Trump's tariff policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2dcd3e4e81b1de6f9a515dc5b6adfa8</guid></item><item><title>Israel to compete at Eurovision Song Contest in 2026, prompting several nations to withdraw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/israel-allowed-to-compete-at-eurovision-2026-prompting-boyott/106104460</link><description>Public broadcasters in Spain, Ireland and the Netherlands say they will not participate in next year's event and more are expected to follow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58b2f0f1f947dfe1f049f7fcb63a55d2</guid></item><item><title>AUKUS will survive Trump, says Australia's top diplomat in London Stephen Smith</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/steven-smith-prepares-to-leave-london-after-three-years/106103968</link><description>The trilateral agreement has come under significant scrutiny, but Australia's top diplomat in London says he believes its future is assured.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87cc7c62361d5c820c9adee8662b5b2e</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 5: How Prohibition was brought down by gangsters, bootleggers and violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/today-in-history-december-5-end-of-prohibition/105992414</link><description>Prohibition was officially repealed on December 5, 1933. But the beginning of its end can be traced back years earlier — to a highly-publicised massacre by firing squad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acabe812a0a6d147ea3eda53a2b2a0d1</guid></item><item><title>The best new TV shows of 2025, from The Golden Bachelor to The Studio</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/best-tv-shows-2025-golden-bachelor-the-studio-wayward/106074292</link><description>From a send-up of Hollywood studios to a chilling depiction of violence and masculinity to an age-appropriate reality TV romance, these are our favourite TV shows of 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e2b633a744ea39e8ec6696aeeafa789</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: Blacked-out raccoon, poor strategy call and the PM's wedding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/abc-weekly-news-quiz-december-5/106101696</link><description>Think you have had your ears to the ground? It's time to test your knowledge of the week that was.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdd649722a26f401bbd5e1addf2883f2</guid></item><item><title>Victorian prisoners held in police stations for weeks, lawyer says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/victoria-criminal-lawyer-clients-remand-held-in-police-cells/106100524</link><description>A Victorian lawyer says a "crisis" is unfolding in the state's jails, with remand centres so crowded prisoners are instead being kept in police holding cells for up to a month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">207849410ecb673d23fcc7e3fac01014</guid></item><item><title>Corowa residents caught off guard by 'early' fire a sign of 'apathy', authorities say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/corowa-residents-caught-off-guard-by-early-fire/106096104</link><description>A fast moving grass fire almost burned through the southern NSW town of Corowa last week. Despite the extreme fire danger rating, residents say they weren't prepared for such an intense fire so early in the season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be394ebe193cc2ae42522f01a2830b84</guid></item><item><title>Is Tasmanian AFL team a holy grail or poisoned chalice? Time will tell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/tasmanian-afl-team-holy-grail-or-poisoned-chalice/106100862</link><description>When it comes to the Macquarie Point stadium in Tasmania, there is clearly something deeper at play than seats, concrete and a roof. You simply couldn't vote for it otherwise, writes Chris Rowbottom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d096c0649afaa9b8188d4c18341020d7</guid></item><item><title>Search engines will soon have to blur porn image results in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/search-engines-will-soon-have-to-blur-porn-image-results/106103600</link><description>Pornographic image results will be blurred and searches for self-harm information will redirect to mental health supports under new Australian online safety codes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d02383c63601660295ab094f6471369</guid></item><item><title>Teen becomes first nationally accredited netball umpire in a wheelchair</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/brodie-taylor-wheelchair-umpire-netball/106055516</link><description>Brodie Taylor has changed the game of netball by overturning disability preconceptions to become the first person in a wheelchair to attain national netball umpiring accreditation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dad8e91985bdccf351d89b6352cf5cb3</guid></item><item><title>Industrial relations are risky business for the Liberals after WorkChoices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/liberals-industrial-relations-workchoices-unions-labor-workers/106088082</link><description>The Liberals argue Labor's industrial relations concessions to the unions are a "handbrake on productivity" but this area has been tricky for the Coalition since John Howard's disastrous overreach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ec8241dae12cdb6d8eb1b9f8047c34a</guid></item><item><title>Australia's PALM workers are leaving their employers, becoming 'extremely vulnerable' in visa limbo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/palm-worker-disengagement-new-report/106009270</link><description>Pacific Islanders have been leaving Australia's guest worker scheme, a decision that breaches their visa conditions and leaves them "extremely vulnerable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">841c80aff565d1b60279268f926fdcf6</guid></item><item><title>Israel-aligned anti-Hamas Gaza militia leader Yasser Abu Shabab killed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/anti-hamas-gaza-militia-leader-yasser-abu-shabab-killed/106104292</link><description>Gaza militia leader Yasser Abu Shabab, whose anti-Hamas group had been supported by Israel, has been killed after an attack in southern Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a039d541a2cce7a8ca74c90404a7cb33</guid></item><item><title>Lawyers to face regulators after AI was used to prepare legal document</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/artificial-intelligence-used-to-prepare-legal-document/106086724</link><description>Three lawyers will face Australian legal regulators, with one ordered to pay $10,000 in costs, after submitting a legal document prepared with artificial intelligence and found to contain "inaccurate and misleading references".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">febc0fb716abae98a48b79be40fa0dce</guid></item><item><title>Pentagon watchdog releases report on Pete Hegseth's use of Signal app</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/pentagon-inspector-general-releases-pete-hegseth-signal-report/106104450</link><description>The 84-page report finds US Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth violated policy and could have put American troops at risk when he used the Signal app to discuss military strikes in Yemen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b81f7be2d1c07cc10f66b20e47460a7e</guid></item><item><title>The Ashes are kickstarted at last by Mitchell Starc and Joe Root, but Australia's underbelly is tested</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ashes-gabba-day-one-mitchell-starc-joe-root-australia-england/106102778</link><description>A day of tough, fluctuating Test cricket kickstarts the Ashes series at last as Mitchell Starc and Joe Root carry their sides despite concerns about what lies beneath.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">226df8ba60b1cb43029c91d0a941d28d</guid></item><item><title>What is shotcrete, the material that caused Sydney's M4 tunnel closure?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/what-is-shotcrete-roof-material-sydney-m4-tunnel-closure/106102704</link><description>The issue with the commonly used substance caused delays where some motorists were gridlocked for more than four hours on Thursday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e8cb75bc69a94b8a035799e0a33f58f</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave stretches from Kimberley to Sydney as hot summer arrives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/heatwave-from-kimberley-wa-to-sydney-nsw-as-hot-summer-arrives/106102804</link><description>The burst of heat is short and sharp in southern states, sending temperatures more than 10 degrees Celsius above average and raising fire dangers to extreme, with the heat to linger into next week in the northern outback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2faa4b9ee2581ce3d2317111df449d3a</guid></item><item><title>Living with ADHD and how I make my life easier after being diagnosed as an adult</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/how-i-make-my-life-easier-after-adhd-diagnosis-personal-story/105920656</link><description>International Day of People with Disability scholar Mark du Potiers shares how attention deficit hyperactivity disorder impacts him day-to-day and what he does to make life more manageable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1ccfe4f116b86c4ddbb7dd14fdbf34a</guid></item><item><title>Impacts of working from home on mental health tracked in study of 16,000 Australians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/australian-working-from-home-mental-health-impacts-tracked/106096688</link><description>Working from home can positively impact the mental health of Australian men and women in different ways, according to a new study of more than 16,000 people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a23a31d4290c8ad43874888df90371da</guid></item><item><title>A blend of Cool Runnings, Eddie the Eagle: The Filipino curling team on the cusp of an Olympic spot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/phillippines-curling-team-channel-cool-runnings/105880680</link><description>The idea of the Philippines curling team reaching the Winter Olympics has a hint of Cool Runnings about it, while one team member, Alan Frei, has more than a suggestion of Eddie the Eagle. But at the heart of this story is a genuine sporting fairytale that is one step away from becoming an Olympic legend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8897aa2cdb4d9d98c2d32748ef874a0</guid></item><item><title>The cold supermoon will appear in the night sky tonight. Here's how to spot it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/how-to-see-the-cold-supermoon/106101342</link><description>The final supermoon of the year is set to delight stargazers tonight. Here's how to spot it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe06bd21c7eb1cda6c5df6a7292c0667</guid></item><item><title>Rheumatic heart disease cases drastically reduced in North West Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/rheumatic-heart-disease-cases-reduced-in-north-west-queensland/106099658</link><description>A lack of access to clean clothes and sheets led to high rates of heart disease in this outback Queensland town. But an Indigenous-led washing initiative is changing health outcomes in the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">513ce4de57fc29f398364fa465cc5d6c</guid></item><item><title>Manhunt underway in Adelaide for man in cuffs and hospital gown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/police-search-for-man-who-escaped-custody-at-adelaide-hospital/106104514</link><description>Police are looking for a man who escaped custody in a medical gown and handcuffs in Adelaide's western suburbs, and are warning the public not to approach him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2aafddb8873f46e1e153d0e8546074d9</guid></item><item><title>Alex Carey channels AFL pedigree for classic Ashes catch despite Marnus Labuschagne's tackle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/alex-carey-catch-marnus-labuschagne-tackles-ashes-test/106103934</link><description>Alex Carey's phenomenal catch late on day one at the Gabba would have been special all on its own, but it was made even more impressive after he had to "out-body" his own teammate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bc8c0c6309a235dfb1ac59547cac646</guid></item><item><title>South Australian golf course wetland is breeding site for locally extinct tiny native olive perchlet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/sa-golf-course-wetland-used-as-breeding-site-for-olive-perchlet/106102092</link><description>Golf courses around the world feature picturesque water ponds as a challenging hazard for players to avoid, but scientists are diving right in. They say golf club wetlands are an ecological safe haven to repopulate threatened native fish.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ee1f1543bd846b93c0d7845f74d1acc</guid></item><item><title>ChatGPT's owner OpenAI launches in Australia, partners with NextDC, ASX closes slightly higher — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/asx-markets-business-live-news-dec-5-2025/106104580</link><description>The company that brought AI into household vernacular launched in Australia today. It comes as other companies like Meta are struggling to make traction in this space.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97ffbb609f0db052123663cd504a92ec</guid></item><item><title>Local consortium races to rescue Sanjeev Gupta's Tahmoor mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/local-australian-bid-to-take-over-gupta-tahmoor-mine/106101390</link><description>A local consortium is rushing to put forward a bid for the mothballed Tahmoor coal mine, saying it wants the site reopened quickly to protect hundreds of jobs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ce422c06fcba8101b36e09ceeebfef2</guid></item><item><title>Compressed air energy storage is coming to Broken Hill, but how does it work?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/compressed-air-energy-storage-explainer/105999452</link><description>Broken Hill will be the location of Australia's first large-scale compressed air energy storage system. What is it and how does it work?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0efc28edd209486ddfa4f2a24046a67e</guid></item><item><title>Pentagon's AUKUS review finds areas to put nuclear submarine pact on 'strongest possible footing'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/aukus-review-pentagon-donald-trump-administration/105588512</link><description>The review has "identified opportunities to put AUKUS on the strongest possible footing", the Pentagon says. But a congressman who has seen the report says it "fully endorses" the pact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b23bce599e6ebbcf46142e953f6505eb</guid></item><item><title>Diners and commercial fishers to feel impact of WA demersal fishing ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/demersal-fishing-ban-impacts-food-security/106100994</link><description>New fishing rules come into effect in Western Australia next month, significantly reducing the amount of local fish available in the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cae795942ae953d26eb78b05cc38240</guid></item><item><title>Children risk life in prison for some violent crimes after Victorian parliament passes bill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/adult-time-for-violent-crime-prison-children-bill-parliament/106101956</link><description>Children as young as 14 years old could spend life in prison for some violent crimes after the Victorian parliament passed a controversial bill on Thursday. So what are the changes?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d97b0652c17c3cccbe3f44a04ec6ed8d</guid></item><item><title>F1 title contender Oscar Piastri non-committal about helping Lando Norris win in Abu Dhabi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/oscar-piastri-and-lando-norris-in-abu-dhabi-grand-prix/106104724</link><description>Oscar Piastri dodges the question of whether he might help Lando Norris lift the world F1 title in Abu Dhabi, saying McLaren has not discussed the issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7501564d8239c082852e90c9916d0fe5</guid></item><item><title>Police officer's claim about search for Lindy Lucena in Ballina tested at watchdog hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/officers-claim-about-search-for-lindy-lucena-tested-by-watchdog/106099230</link><description>A Law Enforcement Conduct Commission is examining why it took police officers nearly an hour to respond to a Triple Zero (000) call about an assault which left Lindy Lucena dead at the hands of her partner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbaff3f6e13e94a6fadefcaba28c5d4b</guid></item><item><title>Housing crisis taking a toll on caravan park owners in WA's South West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/housing-crisis-has-impact-on-caravan-parks/106051650</link><description>The housing crisis is landing at the doorstep of caravan parks and owners like Greg Homer, who says the transition from tourism operator to landlord is taking a toll.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">560e4eeca6970f98d3ab29cb9688aa64</guid></item><item><title>Zak Crawley says Nathan Lyon being dropped for second Ashes Test helped him find rhythm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ashes-2025-zak-crawley-on-nathan-lyon-being-dropped/106104822</link><description>Nathan Lyon speaks during an awkward TV interview as Zak Crawley says the spinner's omission helped the English batter find his rhythm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b8bb53a79743035f3a5a726208ac768</guid></item><item><title>Dozens of property damaged in Dolphin Sands bushfire on Tasmania's east coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/bushfire-dolphin-sands-tasmania-december-2025/106104816</link><description>There has been damage to at least 19 homes and shacks and 15 outbuildings at Dolphin Sands, on Tasmania's east coast, firefighters say, with residents told it is not yet safe to return.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7018dcf6e1fc46582fd14533b113bf14</guid></item><item><title>Country Hour reporters join listeners to celebrate 80 years of broadcasting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/country-hour-reporters-celebrate-80-years/106100556</link><description>Outside broadcasts highlight how the Country Hour connects with the daily life of rural Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd8300d14f1560b08c0a000ab75472dd</guid></item><item><title>Ed Craven's VIP gamblers club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ed-craven-vip-gamblers-club-stake-messages/106028000</link><description>Leaked messages between an Australian multi-billionaire and his former associate reveal the inner workings of the online casino Stake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3cdd1980153499e59e25072593fa403</guid></item><item><title>Police on scene at Gregory Hills shopping centre after shots fired at man outside gym</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/gregory-hills-shooting-world-gym-police/106105080</link><description>Police swam on a shopping centre in south-western Sydney after a man narrowly avoided injury after being shot at.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">002f2252717f793570a5b82a7a052a78</guid></item><item><title>Australian red-tipped bananas go viral as social media interest ramps up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/red-tipped-ecoganic-bananas-go-viral-on-social-media/106102526</link><description>Red-tipped bananas are not new to Australian consumers, but they have gone viral on social media this month after an inquisitive post from two bewildered British backpackers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96a1afa6a1c4a4e11aa62494a6c30ebb</guid></item><item><title>Socceroo Aziz Behich excited that World Cup draw could set up rematch with Argentina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/world-cup-socceroos-and-argentina-possible-draw-and-rematch/106104608</link><description>The Socceroos cannot wait to learn who their opponents will be at the upcoming World Cup, especially if it allows them to handle some unfinished business.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">379271a3ecdcd1a5d66aca938f390eb9</guid></item><item><title>US military says it killed four men in strike on suspected drug vessel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/us-military-kill-four-in-suspected-drug-boat-strike/106105538</link><description>The US military says it has killed four men in a strike on a suspected drug vessel in international waters in the Eastern Pacific</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbdd6dd3db4413394fc38b227e838592</guid></item><item><title>Fires, heatwaves strike across Australia with emergency warnings issued — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/heatwaves-fires-live-blog-december-5/106105352</link><description>A broad heatwave is expected to spread across Australia, with short and sharp bursts of heat throughout the southern states.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8394bee0a73b0d19791eaed9f5db0d97</guid></item><item><title>Paul Mescal and Josh O'Connor star in new period romance The History of Sound</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/paul-mescal-and-josh-o-connor-star-in-new-period-romance/106104586</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94990189f4920b90033ea4132b6944c8</guid></item><item><title>WA miners build up massive gold stockpiles at Perth Mint amid record prices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/wa-gold-miners-building-up-massive-holdings-at-perth-mint/106078198</link><description>WA gold miners are stockpiling millions of dollars worth of the precious metal, believing it is more valuable than cash in the current environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9d28b648dbe3d84e262e9e016a63c16</guid></item><item><title>ACT government flags bus network changes from February, fare-free summer weekend evenings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/canberra-bus-network-changes-fare-free-weekend-evenings-summer/106105054</link><description>The ACT government says the bus network will change from term 1 next year as it flags major disruption from work on Commonwealth Avenue Bridge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e665605ed81bf03eaa2bc79dede6457</guid></item><item><title>The queen of New Years Eve Casey Donovan sings This Is Me</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/the-queen-of-new-years-eve-casey-donovan-sings-this-is-me/106105632</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcf96ae53b875516a2c7a967dc73deb4</guid></item><item><title>Police say targeted search for alleged killer Dezi Freeman focused on finding his body</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/dezi-freeman-alleged-police-killer-search-victoria/106105844</link><description>Victoria Police says a targeted search has focused on locating evidence or the body of fugitive Dezi Freeman, four months after he allegedly fatally shot two police officers in Porepunkah, in north-east Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f0a9a0e7171f62c56e9dd1af0b1ccac</guid></item><item><title>All five members of 90s British boy band FIVE are back on tour after 25 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/all-five-members-of-90s-british-boy-band-/106104714</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f48d62d059c34e462424b61a1fc84b9c</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberal leader Vincent Tarzia steps down from leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/sa-opposition-leader-vincent-tarzia-steps-down/106106170</link><description>South Australian Liberal leader Vincent Tarzia will step down from the leadership, just three months out from the next state election. He told a press conference he made the decision on Friday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dc8becab9dacb49fbc7be525b654f96</guid></item><item><title>Homicide investigation launched after man killed in 'targeted attack' at Slacks Creek in Logan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/qld-man-dies-after-targeted-attack-shooting-slacks-creek-logan/106105316</link><description>Police say the 41-year-old man was transported to hospital in a life-threatening condition and was declared dead on arrival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b75a3cdba21b182c4d649367eb4c08a3</guid></item><item><title>Man from high-profile Victorian family found guilty of rape</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/guilty-rape-verdict-for-victorian-man-from-high-profile-family/106106284</link><description>A County Court jury finds a man guilty of two charges of raping a woman in his home after a night of drinking with friends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6d7820be99c971f57edb7f7cd3876cf</guid></item><item><title>Ayers Rock Resort to be sold to American-owned tourism company</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ayers-rock-resort-being-sold-ilsc-to-us-company-journey-beyond/105867822</link><description>A deal for the sale of operations at Ayers Rock Resort, near Uluru, and the Mossman Gorge Cultural Centre, in Far North Queensland, is one step closer after the Indigenous Land and Sea Corporation reached an agreement with Journey Beyond, an Australian-based "experiential tourism" company owned by an American private equity firm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6ef1a0f06a4be580e3676b070b7bf86</guid></item><item><title>What time is the F1 Abu Dhabi Grand Prix and how to watch Oscar Piastri in championship race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/how-to-watch-f1-abu-dhabi-grand-prix-oscar-piastri-championship/105995180</link><description>The Formula 1 world drivers' championship has gone down to the wire, with three drivers set to battle it out for glory at the season-finale Abu Dhabi Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efcb0dbe407a7ea6832e9d01bc0a6e0f</guid></item><item><title>Bo Popowski receives upgraded charge of murder over death of four-year-old in north-west Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/bo-popowski-murder-charge-upgraded/106105662</link><description>Bo Popowski's defence lawyer told the courtroom this was the first time he had heard the word murder used for the case and that he would need time to speak to his client.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a5c273912c2d79ef015cc407810067b</guid></item><item><title>Olympian Ian Thorpe to make his Sydney to Hobart yacht race debut on board supermaxi LawConnect</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ian-thorpe-signs-debut-sydney-hobart-supermaxi-lawconnect/106106496</link><description>Olympic legend Ian Thorpe will make his Sydney to Hobart debut in 2025, sailing aboard one of the fleet's most impressive supermaxi yachts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb44919c9824afabdc42a8255836687a</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri's journey from humble beginnings to the brink of the Formula One championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/oscar-piastri-f1-abu-dhabi-melbourne-racing/106102654</link><description>After finishing last in his first race, Oscar Piastri has risen from humble beginnings to the brink of Australian sporting history as he chases his first F1 world title.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">102f4804cb8a6644fd51e5f66e0f5109</guid></item><item><title>Victorian government defers increases to controversial emergency services levy in budget update</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/budget-update-victorian-government-jaclyn-symes-emergency-levy/106105012</link><description>The Victorian government has backed down on key parts of an unpopular tax used to fund the state's emergency services as part of its budget update.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a670b1f6d27efba52dc3ec8d3455fb1</guid></item><item><title>Will a controversial water plan lead to 'bad years' for Roper River barramundi?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/nt-roper-river-fish-barramundi-sawfish-bad-years/106096762</link><description>Documents obtained under Freedom of Information laws have revealed planned water extraction from the aquifer that feeds the Northern Territory's Roper River could lead to "bad years" for its fish populations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d7bb7831b65908d859d05539c687390</guid></item><item><title>Armed-robbery suspect dies in head-on crash with truck on Gungahlin Drive in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/two-injured-crash-canberra-gungahlin-drive-barton-hwy/106106698</link><description>Police say the driver of the car was cut from the wreck and taken to hospital but died a short time later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a3d10533ba27df3f7339c8b184e55aa</guid></item><item><title>Hot air spreading across the country.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/hot-air-spreading-across-the-country-/106107736</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ca8f455d8b3f69e9fad34fd4a337e08</guid></item><item><title>Police search for gunman after shooting at Ballajura candy shop in suburban Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ballajura-shooting-police-search-for-gunman/106106264</link><description>A search is underway for a gunman who fired shots at a store in Perth's north in what police believe was a stand-over tactic by organised crime networks involved in the sale of illegal tobacco.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e162cd4cbb9d427bfb2f200ba1409666</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025 live updates: Travis Head dropped, Marnus Labuschagne catch ends England's innings on day two of Gabba Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ashes-live-second-test-australia-vs-england-at-the-gabba/106105310</link><description>Travis Head starts swinging after being dropped by England wicketkeeper Jamie Smith, after a stunning Marnus Labuschagne catch ended England's innings on 334 on day two of the second Ashes Test at the Gabba. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e9db51099b8654b3d2221d2afdcbfc5</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire warnings issued for much of NSW as heatwave hits state</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/summer-heatwave-hits-nsw-sydney-hot-weather/106105318</link><description>The first Friday of summer sees Sydney’s temperature soar to almost 38C, with firefighters battling an out-of-control bushfires near Dubbo and Bulahdelah.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a729f54e84613e6b2b26440058e4361f</guid></item><item><title>Former Western Sydney University student charged over more cyber attacks while on bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/western-sydney-university-hacking-arrest-birdie-kingston/106105756</link><description>A former Western Sydney University student already charged with hacking into the institution's servers allegedly continued a campaign against the university by sending more than 109,000 fraudulent emails to students.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c20c3d6492378b9e45e8b92b93932b0</guid></item><item><title>Barwon Coast closes Breamlea track near Geelong after identifying asbestos-containing fragments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/asbestos-fragments-barwon-coast-breamlea-footpath-geelong-barwon/106106572</link><description>Asbestos has been discovered scattered throughout parts of a coastal town near the Great Ocean Road, prompting land managers to close a section to the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4b74efc417e2fda04fed1b6a5ca0ae5</guid></item><item><title>Six native trees poisoned along Noosa's Sunshine Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/six-native-trees-poisoned-along-noosas-sunshine-beach/106105402</link><description>Six Australian native trees have been poisoned on public land along one of Queensland's most expensive and exclusive beachside streets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e85e599f5879fce9e483dfa4f5f8d3e4</guid></item><item><title>Police return Ballarat man's stolen specialised running equipment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/stolen-specialised-running-equipment-returned-by-police/106105922</link><description>When Mick Marshall's car was stolen, he was more concerned about what was inside the vehicle than the car itself, and the training he would likely miss.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bfaf923112b802888545aaec4fcd9b7</guid></item><item><title>Israel's continued participation in Eurovision the latest in a string of contentious moments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/israel-eurovision-participation-latest-contentious-moments/106105888</link><description>Eurovision strives to put pop before politics, but it has repeatedly become embroiled in world events, particularly relating to Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9071735fa8336d50847413c7c5e2c13b</guid></item><item><title>Mother describes her grief on anniversary of her son's workplace death in the Goldfields</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/mother-of-driller-killed-in-workplace-incident-pays-tribute/106105638</link><description>The heartbroken mother of a 29-year-old man has paid an emotional tribute on the first anniversary of his death in a workplace incident, saying her grief will be "as timeless as my love".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b815b18d4e9e0856326e50128607f64</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire at Beni, near Dubbo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/bushfire-at-beni-near-dubbo/106107966</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e421c7e8c223169300828abc1321f3e</guid></item><item><title>Families of officers killed in Wieambilla attack launch court action against Queensland and NSW police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/wieambilla-families-launch-court-action-against-qld-nsw-police/106104660</link><description>The families of the two officers murdered at Wieambilla in 2022 have made personal injury claims against Queensland and New South Wales police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a9c927cebc5db135ef83efde73571c0</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate fatal hit and run in Mooroolbark overnight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/man-dies-after-being-found-on-road-in-mooroolbark-hit-run/106104626</link><description>Police believe a white SUV fatally struck a man in Melbourne's east overnight before fleeing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97b2fba91511c1b0247a48cbb89f8f3f</guid></item><item><title>Territorians urged to prepare for rolling blackouts over Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/rolling-blackouts-power-and-water-darwin-christmas/106105612</link><description>Territorians are being urged to prepare for the possibility of rolling blackouts over Christmas, after damaging winds from ex-Tropical Cyclone Fina forced the shutdown of the NT's main gas supply.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32ce32b8e961571679134d6343fa28cb</guid></item><item><title>High Court to hear appeal against reduced sentence for teenager who killed Emma Lovell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/qld-emma-lovell-appeal-high-court-australia/106107750</link><description>Emma Lovell was murdered at her North Lakes home on Boxing Day in 2022 by the then 17-year-old, who was sentenced to 14 years in prison in 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">620e83404d5c0e57120402b393feea5d</guid></item><item><title>Jury deliberations begin in trial of Rajwinder Singh, accused of murdering Toyah Cordingley in 2018</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/jury-deliberations-rajwinder-singh-trial-toyah-cordingley/106102202</link><description>The jury will retire to deliberate on the case of Rajwinder Singh, who is charged with the 2018 murder of Toyah Cordingley, after an almost four-week trial in the Supreme Court in Cairns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">234cf1baaf8461d9aadd052fcd349c94</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of killing passenger in car rollover found not guilty of causing death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/sa-veering-driver-verdict/106105238</link><description>A driver accused of killing a passenger in a car rollover captured by his own dash cam has been found not guilty of causing the death, but guilty of aggravated driving without due care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5702c1f1ac05f0c33532070c85b5390b</guid></item><item><title>Unlicensed driver hears impact of single-vehicle crash that killed three friends near Tarago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/man-sentenced-over-crash-that-killed-three-near-tarago/106104704</link><description>Nowra man Lachlan Stuckey is facing three charges of dangerous driving occasioning death over a single-vehicle car crash which killed three of his friends near Tarago in July last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">116af7e4b1262197fac451a18a16f1d3</guid></item><item><title>Vape shopfronts move online amid Qld crackdown on illegal products</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/vape-delivery-services-online-after-qld-tobacconist-raids/106106928</link><description>Paper flyers are advertising same-day delivery of illegal vapes on the Gold Coast after police forced several tobacco stores to close their doors for three months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e632b87065ee2326c664681029cc7c24</guid></item><item><title>NSW government review blames $6 billion metro cost blowout on 'funding black holes'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/sydney-metro-west-cost-blowout-to-6-billion/106107980</link><description>The cost of the new Metro West line is expected to soar over budget by $6 billion before it opens in 2032.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad74aa7ae4e3ebd4e141ab89887c8575</guid></item><item><title>Axed Australian opener Sam Konstas lands drought-breaking century for New South Wales</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/sam-konstas-century-nsw-sheffield-shield/106108598</link><description>Almost a year on from his explosive Test debut, Sam Konstas has found form to hit his first century in 14 months in the New South Wales Sheffield Shield clash with Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd385d9dc7105beb464802c4e98b6fc2</guid></item><item><title>Are you affected by the extreme heatwave sweeping through Australia? We want to hear from you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/audience-callout-extreme-heat-warning/106108490</link><description>Extreme heat and bushfire warnings have been issued in several regions across the country. Share your story along with any videos or images you may have to help inform our weather coverage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9907e4c440e6bd0b9a53a72649d6f03d</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs sports precinct could showcase Indigenous soccer players, former Manchester United star says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/gillen-oval-multi-sport-precinct-approved/106106368</link><description>The Gillen Oval Multi-Sport Precinct has been green-lit and could become a shopwindow for Indigenous soccer players, former Manchester United star and Danish international Jesper Olsen says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cb58ca83a824c5708349934831437a1</guid></item><item><title>Chevron invests $3b to continue development of the Gorgon gas project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/chevron-to-continue-development-of-the-gorgon-gas-project/106105984</link><description>The works will connect gas fields in the Greater Gorgon Area to existing infrastructure on Barrow Island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6605d42224c13ea286e827760abcd918</guid></item><item><title>Elderly Perth accountant Joseph Papalia jailed for stealing millions from friends, family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/joseph-papalia-jailed-stealing-friends-family/106108306</link><description>An elderly Perth accountant who stole nearly $10 million from family, friends and former clients is jailed for more than 11 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de8efe4100d4713e558357614abf8a48</guid></item><item><title>NSW tourist who hit woman on mobility scooter in WA's south avoids jail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/tourist-fined-for-running-over-woman-on-mobility-scooter/106108458</link><description>Paul Vallely has received a fine and had his driver's licence suspended for hitting a woman on a mobility scooter in Albany in September.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d01c9606f2cd146245b82cdf21e5e6ef</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's greyhound ban passes parliament's lower house — here's what happens now</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/greyhound-racing-legislation-passes-house-of-representatives/106090430</link><description>Legislation that lays out the phased approach to ending greyhound racing in Tasmania has passed the state's lower house and will be debated in the upper house next week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8578c44093e5303dbcaeb836bf538099</guid></item><item><title>'Cloud Dancer' named as Pantone colour of the year for 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/pantone-announces-cloud-dancer-as-colour-of-the-year-for-2026/106107764</link><description>The colour of the year has been decided by the Pantone Colour Institute, which has described it as a "lofty white that serves as a symbol of calming influence in a society rediscovering the value of quiet reflection".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdf974ac6071451de3554d57385f1069</guid></item></channel></rss>