<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 19:11:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rottnest Channel Swim organisers weigh cancellation as 55 kph winds forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/rottnest-channel-swim-threatened-cancellation-rough-seas/106363432</link><description>As thousands of people prepare to tackle Western Australia's iconic Rottnest Island Swim, rough weather is threatening to grind it to a halt just 48 hours before it begins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a39a33fd7de283d8a2e3ed71fb9cf4e</guid></item><item><title>Labor Opposition, crossbench call for NT MLA Tanzil Rahman to respond to bullying allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/nt-politicians-calling-tanzil-rahman-explain-bullying-claims-clp/106364054</link><description>An MLA accused of bullying by two female staffers is urged to front the public and explain what action has been taken following the claims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1fafc3445b2b59e5354fc437a4169aa</guid></item><item><title>American star completes comeback with figure skating gold after 'retiring' at 16</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-live-blog-day-13/106363160</link><description>Alysa Liu becomes the first American woman to win singles figure skating gold in 24 years, completing her comeback after retiring in 2022 when she was only 16 years old.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfe1fb096a25edbb2543b23f098e496e</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds commemorate the Bombing of Darwin on 84th anniversary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/bombing-of-darwin-commemorations-84-year-anniversary-esplanade/106362662</link><description>Eighty-four years after Darwin was bombed in the largest single foreign attack on Australian soil, hundreds have gathered to remember.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e51b581d2300e82c60871dc1ae74895</guid></item><item><title>Employees of Albany lolly shop fined for illegal tobacco sales say they were never paid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/illegal-tobacco-fines-albany-lolly-shop/106364808</link><description>"Vulnerable" staff at a smoke shop disguised as a candy store in Albany say they were never paid by the shop's mystery operators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">504a81865723b70dcc8bc16fa3cc618b</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/thursday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/106364470</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4c5b51e530a659b7487c6517551d5d1</guid></item><item><title>Abandoned Antarctic base is now a pollution threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/abandoned-antarctic-base-is-now-a-pollution-threat-/106365360</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49846b03030ffc2b913431f02159b7f8</guid></item><item><title>Michael Brian Becton sentenced to more than 24 years in jail for child sex offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/man-sentenced-to-24-years-in-jail-over-child-sex-offences/106365380</link><description>Michael Brian Becton, 33, is handed a 24-and-a-half year prison term after pleading guilty to 77 child sexual offences against children and babies. WARNING: This story contains details that some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">388c384c47b78f4a85d064f1750a1efd</guid></item><item><title>Former prince returns home as police investigation continues — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-epstein-police/106365802</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor has returned to his Sandringham home after being arrested and questioned on suspicion of misconduct in public office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5fc074cadfc2697a563fee6e91b29af</guid></item><item><title>Ally Hickman showed her grit at 2026 Winter Olympics after heavy fall on second run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/ally-hickman-crash-snowboard-slopestyle-2026-winter-olympics/106366350</link><description>In a Winter Olympics beset by both glory and injury, Ally Hickman's heavy fall in the snowboard slopestyle could have turned a happy day into another disappointing one. Instead, the young Aussie showed her grit to get back up and go again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a129ccb67369e26da08c0952f439ed6</guid></item><item><title>Former premier joins community calls for speed reduction at 'dangerous' fatal intersection in Newham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/community-calls-for-speed-reduction-newham-intersection-victoria/106364280</link><description>A community in central Victoria is calling for a 20 kph speed limit reduction at a "terribly dangerous" intersection after four major accidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d28bf645384eca294d072c5b45849511</guid></item><item><title>Sisters Lisa and Rachael Maza reunite on stage for the world premiere of Black Light</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/lisa-rachael-maza-sisters-black-light-malthouse-theatre/106357630</link><description>The former head of Indigenous theatre company Ilbijerri teams up with her sister Lisa for the world premiere of Black Light, which tells the story of three generations of Blak women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1799e84905988608fb42c35ca34a445</guid></item><item><title>Calls for protection of Tasmania's penguins amid reports of birds 'handled by the neck'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/people-interacting-with-tasmanian-penguins-and-harming-them/106361614</link><description>Each summer, tourists flock to Tasmanian beaches to marvel at penguins, but for some, admiring the birds from afar is not enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a8bc422a73f9012a025e072732b4fbb</guid></item><item><title>Police say 'hope is fading' in hunt for kidnapped Sydney grandfather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/chris-baghsarian-kidnapping-dural-update/106366514</link><description>Police believe they have found a "stronghold" used by the kidnappers of Chris Baghsarian in Dural as the search for the 85-year-old continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc8967c1b1d6ddfb449c5911301dc1f2</guid></item><item><title>Georgia Voll top scores as Australia beats India in second Twenty20 by 19 runs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/georgia-voll-following-alyssa-healy-footsteps-in-india-t20/106366526</link><description>The retirement of Alyssa Healy leaves a big hole at the top of the order, but Georgia Voll looks capable of stepping in after a career-best outing in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74487880f457828fe8e726b872f23c9d</guid></item><item><title>As electric car prices fall, will affordability win over drivers?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/cart-electric-vehicles-becoming-more-affordable/106348534</link><description>The price tag of EVs has been a barrier to uptake. As cheaper models hit the market, will more drivers go electric?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8e8609bc047b4700deb6c7a5c8c5aa4</guid></item><item><title>The 2026 South Australia election is here — Have your say about what matters to you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/your-say-sa/106310300</link><description>We want to know what issues matter most to you and what you want us to find out ahead of the March 21, SA election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8775ae3583b363e14b02f155e2e28dce</guid></item><item><title>Full list of 11 Australian women with ISIS links trying to leave Syria revealed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/eleven-australian-isis-brides-trying-to-leave-syria-named/106362024</link><description>The ABC can reveal the names of the 11 women connected to former Islamic State fighters in Syria who attempted to journey home to Australia this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b55cf419212aa7070f0842155fe39b42</guid></item><item><title>Voters divided as Barnaby Joyce considers contesting New England for One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/new-england-divided-over-barnaby-joyce/106353714</link><description>One Nation MP Barnaby Joyce says he might recontest his seat of New England as a candidate for One Nation if the party needs him to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8216e2cb0110f0bcd4db9bab70757914</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's arrest could end monarchy's 'never complain, never explain' mentality</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrest-a-problem-for-monarchy/106365934</link><description>British royals have lived by the adage "never complain, never explain", but these days, many of their subjects are demanding answers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69ce80bb0d80419516702662a1c32494</guid></item><item><title>Victoria Barracks is a 'jewel' in Brisbane's heritage assets — but experts say it might not be easy to sell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/victoria-barracks-sale-history/106332064</link><description>Brisbane's Victoria Barracks will go up for sale, but experts say it might not be an easy sell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dda7dc86e08382c4a4a63589de12e8c</guid></item><item><title>Wild horse art on birth certificates is 'hypocritical', says brumby welfare group</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/brumby-birth-certificate-art-outrage/106363854</link><description>A limited-edition birth certificate released to mark the Chinese Year of the Horse is being labelled "hypocritical" as a cull of wild horses continues in the NSW high country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">036d3db4d54a10ba8cdd2c50a1ae692e</guid></item><item><title>Amyl and the Sniffers singer in escalating legal battle with photographer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/amy-taylor-amyl-and-the-sniffers-court-cases-copyright/106361084</link><description>What began as a photo shoot with champagne, ice cream and humorous glamour shots of Amy Taylor, singer from punk band Amyl and the Sniffers, has escalated into a legal fight over copyright, the US Constitution and an application for a restraining order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2eecb7daec40c63d6dec04c319e48120</guid></item><item><title>Coalition willing to help stop passports for IS-linked women— as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/federal-politics-live-albanese-taylor-labor-coalition/106363700</link><description>Angus Taylor says the Coalition is willing to help the government strengthen legislation so women with ties to Islamic State are not issued Australian passports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e73f6a4c21f2ed041db318fdf5bfddfe</guid></item><item><title>More rainfall expected for parts of northern Queensland after wet week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/more-rainfall-forecast-for-northern-qld/106362726</link><description>A risk for further heavy rainfall and thunderstorms is possible in northern parts of the state today and into the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e9add29fa1f01a82340402c2e1aad56</guid></item><item><title>First NT women's prison opens in Alice Springs with focus on rehabilitation to break 'cycle of reoffending'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/first-nt-womens-prison-opens-in-alice-springs/106357580</link><description>Thirty-five female prisoners have moved into the Northern Territory's first women's prison, near Alice Springs, with more expected in the coming months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b13e3f1982f1c6fef53a91ff356eabb1</guid></item><item><title>Major US fund's credit squeeze could 'blow up' — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-friday-20-february/106366740</link><description>Shares in US asset manager Blue Owl have fallen sharply after it announced it was having challenges meeting investors' cash demands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8cfa058595f0f84f2b91273acd73f15</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says Andrew's arrest is a 'shame' for Royal family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/donald-trump-says-andrew-s-arrest-is-a-shame-for-royal-family-/106366752</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3ac836173af3ee6429afa5d754a1fc1</guid></item><item><title>Federal authorities target black flights and drug importation in Far North Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/afp-queensland-police-target-organised-crime-far-north/106366728</link><description>A joint police taskforce has been launched in Far North Queensland to target the importation of illicit drugs, forced labour and sexual servitude.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad129b09fc9d0b15be5f175dc0beddec</guid></item><item><title>Three men, one teen charged over gangland attacks linked to 'Coconut Cartel' conflict</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/matt-utai-greenacre-shooting-coconut-cartel-four-charged/106366832</link><description>The group, police allege, have been charged in relation to the shooting of ex-NRL player Matt Utai in Greenacre and a firebombing linked to conflict with the 'Coconut Cartel'.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac15045bb9b3d9c7b128070559fb5b0a</guid></item><item><title>Sam Altman and Dario Amodei refuse to hold hands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/sam-altman-and-dario-amodei-refuse-to-hold-hands/106366810</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28360275abe5f689dc70a72962b98b0f</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor released under investigation after almost 10 hours in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrested-misconduct-in-public-office/106366200</link><description>The former Duke of York has been released under investigation by British police, as officers continue to search his former Windsor home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94a6bbd07a298ae5c28f71caf5061d5c</guid></item><item><title>Bangarra Dance Theatre wins Golden Lion at international dance festival Venice Danza 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/bangarra-dance-theatre-golden-lion-venice-biennale/106366904</link><description>Indigenous dance company Bangarra Dance Theatre has become the first company and first First Nations performers to receive the Golden Lion at Venice Danza, the international festival of contemporary dance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1e2f7d948461775c920779a3628e602</guid></item><item><title>'Dying' NASA satellite leaves Australia's north waiting hours for latest fire information</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/dying-satellite-delays-nafi-fire-detections/106353398</link><description>A NASA satellite used to detect bushfires in real time across two thirds of Australia is "dying" and it could be months before a replacement is online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">816ad33b117b9b0c1f1a67a375fa58e4</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: JD Vance laments Eileen Gu's choice and Scotty James channels Wolf of Wall Street — day 13 quick hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/winter-olympics-day-13-quick-hits-eileen-gu-jd-vance/106365688</link><description>Scotty James says he is not done, while Sweden claims the entire curling world is "against us". Here are the quick hits from day 13 at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a9ff45d94aa4dfae8c06d942bbc0bcd</guid></item><item><title>Fiji, Palau and Tuvalu set to show world leaders climate change impact ahead of COP31</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/pacific-nations-set-to-host-world-leaders-on-climate-change/106366110</link><description>Fiji, Palau and Tuvalu look set to host world leaders and climate change ministers in the lead-up to COP31 in a bid to encourage larger countries to accelerate cuts to emissions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efb0153cc3ad4a4f839fc3664ed151a9</guid></item><item><title>Is it OK to feed Australia's wild birds?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/is-it-ok-to-feed-australias-wild-birds/106349168</link><description>Many of us love interacting with and feeding wild birds, but experts say giving them the wrong types of food can do more harm than good.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eec910366a2f5aeb070b335682010295</guid></item><item><title>Australian exporters could face windfall if Trump tariffs ruled unlawful by US Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/australian-exporters-windfall-over-trump-tariffs-court-ruling/106363368</link><description>Modelling by consulting firm EY Australia shows Australian exporters would be owed more than $1.4 billion in refunds collectively if the US tariffs are struck down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7de8009fd822c72acadb5cc05ff6a69</guid></item><item><title>NT cattle sector backs draft buffel grass plan as environmental and Aboriginal groups say it favours industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/buffel-grass-weed-draft-plan-groups-say-it-favours-industry/106309368</link><description>Cattle producers support the NT's draft buffel grass weed management plan, but it has attracted criticism from traditional owners and environmental groups.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f63e14c6d52852a5e04560d27f31045b</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos lose World Club Challenge to Hull KR 30-24</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/brisbane-broncos-lose-world-club-challenge-to-hull-kr/106367354</link><description>After pulling off three straight comebacks to win the NRL premiership, the Brisbane Broncos fall just short of another miracle against Hull KR in the World Club Challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">226460c361ffc36183702882e85cf411</guid></item><item><title>Indra Brown's Winter Olympics medal contention doesn't remove the reality of school homework</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/indra-brown-qualifies-2026-winter-olympics-halfpipe/106366490</link><description>Sixteen-year-old Indra Brown came into the Winter Olympics as one of the top medal contenders in freeski halfpipe — a status elevated since she finished fourth in qualification — but it still doesn't get her out of maths homework.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c99296c009f79f41a37a2c64a4d0bb1</guid></item><item><title>David James Pye found guilty of murdering former Rebels boss Nick Martin after recruiting sniper</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/david-pye-guilty-orchestrating-assassination-nick-martin-sniper/106365638</link><description>Bikie David Pye is convicted of murder after he paid a trained sniper to assassinate his former friend and ex-Rebels boss Nick Martin in front of horrified onlookers at a drag racing event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbf544938badafba7fef8c6ab33f86a3</guid></item><item><title>Commercial fishing licence buybacks recommended in latest harmful algal bloom report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/sa-parliament-report-into-harmful-algal-bloom-handed-down/106363850</link><description>Fishing licence buybacks and long-term restocking plans are some of the recommendations in the latest report into South Australia's harmful algal bloom, which has been labelled as "vanilla" by one scientist turned political candidate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d3a00e55feef726ec2f63dce3afd3b3</guid></item><item><title>Timeline of key moments leading to former prince Andrew's arrest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrest-timeline-explained/106366940</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor has for years faced allegations over his contact with Jeffrey Epstein. These key moments led to his arrest on suspicion of misconduct in public office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a2f46ab3e75e5fbccb701232eb54201</guid></item><item><title>Eric Dane, star of Grey's Anatomy and Euphoria, dies aged 53</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/eric-dane-star-of-greys-anatomy-and-euphoria-dies/106188556</link><description>The star was best known for his role as Dr Mark Sloan in long-running medical drama Grey's Anatomy, and as the patriarch of the Jacobs family in teen hit Euphoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38f5c65f82f5e42103bcfbd84e4e18ea</guid></item><item><title>WA councils could make laws to stop cats roaming under proposed state legislation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/wa-councils-could-soon-have-power-to-stop-cats-roaming/106365476</link><description>The WA government announces plans to give local councils the power to require cats to be contained to owners' properties, to protect native birds and other wildlife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9304ac0385f2634a77bf6bab016498b8</guid></item><item><title>The Board of Peace meant to rebuild Gaza may well end up as another monument to Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/donald-trump-gaza-board-of-peace-speech-leaves-questions/106367958</link><description>Unless the Board of Peace begins to focus and genuinely tries to make the world a better place, this may well prove to be yet another monument to Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19b5df8e6b47a6791635a631e37275ff</guid></item><item><title>Eileen Gu says JD Vance is 'sweet' for saying she should be competing for US at 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/eileen-gu-jd-vance-us-china-row/106367168</link><description>Eileen Gu says she is flattered that JD Vance thinks she should be competing for the US, but feels his comments are driven by an anti-China bias from Washington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d89980fb1e4f346814c87b1cd907a8d</guid></item><item><title>Parents speak at sentencing hearing for Christopher Turner over fatal gas mix-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/christopher-turner-gas-pipe-mix-up-hospital-victim-impacts/106367440</link><description>The parents of two babies given nitrous oxide in a fatal gas mix-up at a Sydney hospital almost a decade ago express their pain and trauma at the sentencing hearing for the man responsible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e2ecb02a7ac2a45488be9175b75450f</guid></item><item><title>Kyra Wheatley ready to ride the chaos and speed of ski cross at Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/kyra-wheatley-ski-cross-speed-chaos-winter-olympics/106366406</link><description>The speed and chaos of ski cross is what attracted Kyra Wheatley to the sport, and to realise a dream 12 years in the making of competing at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1a4056e5ff034ff263b9864448b4429</guid></item><item><title>Scientists model best-case and worst-case climate scenarios for Antarctica</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/antarctica-faces-devastating-impacts-under-climate-change/106354182</link><description>Scientists say parts of Antarctica face "devastating" and "irreversible" impacts from climate change unless urgent action is taken to limit greenhouse gas emissions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f426dd0a1878420ce756c07766ef447c</guid></item><item><title>How Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's 10 hours in police custody unfolded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrest-and-birthday-in-police-lockup/106367644</link><description>Ostracised by his family and stripped of his titles, Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor celebrates his 66th birthday with police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7bfb3145d616df7e291cfa8889b3a52</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on day 14</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/winter-olympics-2026-quick-guide-what-to-watch-on-day-14/106369576</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">066e1fb6ed6f781b86c77bb6a6e1fa05</guid></item><item><title>Ellyse Perry's evolution cements greatness as Australian cricket milestone looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/ellyse-perry-australia-cricket-350-matches/106369982</link><description>Cricket superstar Ellyse Perry will become the first woman to play 350 matches for Australia across all formats on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">588cdbd7c7f7eac8850144d63f6e89e7</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of performing Nazi salute at AFL exploring mental health defence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/man-accused-of-performing-nazi-salute-at-afl/106368658</link><description>Tylere Baker-Pearce, 39, was initially charged with giving the salute at the Gabba, and was later hit with two additional counts of the alleged offence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c6e6c8f054caf47133cd346d15cc0fc</guid></item><item><title>Cockroach numbers surge in Adelaide during warm, humid weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/cockroach-numbers-surge-adelaide-warm-weather/106369934</link><description>Adelaide residents have been reporting increased numbers of unwelcome six-legged visitors in their homes, but with humid weather to continue amid a flood warning for the state's north, they are likely to stick around for a while yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c04f68c974214edc09ec93b26b653fd</guid></item><item><title>Cockroaches peer out of a communications access hole in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/cockroaches-peer-out-of-a-communications-access-hole-in-adelaide/106370192</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e08605d17a90fbae10b53943eaeaeaeb</guid></item><item><title>Licence for use of antibiotic florfenicol in Tasmanian salmon industry may be suspended</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/antibiotic-florfenicol-licence-tasmanian-salmon-may-be-suspended/106370212</link><description>The federal agency that approved the use of an antibiotic for Tasmania's salmon industry has proposed to suspend that licence, in the wake of news the antibiotic has been found in native species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6c610d3b2ff6cbefab9c1f1ac62000e</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106369880</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dee6a5fc24b6baae934b701b2e8b0ec5</guid></item><item><title>SA state election polls could lead to one or no seats for Liberal Party, analyst says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/sa-state-election-polls-put-one-nation-ahead-of-liberals/106370280</link><description>Two opinion polls show fewer South Australians intend to vote for the Liberal Party than One Nation ahead of the official state election campaign period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acc64a6ce1e3c0960eff8e074cedbbdc</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand man Tamaohungia Joseph Tepatu-Edwards jailed for 26 years for attempted cocaine importation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/new-zealand-man-jailed-attempted-cocaine-importation/106368264</link><description>A man who tried to smuggle more than 800 kilograms of cocaine into WA – and was only caught when his boat broke down — will spend two decades in jail and is "likely" be deported.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe96af322e56c9cc85664c9573f21026</guid></item><item><title>Tropical low hovering over the NT</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/tropical-low-hovering-over-the-nt/106370656</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8141c64165a2ebd98542546367733e1a</guid></item><item><title>Rottnest Channel Swim cancelled due to strong winds, choppy seas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/rottnest-channel-swim-cancelled-amid-weather-concerns-/106367682</link><description>Perth's iconic Rottnest Channel Swim has been cancelled as forecast strong winds and unfavourable ocean conditions leaves thousands of swimmers and support crew disappointed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e022e3393793fa2b5ca1e4a824be305b</guid></item><item><title>Police receive 'reports of crime' in relation to Pauline Hanson interview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/police-investigation-pauline-hanson-afp-one-nation-muslim/106370420</link><description>One Nation senator Pauline Hanson accuses the government of trying to put her "back in jail", after police received reports of a crime in relation to the senator's inflammatory comments about Muslims during a media interview.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">185dd63416cc7c6d747e0e5e37316352</guid></item><item><title>Rain bands sweep over southeast Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/rain-bands-sweep-over-southeast-australia-/106370726</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8c5d0c11e93bfc68aa7690aeb9d27c6</guid></item><item><title>Norway sets Winter Olympics record with 17th gold medal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/winter-olympics-milano-cortina-day-14-live-updates/106369192</link><description>Norway breaks its own record for the most gold medals won by a nation at a single Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e17b4999cf1076ac0d1642f69ec78c68</guid></item><item><title>Trump wants federal agencies to release files on UFOs and extraterrestrials</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/trump-orders-release-ufo-uap-extraterrestrials-files/106370826</link><description>US President Donald Trump says he will direct federal agencies to begin "identifying and releasing" government files related to UFOs and aliens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b5c0aa7eb838b64e8d4652b0c2bf97b</guid></item><item><title>Dolphins defeat New Zealand Warriors in NRL trial, Jackson Ford sin-bin for hip-drop tackle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/dolphins-defeat-new-zealand-warriors-in-nrl-trial-jackson-ford/106370914</link><description>The New Zealand Warriors' hopes of having no-nonsense forward Jackson Ford on deck for their season opener are in the hands of the NRL's match review committee after he was sin-binned in a 38-34 trial loss to the Dolphins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0de161440ddef1ca126b65b0d1b14faa</guid></item><item><title>NSW Waratahs defeat Fijian Drua in Super Rugby Pacific round two, Pete Samu plays after birth of child</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/nsw-waratahs-vs-fijian-drua-super-rugby-pacific-round-two/106370446</link><description>Wallabies veteran Pete Samu has helped the NSW Waratahs to consecutive wins to start the Super Rugby Pacific season, just hours after the birth of his child.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26c7e757c5bf325353099df43d6d8f38</guid></item><item><title>Australia blows Oman away to end T20 World Cup campaign with a bang</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/t20-world-cup-australia-vs-oman-live-blog/106371016</link><description>Australia has flogged Oman, chasing down 105 in less than 10 overs to end a disappointing World Cup campaign on a high. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48a66d916c759b65504e92b5f344bd88</guid></item><item><title>Man whose girlfriend froze to death after he left her mountain convicted of manslaughter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/austria-manslaughter-after-woman-froze-to-death-on-mountain/106371008</link><description>A man who left his girlfriend to freeze to death on an Austrian mountain has been handed a five-month suspended sentence for manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">effae5ababb3ac61ba124a96f11fe003</guid></item><item><title>UK government to consider removing Andrew from succession line, as royal protection police face grilling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/royal-protection-police-to-be-grilled-over-mountbatten-windsor/106371406</link><description>The UK government is to look at removing Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor from the line of succession, an official says, as royal protection police face a grilling on "anything they saw or heard".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3493cf1504035f8670aff82102e21ef1</guid></item><item><title>Putin is betting Ukraine and the West run out of resources first</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/russia-ukraine-four-year-war-vladimir-putin/106349238</link><description>Russian President Vladimir Putin is betting that the West and Ukraine will run out of resources first.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11d7efa9b8e3b49ad2d1ac3d15d64f51</guid></item><item><title>Should Labor do its own refresh after Angus Taylor's Liberal 'rebrand'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/angus-taylor-shadow-cabinet-albanese-government/106337018</link><description>In the past few days, in a series of largely ignored milestones overshadowed by news of Angus Taylor's new frontbench, Albanese overtook Scott Morrison and John Curtin to become the 12th-longest serving prime minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">070d46246d34302a081ac085940a13ec</guid></item><item><title>Andy Griffiths, author of the Treehouse books, named new Australian Children's Laureate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/andy-griffiths-author-australian-childrens-laureate/106331360</link><description>Famous for writing stories about toilets and tree houses, the bestselling kids' author is taking on a new challenge on the national stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4faf4f52c970006ea1d74e0f15c753b</guid></item><item><title>The town that turned its back on a rape victim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/balmoral-home-town-boys-rape-divides-football-farming-town/106145646</link><description>A local footy star and his mate are convicted of raping their friend. In the tiny town of Balmoral, where the footy club reigns, the town makes it clear whose story they believe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcced53be78cf23e4251d66c753ae52d</guid></item><item><title>Heaviest outback rain in decades forecast to reach SA, NSW and Victorian farmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/widespread-rain-forecast-for-south-australia-riverina-victoria/106370362</link><description>The driest belt of Australia sees its wettest month in decades, and weather modelling tips the outback rain will reach southern Australia this weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b35300dccc79d36c4562bf0324972fa</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's future uncertain under monarch willing to let 'the law take its course'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/andrew-arrest-will-go-down-in-history-books/106367696</link><description>Like so many of the elite caught in Epstein's web, Andrew believed he would escape scrutiny for his behaviour. But it is precisely because of his name and position that his alleged wrongdoing has now delivered him into the hands of the law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">876a05a2e2317a3aa1a9f28c7c53ce70</guid></item><item><title>Why Pacific Islands are rapidly de-flagging Russia's fleet of 'shadow tankers'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/pacific-islands-flags-of-convenience-shadow-vessels/106357172</link><description>Pacific Islands are rapidly de-flagging vessels on their shipping registries after gaining international attention for their role in Russia's "shadow fleet".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f072b9260e3417979d4a703c003d41e0</guid></item><item><title>Landholders fear large-scale battery project will impact Mount Gambier housing developments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/mount-gambier-residents-oppose-blanche-battery-over-housing/106352934</link><description>Landholders call for a proposed 500-megawatt battery energy storage project to be moved amid concerns it will impact on housing developments in South Australia's second largest city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07de98d6be338d20a09b260236ad8580</guid></item><item><title>Nathan Cleary facing two-match suspension over high hit in Panthers' trial loss to Wests Tigers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/nrl-cleary-facing-ban-panthers-lose-tigers-trials-match/106371458</link><description>Nathan Cleary can accept a two-match suspension with an early plea after his high hit on Wests Tigers star Heamasi Makasini.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0688e0c927d67a68c51d9c5a5808dcf7</guid></item><item><title>Eileen Gu calls Australian teen Indra Brown 'the real deal' ahead of 2026 Winter Olympics freeski halfpipe final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/indra-brown-real-deal-eileen-gu-freeski-olympic-final/106371022</link><description>Australian teen Indra Brown's spectacular rise to Winter Olympic medal contender has been stunning to watch, but defending freeski champion Eileen Gu says it's not a surprise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df8afe984e1d68b689fa106cae234001</guid></item><item><title>At Melbourne's Mission to Seafarers, a small team keeps an invisible global workforce afloat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/melbourne-mission-to-seafarers-global-maritime-workforce/106305250</link><description>In a 109-year-old building wedged between mirrored high-rises in Melbourne's CBD, a volunteer team supports a little-known workforce that spends months at a time at sea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e44f3fdcd48ad5e31a22c51f2c67d041</guid></item><item><title>Scientists recommend succulents to protect buildings from bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/succulents-garden-for-fire-protection-bushfire-research/106362920</link><description>As bushfires become more frequent, scientists say garden beds can be a line of defence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a01f9938a43dfe2dc6ef2ca35e27e0a</guid></item><item><title>The art and origins of the courtroom sketch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/the-art-and-origins-of-the-courtroom-sketch/105817718</link><description>They're a small and curious cohort in a line of work rapidly evolving. Welcome to the world of courtroom artists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5051373d22a373be7ac83c73f3f9a4bb</guid></item><item><title>Courtroom sketch artist Rocco Fazzari draws alleged murderer Beau Lamarre-Condon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/courtroom-sketch-beau-lamarre-condon/105978588</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4a00a47ab1c26ba8adf5fd8d248e2c1</guid></item><item><title>Falcon-like drones take to the skies to protect almond and fruit crops</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/falcon-like-drones-take-to-the-skies/106363828</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">889a8f1fc8719f7986113f12fd003021</guid></item><item><title>Peregrine falcon drone could save Australian fruit and almond orchards from hungry birds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/robird-peregrine-falcon-drone-to-scare-birds-from-crops/106105572</link><description>A new falcon drone wards off peckish birds that have been destroying valuable fruit crops.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ad160c79a85d52dff1c43c429b91f7d</guid></item><item><title>Peter Malinauskas is heading for a landslide win in SA. How crushing a victory will it be?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/sa-election-lots-to-learn-despite-predicted-labor-landslide/106363808</link><description>Even if it's a Labor landslide, we'll learn a lot from next month's South Australian election, writes Casey Briggs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2475f1de36b7f53be3206611dfb848d</guid></item><item><title>Manchester United owner Jim Ratcliffe avoids sanctions after saying UK has been 'colonised' by immigrants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/football-man-united-owner-not-charged-colonised-call-ratcliffe/106371480</link><description>Jim Ratcliffe is reminded of his responsibilities as a participant in English football but is not handed any penalties from FA after his controversial call.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69bf802509648780c979dcba937fb0a8</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's arrest shows money talks louder than women's testimony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrest-jeffrey-epstein/106349250</link><description>Why is an email about the trade trip apparently more compelling than the detailed and painful evidence of a woman?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c126708b2400a064fec41430e0ad12c1</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder after mother of three struck by car in Reservoir in Melbourne's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/vic-reservoir-man-charged-with-murder-after-woman-struck-by-car/106371534</link><description>Police and paramedics were called to Reservoir on Friday evening following reports of a woman being hit by a car.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e6e60106e731c07622ec60829c81b8f</guid></item><item><title>Farmer's hands-off approach creates unusual lamb with distinct flavour chefs say is like nothing else in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/braidwood-farmer-new-lamb-cooked-local-restaurant-expat-chefs/106358970</link><description>When Frank was forced to sell the sheep he'd been farming for more than 20 years, something had to change. His "experiment" is helping expats feel at home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">193e31303ed2bfa342879871031db171</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Lindsey Vonn goes 'bionic' as the curling war of words continues — day 14 quick hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/winter-olympics-day-14-quick-hits-curling-barb-lindsey-vonn/106370974</link><description>Swedish curler Oskar Eriksson hits Canadian nemesis Marc Kennedy with his most devastating barb yet as Lindsey Vonn shares an update on her recovery. Here are the quick hits from day 14 at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e305a380a102e8649ea935e7dd6ce29</guid></item><item><title>Cattle tick outbreak raises questions over Queensland's biosecurity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/tick-outbreak-raises-questions-over-queenslands-biosecurity/106367970</link><description>Queensland is known for its hardline biosecurity stance against foreign pests, but farmers say a recent cattle tick outbreak has exposed systemic weaknesses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11798db4c4a29dca21b6773386e53cb7</guid></item><item><title>Americans fearing death of democracy see a glimmer of hope in the Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/supreme-court-tariff-decision-confirms-democracy-isnt-dead/106371496</link><description>Until now, Donald Trump has been one of the most unstoppable presidents ever. But the Supreme Court's tariffs decision proves there are limits to his power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d596259cf551d1d1afc79b3621e90f2d</guid></item><item><title>North Queensland on high alert as deluge continues and rivers rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/large-parts-of-queensland-on-high-alert-as-heavy-rain-continues/106367672</link><description>Flooding is likely to become more widespread in northern and western Queensland over the next few days, with further heavy rainfall and road closures expected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b0a1461ea9964b523d17ba2f1d2a90d</guid></item><item><title>Daly River flood evacuees to return home after more than two weeks in Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/nt-daly-river-evacuees-returning-home-after-flood-emergency/106368994</link><description>After spending more than a fortnight sleeping at a Darwin evacuation centre 220 kilometres away from their flooded community, bus loads of Daly River locals are set to return home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2098d8f0591a5fe0f965b8e16635f308</guid></item><item><title>Bayern Munich coach Vincent Kompany says José Mourinho made 'huge mistake' attacking Vinícius Júnior's character after alleged racist insult</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/football-kompany-criticises-mourinho-over-vini-jr-racism-call/106371656</link><description>Bayern Munich manager Vincent Kompany dissects the racism row involving Real Madrid and Brazil star Viní Jr with a passionate 12-minute speech.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">612aa3df4ab705ac95b277d2f9bcadb5</guid></item><item><title>Lavender growers say watered-down oil imports are pricing them out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/lavender-oil-imports-pricing-local-growers-out/106308156</link><description>Despite an Australian lavender industry dating back to the 1850s, you're more than likely using an imported and "watered-down" product, local growers say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e706f0f5677eaf283fac61a73d10ba9e</guid></item><item><title>Herby potato salad with green beans and tuna - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/herby-potatoes-with-green-beans-and-tuna/106252480</link><description>Turn a potato salad into a tasty meal with pantry staples and fresh greens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bf3639cafb3b89fadd2f76dbfd84322</guid></item><item><title>Opposition does its best to land blows on WA government in parliament's first week back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/wa-parliament-week-one-analysis-basil-zempilas-roger-cook/106365878</link><description>Housing, health and household stress — that's what WA's opposition leader says he's focused on in 2026 as he and his party face an uphill battle against the state government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56f1332a78e625f94d5312f5b9b52fd4</guid></item><item><title>Why economists hate low unemployment for inflation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/why-economists-hate-low-unemployment-for-inflation/106367852</link><description>The theory goes that if you have just the right amount of workers on the unemployment scrap heap, you can keep inflation in check. The problem is that no-one knows exactly what the magic unemployment rate is.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43e029d93818ef09b173d99095546fef</guid></item><item><title>Two teenage boys killed in fatal car crash at Crabtree, in Tasmania's Huon Valley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/double-teen-fatality-in-southern-tasmania-crash/106371746</link><description>Flowers have been laid for two teenage boys who died in a single vehicle crash in Tasmania's Huon valley overnight, with three others taken to hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04a217818d8de71afce27b22293179fd</guid></item><item><title>Women and children in Syrian camp "will end up in Australia" | Insiders On Background</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/insiders-on-background-abul-rizvi/106370578</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">429933e5b0b8244f26a5c83a2eef8995</guid></item><item><title>Potential release of carp control virus into waterways delayed until 2028</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/national-carp-control-plan-decade-delay-carp-herpes-virus/106348408</link><description>Release of a virus to control carp in Australian waterways has been delayed until 2028, a decade after it was initially slated for release.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dbde53e8280f083aef35066d7c03374</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with hate crime after allegedly ramming Brisbane synagogue with ute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/brisbane-synagogue-rammed-man-charged-hate-crime/106371834</link><description>It's alleged the 32-year-old rammed a ute into the gates of the Brisbane Synagogue on Margaret Street on Friday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">560aa622bfc80adf305756789d41b300</guid></item><item><title>Teagan Micah forced out of Matildas' Asian Cup campaign as concussion issues continue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/matildas-teagan-micah-out-of-asian-cup-concussion/106371804</link><description>Teagan Micah's horror run with concussions continues as she reveals she will miss the Matildas' upcoming Asian Cup campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbcf7ae7402006cdd468aa9c66f144ee</guid></item><item><title>How Reuters captured that photo of former Prince Andrew leaving custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/how-reuters-captured-the-photo-of-former-prince-andrew-leavi/106371770</link><description>The image, taken by Reuters photographer Phil Noble, went viral when it was published on Thursday. He says capturing the moment came down to a tip-off and more than a little luck.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23d31204491246cc184daea89e905d39</guid></item><item><title>I had a miscarriage over the summer. It was nothing like I expected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/miscarriage-loss-grief/106308830</link><description>My understanding of miscarriage was built on a handful of Hollywood representations and snatches of stories I'd read. Outside of this, I had few reference points.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a18951e43e4efa639be7b2845bc9d57e</guid></item><item><title>A 'return to craft' for the NT's award-winning young artists showcased at this year's Exit Art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/nt-exit-art-exhibition-return-to-crafting-darwin-gallery-museum/106368426</link><description>Almost a dozen high school-aged artists have received awards as part of a prestigious Northern Territory showcase, with a number of finalists exhibiting self-portraits.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ed4262d4757e1158f4f7f9fb3c9f716</guid></item><item><title>Concerns over death of iconic salmon gums in WA's Great Western Woodlands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/concerns-over-tree-deaths-great-western-woodlands/106355300</link><description>Kalgoorlie horticulturalist Phil Stanley says he is struggling to get authorities to take the deaths of more than 100 salmon gums near the mining city seriously.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cef65ddf1756cc101cb4a0d10888de3f</guid></item><item><title>Adam Zampa says claims Australia does not care about T20 cricket 'totally false' after World Cup flop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/cricket-zampa-defends-australia-t20-prep-world-cup-exit/106371894</link><description>Adam Zampa hits back at claims that Australia does not care about T20 cricket after a disappointing World Cup campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47ff9ce19c56b6ba685a684eb3b125df</guid></item><item><title>How a window opened for IS-linked Australians to leave Syria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/how-a-window-opened-for-is-linked-australians-to-leave-syria/106368348</link><description>After holding a large swathe of autonomous territory that included two detention camps, Kurdish-led forces are now reluctantly handing over control to Syrian government forces, following their successful military offensive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79af036f525934cd4e37d746768f51d7</guid></item><item><title>The shamans and designer handbags before Yoon Suk Yeol's insurrection conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/the-scandalous-downfall-of-yoon-suk-yeol/106358072</link><description>Former South Korean president Yoon Suk Yeol's sentence for insurrection comes after a tumultuous era of shamanism, Chanel bags and conspiracy theories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c392edec639f36481f4ec7269ef84031</guid></item><item><title>How a Belgian techno producer with some old synthesisers has reimagined Terminator 2</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/terminator-2-new-score-hear-my-eyes-mess/106369562</link><description>Terminator 2: Judgment Day is getting the live score treatment, but not in the way you might expect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">689c4da252c634c2c4554ed5d31bba80</guid></item><item><title>NASA boss blasts Boeing and agency over bungled test flight that left astronauts stranded on space station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/nasa-report-reveals-starliner-mission-failings/106371706</link><description>A bungled Boeing mission that left two astronauts stranded on the International Space Station for nine months has been criticised by NASA's new boss.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3928101430826cc338efc88bfa7afd86</guid></item><item><title>Drugs with estimated street value of $1.45 million seized in traffic stop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/nabiac-traffic-stop-leads-to-drug-seizure-police-say/106372078</link><description>A traffic stop on the Pacific Highway on the NSW Mid North Coast has led to the seizure of hundreds of thousands of dollars' worth of cocaine and cannabis, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52ce47c8e206ebeeccdec73dced1e56e</guid></item><item><title>Farmer builds chapel for Tongan workers, the 'backbone' of her banana farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/lakeland-chapel-tongan-workers-palm-scheme-queensland/106362494</link><description>A Queensland banana farmer spent 10 years saving to build a chapel for the Tongan workers who form the backbone of her family’s operation on Cape York Peninsula.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9129d4087a3dedd75e8c65e58a866cf</guid></item><item><title>The US Supreme Court's take-down of Trump's tariffs explained</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/explaining-the-us-supreme-court-takedown-of-trumps-tariffs/106372118</link><description>The ruling on tariffs is a hugely consequential decision that has infuriated the president, who is now looking for workarounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d66c597b8db50bd67f75d00125911020</guid></item><item><title>Punch the baby macaque draws a crowd at Japan's Ichikawa City Zoo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/punch-baby-macaque-japan-zoo-soft-toy-orangutan/106371376</link><description>The six month old macaque's relationship with a soft toy orangutan has become an internet sensation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76354b2a83722acb0b827836893c9d71</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on day 15</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/winter-olympics-2026-quick-guide-what-to-watch-on-day-15/106372058</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f86a080ae9e7d9178bbe13efe477941</guid></item><item><title>Formula 1 preseason testing: Ferrari has a rotating rear wing, Red Bull, McLaren and Mercedes show pace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/f1-preseason-test-bahrain-ferrari-red-bull-mclaren-mercedes/106370550</link><description>Preseason testing for the new Formula 1 season ends in Bahrain, with teams not putting their cars on a track until the first practice session of the Australian Grand Prix weekend on March 6.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0558efd2ad2bea9a138b21ff74317c2</guid></item><item><title>Rottnest Swim cancellation prompts dozens to descend on Perth pool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/team-saba-takes-rottnest-swim-to-bold-park-swimming-pool/106371972</link><description>Weather may have derailed the main event, but some swimmers were determined to complete their own version of the Rottnest Channel Swim in the name of charity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad37267373fc428efc986e0b1c03c7b0</guid></item><item><title>Auckland FC defeat Wellington Phoenix 5-0 in A-League Men, goalkeeper Josh Oluwayemi own goal begins rout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/auckland-fc-defeat-wellington-phoenix-5-0-in-a-league-men/106372300</link><description>Wellington Phoenix goalkeeper Josh Oluwayemi commits one of the worst howlers this A-League Men season, heading a clearance kick into his own net as Auckland FC romps to a big win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c520681fd47bae4fe6c8395992f4c0c7</guid></item><item><title>South Australian election countdown officially begins, campaign kicks off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/south-australia-election-2026-campaign-begins/106371978</link><description>Election campaigning in South Australia is officially underway, with candidates seizing the opportunity to begin making their formal pitches to voters before they head to the ballot box in March.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9242c102760eb4813ef7943f0f70998b</guid></item><item><title>Walker and Reddingius create Aussie Olympic bobsleigh history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-day-15-live-updates/106369762</link><description>Bree Walker and Kiara Reddingius achieve Australia's best Olympic result in two-woman bobsleigh, as teenager Indra Brown is forced to wait for her chance to compete for a medal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33411d877244b39dedeca2c7ac9dd8b0</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout sets another record with 10-second 100m sprint in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/gout-gout-sets-another-record-with-10-second-100m/106372384</link><description>Australian sprinting sensation Gout Gout comes perilously close to breaking the 10-second barrier, with another eye-catching run in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f819100df65bcd7e882e251d29a23826</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong offers buy-out scheme for owners who lost homes in last year's deadly apartment fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/hong-kong-fire-buyout-wang-fuk-court/106372476</link><description>After a deadly Hong Kong fire that killed 168 people and left thousands homeless in November, authorities have announced a buy-out offer for owners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55f16056969c0e2085dce62a54afd956</guid></item><item><title>Hungary and Slovakia threaten Ukraine over stalled Russian oil shipments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/hungary-and-slovakia-threaten-ukraine-russian-oil/106372526</link><description>Hungary and Slovakia, which have both received a temporary exemption from an EU policy prohibiting imports of Russian oil, have accused Ukraine of deliberately holding up supplies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e8c5eda8272aceae2a467ae014b516a</guid></item><item><title>Danielle Scott, Cooper Woods named as Winter Olympic Games closing ceremony flag-bearers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/dani-scott-cooper-woods-winter-olympics-closing-ceremony/106372970</link><description>Two of Australia's 2026 Winter Olympic Games medallists, Cooper Woods and Danielle Scott, will carry the flag at the closing ceremony in Verona.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a62fd84bff8ab78237038f75ef184296</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government bears inflation pressure while premiers spend big, poll well</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/albanese-government-premiers-peter-malinauskas-david-crisafulli/106349260</link><description>High-spending premiers remain popular and seemingly impervious to the rising cost-of-living anxiety piling pressure on the Albanese government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0ff2d992e25fd6ee865c92e0a78f4e5</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Think you're a trivia boss? Show us what you've got</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/106366918</link><description>Well, this is cute — you thinking you're a quiz pro. It's time to play … HARD!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa1afae586e91600568a748b64e08b37</guid></item><item><title>On the frontlines of Australia's fight against vaccine hesitancy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/australia-vaccine-hesitancy-fight-restore-confidence/106353012</link><description>With immunisation rates declining and outbreaks of infectious diseases like measles increasing, the consequences of vaccine hesitancy in Australia are becoming clearer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8359da5691e58e050b22964baecf814e</guid></item><item><title>Bridgerton's Yerin Ha is living her own Cinderella story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/bridgerton-season-four-part-two-yerin-ha-interview/106363336</link><description>Yerin Ha built a name for herself in local and international productions for almost a decade before transforming into Bridgerton's newest paramour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99b5fbc19663ba58a0fb1032c0e7fedf</guid></item><item><title>More assault allegations surface against footballers in tiny town of Balmoral</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/hometown-boys-culture-of-football-misogyny-called-out-balmoral/106358784</link><description>More women come forward with allegations of sexual assault in a small Victorian town, years after a rape victim was shunned by the town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e4baf80ef8954cf91ddfdc29c6843b8</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor was the Queen's rumoured favourite. Did she do too much to protect him?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/queen-elizabeth-former-prince-andrew-and-epstein/106371728</link><description>It will be up to King Charles to shepherd his family's institution through its darkest hour. But could his own mother have done more to snuff out this crisis before he inherited it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75d2f85e2faea6fba90af13bf1129d78</guid></item><item><title>Predator Jeffrey Epstein used promises of university scholarships and modelling contracts to lure victims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/how-epstein-lured-girls-using-university-and-modelling/106320804</link><description>Admission into elite universities. A job that promised travel around the world. An audition for Victoria's Secret. This is how Jeffery Epstein lured his victims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a152c09ebc56da809bd762fe0027283</guid></item><item><title>A visual guide to the prices that landed Coles in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/coles-grocery-pricing-down-down-accc-court/106355492</link><description>The pricing patterns of these six products show how Coles stands accused of using its Down Down marketing campaign to dupe shoppers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6972c0ae544a3d055ce6b66632f8a24d</guid></item><item><title>Scammers fleeced pensioner Ian Williams out of $1,338. So he sued his bank for $379 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/ian-williams-on-why-he-sued-nab-bank/106093720</link><description>Ian Williams has brought a whole new meaning to "taking on the big guy". When scammers stole from the pensioner the bank blamed him. So he launched a $379 million lawsuit to "make it right".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93fea5943f6595243ac093002bc3773d</guid></item><item><title>The Miracle on Ice, when an unheralded USA team knocked off the mighty USSR</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/miracle-on-ice-usa-vs-ussr-ice-hockey-lake-placid-winter-olympic/106287402</link><description>On this day in 1980, a group of American students pulled off the most unlikely of victories, beating the greatest team in international ice hockey history in the upset of the century. Some even called it a miracle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f4d5cb63c8a8a13d65063f95b599cf7</guid></item><item><title>Doctors race through Kyiv missile strike to deliver child's donor heart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/ukraine-doctors-operate-under-attack-heart-surgeons-todurov-kyiv/106352796</link><description>Kyiv surgeons who drove through a massive missile strike to deliver a child's donor heart say they will stop at nothing to save lives — even when under attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11ce04a812127cad5b64ddbea55f999a</guid></item><item><title>Coastal communities weigh costs and potential retreat as erosion batters SA's Limestone Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/beach-communities-battling-coastal-erosion-costs-south-australia/106349638</link><description>With costs and damage mounting, councils are considering all options, including pulling back from the beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">358ed68ef9f52813ec32ea720e241852</guid></item><item><title>Bureau of Meteorology says Warrnambool recorded its hottest day ever but locals aren't convinced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/warrnambool-weather-station-location-bom/106349068</link><description>Can a weather station that is 10 kilometres away from a coastal town centre give an accurate forecast? These locals think not.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9492e6e47531283737e94c93b98be267</guid></item><item><title>Australian underdogs edged out of mixed aerials team medals at 2026 Milano Cortina Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/mixed-aerials-team-near-miss-2026-winter-olympic-games/106373012</link><description>Australia goes desperately close to an underdog medal in the mixed team aerials competitions at the 2026 Winter Olympic Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2135bddd8ebe93c8e517a13b729792e</guid></item><item><title>India claims series win over Australia in Ellyse Perry's historic 350th international match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/cricket-perry-milestone-ruined-india-beats-australia-series/106373140</link><description>There is no fairytale for Ellyse Perry in her 350th international match as Smriti Mandhana stars to lead India to a series win over Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22813ee6d5f524e54f265a57bbca0060</guid></item><item><title>SA Labor mulls One Nation's rise as Liberals fight for campaign oxygen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/peter-malinauskas-aged-care-comments-analysis/106365716</link><description>In the final week before the election writs were issued, the SA Premier trained his sights on One Nation while the Liberals fought for oxygen. Is it a sign of the campaign ahead?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28d074d0aa52fc3f4a0dea405c714d5a</guid></item><item><title>Daly Cherry-Evans and Sam Walker show promising signs as Eels down Roosters in NRL trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/nrl-cherry-evans-walker-combine-roosters-beaten-eels/106373172</link><description>Daly Cherry-Evans shows immediate signs of a strong combination with new Roosters halves mate Sam Walker in his first match for his new NRL club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">652b9b70e5dcf7d760e9ffc868488ab3</guid></item><item><title>Cawleys Bridge retrofit reconnects wildlife habitat above Princes Motorway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/cawleys-bridge-wildlife-crossing-retrofit/106365756</link><description>A forgotten bridge over one of the busiest commuter routes in NSW is being reborn as a safe crossing for wildlife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27a82b14a4be74352a28c842f1958ec0</guid></item><item><title>After 20 years as the only town listed on the NSW State Heritage Registry, Braidwood is at a turning point</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/braidwood-nsw-heritage-listed-town-turning-point-future/106362514</link><description>A walk along the main street of this town is stepping in the footsteps of bushrangers, movie stars, artists and migrants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d656e7e9b2917ee3f3461fd7337804e</guid></item><item><title>Farmers on tenterhooks as trade deal with the European Union edges closer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/farmers-anxious-about-imminent-european-union-trade-deal/106348868</link><description>Australia is on the cusp of signing a landmark free trade deal with the EU, but will it come at a cost?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82cfad3ff6256c29ffde29e8e2faf1ba</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Wild Livigno weather puts Indra Brown's medal tilt on hold — day 15 quick hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/winter-olympics-day-15-quick-hits-blizzard-indra-brown-livigno/106372510</link><description>Indra Brown's medal tilt is put on hold as a horror bobsleigh crash and wild weather rock day 15. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79fbdd8b9c884446c2092272f8288188</guid></item><item><title>Johannes Høsflot Klæbo becomes first athlete to win six gold medals at one Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/winter-olympics-h%C3%B8sflot-kl%C3%A6bo-gold-medal-record/106373216</link><description>Johannes Høsflot Klæbo adds to his legacy as the greatest Winter Olympian of all-time by winning his sixth gold of these Olympics and 11th overall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">510c61228b9a195419d4335632366049</guid></item><item><title>Police scour Glenorie property as part of search for kidnapped grandfather Chris Baghsarian</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/police-operation-glenorie-hunt-kidnapped-chris-baghsarian/106373224</link><description>Police conduct an operation at Glenorie, a suburb near a house which investigators believe Chris Baghsarian's captors had used as a base.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7292f898f776bccee02202837ea51c90</guid></item><item><title>Lighthouse keepers' cottages on Pine Islet to be demolished by reef authority</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/lighthouse-keepers-cottages-on-pine-islet-to-be-demolished/106368846</link><description>The remnants of a lighthouse station close to 100 years old on an island off the Mackay coast are set to be dismantled due to asbestos concerns, sparking fears important history will be lost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14976cd654b70d0078ff8d722e349265</guid></item><item><title>Massive goat trap in remote WA merges new technology and old ideas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/nine-kilometre-feral-goat-trap-murchison-station/106368604</link><description>When their station's fragile landscape needed protection from feral goats, Calum and Belinda Carruth seized on an idea that has become marvel of technology and pest management.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e4dab5480ecabc73e64d29b22876250</guid></item><item><title>Punk's boom began 50 years ago in Brisbane — and the scene is still thriving</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/50-years-of-punk-brisbane-the-saints-im-stranded/106363856</link><description>The Saints released their single "(I'm) Stranded" in 1976, kicking off the punk movement in Australia. So how did it all unfold?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ff7aba07da49374830b95165bce08cb</guid></item><item><title>SA Water to run Coober Pedy network in bid to bring down high water bills</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/sa-water-to-run-coober-pedy-network-lower-bills-expected/106367312</link><description>SA Water will take over the decrepit water infrastructure in Coober Pedy, where burst pipes have led to residents paying some of the highest water bills in the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bf3d23b1649bc1b1eb3438ed4925e51</guid></item><item><title>Bodies of nine back-country skiers recovered days after California avalanche</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/california-skiers-bodies-recovered-after-avalanche/106373320</link><description>The bodies of nine back-country skiers killed in a California avalanche four days earlier are recovered, following a harrowing operation hindered by intense snowfall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39af55e600ea9a9ea051ed5cd995ea77</guid></item><item><title>Miner MMG puts forward alternative Rosebery tailings dam site in Exe Valley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/tailings-dam-new-approach-from-mmg/106372128</link><description>Global mining company MMG has long been seeking to build a third tailings storage dam at its mine on the Tasmanian west coast, in the face of strong opposition from environmentalists. It's now put forward an alternative which conservationists say they won't fight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aaf7bb61abe5724fd547643fb34b7f0e</guid></item><item><title>Regional WA courthouses given new life with unlikely tenants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/courthouse-florist-gym-new-purpose/106144602</link><description>Two regional towns in WA's Wheatbelt have breathed new life into their heritage courthouses, with unlikely tenants inside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9c6cd80edf57e10dd3f78727829a7c7</guid></item><item><title>UK passport changes leave Australians with dual citizenship scrambling before border rules kick in</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/uk-passport-changes-dual-citizenship-scramble/106358092</link><description>There's been a last-minute scramble for some Australians with dual British or Irish citizenship, as new UK border rules come into force within days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0132530ce764a5648b973f42e492ac9f</guid></item><item><title>What is the bare minimum when it comes to packing kids' lunch boxes?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/easy-ways-to-pack-a-nutritious-healthy-school-lunch-box-/106358546</link><description>This is the bare minimum you should aim for to cover the nutritional basics for your children's school lunches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f3a4974aba1f9fb1b9b53bdb3f9662c</guid></item><item><title>Rap program aims to reduce reoffending among young people in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/prison-rap-workshop-reduce-reoffending/106367348</link><description>The musical genre is helping young offenders at a juvenile detention centre in southern NSW find their voices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">495a5e078b7fbe73bfa1d3968a35bef1</guid></item><item><title>British nuclear-powered attack sub HMS Anson arrives in Perth for training exercises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/british-nuclear-powered-submarine-in-australia/106372406</link><description>The two countries are expected to conduct AUKUS pillar 2 tests while HMS Anson is within Australian waters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcd35ae02a7adc2003fb98aad3a002ce</guid></item><item><title>Child psychiatrist Benjamin Wen indecently touched boys while doing 'puberty checks', court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/benjamin-wen-aaron-voon-trial-indecent-dealing/106370582</link><description>A former child psychiatrist who changed his name after being convicted of child exploitation touched young neurodivergent boys indecently at his practice, a Perth court hears. WARNING: This story contains details that may distress some readers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc7200b0badd5692276a5f2501ebaa54</guid></item><item><title>Eating disorder clinic to open near Mandurah as frustration grows over residential facility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/eating-disorder-clinic-to-open-near-mandurah/106371852</link><description>As an eating disorder clinic prepares to open its doors near Mandurah south of Perth, a residential eating disorder clinic is still in the planning stages despite being on the cards for years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2d5ed404ab21a793c92326ae065626b</guid></item><item><title>Minister reveals process has started to ban Hizb ut-Tahrir under new hate laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/minister-reveals-process-has-started-to-ban-hizb-ut-tahrir/106373384</link><description>Tony Burke has also provided an update on the cohort of 34 Australians seeking to leave a Syrian refugee camp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c92753a52307b8887ca37f5a769a82c</guid></item><item><title>Inside the trend of renovating old churches on the Darling Downs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/old-queensland-churches-transformed-into-houses-galleries/106326094</link><description>A small timber church built in 1917 is at the centre of a growing trend reshaping the future of regional sacred spaces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b26befc6307565c40a577a8f1cd21ce7</guid></item><item><title>Alisa Camplin-Warner calls for more funding after historic 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/australia-winter-olympics-2026-more-funding-alisa-camplin/106373014</link><description>Australia's chef de mission Alisa Camplin-Warner says the successful team deserve more funding for future Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f2634dfe4b1f91b79a479b5888bf5d3</guid></item><item><title>What the Bad Bunny in Australia tour means for Puerto Ricans far from home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/bad-bunny-australia-sydney-puerto-rico-live-concert-latino/106333062</link><description>This weekend Bad Bunny offers Australia a lesson in community, identity and how to belong without diluting your true self.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a17020b4ce51c2572315a7851d6ffd5</guid></item><item><title>Great-grandmother's garlic mushroom artwork puts new spin on managing food waste</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/wa-artist-turns-garlic-stems-old-teabags-into-art/106221554</link><description>Meet the country artist putting a slightly unexpected spin on garlic mushrooms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14ba8dc8bb3072d0a4f0467157374b25</guid></item><item><title>First Nations leaders call for federal treaty and truth-telling to follow Victoria's lead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/call-for-federal-treaty-truth-telling-victoria/106372296</link><description>First Nations leaders, Elders and advocates are urging the federal government to commit to a national treaty and truth-telling process, labelling some states as "hostile" to the notion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">206bdc1de0ff525ae3370a726f77bdfd</guid></item><item><title>After a rare Supreme Court loss for Trump, here's his record with the bench</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/rare-loss-for-trump-before-the-supreme-court-his-record/106004520</link><description>Donald Trump was furious when the US Supreme Court ruled that his use of tariffs was illegal. Here's how earlier cases in that jurisdiction have fared.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2df862b3b607bed8e4ebdf16a4c5baec</guid></item><item><title>ABC voices from the past look to its bright future on 102.5FM.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/abc-voices-from-the-past-look-to-its-bright-future-on-102-5fm-/106370648</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">878b04a93fa99b8f45e82f52ad3deb6b</guid></item><item><title>The core of ABC radio will remain the same</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/core-of-abc-radio-to-remain-the-same-/106372496</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdc339520926452f4ede7fbcd38a78c1</guid></item><item><title>Migraine is more than just a headache. A neurologist explains the four stages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/four-stages-of-migraine/106365424</link><description>Knowing the four distinct phases of a migraine can help you recognise the symptoms and manage pain at each stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ab8f383b80c8679ec99c0a724d8a937</guid></item><item><title>Rescue operation carried out after multiple boats capsize during Bellerive Regatta</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/multiple-boats-capsize-at-bellerive-regatta/106373620</link><description>A gust of wind caused at least eight boats to capsize in the River Derwent during a race.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a69b46f0c607356de805361f316c3f02</guid></item><item><title>Why has Donald Trump issued Keir Starmer a warning about the Chagos Islands?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/chagos-islands-donald-trump-keir-starmer/106372464</link><description>The US president has told the UK it is making a "big mistake" in its decision to transfer sovereignty of the islands to Mauritius.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">380aca464b31a6260cd5aefcccfd9632</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of 'toxic' poppies stolen from Victorian farm triggers health department alert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/police-investigate-poppy-plant-theft-from-ballarat-area-victoria/106373608</link><description>About 1,700 poppy plants grown for the pharmaceutical industry have been stolen from a regional property north-west of Melbourne, prompting a warning from the state health department.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b46a31ecf8cf87dbc14593028504000c</guid></item><item><title>Labor launches SA election campaign with land and housing promises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/labor-launches-sa-election-campaign-with-housing-policy/106373392</link><description>SA Labor's state election campaign launch is framed around housing, with the premier committing to a scheme for the purchase of land that would then be on-sold to the private sector for development.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f964067ff2a9ebef115ba389630f01ce</guid></item><item><title>How construction corruption is affecting housing affordability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/how-construction-corruption-is-affecting-housing-affordability/106373524</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab4d32700bd69f3f974cf74be9ad9ecc</guid></item><item><title>Police search for mental health patient on approved leave who did not return to Cumberland Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/search-psychiatric-patient-failed-return-cumberland-hospital/106373870</link><description>Madan Pandey failed to return to Cumberland Hospital after his approved leave ended on February 21.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf9e3efd1f491d36787f69212bb3a281</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs prepares for possible flooding amid severe weather warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/alice-springs-prepares-for-flood-amid-severe-weather-warning/106373816</link><description>Alice Springs residents and businesses prepare for possible flooding, amid a severe weather warning, and after flash flooding caused the Todd River to rise dramatically last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f51f578419796c6d5833522a6213deaf</guid></item><item><title>Nathan Cleary to risk missing first three Panthers games by challenging ban at NRL judiciary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/cleary-to-risk-missing-first-three-panthers-games-nrl-judiciary/106373966</link><description>Nathan Cleary will either be available to play Brisbane in round one or will miss the opening three rounds after Penrith decided to challenge his high tackle ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf8618780a44487cf3b6b5a9403ca8c3</guid></item><item><title>East West rail corridor cut by flooding amid heavy rain in northern SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/east-west-rail-corridor-cut-by-flooding-and-downpours/106373490</link><description>The cross-country rail line connecting Australia's east and west has been closed after heavy rain and flash flooding washed away significant sections of track, the corridor's manager says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fe5dd9fbf3f5419283e4e472a07177d</guid></item><item><title>USA beats Canada in overtime to end 46-year gold medal drought</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/winter-olympics-day-16-live-updates-indra-brown/106372016</link><description>Team USA beats Canada 2-1 in overtime to win the country's first men's ice hockey gold medal since 1980 in the last event of the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games, after Australian 16-year-old Indra Brown finishes fifth in the freeski halfpipe final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf4fef30a439dba6841e8f6da19912f4</guid></item><item><title>Coalition calls to criminalise assistance to ISIS-linked Australians seeking to return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/calls-to-criminalise-assistance-to-isis-linked-australians/106373812</link><description>The federal opposition proposes a new criminal offence to punish those who help Australians with links to Islamic State to return home, accusing the government of being complacent about the possible return of 34 wives and children of former fighters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22737ed2a7264d24948e5baf55fd9cb3</guid></item><item><title>Indra Brown's phenomenal fifth in freeski halfpipe at 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics a sign of her rapid rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/indra-brown-medal-freeski-halfpipe-2026-winter-olympics/106373982</link><description>Four months ago, Indra Brown had not even competed in a senior World Cup event. Her fifth-placed finish in her maiden Winter Olympics proves her meteoric rise is no fluke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29490707d1fa9c27fa01eea7ea13b644</guid></item><item><title>US Secret Service agents shoot and kill man trying to unlawfully enter Trump's Mar-a-Lago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/man-shot-dead-unlawfully-entering-mar-a-lago/106374424</link><description>A spokesperson said agents "confronted the individual and shots were fired by law enforcement during the encounter".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84e4e7b7b6d6c48eb1badc0a20139a24</guid></item><item><title>Victorian IT projects blow out by $1.25bn over a decade, government data shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/victorian-government-it-ict-project-budget-timeframe-increase/106310548</link><description>Hundreds of Victorian IT projects have together blown out by more than $1.25 billion in the last decade, with some suffering years-long delays, as experts question whether taxpayers are getting value for money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73c47ba622e9b95baaf11006993d3e86</guid></item><item><title>How to maintain Antarctica's ice runway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/antarctica-ice-runway/106353872</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbfbd36108b432086496484c96d9e5bd</guid></item><item><title>Australian Antarctic Program relies on ice runway at Wilkins Aerodrome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/ice-runway-wilkins-aerodrome-australian-antarctic-program/106369198</link><description>The ice runway at Wilkins Aerodrome is a critical asset in the Australian Antarctic Program, but getting it ready for flights is nothing short of extreme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8c0ef758fa888d872b5a9505e1c4d00</guid></item><item><title>This week in history quiz: Do you remember these past events?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/this-week-in-history-quiz/106046872</link><description>How well do you remember Trainspotting, the story of an iconic photo and the M*A*S*H finale?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7501cc3c65d98e42aff0d1be6d34a55f</guid></item><item><title>Micro-interventions to reduce stress in your day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/small-interventions-to-help-relieve-or-reduce-stress/106354572</link><description>Experts say we don’t need to overhaul our lives to reduce our stress effectively. Here are some tips you can use right now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e0daa9fa68a0484a3e03818686a4267</guid></item><item><title>Live: Winter Olympics come to a thrilling conclusion in closing ceremony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/winter-olympics-closing-ceremony-live-blog/106373682</link><description>The Milano Cortina Games are farewelled in style as the closing ceremony brings the 2026 Winter Olympics to an end. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e3789f87af828de66fe9fd714a971af</guid></item><item><title>Simon Gordon's endometriosis surgeries were gynaecology's open secret. Now colleagues and patients are speaking out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/endometriosis-gynaecologist-simon-gordon-complaints-four-corners/106361726</link><description>Complaints had been made about this gynaecologist for years. Only when hospital management discovered that Four Corners was looking into his practice, did it start investigating further.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">546c584366e52080d406c7acee3f13ac</guid></item><item><title>Albanese changes tune on immigration and 'ISIS brides' as One Nation effect hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/one-nation-coalition-labor-isis-brides/106369478</link><description>A lot has been written about One Nation cannibalising the Coalition's vote, but less attention has been given to how the rise of the once-fringe party is also activating Labor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8211d1541a72fd4ec12b613f76841ed</guid></item><item><title>Reducing inequality means taxing capital more — including inheritances</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/reducing-inequality-means-taxing-capital-more/106369480</link><description>Intergenerational inequality will only be dealt with by taxing the people that have the money, not by cutting the taxes of those who don't have it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44b5a5f423885727fd91c6525a98d8c9</guid></item><item><title>Home owners struggle as insurance premiums rise more than 50 per cent in five years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/home-insurance-premiums-increase-51-per-cent-in-five-years/106308824</link><description>Home insurance premiums continue to rise, with properties in natural disaster-prone areas paying the most.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26e5815da54050b913be5dc0278140a0</guid></item></channel></rss>