<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 05:51:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Discovery in desk's nook paints picture of Australia's oldest continuously operating crematorium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/rookwood-crematorium-artefact-find-in-architect-desk-sydney/106016866</link><description>An architect's desk at Australia's oldest continuously operating crematorium housed a trove of artefacts inside a compartment, only to be unearthed 100 years later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18a0cb16a312f34eba9ba1cbb621bbe7</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Fina intensifies to a category four system over water, BOM confirms — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/tropical-cyclone-fina-live-updates-sunday-november-23/106041128</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says Tropical Cyclone Fina is expected to reach category four strength while still in Northern Territory waters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">787ca815823e5ea13964631d84e915b9</guid></item><item><title>Severe Tropical Cyclone Fina moves towards WA as Darwin surveys the damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/severe-tropical-cyclone-fina-sunday-darwin-surveys-damage/106040870</link><description>Severe Tropical Cyclone Fina was the first cyclone to pass Darwin at a category three since Cyclone Tracy in 1974. Here is the damage it left in its wake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f31667c70164c836fd9dac92eb67e354</guid></item><item><title>Will teens without accounts be safe on YouTube under social media ban?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/will-teens-without-accounts-be-safe-on-youtube-social-media-ban/106031868</link><description>BTN High tests what YouTube content will be viewable without an account ahead of next month's social media ban, as an academic says the restrictions are unlikely to change what young people are watching.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50698d5676700fee887f04d7b15eb0f4</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Think you'll nail it this week? I do love some misguided confidence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/105951746</link><description>Spent too much time online shopping this week, and not enough time studying fun facts? Let's see.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45c52af5024bd88b843172ebcc4a8b2f</guid></item><item><title>David Boon's Test debut came as Australian cricket lurched into crisis against rampant West Indies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/today-in-history-november-23-1984-david-boon-test-debut/105951100</link><description>David Boon is one of Australia's greatest and most-beloved Test cricketers. His debut, at the Gabba on November 23, 1984 was not the most auspicious of starts, though.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0175adadb908fd2c601cef4a28bd695</guid></item><item><title>Experiences of homophobia 'happening every day' in Australia's most progressive city</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/homophobia-in-canberra-australias-most-progressive-city/106004910</link><description>Luke was only minutes into his first shift at his new workplace when he began hearing his colleagues making homophobic comments. Despite being a resident of Australia's most progressive city, he says he no longer feels safe in public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07565072cbf43ea80cac6e9863aebefe</guid></item><item><title>Water is under pressure in the Great Artesian Basin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/water-is-under-pressure-in-the-great-artesian-basin/106002448</link><description>The Great Artesian Basin covers a fifth of Australia and contains water that has been there for millions of years. Now, decades of extraction are taking their toll and traditional owners are fighting a mining giant for compensation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f93e8b3e6314dd27f4ab4a3e8b246163</guid></item><item><title>From living homeless as a teenager to becoming Toowoomba's motorbike-riding priest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/motorbike-riding-anglican-priest-pauline-harley-toowoomba/106015442</link><description>Pauline Harley did not grow up with religion, far from it. She was homeless for six months as a teenager, which has informed her passion now for social justice in Toowoomba.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0249aa734fd607c50779a712b4a4798</guid></item><item><title>'Hope is the strongest weapon': Afghan women celebrate return to international football</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/hope-strongest-weapon-afghan-women-united-international-football/105993742</link><description>After four years in exile, some of Afghanistan's female footballers have returned to the pitch, giving hope to those still in the country, fighting for basic rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67ce65879a558d6c10b795ea483011f1</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian man's wait for surgery stretches into years as daily pain worsens with no relief within sight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/elective-surgery-tasmania-wait-for-years-timothy-smith/106040548</link><description>Within three months is the recommended time for surgery to remedy the painful health problem Timothy Smith has. But the 60-year-old has been forced to wait for years and still has no idea when he will get relief.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">962bc180bde0b32ad3b40cf43c2dea30</guid></item><item><title>As climate change accelerates Launceston's flood risk, some propose putting floodgates on the estuary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/climate-change-flood-risk-launceston-tamar-estuary-floodgates/106004394</link><description>Andrew Lovitt is part of a community group that has spent 15 years investigating a large-scale infrastructure proposal to prevent flooding in Launceston, in northern Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7a83f5b024e830180eda53851f2dc58</guid></item><item><title>Golden Guitars to review stance on AI after 2026 awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/golden-guitar-awards-generative-ai-country-music/106023832</link><description>After a snap decision to ban generative tracks made using Artificial Intelligence for the 2026 Golden Guitar Awards, the Country Music Association of Australia is reviewing whether AI has a place in country music.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67651833aa9dc924741152f3b46a94f9</guid></item><item><title>Government promises stronger protection for native forests if Greens back environment reforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/labor-greens-deal-on-environment-laws-native-forests/106040766</link><description>The ABC has been told the federal government is willing to ensure native forestry complies with tougher new standards within three years if the Greens back the reforms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b406504f8a8bc14e613f05d39f1f300</guid></item><item><title>Victorian farmer crafts unique spirits from sugar beet and red wheat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/victorian-farmer-unconventional-crops-spirits-alcohol-distilling/103563416</link><description>A Victorian farmer is making unique alcoholic drinks from unconventional crops.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60ab2971dfec0e29a781fcac231b7bdc</guid></item><item><title>England's first Ashes Test capitulation with bat and ball a symptom of 'dumb', brainless batting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/ashes-england-hammered-ben-stokes-batting/106041156</link><description>As England counts the cost of its first Ashes Test defeat, questions over how its world-beating pace attack was rendered so impotent and its high-class batters so comprehensively lost the plot will rumble all the way to Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ffb0de34551bc7bf42ebe72b0618ea4</guid></item><item><title>Extent of damage from Tropical Cyclone Fina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/extent-of-damage-from-tropical-cyclone-fina/106042028</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">092984bbb16c0cb81cb929f635139647</guid></item><item><title>JFK's granddaughter Tatiana Schlossberg reveals terminal cancer diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/jfk-granddaughter-tatiana-schlossberg-cancer-diagnosis/106041994</link><description>Tatiana Schlossberg says the cuts to research made by her cousin RFK Jr, the US Health and Human Services secretary, are disappointing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff63406b1fd607cb085ba37acee6421b</guid></item><item><title>Why is the Blue Lake in Mount Gambier so blue?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/why-is-mount-gambier-blue-lake-so-blue/106031572</link><description>Most lakes are kind of blue, but this lake in South Australia stands out for its super-bright colour that attracts tourists from around the country. But just why it is so blue and why it changes colour during the year are not well known.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bcaf22035bd2fd217025ad9de55d64e</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne star on side’s ability to run opposition ‘out to the last siren’</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/alice-oloughlin-north-melbourne-win-over-melbourne-aflw/106041940</link><description>North Melbourne will play in its third consecutive AFLW grand final after weathering an almighty scare from Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c27668d7ad5b1d4f913eab612b73abb</guid></item><item><title>Police rule out schoolies link after Noosa teenage pedestrian killed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/police-rule-out-schoolies-link-after-noosa-pedestrian-killed/106042074</link><description>A 17-year-old boy was struck by a ute about 2am and died at the scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cd345a4f54d671f88ceff24be87080f</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Lions beat Carlton by 35 points to set up third straight AFLW grand final against Kangaroos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/svarc-plug-ruby-dazzles-as-lions-blitz-ends-blues/106042056</link><description>The Brisbane Lions will meet North Melbourne in the AFLW decider for a third straight season after a crushing 35-point preliminary final defeat of Carlton.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b23c002d02dd251928c1da2c16dca6b</guid></item><item><title>How an anti-war blockbuster starring Mel Gibson helped rebirth the Anzac Gallipoli legend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/gallipoli-mel-gibson-anzac-legend/106005722</link><description>By the 80s, the story of the Anzacs at Gallipoli had started to fade from the public consciousness. Then an Australian anti-war filmmaker had an idea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d4f822d85e6cb3952d8475468144ecd</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine and Europe scramble to respond to US plan to end Russia's war</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/ukraine-europe-scramble-to-respond-to-us-plan-to-end-war/106042072</link><description>Ukraine and its European allies are scrambling to come up with counter-proposals after US President Donald Trump gave Kyiv a tight deadline to approve a deal to end the war that accepts some of Russia's hardline demands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">962224e343051a5df1d5678365c27c0d</guid></item><item><title>Woman sheds light on life with severe pelvic pain as research gaps persist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/pelvic-pain-devastates-lives-amid-vast-research-gaps/106033730</link><description>As the country attempts to close the gaps in pelvic pain research and treatment, Jaali Barton continues to search for help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e8ecdb938196c1df7e06360063f4776</guid></item><item><title>Australia's two-day Ashes Test win to leave Cricket Australia millions short of expected revenue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/two-day-ashes-test-could-cost-cricket-australia-millions/106041938</link><description>Travis Head's stunning take-down of England, leading to a speedy day two finish in Perth, is set to cost Cricket Australia millions in lost ticket revenue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42db2822cc4bd5346d8cdd116b767a99</guid></item><item><title>Treasury needs to breathe more life into Australia's uncompetitive sectors, new think tank says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/treasury-should-take-on-oligopolies-policy-institute-australia/106040652</link><description>We need to empower Treasury to breathe more life into Australia's uncompetitive sectors, a new think tank says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01c02744a122a95414d94dc247d1243a</guid></item><item><title>Martu rangers capture rare night parrot in WA's Pilbara region.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/martu-rangers-capture-rare-night-parrot-in-wa-s-pilbara-region/106034066</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b21800156c4a741b9f8c24db2648fa27</guid></item><item><title>Critically endangered night parrot captured by Martu rangers in east Pilbara</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/thirsty-night-parrot-pilbara/106029246</link><description>After thousands of hours of recording, the elusive night parrot has been captured on camera drinking from a water hole for the first time, reshaping researchers' understanding of their needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2d81811f2cbdb83f25b0a1eec6f1057</guid></item><item><title>Man suffers life-threatening burns after light plane crash at Raglan in central Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/man-suffers-life-threatening-burns-light-plane-crash-raglan/106042294</link><description>Paramedics are treating a man in his 60s with significant burns to his limbs, face and chest following a light plane crash in central Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e65c854752b07d862ac5ecd112f04378</guid></item><item><title>Trump, Zelenskyy and European leaders under pressure over peace deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/ukraine-russia-zelenskyy-putin-trump-nato-eu/106042192</link><description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy is under pressure to agree to a peace deal, while US President Donald Trump faces domestic blowback over his foreign policy decisions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4a7975454f1263ccfc241675b9f8658</guid></item><item><title>First Hike Project helps refugees experience hiking in Australian bush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/first-hike-project-refugees-hiking-australia/106042266</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fc281197771a8f93a53a280b62fddeb</guid></item><item><title>Brazil's ex-president Jair Bolsonaro arrested over alleged plot to escape</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/brazils-ex-president-bolsonaro-arrested-over-alleged-escape-plot/106042220</link><description>Jair Bolsonaro has been taken into police custody after the country's Supreme Court found he was trying to escape house arrest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c6de39732bb02f2a6af94acbabac242</guid></item><item><title>Storm and wind gusts of 119km/h damage homes, trees, powerlines at Port Pirie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/storm-causes-widespread-damage-at-port-pirie/106042166</link><description>Thousands of residents were faced with outages in the South Australian town of Port Pirie after a severe thunderstorm and hail destroyed roofs as well as bringing down trees and powerlines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0468b7e73c4576b2bd73f7c8fe0a8990</guid></item><item><title>Make a Christmas wreath with flowers from your garden</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/make-your-own-christmas-wreath-with-flowers-from-your-garden/106006876</link><description>Worried you might make a mess, get it wrong or waste your time making a wreath? Read our tips first.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfb834459f70c0113e9a903223f2b896</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies showed promised in 2025 but have stalled two years out from World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/wallabies-progress-stalls-after-promising-signs-in-2025/106042214</link><description>The Wallabies did not turn the corner this year, as many had suggested, as they instead face a daunting challenge to be competitive at the 2027 World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">824c646920e68fd5e2f99ed533b16ec0</guid></item><item><title>How migrant and overseas Christians are helping keep Australian churches alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/christian-migrants-asia-pacific-sustain-australian-churches/105997642</link><description>Without 11 Pacific Islander ministers serving parishes in north Queensland, the region's Anglican church would collapse, according to bishop Keith Joseph.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb86bd5bbe8cccb2bfd413fa8d120b7d</guid></item><item><title>Brazil COP30 deal sidesteps fossil fuels, triples climate finance for developing nations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/cop30-climate-deal-sidesteps-fossil-fuels/106042660</link><description>Denial and division have been highlighted in the COP30 deal that makes no mention of cutting fossil fuels but boosts climate aid for developing nations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5cc72a82efdfdfd6ccc8f43fd61cf1b</guid></item><item><title>Former federal Liberal candidate Amelia Hamer wins preselection for state seat of Malvern</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/amelia-hamer-wins-preselection-for-malvern/106042776</link><description>Amelia Hamer has been endorsed as the Liberal Party's candidate for the state seat of Malvern at Victoria's 2026 election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e302238c926d762fd123474a9bdc8560</guid></item><item><title>WA government releases business case and images of controversial $217m Burswood racetrack project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/wa-government-releases-images-of-burswood-racetrack-project/106042566</link><description>The deputy premier accuses the Town of Victoria Park of lying to ratepayers over the controversial $217 million entertainment and sporting precinct in Burswood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a7e961be9f631d804104d184430cf6b</guid></item><item><title>Bureau of Meteorology's new boss asked to examine $96.5m bill for website redesign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/bureau-of-meteorology-new-website-cost-blowout-to-96-million/106042202</link><description>Federal Environment Minister Murray Watt has asked the weather agency's new boss to examine how the website's cost and redesign went so wrong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77632c609a2a766464db3db93e3232ff</guid></item><item><title>Draws released for 2026 men's, women's and wheelchair rugby league world cups</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/rlwc-draws-released-2026-mens-womens/106042928</link><description>The draws for next year's rugby league world cups have been confirmed, with a format change on the cards for the men's and women's tournaments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1184e0900d191319d6c4d2b9dbcebb0a</guid></item><item><title>Rental affordability data shows 'dire' situation across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/sgs-economics-rental-affordability-index-data-release/106031672</link><description>Data shows rental affordability in regional parts of Australia has fallen in the past year, while the situation in most capital cities has not improved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97b02490c80e60ad6d24448d120dbbcd</guid></item><item><title>US, Ukraine negotiating 'updated and refined' peace proposal aimed at ending war with Russia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/trump-says-ukraine-zero-gratitude-us-support/106043358</link><description>The US and Ukraine say they have created an "updated and refined peace framework" to end the war with Russia, apparently modifying a Trump-backed plan Kyiv and its allies saw as too sympathetic to Moscow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53b45af3ff6d7d899b82c2b76c376f93</guid></item><item><title>Humanoid robots present an unprecedented dilemma for the economy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/artificial-intelligence-robot-humanoid-workforce-labour-tax-ubi/106034208</link><description>There is now a global race to build humanoids that can walk, talk, reason, lift, carry, fetch, stack and generally operate in a human environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11015f2f3ba4acc558810e73151bbb62</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley faces a fight for her political survival in parliament's final week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/sussan-ley-leadership-liberals-women-angus-taylor-andrew-hastie/105884524</link><description>The optics of rolling the Liberal Party's only woman leader when NSW and Victoria have managed to elevate traditional "small-l liberal" candidates is playing on the minds of some members.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eaee738e013977074c56a612f24dc099</guid></item><item><title>Murray Watt declares 'now or never' for environment laws as parliament stand-off looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/watt-declares-now-or-never-for-environment-laws/106042780</link><description>As politicians converge on Canberra for the last time this year, Labor is determined to pass its environment law reform and insists it will work with either the Coalition or the Greens to do so.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7275f31ad98a6ce8e5713f37f17da866</guid></item><item><title>Teenage boy charged after elderly man slashed during alleged robbery at Lilydale station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/teen-charged-after-elderly-man-slashed-lilydale-station/106043582</link><description>Police allege a 16-year-old boy has slashed an 80-year-old man with a knife while trying to steal his wallet in the car park of the railway station in Melbourne's outer east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d60de161b37f63beaf0725e00d5ecd5</guid></item><item><title>Australia records highest number of aircraft bird strikes in over a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/australian-aircraft-bird-strikes-highest-decade/106011582</link><description>The first recorded bird strike, when a bird collides with an aircraft, was in the United States in 1905 but now they occur almost daily. Last year, Australia recorded the highest number in more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49c4df962a4bb66106a0ba0a422d46f2</guid></item><item><title>Artist Paola Pivi's vibrant new exhibition fills Art Gallery of Western Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/paola-pivi-art-gallery-wa/106020310</link><description>Giant dancing polar bears covered in fluorescent feathers, a three-storey inflatable comic strip and a donkey in a dinghy have taken over the Art Gallery of Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71f3bc034ccf249a9594104d2728bc3e</guid></item><item><title>The democracy ambassadors smashing misconceptions about voting in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/democracy-ambassadors-making-voting-accessible/106016464</link><description>There are a lot of misconceptions about voting, particularly among marginalised groups. But these "democracy ambassadors" are working hard to ensure everyone knows their rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c7d770ef217a228f186aaeed1630f08</guid></item><item><title>The joys and challenges of connecting to nature as a person with disability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/connection-to-nature-hiking-with-disability/106005162</link><description>There are a multitude of physical and mental benefits that come with hiking and connecting with nature — but for people with disability across Australia, accessing the outdoors is often difficult.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da4dcc1038ff1f61c29eeef7c0c7e4f9</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Fina approaches northern West Australian coast at category four status</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/cyclone-fina-kimberley-coast/106037750</link><description>Residents in far-north WA are being warned of expected damaging wind and heavy rain today as Cyclone Fina approaches the Kimberley region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9f67560aae6e23322d1233a6cf38e41</guid></item><item><title>Growing complaints against Sydney shared housing provider ShareSorted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/nsw-complaints-against-sharesorted-affordable-housing-agency/105902466</link><description>A new face of Australia's housing crisis is emerging with companies making lucrative business out of university student tenants desperate to find somewhere to live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4a0e5b224694376679eaca57f5a1020</guid></item><item><title>Children take over their mother's case against Beauty Point caravan park following her death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/children-takeover-beauty-point-caravan-case-after-mother-dies/106037606</link><description>In the last months of her life, Roslyn Grima was fighting in court for the right to sell her home at a tourist park to fund her cancer treatment, but died before that could happen. Now, her children will continue her battle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b93c209d2691aad3485562e97e71480</guid></item><item><title>Iranians fear taps running dry as country faces worst drought in 60 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/iran-facing-worst-drought-in-60-years/106035210</link><description>As Iran suffers through a drought and the president warns the capital could be evacuated, millions are worried about what the future will hold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbdcc6ab5444bc9838633f7144346b5e</guid></item><item><title>Big fines, little paid — the battle in Australia's illicit tobacco market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/illegal-tobacco-industry-millions-in-fines-unpaid-queensland/106030978</link><description>Data obtained in an ABC investigation shows the bulk of fines for selling illicit tobacco — tens of millions of dollars — are not being paid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b916256338855c8b9c2644425100e98</guid></item><item><title>England coach Brendon McCullum urges Ashes calm after first Test loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/england-coach-brendon-mccullum-urges-calm-after-ashes-test-loss/106043608</link><description>Brendon McCullum says England will find itself in trouble if it abandons Bazball now, with the team to double down on its aggressive tactics heading into Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a75de7821250fa7bd59909881e121b01</guid></item><item><title>Infuriated Inverloch community 'still waiting' as FOI reveals years of delay in erosion works</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/inverloch-coastal-erosion-foi-government/105995048</link><description>Inverloch residents are "infuriated" by the Victorian government's delay in spending $3 million in federal funding to help fix coastal erosion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7f453f7f7a27d787d012f8580e8fed3</guid></item><item><title>Calls to end water extraction from Great Artesian Basin before culturally significant springs are lost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/calls-for-end-to-water-extraction-at-great-artesian-basin/106038490</link><description>Environmentalists are calling for mining giant BHP to end its water extraction from the Great Artesian Basin when a major desalination plant is built in South Australia's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fca6049feefb20e454a9a71cee3b252</guid></item><item><title>Soccer journeyman Valentino Yuel travels around the world playing for different clubs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/valentino-yuel-football-player-travels-around-the-world/106003962</link><description>Since becoming a professional, Valentino Yuel has played in Australia's A-League, as well as for clubs in Türkiye, Iran, Qatar, Uzbekistan, Libya and now Hong Kong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f9ffc29427452bc19d6f8ac0542798c</guid></item><item><title>BHP says no takeover deal with Anglo American, ASX 200 gains 1.4pc — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/106042520</link><description>Preliminary talks between miners BHP and Anglo American end without a deal. The ASX rebounds more than 1 per cent after renewed hopes of a December rate cut powered Wall Street higher. Here's how the session played out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d69851811a14426709ca657d186a6827</guid></item><item><title>For people like Benn, the hope of a fairer law on medicinal cannabis is life-changing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/nsw-medicinal-cannabis-driving-bill/106034044</link><description>After years of chronic pain and legal uncertainty, a new bill could finally let NSW patients like Benn drive safely with medicinal cannabis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9819382a2fe6835e8a94246a13f148c</guid></item><item><title>Retailers in north-west Victoria fed up with increasing crime rates amid proposed state law change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/mildura-shops-fight-back-against-increasing-retail-crime/105920374</link><description>Retail stores in north-west Victoria are taking their own measures to curb increasing retail crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b81cf56e5289d295379ac18259fe70e</guid></item><item><title>Billion-dollar proposal to turn coal seam gas waste into valuable chemicals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/company-announces-plans-for-queensland-brine-processing-plant/106008970</link><description>Five million tonnes of salt could be dumped in ponds over the life of the coal seam gas industry. Now, there could finally be a better solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3d3a80f91eeb5b6c5f53734ecdcae5b</guid></item><item><title>Domestic abuse survivors in PNG have to 'queue in front of the police station' to report their husbands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/png-national-crisis-of-domestic-violence-port-moresby/106017140</link><description>Women are twice as likely to suffer domestic violence in Papua New Guinea compared with the rest of the world, a new report finds. Here's what the country is doing to fix it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a540cb88a5bc95363fd785a4b5df81e1</guid></item><item><title>Australian workers find it harder to change jobs, with concerns AI will cause further disruption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/australians-switching-jobs-as-ai-changes-workforce/106036106</link><description>Australians are finding it harder to change jobs. It comes at a time when artificial intelligence is poised to further disrupt the workforce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">721b43c75d43d74dc0e423af24d2f291</guid></item><item><title>Cristiano Ronaldo scores bicycle kick goal for Al-Nassr in Saudi Pro League</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/cristiano-ronaldo-scores-stunning-bicycle-kick-in-saudi-league/106043828</link><description>Veteran superstar Cristiano Ronaldo responds to a recent high-profile send-off with a brilliant bicycle kick for his Al-Nassr side in the Saudi Pro League.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edf7c4a8a089ddc2345e6c9f5c7c1666</guid></item><item><title>Environmental experts challenge prescribed burn assessment in endangered bird habitat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/prescribed-burn-lit-in-endangered-cockatoo-habitat/106041070</link><description>Environmental and conservation experts in Western Australia challenge claims by Environment Minister Matthew Swinbourn that two endangered bird species were not present in a patch of Great Southern bushland set ablaze.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ae37c4a3556018990629c93b129cf19</guid></item><item><title>What did McLaren do wrong to get Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris disqualified from the Las Vegas F1 Grand Prix?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/what-did-mclaren-do-wrong-at-the-las-vegas-f1-grand-prix/106043812</link><description>McLaren apologises to Norris and Piastri as F1 officials explain why the drivers were disqualified in Las Vegas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2671ab4d067425eab2cc4bd22461f6b1</guid></item><item><title>Hinchinbrook candidates reveal key policies amid tough by-election campaign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/queensland-by-election-hinchinbrook-candidates/106028746</link><description>A hard-fought by-election in a north Queensland cane-growing district is growing more heated by the day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64a7d2040f6347d78085a81fe8395e4d</guid></item><item><title>The Wieambilla attack could not have been predicted, but extreme violence can be prevented</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/wieambilla-inquest-findings-trains-violence-recommendations/106042146</link><description>A coronial inquest does not fault police or the government for failing to pick up the curdling paranoia of the deluded Train family, but it does offer some paths forward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a23298d8ee96c11ad089c3515b873ed1</guid></item><item><title>Morgan Geyser, woman behind 2014 Slender Man stabbing, retaken into custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/slender-man-stabber-morgan-geyser-missing-wisconsin/106044134</link><description>in 2014, Morgan Geyser and an accomplice nearly stabbed a classmate to death and later told police they did so to earn the right to be Slender Man's servants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a2b0d46bc21bf4ee8e43b842bc1dfa0</guid></item><item><title>Sustainable and organic wines pique interest of young people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/organic-wine-on-the-rise/106031838</link><description>Central-west New South Wales winemaker Sam Statham has noticed a trend that has nothing to do with price or palate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ef26eee022b81ec4396a6833a726cb0</guid></item><item><title>WA Spud King's newest supermarket revives memories of Kalgoorlie market gardens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/new-supermarket-revives-memories-of-kalgoorlie-market-gardens/106040602</link><description>The opening of a new supermarket franchise in one of Australia's biggest inland cities has revived memories from the past when Kalgoorlie-Boulder was home to at least 35 market gardens, run mostly by European migrant families.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c30282f64a3ba7fa08640ec02731912</guid></item><item><title>Jeeno Thitikul retains LPGA's Tour Championship for biggest winning cheque in women's golf history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/thai-superstar-thitikul-backs-up-with-6-2-million-golf-win/106044014</link><description>Thai world number one Jeeno Thitikul claims the biggest cheque in women's golf history, as Aussie Steph Kyriacou gets a final round hole in one at the Tour Championship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de20912395c97b9ed293185f0d717d91</guid></item><item><title>Alcoa shelves plans to explore Perth Hills for bauxite mining expansion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/alcoa-shelves-plans-to-explore-perth-hills-for-bauxite-mining/106044264</link><description>US mining giant Alcoa will withdraw part of its plans to expand its mining operations in the world's only jarrah forests, following community concerns around water security and environmental impacts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a44bf494203d43f3d0f84333355f125</guid></item><item><title>Erin Phillips hired as GM to help Gold Coast Suns' struggling AFLW program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/aflw-erin-phillips-hired-gm-gold-coast-suns-womens-program/106044648</link><description>Erin Phillips joins the Gold Coast Suns as the club's new general manager of women's football as she looks to bring a premiership culture to this year's wooden spoon winners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35b477d128fd0c9476ef3364123343b5</guid></item><item><title>Victims of AI deepfakes could sue for emotional damages under new bill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/victims-ai-deepfake-sue-under-david-pocock-bill/106037560</link><description>Australians who share AI deepfakes of another person without consent could be sued or fined under a new bill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbd5d269a8b787b6ae61c471cd090a28</guid></item><item><title>CFS firefighter Peter Curtis dies at scene of Eyre Peninsula blaze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/cfs-firefighter-dies-at-pinkawillinie-conservation-park-blaze/106044594</link><description>Emergency authorities are paying tribute to Country Fire Service firefighter Peter Curtis, who died in the line of duty at a conservation park on South Australia's Eyre Peninsula.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b4cf83fcec37422df0bee5cacf5d735</guid></item><item><title>Fifth person charged with murder over fatal Bega stabbing denied bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/fifth-person-charged-murder-bega-stabbing-death/106044146</link><description>Five people have now been charged with murder over a fatal stabbing on the NSW South Coast, after a 48-year-old man was arrested at a local hospital over the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">150c65dc1cf5e9c45b3fc656be4d5640</guid></item><item><title>History of market gardens in Kalgoorlie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/history-of-market-gardens-in-kalgoorlie/106044550</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02e042170a2b163572d2ad8a2d8a2fc9</guid></item><item><title>ACT Supreme Court dismisses appeal against man jailed for raping friend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/court-dismisses-appeal-against-man-jailed-for-raping-friend/106044206</link><description>The first person sentenced for a sexual offence after a major review of cases previously rejected by ACT Police has had an appeal over his sentence dismissed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ce2c4a70ac2e169e1a2320555118188</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins closes in on second Ashes Test berth, Josh Hazlewood to return 'at some point' in series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/australia-gives-latest-on-injured-pace-aces-hazlewood-cummins/106045008</link><description>Australia coach Andrew McDonald provides an update on sidelined quicks Pat Cummins and Josh Hazlewood ahead of the second Ashes Test at the Gabba.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f41cd57ae64bd410a3b1e2fae3e9f6e7</guid></item><item><title>Half tonne of cocaine retrieved from WA waters off Lancelin, as livestock vessel chief charged</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/lancelin-cocaine-bust-livestock-ship-afp/106045080</link><description>Police charge the chief officer of an international livestock carrier and three others, after half a tonne of cocaine was found floating off Western Australia's coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a64f00ebef23e7559b1008877c04f2bf</guid></item><item><title>ElecraNet to explore alternative options for Northern Transmission Project after farmers voice concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/northern-transmission-line-moved-from-south-australia-mid-north/106045600</link><description>ElectraNet are shifting their focus east, after farmers voiced concerns about renewable energy line Northern Transmission Project running through prime cropping country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87bbcecad36ba980df103634b30e7276</guid></item><item><title>Bendigo secondary school teacher Kirsten Thomas sentenced for raping student</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/bendigo-drama-teacher-kirsten-thomas-rape-jail/106021984</link><description>A Central Victorian drama and dance teacher is handed an 18-month jail term for raping a student at her home following an event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c032c5b39aa928fb51f642b29e3cbdad</guid></item><item><title>Alleged one-punch attack leaves 62-year-old man fighting for life on the Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/southport-gold-coast-alleged-one-punch-attack/106044256</link><description>The man's alleged attacker gave himself up to police at the scene of the incident and was charged with grievous bodily harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53e2205671448fe888e5cb7717d3f946</guid></item><item><title>Sister of accused killer Rajwinder Singh gives evidence in Toyah Cordingley murder trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/rajwinder-singh-sister-toyah-cordingley-murder-trial/106045064</link><description>The sister of the man accused of murdering Cairns woman Toyah Cordingley has told a court she has spoken to her brother "two or three times a week" since his extradition from India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d532ec9ee2a0222927bd86b8658ca69</guid></item><item><title>How last year's AFLW grand final loss made the Brisbane Lions rethink everything</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/brisbane-lions-with-game-style-for-aflw-grand-final/106046180</link><description>Brisbane returns to the AFLW grand final with a new game plan to tackle the unbeaten, reigning premiers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66c03d2ab340451e2d0d7d1a40a5c888</guid></item><item><title>The Trump presidency could be a priceless gift to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/trump-presidency-could-be-priceless-gift-australia-boyer-lecture/106028102</link><description>Trump cares little for alliances. So his presidency could well offer a priceless gift to Australia: a rare moment when national self-interest can eclipse sentiment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fab117e54e32bb81199e3000b090b31</guid></item><item><title>Port Pirie clean-up efforts continue after thunderstorms slams SA town</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/thunderstorms-slam-port-pirie-clean-up-extreme-weather-sa/106045154</link><description>Port Pirie residents and businesses are picking up the pieces after record-breaking thunderstorms hit town over the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e40c3be172a4e5cc1b74eff0d8200514</guid></item><item><title>Bail granted for alleged NSW child groomer cult leader William 'Little Pebble' Kamm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/bail-granted-for-alleged-nsw-child-groomer-cult-leader/106045500</link><description>At the age of six, the complainant was allegedly told she had a "beautiful mission from God" to be the wife of William "Little Pebble" Kamm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbaf43e75cc2b7bc0ed425deb9227cbd</guid></item><item><title>Man faces court charged over alleged car theft where toddler was left in a Shepparton car park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/car-theft-shepparton-shop-parking-lot-baby-box-court/106042544</link><description>A man charged over the alleged theft of a car from a supermarket car park which had a toddler inside has faced court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e6fd4bf11ac9d62fd617ad20dfd6e10</guid></item><item><title>NZ has halted access to puberty blockers. What does the rest of the world do?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/nz-halt-access-puberty-blockers-transgender-youth-australia/106036326</link><description>New Zealand has become the latest country to halt access to puberty blockers for young people with gender dysphoria but are they following best health practice or an outlier?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07004f410e596dbe19ea4c0009181e0d</guid></item><item><title>NT Health calls for new facility as Royal Darwin Hospital recovers from Tropical Cyclone Fina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/nt-royal-darwin-hospital-cyclone-fina-damage-government-funding/106045310</link><description>The Northern Territory's largest hospital is "literally creaking at the seams" after Tropical Cyclone Fina, prompting NT Health to call for more federal funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d30d8a698c8fc6d570e5e8735b7e2c4</guid></item><item><title>Trial of Brendan Kantilla, accused of murdering 23-year-old Bangladeshi student, begins in Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/brendan-kantilla-murder-trial-begins-in-nt-supreme-court-darwin/106045814</link><description>The week-long murder trial of Brendan Kantilla, charged over the death of Bangladeshi student Md Isfaqur Rahman in 2023, has begun in the Northern Territory Supreme Court in Darwin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43f580914eb444d84a391dd93c8f48fa</guid></item><item><title>Footage of deadly Sea World helicoper collision plays in court as inquest into 2023 crash begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/sea-world-helicopter-collision-inquest-shown-vision/106043950</link><description>First responders have recounted the "absolute chaos" after two Sea World helicopters crashed in 2023, killing four people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48765572a1af1da2bf5fd3d630689620</guid></item><item><title>Brazil's ex-president Jair Bolsonaro says 'hallucinations' made him tamper with ankle monitor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/bolsonaro-hallucinations-jail-ankle-monitor-tamper/106045940</link><description>Former Brazilian president Jair Bolsonaro says medication he takes for hiccups made him so paranoid that he used a soldering iron to tamper with his court-mandated ankle monitor while under house arrest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8c295904d79f63c48bdae56991d5eb8</guid></item><item><title>Severe thunderstorms and hail damage crops in WA's South West and Great Southern</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/south-west-wa-severe-thunderstorms-hail-causes-crop-damage/106044318</link><description>Farmers in southern WA say crops have been destroyed by hail and trees "snapped like matchsticks" during weekend thunderstorms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9901bcf44a39ef7413d69877c9643241</guid></item><item><title>Donald Glover reveals he had a stroke last year which forced him to cancel his New World tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/donald-glover-stroke-tour-cancellation/106046562</link><description>Despite a "really bad pain" in his head, Donald Glover performed a full show before heading to the hospital where he was diagnosed with a stroke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">360bf77f27a3b539d9f12a3845590444</guid></item><item><title>Perry Kouroumblis's lawyer questions handling of DNA evidence in Easey Street murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/easey-street-murder-perry-kouroumblis-committal-nov-24/106045702</link><description>Perry Kouroumblis's lawyer has questioned former officers about their handling of evidence in the 1977 murder case that the prosecution said relied on DNA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9136bdfa97c93d42a714d8e26f7f6d80</guid></item><item><title>Min Woo Lee hails 'career best' mindset ahead of Australian PGA Championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/lee-hails-career-best-mindset-ahead-of-australian-pga/106047118</link><description>Min Woo Lee learned valuable lessons from the way he handled the first US PGA Tour win of his career, which are set to put him in a strong position to fire at the Australian PGA Championship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c9aa226e2627a1203ca3e2c042232a1</guid></item><item><title>Senate shut down for 1.5 hours after Pauline Hanson's burka stunt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/senate-suspended-after-pauline-hansons-burka-stunt/106047124</link><description>The rare break in proceedings came after One Nation's Pauline Hanson strode into the chamber wearing a burka and then refused to leave after being slapped with a sanction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d6429f3e1262d2f2bb8f4a006772aae</guid></item><item><title>Teenage boy dies in stabbing at reserve near schools in Sydney's Rouse Hill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/teenage-boy-dies-in-stabbing-at-rouse-hill-reserve-sydney/106047158</link><description>NSW Police said two young boys were at a reserve at Rouse Hill when they were approached by three other boys about 4:20pm on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a98c35799035dabe2cc22516c4b5aa9</guid></item><item><title>Banksia Hill detention centre rooftop protest resolved after overnight stoush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/banksia-hill-youth-detention-centre-disturbance-children-roof/106047452</link><description>The remaining three detainees who were on the roof of Perth's Banksia Hill juvenile detention centre come down, after a disturbance yesterday which saw at least six inmates scale the building.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fe101112bab83a127f7473f1662be02</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106045296</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf82eae6af9e5547020273067772661e</guid></item><item><title>Australia no guarantee to pick Usman Khawaja for second Ashes Test at Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/usman-khawaja-not-certain-for-second-ashes-test-at-gabba/106047330</link><description>Australia coach Andrew McDonald has failed to guarantee Usman Khawaja will be selected for the second Ashes Test, even if the under-pressure veteran opener is fit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ec38976abf860865945a537227d037c</guid></item><item><title>Bureau of Meteorology boss reveals website rebuild 'approved and funded' by Turnbull government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/bom-website-approved-by-coalition-ceo-says/106047518</link><description>The Bureau of the Meteorology's new chief executive has blamed a "miscommunication" for the furore that has erupted over a costly and controversial website redesign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3e1fd100defb0bfa9853d15887bab14</guid></item><item><title>Nikhil Chaudhary becomes first Indian to score Sheffield Shield century in the 2000s</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/nikhil-chaudhary-sheffield-shield-century-tasmania/106047722</link><description>Nikhil Chaudhary has become the first Indian to hit a Sheffield Shield hundred this century, helping put Tasmania in a position of utter dominance against NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47b1a7e563f24158fb103966d98eeb1b</guid></item><item><title>The switch off for teenagers on social media looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/the-switch-off-for-teenagers-on-social-media-looms/106047538</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f098011b6f6f65142389e8e16bdfc53</guid></item><item><title>Aerial footage shows inmates on the roof on Banksia Hill Detention Centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/banksia-hill-disturbance-aerial-footage/106047822</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f29792297887e30ba65d7747c0e395db</guid></item><item><title>What is really in a vape?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/what-is-really-in-a-vape-/106047546</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92d6a952ac3d31ad31ba4da39f49a406</guid></item><item><title>Bollywood superstar Dharmendra dies in Mumbai, aged 89</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/bollywood-star-dharmendra-dies-aged-89/106048046</link><description>India's Prime Minister Narendra Modi is one of many to pay tribute to the icon of Indian cinema.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34b22d1d22ba520f5805e3d7d6efc5a1</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Cliff, reggae music pioneer, dies at 81</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/jimmy-cliff-reggae-music-pioneer-dies-at-81/106048100</link><description>Cliff was known for singles You Can Get It If You Really Want It and Many Rivers To Cross, as well as for his cover of Johnny Nash's I Can See Clearly Now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">942c2061a19b7baaa666a14ae1d9e1a1</guid></item><item><title>Cotality Housing Affordability Report shows 'extraordinary rise' in home values</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/housing-unaffordability-reaches-record-levels-in-australia/106044078</link><description>Home prices have risen by almost 50 per cent in the past five years, with more than a decade now needed to save for a standard 20 per cent deposit for a house in most capital cities, according to a new report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38c95cfa820797d880fc1ce28df23757</guid></item><item><title>'AI slop' crowned word of the year 2025 in Macquarie Dictionary's committee and people's choice categories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/ai-slop-named-macquarie-dictionary-word-of-the-year-2025/106047682</link><description>'AI slop' refers to low-quality content created by generative AI which often contains errors and is not requested by the user, according to Macquarie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15f7be66dae9586a25cb96c8a7a6e510</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos star Ash Riddell wins AFLW best and fairest award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/kangaroos-star-ash-riddell-wins-aflw-best-and-fairest/106047276</link><description>Runner-up to Adelaide's Ebony Marinoff last year, Riddell polled 23 votes to add the league's highest individual honour to her fifth All-Australian selection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4e13d0c58d7930b4fa3c009703f0047</guid></item><item><title>Volodomyr Zelenskyy warns Ukraine peace plan cannot change borders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/us-ukraine-refined-peace-plan-russia-invasion-europe/106048192</link><description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy warns his country's borders "cannot be changed by force", highlighting a key sticking point in negotiations with the US over a potential peace deal with Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2f57d8e7891cd5275398dacbdbfc1e8</guid></item><item><title>US labels Maduro-tied Cartel de los Soles a terror organisation — but experts question whether it exists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/us-set-to-label-maduro-tied-cartel-as-a-terror-organisation/106048356</link><description>The designation — which is unusual, as experts say it isn't a real organisation — is the latest measure in the Trump administration's escalating campaign to combat drug trafficking into the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0e90bfc78d02c5d07b69ce808666767</guid></item><item><title>Xi Jinping tells Donald Trump Taiwan's 'return to China' is key to international post-war order</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/xi-jinping-and-donald-trump-reportedly-discuss-taiwan/106048382</link><description>Chinese state media reported some of what was discussed in the phone call that took place on Monday, local time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b434e31844f0d265c79cad94e0465a5</guid></item><item><title>Gaza Humanitarian Foundation closes as ceasefire holds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/gaza-humanitarian-foundation-closes/106048550</link><description>More than 800 Palestinians died in the vicinity of Gaza Humanitarian Foundation aid sites after it took over the distribution of all supplies in the strip in May.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71c7e704943714c236111d0736b4e75a</guid></item><item><title>Australia's first female supreme court chief justice has never thought of herself as a trailblazer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/today-in-history-november-25-marilyn-warren/105999384</link><description>Marilyn Warren made history when she was appointed chief justice of the Supreme Court of Victoria, though she has never thought of herself as a trailblazer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">246c15a6bfcdd28d684be6ec90de70f6</guid></item><item><title>ABC 50-50 quiz: Every question is an even chance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/abc-50-50-quiz/106031928</link><description>Every question has only two options, one is right and the other is wrong. You have an even chance of guessing correctly each time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d0f0aa8d8f16818ddf2cbeacbdb6638</guid></item><item><title>Court dismisses criminal cases against Donald Trump critics James Comey and Letitia James</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/james-comey-letitia-james-court-cases-dismissed/106048580</link><description>Former FBI director James Comey and New York Attorney-General Letitia James had been charged shortly after Donald Trump used social media to instruct his attorney-general to take action against them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">871d4405fd3fca7dbcee25ddbb509b8d</guid></item><item><title>Gambling ad ban would pass parliament with a conscience vote, Labor MP says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/gambling-advertising-ban-push-multi-partisan-support/106047600</link><description>Macarthur MP Mike Freelander believes the multi-partisan support for restricting gambling advertising means the reforms will "get there" eventually.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e33d844f39e4d1417a89e9b82f0353a</guid></item><item><title>Terminally ill man allegedly abused as a child at Ashley detention centre fights to access records</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/former-ashley-inmate-access-to-records-of-time-in-prison/106046056</link><description>The family of a dying man asked for his records from Tasmania's only youth detention centre, Ashley. They were told it could take eight months — time he does not have.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7212f1db7ad7d1f7718d838f33815e78</guid></item><item><title>Bitcoin crash unsettles financial markets, with 'contagion' fears surfacing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/cryptocurrency-fears-as-bitcoin-crash-unsettles-market/106044010</link><description>It's been a wild ride for bitcoin traders in recent months and, after a weekend of crypto and blockchain enthusiasm at a Sydney convention, sceptics continue to flag the risks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07e1206842ae36c450a4eab1f098a814</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Fina misses main communities in far north Kimberley and now category one</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/cyclone-fina-crosses-west-australian-coast/106045094</link><description>Cyclone Fina is tracking inland in WA's far north as a category one system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfbca7f72cfee3ef39aa03559834b258</guid></item><item><title>Emergency department wait times for mental health patients stretching over 23 hours, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/emergency-wait-times-for-mental-health-stretch-out/106044964</link><description>New data shows some patients with serious mental health conditions have been waiting more than 23 hours for a bed in emergency departments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45ece3d20457fd9ca050c0ac0da5d45b</guid></item><item><title>Why APRA wants to slowly deflate the property bubble</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/apra-wants-to-deflate-australian-property-bubble/106046326</link><description>Amid global warnings of impending financial doom, APRA and the Reserve Bank are far more concerned about a home-grown bubble, one that's been taking in oxygen for almost three decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c8d98576355ba43ca8f264e08a431ae</guid></item><item><title>The 28-point peace plan for Ukraine mostly contains the same points previously made by Moscow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/what-we-know-about-the-28-point-plan-for-peace/106046140</link><description>A detailed look at the 28-point plan — as it has been reported — shows some very minor concessions to Russia. But it mostly contains all the same points that have always been made with more or less force by Moscow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bd44ea75eb058665f413b545a812ea8</guid></item><item><title>Marufa Akter is inspiring Bangladeshi girls in a 'revolution' for women's cricket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/marufa-akter-bangladesh-womens-cricket-revolution/105993656</link><description>From ploughing rice fields during COVID, Marufa Akter’s remarkable rise to Bangladesh cricket star has inspired a generation of girls to take up cricket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09250b5262fc7064211e2f64187fbb7c</guid></item><item><title>Andor and Death by Lightning costumer designer Michael Wilkinson creates worlds with fabric</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/michael-wilkinson-costume-designer-andor-death-by-lightning/103577456</link><description>Michael Wilkinson won an Emmy for his intricate costumes in the celebrated Star Wars series Andor. Now, he is recreating 1880s America for Death By Lightning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d44e7c4f2be635334da31336676aa21</guid></item><item><title>Sydney architect Anthony Dibden, 78, jailed over 'disturbing' images of child abuse material</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/lane-cove-architect-anthony-dibden-convicted-child-abuse-materia/106045060</link><description>His crimes were so disturbing some police sources described it as the worst case of child abuse material they have ever seen in their careers. The man at the centre of it could be released next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">769deea839070616f3cbd5cfcdd7bb39</guid></item><item><title>Sydney photographer Gavin Libotte captures 'magic in mundane' with Wanderland collection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/sydney-street-photographer-gavin-libotte-wanderland-collection/106005106</link><description>Animals and objects dwarf humans in Gavin Libotte's unique perspective on suburban life, challenging the way we see the familiar world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddc677d641ae0f32a98aeffd59c400c0</guid></item><item><title>Yancoal begins plans to extend life of central Queensland coal mine to 2070</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/yancoal-central-queensland-coal-mine-extension-plans/106037050</link><description>Yancoal begins plans to extend the life of its central Queensland coal mine, which would see roughly 74 million tonnes of coal extracted over the life of the mine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4193c08b972127a904e0a454173cd539</guid></item><item><title>Experts respond to myths and truths around living with migraine and how to get treated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/living-with-migraine-myths-and-truths/106036406</link><description>More than 1,000 people got in touch directly with the ABC to share their experiences with migraine and now the experts have weighed in.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63e05a96e13f6dbab849c8f0314945de</guid></item><item><title>Portland Trail Blazers NBA coach Chauncey Billups pleads not guilty in rigged poker case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/nba-portland-trail-blazers-chauncey-billups-pleads-not-guilty/106048692</link><description>Portland Trail Blazers coach Chauncey Billups appears at a federal courthouse in the United States, pleading not guilty to a series of charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33b67881344f801a413897edbb862777</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: Pauline Hanson suspended from Senate for seven sitting days over 'disrespectful' burka stunt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/federal-politics-live-nov-25/106047174</link><description>One Nation leader Pauline Hanson has been censured by the Senate and suspended for seven sitting days, a day after she wore a burka in the chamber to push for the garment's ban. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">794169b51c4293e066e74fbde1d44400</guid></item><item><title>Victorian government blocked fire service from pursuing US giant over PFAS contamination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/fire-rescue-victoria-pfas-3m-lawsuit-blocked-state-government/106044128</link><description>The ABC can reveal that in 2023 the Victorian government blocked Fire Rescue Victoria from pursuing legal action against PFAS manufacturer 3M.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af5e87b33d10b9249f00d5323898e221</guid></item><item><title>Cloncurry copper mine set to inject $17 billion into Queensland's economy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/harmony-gold-green-lights-eva-copper-project-cloncurry/106048642</link><description>South Africa's largest gold producer, Harmony Gold, has officially signed off on a significant outback copper mine that is set to boost Queensland's economy by $17 billion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3aee1dc676faca1ea5427b204f925c7</guid></item><item><title>1800 Respect gets funding boost ahead of final women's ministers meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/1800-respect-gets-funding-boost-ahead-of-meeting/106048784</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a4a41aefbf375a42e01582262acae1f</guid></item><item><title>Youth homelessness crisis exacerbated by rental market and demand for public housing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/youth-homelessness-service-demand-surges-amid-housing-crisis/105973714</link><description>Youth homelessness support services say the pandemic and an associated surge in real estate prices have made it even harder to secure accommodation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96aec2c16e14594fe7355c6ed1d665c2</guid></item><item><title>Ash Riddell credits Kangaroos teammate Jasmine Garner after winning AFLW best and fairest award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/aflw-best-and-fairest-ash-riddell-jasmine-garner-kangaroos/106048756</link><description>Ash Riddell says her close relationship with North Melbourne teammate Jasmine Garner helped her win the AFLW's best and fairest award.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5607eafc02165d17cffa3820a0888ac3</guid></item><item><title>Tiwi Islanders tell of 'pretty terrifying' night as Tropical Cyclone Fina battered homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/nt-tiwi-islands-severe-tropical-cyclone-fina-damage-recovery/106044336</link><description>While Darwin experienced the outer edge of Severe Tropical Cyclone Fina this weekend, the eye of the storm came much closer to the Tiwi Islands. Locals in Wurrumiyanga share their experiences with the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88684b878eac2f3702f5052b8f9e4c63</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of women missing out on program dubbed maternity 'gold standard' care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/midwifery-group-practice-program-gold-standard-care/106044292</link><description>A free "gold standard" antenatal care program is proving hugely popular and successful, but women are scrambling to get access.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e097dedd701ae89c22f4ae1e488f6a86</guid></item><item><title>Markets live updates: Bendigo Bank shares dive on money laundering worries, ASX flat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/asx-markets-business-live-news-25-nov/106048786</link><description>Australian shares are trading flat, despite Wall Street extending a tech-led rebound overnight. Bendigo and Adelaide Bank shares plunge more than 7 per cent after "deficiencies" in anti-money laundering systems are uncovered. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6061900c7330739edff911117da0d170</guid></item><item><title>90,000 households without power and 11 damaged schools closed after south-east Queensland storms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/residents-without-power-queensland-storms/106048734</link><description>About 90,000 households remain without power and 11 state schools are closed after giant hailstones, destructive winds and intense lightning lashed south-east Queensland, with more extreme weather on the way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96877d27b3b04dca882c586192a585d4</guid></item><item><title>More storms predicted amid 'very unsettled' Queensland weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/storms-queensland-very-unsettled-weather-tuesday/106044748</link><description>Storm-battered south-east Queensland is on alert again today while other regions endure a blistering heatwave as instability grips the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94389a8ece67fe8a8fa3ef8fe1c92aea</guid></item><item><title>Pep Guardiola apologises to camera operator after confrontation in Manchester City's Premier League loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/premier-league-pep-guardiola-apologises-camera-operator/106048840</link><description>Manchester City manager Pep Guardiola apologises to a camera operator after an incident during his side's Premier League defeat at Newcastle United.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb039c2d99cb2c23fea8cecb9f2c8f0e</guid></item><item><title>Next generation of home owners priced out of WA towns they grew up in as median hits $1 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/south-west-million-dollar-club/106028132</link><description>South-west residents are worried they have been priced out of their home towns after research revealed the region is WA's most expensive area, with nine suburbs now boasting a seven-figure median house price.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75d2bfc99e75bdff01ff3e4b857b5246</guid></item><item><title>China's regional trade pact bid derails as Australia stalls and Japan tensions deepen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/china-japan-trans-pacific-partnership-australia-trade/106045604</link><description>China's escalating confrontation with Japan is colliding directly with its attempt to join one of the world's most demanding trade agreements.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69e3b2863001d8925873d7711d97d8e3</guid></item><item><title>Will the WA government's 'Perth Park' rebrand of Burswood motorsport precinct win over doubters?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/perth-park-governments-latest-rebranding-street-circuit/106045790</link><description>The WA government will be hoping its second crack at rebranding this project will capture the public's imagination, or it may be back to the drawing board.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50c7e8ecbeb4f4ec81eda17a42f16744</guid></item><item><title>Everton's Idrissa Gueye sent off for slapping teammate Michael Keane in Premier League match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/idrissa-gueye-michael-keane-everton-slap-red-card-premier-league/106048932</link><description>Idrissa Gueye is involved in a heated moment with Michael Keane during Everton's Premier League match against Manchester United.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d6e163678227986bf73960629bcdbd5</guid></item><item><title>Elderly woman charged over alleged hit-run crash that killed six-year-old boy in Teesdale</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/woman-charged-over-fatal-teesdale-march-crash/106049036</link><description>An 84-year-old woman is facing charges including fail to render assistance following the fatal collision west of Geelong in March.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c077c928f8a540a29384eee575b9e476</guid></item><item><title>Trees toppled, cars crushed and thousands without power: Tropical Cyclone Fina in pictures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/nt-severe-tropical-cyclone-fina-in-pictures-2025-storm-damage/106046118</link><description>The rare November cyclone, with wind gusts at its core reaching almost 200km/h, pushed over massive trees and damaged homes, cars and infrastructure when it passed Darwin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5425dae09f117c26a47c1f20e706e842</guid></item><item><title>Child murderer Bevan Spencer von Einem has short time to live, ABC understands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/sa-bevan-spencer-von-einem-in-yatala-infirmary/106047868</link><description>The ABC understands convicted child murderer Bevan Spencer von Einem has been taken to the Yatala infirmary in Adelaide where he only has a short time to live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">944a183101c1d73208a0e66f883b140c</guid></item><item><title>Historic pay deal with Uber Eats and DoorDash could set minimum pay for gig economy delivery workers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/minimum-wage-for-gig-workers-in-historic-deal-uber-eats-doordash/106048976</link><description>A deal between the Transport Workers Union and Australia's two largest on-demand delivery platforms looks set to rewrite the meaning of gig economy work, if it is approved by the Fair Work Commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40eb03c18c3becf155802cb33a951a6d</guid></item><item><title>Walkabout Creek Hotel from Crocodile Dundee sells after three years on the market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/crocodile-dundee-pub-the-walkabout-creek-hotel-sells/106048772</link><description>Famous worldwide, the Walkabout Creek Hotel has been sold for an undisclosed sum. The previous owners have retired, passing the reins to a young local family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13834599f4cedf0665f16a054f6b1836</guid></item><item><title>How Ash Riddell's rise to become AFLW's best mirrors Kangaroos' dominance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/aflw-ash-riddell-best-and-fairest-north-melbourne-kangaroos/106049038</link><description>Overlooked in multiple drafts before making her debut in 2019, North Melbourne's Ash Riddell is now the best player in the league.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b051580800df3932d5dc39a866fdb856</guid></item><item><title>Townsville man advocates for pancreatic cancer awareness after diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/malcolm-stephens-pancreatic-cancer-awareness-terminal-diagnosis/106028808</link><description>A Townsville man says there were no warning signs before he was told he had terminal cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7921e071781941a4550acd0ae98b079</guid></item><item><title>Roof ripped off property at Bribie Island during south-east Queensland storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/roof-ripped-off-property-bribie-island/106049582</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56a4d756624e5b0faca451438920a3a8</guid></item><item><title>Hanson burka stunt 'abhorrent' and left senators feeling 'unsafe': Payman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/hanson-burka-stunt-abhorrent-and-left-senators-feeling/106048990</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18db566df90ddf392e67de7f0ff537c5</guid></item><item><title>Pauline Hanson cooks Barnaby Joyce steaks on a sandwich press</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/pauline-hanson-steak-sandwich-press/106049588</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64430ec7074db21e27424b977534086c</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios's Australian Open wildcard campaign boosted with Kooyong Classic entry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/kyrgios-australian-open-wildcard-bid-heats-up-with-kooyong-entry/106049462</link><description>Nick Kyrgios's Australian Open wildcard campaign is on in earnest after the former Wimbledon runner-up was announced in the Kooyong Classic exhibition field.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">784d830bb0a03ea0b4a45c5888dcdded</guid></item><item><title>Teen charged with murder over Rouse Hill stabbing faces court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/rouse-hill-stabbing-15-year-old-faces-court/106049804</link><description>The 15-year-old allegedly fatally stabbed a 17-year-old boy on Monday a reserve in Rouse Hill in an "unprovoked attack".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a4157b10d3e9cb85700634a7d080c18</guid></item><item><title>Sister Kate's site to become home to Perth's first Aboriginal aged care facility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/sister-kate-perth-first-aboriginal-aged-care-home/106033104</link><description>The 100-bed facility will be constructed on a site where Stolen Generations were taken to against the will of their parents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02365fa4b61b4f91a0cd6ae1e3a54acc</guid></item><item><title>Soldiers Beach drowning victim remembered as 'a remarkable young man'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/nsw-central-coast-drowning-beach-safety-concerns-norah-head/106048794</link><description>The Central Coast Council will consider safety improvements at a popular NSW beach as loved ones pay tribute to 18-year-old Riahne Louie Vasquez, who drowned while swimming with friends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edf3844b4135d6939c8b7a4b74abc5ff</guid></item><item><title>Joel Cauchi's psychiatrist gave 'wildly inconsistent' evidence, Bondi Junction Westfield attack inquest hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/bondi-junction-westfield-attack-cauchi-psychiatrist-inconsistent/106049828</link><description>The counsel assisting the coroner says Joel Cauchi's former psychiatrist showed an "exceptional level of belligerence and confrontation" at the inquest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fd6784ce1d94d163f9ebeb9679dce60</guid></item><item><title>What's feeding our fascination for murder mysteries and crime series?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/return-to-paradise-cosy-crime-why-we-like-murder-mystery/106019206</link><description>In an era of grim news and uncertainty, audiences are consistently drawn to murder mysteries. But what's behind that enduring fascination for the genre?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c433d85e0e4d20e45dbf82946d8e22c</guid></item><item><title>Bird flu confirmed in elephant seal population at Heard Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/avian-influenza-h5-bird-flu-found-on-heard-island/106050412</link><description>The federal government says testing confirms the presence of avian influenza in samples collected from southern elephant seals on Heard Island — a sub-Antarctic Australian external territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db1909e437b8539ed789301ea69ab7ad</guid></item><item><title>'We all want that feeling that music gives us': Franz Ferdinand on what's stayed the same</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/franz-ferdinand-on-what-hasn-t-changed-since-1975/106050076</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f198795fe300c4a41acd579e38c711f</guid></item><item><title>Sydney man avoids jail over $100,000 anti-Israel vandalism spree</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/no-jail-man-alleged-100-000-anti-israel-sydney-crime-spree/106049888</link><description>The court heard Thomas Stojanovski was financially motivated to help fund his illicit substance abuse for an injury he was dealing with at the time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76de88671ba23815b80cc3e047dd769b</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne man fabricated evidence to cover up house party rape, County Court trial hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/melbourne-man-faces-trial-alleged-house-party-rape/106050218</link><description>A Melbourne man engaged in "deceptive" conduct when he raped a woman during a house party and tried to cover it up, prosecutors say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd2b45266609d3c1addee305be4f7b92</guid></item><item><title>London 'tourist tax' proposed for Australians and other international travellers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/uk-looking-at-london-tourist-tax-for-international-travellers/106049490</link><description>Australians heading to London could soon pay a new "tourist tax" on accommodation, as the as the British government moves to give cities across England the power to impose levies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eff43a91d9e63697e88789b7594d9aba</guid></item><item><title>Detainees involved in rooftop protest at Banksia Hill detention centre moved to Unit 18</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/banksia-hill-youth-detention-roof-protest-fallout/106049434</link><description>WA's corrective services minister says three of the youths involved in last night's disturbance at Perth's juvenile detention centre have been moved to the notorious Unit 18, as he continued to take a hardline stance on youth detention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bf12a3ddc7783e7b438b8c86672335e</guid></item><item><title>Veteran journalist Niki Savva reflects on the 2025 federal election in her new book Earthquake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/veteran-journalist-niki-savva-reflects-on-the-election/106050042</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e51ba625a8d74a4644b900525597c82</guid></item><item><title>Children removed from Australian-British couple living off-grid in Italian forest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/italian-court-removes-children-off-grid-australian-uk-couple/106049422</link><description>The family's alternative lifestyle came under scrutiny after the British-Australian couple and their three children were hospitalised last year with mushroom poisoning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f228341e12ae3c043f7b7a54adebd34</guid></item><item><title>Nauru president says NZYQ members could go home in interview about secretive deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/nauru-president-says-nzyq-could-go-home-/105982474</link><description>David Adeang said in an interview conducted in Nauruan that members of the NZYQ cohort could be returned to their home countries and suggested Australia should remain partially responsible for finding a longer-term solution for the group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89c364b0307b977adbe565ba87ad5cfc</guid></item><item><title>Solomon Islands and Australia's $190 million policing deal delayed over 'language' disagreement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/australia-solomon-islands-police-deal-slow-progress/106049880</link><description>Australia and Solomon Islands have made little progress on a $190 million package to expand the Pacific nation’s police force, almost a full year after the high-profile initiative was announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f8bfa2cf911ee2c032325b359e598ff</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos star Ash Riddell on winning the AFLW best and fairest award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/kangaroos-star-ash-riddell-on-winning-the-aflw-best/106049750</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7859a6da58235d08777a9a863fd15b9</guid></item><item><title>Cameron Smith trying to relax as he prepares for Australian PGA Championship in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/cameron-smith-australian-pga-championship-preparation/106050692</link><description>Cameron Smith admits he has felt every poor shot and poor round more than ever this season, but he will not reinvent himself to arrest the slide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dca9243ef077f59fb13fd929dfd79e4</guid></item><item><title>Jakarta overtakes Tokyo as world's largest city, according to UN</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/jakarta-overtakes-tokyo-as-worlds-largest-city/106049122</link><description>For decades Tokyo held the title of the most populous city on the planet. Yet the Indonesian and Bangladeshi capitals have overtaken the Japanese megacity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00d1c87a49d7134a4b5a7082ebd15cd2</guid></item><item><title>Superannuation giant Cbus ordered to pay penalty for breaking law over death and disability insurance claims handling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/superannuation-cbus-court-penalty-for-death-disability-claims/106046686</link><description>Superannuation giant Cbus will pay a $23.5 million fine after admitting it breached the law over major delays in its handling of insurance claims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07b2a951c5928e66469310e3b4652c1b</guid></item><item><title>Labor to squeeze public service, sparking warnings of job losses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/labor-to-squeeeze-public-service/106050668</link><description>After it campaigned against a Coalition pledge to cut 41,000 public servants, Labor is ramping up its own efficiency drive in a move expected to cost jobs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5670fcbadb8db958abbf3b9c7651badb</guid></item><item><title>Rare earth element exploration in early stages in SA Mallee region, with more drill testing to come</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/rare-earth-element-exploration-in-murray-mallee-region/106042826</link><description>A publicly listed resources exploration company says it will conduct further testing in early 2026 after initial drill samples show promising results.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7707ba8a5dfea83189e2af94f6e79c1</guid></item><item><title>US revokes immigration status for Myanmar nationals, points to 'sham' elections as progress</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/us-ends-temporary-status-myanmar-nationals-elections-progress/106050086</link><description>The US government is ending the temporary legal status of thousands of Myanmar nationals arguing they can safely return to the war-torn South-East Asian country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c9deb25577ed157e549567b6a12f7d0</guid></item><item><title>TasNetworks says 'large' executive payouts are due to legacy entitlements that no longer exist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/tasnetworks-legacy-entitlement-executive-payouts/106050224</link><description>Tasmania's state-owned electricity distributor says a wave of executives receiving six-figure termination payments will, in the end, save the utility money in the long run.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8772a5f6cef5623b07f721b6e81f141e</guid></item><item><title>Thousands to endure heatwave without power, as Sunshine Coast towns hit by intense storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/sunshine-coast-hail-coolum-storm-heatwave/106049686</link><description>A Queensland coastal town may go without power for days in heatwave conditions as it cleans up after a ferocious storm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ada9be3ed8aa2676d07b3dfc951f7b4</guid></item><item><title>West Coast Eagles draftee Josh Lindsay wants to carry on Troy Selwood's legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/west-coast-eagles-draftee-josh-lindsay-honours-troy-selwood/106051186</link><description>West Coast draftee Josh Lindsay has opened up about the devastation of losing his mentor Troy Selwood, saying the former Brisbane tagger played a vital role in helping him get on an AFL list.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61866e29459853828234c4031eb7c730</guid></item><item><title>How to take care of yourself online postpartum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/taking-care-online-during-postpartum/106045302</link><description>New mum Hannah Gheller says social media became a “shame-inducing tool” during the early postpartum weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc70621ab3e58cbf4f4b7f8ce8d1a3b0</guid></item><item><title>Matthew William Lawson jailed after severing Trae Black's leg in violent City Beach attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/matthew-lawson-jailed-over-attack-on-trae-black-in-city-beach/106051028</link><description>A man who severed a workmate's leg before viciously assaulting him with a demolition hammer during a violent attack in Perth's western suburbs is sentenced to 14 years in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0c6ad1b4fa1591cc77331c141fe2781</guid></item><item><title>New location feature on Elon Musk's X 'weaponised' to spread misinformation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/social-media-x-location-feature-user-trust/106045476</link><description>Social media platform X launched a new location tool globally over the weekend to "verify authenticity" of profiles, but some experts says the tool has breached user trust and increased misinformation on the platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9633eac8463321850a1f0c9b7e75494f</guid></item><item><title>Luxury tourism resort Berkeley River Lodge suffers 'significant damage' in Cyclone Fina direct hit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/tropical-cyclone-fina-impacts-luxury-resort-berkeley-river-/106050682</link><description>A luxury wilderness resort only accessible by sea and air has been significantly damaged in a direct hit from Severe Tropical Cyclone Fina, which made landfall in an extremely remote part of WA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">892ce3017b1a66dffc907098cdc0f0f5</guid></item><item><title>Service NSW Centre windows damaged in Dubbo storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/service-nsw-centre-windows-damaged-in-dubbo-storm/106051070</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">835fa0199cf9ea242a81120b3801e176</guid></item><item><title>Images of a dust storm at Griffith.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/dust-storm-at-griffith/106051020</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f70eed33a6ab326052917e3e926ebfa5</guid></item><item><title>Damaging winds close Dubbo's Service NSW Centre as severe weather hits inland NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/wild-winds-damage-windows-at-dubbo-service-nsw/106050664</link><description>Wild winds of up to 100 kilometres per hour have battered inland New South Wales, with strong gusts knocking out the windows of a Service NSW building in Dubbo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6d4bf8dcf6ca76346908270ab9cdc5d</guid></item><item><title>Menulog signs commercial agreement with Uber Eats before ceasing operations in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/menulog-uber-eats-commercial-agreement/106050600</link><description>Uber Eats says the partnership allows a "smooth transition" for Menulog customers before the service ceases operations in Australia on November 26.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07d8e436971c10f2a5b1397e7b0d3868</guid></item><item><title>Vision of the storm that brought trees down near Poona</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/vision-of-the-storm-that-brought-trees-down-near-poona/106051352</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e696a22fc508e0ab7b335be2df38b3ad</guid></item></channel></rss>