<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 09:00:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Brain research centre The Florey sues executive, alleging he stole and erased files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/the-florey-brain-research-centre-files-claims-against-executive/106135388</link><description>Australia's biggest brain research centre is suing one of its executives, alleging he deleted troves of commercially sensitive information during a midnight incursion at its Melbourne laboratory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8345d1270fa7ecf8c2167fcfa10b7f08</guid></item><item><title>Photographing penguins in Antarctica</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/leila-jeffreys-photographing-penguins-antarctica/106136800</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f292e504bf8faabeea539a3c5e5b979c</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic Arts Fellowship allows artists to develop works on the ice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/australian-antarctic-arts-fellowship/106139246</link><description>Over the past four decades, the Australian Antarctic Arts Fellowship has given creatives the opportunity to travel south and develop works on the icy continent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">574f0d2516ef3270e6679d6ed8e90ea9</guid></item><item><title>Retiring captain Elyse Villani says Hurricanes' WBBL win shows team's potential</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/hurricanes-captain-elyse-villani-retires-after-wbbl-win/106141334</link><description>Elyse Villani has described the Hurricanes' win as a "fairy tale" ending to her WBBL career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">111f91f49499824a5d1f69e7c6e6f83c</guid></item><item><title>Superannuation funds accused of delaying disability insurance claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/super-funds-accused-of-poor-handling-of-tpd-insurance-claims/106050046</link><description>The regulator has found that while some superannuation funds have improved insurance claims response times, others are still falling short, with long delays in relation to mental health claims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed72917ef5a3d4a0f3e4254687d92da</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting death toll rises as police scour crime scene after terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/nsw-sydney-bondi-beach-shooting-hanukkah-jewish-community/106141648</link><description>Fifteen people and one of two gunmen are confirmed to have died after the attack on Sunday evening as members of the Jewish community attended a Hanukkah event in the city's eastern suburbs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f396411115ff090ddac9ce77ff86537f</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting updates: PM to strengthen gun laws across Australia following Bondi attack — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-beach-shooting-terrorist-attack/106142446</link><description>Fifteen people were killed, including a 10-year-old girl. One of the two gunmen has also died, while a further 42 people were taken to hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53ed92f5b0514ac2d2ce9a3d9c4074e1</guid></item><item><title>Cooper Connolly stars as Perth Scorchers down Sydney Sixers in BBL opener</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/scorchers-down-sixers-bbl-opener/106142124</link><description>Cooper Connolly leads the Scorchers to victory as star Sixers recruit Babar Azam struggles in the BBL curtain raiser at Perth Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50698296472667855f8c9cd66d6cabac</guid></item><item><title>Mildura council, Mallee Family Care to face tribunal over $28m building without valid permit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/mildura-council-mallee-care-building-without-permit-vcat/106140872</link><description>A Victorian tribunal will investigate whether Mallee Family Care and Mildura Rural City Council could have breached planning permit rules.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">701c81a555e0dc1879cde61932844b2b</guid></item><item><title>ASIO examined Bondi Beach gunman Naveed Akram in 2019 for close ties to Islamic State cell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-beach-attack-gunmen-father-and-son/106142630</link><description>Australia's domestic intelligence agency, ASIO, examined one of the Bondi Beach gunmen six years ago for his close ties to a Sydney-based Islamic State terrorism cell, the ABC understands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61d8702038585ef6be9d3817b6662640</guid></item><item><title>Kendrick Lamar delights young fan with birthday song at Canberra Spilt Milk festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/kendrick-lamar-serenades-young-fan-at-canberra-spilt-milk/106142574</link><description>American rap superstar Kendrick Lamar brought the house down at Spilt Milk in Canberra, but it was his interaction with a nine-year-old superfan that stole the show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16ca55a20161d6ca4cbf526e3b6f236a</guid></item><item><title>England warned Adelaide pitch is not as friendly as it looks ahead of third Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/ashes-adelaide-test-england-warned-pitch-not-friendly/106142732</link><description>With England pinning its hopes on victory in the third Test, the tourists have been warned that the Adelaide pitch is not as friendly as it looks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aec1d41e99ee9fd7c4c64bcffb15282b</guid></item><item><title>Hollow Knight: Silksong, Death Stranding 2 and Donkey Kong Bananza among our best games of 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/video-games-end-of-year-wrap-2025/106038598</link><description>There are games to suit everyone, and overwhelmingly Australians are a game-playing nation. Here are some of the most important titles released this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">213c78332ceb94cd8515daaa19a2dc06</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley accuses Albanese of failing to keep Jewish Australians safe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/albanese-told-to-endorse-antisemitism-plan-after-bondi-shooting/106142578</link><description>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley says Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has allowed antisemitism to "fester" and failed to keep Jewish Australians safe in the wake of yesterday's "evil" terror attack on the shores of Bondi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b45fc7ff1574ff3e49240c068f74667d</guid></item><item><title>WA's wettest towns have had no local drinking water for 15 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/wa-wettest-towns-drinking-water-carting/106120700</link><description>Quinninup and Northcliffe in Western Australia's south-west receive an average of 1 metre of rain every year, so why has the state government spent millions of dollars trucking in drinking water?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b73df9467313d7d89bd980191d5e1a4</guid></item><item><title>Matildas star Sam Kerr impresses again for Chelsea in WSL after starting as sub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/matildas-star-sam-kerr-impresses-again-for-chelsea-in-wsl/106143024</link><description>Matildas gun Sam Kerr starts on the bench again, but makes an immediate impact for Chelsea in a 3-0 WSL victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e34c904b76ecd95d28f27217323aecd</guid></item><item><title>Kahu's been woodchopping his whole life, but a heart attack mid-competition almost killed him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/axeman-brought-back-to-life-after-heart-attack/106113688</link><description>Kahu Woolley was clinically dead multiple times, but quick actions by his friends brought him back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cf809b3bb5a37d997237793fca40e31</guid></item><item><title>Australians urged to give blood in wake of Bondi Beach mass shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-shooting-how-to-help-call-for-blood-donations/106142864</link><description>NSW Premier Chris Minns urges community members wanting to help the Jewish community following the Bondi terror attack to donate blood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63d91f901c3614f575701fabeb7f39f0</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Police ramp up presence at Jewish places of worship after Bondi mass shooting, as public Hanukkah events cancelled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/qld-police-meet-review-security-arrangements-bondi-shooting/106143320</link><description>Queensland Police Acting Commissioner Cheryl Scanlon says authorities are not aware of any specific threats to the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">deca6f8205be81b067e5b4bd6a025549</guid></item><item><title>Parole release of Snowtown murderer James Vlassakis overturned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/sa-snowtown-murderer-james-vlassakis-parole-overturned/106143062</link><description>Snowtown serial killer James Vlassakis will remain behind bars, after the South Australian Parole Board's decision to release him was overturned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54e1e8b751e40e2d894b77e66170274a</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese will face questions over Bondi Beach shooting as Australia mourns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/anthony-albanese-bondi-terror-attack-sussan-ley-mike-burgess/106143400</link><description>Anthony Albanese's first responsibility after the horrific Bondi terror attack is to lead a grieving nation. His next will be to explain how this happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6338d979d5dcf6d65657f254be1bde4f</guid></item><item><title>What videos tell us about the final moments of the Bondi Beach terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/abc-news-verify-bondi-beach-terrorist-last-six-minutes/106143126</link><description>In the final horrific minutes of the Bondi Beach terror attack, more than 100 shots were fired. ABC NEWS Verify has analysed footage showing how the last six minutes unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a855c002e49658b5a61e812833f1e71</guid></item><item><title>Inquest to probe death of Allan John Houston at Saraji mine in 2018</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/inquest-for-death-of-allan-john-houston-at-saraji-mine-in-2018/106143884</link><description>The veteran miner died when the bulldozer he was operating rolled off an embankment into a pool of mud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55c0604be4bff0f1b094511f5bc1eaa7</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong media mogul Jimmy Lai found guilty of sedition and collusion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/hong-kong-media-mogul-jimmy-lai-guilty-sedition-collusion/106143206</link><description>Jimmy Lai, a former Hong Kong media mogul and one of the city's most outspoken critics of China, has been found guilty of sedition and collusion in a landmark national security case that has drawn international scrutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b999a3880da2cb74b288fabc6b5fd306</guid></item><item><title>Deaths of Rob Reiner and wife investigated as apparent homicide, LAPD says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/two-found-dead-at-rob-reiners-home-brentwood/106145062</link><description>Rob Reiner, known for directing When Harry Met Sally... and A Few Good Men, was found dead alongside his wife inside their Los Angeles home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d04a94b290cb0635eec136bb99bef983</guid></item><item><title>Man convicted of kidnapping 19yo Charlie Gander now eligible for parole</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/danny-clarke-convicted-of-kidnapping-eligible-for-parole/106137450</link><description>A judge says the offending of a man found guilty of kidnapping a Victorian 19-year-old, who was later murdered, was "spontaneous" and "born of panic".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ead77bc71a42109697426dd3359607aa</guid></item><item><title>National cabinet agrees unanimously to strengthen Australia's strict gun laws in wake of Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/albanese-proposes-tougher-gun-laws-after-bondi-attack/106143310</link><description>An urgent meeting of national cabinet agrees to strengthen Australia's gun laws in the wake of the Bondi Beach shooting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e758b09f0c99d1348b909c0f9e2e87a</guid></item><item><title>Man who killed two people in Bowen Bridge crash sentenced to home detention and community service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/death-by-negligent-driving-bowen-bridge-sentence/106143712</link><description>A man who caused the death of an elderly couple while driving with methamphetamine in his blood is ordered to complete 100 hours of community service and four months of home detention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb2e47144ce2e8a2f0896e8526ff92b3</guid></item><item><title>WA government meets with Jewish leaders after Bondi beach terror attack, increased police patrols</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/wa-government-meets-with-jewish-leaders-after-bondi-attack/106143968</link><description>WA Premier Roger Cook condemns the "cowardly and heinous" attack in Bondi, after meeting with Jewish leaders in Perth as police increase patrols.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aebd956f068195b9dae5bb04c75acfc7</guid></item><item><title>NSW inquest told how exploding lithium-ion batteries caused volatile fires killing three</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/lithium-battery-fire-inquest/106143100</link><description>A NSW inquest has been told exploding lithium-ion batteries caused volatile fires killing three people in separate blazes within minutes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45b2521beb7a85c63b52380d119cbe74</guid></item><item><title>Consolidated Pastoral Company buys Beetaloo aggregation in historic deal worth more than $300m</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/cpc-buys-beetaloo-station-aggregation-for-300-million-plus/106143408</link><description>Consolidated Pastoral Company spends more than $300 million to buy the Beetaloo aggregation of stations in the NT.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49aa2ab64911fd8e49ebe2728109def3</guid></item><item><title>Harry Brook will rein in batting technique as England confirm team change for Adelaide Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/harry-brook-adelaide-test-cricket-bazball/106145512</link><description>As England reveal their changes for the Adelaide Test, Harry Brook has conceded he will rein in his batting technique in an effort to save the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08d7ea0d4a671a1c52d26ce33f1bcc66</guid></item><item><title>From barbecues to busy weeknights, here are seven salads to prepare this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/best-easy-summer-salads/106090760</link><description>Summer is the season for salad, and in that spirit, we've gathered seven of our finest together for you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a893c2c3c550d95330f8fcc101b821c</guid></item><item><title>Bondi's antisemitic attack is the Jewish diaspora's worst nightmare come true</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/benjamin-netanyahu-anthony-albanese-bondi-massacre/106144038</link><description>Israeli politicians have blamed Anthony Albanese for the devastating massacre in Bondi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93258c51718a7305f368056d7988e502</guid></item><item><title>What is Hanukkah, the Jewish festival being celebrated before the Bondi Beach terrorist attack?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/hanukkah-chanukah-jewish-holiday-candles-menorah/106143052</link><description>Also spelt Chanukah, the eight-day celebration observed by Jewish people around the world carries a message of resilience and positivity — one that a Melbourne rabbi said would endure despite the Bondi Beach terrorist attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89cf5b5fb3f6fd35ca69ac32e730ca4a</guid></item><item><title>New Queensland hospital bed timeline reveals some pushed back to 2032</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/queensland-hospital-beds-expansion-plan-pushed-back/106142866</link><description>The Queensland LNP government says it aims to roll out 2,600 new hospital beds across the state by 2032 at a cost of about $18.5 billion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0f70e307f0a646af575be863068b029</guid></item><item><title>As medicinal cannabis approvals surge, regulation sits on the fence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/medicinal-cannabis-approvals-alan-kohler/106146088</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f52809e4d9aa8ad5a5d7986ce32b28ff</guid></item><item><title>CAR T-cell cancer therapy to be available in SA from mid-2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/cart-t-cell-cancer-therapy-sa-royal-adelaide-hospital-mid-2026/106145758</link><description>The number of critical patients having to travel interstate to receive CAR T-cell therapy will be reduced from mid-next year, with SA to launch a service at the Royal Adelaide Hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ae439e4e2397dd9c07932e389d511f8</guid></item><item><title>Nathan Lyon insists he has nothing to prove in Adelaide ahead of Test return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/nathan-lyon-adelaide-ashes-england/106146112</link><description>For the first time in an age Nathan Lyon is not an automatic selection in the Test side but the returning off spinner insists he has nothing to prove ahead of the upcoming clash with England in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97c540c4314a16e1aaf6f5acb8364799</guid></item><item><title>Largest Western Power outage in 15 years cuts essential mobile phone services in firegrounds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/western-power-outage-firefighters-mobile/106144026</link><description>Firefighters are left without communications while battling emergency-level bushfires as an extended power outage sees mobile phone towers fail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c3c9a457b6b4b4e000fe93d9490541c</guid></item><item><title>How to talk to your kids about the Bondi Beach shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/talking-to-kids-about-bondi-shooting-terror-attack/106143526</link><description>This is what psychologists have to say about approaching the subject with children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9576f64cd4cb9ccb08452a02745df59</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106146368</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94742278037ce655405db43417aa2f4a</guid></item><item><title>Four dead, five hospitalised after minivan crashes near Victoria–New South Wales border</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/victoria-four-dead-in-car-crash/106146620</link><description>Police say they are responding to a crash that has claimed the lives of four people near Cobram in Victoria's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac7ff04f0322194ccb615a188f90cfbe</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder of woman in Adelaide's parklands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/man-charged-with-murdering-woman-in-adelaide-parklands/106146510</link><description>Police have arrested a 37-year-old man for the alleged murder of a woman who was found unresponsive in Adelaide's parklands in January.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b9fdeadd6941ea76da4164d30f3f01f</guid></item><item><title>Suzi Milgate defends crepe attack on former NT chief minister Natasha Fyles as 'protest', during assault trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/suzi-milgate-nt-chief-minister-crepe-assault-trial-evidence/106144734</link><description>A former Darwin real estate agent charged with assaulting the Northern Territory's then-chief minister with a plate of crepes has tried to justify her actions as a "protest" against COVID-19 rules.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2ae2ac70dd50b27bd25b8dc92a5b1aa</guid></item><item><title>Communities pay tribute to Bondi shooting victims in Sydney and Melbourne vigils</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-shooting-vigil-jewish-community/106145098</link><description>Crowds gather at Bondi to lay floral tributes and mourn, just 24 hours removed from a mass shooting that left 15 people dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45313a13879a0109b10eb980263e24e5</guid></item><item><title>McLeod's Daughters star Rachael Carpani dies aged 45</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/mcleod-s-daughters-star-rachael-carpani-dies/106147286</link><description>Rachael Carpani had recently appeared on long-running Australian soap Home and Away and frequently spoke out on a range of issues, including the need to address domestic violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b8b6b2d5bba69f83523097d1fe5e862</guid></item><item><title>Son arrested on suspicion of murder after Rob Reiner and wife found dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/rob-reiner-son-nick-reiner-arrested-in-custody/106147532</link><description>Nick Reiner is being held in custody in the US according to the Los Angeles Sheriff's Department.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">310c0afd467fe2306829cf4dea084cd5</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting updates: Police promise 'highly visible, precise and around-the-clock' investigation — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-beach-shooting-terrorist-attack-december-16/106147374</link><description>Bondi Beach will remain a crime scene, with security around Sydney's eastern suburbs bolstered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">143eb1595903ed68600582ebb93c93e9</guid></item><item><title>After being run over by a car while sunbaking, Sam reunites with paramedics who saved her</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/sunbaker-survives-car-accident-mica-paramedics-cardiac-arrest/106145824</link><description>Melbourne woman Samantha Hind was sunbaking on her lawn when her husband ran over her. After recovering from the brink of death, she is reunited with the paramedics who saved her life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c831b5ea961a7d56dd0fa761d4d7971e</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian parliament passes new sentencing laws, leading to stronger punishments for hate crimes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/tasmania-passes-new-hate-crime-laws/105767410</link><description>The Tasmanian government's new laws to protect people from targeted violence have sailed through the state's parliament, with experts celebrating their "innovative" approach. But some say the job is not done yet, with work still needed to implement them successfully.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4fbfd6b10cf9d60262a3a9e7792d506</guid></item><item><title>It's author Jane Austen's 250th birthday, and her books still have lessons for us today</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/this-day-in-history-jane-austen-250th-birthday/106143026</link><description>Her books like Pride and Prejudice and Emma were written hundreds of years ago, but have themes that still resonate in today's society.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">686588500f4cdb12d6f2ef95bb7c415d</guid></item><item><title>What Australia can learn from the great Kiwi interest rate hike experiment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/rba-interest-rates-what-australia-can-learn-from-new-zealand/106143194</link><description>The RBA's interest rate-cutting cycle is at an end, and now a hardcore handful of critics say they shouldn't have cut rates in the first place. Conveniently, you only need to look across the ditch to see what could've happened if we'd followed that path.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1b2084b9bc67e4d71a38d1f785d89e5</guid></item><item><title>Bondi attack caused by 'cascading hate' left unchecked, say critics urging antisemitism plan be adopted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-unchecked-hate-antisemitism-plan-adoption/106143840</link><description>A report that has sat on Prime Minister Anthony Albanese's desk for months is being raised by critics as key evidence that the federal government has done too little, too late to respond to the rising tide of antisemitism since the October 7 terror attack in Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c19e0c4318584a39ff92f0045d5dbe37</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting: Community pays tribute to terror victims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-beach-shooting-victims-tributes/106144588</link><description>An act of terror took the lives of 15 people at Bondi. Their names, stories and legacies are held close by a shaken, grieving community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6444854282aecb8338066ba6efb222ab</guid></item><item><title>NSW Premier Chris Minns defends police response to Bondi Beach terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/nsw-sydney-bondi-beach-mass-shooting-inquiry-update/106145160</link><description>NSW Premier Chris Minns has defended the police response to Sunday's Bondi Beach terror attack, saying officers acted with "bravery and integrity".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6a75769e600bdbe0ef597e6f7ee7566</guid></item><item><title>Magic mushroom warning as Nimbin farmer fed up with trespassing foragers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/nimbin-farmer-warns-magic-mushrooms-sprayed-with-herbicide/106136770</link><description>A farmer is concerned for the safety of people foraging for magic mushrooms, which he has sprayed with herbicide, as a toxicologist warns about the dangers of fungi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">235afd5ea704c22d47cdfdea7d76344f</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Day weather forecast points to heatwave, tropical storms and festive sunshine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/christmas-day-weather-australia-heatwave-storms-sunshine/106144926</link><description>With only nine more sleeps until Christmas, we have now entered the meteorological window of predictability — in other words, forecasts are more accurate than just guessing the weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c35555d46a80393c36a4ca258163f838</guid></item><item><title>Inquest into Sonya Dutton's death in outback NSW hears of 'many unanswered questions'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/coronial-inquest-into-sonya-dutton-death-in-outback-nsw/106144034</link><description>Barkindji mother-of-two Sonya Dutton, 31, was found in her family's Wilcannia residence on March 29, 2022 — four days after she was reportedly last seen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0798f908bc137573034726977e2d0c2d</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting gunman Naveed Akram was follower of pro-Islamic State preacher Wisam Haddad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/video-shows-bondi-beach-shooting-gunman-preaching-islam-to-teens/106145626</link><description>At least one of the gunmen who killed 15 people in Sunday's Bondi Beach terrorist attack was known to authorities as a follower of a notorious Sydney pro-Islamic State cleric, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b52ae302a33646b87014607b9cbabe0e</guid></item><item><title>Richmond takes Olivia Wolmarans with top pick in the 2025 AFLW draft, Suns complete raid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/aflw-draft-2025-richmond-takes-olivia-wolmarans-at-number-one/106147828</link><description>Richmond takes Olivia Wolmarans with the top pick in the AFLW draft, as the Suns complete a stunning raid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f25b2ae36c9f9ebbabab0d92fd7d4e5</guid></item><item><title>Darwin filmmaking program gives storytellers with disabilities a platform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/disability-filmmaking-program-bus-stop-films/106123510</link><description>Aspiring Darwin filmmakers with disabilities have been getting job-ready, developing skills in scriptwriting, directing, cinematography and editing. It is the first time the program has been offered in the NT, with plans for it to expand even further.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4a1568496c0d480a3cc6808bf6132d5</guid></item><item><title>Four killed in Muckatah mini-van crash may have been farm workers, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/four-dead-minivan-muckatah-crash/106147696</link><description>Four passengers in a van, who are yet to be formally identified, died at the scene, north of Shepparton in Victoria. Five injured people, including three children and the male driver, were taken to various hospitals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c652501eea0b54a4454d9d91e222a691</guid></item><item><title>Manhunt for Brown University shooter renewed after police release detained man</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/manhunt-for-brown-university-shooter-renewed/106147734</link><description>With police releasing a person of interest, the manhunt continues for the Brown University shooter who killed two students and injured nine others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cda4f7b4ce792a68bca03af4dc4c2e4</guid></item><item><title>Man killed, two taken to hospital after unit fire in Brisbane suburb of Spring Hill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/brisbane-spring-hill-unit-fire-three-taken-to-hospital/106147938</link><description>Emergency services rushed to a Water Street address in Spring Hill after 3am following reports one of the units in the complex was fully engulfed by flames.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a26c7e38a9f9ba358b29fc9ba3edb535</guid></item><item><title>Advocates express concerns over ACT government wombat management plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/act-government-considers-wombat-management-plan/106146098</link><description>The ACT government is considering how to better manage the territory's wombat population, in response to challenges being experienced by farmers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b410c4eebc046f7d2b49c70d1bfa647</guid></item><item><title>Noosa region hit with minor flooding, with isolated storms, rain and cooler temperatures forecast for Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/qld-weather-rain-storms-summer-bom-forecast-brisbane/106146608</link><description>Storms and heavy rain are forecast to again hit large parts of Queensland today, with temperatures dropping across much of the sunshine state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a6e5c1436b140651eb92fbb95969cde</guid></item><item><title>London plane trees to be removed in Hamilton following infrastructure concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/hamilton-london-plane-trees-to-be-removed/106143002</link><description>Twenty-five London plane trees are set to be removed from Hamilton after they were found to be causing problems with local infrastructure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">650a4458c8203323dc2f86e1bcacfc46</guid></item><item><title>NSW cricketer banned from playing after allegations of nude photos being sent to teammates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/nsw-cricketer-banned-after-allegations-of-nude-photos/106148042</link><description>A NSW cricketer, who has played at Sheffield Shield level, is banned from playing after allegations he sent nude photos to young teammates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4afec07e7555499e2f1688d527834cd1</guid></item><item><title>Umpires pull Pakistan one-day skipper Shaheen Afridi out of Big Bash attack following full-toss drama</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/big-bash-shaheen-afridi-pulled-out-of-big-bash-attack/106148124</link><description>Umpires in the Big Bash clash between the Renegades and Heat sensationally pull Shaheen Afridi out of the attack after two full-toss deliveries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2718a28176625ac47cd21b4fba3462d</guid></item><item><title>Consent laws now protect sex workers against non-paying clients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/nsw-consent-laws-protect-sex-workers-against-non-paying-clients/106114406</link><description>Victims say NSW Police's frontline officers are still catching up with the changed legislation, which makes non-payment for sexual services a criminal offence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b8b1f11878ea34f099847c926ae3387</guid></item><item><title>The Bondi shooter only had a basic gun licence. How could he buy multiple high-powered rifles?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-shooter-legally-had-many-guns-australian-laws-explained/106145624</link><description>The Bondi shooter's gun licence entitled him to an uncapped quantity of certain kinds of rifles and shotguns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8843ad471684b6cba1aed9759fb08022</guid></item><item><title>The best board games to play (and gift) this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/the-best-board-games-to-play-and-gift-this-summer/106139214</link><description>Over the holiday period, the right game can make all the difference while spending time with friends and family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afc9ef668c6e91a92a25b0f8351ea204</guid></item><item><title>HelloFresh and Youfoodz sued by ACCC over allegedly misleading consumers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/hellofresh-and-youfoodz-sued-by-accc-for-misleading-consumers/106148656</link><description>The consumer watchdog is suing home meal delivery providers HelloFresh and Youfoodz for allegedly misleading consumers over subscriptions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">451560493899fb75f81460582ad748e7</guid></item><item><title>Bondi attack gunman had pro-Islamic State group links</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-attack-gunman-had-pro-islamic-state-group-links/106148538</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6da25e43f688af4beb9128d9c60dc6d6</guid></item><item><title>John Howard calls push to tighten gun laws in wake of Bondi attack an 'attempted diversion'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/john-howard-gun-laws-attempted-diversion/106148416</link><description>Former prime minister John Howard, whose gun reforms fundamentally reshaped Australia, says he would support further tightening, but it cannot be made into a distraction or an "excuse" not to tackle antisemitism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1ec6f3fc1f7f27d32e49292924e37f0</guid></item><item><title>What time does the Adelaide Test start? How to watch the Ashes, and Adelaide weather forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/ashes-2025-how-to-watch-and-follow-the-adelaide-test/106148302</link><description>The third Ashes Test is upon us and the series is on the line. Here's everything you need to know about the clash in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e92c26a7c6ff558c6b311e874066f635</guid></item><item><title>Former taekwondo instructor Kwang Kyung Yoo jailed for murdering three people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/former-taekwondo-instructor-jailed-for-murdering-three-people/106148710</link><description>Kwang Kyung Yoo murdered a woman and child at a Sydney taekwondo studio before killing the woman's husband at their home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a4caa5637009f4c590c06120b5e109e</guid></item><item><title>Nick Reiner, son of Hollywood director Rob Reiner, 'responsible' for parents' deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/nick-reiner-responsible-death-parents-rob-rainer-michele-singer/106148280</link><description>As Nick Reiner, son of film director Rob Reiner and Michele Singer Reiner, is arrested on suspicion of their murder, US President Donald Trump's response sparks a bipartisan backlash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2db985e8722039bee131e170b54d9019</guid></item><item><title>Bondi terrorists travelled to Philippines for 'military-style training', security sources say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-gunmen-went-to-philippines-for-military-style-training/106148662</link><description>Father-son gunmen Sajid and Naveed Akram travelled to the Philippines to receive "military-style training" in the month before they killed 15 people at a Hanukkah celebration at Bondi Beach, security sources have confirmed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52edb6122488935f51e540d7c1ade39e</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese visits Ahmed Al Ahmed as Bondi hero's first video message circulates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/albanese-visits-bondi-hero-hospital/106148762</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese visits Bondi hero Ahmed Al Ahmed at St George Hospital in Sydney's south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d622416ed60be55e60141eea55520e96</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja left out of Adelaide Test as Pat Cummins and Nathan Lyon return to Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/ashes-2025-usman-khawaja-left-out-of-adelaide-test/106149056</link><description>Australian selectors stick with Josh Inglis as Usman Khawaja misses out on selection for the third Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cb08134c57fd6032acedb421aedb22c</guid></item><item><title>Bywong man pleads guilty to animal cruelty after dragging conscious kangaroo behind car</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bywong-man-pleads-guilty-after-dragging-kangaroo-behind-car/106148726</link><description>A Bywong man pleads guilty in the Queanbeyan Local Court to aggravated animal cruelty after dragging a conscious kangaroo behind his car earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be8c7e4347166b374b6e73178e43403f</guid></item><item><title>Farmers' Facebook group racks up 100,000 followers as they seek support across seasons</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/australian-farmers-harvesting-the-crop-facebook-group/106143522</link><description>A group dedicated to Australian grain farming created more than a decade ago has just cracked 100,000 followers with about 20,000 people following from overseas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45bd01ef5eb6e271490a8f818c46382c</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump files $US10 billion lawsuit against BBC over documentary edit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/trump-sues-bbc-10-billion-dollars-documentary-edit/106148940</link><description>US President Donald Trump has filed a defamation lawsuit against the BBC in Miami federal court, seeking at least $US10 billion ($15.1 billion) in damages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">792fe9ca2a9764e9d53b880358f0a650</guid></item><item><title>Bendigo Writers Festival debacle continues as La Trobe University is asked to apologise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bendigo-writers-festival-la-trobe-apology-call/106142986</link><description>The debate around the failed Bendigo Writers Festival, which will not run next year, again embroils sponsor La Trobe University in controversy amid calls for more transparency and accountability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a562f742d6a8cdb21c5809d7bdab97b0</guid></item><item><title>South Australia's Chief Justice Chris Kourakis retires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/sa-supreme-court-chief-justice-chris-kourakis-retires/106148240</link><description>After 13 years serving as South Australia's top judge, Chief Justice Chris Kourakis says it is "an appropriate time to retire".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f647f7488856dfa3766ed0ad851d128</guid></item><item><title>David Sharaz declared bankrupt in federal court hearing prompted by Linda Reynolds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/david-sharaz-declared-bankrupt-by-federal-court/106148670</link><description>Brittany Higgins's husband David Sharaz is declared bankrupt in the federal court, two months after former senator Linda Reynolds served him bankruptcy papers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ab52fd75c9bbaa1d85367a97b9c756d</guid></item><item><title>NT police charge man, 27, with murder after partner's 'suspicious' death in Borroloola</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/nt-borroloola-man-charged-with-woman-dv-murder/106149402</link><description>Police have charged a 27-year-old man with his partner's murder after she was found unresponsive in the remote community of Borroloola, south-east of Darwin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96f585c0dcce66c92dabe2ecf95f16c3</guid></item><item><title>Small plane crashes in central Mexico, killing at least 7 people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/mexico-plane-crash/106149526</link><description>Authorities say the accident took place in San Mateo Atenco, an industrial area 5 kilometres from the Toluca airport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3848244dd9521954a15670ed933c8a77</guid></item><item><title>Flu prompts postponement of A-League Women's match between Reds and City</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/a-league-women-match-postponed-because-of-flu-outbreak/106148360</link><description>An outbreak of the flu has delayed an upcoming A-League Women's match between Adelaide United and Melbourne City, as South Australia grapples with a record number of cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ebdff9d08294f39e4ad9d4a19bde8db</guid></item><item><title>How music makes Jane Austen’s stories sparkle on the page and on screen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/jane-austen-at-250-music-in-books-and-on-screen/106136640</link><description>250 years after Jane Austen's birth, her love of music lives on in the characters from her books and screen adaptations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfa8f5b4cf66817ecbf325bf49b17967</guid></item><item><title>WA's gun laws in national spotlight with national reforms flagged after Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/wa-gun-laws-in-spotlight-as-national-reform-flagged/106147144</link><description>As Australia looks to strengthen its firearms laws in the wake of the Bondi terror attack, recent changes to Western Australia's gun rules could provide a blueprint for the nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44045f403addf2db81fcab01e301a654</guid></item><item><title>The boom or bust rehab plan that saved Pat Cummins's Ashes series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/pat-cummins-ashes-adelaide-england-injury-return/106149958</link><description>It normally takes four months to come back from the injury that has sidelined Pat Cummins thus far during the Ashes, but the Australian skipper is set to return after just seven weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e12cb953845d1c23b62436bea61374bf</guid></item><item><title>Family of Bondi attack victim Matilda express their gratitude for support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/matilda-aunt-bondi-attack/106150182</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c54e4857d9b9842364939406aff71933</guid></item><item><title>Rob Reiner's classic films and the lines that have endured</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/rob-reiner-classic-films-and-the-lines-that-have-endured/106149700</link><description>Rob Reiner directed some classic films, many of which contained quotable lines that stuck around long after he yelled "cut!"</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a96b0aa6f1fcd784200c8c5411b6fe97</guid></item><item><title>Crisis hotline Lifeline records more than 4,300 calls after Bondi shooting in busiest day of year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/lifeline-busiest-day-after-bondi-shooting-tragedy/106149344</link><description>Crisis hotline Lifeline has experienced its busiest day of the year in the wake of the Bondi mass shooting, with more than 4,300 calls made in 24 hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">883779dc698385d4b0a9ac8d5a876dfb</guid></item><item><title>Residents urged action to restrict burn-offs for years before Dolphin Sands bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/dolphin-sands-residents-warned-authorities-fire-ban-bushfire/106139290</link><description>Locals of an east coast Tasmanian community say they urged authorities to tighten rules around burn-offs in the years before yet another bushfire tore through the area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ae1fddabb7ee0fff3c5684577a4eecf</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Joshua has found clarity ahead of Jake Paul Netflix boxing match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/anthony-joshua-jake-paul-clarity-boxing/106122632</link><description>Anthony Joshua tells ABC Sport Daily that he has found clarity ahead of fighting Jake Paul in the latest Netflix spectacular, or as close to it as the madness of 21st century boxing will allow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d6ff1c62fdb2fef02e87faa65da26b0</guid></item><item><title>Suzi Milgate guilty of aggravated assault over crepe attack on Natasha Fyles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/nt-chief-minister-assault-suzi-milgate-guilty/106148236</link><description>Former Darwin real estate agent Suzi Milgate has been found guilty of aggravated assault after pushing a cream-covered crepe into the face of a former Northern Territory chief minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a01091c1a634d137d6f2ac1c5b4240fd</guid></item><item><title>Bondi gunman Naveed Akram was follower of pro-Islamic State preacher Wisam Haddad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-gunman-was-follower-of-pro-is-preacher-wisam-haddad/106150512</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">865d1b0a86f761dba693a7be0a9e8c2e</guid></item><item><title>Deciding to get a pet when I didn't think I could</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/deciding-to-get-a-pet-when-i-did-not-think-i-could/105985508</link><description>It took me a long time to decide to get a cat, and just as long to adopt after I had decided. When I saw Giles, any lingering uncertainties I had disappeared.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c571e4ddcb865455d328f73d7438687</guid></item><item><title>How to watch Tim Tszyu vs Anthony Velazquez and what time does the fight start</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/tim-tszyu-boxing-comeback-next-fight-start-time/106150318</link><description>As Tim Tszyu prepares to put his boxing career on the line, here's everything you need to know about the former world champion's return bout.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78a1dc8cff29250a31c0997d2f27850c</guid></item><item><title>Premier Roger Cook handed extra powers as pro-development laws pass WA parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/wa-state-development-act-passes-parliament/106146908</link><description>The powers allow WA Premier Roger Cook and a bureaucrat to sign off on projects with "strategic or economic significance", sparking concerns about the wide-ranging powers and potential environmental impact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dec3386a50ab9f81090620dc6cafe1e6</guid></item><item><title>Man, 18, charged over allegedly displaying Nazi symbol near mosque in Perth suburb</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/man-18-charged-over-allegedly-displaying-nazi-symbol-near-mosque/106150612</link><description>A man is charged after allegedly wearing a necklace displaying a Nazi symbol, caught by increased police patrols in WA after the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">391a82107f91735e13025f94f3e224ef</guid></item><item><title>Sir Cliff Richard urges awareness following cancer treatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/sir-cliff-richard-urges-awareness-following-cancer-treatment/106150232</link><description>The 85-year-old singer says the disease has been successfully treated, and he is urging people to get checked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e0ddc216ff4df93386c483143bc4689</guid></item><item><title>SA government doubles Holocaust education funding after Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/sa-government-doubles-holocaust-education-funding-after-bondi/106143380</link><description>A Holocaust survivor says the Bondi terror attack should be "a wake-up call" for the nation as the South Australian government double its funding for education programs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0600548c3e92b4ca935412a1f1d4809c</guid></item><item><title>Reuven Morrison was killed in the Bondi Beach shooting one year after warning about antisemitism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/nsw-reuven-morrison-daughter-bondi-beach-shooting/106149216</link><description>One year before Reuven Morrison was killed during the Bondi Beach massacre, he issued a dire warning about escalating antisemitism in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef3485864d2a755af98d703e78cae47a</guid></item><item><title>Out-of-control bushfire damages historic Mogumber Mission, WA Wheatbelt crops</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bushfire-damage-mogumber-mission-eneabba-crops/106148826</link><description>As firefighters continue to battle bushfires across WA's south-west land division, a century-old mission, which was part of the Stolen Generations history, has reportedly been badly damaged in the fire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49b10e7c50767dedd5784abc231a029d</guid></item><item><title>Driver charged with attempted murder after woman dies following alleged deliberate hit-and-run in Maroochydore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/woman-dies-maroochydore-hit-and-run/106151060</link><description>A 38-year-old man has been charged with eight counts of attempted murder after allegedly driving his car at a group of pedestrians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c01f40a445bf738c2367c5d0989100d2</guid></item><item><title>Video shows Bondi couple Boris and Sofia Gurman confronting terrorist gunman before their deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-beach-shooting-hero-second-civilian-confronting-shooter/106149306</link><description>A video circulating on a Chinese social media platform and verified by the ABC has revealed a couple confronting the Bondi Beach shooter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87f9ea88fb6cdb03e7c1031ad56004a0</guid></item><item><title>US military says it carried out strikes on three vessels in Eastern Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/us-pacific-strike-three-vessels/106150936</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1376a8fcdf1cde98e7172e4c0b200655</guid></item><item><title>US strikes on three suspected drug boats kill eight people in eastern Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/us-strikes-on-three-vessels-in-eastern-pacific-kill-eight/106150752</link><description>The US military says eight people have been killed in strikes targeting "designated terrorist organisations".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b03965041df9914a4d41cf919e73306</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106151016</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba4c14b2dca2b65d3fe96067cc89605c</guid></item><item><title>Peri the koala released into the wild</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/peri-the-koala-released-into-the-wild/106150644</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf90a6d6cca60b11e3b5fb0195540481</guid></item><item><title>Koala rescued from Brisbane city bus after death-defying dash across busy Camp Hill street</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/koala-rescued-brisbane-city-bus-camp-hill-city-glider-schrinner/106150364</link><description>A rescue group says the quick-thinking of a Brisbane bus driver could have saved the koala — named Peri — from being hit by traffic on a busy road.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70afd410865b1442d9d643b73ee8cd66</guid></item><item><title>Queensland coroner investigates 'extremely unusual' deaths of premature twin boys</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/baby-boy-twins-death-inquest-queensland-extremely-unusual/106150808</link><description>The Coroners Court in Brisbane hears details about the twins' short lives before their "cold, blue and lifeless" bodies were discovered in separate cots one morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8880cb91ed6f73ceeef0783f0684311</guid></item><item><title>Conservationists slam 'pointless' federal regulator's long-awaited draft to crack down on rat bait poisoning of wildlife</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/rodenticide-decision-apvma-slammed/106143876</link><description>After a five-year wait, conservationists say draft regulations on second-generation rat baits do not go far enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11f6c007bd18c434ad67b23fb247aa69</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach terrorism survivor Jessica Chapnik Kahn threw herself and daughter to shelter as people around them were killed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-beach-terrorism-survivor-tells-of-15-minutes-of-terror/106150322</link><description>A mother throws herself and her daughter into a pit to avoid bullets as her husband goes searching for her among the bodies of the dead at Bondi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74f6bbcf501b5b52d668fc77771f7d06</guid></item><item><title>Coalition launches antisemitism taskforce after Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/coalition-launches-antisemitism-taskforce-after-bondi-terror-att/106151212</link><description>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley will head the internal group aiming to intensify scrutiny of the federal government's response to antisemitism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">154d4d3a302eba3a7e957b33b878e008</guid></item><item><title>Mid-year budget update to show $8.4b improvement to bottom line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/myefo-budget-update-show-deficit-improvement/106150778</link><description>A combination of savings and higher tax takes have delivered an $8.4 billion improvement to the federal budget's bottom line, the mid-year update is expected to show when it is released on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2522fb5ff1f2ae144f04edc9bc349cae</guid></item><item><title>Driver in Liverpool soccer parade ramming handed 21-year prison sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/liverpool-car-attack-driver-sentenced-paul-doyle/106151538</link><description>Paul Doyle rammed his minivan into a crowd celebrating Liverpool's Premier League championship win, injuring more than 130 people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64c5fdefc5761849d8a23106bb459b9a</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine peace deal could be presented to Russia within days: Zelenskyy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/ukraine-war-wrap-deal-could-be-presented-to-russia-in-days/106151590</link><description>Marathon talks between the US and Ukraine led to "not perfect" but "very workable" framework that could bring to an end Russia's near four-year-old invasion, the Ukrainian president says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67e5109aa32a118bbbfd67804a4affec</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting live updates: Bondi gunman charged with 59 offences, including 15 counts of murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/bondi-beach-shooting-terrorist-attack-islamic-state-live-blog/106151426</link><description>Bondi shooter Naveed Akram has been charged with 59 offences over the mass shooting on Sunday. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afddd661a5a897e8db6446a7392d0483</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 17: Kim Jong-il's death kept secret</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/today-in-history-december-17-kim-jong-il-s-death-kept-secret/106138030</link><description>The death of North Korean leader Kim Jong-il was such a closely guarded secret that few outside the North Korean elite would even have guessed anything was amiss.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aab6bcc501b82bdd735ec6d3e8033318</guid></item><item><title>ABC Places quiz: Find your way around the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/abc-places-quiz/106149122</link><description>Your task in the ABC Places quiz is to correctly identify the location shown in each of 10 photos. Grab your passport and let's go.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">635f8ff0f16200751d370dfcdd8b0d89</guid></item><item><title>Racist and antisemitic false information spreads online following Bondi Beach terrorism attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/abc-news-verify-misinformation-bondi-terrorist-attack/106150286</link><description>ABC NEWS Verify finds social media posts spreading misinformation about the Bondi attack are receiving millions of views, as a deepfake image depicting one of the victims circulates online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">768653d079cfb0b1e9879c0687c161a9</guid></item><item><title>As the BOM's Christmas outlook nears, here is the truth about forecast accuracy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/bom-christmas-forecast-accuracy/106135952</link><description>Some forecasts will tell you the weather 28 days from now. But is it accurate?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1c1e331b53722c210a16aca3f1ec5bc</guid></item><item><title>Darwin residential youth justice operator sues NT government for breach of contract</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/darwin-youth-justice-operator-sues-nt-government-contract-breach/106150782</link><description>An Aboriginal-owned business is suing the NT government for allegedly withholding more than $1 million in payments as part of a "campaign" to remove its contract for delivering alternatives to youth detention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edb18e35b08034f02a74adaba1a6078e</guid></item><item><title>De-escalation skills, not guards, needed in Tasmanian hospitals, nurses' union says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/security-guards-tasmania-public-hospitals-emergency-department/106136802</link><description>The nurses' union in Tasmania wants to see private security guards in public hospitals replaced with support officers trained in de-escalation, after a review found "overwhelming dissatisfaction" among staff.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2065c23d952786ecca31a4197c78b796</guid></item><item><title>Man who stabbed 11yo Australian tourist in London to be detained indefinitely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/ioan-alexandru-pintaru-to-be-detained-indefinitely/106151690</link><description>A judge at the Old Bailey rules Ioan Alexandru-Pintaru, who stabbed a young Australian girl in Leicester Square last year, will be detained at a mental hospital indefinitely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1488d7b5ca3d057a0fb827e1aec0141</guid></item><item><title>'Significant' jump in sea lion pup deaths on South Australian island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/significant-jump-in-sea-lion-pup-deaths-on-sa-island/106000790</link><description>Australia's sea lion population has had a tough winter with rising pup mortalities amid the algal bloom, but dedicated researchers are doing everything they can to help their survival as a species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91b1d14c3da3130c0085c3b25cfa240b</guid></item><item><title>Medical and charity groups back free period product vending machines in NSW hospitals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/groups-call-for-free-period-products-in-nsw-hospitals/106148444</link><description>Share the Dignity and the Australian Society of Psychological Medicine back calls for vending machines providing pads, tampons and underwear in NSW hospitals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cdda50e37f457c94b32eace77f622c2</guid></item><item><title>Fitzroy Community School facing potential legal action over abuse allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/fitzroy-community-school-parents-consider-legal-action/106129242</link><description>The school that inspired author John Marsden is facing potential legal action from parents over allegations of physical abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7958a3c152438c2eff745846df6f2f5</guid></item><item><title>Mary River cod thriving in Brisbane River catchment, century after relative went extinct</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/mary-river-cod-brisbane-river-cod-catchment-apex-predator-bremer/106146520</link><description>An important apex predator died out 100 years ago due to overfishing and land clearing. Now, a close relative is bringing balance back to the habitat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">102512458cf9eca07cbb7dfdab770941</guid></item><item><title>Man in custody as police investigate death of man in Melbourne's south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/vic-police-investigate-cheltenham-death/106151724</link><description>A man is in custody following the fatal assault of a man in Cheltenham on Tuesday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c643a6d8028b62412ad9281b1acc9fc5</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Chalmers flags difficult decisions to come in next year's budget — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/federal-politics-live-blog-dec-17/106151730</link><description>Treasurer Jim Chalmers hands down the Mid-Year Economic and Fiscal Outlook showing an $8.4 billion improvement to the budget bottom line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a7e01f90ad3f50e53451cca124d08ad</guid></item><item><title>IPL auction sees Cameron Green become the highest-priced overseas player in history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/ipl-cam-green-breaks-record-as-most-expensive-overseas-player/106151784</link><description>Cameron Green earns a massive payday on the eve of the Adelaide Test, creating history in the Indian Premier League.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a585148507768ba7aeab76f517ec0a89</guid></item><item><title>Rescuers rescue stranded sailors off Lakes Entrance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/rescuers-rescue-stranded-sailors-off-lakes-entrance/106151780</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bb8a9d5690cc1b7afc8fe7cb74698be</guid></item><item><title>Australian sharemarket falls, Westpac removes rate cut call, silver tops $US65 per ounce — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/asx-markets-business-live-news-dec-17/106151834</link><description>Major bank economics teams are rushing to change their cash rate calls ahead of next year. The ASX drops for its third straight day as it follows a mostly negative session on Wall Street, while the price of oil has drops to its lowest level in four years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3acfe2df10a5caea06bc87d82896cc6d</guid></item><item><title>Lung Foundation calls for urgent action on underdiagnosis and undertreatment of COPD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/drop-in-testing-behind-underdiagnosis-of-copd-lung-foundation/106115100</link><description>Experts call for urgent action to turn around an "unacceptable" decline in testing for a disease that kills 20 people every day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">272ce8b47bb8d502180121ee61c09156</guid></item><item><title>Doctor who helped supply ketamine to Matthew Perry sentenced to home detention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/matthew-perry-ketamine-supply-doctor-eight-months-home-detention/106151902</link><description>A doctor involved in supplying ketamine to Friends actor Matthew Perry before his overdose death is sentenced to eight months of home confinement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5607f04920af7c9a2b5f8d5f9365b5a7</guid></item><item><title>WA Jewish MP Simon Ehrenfeld feared terror attack before Bondi shooting, says antisemitism 'part of life' in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/simon-ehrenfeld-details-wa-jewish-community-grief-after-bondi/106151184</link><description>State Liberal MP Simon Ehrenfeld says he has felt a greater sense of risk when attending events recently, fearing an increase in antisemitism and the possibility of a terror attack on Australia's Jewish community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0728da40797c909810da147dd24511e1</guid></item><item><title>Nick Reiner to be charged with murder of parents Rob Reiner and Michele Singer Reiner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/nick-reiner-charged-over-rob-reiner-and-michele-deaths/106152000</link><description>Prosecutors will charge the son of film director Rob Reiner and Michele Singer Reiner with two counts of murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08f9b8da63830996f6068cb4c57e0312</guid></item><item><title>FIFA cuts World Cup tickets prices following global backlash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/fifa-cuts-world-cup-ticket-prices-for-2026-tournament/106151914</link><description>FIFA backtracks on high-priced World Cup tickets, with a limited amount of seats to be made available for less than $100.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6ccc497b76281a23502e841482e4847</guid></item><item><title>Hugh Jackman says he is 'heartbroken' for communities affected by Bondi Beach attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/hugh-jackman-says-he-is-heart-broken-for-communities-affected/106152016</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7f6802876a5e5b88e0a0af34e76b84a</guid></item><item><title>Crisis teams offer psychological first aid to those affected by Bondi shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/crisis-teams-provide-psychological-first-aid-to-those-affected/106151216</link><description>In the chaotic hours after the Bondi shooting, bystanders, surf lifesavers and emergency services rushed to the victims to provide first aid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">238825bbf14db6cd72ad8ab9602d9f37</guid></item><item><title>WA teenager escapes jail time over petrol station caravan-car theft that left tourist in coma</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/teenager-halls-creek-service-station-car-theft/106144328</link><description>A 15-year-old boy who left an elderly tourist in a coma after a Kimberley car theft has escaped immediate jail time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">453ef77b6606cc368fed1608b35862ba</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Alex Carey century carries Australia on day one of third Test against England at Adelaide Oval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/ashes-live-adelaide-oval-third-test-australia-england/106151318</link><description>Australia's Alex Carey scores his maiden Ashes century to carry his team to a solid total of 8-326 on day one of the third Test at the Adelaide Oval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">819f3d45b272204d8e59b997b481e2f4</guid></item><item><title>Rabbi brother of man shot at Bondi urges Jewish Australians not to 'cower'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/injured-bondi-volunteer-yaakov-super-identitified/106151280</link><description>The rabbi brother of a healthcare volunteer shot in the Bondi Beach terror attack, damaging his lungs, urges Jewish Australians not to "cower".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4cf187882931b646be90b4aaa04434f</guid></item><item><title>Taskforce Falcon charges alleged 'onshore leader' of Alameddine crime family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/taskforce-falcon-charges-alameddine-alleged-onshore-leader/106151918</link><description>The alleged "onshore leader" of Sydney's fracturing Alameddine crime family has been charged with conspiring to murder two underworld adversaries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">897048ebb3213affa96712c42cf76417</guid></item><item><title>Tom Silvagni, son of AFL star, sentenced to more than six years' jail for rape</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/tom-silvagni-rape-court-sentencing/106149996</link><description>Tom Silvagni, son of former AFL star Stephen Silvagni, will have to serve at least three years and three months of his sentence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f31aa30d69dd5d7991c7745f913ddd4</guid></item><item><title>Celine Cremer search in Tasmanian bushland uncovers water bottle, garbage bag</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/celine-cremer-tourist-search-in-tasmania-water-bottle-found/106151898</link><description>Searchers find a water bottle and a garbage bag that may have been used as a poncho in the Tasmanian bushland where Belgian tourist Celine Cremer went missing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d506ed73cdc22035e7c10eb8a17b54e2</guid></item><item><title>High Court overturns ruling that NSW government was not liable for light rail delays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/high-court-appeal-light-rail-class-action-result/106152520</link><description>The move clears the way for businesses to seek compensation from the NSW government after the project hampered traders in the city's CBD for four years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0043d65c5f88e0e57b54230cc585af3c</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith ruled out of third Ashes Test in Adelaide due to nausea and dizziness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/ashes-2025-steve-smith-unwell-as-usman-khawaja-comes-into-team/106152450</link><description>Pat Cummins says Steve Smith is a "little bit unwell" as Usman Khawaja makes a shock return to Australia's Test team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3602037b5fbe504f5474e0c58c580aa1</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump orders blockade of sanctioned oil tankers leaving and entering Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/trump-orders-blockade-of-sanctioned-oil-tankers-leaving-entering/106152674</link><description>US President Donald Trump's move comes a week after the United States seized a sanctioned oil tanker off the coast of Venezuela.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe80f3330323ab69b92266c07b4867c9</guid></item><item><title>Why photos are not the most harmful thing we share about our kids online</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/photos-not-most-harmful-thing-we-share-about-our-kids-online/106074142</link><description>Many parents are aware posting photos of their children online comes with risk. But it's not only images that can be harmful for your child.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f06b6f0af87f0a4c7f5751a28757e008</guid></item><item><title>Call for action on homelessness as WA government falls short of target to end rough sleeping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/call-for-action-on-homelessness-as-rough-sleeping-target-missed/106151378</link><description>Social services want the WA government to use its significant budget surplus to invest in breaking people out of the cycle of homelessness, after it failed to achieve its goal of ending rough sleeping.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88ca5d2f55c6502293c0bdf39d0bbdcf</guid></item><item><title>Gippsland vegetable farm accused of underpaying migrant workers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/bulmers-vegetable-farm-charges/106022616</link><description>The Fair Work Ombudsman has accused Bulmer Farms in Victoria's East Gippsland region of underpaying migrant workers more than $645,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06c24ddc050b6be2cafb6c5df9b2768e</guid></item><item><title>Man who drove getaway car from fatal Canberra crash will spend at least 21 months in jail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/act-getaway-driver-jailed-fatal-crash-parliament-house/106152518</link><description>A getaway driver who helped two teenagers flee the scene of a fatal crash near Parliament House is jailed in the ACT Supreme Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3f89b14d11f071139db45228d71feb2</guid></item><item><title>World's tallest spotted gum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/world-s-tallest-spotted-gum/106136966</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d3e11b4570a9c937e20f4ee7feae191</guid></item><item><title>Call for North Brooman nature reserve to protect 70-metre-tall 'Big Spotty'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/big-spotty-spotted-gum-north-brooman-state-forest/106135758</link><description>Thought to be 500 years old, a 70-metre-tall spotted gum is almost hidden in the middle of a South Coast state forest. Conservationists want the "world champion" tree and the forest it lives in recognised and celebrated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ff6d0b6b816341b1c9cd9953cfbf863</guid></item><item><title>Short-term spending rises despite overall budget improvement as Treasury upgrades inflation forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/short-term-spending-rises-despite-overall-budget-improvement/106152498</link><description>Treasurer Jim Chalmers and Finance Minister Katy Gallagher hand down their first budget update since the 2025 federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cca1dc7dffc05df6f14c303b00844651</guid></item><item><title>Bondi attack came after huge increase in online antisemitism, early research finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/bondi-attack-came-after-huge-increase-in-antisemitism/106153148</link><description>Research, which is in the early stages and yet to be peer reviewed, records a significant and worrying increase in antisemitic sentiment since October 7.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4aee4562ea378579144863503d5386ad</guid></item><item><title>Former treasurer calls for royal commission into Bondi Beach terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/former-treasurer-calls-for-royal-commission-/106153518</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0830678d8433218180e0454bd4c824a2</guid></item><item><title>Multi-division world champion Terence Crawford announces retirement from boxing at age 38</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/terence-crawford-retirement-boxing-best-in-the-world/106152704</link><description>Multi-division, undefeated world champion Terence Crawford has called time on his legendary boxing career and will hang up the gloves at age 38.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2753f5b099108bbd62dacf865448dde</guid></item><item><title>Increased police powers begin at Adelaide Oval Ashes Test following Bondi attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/increased-police-powers-begin-at-adelaide-oval-following-bondi/106152410</link><description>South Australian Police will be carrying rifles and exercising additional weapon and drug search powers at Adelaide Oval during the Third Ashes Test, following the Bondi terror attack on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bdfe322d0fc11117ff95fb3815d52c3</guid></item><item><title>FBI releases footage of Brown University shooting suspect</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/fbi-releases-footage-of-brown-university-shooting-suspect/106152432</link><description>Police say the footage shows the suspect "casing" the area around the campus before the attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8597de67c564c508dfdc1aa57665f2b</guid></item><item><title>CSIRO to receive $233 million in mid-year budget but up to 350 jobs still to be cut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/csiro-funding-233-million-mid-year-budget-long-term-solution/106152446</link><description>Just a month after announcing 350 job cuts, the CSIRO has received a funding boost, but proposed job cuts will still happen, the national science agency says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">116d2d494313030b9b86e39c61cb9d69</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach terror attack victim Rabbi Eli Schlanger farewelled at synagogue funeral</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/funeral-for-rabbi-eli-schlanger-killed-bondi-terrorist-attack/106152092</link><description>The 'Devoted Rabbi' was the first Bondi terror attack victim farewelled during a heavily guarded funeral at a Bondi synagogue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba06341487c0e90b963c297d1b09da52</guid></item><item><title>Police officer shot in Bondi Beach terror attack named as Jack Hibbert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/bondi-beach-attack-injured-officer-jack-hibbert/106153520</link><description>The second police officer injured in Sunday's terrorist attack at Bondi Beach has been identified as 22-year-old Probationary Constable Jack Hibbert.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">730f74a83bd1efe37aa5b82216d91bf8</guid></item><item><title>Bondi hero Ahmed Al Ahmed a 'source of pride' for family and friends in Syria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/bondi-beach-attack-hero-ahmed-hometown-in-syria-proud/106152374</link><description>The village of Al Nayrab, in north-west Syria, is the hometown of Bondi hero Ahmed Al Ahmed — and its residents are filled with pride.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7615ddca5036b8e0d311e00d04942785</guid></item><item><title>NSW parliament recalled to discuss gun reforms after Bondi Beach shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/nsw-parliament-recalled-for-gun-reform-over-bondi-beach-shooting/106154014</link><description>Premier Chris Minns said among the reforms to be discussed were proposed limits on the number of firearms a licensed shooter could own.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14af22be07c59ec6087f816ac2ef74c7</guid></item><item><title>Falling tree kills farmer tackling blaze in Mindarabin, in WA's Great Southern</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/volunteer-firefighter-farmer-killed-in-mindarabin/106154044</link><description>A 34-year-old farmer dies helping fight a fire in Mindarabin, in WA's Great Southern region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">634525a829a1a63f04c1966f631cc7e6</guid></item><item><title>Former Beauty and the Geek contestant's murder case adjourned as SA court awaits more evidence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/former-beauty-and-the-geek-contestant-murder-case-adjourned-sa/106152380</link><description>Police are still waiting to examine a large volume of evidence, including a a post-mortem report in the "complex" alleged murder case involving Tamika Chesser, a court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb9db6b05e5fc08d0a56729066826346</guid></item><item><title>Arsonist sentenced for 2023 fire that killed housemate in north-west Victorian town of Red Cliffs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/arsonist-jailed-over-red-cliffs-house-fire-that-killed-housemate/106152068</link><description>A man who pleaded guilty to arson after lighting a fire that killed his housemate has been jailed for 11 years. A Supreme Court justice said his actions were "extremely dangerous" and unsophisticated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8aaae6cbcbeed219d64f01a78beed172</guid></item><item><title>Shakira Adams gets maximum time behind bars for crash that killed Matthew McLuckie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/shakira-adams-jailed-over-matthew-mcluckie-canberra-road-death/106153876</link><description>Shakira Adams had no licence and methamphetamine in her system when she drove a stolen car at least 177 kilometres per hour into Matthew McLuckie's car.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2b208b9427e6081b758247813cd6f7f</guid></item><item><title>Rays and sharks washed up on Kangaroo Island linked to algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/rays-and-sharks-washed-up-on-sa-kangaroo-island/106153566</link><description>Dead rays and sharks found along a regional South Australia beach have been linked to the algal bloom, the government confirms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05739e15ce3e7048e1ca460c5f1d0537</guid></item><item><title>Former AFL footballer Marlion Pickett handed suspended prison term</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/ex-afl-tigers-star-marlion-pickett-given-suspended-prison-term/106152720</link><description>Dual Richmond premiership player Marlion Pickett receives a suspended prison term for possessing and dealing with proceeds of crime, in what a judge calls a "line-ball decision".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7e4ebf01d24b153bc9ab0ce85ca953b</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania Police charge man and woman over alleged carjacking and firearm incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/police-charges-carjacking-firearm-incident-hobart/106154596</link><description>Police arrested the pair on Tuesday, following investigations into an alleged carjacking and firearm incident on Hobart's eastern shore in October.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">434db991b85f8b9a631611dd45a6f19d</guid></item><item><title>Police lay murder charge against 47-year-old man, three years after woman's death in Katherine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/police-charge-man-with-murder-over-death-of-woman-in-katherine/106152656</link><description>Police have charged a 47-year-old man with murder three years after the death of a woman who was found unconscious on a street corner in Katherine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42c0a97b78b59e0221488307fe11c96e</guid></item><item><title>Frydenberg calls for antisemitism royal commission after Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/frydenberg-s-fury-at-bondi-attack-royal-commission-calls/106154546</link><description>Former treasurer Josh Frydenberg has called for bans on radical "hate preachers," protests, stronger immigration laws and a royal commission into antisemitism in an emotional speech at the site of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fa5dd9cd4cf4be1f32efc021bb8eb42</guid></item><item><title>Bondi shooter Naveed Akram charged by NSW Police over terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/nsw-bondi-shooting-naveed-akram-charged-police-terrorist-attack/106144420</link><description>Naveed Akram has been charged over the terrorist attack that killed 15 people at Bondi Beach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6569b2c06614349d9fe2db5225701c8</guid></item><item><title>North Queensland's small Jewish community celebrates Hanukkah in Townsville</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/strong-turn-out-at-private-north-queensland-hanukkah-event/106154056</link><description>North Queensland's only rabbi did not let a nine-hour traffic delay stop him from spreading light during Hanukkah to a Jewish community grappling with the Bondi tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af71850fa42fbe1e495c51164dc623db</guid></item><item><title>High school graduate Annabelle Klint-Pedersen weeks away from moving overseas before fatal fall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/father-pays-tribute-to-teenage-daughter-following-lookout-death/106153356</link><description>Annabelle Klint-Pedersen was celebrating the end of year 12 with friends on the Sunshine Coast when an innocent trip to watch the sunset went tragically wrong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bedcef7b7664cda822f014bc2ccfa138</guid></item><item><title>Australians are rushed and time-poor with most working unpaid hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/how-australians-are-spending-time/106153236</link><description>Most people spent time doing unpaid work in 2024, according to new data from the Australian Bureau of Statistics. It found women spent on average an hour more doing unpaid work than men.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6f641840e295793eba7e38b6528aee9</guid></item><item><title>Queensland records worst flu season in a decade, with cases 18 per cent up on last year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/queensland-flu-statistics-worst-season-in-over-decade/106152596</link><description>Official data shows more than 90,000 lab-confirmed cases of influenza in 2025, which is more than an 18 per cent jump on the number of cases reported last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a20def121db0a0cbe627dcfdc9ca93e0</guid></item><item><title>Tom McLuckie outside court after Shakira Adams is sentenced over his son Matthew's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/tom-mcluckie-outside-court-after-shakira-adams-sentence/106155130</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21aa00fd8dab2a872ab9d399d149c891</guid></item><item><title>Noosa Council blames 'human error' for $2.3 million AI scam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/noosa-council-backflip-scam-human-error/106152030</link><description>The Noosa Council is now blaming human error for a major fraud incident that cost ratepayers millions of dollars — while not acknowledging earlier supplier scam warnings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4110601b030ead0375c8dfe9bac56ff5</guid></item><item><title>Loved ones seek support to repatriate minivan crash victims to Papua New Guinea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/muckatah-crash-victims-papua-new-guinea-repatriation/106154584</link><description>A teenage boy and a 51-year-old woman from Papua New Guinea have been identified as victims of a fatal crash in Northern Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4828fad546ec111665a7bb108b486c41</guid></item><item><title>Day-night Tests locked in for Australian summer until 2031</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/day-night-tests-cricket-australia-future/106155236</link><description>Cricket Australia CEO Todd Greenberg opens up on the future of day-night Tests in the future summer schedule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">972090bdd7440acf1461a2b76ff872da</guid></item><item><title>Talison Lithium will not reopen historic rail line from world's biggest lithium mine after finding it economically unviable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/lithium-train-not-viable-company-says/106154826</link><description>Talison Lithium rules out reopening a century-old rail line from the world's biggest lithium mine, despite ongoing complaints about truck traffic and dust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac27301025a5bad1cc22c64372711f0a</guid></item><item><title>Ashes drama for Steve Smith, Alex Carey and DRS — quick hits from day one of the fourth Test at Adelaide Oval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/ashes-adelaide-oval-day-one-quick-hits-alex-carey-snicko/106152316</link><description>Australia's first-innings topscorers get some help from England's sloppy fielders and the DRS technology on a tightly contested day in Adelaide. Here are the quick hits from day one of the third Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">168d5a951ad1597d526d5d5c906e799b</guid></item><item><title>Teenager jailed after stabbing doctor at Tasmanian hospital in 2023</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/teenager-sentenced-stabbing-north-west-regional-hospital-tas/106153638</link><description>A doctor went through a "lengthy, risky and complicated" surgery and continues to experience nightmares and flashbacks after being stabbed by a teenager he was treating in 2023, a court is told.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72c2e48d63b3e2eccd869cb1bf1d0ec2</guid></item><item><title>Live updates: Tim Tszyu vs Anthony Velazquez, super welterweight boxing clash in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/live-updates-tim-tszyu-vs-anthony-velazquez-boxing/106154982</link><description>Tim Tszyu faces a make-or-break test against unbeaten American Anthony Velazquez at the Sydney Entertainment Centre. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d550e41b0a45fbec1292c1a76116d98</guid></item><item><title>Alex Carey's maiden Ashes ton rescues Australia, delights Adelaide and elevates his status</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/carey-rescues-australia-in-adelaide-third-test-day-one/106153158</link><description>Alex Carey looked to the heavens as his name rang out from the Adelaide Oval stands, his emotional century saving Australia's day one and furthering his push to one day stand among the great wicketkeeper-bats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0317b7d746872f59f5a90670e1d2994</guid></item><item><title>Cyril Mark Yeeda faces court over alleged $170k sale of alcohol in WA dry communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/cyril-mark-yeeda-alcohol-sly-grogging-court/106149408</link><description>Police allege Cyril Mark Yeeda sold $45,000 worth of alcohol in dry communities for $170,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a25e665f036e38c92f0afddd7a2d1fe</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106155170</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b27f0578a1a3d0b8152250148316f669</guid></item><item><title>NSW man refused bail charged with depicting Adolf Hitler and Nazi symbols on boat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/man-refused-bail-charged-with-depicting-hitler-and-nazi-symbols/106155230</link><description>Lake Macquarie man Jake Dearie has been refused bail after being charged with depicting Adolf Hitler and Nazi symbols on his boat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df2520c3ae6b970e249131c4d998b94c</guid></item><item><title>ACT inquiry slams 'aggressive' debt recovery in stamp duty concession scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/act-stamp-duty-home-buyer-concession-scheme-recomendations/106154636</link><description>A legislative inquiry has criticised the ACT government for aggressively recovering debts from people it found were ineligible for stamp duty concessions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8d36997b76e9a757a47722142b7db06</guid></item></channel></rss>