<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 21:45:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fairy Meadow drive-by shooting was a targeted attack, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/fairy-meadow-drive-by-shooting-targeted-attack-police-say/105763278</link><description>Police say the attack on a home in Fairy Meadow, near Wollongong, was targeted and that they are investigating potential links to gang and black market activity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da239128e0b360141a2c313c08945503</guid></item><item><title>How Hawthorn and Gold Coast proceed to the AFL preliminary finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/how-hawthorn-and-gold-coast-get-to-prelim-finals/105762028</link><description>Hawthorn and Gold Coast go into their cut-throat semifinals with reasons for some confidence against the Crows and Lions. Cody Atkinson and Sean Lawson look into the factors driving both teams' September runs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bee6f2e0e1aee53ecd326cca279df14</guid></item><item><title>'Unconscionable' for Ireland to participate in Eurovision 2026 if Israel takes part, says broadcaster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/ireland-threatens-eurovision-boycott-if-isreal-takes-part/105764652</link><description>Irish national broadcaster RTE has said Ireland will not participate in Eurovision 2026 if Israel does, citing the ongoing and appalling loss of lives in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6e6c785f4a9425e849bb6220cf8b39f</guid></item><item><title>Inside the $8b plan to station American sailors and subs near Perth through AUKUS</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/inside-the-aukus-plan-to-station-american-subs-near-perth/105763818</link><description>The head of Australia's submarine agency says planning is so far advanced to settle the American soldiers that quarantine arrangements for their pets are underway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">408a7c086f55e88dc737ae6abf54f948</guid></item><item><title>The Nampijinpa Price saga doesn't bode well for the future of the Liberal party</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/sussan-ley-jacinta-nampijinpa-price-sacking/105748980</link><description>The fracas over Jacinta Nampijinpa Price shows the Liberal party is a seething mass of frustrated ambition, resentment, tribalism and deep ideological division.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">feedeaba5252352450343177c37f6ab3</guid></item><item><title>The Nampijinpa Price saga doesn't bode well for the future of the Liberal party</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/sussan-ley-jacinta-nampijinpa-price-sacking/105748980</link><description>The fracas over Jacinta Nampijinpa Price shows the Liberal party is a seething mass of frustrated ambition, resentment, tribalism and deep ideological division.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a3f03e332ecefe105b34b6cea557f24</guid></item><item><title>Sydney live music venue embraces grant for soundproofing amid noise complaint concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/nsw-government-grants-soundproofing-sydney-live-music-venues/105748102</link><description>When the Red Rattler theatre in Sydney's inner west installed acoustic foam in the walls behind its stage, it didn't just make the venue soundproof — but future-proof.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ff16aa762f54c42d123cbb2a78c68e5</guid></item><item><title>Basil Zempilas took a stand on key issues, but uniting his party is proving to be a tough task</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/basil-zempilas-taking-stand-headaches-wa-liberal-party/105764472</link><description>Basil Zempilas has been vocal in giving his federal party colleagues advice, but the events of the last week show just how difficult the job of uniting the WA Liberals truly is.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b839995ecd49b53d51b78f38dc57e4b5</guid></item><item><title>How Jamal Fogarty learned to be the hero Canberra needed for its premiership charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/jamal-fogarty-canberra-raiders-nrl-finals-broncos/105763708</link><description>Jamal Fogarty has spent a rugby league lifetime waiting to play on a team like the Raiders. Now with the NRL finals approaching, he's ready for his close-up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37ebbb2fb5d1d3bfd53ea39bbcdce144</guid></item><item><title>What happens to your data when you trade or recycle your device?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/what-happens-to-data-when-disposing-of-old-devices-in-ewaste/105681804</link><description>A cybercrime expert says trading or recycling electronics may not completely erase personal data and users should adopt a "risk-adjusted strategy" when disposing of devices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a43950c96dbc6efda59bd57a5459809</guid></item><item><title>Community farewells Dapto Dogs after 90 years of greyhound racing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/dapto-dogs-greyhound-racing-ends-after-nearly-90-years/105758074</link><description>One of the most famed tracks in Australian greyhound racing, known as the Dapto Dogs, has held its final race meet after almost 90 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e060f9420926fadd303544221c85c2f5</guid></item><item><title>Stewards placed hundreds of bets on Tasmanian races, integrity investigation finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/stewards-placed-bets-on-tasmanian-races/105766996</link><description>A Tasmanian racing integrity investigation finds a number of racing stewards, including the acting chief thoroughbred steward, placed more than 200 bets on races across a two-and-a-half-year period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ca544808016df18feab5bcb55b53cd0</guid></item><item><title>Murray Watt stamps final approval of Woodside's North West Shelf extension to 2070</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/woodside-north-west-shelf-decision-murray-watt-pilbara/105758850</link><description>Australia's biggest gas project, Woodside's North West Shelf, has received final approval to extend operations through until 2070.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d18fcc83afaca4bb228cc354760d240</guid></item><item><title>Australia to face Belgium in Davis Cup in Sydney with Final 8 spot up for grabs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/nothing-for-granted-aussies-wary-of-belgian-davis-cup-threat/105767498</link><description>Lleyton Hewitt's Australian Davis Cup team is ready for another fierce battle with old foes Belgium as they chase a spot in this year's Final 8 in Italy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25e0a60e31cf0b026f68b6ea2239af89</guid></item><item><title>Artists and users boycotting Spotify over AI use and CEO's military tech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/spotify-boycott-daniel-ek-ai-music-military-tech-fenn-wilson/105765846</link><description>A growing number of artists and users are leaving Spotify. What's changed with the streaming giant? And what comes next?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dce4c940b969890ecfdfb4e37ad98c9</guid></item><item><title>Independent accreditation system for fertility sector to be established as all recommendations of IVF review accepted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/health-ministers-meeting-ivf-rapid-review/105767258</link><description>Federal Health Minister Mark Butler has announced he has accepted all recommendations of a rapid review into the IVF sector at a meeting with state and territory health ministers in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fa1b97ddad00e883abaf6ad33c49ac4</guid></item><item><title>British YouTube creator Yung Filly to travel home to UK on bail for sexual assault charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/youtube-creator-yung-filly-allowed-to-fly-overseas-on-bail/105094220</link><description>British YouTube content creator Yung Filly, who's facing trial in Perth on sex assault charges, is granted permission to travel home to the UK for the first time since he was arrested.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c89f9603e811b96cf1412b9f341613a</guid></item><item><title>Former Geraldton family appeals pet labrador's dangerous dog declaration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/family-appeals-labradors-dangerous-dog-declaration-wa-council/105766142</link><description>A WA family asks the State Administrative Tribunal to overturn the City of Greater Geraldton's ruling that Dozer, their golden labrador, is a dangerous dog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e55a65c5af9b846f557497d2f6ef2701</guid></item><item><title>NRL finals: Melbourne Storm defeat Canterbury Bulldogs 26-18, Stephen Crichton injured</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/nrl-finals-live-updates-melbourne-storm-canterbury-bulldogs/105751872</link><description>Bulldogs coach Cameron Ciraldo feels his side was let down by the refereeing performance in their 26-18 defeat to the Storm in their qualifying final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b35b168c35672017d9e1e7c85773c92</guid></item><item><title>Perth man found guilty of murdering Helen Marsuk after body found in South Fremantle harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/man-guilty-of-murdering-helen-marsuk-disposing-body-in-ocean-/105763488</link><description>A man accused of murdering a woman he invited to his house to have sex with him in exchange for drugs is found guilty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a860361db3e29137c3807a614242d73</guid></item><item><title>Matildas to face England Lionesses in October international window</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/matildas-to-face-england-in-october-international-window/105768734</link><description>The Matildas have announced an international friendly against England this October, the first time they will face the European champions since the semifinal of the 2023 FIFA Women's World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dcbfca402515a25dcb9fa30ae7dbe58</guid></item><item><title>Pacific leaders reaffirm support for Taiwan's right to attend regional forum</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/pacific-backs-taiwan-in-regional-forum-despite-chinas-opposition/105768946</link><description>Despite pressure from Beijing, Pacific leaders have backed Taiwan's right to attend the Pacific Islands Forum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d49fc9494c51566f7cf037193382d71</guid></item><item><title>Pacific leaders reaffirm support for Taiwan's right to attend regional forum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/pacific-backs-taiwan-in-regional-forum-despite-chinas-opposition/105768946</link><description>Despite pressure from Beijing, Pacific leaders have backed Taiwan's right to attend the Pacific Islands Forum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be257f4ebf8ffb7425aa8971ff6a5ff8</guid></item><item><title>Sushila Karki sworn in as Nepal's new prime minister after gen Z protests prompt political change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/sushila-karki-nepals-new-prime-minister-after-gen-z-protests/105769388</link><description>Sushila Karki garnered widespread support from many young Nepalese people who took to the streets in anger over government corruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b14068c37ad26302453e199b0b0960b7</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump and his 'good man' Anthony Albanese share some common ground</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/donald-trump-anthony-albanese-common/105756898</link><description>The MAGA president's grip on the Republican party is near total while Albanese holds a sway over his left-leaning caucus like few of his Labor predecessors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88bb570d5f115243764edac358fd6925</guid></item><item><title>North West Shelf extension comes at critical juncture in Australia's climate conversation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/north-west-shelf-extension-part-of-climate-conversation/105766008</link><description>Seven years after it was first mooted, the extension of Australia's biggest gas project could not have landed at a more critical juncture for the nation's climate credentials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9765dc66a42d1f27ca625f703478a49b</guid></item><item><title>Australians watched the moment of Charlie Kirk's assassination on social media with no warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/young-australians-watched-charlie-kirk-murder-social-media/105766060</link><description>Young Australians say they are seeing graphic video of US commentator Charlie Kirk being shot dead pop up in their social media algorithms without warning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9340dfaeb79e8ebb902319c5caea2078</guid></item><item><title>Evidence points to remains found in Vietnam cave being South-East Asia's earliest known homicide victim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/vietnam-remains-earliest-known-homicide-victim-cold-case/105741956</link><description>It was on a sweltering morning in 2018 in a cave in northern Vietnam when Chris Stimpson and his team uncovered what may be the oldest cold case murder in South-East Asia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34f92776d6167c167af22a4b170f6648</guid></item><item><title>When does Gout Gout run in the 200m at the 2025 World Athletics Championships in Tokyo, and other key events</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/when-does-gout-gout-run-at-the-world-athletics-championships/105748430</link><description>The 2025 World Athletics Championships in Tokyo sees Australia's largest-ever team tackle the best athletes on the planet. Here are the key events you won't want to miss.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed7a4e602de605c0371a42019cfce15a</guid></item><item><title>Who is Tyler Robinson, the accused killer of Charlie Kirk?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/tyler-robinson-charlie-kirks-alleged-killer/105769710</link><description>After his father encouraged Tyler Robinson to turn himself in, people close to the 22-year-old provided investigators with crucial insights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeb2177456349534e747aeb65ed554d9</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne's Royal Children's Hospital cancels children in war discussion citing staff safety</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/royal-childrens-hospital-children-in-war-event-cancelled/105768998</link><description>Melbourne's Royal Children's Hospital says a symposium on the effect of war on children has been cancelled due to safety fears, but some doctors say pressure from a group opposing antisemitism is to blame.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fccbb42b0ca2b5ba0a4d9a7fdb9a9816</guid></item><item><title>Bush band tells Aboriginal people's side of the Maralinga nuclear weapon tests story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/bush-band-song-tells-story-of-maralinga-atomic-bomb-tests/105765452</link><description>For Liam Tunkin, making music is about continuing his late father's legacy and sharing a dark part of Australia's history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b898813878aa4745672fc29e28ce560b</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fall to 28-26 defeat against Argentina in The Rugby Championship in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/live-updates-wallabies-vs-argentina-the-rugby-championship/105753320</link><description>The Wallabies have fallen just short of a magical comeback against Argentina, losing 28-26 in a thrilling Rugby Championship Test in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac9963693b81c061d5a7137f7874121c</guid></item><item><title>Erika Kirk makes first public statement after assassination of husband Charlie Kirk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/erika-kirk-pays-tribute-to-late-husband-charlie-kirk/105770008</link><description>Charlie Kirk's widow, Erika, delivers her first public remarks since the fatal shooting of her influencer husband.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a3e797f573f130d4cdaa37fc918652a</guid></item><item><title>Advocates call for action on brain health as AIHW reveals dementia is leading cause of death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/australians-dying-from-dementia-more-than-any-other-cause/105768682</link><description>Advocates warn the number of people with the condition could exceed 1 million without government intervention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b35bf8bb29f6390428b007c4fc10877</guid></item><item><title>Supreme Court gives Queensland hospital permission to terminate 12yo girl's pregnancy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/qld-hospital-gets-court-permission-for-abortion-on-12yo-girl/105770196</link><description>A 12-year-old girl in residential care in Queensland should be allowed to have an abortion, a court rules, after a judge found she was not capable of making the decision herself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86cd5589ba9855a3f68a146a74e238ad</guid></item><item><title>Heavy police presence monitors thousands of protesters across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/protesters-across-political-spectrum-rally-across-australia/105769960</link><description>Rallies against racism and in support of Indigenous sovereignty coincide with mixed anti-government protests in major cities around the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">114f96de2b5f61b5df11c8299f73fdb6</guid></item><item><title>WA Health issues measles warning as two more cases linked to Bali travel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/two-more-measles-cases-in-wa-linked-to-bali-travel/105770492</link><description>West Australians planning to visit South-East Asia are being urged to get vaccinated against measles, with two more cases linked with travel to Bali.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1897bbaf4493022b86af465fcc949ac6</guid></item><item><title>Labor win Kiama by-election as voters replace disgraced MP Gareth Ward</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/kiama-byelection-polls-close-votes-counting/105770414</link><description>The NSW Premier said Kiama now has the ear of the government after it claimed victory in the by-election triggered by the resignation of convicted rapist Gareth Ward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f8148eb8e329e6cf74190c6118a0a8f</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane far too good for Gold Coast in QClash semifinal, setting up Collingwood prelim date</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/afl-finals-brisbane-lions-gold-coast-suns-live-blog/105768034</link><description>Bouncing back from a resounding loss to Geelong, the Brisbane Lions comfortably dispense of the Gold Coast Suns to advance to the preliminary finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35fd90e486aa2532889961cd9ae474b8</guid></item><item><title>Torrie Lewis makes semifinals at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo, Day 1</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-2025-in-tokyo-day-1/105770190</link><description>Torrie Lewis broke the national record to claim a spot in the women's 100m semifinal, as Lauren Ryan recorded Australia's best finish in a 10,000m final since 2003 on day one of the World Athletics Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1fd0acc71517e138058f6992507918f</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government pours $12 billion into expanding AUKUS defence facility near Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/albanese-announces-aukus-12-billion-dollar-defence-spend-perth/105770188</link><description>The Albanese government will spend $12 billion on building a submarine and naval shipbuilding facility south of Perth under AUKUS, as doubts linger over the agreement's future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">420e959c71ffce19abd7eac4b8f6483e</guid></item><item><title>From Formula 1 to creating the 'world's best' croissant, how baking saved Lune founder Kate Reid's life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/cars-to-croissants-kate-reid-and-the-lune-empire/105750472</link><description>Kate Reid's Lune croissants have been called the world's best. But how did a young woman struggling with a near-fatal eating disorder end up perfecting pastry?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d09b350f758690100795053d1425df1</guid></item><item><title>Children missing out on early intervention for language delays due to shortage of speech pathologists</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/australias-speech-pathology-therapy-language-delay/105658306</link><description>One in four children starting school now has a speech or language delay. It can hold back their learning, affect their friendships and harm their mental health. Speech therapists are struggling to find ways to support them all, but one school is leading the way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05deb257beb46d1c534546390ab6f12c</guid></item><item><title>Children missing out on early intervention for language delays due to shortage of speech pathologists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/australias-speech-pathology-therapy-language-delay/105658306</link><description>One in four children starting school now has a speech or language delay. It can hold back their learning, affect their friendships and harm their mental health. Speech therapists are struggling to find ways to support them all, but one school is leading the way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fd8643f474de3cb897a95d95769fb75</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's health chief, RFK Jr, is dividing Republicans on vaccines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/trump-health-chief-rfk-jr-divides-republicans-on-vaccines/105763060</link><description>US Health Secretary Robert F Kennedy Jr's anti-vaccination agenda is gaining ground, but resistance is coming from all sides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">550382bc4a2dad860c2ebd332ba5da22</guid></item><item><title>Trump hits out at Florida's 'tough stance' on vaccines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/trump-hits-out-at-floridas-tough-stance-on-vaccines/105767070</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">411cbb4e0109999f07a638bac1bb9e45</guid></item><item><title>Perth had its wettest winter in 30 years. Why aren't its dams full?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/perth-dam-remains-low-despite-the-wettest-winter-in-30-years/105767386</link><description>The last time it rained that much in winter, Perth's drinking water dam overflowed. Now it's barely half full. It's telling the story of a water crisis that's not only affecting Australia, but the globe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">520afffe8e8f2b9614549ec3a2399a4d</guid></item><item><title>The Pacific won a stunning climate victory at the International Court of Justice. What's next?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/whats-next-after-pacific-icj-climate-victory/105747794</link><description>Pacific Island nations are weighing up how to use a historic international court ruling in their fight to bring about stronger emissions reductions and climate justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4d5352fd2872714b73915e90a078b57</guid></item><item><title>Steeplechaser Tim Van de Velde stops to help struggling rival at World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/world-athletics-championships-steeplechase-tim-van-de-velde/105771466</link><description>Belgium's Tim Van de Velde provides the highlight of the opening night of the World Athletics Championships, helping a fellow competitor cross the finish line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d470e01e604db46cc6545807e9ed2bc</guid></item><item><title>The Franklin River rescue was extreme. Here's how medics prepare for the wilderness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/expedition-medicine-frontline-wilderness-rescue-tasmania/105647214</link><description>The Franklin River rescue was an extreme test for the skills of medics. In remote Tasmania, here's how they train for "chaos".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ad6b3276dc3d97f9e83daaf4447dd1e</guid></item><item><title>The federal press gallery is ceding power to the Albanese government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/australias-press-gallery-problem-with-political-coverage/105762464</link><description>The federal press gallery is ceding power to the Albanese government. It needs to take it back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ab87f4785a2cdb321543f771c1d84de</guid></item><item><title>All Blacks forced to re-group after 43-10 loss to Springboks in Rugby Championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/all-blacks-regroup-after-springboks-defeat/105771568</link><description>After a demoralising 43-10 loss to the Springboks on home soil, the All Blacks are looking to rebound against the Wallabies in the upcoming Bledisloe Cup Tests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14cb19776ed7e08739a74354c2afa92e</guid></item><item><title>Albanese announces new AUKUS facility in WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/albanese-announces-new-aukus-facility-in-wa/105771780</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">351395ae5e354677773f0fc914b78d26</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley reshuffles frontbench in wake of Jacinta Nampijinpa Price saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/coalition-frontbench-reshuffle-melissa-price-claire-chandler/105771468</link><description>West Australian MP Melissa Price will replace Jacinta Nampijinpa Price as the shadow minister for defence industry and personnel, after the outspoken senator was sacked for refusing to back her leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5afabc2037eaede8864df8e5a67e0e3f</guid></item><item><title>How to give your indoor plants a spring clean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/how-to-spring-clean-indoor-plants/105754044</link><description>As gardens, parks and nature strips start showing signs of spring, our indoor plants might need a little help to jump into the new season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7041345f64a52b3d64fb6ac2ef82f3b</guid></item><item><title>FBI director Kash Patel to face congressional hearing amid missteps on Charlie Kirk assassination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/kash-patel-faces-congressional-hearing/105771606</link><description>Kash Patel faces a clear test of whether he can convince the country that the FBI, under his watch, can avoid compounding its mistakes in a time of political violence and deepening distrust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff3edf3e8615beb76880722256515f03</guid></item><item><title>WA set to get two new public holidays in 2028 in upcoming legislation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/wa-set-to-get-two-new-holidays-in-shake-up-of-public-holidays/105771652</link><description>WA Premier Roger Cook announces plans to change the state's public holidays from 2028, adding Show Day and Easter Saturday to the calendar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">295fa0b064b6ec349ac3a310f7c3f0f0</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull cruises to 1,500m final at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-2025-in-tokyo-day-2/105772150</link><description>Jess Hull made light work of a rough semifinal to progress in the women's 1,500, but Linden Hall and Torrie Lewis both fell just short of making the final themselves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3251a6322d104d5e8dec69a8eb3f155</guid></item><item><title>Belgians break Australian hearts in Davis Cup classic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/tennis-de-minaur-australia-belgium-davis-cup-wrap/105772264</link><description>Beligum's Raphael Collignon wore down late stand-in Aleksandar Vukic in the deciding rubber to lead Belgium to the quarter-finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48108db3db36157632582610dcc8f4ed</guid></item><item><title>Reece Walsh grabs the Sun to lead Brisbane to an all-time victory over Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/canberra-raiders-brisbane-broncos-nrl-finals-reece-walsh/105767838</link><description>Brisbane and Canberra went to the great beyond in their golden point finals match and it was Reece Walsh who led the Broncos to the promised land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">863df8dd52133df36ae1790ea450fe7c</guid></item><item><title>Liberal Party immigration fight is a battle over how the party wants to position itself</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/liberals-mass-immigration-debate-protests/105771786</link><description>Immigration has become a new fault line inside the Liberal Party that will erupt again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a99f0ce667959a16433080650b5d2dc</guid></item><item><title>The year Australia is due to blow its carbon budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/australia-carbon-budget-2035-emissions-target/105341080</link><description>Unless Australia lifts its ambitions, its "fair share" of carbon emissions will be spent 14 years early. With the government announcing a 2035 climate target this week, there is intense debate on how high the government should aim — and whether it will be enough to help limit global warming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92c26486065559e6e68fc907f4300c31</guid></item><item><title>The higher Australia's 2035 emissions target, the more necessary a carbon tax will be</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/albanese-government-2035-climate-emissions-target/105771566</link><description>Australia's emissions reduction number is, in short, a laugh-or-cry-o-meter, or perhaps more accurately, a tax-o-meter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5aae41b286ff6b7c3400069e180e67f</guid></item><item><title>GIM Trading accused of defrauding millions from ordinary Australian investors with 'low risk' bonds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/gim-trading-alleged-fraud-investors-bonds/105747410</link><description>A Gold Coast musician approached by a man he knew from a local bar went on to front a trading company, later accused of defrauding millions from ordinary Australian investors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef7a680d03253010b78fa5b88e06a4f0</guid></item><item><title>Family violence survivors waiting years for social housing as demand surges in Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/social-public-housing-wait-times-victoria-family-violence/105655044</link><description>As family violence survivor and mother-of-two, Maya was assessed as a high priority for social housing. Eight years later, she's finally moved into a suitable home in outer-suburban Melbourne, with vulnerable Victorians left waiting for years as the social housing waitlist soars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e74302190404e5284428c6e45ccbce8a</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic expeditioners join research project to help astronauts on space missions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/antarctic-expeditioners-join-astronaut-research-project/105767136</link><description>Expeditioners at Australia's Antarctic stations are taking part in a research project to better understand the cognitive and physiological impacts of extended deployments — which can include actual "brain shrinkage".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d57ace742d2dab72c8470091d9eea61</guid></item><item><title>Residents say former Moe Hospital could become public housing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/moe-hospital-newborough-derelict-building-social-housing/105637366</link><description>A retired nurse who worked at Moe Hospital says the closed facility could be used for housing rather than left to further rot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d6259927cc7b3ea15a9fcb2704c8b7c</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk shooting suspect not cooperating with authorities, Utah governor says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/charlie-kirk-shooting-suspect-not-cooperating-with-authorities/105772848</link><description>Investigators are working to piece together why Tyler Robinson allegedly scaled a rooftop at Utah Valley University during an outdoor event and shot Mr Kirk in the neck at long range.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84a96eb58021324ea7568c8d91e90253</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr scores 100th goal for Chelsea in long-awaited WSL return from knee injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/sam-kerr-makes-wsl-chelsea-return-from-torn-acl/105772878</link><description>Matildas star Sam Kerr scores her 100th goal for Chelsea just minutes after returning to the pitch for the Blues for her first game since 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bae5f25a567be7986ec4489f569f5f25</guid></item><item><title>Nepalese migrants in Australia turning to parents to help with childcare and culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/canberra-nepalese-community-family-tradition-and-culture/105772020</link><description>For many Nepalese families living in Canberra, the arrival of parents from overseas is both a helping hand with raising children and a connection to their homeland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83d7bb8c245d2e5d11433eda0c9b3fd1</guid></item><item><title>Traditional custodian readies for 'challenge' over North West Shelf gas project extension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/traditional-custodian-fights-north-west-shelf-approval/105770306</link><description>Environment Minister Murray Watt approved the extension of Australia's biggest gas project last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fff78b1c904abb60057a8fd295536c56</guid></item><item><title>Emmys 2025 red carpet: Jenna Ortega, Lisa, Sydney Sweeney, Aimee Lou Wood, Walton Goggins, Selena Gomez and Pedro Pascal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/2025-emmys-red-carpet-fashion/105752046</link><description>The stars of the television industry are bringing the drama with their fashion choices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85981e3d6d9c2977cda8244d6580248c</guid></item><item><title>Emmy Awards 2025: The Pitt, Adolescence and The Studio win big as Owen Cooper makes history — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/emmy-awards-2025-live-blog-latest-updates/105757172</link><description>The Pitt wins Best Drama at the 77th Annual Primetime Emmy Awards, with The Studio, Adolescence and even Stephen Colbert walking away as the biggest winners of the night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f0dab0d1494400d0b01fc6483c43b32</guid></item><item><title>First climate risk assessment finds 1.5m Australians at risk from sea level rise by 2050</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/climate-risk-assessment-sea-level-rise-2035-target/105765456</link><description>One and a half million Australians are at risk from sea levels rising by 2050 unless climate change can be limited, Australia’s first national climate risk assessment warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84bc65afd0d8a3b350ab90314dff5f21</guid></item><item><title>Nepal's Gen Z demands reform as country begins new political path</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/nepal-generation-z-anti-corruption-protests-kathmandu/105773042</link><description>Protesters in Nepal say their Gen Z-led movement was not just about removing one leader, but about reforming the system to ensure accountability and protect Nepal’s future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">836ee3f4801e6cf8e546d51627e6e4b8</guid></item><item><title>Australian rules football and SANFL administrator Max Basheer dies aged 98</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/sanfl-administrator-max-basheer-dies-aged-98/105773500</link><description>Max Basheer — the football administrator who oversaw the creation of the Adelaide Crows and the purpose-built stadium Football Park — has died aged 98.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">594325c3e747906c91d2cd8c90983d6f</guid></item><item><title>AFL State of Origin will return, with Western Australia-Victoria clash confirmed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/afl-announces-state-of-origin-return-with-wa-vic-clash-confirmed/105773392</link><description>AFL chief executive Andrew Dillon confirms Western Australia will play Victoria in Perth next February in the first State of Origin match since 1999.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d22aa23c3e429a537fcaf8a6093051d</guid></item><item><title>Indian cricketers refuse to shake hands with Pakistani counterparts at Asia Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/indian-cricketers-refuse-to-shake-hands-with-pakistanis-asia-cup/105773820</link><description>Indian captain Suryakumar Yadav refuses to shake hands after his side's seven-wicket win over Pakistan at the Asia Cup in the latest controversial episode between the two rivals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e14fcc55b27a2d660ff4a5b3250b9de6</guid></item><item><title>Emmys 2025 winners: Adolescence, Severance, The Pitt and The Studio win big</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/primetime-emmy-awards-ceremony-winners-list/105752034</link><description>The 77th Primetime Emmy Awards are honouring the best and brightest in the US television industry. Here are the shows that picked up the trophies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d8d75f9c20e7825a51aab42eb0d2ca3</guid></item><item><title>Arhab Haque sprayed fart gas at restaurants for TikTok clout, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/arhab-haque-sentenced-over-fart-gas-prank-gone-wrong/105774764</link><description>An amateur mixed martial arts fighter sprayed fart gas in a fast food restaurant so he could make TikTok prank videos, a Perth court hears.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b3e5750b5b7883a158b5adc9cf27be0</guid></item><item><title>2025 Emmys key moments: From Hacks star Hannah Einbinder's acceptance speech to chants for Stephen Colbert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/emmys-2025-key-moments-from-hannah-einbinder-to-stephen-colbert/105773412</link><description>From a rallying political cry from Hacks star Hannah Einbinder to standing ovations for Stephen Colbert, here are your Emmys 2025 key moments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5949a0290fa0abaf999a6b633f1291cd</guid></item><item><title>How much fish is in tinned tuna, and how to shop for your needs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/packaged-foods-content-supermarkets/105707244</link><description>When you're at the supermarket, do you wonder how much much tuna you're getting in a can? A series of popular social media has been comparing how much food there is in some packaged items.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c07e1af76a9ce085f39b2e2924bc18d</guid></item><item><title>How is Australia affected by climate change? The National Climate Risk Assessment models the future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/national-climate-risk-assessment-and-why-it-matters-explained/105773936</link><description>For the first time, the government has modelled the threats from climate change on Australia's future. What's the point of a document like this, and can it help us avoid the worst-case scenarios?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ad84229da5de3e8a79b28e4eacc8cab</guid></item><item><title>Cricket Tasmania seeking ways to make proposed Macquarie Point stadium 'compatible' for matches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/cricket-tasmania-support-macquarie-point-afl-stadium/105774588</link><description>After initial concerns that the roof design of the proposed Hobart AFL stadium at Macquarie Point would hinder cricket matches, sporting authorities have thrown their support behind the build, saying "we will find a way".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52fc9b1b49c5b01644f528cf1efb60b0</guid></item><item><title>Pasifique Zawadi Niyonyishi sentenced to life in prison for murder of Colin Norton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/pasifique-niyonyishi-sentenced-for-greenwood-murder-colin-norton/105773994</link><description>A man who killed an elderly man as well as stabbing his wife and dog in a "callous and senseless act of unimaginable violence" has been sentenced to life in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0daf907629f0fbd938b2c3568e7ace7e</guid></item><item><title>Defence dilemma facing Anthony Albanese as he heads to New York</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/the-defence-dilemma-facing-albanese-as-he-heads-to-new-york/105775954</link><description>Amid uncertainty over whether the prime minister will secure his first one-on-one meeting with Donald Trump, the political test is whether his recent defence commitments will be seen as a genuine step-up on capability or a sidestep from American calls to spend more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30bac552ea1477bb6ea09d9f427e1a77</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle Knights announce Justin Holbrook as new NRL head coach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/-newcastle-knights-justin-holbrook-nrl-head-coach/105776208</link><description>Sydney Roosters assistant coach Justin Holbrook has been named the new head coach of the Newcastle Knights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1dd4d58f20f4f23adda8178a9bef8c9</guid></item><item><title>Shadow minister Andrew Hastie says he will be 'without a job' if Liberals don't abandon net zero</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/andrew-hastie-flags-resignation-or-sacking-over-liberal-net-zero/105776432</link><description>Liberal frontbencher Andrew Hastie indicates he will quit or be dumped from the shadow cabinet if the Coalition does not abandon the target of achieving net zero greenhouse gas emissions by 2050.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a10d2db02fc472fefaa512221affcf2f</guid></item><item><title>Shadow minister Andrew Hastie says he will be 'without a job' if Liberals don't abandon net zero</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/andrew-hastie-flags-resignation-or-sacking-over-liberal-net-zero/105776432</link><description>Liberal frontbencher Andrew Hastie indicates he will quit or be dumped from the shadow cabinet if the Coalition does not abandon the target of achieving net zero greenhouse gas emissions by 2050.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d65a81fca15feb36d2a53c3d3bdd85a3</guid></item><item><title>Whispering Jack: The John Farnham Musical to premiere in Sydney Theatre Company's 2026 season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/whispering-jack-john-farnham-musical-sydney-theatre-company-2026/105766868</link><description>Whispering Jack: The John Farnham Musical is one of 13 plays coming to Sydney Theatre Company next year, alongside shows starring David Wenham and Miranda Otto.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ade2dd75f87979058d05fced4a9318</guid></item><item><title>Armand Mondo Duplantis breaks world record, Kurtis Marschall wins pole vault bronze at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-2025-in-tokyo-day-3/105774960</link><description>Kurtis Marschall wins bronze in the men's pole vault final on day three of the World Athletics Championships in Tokyo, as Armand Duplantis soars to a 14th world record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a75c97c2c4e50d1aabaf437d14731d7d</guid></item><item><title>All the latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/all-the-latest-financial-news/105776480</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f073c7f7020949078deb2eb0c7a85c</guid></item><item><title>Final rules for social media ban revealed, with no legally enforceable effectiveness standard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/social-media-ban-final-rules-announced/105776730</link><description>While substantial fines would apply to social media platforms that make no effort to ban under-16s, they would not need to test the age of every user.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bf25735e4356b3846b028a3101595a6</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste students protest government plan to buy new cars for parliamentarians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/timor-leste-protesters-demand-repeal-of-plan-to-buy-cars-for-mps/105776898</link><description>About 1,000 students hit the streets of the capital to rally against the plan, before police clashed with some protesters who reportedly threw rocks and damaged properties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ce414e161409b0fcdd72ce826062fbc</guid></item><item><title>US and China agree to TikTok 'framework' ownership agreement at trade talks in Spain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/us-and-china-agree-to-framework-for-tiktok-sale/105776964</link><description>US Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent says the framework would see the platform switch to US ownership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5792446bfea9843c09b316ffd472ee8e</guid></item><item><title>Former MMA fighter Conor McGregor drops out of Irish presidential race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/conor-mcgregor-drops-out-of-irish-presidential-race-/105776960</link><description>Critics say the former MMA fighter's pre-emptive dropout was to save face in a likely knockout at the hands of Dublin City Council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60f1b0734e35fba4e5506343df9a6d2a</guid></item><item><title>Australia-PNG defence treaty will require countries to 'act' if either one is attacked</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/australia-and-png-defence-treaty-could-oblige-military-action/105776214</link><description>Australia and Papua New Guinea will be legally obliged to defend each other from a military attack on either territory under a landmark defence treaty, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a01cbea51a11c9d04e1bcff45aa8aa5</guid></item><item><title>DNA at crime scene matches Charlie Kirk murder suspect, FBI says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/charlie-kirk-crime-scene-dna-matches-murder-suspect/105777360</link><description>Tyler Robinson, 22, was arrested last week over the death of conservative influencer Charlie Kirk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7cf3e37a6ee22b7ae5bb477725734fa</guid></item><item><title>Lawyers urge Australians to ensure valid will in place as house prices rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/lawyers-urge-australians-to-ensure-valid-will-in-place/105767604</link><description>Lawyers urge Australians to ensure they leave behind a valid will to avoid legal disputes as surging house prices and superannuation balances increase the size of inheritances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a89e25f073724834a4daf823bb8d4cd</guid></item><item><title>Fewer Aussies would need NDIS if government boosted mental health support, expert says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/psychosocial-disability-mental-health-ndis/105773308</link><description>As the Albanese government seeks to rein in the cost of the NDIS, a former Australian of the Year says money could be saved with this one shift.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5bca27cbb4ae9aab43ea5684315161e</guid></item><item><title>Climate Risk Assessment's 'high risk' warning for 1 million Australian homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/climate-risk-assessment-million-homes-insurance-gdp-costs/105774418</link><description>One in 10 homes could be effectively uninsurable by 2050, while lost labour productivity to extreme weather could wipe $211 billion in household wealth, the Climate Risk Assessment warns, with tourism, trade, and property values forecasted to take a dive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">801dfb5f2bac8394e795c9893975dce2</guid></item><item><title>ANZ commits bank errors in its favour. Is there any other kind?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/anz-slammed-for-bank-errors-in-its-favour/105775702</link><description>ASIC has lived by that aphorism in its decision to strike a settlement deal with ANZ over a raft of wrongdoing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eab85143099e30eb989aba207539b011</guid></item><item><title>These Plymouth Brethren members stepped out of line, then the threats and intimidation started</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/exclusive-brethren-plymouth-former-members-threats-four-corners/105766026</link><description>The Plymouth Brethren Christian Church is fiercely protective of a multi-billion-dollar business which supports the church. These men found out the extraordinary lengths it will take to keep it safe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f185e31ae155fb6ec535b8575cf57c39</guid></item><item><title>How Melbourne mosquitoes are being used to fight dengue fever and save lives in Laos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/melbourne-mosquitoes-fight-dengue-fever-laos-save-the-children/105773926</link><description>They are the deadliest animals in the world, and millions of them are being sent from Australia to the Laos capital Vientiane in a bid to save lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a24e6c7c32402fe5603b887c428f2552</guid></item><item><title>Pathological Demand Avoidance, a little-known profile of autism affecting kids and adults</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/pathological-demand-avoidance-awareness-of-autism-subtype/105772066</link><description>A surge of professional and personal interest in Pathological Demand Avoidance (PDA), an autism subtype — which in children can affect everything from cleaning teeth to attending school — has led to Australia's first-ever PDA conference, to be held in Perth in November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21dc9dcc25ab99ec13266f4d172f1692</guid></item><item><title>What to expect from Donald Trump's state visit to the UK</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/what-to-expect-donald-trump-uk-state-visit-king-charles/105776968</link><description>The US president will arrive in London on Tuesday evening, local time, for an unprecedented second state visit to the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19d933d53256fb1c8c6c8419ba9dba94</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull believes in world championship 1,500m glory against serial winner Faith Kipyegon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/jess-hull-believes-in-world-championship-1500m-victory/105772376</link><description>Australia's Jess Hull has self-belief, despite facing an uphill task to beat three-time world and Olympic champion Faith Kipyegon over 1,500m at the World Athletics Championships in Tokyo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">101bafefa4e4f1f51f1ac514223465df</guid></item><item><title>WWII-era bombs are killing and injuring thousands in PNG. Now trainees will learn how to remove them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/png-world-war-2-unexploded-ordnance-removal/105774308</link><description>Trainees in Papua New Guinea will learn to remove unexploded ordnance, as fading memories of World War II expose more people to the conflict's dangerous legacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8bf240cd5378047327fc404a9e7f897</guid></item><item><title>Building industry wants more skilled migrants to address housing crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/queensland-building-industry-lobbies-more-skilled-migrants/105774824</link><description>It comes in the wake of anti-immigration rallies held around the country where some blamed "mass migration" for families not being able to afford a home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74f5a976815d824b4a753eec30251425</guid></item><item><title>Victorian childcare worker denies abusing toddlers, says he is appealing ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/victorian-childcare-worker-denies-abuse-appeals-ban/105702584</link><description>A Goodstart worker who allegedly abused toddlers at a Ballarat centre speaks out for the first time and says he is appealing after being banned from working with children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77e6b47d221359d2363dbff039a62a30</guid></item><item><title>Will it happen? Crunch time imminent for Tasmania's proposed Macquarie Point stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/macquarie-point-stadium-planning-decision/105759040</link><description>It's not the be all and end all — but the impending delivery of the Tasmanian Planning Commission's final report is a major moment for the Macquarie Point stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b39f129ad1988ebe3b71971d4e7bb065</guid></item><item><title>US strikes another suspected Venezuelan drug vessel at sea, killing three men</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/us-strikes-venezuelan-vessel-at-sea/105777504</link><description>United States President Donald Trump says the American military carried out a strike on a Venezuelan drug cartel vessel that had been on its way to the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c162ac70f715827468acaca152e97175</guid></item><item><title>American sailor missing after boat found on Queensland's Cape Bedford beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/missing-sailor-cape-bedford/105777430</link><description>Police are appealing for information about a 62-year-old American man believed to have been sailing the Ocean Rambler from Vanuatu after it was found empty on Cape Bedford Beach, north of Cooktown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddc9c84e653ab2b58aacad044cf1c586</guid></item><item><title>Lisa Cook and Stephen Miran set for US Federal Reserve meeting, ASX gains — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/asx-markets-business-live-news-september-16-2025/105776832</link><description>The ASX gained ground on Tuesday, while markets now have greater certainty about the make-up of the US Federal Reserve board for this week's key rates meeting. Look back on the day's events and insights on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1b63a55aee1200f8bf11f3ef182b626</guid></item><item><title>Bird's eye view of military strike on alleged drug ship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/birds-eye-view-of-military-strike-on-alleged-drug-ship/105777620</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">895b5ecf71da0cd080acea4fe5c25c3a</guid></item><item><title>Tia-Clair Toomey-Orr's eighth CrossFit Games title confirms her GOAT status</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/tia-clair-toomey-on-motherhood-and-becoming-the-crossfit-goat/105774312</link><description>Tia-Clair Toomey-Orr has been considered the CrossFit GOAT for some time, and she is not slowing down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b1bf3278129b6f1f5eae0776b29f16f</guid></item><item><title>Jacinta Nampijinpa Price and Kerrynne Liddle a 'unity ticket' on Indigenous affairs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/kerrynne-liddle-backs-jacinta-nampijinpa-price/105776102</link><description>Kerrynne Liddle speaks for the first time since Jacinta Nampijinpa Price was dumped from the frontbench, saying the pair are "on a unity ticket" when it comes to Indigenous affairs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">baf6de4a9c0796b996abab3ba46e1810</guid></item><item><title>Spanish prime minister calls for Israel to be banned from sport after La Vuelta a España finale called off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/vuelta-a-espana-final-stage-cancelled-pro-palestinian-protests/105777508</link><description>Pro-Palestinian protests sparked by the inclusion of an Israeli team in La Vuelta a España prompt the cancellation of the last stage of the race, with Spain's prime minister calling for Israel to be treated like Russia by sporting organisations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac0ef3fdcf72c0008f752df151d4c3f8</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Government releases guidelines for social media platforms ahead of teen ban — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/federal-politics-live-sept-16/105776142</link><description>The communications minister and eSafety commissioner have released guidelines for social media platforms ahead of the government's social media ban for children under 16.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0af2050e9243a41158d9a8cc7d6317a0</guid></item><item><title>The hidden impact of injuries costing AFL clubs millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/the-hidden-costs-of-injuries-costing-afl-clubs-millions/105777624</link><description>New research highlights the financial impact of injuries in the AFL, with one club losing $13 millions over six seasons, nearly 17 per cent of its total player salaries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1df9a60d5e14380c28dd088a5cbf203a</guid></item><item><title>Rex Airlines apologises after wheelchair-using passenger stranded for six hours at Perth Airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/rex-passenger-issues-albany-perth-wheelchair-user-/105774708</link><description>Albany woman Debby Butler says she had to ask strangers to help her to the bathroom after Rex delayed her flight home from Perth Airport and left her without a wheelchair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbfe858ddf70fc0694fbe80e02bdc22a</guid></item><item><title>Trump announces crackdown on crime in Memphis and potentially Chicago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/trump-announces-crackdown-on-crime-in-memphis-and/105777884</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0ba18c5a8036c7a65716b099a960d11</guid></item><item><title>Future of Bendigo Writers Festival unclear amid calls for transparent review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/bendigo-writers-festival-future-unclear-after-boycott/105773484</link><description>A councillor is demanding answers from his own executive over the botched Bendigo Writers Festival, asking colleagues whether they want to be remembered as the council that "killed" it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a2675a41175e051c99bd70c72ebf69a</guid></item><item><title>Opponents react to Trump's crackdown on crime in Memphis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/opponents-react-to-trumps-crackdown-on-crime-in-memphis/105778000</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afb3ae0109a5af6fae1efda3a3fd4422</guid></item><item><title>Cathy Freeman and Ian Thorpe among Stadium Australia's first hall of fame inductees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/cathy-freeman-ian-thorpe-stadium-australia-hall-of-fame/105777908</link><description>The first golden group of inductees were honoured at an event that threw back to the Sydney 2000 games with Nikki Webster reproducing her iconic opening ceremony performance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdef62442b745f1023ee6848ed55f9e3</guid></item><item><title>Nikki Webster sings with her children for 25th anniversary of Sydney Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/nikki-webster-sings-with-her-children-for-25th/105778014</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c83bf0274f16a9fa314e120145c3d8f</guid></item><item><title>Lisa Reihana's exhibition, Voyager, recasts history through an Indigenous lens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/lisa-reihana-ngununggula-exhibition-voyager-indigenous-maori/105760474</link><description>The internationally renowned Maori artist's technically complex, visually mesmerising exhibition spans nearly a decade of artwork.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ed46a76298102094bcf604b8536fb9b</guid></item><item><title>How to determine if your kid is well enough for child care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/the-advice-around-sending-a-sick-kid-to-child-care/105734762</link><description>Work demands and a lack of village mean keeping a child at home from care every time they have a sniffle can be a dilemma for many parents. So when it it OK to send them?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3431c0d66326982196374e9a6c348b5f</guid></item><item><title>Family comes first for Queensland newsreader Rob Brough after months off-air</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/newsreader-rob-broughs-family-battle/105775464</link><description>The long-time nightly newsreader says it was an "instant choice" to leave work as his daughter faced a battle with cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23d10f83e00ccce3717d0f0a569d4a1c</guid></item><item><title>One dead, seven hospitalised after gas leak at Sydney restaurant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/nsw-sydney-riverstone-gas-leak-restaurant/105778610</link><description>One person has died and several others, including police officers, are receiving medical treatment after a gas leak at a restaurant in north-west Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76b6419455a92ca2c50b00a13fd21c01</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump to send National Guard into Memphis to combat crime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/donald-trump-to-send-national-guard-to-memphis-to-combat-crime/105777774</link><description>Donald Trump signs a memorandum to send the National Guard into Memphis to combat crime, setting up another major test of his presidential power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c86283160022e1f0e8600e6a1f66f14</guid></item><item><title>Which Centrelink payments will be increasing (slightly) over the weekend?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/centrelink-pension-carer-payment-disability-support/105777756</link><description>Certain Centrelink payments will be increasing with inflation from Saturday. Check to see if you're affected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e79f140d0b4167604ec1dbdef40cb82</guid></item><item><title>As the Trump administration blows up suspicious boats, legal experts raise red flags</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/trump-administration-lethal-force-drug-cartels-international-law/105778434</link><description>Donald Trump is using the US military to bomb boats suspected of carrying drugs in international waters. But little is known about who is being killed, and military and legal experts are raising several red flags.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f45edea7a8f89a760d2113ff13065ce7</guid></item><item><title>Trump confirms US military carried out strike on drug boat from Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/trump-confirms-us-military-carried-out-strike/105777688</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac78de1cdb120bc010d65f78e27d2742</guid></item><item><title>Craig McLachlan withdraws from Cluedo stage show following backlash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/craig-mclachlan-withdraws-cluedo-the-play/105779280</link><description>Less than a week ago, Craig McLachlan was announced to play Colonel Mustard in the forthcoming national tour, making his return to the theatre after The Rocky Horror Show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2abe05c441b509ea22995eb926f87711</guid></item><item><title>Australia Diamonds announce netball squads for Test series against New Zealand, South Africa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/australia-diamonds-announce-test-netball-squads-new-zealand-sa/105779230</link><description>Goal-shooter Lucy Austin is a shock selection in the Australian netball squad to face South Africa, winning a place after initially being included as an "invitee" to their training camp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f84722b6abee542504171a8343b1b82</guid></item><item><title>Where and how to watch the 2025 Primetime Emmy award-wining shows in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/where-and-how-to-watch-the-emmy-award-wining-shows/105778142</link><description>From The Studio to The Pitt, here's how to stream the biggest winners of the 2025 Primetime Emmy Awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3034e31269c6f5feac0ed68921c317c</guid></item><item><title>Perth childcare worker Robert David Reti faces court for allegedly indecently touching two girls at separate centres</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/perth-childcare-worker-robert-reti-accused-of-indecent-acts/105778920</link><description>A male childcare worker indecently touched two young girls in his care at separate childcare centres in Perth, a court hears.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8773ffc337006c01be69dfa51723999</guid></item><item><title>Victoria delays Gippsland offshore wind auction, stalling developers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/victoria-offshore-wind-auction-delay/105778708</link><description>The Victorian government pushes back its timeline for new offshore wind farms in the state's east in a blow to developers looking to move their projects to the next stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80c982b89a58ea8f9bc5c06f098af297</guid></item><item><title>Aaron Chen talks comedy, faith, and moving to New York</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/aaron-chen-take-5-comedy-interview-music-tonight-fisk/105773602</link><description>How Aaron Chen went from being booted out of Sydney pubs to winning Logies and chasing global stardom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd43f88c371be470e8b83b1b925f650a</guid></item><item><title>Papua New Guinea celebrates journey to independence, 50 years after parting with Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/papua-new-guinea-50-years-independence-from-australia/105775268</link><description>On the foreshore of Papua New Guinea's capital city, Ela Beach is where locals come to exercise, mingle and unwind at the end of a long day. But it wasn't always this way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7147eb3a5bc7c7f0eca073099802ceb5</guid></item><item><title>Does washing your fruit and veggies remove chemicals?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/best-way-to-wash-fresh-produce-fruits-veggies-remove-chemcials-/105773664</link><description>This is what experts have to say about washing fruit and veggies, with removing chemicals and reducing the amount we consume in mind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57b4d4864180c3c11eed8be0eca03f20</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump files defamation and libel lawsuit against The New York Times, claiming 'massive economic damage to his brand value'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/trump-files-us15-billion-lawsuit-against-new-york-times/105779782</link><description>In a lengthy post on his social media platform, the US president accused The New York Times of lying about him, his family and his business.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">025394af4103f19c4c76069f86680f4b</guid></item><item><title>Concurrent disasters will overwhelm responders, stress ADF, risk report warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/defence-forces-disaster-response-climate-risk-assessment/105778304</link><description>A dedicated disaster recovery force is needed, or else responders and defence forces could be "overwhelmed" by multiple concurrent natural disasters, the National Climate Risk Assessment warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79a82e7988ce64cb47e2aea9d939b300</guid></item><item><title>Breastfeeding Gold Coast mum says she was asked to leave Virgin Australia lounge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/virgin-australia-apologises-mother-pumping-breast-milk/105779738</link><description>Mother-of-two Elise Turner says she was asked to leave the Virgin Australia business lounge after refusing to go to a bathroom to pump breast milk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a5d01ae6ec3bc3224e376127e761ff5</guid></item><item><title>How Isabelle Kelly shook off getting her 'teeth pushed back' to return for Roosters' NRLW finals charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/isabelle-kelly-injury-jaw-teeth-roosters-nrlw-finals/105780582</link><description>Isabelle Kelly was meant to rest up for a few weeks after suffering an oral fracture that nearly cost her several teeth but the Roosters skipper missed just one match and has now returned to lead the club's premiership charge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">062a7201f7cd32cadeb54c8069a61337</guid></item><item><title>China has a 'chokehold' on the rare earth supply chain. Could Australia offer an alternative?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/china-rare-earths-monopoly-australia-alternative-supplier/105748058</link><description>Rare earths are critical for manufacturing everything from electric vehicles to wind turbines and defence equipment, and with China's dominance over the supply chain, they have also become inextricably enmeshed in geopolitics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7e66c6df15c930bf8fa103970dac05b</guid></item><item><title>Israeli military launches ground offensive to occupy Gaza City</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/idf-launches-military-offensive-to-occupy-gaza/105777948</link><description>The Israel Defense Forces says its expanded operation in Gaza City "to destroy Hamas's military infrastructure" has begun, with residents warned to move south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80bfd937165cc59a068b4d0ad85e2045</guid></item><item><title>Israel is committing genocide in Gaza, major United Nations report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/israel-committing-genocide-in-gaza-un-report-says/105780230</link><description>Israel has committed and is continuing to commit genocide in Gaza, according to the "most authoritative assessment" to date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e547fcd275b42fb12bbaa7d9028fd7aa</guid></item><item><title>James O'Connor still hopeful of playing Bledisloe Cup for Wallabies against All Blacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/james-oconnor-still-hopeful-of-playing-bledisloe-cup/105780738</link><description>James O'Connor has flown to England with his Test future still up in the air, but the Wallabies playmaker has not given up on playing in his first Bledisloe Cup match in five years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fe6060cfa537dad8e49fa78e8c41f63</guid></item><item><title>A UN report says Israel is committing genocide. Experts hope it spurs Australia to act</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/un-report-on-israel-genocide-msg-to-nations-including-australia/105777232</link><description>What ultimately determines whether the UN's report joins the list of other shocking but overlooked inquiries is whether this latest finding moves any governments, including Australia's, to take further action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">121775c05df3d7bd0ed0b0d63cee2c23</guid></item><item><title>Simon Lviev, the Tinder Swindler on Netflix, arrested after allegedly scamming victims out of $15 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/the-tinder-swindler-simon-lviev-arrested-in-georgia/105780320</link><description>Simon Lviev, 34, rose to notoriety after a pattern of romance fraud and financial crimes, with victims scammed out of an estimated $15 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">408e01733332e7bcef8aa275d501d586</guid></item><item><title>Jacinta Allan's trip to China aims to court investment and voters back home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/victorian-premier-jacinta-allan-in-china-analysis/105780358</link><description>Jacinta Allan's one week trip to the Middle Kingdom is a show with two audiences, as she eyes Chinese investment and hopes to solidify her party's relationship with Chinese Victorians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dda66615efc3bab85e42708bef31ff82</guid></item><item><title>China accuses Philippines of 'illegal' intrusion at its new nature reserve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/china-accuses-philippines-of-illegal-intrusion-at-new-reserve/105781038</link><description>China's coastguard has accused Philippine ships of illegally entering China's territorial waters at a shoal that is internationally recognised as within the Philippines' exclusive economic zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d22fae2218c2b953ce31ac500d27401e</guid></item><item><title>NRL finals week two team lists: Canterbury Bulldogs pick new halves combination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/nrl-finals-week-two-team-lists-bulldogs-panthers-raiders-sharks/105781098</link><description>Winger Jacob Kiraz has revealed he is happy to keep playing with painkilling injections as a patched-up Canterbury turn to a barely tested halves combination of Lachlan Galvin and Toby Sexton to save their NRL season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e00963cd95ccbc1a7f4dac1f88d12452</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105781402</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e2b5a3b30f5fdf1b8c8739f00047ca8</guid></item><item><title>Man 'choked to death' on ribbons and food in Adelaide nursing home, inquest told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/sa-inquest-hears-nursing-home-resident-choked-on-ribbons/105697736</link><description>A nursing home resident known to wander and ingest foreign objects died after choking on ribbons at a facility in Adelaide’s north, an inquest has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95ba5d590939d36f5248d85d89547a6f</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull wins 1,500m bronze, Peter Bol crashes out at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-jess-hull/105778240</link><description>Jess Hull claims bronze in the women's 1,500m at the World Athletics Championships, after Peter Bol was eliminated from the 800m in the heats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7250f2b7b3eaaed7b8f51092ef3fc818</guid></item><item><title>Queensland foster care system in crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/queensland-foster-care-system-in-crisis/105781478</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">050276968a234a4a8e5809f380070fb4</guid></item><item><title>Is the Opposition in crisis over climate change policy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/is-the-opposition-in-crisis-over-climate-change/105781502</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e90e0f2ed4edff762cfcb406a5eae813</guid></item><item><title>Loosening China’s grip on the rare earths and minerals market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/loosening-china%E2%80%99s-grip-on-the-rare-earths-and/105781508</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d020be72c308ae5ce30906d44c2f2fa</guid></item><item><title>Celebrating PNG’s 50th anniversary of independence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/celebrating-png%E2%80%99s-50th-anniversary-of-independence/105781522</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dabfed74d454bdf5be85a7bf1add319</guid></item><item><title>Broadcaster Alan Jones hit with nine new indecent assault charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/alan-jones-new-indecent-assault-charges/105781256</link><description>Court records confirm the new charges were formally laid against veteran broadcaster Alan Jones on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b603c10b6c32f66440446167e3e24ee3</guid></item><item><title>Robert Redford, Hollywood idol of the 1970s and Oscar-winning director and actor, has died aged 89</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/actor-and-activist-robert-redford-dies-aged-89/105781564</link><description>Redford died "at his home in Sundance in the mountains of Utah" surrounded by family, his publicist announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f08a88e14f2b784115f4aa8b363f1ecc</guid></item><item><title>Nepal's protests estimated to have caused hundreds of millions of dollars in damage as families farewell those killed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/nepal-gen-z-protests-cause-millions-of-dollars-in-damage/105781578</link><description>As clean-up efforts continue and an interim government finds its feet, families have said farewell to loved ones killed in last week's violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1064109a46dbf7b37962228d9f172092</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump takes aim at ABC journalist as he suggests he'll meet Albanese 'very soon'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/donald-trump-john-lyons-exchange-before-anthony-albanese-meeting/105781624</link><description>Donald Trump takes aim at the ABC's Americas Editor during an extraordinary exchange at the White House, as the president suggests he will meet Prime Minister Anthony Albanese "very soon".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">156db315a11501aa8fbeaf35550e4091</guid></item><item><title>New York judge dismisses state terrorism charges against Luigi Mangione</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/judge-dismisses-terrorism-charges-against-luigi-mangione/105781696</link><description>The 27-year-old Ivy League graduate still faces New York state second-degree murder charges and a federal death penalty prosecution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdb179c60ca3cc9f40d0ef6ea086656d</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste protesters vow to continue rallying until plan to buy MPs 65 cars is overturned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/timor-leste-protests-over-mp-car-plan-grow/105781726</link><description>The protests nearly doubled in size on Tuesday as people continued to vent their frustrations at a plan to buy MPs 65 new SUVs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">feeb6a6ab4a2322ebf2709358b8c2353</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk shooting suspect Tyler Robinson charged with murder as prosecutors seek death penalty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/alleged-charlie-kirk-shooter-tyler-robinson-charged/105781872</link><description>Utah prosecutors say they will seek the death penalty for the 22-year-old alleged shooter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87bd66a147b9d8ff76e79fdd79e8ff76</guid></item><item><title>Australians too dependent on government, says Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/australians-too-dependent-on-government-says-sussan-ley/105781276</link><description>In her first major economic speech, the opposition leader hits out at universal subsidies and says "dependency" has affected Australia's "national character".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">651c319b8e005af88f9f36c064e26d9e</guid></item><item><title>Britain is hoping it has a secret weapon to charm Donald Trump this week: 'all his favourite things'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/donald-trump-heads-to-uk-for-second-state-visit/105764556</link><description>The US president has been given something no other world leader has ever received: a second state visit invitation from Buckingham Palace. But assessing the trip's success means looking beneath the pomp and pageantry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">816968e21bc208bd8ed8cd9ca5863c1d</guid></item><item><title>Botox, fillers among the cosmetic injectables targeted in medical regulator's new rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/cosmetic-injectables-rules-botox-fillers/105778596</link><description>New rules have come into place aimed at better protecting patients from unsafe cosmetic procedures. Here's what it mean for your next appointment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f034dc98c168b046f196741357b091bf</guid></item><item><title>Threat of stagflation bears down on world's largest economy as Federal Reserve decision looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/threat-of-stagflation-bears-down-on-world-s-largest-economy/105781264</link><description>The world's largest central bank is less than 24 hours from announcing one of the most anticipated interest rate decisions of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">317d2acf44c6b55d5cef638469f7338f</guid></item><item><title>When does Gout Gout run at the World Athletics Championships? How to watch Gout Gout's 200m heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/when-does-gout-gout-run-200m-at-world-athletics-championships/105775006</link><description>Gout Gout will make his senior World Athletics Championships debut at the Tokyo National Stadium on Wednesday night. Here's how to watch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d64ce570ae00cb2a79c594c389ec4b0</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of childcare workers blacklisted but parents kept in the dark</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/childcare-workers-blacklisted/105774698</link><description>About 400 educators were issued prohibition orders banning them from early education or care in the past five years, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">969481d17339daff15088beab11c2217</guid></item><item><title>A plan to simplify Melbourne's bus network went to government, so why hasn't it happened?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/victoria-bus-system-public-transport/105780926</link><description>Victoria is spending the least per capita on its urban bus system of any state, leaving some Melbourne residents in the lurch at their local bus stop.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cb0b4a268780d533d155aede414aefc</guid></item><item><title>Trump tells off ABC reporter over question about personal wealth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/trump-tells-off-australian-reporter/105781964</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4126cdea12b1cfee4255c1102333a08</guid></item><item><title>Federal Home Guarantee Scheme to expand – but just how many will be able to afford to buy in?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/home-loan-guarantee-scheme-cost-first-home-buyers/105772918</link><description>The expansion of the scheme, which allows first home buyers to purchase a property with as little as a 5 per cent deposit, has some warning it will also inflate the market. Here's what you'll need to be earning to get a foot in the door.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4fd4e5c6040f2d8b9de5c0800458317</guid></item><item><title>Unpaid mandatory work experience a 'significant barrier' for some NSW law students</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/plt-unpaid-placements-nsw-law-students-a-financial-difficulty/105774700</link><description>During her unpaid placement at a not-for-profit community legal centre in Sydney, Dani struggled to make ends meet. She is among some law students whose entry into the profession is fraught with financial difficulty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a77e2484c201c3b6a1ff99c5e168d5c6</guid></item><item><title>Fingal Post Office saved from closure after local pig farmers confirmed as new operators</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/fingal-post-office-in-tasmania-saved-by-local-pig-farmers/105779962</link><description>A rural Tasmanian community has fought to keep its post office open, fearing losing the important service could lead to their hometown disappearing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08e347abc9bfa22abeb9447ad06020ab</guid></item><item><title>Israeli military vision appears to show vehicle movement through Gaza City</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/israeli-military-vision-appears-to-show-vehicle-movement/105782006</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88f2226649850cdf70cba484717babdc</guid></item><item><title>Israeli military vehicles among damaged buildings near Gaza City.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/israeli-military-vehicles-among-damaged-buildings-near-gaza-city/105782022</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdb604848ca36e54000e0b2b24d4f064</guid></item><item><title>SA's ongoing harmful algal bloom labelled 'cultural emergency' by First Nations groups</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/sa-algal-bloom-cultural-emergency/105631230</link><description>First Nations South Australians say the harmful algal bloom impacting the state's coastline is a cultural emergency, as it continues to devastate beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ed15cf74630a813b331beecfe638cdf</guid></item><item><title>Fire threatens koala habitat at Gold Coast national park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/fire-threatens-koala-habitat-at-burleigh-headland/105781982</link><description>Police are investigating how a suspicious fire started in a Gold Coast national park and popular tourist spot overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a9ef095f199bc494bedacf6b3ab64f2</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians fear they have no place to flee as Israel's army pushes deeper into Gaza city</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/israel-push-deeper-gaza-city-palestinians-fear-no-place-to-flee/105781870</link><description>Israeli troops encircle Gaza City as the UN chief slams the offensive as "systematic destruction", with thousands of Palestinians unable or unwilling to flee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d201c662cb235506a4e3a65fa23e2158</guid></item><item><title>For the Adelaide Crows, the AFL season was a matter of 'what could have been'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/adelaide-crows-reflect-on-afl-finals-exit-after-minor-premiers/105778196</link><description>After an eight-year AFL finals drought, the Adelaide Crows finished this year's home-and-away season as minor premiers — but the club's hopes were dashed by consecutive defeats that left the players and their fans wondering about what might have been.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b79b17dec6a9f9b23b4349c7283d3818</guid></item><item><title>Children are being 'poisoned' by high lead levels as state government agency is accused of report cover-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/broken-hill-lead-poisoning-cover-up-mudgee-silver-mine-fears/105775230</link><description>A state government body sat on a report into lead dust that was "poisoning" children for nearly four years and tried to keep its release quiet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c539d0a8e324dc8143836fe465192aec</guid></item><item><title>Griffith locals push for new health district to meet needs of their community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/griffith-locals-push-for-new-health-district/105729862</link><description>Residents and medical professionals in south-western NSW are pushing to establish a new local health district in Griffith, arguing current services are not good enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">811a2f3a903585b4dace7ad758f6a3f0</guid></item><item><title>ABC reporter reflects on heated exchange with Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/abc-reporter-reflects-on-heated-exchange-with-trump/105782066</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d66c9b484df7f246f7468910b081bdfa</guid></item><item><title>Cashrewards's abrupt closure leaves shoppers many unanswered questions. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/cashrewards-abrupt-shutdown-stuns-many-australians/105765936</link><description>Two and a half million Australians have signed up for this cashback app, which leaves them wondering what's next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74d5aaf89ebaad05dd5c26265b442d23</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: Donald Trumps flags meeting with Anthony Albanese</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/federal-politics-live-september-17/105781024</link><description>A long-awaited meeting between Anthony Albanese and Donald Trump could take place next week, the US president has suggested. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43721cebab6002970109bf4316e512ac</guid></item><item><title>New doco Signorinella: Little Miss celebrates the Italian women who shaped modern Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/signorinella-little-miss-documentary-italian-film-festival/105774428</link><description>Signorinella: Little Miss, the new documentary from the filmmakers behind Lygon St — Si Parla Italiano, celebrates the tenacity of Italian Australian women in business and beyond.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dc3ea23b27aab754a73fa0319a25aee</guid></item><item><title>NT DPP considering appeal of 'callous' fatal hit-run driver's home detention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/nt-appeal-call-in-shocking-aboriginal-hit-and-run-death/105780750</link><description>The Northern Territory’s Director of Public Prosecutions is considering whether to appeal a decision to allow a young fatal hit-and-run driver who bragged to his friends afterwards to avoid jail time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb939e2ec24d851b13e88e0a5a420eb3</guid></item><item><title>Starving wallabies on the Mornington Peninsula have been spared from euthanasia after council motion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/vic-briars-wallabies-council-decision/105781992</link><description>A council on Victoria's Mornington Peninsula has voted to relocate starving wallabies from The Briars wildlife sanctuary, rather than destroy them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02ef3566afd789e1a2e2de6749141251</guid></item><item><title>Sam Konstas scores Australia A century in four-day game in India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/sam-konstas-scores-australia-a-century-against-india-a/105782060</link><description>Sam Konstas's push for an Ashes spot continues as he clatters a century in an extended session for Australia A in Lucknow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cec1e71dd86b61ad4d12f75e6292662</guid></item><item><title>WA Police officers subject to restraining orders desk-bound under gun reforms, union says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/wa-police-taken-off-beat-under-gun-reforms/105743700</link><description>WA Police officers are being taken off the beat because new firearms laws mean they can't carry a gun if they're subject to a restraining order, their union says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9778f00d409cd20aa6f59b898e30bc37</guid></item><item><title>Animal advocates want WA to 'get on board' with phasing out greyhound racing amid welfare concerns</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/wa-greyhound-racing-parliamentary-inquiry/105781496</link><description>Animal advocates call on the WA government to follow the lead of other jurisdictions and phase out greyhound racing, as a state parliamentary inquiry examines the sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca3dd25af1228f5719bc5e267e38741b</guid></item><item><title>Animal advocates want WA to 'get on board' with phasing out greyhound racing amid welfare concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/wa-greyhound-racing-parliamentary-inquiry/105781496</link><description>Animal advocates call on the WA government to follow the lead of other jurisdictions and phase out greyhound racing, as a state parliamentary inquiry examines the sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d151b0111cbdf98135b0a72304ccd15</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull completes second act at World Athletics Championships as quest for gold continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/jess-hull-world-1500m-bronze-medal-wants-gold/105781748</link><description>Jess Hull claimed Australia's best result in a 1,500m at the world championships with a bronze medal, but she wants to make it gold next time around.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b678c9c3d3bc90e24f522348f78b840</guid></item></channel></rss>