<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 03:22:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Alice Springs Mayor Asta Hill tells of family tragedy that brought her back to home town</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/how-family-tragedy-brought-asta-hill-back-to-alice-springs/105784262</link><description>Asta Hill's grief over the tragic death of her younger brother 10 years ago is still raw, but the sad event is part of her story of connection to Alice Springs and hope for the outback town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a31d7502a77bae2501d929fd094d9fc2</guid></item><item><title>EPA investigates disturbing hum sound keeping north-west Sydney residents up at night</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/epa-investigates-disturbing-hum-sound-parramatta/105805278</link><description>One sleepless resident said he drove around his local area to find the source of the disturbance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b07ecb0776d08afdd32e2f257e0a26f</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of hitting 42yo with vehicle in Kalgoorlie appears in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/detectives-from-major-crime-investigate-kalgoorlie-mans-death/105801802</link><description>A 29-year-old man has faced court today after detectives from WA Police's Homicide Squad charged him with murder, two days after the death of a man in the state's Goldfields.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46cd053682653a831ef9b4ab4db28ca6</guid></item><item><title>Siosifa Talakai says Cronulla Sharks players 'at each other's throats' before revival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/nrl-siosifa-talakai-cronulla-sharks-season-revival/105806244</link><description>Sharks star Siosifa Talakai gives an insight into the heated player meetings that came during Cronulla's mid-season slump before the team's spectacular charge to an NRL preliminary final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5df9ad45da27441d21ee6e4e6523186c</guid></item><item><title>ICC prosecutors charge Phillipines' former leader Duterte with crimes against humanity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/icc-prosecutors-charge-duterte-3-counts-crimes-against-humanity/105806448</link><description>Former president of the Philippines, Rodrigo Duterte, is accused of being involved in the murder of dozens of people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">186fbab29d9070e10f640592f7123774</guid></item><item><title>Bill Gates pledges $US912 million to AIDS and malaria non-profit as US cuts funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/bill-gates-foundation-pleaged-millions-to-global-fund/105806406</link><description>The tech entrepreneur's announcement follows deep cuts from governments around the world, led by the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd0e8c660df290dadbcdf29a13957875</guid></item><item><title>Man known as 'Moore Park Rapist' pleads guilty to series of sexual assaults in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/moore-park-rapist-glenn-cameron-pleads-guilty-sexual-assaults/105806986</link><description>Glenn Cameron has remained in custody since he was arrested in February last year and charged with more than 30 offences in relation to eight victims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c631b0b48e05bf34d6cd7b4127803d77</guid></item><item><title>MS support agency MS Society SA &amp; NT outlines three-year losses, $2.5m debt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/ms-society-sa-nt-facing-millions-in-debt/105806282</link><description>Non-profit organisation MS Society SA &amp; NT, says it has debts of about $2.5 million and has been facing losses for three years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">170d075b7f4176d41d4a209cb5faf5bc</guid></item><item><title>Why many Palestinians are underwhelmed by countries like Australia only now recognising statehood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/palestinians-react-to-statehood-recognition-australia-un/105805514</link><description>Australia joined nine other nations in formally recognising Palestinian statehood at the UN this week. But Palestinians have mixed feelings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57a8a3d3134b09135ecae50caa8ec2a8</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu plans to sign police deal with China while Nakamal pact with Australia is left hanging</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/china-vanuatu-police-agreement-equipment-training/105806934</link><description>Vanuatu declares it will sign a new policing agreement with China as the landmark Nakamal pact between Australia and the Pacific Island nation hangs in the balance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e015a5946bffafc3e5c33cd1d8fa895e</guid></item><item><title>Concerns 'off-brand' cigarettes easy to access and cheaper</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/concerns-off-brand-cigarettes-easy-to-access-and/105807734</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e1d889cc16fa1dfacac6368020592c5</guid></item><item><title>Sean 'Diddy' Combs's lawyers pitch shorter prison term, therapy ahead of sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/sean-diddy-combs-lawyers-try-to-impose-14-month-sentence/105807480</link><description>The disgraced hip-hop mogul is expected to be sentenced on October 3.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a3eba260c2608ab5712fd146ba5a4b4</guid></item><item><title>Optus triple-0 outage tragedy: What we know and how events unfolded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/timeline-on-optus-triple-0-outage-what-we-know/105805890</link><description>The first sign something was wrong came late on Friday afternoon. Now we have a clearer picture of how the triple-0 outage unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c548c42002e87e4dd015358e8d8279e9</guid></item><item><title>Victoria Police dog on the road to recovery after horror collision in Melbourne's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/victoria-police-dog-injured-car-accident/105805824</link><description>A man has been charged following a collision in Tullamarine that left a police dog and his handler with injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63e90f91a0b55706b1f1ae1fb7432821</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of bees swarm Wagga Wagga CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/thousands-of-bees-swarm-wagga-wagga-cbd/105808258</link><description>Thousands of bees appear without warning in the regional city, alarming locals and causing a commotion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27722e02bcf2c9eb1efacb7eed1b7299</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm's Jahrome Hughes and Ryan Papenhuyzen return for NRL preliminary final against Cronulla</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/storm-jahrome-hughes-against-cronulla-broncos-panthers/105808480</link><description>Melbourne recall three big guns, led by star half Jahrome Hughes, as their NRL title hopes go on the line in Friday night's preliminary final against Cronulla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1926a9906773436f42474dc790c296f5</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105809052</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2291dde89e5f6f2e800c553bd2118818</guid></item><item><title>Super Typhoon Ragasa lashes Taiwan, with at least 15 dead and 152 missing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/super-typhoon-ragasa-taiwan-dead-missing/105809264</link><description>The most powerful storm so far in 2025 is now heading towards the Chinese mainland, prompting widespread disruption and warnings of sea surges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e86c797982ae3107e7d7d8203132df06</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump uses United Nations speech to lay out the US's complaints with the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/united-nations-general-assembly-donald-trump-speech/105809190</link><description>Donald Trump uses a speech at the UN to criticise US allies' moves to recognise Palestine and chastise the international community over a range of other American grievances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">251d1ac533cc88fd01a9540772aff365</guid></item><item><title>Russia systematically torturing Ukrainian civilians, UN says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/russia-systematically-torturing-ukrainian-civilians-un-says/105809316</link><description>The report is based on detailed interviews with 215 former detainees captured since Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b3ec3854b230344943aa0ea9a1c50f</guid></item><item><title>Incoming triple-0 reforms may not have helped prevent Optus failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/triple-0-reforms-may-not-have-helped-optus-failure/105807524</link><description>The federal government has yet to pass legislation to empower a new coordinator for the emergency services line, but experts say tougher conditions are needed on the telco itself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">196d665b157a51d6ce3440ca5be81bfc</guid></item><item><title>Record number of calls to poisons hotlines for children ingesting melatonin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/melatonin-poisons-hotline-kidshealth/105802406</link><description>The ABC has analysed data from poisons hotlines across the country, revealing almost 1,500 calls were made about children taking melatonin last year, a dramatic rise on previous figures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6379f1180fb83dd59536f7b7017c4f87</guid></item><item><title>Could artificial intelligence and a universal basic income eliminate 'meaningless jobs'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/will-we-need-a-universal-basic-income-to-deal-with-ai-job-losses/105747954</link><description>COVID showed just how "fragile" our economic security is. As artificial intelligence potentially takes jobs from humans, a universal basic income might be a solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5953e2ae7f84df41d0ff5021a284652b</guid></item><item><title>Ryan Routh faces life in prison after guilty verdict in Donald Trump assassination attempt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ryan-routh-guilty-of-donald-trump-assassination-attempt/105809490</link><description>A man accused of trying to assassinate Donald Trump at his Florida golf course last year has been found guilty on all charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0214a8b817cf4108f24678a4dba1f80a</guid></item><item><title>Australians are moving to Tasmania to escape climate change, but the island state is not immune</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/australians-moving-to-tasmania-to-escape-climate-change/105785996</link><description>Jack and Anna swapped the humidity of Queensland for chilly days in Tasmania, but is Tasmania really the climate refuge many think it is?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0ff7fbad477aed99626b4746b82c14c</guid></item><item><title>Holbrook Landcare wins Bob Hawke award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/holbrook-landcare-wins-bob-hawke-award/105806834</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebdc5b27d20f0774f792387b024bec7b</guid></item><item><title>Holbrook Landcare Network wins 2025 Bob Hawke Award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/holbrook-landcare-network-wins-2025-bob-hawke-award/105803040</link><description>A landcare network at "the forefront of technology" has won the 2025 Bob Hawke Award for its innovative approach to sustainable farming practices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">704bd35d01dd4bdc8154c105eb49b76a</guid></item><item><title>How climate change impacted the 2025 snow season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/climate-change-impacted-2025-snow-season/105808698</link><description>The general sentiment is Australia's ski resorts are coming to the end of a bumper snow season — but is this evaluation accurate, or just positive spin after the dismal 2023 and 2024 seasons?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d83586cda83a6d18a50afafa5ab2f844</guid></item><item><title>Dickie Bird, former English cricket umpire, dies aged 92</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/dickie-bird-former-english-cricket-umpire-dies-aged-92/105809586</link><description>One of international cricket's most recognised umpires is being remembered for his "fairness, humour and love of the game".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ea286fdda73733b0f123adaeb2b514e</guid></item><item><title>Video record of violence and racism at Purnim Bears, Noorat country football grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/violence-racism-of-80s-country-victoria-football-grand-final/105741080</link><description>The Purnim Bears were supposed to be the feel-good story of country football — a team uniting black and white communities. But their 1987 grand final was so violent it ended with their expulsion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">231bb9fc7a4848fb3114f306c75ce3e0</guid></item><item><title>England names squad to face Australia in men's Ashes series 2025/26</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/england-name-squad-to-face-australia-in-men-s-ashes-series/105809606</link><description>England will bring a strong pace bowling attack, but several members of the squad, including captain Ben Stokes, are under injury clouds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d0a0a9cfab837e21e9251c67e841c3</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine can win back all territory lost to Russia, Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ukraine-can-win-back-all-territory-lost-to-russia-trump-says/105809578</link><description>The US president criticised Russia on the sidelines of the UN General Assembly, saying it had been fighting "aimlessly" in a war that a "real military power" would have won in less than a week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51fff57c3ffcb071ce802513857b4a30</guid></item><item><title>Mal Lanyon chosen as next NSW Police Force commissioner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/mal-lanyon-new-commissioner-of-nsw-police-force/105701914</link><description>Deputy Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon has been chosen to head up the NSW Police Force, replacing commissioner Karen Webb.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cd3192bee4641f04f5b65931d5fe5d6</guid></item><item><title>Offshore wind pioneer Henrik Stiesdal says Australia can learn from Europe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/offshore-wind-pioneer-henrik-stiesdal-lessons-for-australia/105783010</link><description>A Danish clean energy pioneer says Australia is poised for success with offshore wind, but there are lessons it can learn from abroad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e8e43f8da41b1a8bb53cc06569e333e</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou 'excited' to defend his Europa League trophy with Nottingham Forest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ange-postecoglou-nottingham-forest-europa-league/105809674</link><description>Four months after leading Tottenham Hotspur to Europa League triumph in Bilbao, Ange Postecoglou has returned to Spain and UEFA's second-tier club competition with a new challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d7d5db2308c2c5b39a10ccc3cdf7870</guid></item><item><title>Unexplained lights in the sky sparks UAP chatter across much of Western Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/unexplained-uap-sightings-reported-across-midwest-wa/105803264</link><description>Perth Observatory says it has received reports of lights dancing in the sky across a significant part of WA's Midwest and Goldfields, with an explanation yet to be found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b4cb4ae36f5ab9e984491b519fa7152</guid></item><item><title>Queensland speed skydiver Natisha Dingle shows off her impressive skills.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/speed-skydiver-natisha-dingle-shows-off-her-impressive-skills/105807064</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c809122700c1bf91a2b261a16e110608</guid></item><item><title>Artemis program on track to take astronauts around the Moon: NASA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nasa-artemis-program-on-track-to-take-people-to-the-moon/105809764</link><description>NASA's first crewed flight in its Artemis program — a trip around the Moon and back — is on track for launch in April 2026 and could potentially be moved up to February, the space agency says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87a63c967423b595bde610ff51e979b6</guid></item><item><title>Trump claims paracetamol link to autism. Five experts explain what's wrong with that statement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/what-the-experts-are-saying-about-paracetamol-use-lead-to-autism/105806230</link><description>Some leading Australian experts in medicine, autism research and obstetrics say the US president's claims are "a misreading of science," or at worst, "a misuse". Here's why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bffee58bd319bdb466db1eb8559f629b</guid></item><item><title>Why the legacy of the 2023 NRL grand final hangs over the Broncos and Panthers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/panthers-broncos-nrl-preliminary-final-grand-final-cleary/105809026</link><description>On Sunday, the Broncos and Panthers will face off in the finals for the first time since the 2023 grand final, but the memory of that night still hangs over both sides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad8624f8c74a64751af52bbcd1e11c56</guid></item><item><title>ABC ordered to pay $150,000 fine for unlawfully sacking journalist and presenter Antoinette Lattouf</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/antoinette-lattouf-costs-decision-in-abc-unlawful-termination/105810052</link><description>The judge ordered ABC to pay a fine of $150,000 for unlawfully sacking journalist and presenter Antoinette Lattouf for reasons including her political opinions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dad4cb7dec36a5f662b73fe15e33939</guid></item><item><title>SA childcare centre ordered to temporarily close after claims children were left unsupervised</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/sa-childcare-temporary-closure/105810184</link><description>A childcare centre in Adelaide's inner south-west has been ordered to close for two weeks after being handed an emergency action notice following claims children were left unsupervised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ced9254233f9890a9fb241090eae10e</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann seeks funding to pay for legal representation over raids at his home in 2024</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/bruce-lehrmann-seeks-funds-for-legal-representation-over-raids/105809920</link><description>Former Liberal staffer Bruce Lehrmann launches Federal Court action seeking funding for legal representation at a National Anti-Corruption Commission hearing after raids on his home in June last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">749a230c4ad7fe395ea22940c47b8259</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fullback Andrew Kellaway ruled out of first Bledisloe Cup Test match against All Blacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/wallabies-andrew-kellaway-ruled-out-bledisloe-cup-all-blacks/105810670</link><description>Wallabies fullback Andrew Kellaway will miss Saturday's Bledisloe Cup Test match against the All Blacks in Auckland, ruled out with a calf strain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11b979e7ef790b13cc2880a8a193f4dd</guid></item><item><title>Canberra golf course redevelopments providing both much-needed housing and financial lifelines for struggling clubs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/golf-course-redevelopments-providing-housing-financial-lifelines/105799100</link><description>With the ACT government pushing for greater urban density, golf courses in inner Canberra suburbs are becoming attractive sites for redevelopment to provide much-needed housing and a way for struggling clubs to bolster their budgets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b488a99ab4311911d8fa6f87e596dc4c</guid></item><item><title>Trump backs NATO powers to shoot down intruding Russian aircraft</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/trump-backs-nato-powers-to-shoot-down-intruding-russian-aircraft/105811080</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26fadd46aeef6d149deb13f7be4e3177</guid></item><item><title>Camp Mystic plans to reopen next summer, a year after floods killed 27</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/camp-mystic-plans-to-reopen-a-year-after-flood-deaths/105810114</link><description>Camp Mystic also announces plans for a memorial dedicated to "the lives of the campers and counsellors lost on July 4th".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">496ec39f957a1a61a68f959f6319b508</guid></item><item><title>Sculpture by the Sea could be cancelled due to $200,000 shortfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/sculptures-by-the-sea-facing-cancellation-funding-shortfall/105810510</link><description>Australia's famed sculpture walk is facing cancellation after failing to secure funding less than a month out from this year's event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ca69999aba4ff9483322749a16b717e</guid></item><item><title>Man behind iconic ABC TV programs, Graham White, dies aged 93</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/graham-white-abc-tv-and-radio-pioneer-dies-at-93/105806806</link><description>Graham White was a pioneer of Australian radio and television and played a key role in the creation of numerous television series, including A Big Country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54c9a84115c56f73f0923751c300a0e1</guid></item><item><title>Despite past controversy, NSW Police commissioner Mal Lanyon has a strong backing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nsw-police-commissioner-mal-lanyon-premier-chris-minns-analysis/105810774</link><description>For newly-announced Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon, Wednesday morning would have been both one of his proudest moments, and his most uncomfortable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed72f9bcc7ce20d2d722b8b43d539719</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel returns, addressing Charlie Kirk and 'un-American' axing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/jimmy-kimmel-returns-thanking-supporters-speaks-to-free-speech/105808410</link><description>Despite the late-night host's return, several US ABC affiliates did not air the episode, excluding an estimated one-quarter of American households.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac8b78a8e557c0d2a91d42ed04e2eed</guid></item><item><title>Family suspects foul play in Noosa man Byron Dumschat's death in a Bali villa pool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/family-suspects-foul-play-in-bali-death-noosa-man-byron-dumschat/105809846</link><description>An Australian family is asking why Indonesian police allowed three Australian witnesses to return home without being interviewed after their 23-year-old son died on the Indonesian holiday resort island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4e8e32abe23c1a44f62c5e3f023e2a2</guid></item><item><title>Rape case against Bruce Lehrmann delayed after lawyer misses deadline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/bruce-lehrmann-rape-case-faces-more-delays-in-toowoomba/105811608</link><description>A judge says the process of a bid to stop a criminal rape case against former Liberal Party staffer Bruce Lehrmann proceeding has been "problematic" after his lawyer missed a key deadline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20b38956daedd1cd16f45a4769958aa6</guid></item><item><title>How #RedundancyDiaries are busting the stigma of being let go</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/busting-the-stigma-on-redundancy-by-sharing-online/105751880</link><description>Camille says being made redundant was hard, so she began sharing her experiences on TikTok hoping to help others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69e9a0930ebbcb9805519c817968e9ee</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's changed stance on Ukraine could be a challenge for Vladimir Putin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/donald-trump-ukraine-nato-comments-a-challenge-to-vladimir-putin/105810170</link><description>If Donald Trump actually means what he has just said — that NATO countries have a right to shoot down any Russian jets in their airspace — the US president may be contracting out a serious counteroffensive against Russian aggression to NATO countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c624737442bcb04137b18db123e6997</guid></item><item><title>Report recommends gondola access to Jenolan Caves near the Blue Mountains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/report-recommends-gondola-access-to-jenolan-caves/105809918</link><description>A report recommends building a gondola to the tune of $44 million to bypass catastrophic road failures that have long plagued the Jenolan Caves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27aa154744525803a917b0b5069cde36</guid></item><item><title>Elon Musk's father, Errol Musk, accused of abusing five of his children over three decades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/errol-musk-elon-father-abuse-allegations/105810162</link><description>Multiple police reports, social workers and family members uncover the allegations against 79-year-old Errol Musk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b128f012c363aa69849c2a916828663b</guid></item><item><title>Mount Isa man charged with more than 70 child sex offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/mount-isa-man-charged-child-sex-offences/105811958</link><description>Police charge a 40-year-old man in Mount Isa and allege the offences occurred over 25 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f170f1084a78ce506347bb313d68dd8b</guid></item><item><title>Doctor who lost daughter to brain cancer receives grant in race to clinical trials</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/doctor-receives-grant-to-continue-brain-cancer-research/105810368</link><description>A professor who lost his daughter to brain cancer in 2018 is hopeful the research to find a cure in children is just five years away from clinical trials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc0272343034af8958b1ec9f51c4c20f</guid></item><item><title>Optus admits procedural failure before outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/optus-admits-procedural%C2%A0failure-before-outage%C2%A0/105811978</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b84c417046bbfc3acea16532e90a47cf</guid></item><item><title>Optus to pay $100m fine, as crisis engulfing Australia's second biggest telco continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/optus-fined-100-million-for-sales-misconduct/105810174</link><description>In enforcing the fine today, the Federal Court's Justice Patrick O'Sullivan described the company's conduct as "extremely serious" and "appalling".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5b8ef086dc95c25b9efd2536b1850d6</guid></item><item><title>Concerns Launceston City Council could give away Birchalls CBD site it bought for $8.8m</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/launceston-council-developer-plans-for-birchalls-building/105809796</link><description>Launceston City Council bought the historic Birchalls building for $8.8 million five years ago. A ratepayer association says it has learnt of a proposal to give it away "for nothing".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57bb6bb59e636d4105fd48c27dcdbaca</guid></item><item><title>Kindergarten cleaner who allegedly filmed children in bathroom faces more charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/kindergarten-cleaner-who-secretly-filmed-children-in-toilet/105811222</link><description>Prosecutors have flagged more potential charges for the Victorian kindergarten cleaner accused of secretly filming children in a bathroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a0e03375009bb4e55aea4b0a8b01d7e</guid></item><item><title>Missouri woman gets more than four years jail for trying to sell off Elvis' Graceland property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/missouri-woman-jailed-for-elvis-graceland-property-scam/105810930</link><description>A woman's attempt to sell off one of the most storied pieces of real estate in the US has come to naught. Here's how it happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87c9bf726b751fc3728cdd75266b9d0d</guid></item><item><title>Electric vehicle-to-grid trial in Exmouth generates promising results for state power distributor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/electric-vehicle-to-grid-v2g-trial-in-exmouth-promising/105811868</link><description>State distributor Horizon Power says a trial of bi-directional charging with electric vehicles to both supplement the grid and take up excess power, known as V2G, has proved a success.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c657879091e2ce95be5b33b932b29f12</guid></item><item><title>Christopher John Sullivan sentenced for stabbing partner Pauline Mountford in Gooseberry Hill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/christopher-john-sullivan-domestic-violence-sentencing/105812460</link><description>A 74-year-old man who slashed his partner's throat in their Perth Hills home is sentenced to 10 years in jail over the near-fatal attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b34ba7512fda4d4c878ff84234b915f6</guid></item><item><title>Former A-League footballers Clayton Lewis and Kearyn Baccus sentenced over betting scam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/a-league-betting-clayton-lewis-kearyn-baccus-sentencing/105811400</link><description>Both players were paid $10,000 each to intentionally get themselves yellow cards while playing for Macarthur FC against Sydney FC to influence overseas bets on the game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4d047a9369284c7941aaf5cccc0a654</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of Australians fighting 'cruel' battle for COVID vaccine injury compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/fight-for-compensation-for-covid-19-vaccination-injuries/105808630</link><description>Thousands of Australians who were injured by COVID vaccines say they are facing a 'cruel and complex' system to get compensation from the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc0182bdb4d37c0f24454edad8263808</guid></item><item><title>Productivity Commission to review state and territory GST deal, including $60b WA windfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/australia-gst-review-under-review-wa-gst-deal/105813372</link><description>Western Australia's GST deal, expected to cost the Commonwealth $60 billion by 2029, will form part of a review by the Australian Productivity Commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b22ae8ce5ff8afaa0d867d88f15dc4f0</guid></item><item><title>Former police officer Stephen Michael Calcutt pleads guilty to filming teenagers in shower and up skirt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/former-police-officer-pleads-guilty-filming-teenager/105812714</link><description>The former sergeant also filmed up another teenager's skirt and had a number of cartoons depicting children in sexual situations on a hard drive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d016f9d7ccabbb8651e7cb9fc607919e</guid></item><item><title>Murder trial hears final arguments from trio accused of 2022 stabbing death of David Jenkins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/trial-of-men-accused-of-david-jenkins-murder-final-arguments/105805736</link><description>The trial of two brothers and another man accused of the stabbing murder of a man in Tasmania's north in 2022 hears there is "no serious dispute" that Luke Shaw "was the person who killed" David Jenkins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">621a1d67e3bb519003eb4e577b718a6e</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105813848</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbeee129e3122b06287a24ba6aa752ed</guid></item><item><title>Senate inquiry examines federal environment department's SA algal bloom response</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/murray-watt-briefing-algal-bloom-july/105813252</link><description>Officials from the federal environment department say they were not aware of the impact of SA's algal bloom until the state government contacted them in May, two months after the bloom was first detected. Speaking at a senate inquiry, department officials say the federal environment minister was not formally briefed on the bloom until July.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47629bf3fc1342b70bb629add33dbfd9</guid></item><item><title>Alzheimer's drug Lecanemab approved by Therapeutic Goods Administration for use in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/alzheimers-drug-lecanemab-approved-by-tga/105813710</link><description>The Therapeutic Goods Administration approves the drug Lecanemab, which can slow down cognitive decline in the early stages of Alzheimer's.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4467a4bcfcdb0b2847fe165e1550be39</guid></item><item><title>Italy sends navy frigate to assist Global Sumud Flotilla after vessels targeted by drones off Greece</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/global-sumud-flotilla-says-vessels-targeted-by-drones/105812860</link><description>The flotilla carrying aid and pro-Palestinian activists said they heard explosions and saw multiple drones that targeted some of their boats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b77e1392b4829d64f6d75add8a54c81</guid></item><item><title>Gaza aid flotilla targeted by drone explosion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/gaza-aid-flotilla-targeted-by-drone-explosion%C2%A0/105813242</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0a5e80c988063752bd5ac9a46ef8695</guid></item><item><title>One dead in 'targeted' shooting at Dallas immigration centre, DHS says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/multiple-dead-at-dallas-ice-shooting/105814138</link><description>Police were first alerted to the incident at 6:40am on Wednesday, local time, and later found the shooter on a nearby roof dead from an apparent self-inflicted gunshot wound.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41372aed6a1e8513347f563b066ef004</guid></item><item><title>Kimmel monologue racks up millions of views on social media as Joe Rogan slams government 'dictating'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/kimmel-video-and-rogan-lashing-viral/105814274</link><description>Kimmel's program was indefinitely suspended last week after he made comments about the late conservative commentator Charlie Kirk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">125445d0de8a02f7060a350896e799ff</guid></item><item><title>Australia's social media ban wins praise from Europe at UN event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/united-nations-general-assembly-social-media-ban/105814246</link><description>Australia's willingness to take on the social media giants is drawing significant international interest, winning the support of the European Commission president at a forum in New York.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13cbd1fcaa9fc632384fa2b086577151</guid></item><item><title>Australia in a 'dangerous place' as AI adoption ramps up, prompting calls to protect jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/australia-in-dangerous-place-as-ai-adoption-ramps-up/105807430</link><description>Artificial intelligence is coming for our jobs — but will it take them away, or just give us a powerful new assistant?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48e1ecb4ff4fc7a8cb46b98272af471f</guid></item><item><title>Will food prices ever come down? Don't bet on it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/will-food-grocery-prices-ever-come-down/105811296</link><description>While recent cuts to interest rates may have given mortgage holders a bit of a financial breathing space, the cost of food continues to creep upwards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fce87e998f0daf4d07d83c36c6038f70</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy blames Putin for 'most destructive arms race in human history'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/zelenskyy-blames-putin-for-most-destructive-arms-race/105814378</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7700655ee2a3abe520a419b677e6593f</guid></item><item><title>Free speech pathologist sessions turning poor literacy rates around in Logan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/qld-logan-children-literacy-boost-free-speech-pathologist/105809794</link><description>A federal government backed weekly reading session led by experts is helping improve literacy rates in Queensland children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6f3a9ca2aa561db64986a266e4fcdcd</guid></item><item><title>Independent review launched into fire ant eradication program amid 'closing window of opportunity'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/fire-ant-eradication-program-review-launched/105811790</link><description>Authorities launch an independent review of Australia's national fire ant eradication program to evaluate the country's fight against one of the world’s most destructive pests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c444298e462f9192611f3572f0c28de3</guid></item><item><title>Families demand inquiry into NSW Police handling of missing persons cases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/families-of-missing-persons-call-for-probe-into-police/105693338</link><description>Nikii Smith is one of 10,000 people who signed a petition calling for a NSW inquiry into the handling of missing persons cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86bd1e4db1094cebb0f4277ff0ad4c3b</guid></item><item><title>China retains narrow edge over US as South-East Asia's most influential partner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/china-us-influence-south-east-asia/105812866</link><description>New research shows that China retains a very narrow edge over the United States as South-East Asia's most influential partner, with experts predicting it will soon pull further ahead as the Trump administration's policies begin to bite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7b10409c8753c731ed70c5ed5ed7bea</guid></item><item><title>Solar, batteries and the 'phone charger dilemma': How a standards gap threatens clean tech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/smart-tech-benefits-at-risk-over-lack-of-common-standard/105808798</link><description>In the same way Apple and Samsung used different phone chargers, many clean tech products are not compatible with others. Experts say it is a big problem for the energy transition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84ec00dd3b63db045677af76a0c64880</guid></item><item><title>Family calls for change amid frustration at seven-year coronial inquest wait</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/anger-at-seven-year-coronial-inquest-wait/105805234</link><description>Robert Hall was killed when he was struck by partially blind driver John Charles Robertson on the Horrocks Highway in 2018. It has been a long wait for the family ahead of the release of coronial findings into his death next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dedbef63ba8aa61b8045e0d358939858</guid></item><item><title>Rodeo attendees told to practise safe sex as STIs continue to rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sti-cases-continue-to-rise-indigenous-overrepresented-in-data/105809704</link><description>Health providers in outback Queensland are taking a light-hearted approach to promoting safe sex, as new data shows sexually transmitted infections are on the rise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a991448f6d24b7d59719d012fdc3e584</guid></item><item><title>Victim-survivors left to self-represent in Family Court of Australia proceedings due to legal fees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/parents-self-representing-in-family-court-due-to-high-legal-fees/105767468</link><description>Jacinta says she is part of a "big wave" of litigants self-representing in Family Court of Australia proceedings after facing extraordinary fees from family law firms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5a4fec0b01dc945b1744b6c215769aa</guid></item><item><title>Elevated E. coli levels recorded at major NT crocodile farm owned by luxury label Hermès</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/lambells-lagoon-crocodile-farm-nt-high-e-coli-levels-in-water/105806340</link><description>One of Australia's largest crocodile farms, owned by a subsidiary of luxury label Hermès, is consistently irrigating with water containing E. coli concentrations almost 500 times the national guidelines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcebaaf92f52cb686dddde475db8c67b</guid></item><item><title>Police launch fresh search of WA outback over Ray and Jennie Kehlet cold case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/wa-police-search-sandstone-kehlet-cold-case/105813086</link><description>Detectives are this week revisiting the site in WA's outback where the body of prospector Ray Kehlet was found. His wife Jennie is still missing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eda36c180ee83ef793f5a6e386ed8ef6</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous teen speaks out against heckling of Welcome to Country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/indigenous-writes-essay-against-heckling-welcome-to-country/105808140</link><description>An Indigenous high school student's essay on the Anzac Day heckling of an Indigenous elder by far-right supremacists has earned her a nationally recognised award.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d0978c16ddeb79e39b966dd2e565459</guid></item><item><title>Magnitude-4.1 earthquake rattles Tasmania from Maydena to Hobart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/tasmania-rattled-with-magnitude-4-1-earthquake/105814558</link><description>Tasmania records a magnitude-4.1 earthquake in the state's south-west that was felt from Maydena to Hobart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84775edf57cd76c9bc0ca385f3b919d5</guid></item><item><title>'On guard' for share market correction, Optus debacle began in India — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/105814572</link><description>Optus has now told the ABC the firewall upgrade that led to disrupted triple-0 calls was initiated in Chennai, India. Meanwhile veteran stockbroker Marcus Padley says he's "on guard" for a share market wipe-out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d14279b842237d15d950214fbd7b970</guid></item><item><title>Who is Samoa's new prime minister, Laaulialemalietoa Polataivao Fosi Schmidt?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/new-samoa-prime-minister-election/105789496</link><description>Supporters are fervent in their enthusiasm for Samoa's new prime minister, but voters who are more sceptical of Laaulialemalietoa Polataivao Fosi Schmidt, question his motives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">625c6497fc8280a6929fa5f29c6e97f3</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of new dust-related lung disease cases recorded in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/new-cases-deadly-lung-disease-recorded-in-queensland/105800886</link><description>Nearly 300 workers from mines and work sites have had cases of lung cancer, black lung and other illnesses recorded by the state's dust disease register in the space of 12 months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2884483a655c30376f0362816224a66</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy warns UN of 'the most destructive arms race in human history'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/united-nations-general-assembly-volodymyr-zelenskyy-speech/105814462</link><description>Ukraine's president calls for global action to regulate the twin threats posed by drone technology and artificial intelligence, warning "no-one can feel safe" from Russia's expansionist goals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5f96320cb70d90485b91a1058586e74</guid></item><item><title>Macquarie to repay Shield investors after super platform failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/macquarie-admits-to-shield-contraventions/105814728</link><description>Macquarie commits to repaying thousands of Australians who invested hundreds of millions of their retirement savings in the collapsed Shield Master Fund amid admissions it contravened the Corporations Act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6ef3dcad386254cfbd1a1063f29bbf1</guid></item><item><title>China's President Xi Jinping announces new climate goal to cut emissions by 2035</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/china-plans-carbon-emissions-cut-by-2035/105814492</link><description>Outlining China's new carbon targets in a video link to the UN climate conference in New York, President Xi Jinping says "green and low carbon transition is the trend of our time".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f28b3d1c00395f4695e9369d6c444f2</guid></item><item><title>Katanning drivers fear the worst as untagged livestock roam roads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/katanning-farmers-fed-up-with-livestock-wandering-rural-roads/105753144</link><description>A Katanning school bus driver and local farmers are calling for urgent action to address a growing danger posed by wandering livestock on rural roads.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13a15cf930e91758bba06110e305613a</guid></item><item><title>Nottingham Forest draws 2-2 with Real Betis in opening UEFA Europa League match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nottingham-forest-draws-with-real-betis-europa-league/105814730</link><description>Nottingham Forest's long-awaited return to European competition ends 2-2 at Real Betis, with Igor Jesus's first-half double cancelling out by a late Antony strike.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7da92da66bbef30024c541232032313</guid></item><item><title>Peter Tonagh to replace Catherine West as Nine's chair</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/peter-tonagh-to-become-chair-of-nine/105814974</link><description>He replaces Catherine West, who spent 18 months in the position.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2a5f2c444b61e900f222e4b49c5f0b5</guid></item><item><title>Dramatic footage shows sinkhole swallowing up road in central Bangkok</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sinkhole-swallows-road-in-central-bangkok/105814850</link><description>Social media footage shows powerlines being pulled down into the 50-metre deep hole and vehicles teetering on the edge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">341b949dae61cd2058ac47c271016c61</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with multiple offences over pursuit, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/vale-park-man-arrested-over-alleged-dv-incident/105815044</link><description>South Australia Police says a Vale Park man has been charged following a pursuit that led STAR group officers and police negotiators to a unit in Adelaide's western suburbs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55d31264009557887152139ca68f0250</guid></item><item><title>Liberal candidate Gisele Kapterian abandons court challenge for Sydney seat of Bradfield</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/liberal-gisele-kapterian-abandons-bradfield-court-challenge/105815662</link><description>Gisele Kapterian abandons her court action challenging the election result in the federal Sydney seat of Bradfield.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72e919021e6b203c2c61364023ef65cb</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese addresses UN on climate goals, Gaza and Australia's security council bid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/albanese-united-nations-general-assembly-speech/105815200</link><description>The prime minister uses his UN speech to talk up Australia's emissions plan after Donald Trump called climate change a "con job", and confirms Australia is still seeking a temporary seat on the body's security council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a232f435066d64bce12998bbb55c68d5</guid></item><item><title>Nicho Hynes shrugs off personal barbs ahead of NRL preliminary final between Melbourne and Cronulla</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nicho-hynes-cronulla-sharks-nrl-preliminary-final/105815774</link><description>Accused by some of being too nice and not nice enough by others, polarising Cronulla star Nicho Hynes "doesn't give a rats" about criticism that comes his way anymore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab3262fd8438997bf3566bc3f3afd340</guid></item><item><title>New head of Queensland's troubled DNA lab says backlog of testing could take years to clear</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/queensland-dna-lab-forensic-lab-mick-fuller-investigation/105815548</link><description>More than 170 rape kits caught up in the Forensic Science Queensland laboratory's backlog will be sent offshore next week for vital forensic testing, as the facility's new boss says it will take years to clear them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f10104713dca5809a4ee3120e1d5a35</guid></item><item><title>Seasonal farm worker from Samoa pleads guilty to rape on Arrawarra beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/arrawarra-rape-farm-worker-pleads-guilty/105800896</link><description>The 27-year-old worker from Samoa changed his plea after hearing the victim give evidence at trial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5297df5ebdb4d1df00f40eba4157b444</guid></item><item><title>Postal voting issues identified ahead of 2025 WA local government elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/postal-voting-problems-for-2025-local-government-election/105815250</link><description>Incorrect ballot papers are among several problems identified with postal voting packages sent out ahead next month's local government elections in WA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4995a33060a008be1386f30e6e5a7afe</guid></item><item><title>Scott Selwood takes break from AFL after 'personally challenging year'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/scott-selwood-steps-away-afl-collingwood/105815996</link><description>Scott Selwood will take time away from football, stepping down as an assistant coach with Collingwood, following a year marked by personal tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41d251b3ccf71ca56edd70b60deeeab9</guid></item><item><title>AI image recognition technology used to detect traffic offences raises privacy concerns, Queensland audit finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/ai-image-technology-phone-speeding-offences-privacy-audit-qld/105815134</link><description>Queensland's transport department uses AI in its cameras to detect mobile and seatbelt offences, but a new audit has ordered called for a review into how that's done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11d46c909160642ceb7265e8809e201c</guid></item><item><title>What are Australia's chances of returning to the UN Security Council?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/australia-renews-un-security-council-bid/105816596</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese makes a fresh push for Australia to get a seat on the United Nations Security Council in 2029-30.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12bbee71870039ed7798c50667d1fea5</guid></item><item><title>Snoop Dogg says AFL grand final is 'a way of life' ahead of headline show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/snoop-dogg-afl-grand-final/105816718</link><description>Snoop Dogg has strutted into the MCG for his official appearance ahead of a fascinating, somewhat controversial, AFL grand-final entertainment set.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b66d08f7f421a2cabf591d770048f0f</guid></item><item><title>Denmark PM apologises to indigenous Greenlanders who faced forced contraception</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/denmark-pm-apologises-to-greenland-over-contraception/105816090</link><description>The apology by Mette Frederiksen in Greenland’s capital, Nuuk, hopes to close a traumatic chapter in Greenland's history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10e2f68d02a379a76e33cb0667531d03</guid></item><item><title>Forestry industry says it can meet demand for biofuels as climate targets near</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/forestry-wood-waste-into-biofuel-ships-planes-climate-targets/105806578</link><description>With biofuels earmarked as a way to power the transport sector in the future, one industry says its waste can be converted into aviation and shipping fuel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c43fb3bd94bcaa6f5b6b2cc07bb8ea3a</guid></item><item><title>Violent man abandons appeal to avoid jail for assaulting teenage ex-girlfriend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/appeal-fails-for-man-who-assaulted-teenage-ex-partner/105816094</link><description>A 19-year-old Victorian man, who recorded 67 prior convictions for stalking and breaching family violence orders against his young ex-girlfriend, has failed in a bid to stay out of jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20150ffcc414f4230c66ae54c5be6f85</guid></item><item><title>Perth grandmother Donna Nelson loses appeal over Japan drug smuggling conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/donna-nelson-loses-japan-drug-smuggling-appeal/105804346</link><description>Convicted drug smuggler and Perth grandmother, Donna Nelson, loses her appeal against her conviction for smuggling two kilograms of methamphetamine into Tokyo Airport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47b528f98203d1300e8e1b40978bdddc</guid></item><item><title>Trio of space weather satellites launched to study the Sun's violent side</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nasa-launch-three-spacecraft-sun/105815108</link><description>NASA successfully launches multiple satellites designed to get a better understanding of the Sun's influence on Earth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59a16bd185eeee6f5d85c73a75953dbf</guid></item><item><title>TGA approves new brain stimulation device for treatment of depression</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/brain-stimulator-device-approved-for-treatment-of-depression/105816064</link><description>Some international users of Flow Neuroscience's device have labelled the wearable tech as a game-changer in treating depression, but not everyone is convinced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d613860a63e9e5d904cc9b6ac0bd749</guid></item><item><title>Key takeaways from day two at the UN General Assembly's world leaders week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/united-nations-general-assembly-day-two-takeaways/105814272</link><description>The world's most powerful people are meeting in New York this week. Here are the key takeaways from the UN summit's second day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddb580a737f4f04170f65ae765ac9dd6</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies vs All Blacks Bledisloe Cup: Team lists, what time is kick-off? How can I watch?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/wallabies-vs-all-blacks-bledisloe-cup-team-lists/105814670</link><description>Wallabies prop James Slipper will notch an important milestone against New Zealand on Saturday, while James O'Connor will start at fly half.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03e6a514a7b10816017fc77c6d1b0aaa</guid></item><item><title>South Australia passes laws to protect victims of personal injury from 'claim farmers'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sa-claim-farming-laws-pass-parlia/105816232</link><description>Individuals who contact a survivor of abuse or personal injury without their permission to encourage them to make a claim for compensation could face fines of up to $50,000 under new laws which have passed in South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70085da5c5bdc719bc2ab735b7ccda09</guid></item><item><title>Hastie lets loose, one-on-one with Albanese and Trump, and the politics of Palestinian recognition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/hastie-ley-trump-un-palestine-cop-turkiye-bradfield-byelection/105814488</link><description>It turns out that Prime Minister Anthony Albanese didn't need a can of Diet Coke and a cheeseburger to attracted the US president's attention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93642a3e3240ad1fdff7cfac3d949f64</guid></item><item><title>Celebrity crocodile wrangler Matt Wright set to appeal guilty verdict on five grounds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/matt-wright-set-to-appeal-guilty-verdict-on-five-grounds/105816918</link><description>Matt Wright’s lawyers have confirmed they will file a notice of appeal within the next 48 hours, indicating it will be based on five different grounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">235091d5d14d90d64ed46d67022a1cf6</guid></item><item><title>Ahead of the biggest game of his NRL career, Nicho Hynes returns to where it all began</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/storm-sharks-nicho-hynes-nrl-preliminary-finals/105816184</link><description>Ten years to the day since his first moment in the spotlight, Nicho Hynes returns to AAMI Park for the most important game of his NRL career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ba9e5f21df0896a8a84e51f1a77817b</guid></item><item><title>SA government grapples with whether it should issue daily bloom updates during summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/algal-bloom-persists-on-adelaide-metropolitan-beaches/105815614</link><description>South Australia's Premier says the government is grappling with whether it should give daily updates on the bloom's location during summer, and says it has been "actively engaged" in conversations with the federal government since its emergence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58acb5d5694220c60122ae3f346438b9</guid></item><item><title>Queensland police to receive 8 per cent pay rise over three years after accepting pay offer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/queensland-police-accept-8-per-cent-pay-rise-gov-offer/105817830</link><description>Queensland police officers will receive a wage increase, retention incentive and new allowances after accepting a pay deal from the state government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">888203bc80b607c4a59716509329c554</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters race to set hazard reduction burns across Greater Sydney ahead of fire season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/firefighters-race-to-set-hazard-reduction-burns-across-sydney/105801784</link><description>Sydney's wettest August on record has dampened efforts by fire authorities to meet hazard reduction burn targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c594b646d35e85e315447033ddb7a1b</guid></item><item><title>Liberal veteran Amanda Vanstone chides Andrew Hastie for not being a team player, warns of runaway ego</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/andrew-hastie-warned-of-division-amanda-vanstone/105817288</link><description>A doyenne of the Liberal Party and veteran of leadership battles dating back to the 1980s Howard–Peacock era has chided Andrew Hastie for not being a team player.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7155a17bde099fcac4270569e823ea49</guid></item><item><title>Matildas strike force could benefit from having both Sam Kerr and Michelle Heyman firing fit up front</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/matildas-could-have-sam-kerr-and-michelle-heyman/105817900</link><description>A fit-again Sam Kerr doesn't necessarily spell the end for Michelle Heyman's time in the Matildas, if anything the A-League star can't wait for her return.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c878d14058b221a67d55c4c8bdc80e94</guid></item><item><title>SA Water fined $60k for causing 'environmental harm' during botched maintenance of Warren Reservoir</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sa-water-fined-after-botched-maintenace-warren-reservoir/105817688</link><description>SA Water — which is owned by the SA government — has been fined for polluting the waterways with grey clay silt when draining the Warren Reservoir, in the Barossa Valley, in May 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fba0457dd1912373941155d18bca081c</guid></item><item><title>Lachie Neale and Rhys Stanley named in AFL grand final teams as Jarrod Berry fails to recover from shoulder injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/afl-grand-final-geelong-brisbane-lions-team-selections-live-blog/105812378</link><description>Brisbane's co-captain returns just weeks after doctors gave him as little as a five per cent chance of featuring in his third straight grand final as Geelong welcomes back a familiar face to take the place of Tom Stewart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd6e232727e7d0a979b313cd8bef11d5</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide 36ers terminate Montrezl Harrell's contract amid China doping case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/montrezl-harrell-dropped-by-36ers-while-doping-ban-continues/105817866</link><description>The Adelaide 36ers terminate Montrezl Harrell's contract while he serves a provisional ban after testing positive for an illicit substance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51284986b60e643af30239de40743cff</guid></item><item><title>Measles case detected in Brisbane, prompting calls for vaccination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/measles-brisbane-qld-health-alert-disease-infection/105817886</link><description>Queensland's health department says the person was believed to have contracted the virus in Bali, before visiting a number of businesses across Brisbane and the Sunshine Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69d52cc929c6deec63f591815c89b60a</guid></item><item><title>Lawyers for Raiders star Josh Papalii ask court to discontinue charges over police group chat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/raiders-josh-papalii-lawyers-ask-court-for-stay-on-charges/105817698</link><description>The Raiders star's lawyers are asking the ACT Magistrates Court to discontinue charges against him over a 2024 incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33a2e67d4e0df98eac893b5dbf74eab0</guid></item><item><title>Horse trainer Dwayne Schmidt jailed for raping and impregnating 13yo girl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/horse-trainer-raped-and-impregnated-13-year-old-girl/105813440</link><description>New South Wales horse trainer Dwayne Schmidt is sentenced to more than three years in jail for raping and impregnating a 13-year-old girl.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cff6a74bc32102a2a7bdba358773bf49</guid></item><item><title>Gympie Regional Council votes to remove fluoride from town's water supply</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/gympie-removes-fluoride-water-supply-dental-health-fears/105814678</link><description>Gympie scraps fluoride from its water supply and becomes the third region in Queensland to reject the practice in just over a year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9960f09af437f02819e5359d8481878</guid></item><item><title>Coroner finds Monash Health provided unreasonable care before toddler Dio Kemp's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/coroner-finding-into-death-of-dio-kemp/105816186</link><description>Three-year-old Dio Kemp was taken to Monash Medical Centre four times over 10 days before she died of sepsis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37b865829bea191edfe0af886035c9e4</guid></item><item><title>Mass puffer fish deaths and red-bell jellyfish bloom put Pilbara coast on alert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/pilbara-coast-alert-jellyfish-bloom-toxic-puffer-fish-deaths/105815554</link><description>Hundreds of dead puffer fish are found on a Pilbara beach, as an epic red-bell jellyfish bloom prompts a warning from the region's ports authority.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39c787a5232b58cd251e6bebea3ae077</guid></item><item><title>Arts industry leaders call for tax reforms to help struggling sector</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sydney-arts-leaders-calling-for-tax-reform-to-the-sector/105816210</link><description>Arts industry leaders say creative tax form is needed to create greater opportunities for Australian artists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7181bdf23c74d11e765b61f89bc136e</guid></item><item><title>All the latest finance news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/all-the-latest-finance-news/105818574</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">024e11ae51d50a5a396284951c067a9d</guid></item><item><title>How old is too old to drive?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/how-old-is-too-old-to-drive/105818680</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed19a19fa1a549efe63a7f6c0a28666a</guid></item><item><title>AFL Final – The Cats, the Lions and Snoop Dogg</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/afl-final-%E2%80%93-the-cats,-the-lions-and-snoop-dogg/105818686</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">982a50cfa771e5d95dd460664f679bdc</guid></item><item><title>Denmark's defence minister says 'professional actor' behind drone flights over airports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/denmark-defence-minister-says-professional-actor-behind-drones/105818578</link><description>The drone flights occurred over several airports across the country throughout the week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20f1e4ac4ecc78b08f38c32ffe5fa970</guid></item><item><title>Former French president Nicolas Sarkozy found guilty of criminal conspiracy in case linked to Muammar Gaddafi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nicolar-sarkozy-found-guilty-of-criminal-conspiracy-libya-trial/105818560</link><description>Nicolas Sarkozy is found guilty of obtaining millions of euros in illegal financing from late Libyan dictator Muammar Gaddafi for his successful 2007 presidential bid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96ff22933c8a0523f09fb4365a1711db</guid></item><item><title>Jerry Robertson found guilty of murdering partner with sledgehammer in Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/jerry-robertson-found-guilty-of-dv-murder-of-woman-alice-springs/105806492</link><description>An NT Supreme Court jury finds an Alice Springs man guilty of murdering his female partner in July 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">693256933f0d4ab5bb1c7eda5803141d</guid></item><item><title>Top stories from ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/top-stories-from-abc-news/105818778</link><description>Listen to ABC News interviews and commentary and analysis from radio programs like AM, PM and The World Today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4caafa592440ba60dc185e7f3d51922b</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy says he will step down as president after Ukraine war ends</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/zelenskyy-to-leave-office-after-war/105818790</link><description>Ukraine's president has been in office since 2019, with elections slated for last year suspended by martial law as a result of Russia's ongoing invasion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">473d9a464ce1fda89fe9d2c223665ebf</guid></item><item><title>Sean 'Diddy' Combs seeks to appeal to prostitution conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/sean-combs-returns-to-court/105819070</link><description>The former hip-hop mogul was found guilty by a jury on prostitution charges but cleared him of the more serious counts of sex trafficking and racketeering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">939980e64084cf527632d2ce32f228d4</guid></item><item><title>Amazon fined $3.8b for misleading American Prime subscribers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/amazon-fined-over-prime-subscriptions/105819274</link><description>Around 35 million US Prime customers, equivalent to one in 10 American citizens, will be eligible for a payout.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e66d7952eebe4a7ab86c99093620d2f</guid></item><item><title>Out-of-pocket costs, eroding trust contributing to decline in childhood vaccination rates, new report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/research-urges-action-on-declining-childhood-vaccination-rates/105815232</link><description>A new report finds out-of-pocket costs and eroding trust are contributing to a "concerning" decline in childhood vaccination rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfdd1a56127bc667f2e5ffab313e2712</guid></item><item><title>China's 'soft' 2035 climate target frustrates experts amid rapid renewable growth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/chinas-new-climate-target-is-both-historic-and-inadequate/105814784</link><description>China baffles climate experts by setting the bar low with its 2035 emissions reduction target amid speculation the renewables superpower will most likely exceed its ambitions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9faa430fbc4d58914719cd9df045ca3</guid></item><item><title>GIM Trading used virtual office space to create veneer of legitimacy as it allegedly defrauded millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/gim-trading-bond-fraud-allegations-investigation/105782912</link><description>GIM Trading has been accused of defrauding Aussie investors out of millions of dollars. Financial investigators say the company created a veneer of legitimacy and evidence suggested overseas criminals could be involved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6cac9ce30ae5a47bbfc9f7617e7dc39</guid></item><item><title>China aid and investment returns to Solomon Islands's Malaita province after ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/china-aid-solomon-islands-malaita-road-development/105789780</link><description>The Solomon Islands's province of Malaita made global headlines five years ago when it banned Chinese investment. But today, a new China-funded road project is on the way — and the people are all for it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aef86fbb6ca57b72f9ef6089dc9580e9</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: A viral Donald Trump moment, a retracted study and daylight saving time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/abc-weekly-news-quiz-friday/105815222</link><description>It's that time of the week again. Test your news knowledge to see how much you remember for the week that was.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df7a412c56b638cb983f8287e8d386ed</guid></item><item><title>Imported potatoes threaten Tasmanian growers, as companies look for cost savings overseas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/imported-potatoes-price-cuts-threaten-australian-potato-industry/105815458</link><description>Cheap potato imports from India and China are threatening the livelihoods of Tasmanian growers, as stalled negotiations with potato giant Simplot leave some farmers about to plant this year's crop without a contract.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddc6d456a4e47433bae32855e5b52bae</guid></item><item><title>2025 AFL season quiz: Twenty questions before the AFL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/afl-2025-season-quiz/105806256</link><description>There are just four quarters of footy left in the 2025 men's AFL season, so now is as good a time as any to see how much you remember about the year just gone with our quiz.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63ca7ae077d47b2b6fd2fe7c3941c026</guid></item><item><title>Police search for alleged Porepunkah gunman Dezi Freeman hits one-month mark</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/porepunkah-gunman-dezi-freeman-shooting-latest/105806284</link><description>A month into the high country search for alleged Porepunkah gunman Dezi Freeman, a former detective says Victoria Police can not realistically expect to continue the manhunt indefinitely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">232d07227b15324a710ddc69e78d015c</guid></item><item><title>AFL popularity growth fuels calls to move the Barassi Line separating codes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/barassi-line-rugby-league-aussie-rules-tathra/105782938</link><description>Initially laughed off, these pioneers from Victoria were determined to challenge Australia's sporting status quo, and their legacy continues today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">853354932de7c66115ea465660b6ef08</guid></item><item><title>Tania's parents took her to Russia, where she says they were 'brainwashed'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/inside-the-plight-of-ukrainian-children-taken-to-russia/105755812</link><description>Years of fighting have created a crisis among Ukrainian children, with thousands estimated to have been transferred to Russia, where some are placed in so-called "re-education camps".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">245e3af23de60d9db7e7068eb195ba3a</guid></item><item><title>Southern rock lobster prices finally bounce back amid demand from China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/aussie-rock-lobster-prices-strong-china-demand-sa/105815982</link><description>After years of export trade disruptions, southern Australian rock lobster commercial fishers are hauling in catches that will fetch up to $125 per kilogram.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4f3eb64091cd22b844cb02f1d763fbf</guid></item><item><title>Teacher and librarian facing animal cruelty charges lose fight against ban from working with children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/teacher-librarian-animal-cruelty-charges-banned-working-children/105789956</link><description>A teacher and a librarian banned from working with children after they were charged with ill-treating animals have lost a bid to have the ban rescinded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8517cf735135a7e3b04f84d4d11924dd</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: Albanese–Trump meeting not linked to AUKUS review: Marles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/federal-politics-live-blog-september-26/105819440</link><description>Anthony Albanese's planned meeting with the US president has "absolutely" no link to the expected finalisation of the Trump administration's review into the AUKUS security pact, Richard Marles says. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c8cce790d919b71b1ce3d3a34da8678</guid></item><item><title>Dallas authorities give update on shooting at ICE facility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/dallas-authorities-give-update-on-shooting-at-ice-facility/105819488</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2901193f49033d6a091ea292a7d1a67a</guid></item><item><title>Trump says 'radical left' is fuelling violence against ICE</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/trump-says-radical-left-is-fuelling-violence-against-ice/105819382</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f964ce9b32a074aa606d4783afe19919</guid></item><item><title>FBI finds notes by ICE shooter saying he wanted to target agents, not detainees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/ice-shooter-wanted-to-target-agents-not-detainees-fbi-says/105819378</link><description>The FBI has searched the home of the man who opened fired on an Immigration and Customs Enforcement facility in Texas, finding notes that say he was acting alone and intended to target agents, not detainees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3796b636d369ed92c9beb50a3697283</guid></item><item><title>Illawarra groups want Port Kembla ruled out for AUKUS nuclear submarine base</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/port-kembla-declaration-against-aukus-nuclear-submarine-base/105815986</link><description>The federal government says it will not make a decision on the location of the nuclear submarine base until later this decade, but Illawarra institutions — from unions to churches — are sending a strong message now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9576ab16c1d1be2862cfa1862bc87c3</guid></item><item><title>Live updates: CSL falls on Trump's 100pc tariffs on pharmaceuticals from October while ASX edges lower</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/asx-markets-business-live-news-26-sept-2025/105819610</link><description>US President Donald Trump has announced 100 per cent tariffs on pharmaceutical imports from October. Meanwhile, the ASX has nudged lower at the open with CSL falling by three per cent. Follow the day's events and insights as they happen with our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4be65eb1cbcd8e56b4e7411bef244b6b</guid></item><item><title>Robert Carlyle on the hacking scandal that brought down a Murdoch paper</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/uk-phone-hacking-scandal-robert-carlyle-the-hack/105810728</link><description>Robert Carlyle plays an integral role in The Hack, co-starring David Tennant, which digs deep into the News of the World phone-hacking scandal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a90e196287202fbd21af9cda9ac6774</guid></item><item><title>Bondi's Sculpture by the Sea offered $200,000 lifeline after financial woes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/bondi-sculpture-by-the-sea-to-go-ahead-2025-due-to-lifeline/105819510</link><description>Sculpture by the Sea was facing cancellation with organisers forced to make an urgent public plea for last-minute funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6b9cfa8185df988b1552b57c5404e42</guid></item><item><title>WA government accused of treating Port Hedland's water supply like 'lolly shop'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/port-hedland-residents-lash-water-corporation-bungle/105812946</link><description>An Indigenous elder says the rapid depletion of Port Hedland's groundwater stores has been evident for decades, but the government has prioritised mining interests over people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dba911c331c3d40c04227fbc691550d3</guid></item><item><title>'I am innocent,' says former FBI director James Comey after being indicted on two counts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/james-comey-former-fbi-director-indicted-swears-innocent/105814672</link><description>He was indicted on one count of making false statements and one count of obstruction of justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beacc8c1c93306cafeca910785eac6ab</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong and southern China reopen after powerful Typhoon Ragasa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/hong-kong-southern-china-reopens-after-typhoon-ragasa/105819590</link><description>Hong Kong and cities in China's Guangdong province have reopened businesses and schools after the world's most powerful tropical cyclone this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10090b8e1d20790341deb6dcd5bc8e3f</guid></item><item><title>Encouraging more people to learn Auslan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/encouraging-more-people-to-learn-auslan/105810314</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bd39155d4da292943a88d682b3725ed</guid></item><item><title>Connecting with Auslan in Deaf spaces</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/connecting-with-auslan-in-deaf-spaces/105819592</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5afd6fe02a51b32b6b422a80735a79cb</guid></item><item><title>International Week of Deaf People marked in unique Deaf spaces where Auslan is celebrated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/international-week-of-deaf-people-celebrated-unique-deaf-spaces/105808090</link><description>Access to language is essential for the Deaf community, but it isn't always guaranteed — especially in isolated parts of Australia. Locals are advocating for more awareness and support this International Week of Deaf People.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3fefeef0383cd4f8e36b91ad97fcd06</guid></item><item><title>Security council bid 'important': Richard Marles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/security-council-bid-important:-richard-marles/105819886</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fc60daab26e4800af55b4b15d077d08</guid></item><item><title>Hiker with motor neurone disease takes on WA's 1,000km Bibbulmun Track</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/mullumbimby-motor-neurone-disease-hiker-walks-bibbulmun-track-wa/105810642</link><description>One week into her 1,000-kilometre trek of WA's Bibbulmun Track, 70-year-old Catherine Perversi says "the stillness is sublime" — and she would not be anywhere else.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">562a1176a7305ccb5b4ebc35f0433aaa</guid></item><item><title>Barassi line divide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/barassi-line-divide/105819476</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0fefd96a6df7559e212c7c8d875ab3d</guid></item><item><title>Trump has signed an executive order on TikTok. What does that mean?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/donald-trump-signs-tiktok-executive-order-what-does-that-mean/105819550</link><description>Donald Trump has signed an executive order that he says will allay security concerns regarding Chinese influence on social media platform TikTok.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56898e42bde26b739d92f79a2ebd6d02</guid></item><item><title>Foster carer shortage in WA's Kimberley forces children away from country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/foster-carer-shortage-in-kimberley-forcing-kids-off-country/105815878</link><description>A shortage of foster carers in regional WA is pushing vulnerable children, especially First Nations kids, thousands of kilometres from their families, culture and country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ce81c66ef721335c43f5ba3654f32c4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump imposes 100 per cent tariffs on branded pharmaceuticals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/trump-100pc-tariff-on-drugs-us-politics-/105820198</link><description>The United States will impose a 100 per cent tariff on imports of branded or patented pharmaceutical products from October 1, unless a pharmaceutical company is building a manufacturing plant in the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">739af64d542d4f460697eb9a7951741d</guid></item><item><title>Freight train derails after collision with sheep truck at Bribbaree</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/freight-train-derails-after-collision-with-sheep-truck-bribbaree/105820076</link><description>A freight train derails following a crash with a truck carrying livestock in central west New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fa1de29d55673a44a56301cdea1ea8b</guid></item><item><title>Beleaguered Townsville mayor Troy Thompson resigns, vows to run again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/townsville-mayor-troy-thompson-resigns/105820030</link><description>A Queensland mayor under investigation for misrepresenting his military, education and business credentials has announced his resignation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">188cbd5bdbf5946e0955118435bfdf74</guid></item><item><title>Scientist wins peace prize for farmer-managed natural regeneration work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/tony-rinaudo-wins-luxembourg-peace-prize-regenerative-farming/105666674</link><description>A Victorian scientist whose farming technique has revolutionised agriculture in Niger has been awarded an international peace prize.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdd4d1ecb9ea1ba749bbf16d1448e605</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle Ocean Baths the setting for new headphone theatre production, Meet Me at the Baths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/meet-me-at-the-baths-ang-collins-newcastle-new-annual-festival/105809954</link><description>A new headphone theatre production is set among the swimmers and sunbakers at a NSW city's much-loved ocean pool.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27e003348ea3b7a57ee535f59076db94</guid></item><item><title>Health minister concedes tobacco black market has 'exploded'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/health-minister-concedes-tobacco-black-market-has-exploded/105820002</link><description>Health Minister Mark Butler admits black market tobacco is now the single biggest threat to public health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05884e55b2091e93d320e424fb5838c7</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final preview — how Geelong's unpredictable set up and late term heroics have set them up for a flag</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/afl-grand-final-preview-2025-geelong-profile-against-brisbane/105819810</link><description>From an innovative ruck set up to an uncanny ability to play out the quarter, the perennially competitive Cats are knocking on the door of another flag.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b332a9a8fd34aa68b5306baa1efb2624</guid></item><item><title>Branxholme Wallacedale Saints under 11s celebrate a win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/branxholme-wallacedale-saints-under-11s-celebrate/105812870</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d1e354fadc4bffdd99339a039272e54</guid></item><item><title>Branxholme Wallacedale Saints focus on club culture to become family-friendly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/branxholme-wallacedale-saints-focus-on-club-culture/105754946</link><description>The Branxholme Wallacedale Saints have worked tirelessly to improve their once-troubled reputation so families and their kids want to play there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afd5403e205bf7f3bbba6c2b15b64b0a</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos face Penrith Panthers in preliminary final without key forward Pat Carrigan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/brisbane-broncos-must-fill-carrigan-void-or-perish/105820354</link><description>Brisbane's forward pack is on notice to do their jobs and a bit more against Penrith in the preliminary final to cover the absence of Pat Carrigan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f832375101d237ed86d9093fecd23395</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane hellbent on ending horror NRLW finals run ahead of preliminary final clash with Newcastle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/nrlw-finals-broncos-knights-brigginshaw-upton/105820672</link><description>The Broncos have been almost untouchable through the 2025 NRLW season but the club's poor finals record in recent years means they can not afford to get ahead of themselves leading into this week's preliminary final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d248af9a48662ba232728304794119fd</guid></item><item><title>Daytime clubbing grows in popularity as dance venues cater to older patrons</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/over-30s-day-clubbing-in-albury-generation-x-dancing/105690616</link><description>Around Australia, over-30s are hitting the dance floor in daylight hours as more venues offer "soft clubbing" opportunities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b6672b9c54776257f90e27421c4afa7</guid></item><item><title>TASC 'confident' Tasmanian school exams are ready after report finds 11 errors last year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/tas-school-exams-report-finds-errors/105819858</link><description>An independent report into Tasmania's senior school exams blames understaffing for a series of mistakes found in last year's exam papers, with the body responsible saying "safeguards" are in place for this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a13ec4b76ef773cfc3fd870efecf82c</guid></item><item><title>Australian doctors become unofficial correspondents from hospital in Gaza City</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/australian-doctors-al-shifa-gaza-hospital/105813828</link><description>In a ruined hospital and with little medication, two Australian doctors say the situation inside Gaza City is a "nightmare".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfe47390104719cccc9dafc8afd130a0</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final preview — how corridor control and the hard ball can lead Brisbane to back-to-back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/afl-grand-final-preview-lions-look-for-back-to-back/105820830</link><description>They've had to deal with adversity all year, but the Lions are one step away from historic back-to-back flags — here's how they can do it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39ffbe3a1c41d9fda76aa7ad5e261837</guid></item><item><title>A Qantas flight from Sydney lands safely at Auckland Airport after mayday call</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/qantas-flight-lands-safely-after-mayday-call/105821038</link><description>The pilot requested an emergency landing after receiving indications about a potential fire in the cargo hold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b1cf306c5385f022b3214d48dd533f9</guid></item><item><title>Marion, Burnside and West Lakes among shopping centres listed by SA Police as Declared Public Precincts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/sa-declared-public-precincts/105820216</link><description>SA Police has announced Declared Public Precincts at eight shopping centres in metropolitan Adelaide, which will allow police to search people and remove them from the site.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b92ca055410bc1b898a51e170aa0a2a1</guid></item></channel></rss>