<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 09:04:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Public library visitor numbers return to pre-COVID levels as cost-of-living crisis bites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/public-libraries-australia-visitors-up-cost-of-living-crisis/106152152</link><description>Public libraries in Australia are experimenting with inventive ways to attract new members — but a lack of funding means they must do more with less.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e273b68565ad26ab3ff69f3d903723a</guid></item><item><title>After Venezuela, Donald Trump's other threats ring alarms around the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/after-venezuela-donald-trumps-other-threats/106203334</link><description>Donald Trump is talking about where US forces might venture next. But one of his cabinet secretaries could provide the clearest clues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">250a454241e20cae5504c394f87e089d</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police commissioner extends restrictions on Sydney protests for another fortnight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/nsw-police-protest-restrictions-decision-mal-lanyon/106203890</link><description>The NSW police commissioner will extend temporary protest restrictions across Sydney for another two weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0745c4340b305515c7295e0f60908cc</guid></item><item><title>WA Police raid Bunbury tobacconist after suspected firebomb of different vape store</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/police-raid-tobacco-shop-bunbury-after-vape-store-incident/106199506</link><description>Police seize vapes and cigarettes from the South West WA store days after two different shops were destroyed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74b2a96d2b8637c8c416829ecffeb71c</guid></item><item><title>Some NSW farmers say 10 guns are not enough ahead of planned restrictions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/some-nsw-farmers-say-10-guns-are-not-enough-firearms-cap/106203318</link><description>New gun laws in NSW will limit farmers to 10 guns but the industry says this is not enough, and the change could see "a whole lot more firearms and ammunition" moving between farms in vehicles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f530343703d6e087769daf3a394e93af</guid></item><item><title>Bondi terror attack royal commission pressure trumps Albanese's beliefs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/bondi-terror-attack-royal-commission-anthony-albanese/106202808</link><description>Whether or not Anthony Albanese believes a federal royal commission is necessary, or even the best use of resources, is now politically irrelevant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fd413938019ae14f86ed8d2268fdb30</guid></item><item><title>Teen faces court over Baldivis convenience store arson linked to illegal tobacco trade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/teen-charged-arson-attack-baldivis-convenience-store/106204496</link><description>A boy who allegedly set fire to a Baldivis convenience store may be facing threats from organised crime figures, Perth Children's Court hears.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef902b7ab40b6d39d9ea83f52d1c0efa</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith treats Sydney to a Smudge Day, in all its weird and wonderful glory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/ashes-fifth-test-day-three-steve-smiths-smudge-day/106203528</link><description>Steve Smith was at his bizarre best on day three in Sydney, grinding England into the dust with his scintillating strokeplay and trademark oddness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">323f9319839ca877e27543eeb68bc9df</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/tuesday-finance-with-david-chau/106204516</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af844bcc6a4cee1825a23893cb37c003</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Jenna the second system to lash Cocos Keeling Islands in less than two weeks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/cocos-tropical-cyclone-jenna-keeling-islands-indian-ocean/106203486</link><description>Residents of the islands clean up following heavy rain and winds brought by Tropical Cyclone Jenna, less than two weeks another system battered the region on Christmas day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd6ee8f687d014634b9cb4ac57cf1730</guid></item><item><title>Human remains found in search for snorkeller missing off WA's Ledge Point</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/human-remains-found-in-search-for-snorkeller-missing-wa/106204822</link><description>Police confirm human remains have been found washed ashore north of Perth, believed to be those of a 32-year-old man missing since New Year's Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">115d2e3da7e9c4da7c8cc4508e5df6e4</guid></item><item><title>What Venezuela's deposed president and first lady are accused of</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/drug-trafficking-allegations-against-nicolas-maduro/106202616</link><description>The US has justified the seizure of deposed Venezuelan leader Nicolás Maduro and wife Cilia Flores by arguing they had breached US domestic law. So what exactly have they been accused of doing?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">941caf9bf09b2b36e2322b47582fc864</guid></item><item><title>Australia books United Cup quarterfinal berth after Alex de Minaur's high-pressure double act</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/de-minaur-dazzles-to-restore-australias-cup-hopes/106205120</link><description>Twin wins from Alex de Minaur drags Australia off the canvas and into the United Cup quarterfinals with a do-or-die victory over Czechia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34a9d1647547c2c1fe6030a93748a2c7</guid></item><item><title>US set to back Ukraine defence coalition if peace deal made with Russia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/coalition-of-the-willing-paris-ceasefire-defence-coalition-us/106205340</link><description>A draft statement outlines what Ukraine's allies could commit to if Russia attacks its neighbour again in the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b290e391153bf910a66318327fd97287</guid></item><item><title>Military force 'always an option' for Greenland, White House says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/european-leaders-back-greenland-after-trump-threats/106205394</link><description>The US president and his officials are continuing to push for an American takeover of the Danish territory, saying the island is needed for national security.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ec6b2a38e5d7036a528511a65d3cf0c</guid></item><item><title>Trump's intervention in Venezuela heralds an incomparable era</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/venezuela-comparisons-donald-trump-greenland-argentina-panama/106200808</link><description>The global shock caused by the Trump administration's interventions in Venezuela sent analysts scurrying for historic comparisons, but nothing really compares to what happened at the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eafc52c7e0c0236e11977d346ff247b</guid></item><item><title>Total fire ban declared for parts of Victoria and SA as heatwave begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/victoria-south-australia-authorities-brace-for-fires-heatwave/106203894</link><description>Firefighters in Victoria continue to battle a bushfire in the state's north-east as a heatwave brings temperatures near 45 degrees Celsius to some parts of the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8543476943a44e681083f27e5a4c34a</guid></item><item><title>Severe heatwave conditions to arrive in Tasmania's north, central and eastern regions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/tasmania-heatwave-fire-risk-weather/106202982</link><description>As Tasmanians make the most of the first heatwave of 2026, authorities are keeping a keen eye on reported high rates of dry grass and other bushfire risks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0d1a6f3b6f2615d6794fc0528ee7b22</guid></item><item><title>A severe heatwave is crossing Tasmania.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/severe-heatwave-tasmania-beuro-meteorology-explainer/106204770</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9cb2d1d6d6ccecd45016fdcc2f499ef</guid></item><item><title>María Corina Machado vows to return to Venezuela following ousting of Nicolás Maduro by US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/maria-corina-machado-vows-to-return-to-venezuela/106205438</link><description>In her first interview since the ousting of President Nicolás Maduro, María Corina Machado says she is confident she will win any election held in Venezuela.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8110fa3a018590501d787a5146695b37</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelans celebrate a future reclaimed — but insiders warn the power struggle is just getting started</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/venezuela-hope-dreams-maduro-machado-voices-challenges/106202872</link><description>Venezuelans celebrate what once felt impossible — but inside the country, armed powerbrokers, nervous officials and rival factions are already jostling over what comes next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87806b5b8b7126e30bdf16d46f45c499</guid></item><item><title>Day-by-day weather guide to most severe southern Australia heatwave in years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/weather-heatwave-southern-australia-day-by-day-temperatures/106204522</link><description>Southern Australia will collectively bake this week through the most intense spell of heat in years as temperatures soar up to 15 degrees Celsius above the mid-summer average.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e21756b0b8879ad9d5f4e98b480fc5d8</guid></item><item><title>Trump has no plan after removing Maduro, Schumer says, after 'troubling' classified briefing — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/venezuela-us-maduro-mission-kills-dozens-live-blog-january-7/106205158</link><description>The Democrats' Senate leader, Chuck Schumer, says he has received a classified briefing from the White House on Donald Trump's plans for Venezuela — and is dismayed by the lack of detail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4495ddff889e8e107378952b7869a9c</guid></item><item><title>Echidna population count underway in Queensland amid urbanisation and climate change fears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/echidna-population-count-queensland-conservation/106127158</link><description>The lack of knowledge about the species has experts worried echidnas could decline without anyone noticing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebe1f96569f58475e6456590bd3d4df5</guid></item><item><title>Australians trapped on Yemen's Socotra island after Saudi Arabia, UAE flare-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/australians-trapped-socotra-island-yemen-saudi-arabia-uae/106205342</link><description>Australians are among hundreds of tourists scrambling to leave a remote Yemeni island, as a crisis on the mainland between Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates causes travel chaos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7346dab8aa0ee77f69c1857ff1a7cba</guid></item><item><title>Half of Canberra's Commonwealth Avenue Bridge is closing for two years. Here's what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/canberra-commonwealth-avenue-bridge-closures-for-upgrade-works/106199138</link><description>Commuters in Canberra are facing major disruptions as Commonwealth Avenue Bridge undergoes two years of major upgrades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31b1cd56ebd627daa7150ecefe614db5</guid></item><item><title>Fire on southern NSW property likely sparked by cigarette butt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/cigarette-butt-sparks-fire-at-the-rock/106199936</link><description>A southern NSW landholder is urging smokers to think twice when disposing of their cigarette butts, after a grassfire razed her property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee174ccb428fe82617770620b9ba9036</guid></item><item><title>Insurer Prosura hit by cyber data breach, customers contacted by 'threat actor'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/car-excess-insurer-prosura-hit-by-cyber-breach-customer-data/106204198</link><description>Australians who have rented cars have been caught up in a cyber incident affecting excess insurer Prosura, with customers receiving modified invoices from a self-proclaimed "threat actor".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">330ce98f3590ee330d11c93cbff6b1c7</guid></item><item><title>Outback NT hotel at centre of Peter Falconio mystery barred from serving alcohol</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/outback-pub-barrow-creek-hotel-liquor-licence-suspended/106203732</link><description>The Barrow Creek Hotel was thrust into the global spotlight during the investigation into British backpacker Peter Falconio's disappearance. Now its liquor licence has been suspended for breaching Northern Territory licensing laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">116c019736e660595b4c4da2ae2cde7d</guid></item><item><title>Kids at tiny school work to save extremely rare 'flying jewel' purple copper butterfly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/meadow-flat-primary-school-purple-copper-butterfly/106173306</link><description>It's the size of a 10-cent piece and matures under the guard of protective ants, but the purple copper butterfly needs more help to survive — and a group of NSW primary school students has stepped up to the challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a78ff0b822d201d809f27d33c730147</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine's allies agree to security guarantees in 'significant step' towards ending Russia's invasion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/ukraine-european-leaders-security-guarantee-agreement/106205560</link><description>At a key meeting in Paris, officials from Europe, Canada, the US and NATO say they will provide Kyiv's frontline forces with equipment and training, and back them up with air, land and sea support to deter any future Russian attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac913b2f29ba0b935dd20a68fea2cf4d</guid></item><item><title>The tough balance of circumstance and support systems as WA woman faces eviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/balance-of-circumstance-and-support-system-wa-mother-eviction/106205110</link><description>As protesters strive to keep a woman from community housing eviction, the complexities of her situation collide with a housing provider's options.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d8ea6cf63b10324e9c1f2392dfdf238</guid></item><item><title>Travellers urged not to rely solely on navigation systems for directions following recent strandings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/travellers-urged-not-to-rely-solely-on-gps-after-strandings/106202818</link><description>A young couple got bogged on a remote dirt road in north Queensland and was forced to walk hours in search of help after trusting their navigation app to find a 24-hour fuel station.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40bf85ccc108f1d047799f881ca9deb2</guid></item><item><title>Emergency warnings issued for Victorian fires as heatwave sweeps southern Australia — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/australia-heatwave-victoria-sa-fire-risk-january-7/106205674</link><description>Southern Australia is enduring its most intense heatwave in years, with temperatures set to soar from today until the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29f88aaecce24da4d9954d44b6c2e769</guid></item><item><title>Mystery over safe with beef jerky inside recovered from Shark Bay's ocean floor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/shark-bay-treasure-safe-found-on-seafloor-with-beef-jerky/106200058</link><description>While hoping for treasure, a nervous Quoin Sellenger was left with a (sadly) inedible salty snack after retrieving a safe from the bottom of WA's Shark Bay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca0339a8741aa48f5393316a5365d03d</guid></item><item><title>Men charged over alleged international car theft syndicate targeting Toyota LandCruisers and Prados</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/men-charged-toyota-landcruisers-prados-stolen-brisbane/106205532</link><description>Queensland Police say 60 Toyota LandCruisers and Prados were stolen across Brisbane between October 20 and December 1.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d28d81f828e897d2d0edf4c0f3bb424</guid></item><item><title>Perth Bears sign Bulldogs forward Josh Curran ahead of 2027 NRL entry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/nrl-perth-bears-sign-josh-curran-from-bulldogs/106205922</link><description>The Perth Bears land their most experienced NRL player so far in their recruitment drive, signing Canterbury's Josh Curran on a three-year deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f1eaf3d731fb881f7716731cf26348f</guid></item><item><title>AI hallucinations and the dilemma of false or misleading information</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/aavegotchi-artificial-intelligence-hallucinations-analysis/106169730</link><description>When a journalist emails a company with questions looking for answers, the least they expect is a real person to feed them the spin, half-truths or outright lies. Not a machine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1955222755afe2ff3d8fb649200d65d</guid></item><item><title>Bayer's Monsanto sues Pfizer, BioNTech and Moderna over mRNA technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/monsanto-sues-pfizer-biontech-moderna-over-covid-vaccines/106206038</link><description>Bayer's Monsanto has sued Pfizer, BioNTech and Moderna for allegedly misusing its messenger RNA technology in COVID vaccines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">652acbaa5c23a6ce009f8e42f4322919</guid></item><item><title>Inflation cools in November with consumer prices rising 3.4pc but still above the RBA's target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/inflation-abs-monthly-cpi-for-november/106205848</link><description>Inflation cooled in November, with the consumer price index rising 3.4 per cent over the year, down from 3.8 per cent a month earlier. Some economists continue to forecast a February rate hike, however.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f13348eb885b0fed864738fbce93301b</guid></item><item><title>Southern Outlet crash between truck and bus sees 17 people treated at Royal Hobart Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/tas-southern-outlet-crash-hobart-kingston-17-treated-hospital/106206300</link><description>A peak-hour crash on Hobart's Southern Outlet leads to 17 people being assessed at the Royal Hobart Hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dcf537ae5b62d23790b82f89faf135a</guid></item><item><title>Who is Nicolás Maduro Guerra, the son of Venezuela's deposed leader?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/who-is-nicol%C3%A1s-maduro-guerra-son-of-venezuelan-leader/106202664</link><description>Nicolás Maduro Guerra rose through the ranks of his father's government and remains in Caracas. It's uncertain for how long.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dabc89c15f5459e8a52d8629ce14dc1</guid></item><item><title>Poland to face Australia in United Cup quarterfinals after Hubert Hurkacz wins singles against the Netherlands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/poland-to-play-australia-united-cup-quarterfinals/106206422</link><description>Poland will meet the host nation in the last eight of the mixed-teams event after in-form Hubert Hurkacz beat Tallon Griekspoor of the Netherlands in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64fe6cf10297ec2f374a68bff622d074</guid></item><item><title>How to avoid heatstroke and when to call Triple Zero in a heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/heatwave-illness-and-how-to-protect-yourself/106205872</link><description>Extreme heat forecast for the next few days has prompted warnings form health experts. Here's how to stay safe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">697d4b3b3f2b3f0a17e64bf6fd46fdc4</guid></item><item><title>Past works reimagined in Second Look — Legacy, the Australian Design Centre's final exhibition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/australian-design-centre-second-look-legacy-exhibition/106192528</link><description>Second Look — Legacy celebrates sustainable making while paying homage to one of the most influential figures in Australia craft and design.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6796a5ca7d920ad8561aac2789c84e6</guid></item><item><title>Truck crashes into five cars on Picton Road at Cataract, north of Wollongong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/truck-crashes-into-cars-picton-road-cataract-wollongong/106206524</link><description>More than a dozen people were assessed by paramedics after a truck smashed into several cars on a major road north of Wollongong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b99241ec366186e5801a4130d581da96</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne tram enthusiasts join fight to save India's last tram network</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/melbourne-tram-enthusiasts-fight-to-save-kolkata-tram-network/106204938</link><description>Melbourne's iconic trams thrive in a car-centred world, but Asia's oldest tramway is now facing extinction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce54859611aa9ff045d5ded24b2b723c</guid></item><item><title>Why does Trump want Greenland and why is it so important?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/why-does-trump-want-greenland-and-why-is-it-so-important/106203650</link><description>Donald Trump's continued interest in Greenland is part of his "America First" agenda to dominate the Western Hemisphere and contain China's interests in the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe83050ed01b2f0d3c705e4286721003</guid></item><item><title>Council calls in diggers as big swells deposit masses of seaweed on Sydney beaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/diggers-called-in-as-seaweed-masses-on-sydney-beaches/106206160</link><description>Piles of kelp were removed from a popular Sydney beach, although some councils prefer to leave the seaweed for its environmental benefit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5637b05772499f34725d36a017b4e93c</guid></item><item><title>Israel clears final hurdle to start settlement construction that would cut the West Bank in two</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/israel-clears-final-hurdle-west-bank-settlement-construction/106206464</link><description>Critics say the E1 project would prevent the establishment of a contiguous Palestinian state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f1db5685c633ee1809bb2f0e2a944b5</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal artist Bobbi Lockyer in tears as Australia Post loses $4k painting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/auspost-loses-4000-dollar-bobbi-lockyer-artwork-before-xmas/106206356</link><description>Indigenous artist Bobbi Lockyer has been left frustrated after she sent a $4,000 custom artwork of the Pilbara to a buyer in Queensland, only for an empty cardboard sleeve to be delivered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9d27135931651e6a5ebc9706fc2eba9</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave conditions likely to bring increase of flies and maggots</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/how-to-reduce-flies-maggots-at-home/105941190</link><description>Forecast heatwave conditions across large parts of the country could mean flies and maggots are more prevalent. Here's how to deal with them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd44e594d644af51a17c967e875c59ba</guid></item><item><title>Kimberly Birrell, Olivia Gadecki, Emerson Jones record second-round losses at Brisbane International</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/aussie-emerson-jones-out-brisbane-international-gadecki/106207056</link><description>Australian players Kimberly Birrell and Olivia Gadecki have fallen in the second round of the Brisbane International, along with rising star Emerson Jones, who went out after a high-quality encounter with the world number 17.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b35e2c4b3e39d3d89b44578a759a1ad6</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged with attempted murder after allegedly stabbing man multiple times with steak knife</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/woman-charged-attempted-murder-steak-knife-lowanna-st-braddon/106207390</link><description>A 37-year-old woman has been charged with attempted murder after allegedly stabbing a man with a steak knife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dd535b675f9669a80a38a752d35f000</guid></item><item><title>Songs from the Hottest 100 of 2005 that should have been higher</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/songs-from-hottest-100-of-2005-should-have-been-higher/106145224</link><description>Arctic Monkeys were that low!? These are the tunes from triple j's Hottest 100 of 20. years ago that deserved to have placed higher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afe7a93ca4bda33c4967345c3488e4f4</guid></item><item><title>Staff at new Noarlunga mental health unit 'visibly distressed and crying', union says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/sasmoa-raises-concerns-staff-pressured-at-mental-health-unit/106206512</link><description>South Australia's doctors' union has raised concerns that clinicians were distressed when asked to admit more patients at a new mental health unit at Noarlunga Hospital when staffing levels were "not clinically safe".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18ada848b526514d9d9fdbfb12165814</guid></item><item><title>Cosmetic nurse banned for two years after injecting botox without consulting doctor or obtaining prescription</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/qld-cosmetic-injectables-nurse-banned-ahpra/106206780</link><description>An AHPRA investigation found Thia Sullivan injected a patient without doctor consultation or a script, falsified records, and urged patients not to co-operate with police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24ab7c914abb7698629cc451740e2e66</guid></item><item><title>Beau Webster sparks another English meltdown and Jacob Bethell brings tears — quick hits from day four of the SCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/ashes-quick-hits-day-four-scg-test/106205924</link><description>Beau Webster sparks a classic English meltdown as Jacob Bethell brings tears while Ben Stokes fails to finish another series. Here are your quick hits from day four of the SCG Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c2b6e11a4423ebcc8a55b02204c09a9</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/wednesday-finance-with-david-chau/106206784</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32abbb1c99e93571bc99a25151991c64</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2026: Jacob Bethell, England's biggest hope and biggest blunder, sets up Sydney finale</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/jacob-bethell-englands-hope-sets-up-sydney-finale-day-four-scg/106206644</link><description>Jacob Bethell's brilliant maiden Test century sets up an intriguing finish in Sydney, but leaves everyone bemused as to where this precocious young player has been all summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31da6c565da8a3ff2614cf41621bb413</guid></item><item><title>Maida Vale, High Wycombe fire extinguished after closing parts of Roe Highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/residents-in-city-of-kalamunda-urged-to-take-shelter-bushfire/106207782</link><description>Ground and aerial crews successfully control a bushfire that closed a section of Roe Highway and brought traffic to a standstill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09de7784b5375473f30d3a264f7b54b3</guid></item><item><title>Nestlé recalls select batches of Alfamino infant formula</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/nestl%C3%A9-recalls-select-batches-of-alfamino-infant-formula/106207844</link><description>The precautionary measure is over concerns that the product could contain a toxin that can cause food poisoning symptoms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5d3dc52ac89a785c547074fcbc7903b</guid></item><item><title>WA police launch search for Kenneth John Giles, 58, after gunshot near Mullewa, woman injured</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/reports-of-man-with-firearm-in-wa-town-mullewa/106208060</link><description>A manhunt is underway for 58-year-old Kenneth John Giles who allegedly fled with a firearm after a shooting on a rural property near Mullewa, about 450 kilometres north of Perth, with a woman suffering non-life-threatening injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bf6207e7d8e932f4f229f3e27c354a8</guid></item><item><title>US seizes more oil tankers as it lays out three-phase plan for Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/us-intercepts-bella-1-venezuelan-oil-tanker-russia-sub/106208100</link><description>Russia says one of the Venezuela-linked tankers is "our vessel" and demands the quick release of its citizens, as the US pledges to continue seizing ships and keep the pressure on Venezuela's interim leaders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29305b17e024b72cafa330d35ccb80e0</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios and Thanasi Kokkinakis's Brisbane International campaign ends in loss to French duo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/special-k-duo-kyrgios-kokkinakis-lose-at-brisbane-international/106208078</link><description>Nick Kyrgios and Thanasi Kokkinakis's doubles campaign at the Brisbane International has come to an end after an entertaining tiebreak decider against France.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f534806a03bfefb2c8c01436015d4bf6</guid></item><item><title>Property losses, warnings for bushfires across Victoria as firefighters prepare for 'catastrophic' conditions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/warnings-bushfire-victoria-longwood-mt-lawson-state-park/106207942</link><description>Emergency warnings remain in place as out-of-control blazes continue to burn in Victoria ahead of "catastrophic" fire conditions on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54310935b70c461d8a627f397c5eb0fe</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, January 8: 'El Chapo' recaptured in bloody raid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/today-in-history-january-8-el-chapo-recaptured/106192234</link><description>"Mission accomplished: we got him," began the triumphant tweet from Mexico's then-president Enrique Peña Nieto.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5827f4bceceda64381161c6f1f412626</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave breakdown state-by-state as breeze offers just a brief reprieve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/how-the-heatwave-will-play-out-in-each-state/106206670</link><description>A breeze will bring a brief reprieve for coastal areas of Victoria and South Australia today before the heat and fire danger ramps up again tomorrow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb45894b9a1eefc5d284f032f9b55958</guid></item><item><title>NATO faces unpredictable threat from Donald Trump as US eyes Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/natos-latest-threat-could-be-coming-from-within-donald-trump/106205214</link><description>Donald Trump has made it clear he's departing from decades of US foreign policy norms and once-close allies are now questioning what it could mean for them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f34a592f3deb295efe74b82e88ce4a5</guid></item><item><title>Organiser of Indigenous deaths in custody rally vows to defy NSW protest laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/nsw-first-nations-rally-organiser-protest-laws-david-dungay-jr/106207676</link><description>Paul Silva says he plans to defy NSW's new protest restrictions to rally against Indigenous deaths in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e56b69535dce50cdc4a24c01dd7f1aa5</guid></item><item><title>Labor fundraiser at centre of Minns donations allegations bigger than official records suggest, newspaper report shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/labor-fundraiser-reportedly-bigger-than-official-records-suggest/106206142</link><description>A decade-old Labor fundraiser at the centre of allegations that NSW Premier Chris Minns conspired to evade a state donations law was reported at the time as a much bigger event than official records suggest, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0730d1e104831103f68c68aaddd0cea</guid></item><item><title>Derailed freight train shuts part of key national railway line. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/train-derailment-affects-key-south-australian-rail-line/106205992</link><description>The derailment of a freight train on a key section of railway in South Australia is affecting all transcontinental train services as heatwave conditions in the area impact the pace of recovery works.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ec1ffc355f468cfacd7c593d01a860d</guid></item><item><title>More than 29,000 head of livestock dead or missing in north-west Qld, as BOM predicts potential cyclone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/cattle-deaths-north-west-queensland-floods-more-rain-to-come/106206592</link><description>The number of livestock found dead across north-west Queensland is expected to rise, but for already devastated producers, a potential cyclone brings the threat of more rain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97b61ee0ffac242cd75d19eb6e026735</guid></item><item><title>Should you exercise during hot weather? Experts weigh in as southern states swelter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/can-you-exercise-safely-in-a-heatwave-australia/106206302</link><description>Despite parts of Australia experiencing the worst heatwave conditions since the 2019-20 Black Summer, people can still be spotted braving the hot weather to go for a run. Should they be doing this?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2c9a65a4f90ad9a05ba00c7174ea0e6</guid></item><item><title>Two-time major winner Coco Gauff heaps praise on rising Australian star Maya Joint</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/united-cup-tennis-coco-gauff-maya-joint-australia-us/106208390</link><description>World number four Coco Gauff describes Maya Joint as a "great talent" ahead of a potential match-up against the 19-year-old Australian at the United Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c0575015d78e3407300f26a351994b0</guid></item><item><title>US authorities intercept oil tanker in Atlantic Ocean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/us-authorities-intercept-oil-tanker-in-atlantic-ocean-/106208338</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">591c75f98c14005b17d9a636d04d8223</guid></item><item><title>NT rangers capture croc a day in first week of new year, after more than 240 caught in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/nt-parks-and-wildlife-rangers-crocodile-capture-data-croc-risk/106206212</link><description>Rangers in the Northern Territory have caught an average of a crocodile per day in the first week of 2026, including one measuring 4.9 metres pulled from waters near a popular swimming spot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">575c9d4ba6f4778c96acb242536571a6</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Emerson Jones targeting rankings jump in 2026 after Brisbane International showing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/brisbane-international-emerson-jones-wants-to-reach-top-100/106208514</link><description>Emerson Jones gave a glimpse of her potential at the Brisbane International, with her 2026 season getting underway in promising fashion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">077a1b3047011e1af773f89ce733c29c</guid></item><item><title>What the 'I'm an American living in Australia' Instagram and TikTok trend reveals about both countries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/what-im-an-american-in-australia-trend-reveals-about-usa-and-us/106135242</link><description>Americans are posting sunny social media dispatches about their new lives in Australia, but there is something more revealing underneath.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ebbb3bb973e31d8db2e95e873ec2ffc</guid></item><item><title>NSW police charge two men over alleged 'car trouble' scam targeting older Australians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/two-men-charged-car-trouble-scam/106206256</link><description>Police have charged two men and are searching for two others following an alleged NSW-wide crime operation targeting the elderly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">012ddfb268f57a2c0aac012a768d960a</guid></item><item><title>CCTV captures trophy theft from Tasmanian Wool Centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/cctv-captures-trophy-theft-from-tasmanian-wool-centre/106208656</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df04bd210f823a22e4b00b1ccf0a3c75</guid></item><item><title>Actor Awards nominations 2026: Australian stars Jacob Elordi, Sarah Snook and Rose Byrne among nominees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/sag-actor-award-nominations/106208668</link><description>Australian names are among the mix of nominees unveiled for Hollywood's Actor Awards, formerly known as the Screen Actors Guild Awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2da960f27bdebc5e7ba4cd8afcc9844</guid></item><item><title>Marble Bar residents share their tips for keeping cool in nationwide heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/beating-the-heat-in-marble-bar-australias-hottest-town/106204346</link><description>From 30 bags of ice in a blow-up pool to misted toilets and getting plenty of sleep, residents in Marble Bar share their top tips to weather a heatwave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09532239a65ed148c6c952b574dd0e7c</guid></item><item><title>Ollie Peake's last-ball six hands Renegades controversial BBL win over Scorchers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/bbl-ollie-peake-melbourne-renegades-perth-scorchers/106208704</link><description>Ollie Peake survives a contentious overturned catch to smash a six on the final delivery to seal a four-wicket win for the Melbourne Renegades in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e340c9416d62ddc933e2a89761b4936</guid></item><item><title>ICE agent fatally shoots woman in Minneapolis.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/protests-erupt-after-ice-agent-fatally-shoots-woman/106208574</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99716935e082906aa4b7bf6ce1ed4743</guid></item><item><title>Fire-fuelled thunderstorms form in Victoria as temperatures soar in SA, NSW — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/fire-weather-heatwave-live-blog-victoria-sa-nsw/106208762</link><description>A heatwave stretching across Australia is in its second day, with authorities battling multiple blazes across Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68a0fa4a071e5d71d734ef91b0abb20f</guid></item><item><title>Community-run heatwave havens offer respite for vulnerable residents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/heatwave-havens-eurobodalla-vulnerable-residents/106204158</link><description>Retrofitted community centres, surf lifesaving clubs and churches are being opened for the first time as 'heatwave havens' on the NSW South Coast, offering vulnerable residents refuge from the heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09705320aefe98adddd6977f80d39331</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2026: Australia claims 4-1 series win after surviving nervy run chase to win Sydney Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/ashes-live-blog-day-five-scg/106208540</link><description>Australia chases down 160 with five wickets remaining in Sydney to round out the Ashes in style as Usman Khawaja bids farewell to Test cricket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">561f6e0d36232b22c3058b783d0b4529</guid></item><item><title>Disability support worker charged with client's manslaughter granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/ndis-manslaughter-carramar-fire/106207916</link><description>The died after a blaze ripped through a home in Carramar in April 2021, having allegedly been left unsupervised by a care worker the night before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec7200926d5dd9a90d5a14261d05f946</guid></item><item><title>Gunshots heard as woman shot dead by ICE officer in Minneapolis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/gunshots-heard-as-woman-shot-dead-by-ice-officer-in-minneapolis-/106208960</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c25ec786dde086a9d79fedbf2e800254</guid></item><item><title>Algal bloom researcher 'deeply disturbed' by political interference claims, committee told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/claims-algal-bloom-cause-probe-delayed-until-after-sa-election/106208450</link><description>An inquiry into South Australia's harmful algal bloom has been rocked by claims from a prominent ecologist, who has raised allegations of government interference in scientific research into the bloom's causes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddbdc6a9b523b6c81afed0925ddeaa47</guid></item><item><title>Commercial fishers hit by Kimberley Marine Park left waiting five years for compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/commercial-fishers-still-waiting-compensation-kimberley-wa/106206918</link><description>Kimberley fishers impacted by the establishment of a marine park say the government has failed to deliver promised compensation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6002d73bf44564f51ba3d2a7fc29d97d</guid></item><item><title>Man dies in quad bike crash on forestry road in Railton, northern Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/man-dies-atv-crash-railton-northern-tasmania/106209100</link><description>A 20-year-old man has died after his quad bike crashed on a forestry road in northern Tasmania, with police saying it is the third serious all-terrain vehicle crash in recent weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8929fc6587375fb930930f84ed2296f1</guid></item><item><title>What the seizure of Maduro means for China, Venezuela's biggest oil buyer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/china-close-ties-with-venezuela-inaction-since-maduro-capture/106205836</link><description>Despite being one of the strongest critics of Donald Trump's move to capture Nicolás Maduro, Beijing has not moved beyond condemnation of Washington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f783c8e2d27f1fa5e3da5837c0681ffa</guid></item><item><title>Veteran Stan Wawrinka says Nick Kyrgios is an 'amazing player' amid wildcard debate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/wawrinka-on-kyrgios-australian-open-wildcard/106209186</link><description>Retiring veteran Stan Wawrinka was all class discussing the AO wildcard debate surrounding Nick Kyrgios, putting aside the pair's troubled history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32410a257a44771fc70bd7f1a788ca37</guid></item><item><title>Independent film collective Movie Juice launches inaugural summer film fest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/independent-film-collective-movie-juice-summer-film-festival/106207546</link><description>Summer has hit its stride with a heatwave across the country this week, providing the perfect backdrop to a new film festival that features beaches, surfing, young love, and that horrible feeling of holidays ebbing by.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c4265944145f44c4bd0a1e77ac10d99</guid></item><item><title>Grand Designs Transformations' Yasmine Ghoniem on living in her car, renovation mistakes and season two</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/grand-designs-transformations-yasmine-ghoniem-season-two/106199108</link><description>We chat with inimitable interior designer Yasmine Ghoniem ahead of Grand Designs Transformations series two to learn how she made it, her hot design takes, and what to expect from this season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0c60eebade36f183638f3ad12c09b98</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Test cricketer Damien Martyn returns home after waking from induced coma</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/cricket-damien-martyn-returns-home-after-induced-coma/106209598</link><description>Adam Gilchrist says his former Australia teammate Damien Martyn has been released from a Gold Coast hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49020d9667afff535b334516291f1145</guid></item><item><title>Kentbruck Green Energy Hub passes planning hurdle but report highlights environmental concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/kentbruck-wind-project-environmental-effects-approval/106206224</link><description>The Kentbruck Green Energy Hub would include wind turbines up to 270m tall, and be built inside active pine plantations, but its location has worried conservationists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3fb1208cb6857282d20eabaa766c4bf</guid></item><item><title>Reserve Bank deputy governor Andrew Hauser downplays easing inflation ahead of February meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/rba-deputy-andrew-hauser-inflation-interest-rates/106208716</link><description>The deputy governor of the Reserve Bank Andrew Hauser confirms the news mortgage borrowers would not have wanted to hear — interest rates are highly unlikely to head lower anytime soon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe254d1365e7c4696f8ec418bfb00e24</guid></item><item><title>Timelapse shows rising river in Texas flash flood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/timelapse-shows-rising-river-in-texas-flash-flood/106209826</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7676bb5a3571b0c6db213b3985f443b6</guid></item><item><title>No subscriptions? No problems. Here are the best movies and TV series you can watch for free</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/free-movies-free-tv-watch-online/106207308</link><description>From Academy Award-winning performances to classic Australian comedy, fill the last moments of your holidays with these free movies and TV series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ce170a90764ebd85c804dafd5fbfac9</guid></item><item><title>Boom time for active holiday tours attracting travellers with 'young energy'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/active-holidays-ocean-swimming-popular-on-turkish-lycian-coast/106173770</link><description>There is no lounging by the pool for these travellers, who are spending a week swimming the remote waters of the Turkish Lycian coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f50bd5e400dc329dbb870202b6788d7b</guid></item><item><title>PM's possible pick to lead Bondi royal commission sparks pushback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/bondi-attack-royal-commission-albanese-pick-pushback/106209204</link><description>Anthony Albanese has been in talks about calling a Commonwealth royal commission into last month's attack, signalling to colleagues he is preparing to renege on his opposition to the idea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42ef15f840ee4889890b49e87d097982</guid></item><item><title>Wild mountain gorilla gives birth to twins in Virunga National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/gorilla-twins-born-virunga-national-park-drc-congo/106209406</link><description>A mountain gorilla named Mafuko gives birth to twins, a "rare and remarkable event", in Virunga National Park in the Democratic Republic of Congo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">998b170e96d5631d89a0dcba5830c535</guid></item><item><title>Lachie Neale given Lions' 'blessing' if he wants to return to Perth at end of 2026 AFL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/brisbane-lions-lachie-neale-chris-fagan/106210014</link><description>The Brisbane Lions will not stand in the way of Lachie Neale if the club's former co-captain chooses to return to Perth at the end of the season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">265443ee944d4f0969e173229e5bcc74</guid></item><item><title>Minnesota ICE shooting takes life of a legal observer, according to local representatives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/minneapolis-ice-shooting-inside-the-legal-observer-networks/106209032</link><description>As Donald Trump's immigration crackdown escalates in Minneapolis, networks of local residents patrol the streets too, warning of incoming ICE raids, documenting what happens and offering legal advice to those targeted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cf336bfbdefd534a2fa8318e8d340b4</guid></item><item><title>Track the temperatures as southern Australian states face heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/southern-aus-heatwave-temperature-tracker/106207608</link><description>Use our tracker to keep an eye on temperatures as a heatwave moves through the southern states.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d8a181032d9a281810c93c1d37de5e5</guid></item><item><title>What led to an ICE agent fatally shooting a public observer in Minneapolis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/ice-shooting-minneapolis-minnesota-immigration-crackdown/106209128</link><description>The fatal shooting of a legal observer by an ICE agent in Minneapolis is the latest flashpoint in Donald Trump's crackdown on immigration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11849a2196d3508fa03e7f8c93c295ee</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja's fitting farewell, DRS drama and Marnus Labuschagne keeps things interesting — quick hits from day five of the SCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/quick-hits-scg-day-five-ashes-khawaja-marnus-labuschagne-run-out/106208590</link><description>The SCG celebrates a retiring hero and a rising star, tempers flair after another DRS debacle and Marnus mourns a horror run-out. Here are the quick hits from the final day of the 2025-26 Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77ca3d9cc1cfdef04cb23ba77b921608</guid></item><item><title>Two children among seven hurt in multi-vehicle crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/banya-crash-two-children-hurt-multi-vehicles/106210690</link><description>Seven patients are being treated after a serious crash on Queensland's Sunshine Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82c5a9a7f1d8dcb7b7f10cbd091fa4ab</guid></item><item><title>Summernats begins in Canberra as organisers brace for large crowds and heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/summernats-2026-begins-city-cruise-canberra/106209124</link><description>Australia’s biggest car festival roars to life amid a scorching heatwave, thrill-seeking crowds and strict policing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d109c5ccd9d8e4556b5f60b426db9d3</guid></item><item><title>Summernats kicks off with City Cruise down Northbourne Avenue in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/summernats-kicks-off-with-city-cruise/106210884</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9c66f22ae31bc1934db6381452d423b</guid></item><item><title>Australia underlines its Ashes dominance of England to write its own story at the SCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/australia-underlines-ashes-dominance-to-write-its-own-story/106209390</link><description>A 4-1 scoreline can leave no doubt, this has been an Ashes summer of dominance for a resilient Australian side and a tour of errors and mismanagement for England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">606001ce9ef51ebfbcdb879075270f38</guid></item><item><title>Lifting ban on developer donations could increase corruption risk, Queensland watchdog says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/qld-political-donation-ban-property-developers/106210392</link><description>Queensland's corruption watchdog has warned lifting a ban on political donations from developers could increase the risk of "actual or perceived" corruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec8a36f9dc9f5bef9f5c83b607d43f0e</guid></item><item><title>Authors withdraw from Adelaide Writers' Week after Randa Abdel-Fattah axed for 'cultural sensitivity'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/randa-abdel-fattah-adelaide-writers-week-axed-authors-withdraw/106210464</link><description>After Randa Abdel-Fattah was dropped from Adelaide Writers' Week by the Adelaide Festival Board, a slew of authors, including Michelle de Kretser, have withdrawn from the event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbd24da619c619fbb5f6c152023696dd</guid></item><item><title>Former High Court justice Virginia Bell to lead Bondi royal commission</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/albanese-bell-royal-commission-antisemitism-bondi/106210052</link><description>A national royal commission into antisemitism and social cohesion has been called by Anthony Albanese after weeks of pressure to establish an inquiry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bafdd0d809232c7d5e25a141799792e</guid></item><item><title>Comiskey Group's 'eco-tourism' park approved for Coochin Creek</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/coochin-creek-tourist-park-approved/106209514</link><description>The state government approves a 150-site tourist park with 95 conditions despite ongoing environmental concerns from authorities and community groups.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5154da108b6229fb799dd8e46b791ef7</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka and Elena Rybakina march on to Brisbane International quarter-finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/sabalenka-rybakina-brisbane-international-third-round-pegula/106210594</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka and Elena Rybakina continue their 2026 campaigns in emphatic fashion with victories at the Brisbane International.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92ccba7ac40057a455324a9c01d15e3e</guid></item><item><title>Two-week chase ends in dramatic seizure of Russian-flagged oil tanker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/how-the-russia-flagged-marinera-oil-tanker-seizure-unfolded/106208808</link><description>When a US-sanctioned oil tanker originally bound for Venezuela abruptly changed course, it set off a dramatic chase at sea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f9641191277ec55bb68a88279d678a9</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: PM announces antisemitism royal commission after Bondi terror attack — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/live-blog-albanese-antisemitism-royal-commission/106205802</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has announced a royal commission into antisemitism after the Bondi Beach terrorist attack</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94310421a68e882725eeea301656e2d8</guid></item><item><title>Three options the US is considering to take Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/three-options-us-considering-to-take-greenland/106207610</link><description>At least three options have been floated for Donald Trump to achieve his goal of taking Greenland for the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3601b8c080e0918077e50115bc01c245</guid></item><item><title>Self defence or murder? What the videos of the Minnesota ICE shooting show us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/what-happened-in-minnesota-ice-shooting-abc-verify/106209188</link><description>ICE agents shot a woman in Minnesota. The president says it was self-defence while protesters claim it was murder. Here's what the vision shows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9039ec1dfeba5997c2b389a07fab6acf</guid></item><item><title>Who is Virginia Bell, the woman who will head the royal commission into antisemitism?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/virginia-bell-antisemitism-royal-commission/106211026</link><description>Former High Court judge Virginia Bell will lead the inquiry into antisemitism. But who is the new commissioner?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a4ecb2b376b1f353482467cb63650ad</guid></item><item><title>Ashes player ratings: England and Australia report card from 2025-26 Test series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/ashes-england-and-australia-player-report-card-grades-ratings/106208798</link><description>Here are the player ratings from a one-sided Ashes series with a few stand-outs and perhaps more flame-outs across the five Tests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">939d1f0d022317cea88e5225e6a8ace9</guid></item><item><title>New research finds keeping room temperature at 24 degrees or below could reduce sleep stress for older Australians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/study-room-temperature-24-degrees-reduces-sleep-stress-elderly/106210362</link><description>The study by Griffith University in Brisbane finds that a room temperature while sleeping of more than 24 degrees Celsius increases heart rate variability and physiological stress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b774992e996255b6e0f55a92360ad037</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106210068</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69e249fc81f420bec1c7f1dbb652f773</guid></item><item><title>No sightings of Kenneth John Giles 24 hours after shooting near Mullewa in WA's Midwest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/mullewa-shooting-manhunt-continues-kenneth-giles/106209978</link><description>Police have issued a "personal plea" for Kenneth John Giles to turn himself in, almost 24 hours after a shooting in Mullewa.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a30c947e66a941861dbed6d92e1c0c20</guid></item><item><title>What is a pyroCB, a fire-generated thunderstorm?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/what-is-a-pyrocb-a-fire-generated-thunderstorm/106210552</link><description>The fire burning in north-east Victoria near Walwa was so fierce it generated its own weather this afternoon, including a substantial pyrocumulonimbus cloud with lightning and thunder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5efce84e61a4f0c416252768757be9b7</guid></item><item><title>Men face court charged with manslaughter of 66-year-old who died after Hobart CBD altercation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/tas-two-charged-with-manslaughter-after-alleged-mall-assault/106211724</link><description>Two men face court after a 66-year-old man died from injuries police allege were sustained in an assault at a popular Hobart shopping strip.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">276f3082327b8cee2b180d1852a59778</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane couples 'blindsided' as wedding venue closed to make way for Olympic Stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/victoria-park-function-axed-for-olympic-stadium/106211296</link><description>Brisbane's mayor says it "should have been obvious" the venue would close as the stadium at Victoria Park was announced early last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b073a4c7197e38602241de3c77d5422d</guid></item><item><title>Tensions rise in Colombia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/tension-rises-in-colombia/106211572</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dfa6765f3cf91cb16400ecb7601c41b</guid></item><item><title>Police arrest suspects after armed heist at airport believed to be Vanuatu's first organised robbery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/vanuatu-robbery-port-vila-airport/106206412</link><description>A brazen heist at Port Vila International Airport has stunned Vanuatu and become the talk of a nation unused to such overtly public acts of crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c81aa2a1227df3ea9a7c5a1bee55281</guid></item><item><title>Albanese defends leadership after royal commission backflip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/albanese-defends-leadership-after-royal-commission-backflip/106212016</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1757135e9c89bd598c5ac817301661c3</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says US oversight of Venezuela could last for years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/trump-says-us-oversight-of-venezuela-could-last-for-years/106211978</link><description>Donald Trump has said that "only time will tell" how long the United States will maintain oversight of Venezuela.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">009a8a43f1559dbff27c6077658d7fa7</guid></item><item><title>England vice-captain Harry Brook apologises for incident at New Zealand nightclub ahead of Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/harry-brook-scuffle-with-bouncer-before-new-zealand-odi/106212164</link><description>Harry Brook was fined $60,000 and has apologised for bringing "embarrassment" to the English cricket team in a scuffle with a bouncer shortly before the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65a3318f02eab2896e6476d757307460</guid></item><item><title>Rinky Hijikata suffers three-set loss against Giovanni Mpetshi Perricard at Brisbane International</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/hijikata-mpetshi-perricard-brisbane-international-quarter-finals/106212468</link><description>Rinky Hijikata's three-set loss to big-serving Frenchman Giovanni Mpetshi Perricard means there are no Australians left in the Brisbane International singles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56035a169d6797e540a548b6b3663643</guid></item><item><title>On her 44th birthday, Princess Catherine is quietly reshaping royal life after cancer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/princess-catherine-wales-birthday-44-reset-normal-royal-life/106206914</link><description>Catherine turns 44 today as she resets royal life with fewer public appearances, tighter boundaries and a strong emphasis on family life — a choice shaped by loss, illness and the pressure of being next in line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3759ffc377b5207d302e17af450cd6f</guid></item><item><title>Three people missing in Longwood bushfire amid 'catastrophic' fire danger for Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/catastrophic-extreme-bushfire-warning-for-victoria/106211318</link><description>Three people, including a child, are missing after a house was destroyed by the out-of-control Longwood bushfire in central Victoria, according to police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10d03171fbffff94b09273cddafc14a5</guid></item><item><title>Victorians on edge as state experiences first catastrophic bushfire conditions since 2019</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/vic-catastrophic-fire-warning-bushfires-fri-walwa-longwood/106210230</link><description>Catastrophic fire danger warnings are in place across parts of Victoria's north and west today, with two significant fires already burning out of control and soaring temperatures forecast on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b31bf8a8081eb882e61131b27dd456c</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave and fire threat forecast for NSW, Victoria and SA as temperatures nudge all-time record highs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/heatwave-fire-threat-peaking-as-temps-hit-record-high/106211144</link><description>Southern states continue to sweat through one of the most intense heatwaves on record, and for many regions, including Melbourne and Sydney, the hottest weather is still to come.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcf6161ee66e70f17cefb19ef9dab4fa</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, January 9: Hungry Adelaide protesters demand beef in violent riot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/today-in-history-january-9-adelaide-beef-riot-great-depression/106195250</link><description>During the Great Depression, Adelaide residents were getting hungrier and more desperate by the day. Then the state government made a wildly unpopular decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e048fb9b1abfe3f20b4d7d07290cb97d</guid></item><item><title>JD Vance defends Minnesota shooting as self-defence amid immigration crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/minneapolis-shooting-fbi-bca-blocked/106212576</link><description>US Vice-President JD Vance says the shooting was justified and that 37-year-old mother-of-three Renee Nicole Good was a "victim of left-wing ideology".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">937d425141ba4a896aa30c8a33c94d21</guid></item><item><title>Antisemitism royal commission welcome, but some say it was called too late</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/bondi-victim-families-react-to-antisemitism-royal-commission-/106211654</link><description>Community groups that lobbied for a national inquiry into antisemitism back the prime minister's announcement of a royal commission as the NSW premier pledges the NSW government's full cooperation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f5153fa8bcfbade566307a3531a93c</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's comments about Greenland were once seen as a joke. Greenlanders are no longer laughing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/donald-trump-greenland-denmark-nato-comments-worrying-island/106210090</link><description>The United States has a long history of wanting to acquire Greenland, but people living on the island say Donald Trump's latest comments about annexation feel different.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">780d9c1f5e1d18550bf80d207f6c5b10</guid></item><item><title>What landlords are obliged to do to cool your rental as temperatures rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/what-rental-landlords-are-obliged-to-do-to-cool-homes/106209220</link><description>With the nation gripped by a heatwave, renters will be looking at their rights for cooling their homes. Here's what they can do.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3c6800978649b78c60677ea43c2cc27</guid></item><item><title>How the internet reacted to the fifth Ashes Test at the SCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/how-the-internet-reacted-to-the-fifth-ashes-test/106198770</link><description>The internet went wild as Australia dominated with the bat, led by Travis Head and Steve Smith, and England crumbled in the dying embers of the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab73112ebb189dad0b2e311cb6ccdeb6</guid></item><item><title>Solar to the fore as grid sails through heatwave and record demand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/solar-powers-australia-through-heatwave-conditions/106211394</link><description>For so long, the pounding sunshine of an Australian heatwave was the grid's biggest threat. It has now become its greatest asset.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae701b0cb782c015f079002489ef8776</guid></item><item><title>US Senate votes to limit Trump's power to order strikes in Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/senate-votes-to-limit-trump-war-powers/106212508</link><description>The vote in the Republican-controlled chamber still needs to pass the US House, and has virtually no chance of becoming law due to Donald Trump's presidential veto.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a5427cd6d6d5921804e7ab4c06fb178</guid></item><item><title>Australian heatwave live: Firefighters battling multiple out-of-control blazes across Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/fire-weather-heatwave-live-blog-victoria-sa-nsw/106212116</link><description>Victorian and South Australian authorities are battling "catastrophic" and "extreme" fire conditions as Australia continues to swelter through a heatwave. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcbd0376d084f9e59fa8783cce3c308c</guid></item><item><title>Insect enthusiasts helping researchers keep an eye on bug populations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/qld-bug-hunt-insects-photos-research-citizen-scientists/106171252</link><description>Queensland insect enthusiasts are snapping photos of their backyard bugs to help researchers monitor native and invasive species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4f7610e986e7cd15889efebe22c7a82</guid></item><item><title>Kings Forest Estate finally for sale after land-banking saga spanning five decades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/kings-forest-for-sale-after-land-banking-saga/106207042</link><description>More than 30 years after the land was rezoned to allow residential development, blocks in the Kings Forest Estate are finally on the market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17e85e361bd0277f36a57fda22dc2c24</guid></item><item><title>Locals, summer tourists swelter through heatwave in South Australia's Riverland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/sa-riverland-heatwave-hot-weather-peak-tourist-season/106205990</link><description>South Australia's Riverland will swelter through yet another day in the mid-to-high 40s on Friday and will have to wait until the weekend for a reprieve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">156f32643cce0f3fd5034709d9ff285a</guid></item><item><title>'High chance' of a tropical cyclone forming off Queensland's north-east coast bringing heavy rainfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/tropical-low-to-hit-far-north-queensland-late-friday/106211562</link><description>A tropical low off the Coral Coast could have the potential to become a tropical cyclone over the weekend, as residents across the far-north prepare for heavy rainfall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c9c9b6e59e8b4ac8d3a9d52215e0ad6</guid></item><item><title>Maya Joint gets Ash Barty's backing with teenager's Australian Open milestone confirmed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/joint-gets-barty-s-backing-ahead-of-aus-open-seeding/106212664</link><description>Teenage star Maya Joint will be the first home women's seed at the Australian Open since former world number one Ash Barty broke a 44-year title drought in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54395c014b677d61b32bba59eed839b6</guid></item><item><title>RBA plays the long game on inflation, so an interest rate rise could still be some way off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/rba-deputy-governor-andrew-hauser-interest-rates-inflation-janda/106210128</link><description>The Reserve Bank says inflation is "too high", but that doesn't mean it will necessarily rush to raise interest rates next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">822c83de4d34fdbaba8bbaad3b53d3a5</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan and foreign prisoners to be released following seizure of Nicolás Maduro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/venezuela-prisoners-to-be-freed-after-us-seizure-of-maduro/106212566</link><description>The president of the country's parliament says that Venezuelan and foreign prisoners will be released in the coming hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">162dbf5e6813226eb49bca2ac138a569</guid></item><item><title>Matildas and Arsenal star Kyra Cooney-Cross returns home in wake of mother's cancer diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/matildas-star-cooney-cross-returns-home-to-face-family-tragedy/106212710</link><description>Arsenal's Australia international Kyra Cooney-Cross flies back to Australia to be with her mother, who has been diagnosed with stage 4 cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">022d27429b844ff00f76299de5f2a1ab</guid></item><item><title>Dubbo woman Molly Croft raises $2 million after battling cancer twice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/molly-croft-raises-2m-and-helps-others-find-their-rainbow/106095998</link><description>This 19-year-old from western NSW, who has been diagnosed with cancer twice, is now helping others "find their rainbow".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7680560ded4679aff964bf9d7446d06</guid></item><item><title>NT pokies clubs report member perks, lavish upgrades as 'community' benefits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/nt-pokies-community-contributions-member-perks-renovations-foi/106084120</link><description>Previously secret documents released under Freedom of Information laws have revealed how the Northern Territory's pokies clubs' community contributions are really being spent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b956be26d539f0a576209395e5c2ce80</guid></item><item><title>Rio Tinto stock tumbles on Glencore merger talks, dragging down ASX — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/asx-markets-business-live-news-jan-2025-9/106212732</link><description>Glencore has confirmed media speculation that the company is back in merger talks with Rio Tinto. Follow updates live on our business and finance blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35335a243eed68ad82bd29a3257dc72c</guid></item><item><title>Top tips for learning a musical instrument or taking up singing at any age</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/top-tips-for-learning-a-musical-instrument-or-taking-up-singing/106206612</link><description>You can pick up an instrument or learn to sing at any age. Here are some helpful tips from experts and ABC Classic audience members to get you started.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b6a800c527cc85e14d26b021f88d536</guid></item><item><title>Community rushes to help victims of Appin crash that left 17-year-old dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/appin-fatal-crash/106212740</link><description>The 17-year-old was killed and other passengers were seriously injured when a ute and sedan collided on a notorious road in Appin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a68ddc45ab11c561ca72d5db7a428e6</guid></item><item><title>Assault-accused MP Nick McBride says home detention makes him 'more wedded' to electorate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/sa-assault-accused-mcbride-speaks-about-home-detention/106211188</link><description>South Australian MP Nick McBride, who has been charged with aggravated assault, says home detention will make him "more focused" on his electorate ahead of the SA election in March.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02f3f4438b200f30196cb731428b4151</guid></item><item><title>Inside Nicolás Maduro's complex network of alleged drug traffickers wanted by the US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/us-nicolas-maduro-indictment-associates-list/106209272</link><description>The deposed Venezuelan president allegedly oversaw a network of associates to facilitate the flow of illegal drugs into the US, aided by false passports, a guerilla training school, jets and grenade launchers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7659a5da2c9963426ef0ce8943ce144d</guid></item><item><title>Airport lost luggage auctions raise thousands of dollars for charity every year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/airport-lost-luggage-auctions/106078890</link><description>From tablets, headphones and laptops to prams, vacuum cleaners and even a prosthetic leg — these are the items being left behind each year at major airports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79e782929d619129a68f7b9ecd8c8977</guid></item><item><title>Man in anaphylactic shock on Virgin flight to WA's Pilbara saved by crew, another passenger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/selfless-act-saves-man-anaphylactic-shock-on-wa-virgin-flight/106209770</link><description>Pilbara resident Andrew Rawle found himself 30,000 feet in the air, unable to breathe due to anaphylactic shock, but was saved by the crew and the selfless act of another passenger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07f2dd24254e8cf0a23a06e972a26c2e</guid></item><item><title>Total fire ban to begin in the ACT for the first time in six years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/total-fire-ban-heatwave-declared-act/106212734</link><description>For the first time since the Black Summer bushfires, a total fire ban will be imposed in the ACT. The ban will be in place for the duration of Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91a761ebca8181ace8fef1f22f568f31</guid></item><item><title>Angela Jones's history-making ride from country upbringing to top of Queensland's jockey ranks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/angela-jones-journey-to-becoming-number-one-jockey-in-queensland/106158424</link><description>Angela Jones became the number one jockey in Queensland in 2025. Now, the determined young woman, who grew up on a central Queensland cattle farm, wants Group 1 glory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61a9fab622749cc9f453903462200fc3</guid></item><item><title>How The Pitt lured ER star Noah Wyle back into the emergency department</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/the-pitt-noah-wyle-er-r-scott-gemmill-john-wells/106118716</link><description>ER launched Noah Wyle's career in 1994. Thirty years later he's back in the emergency room — and scooping awards season — as Dr Robby in The Pitt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93a195925d2de69fb82fd3317eb6f950</guid></item><item><title>US border agent shoots and wounds two people in Portland, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/us-federal-agents-shot-two-people-in-portland-police-say/106213350</link><description>US Border Patrol agents were conducting a vehicle stop in Portland when the driver "weaponised" the vehicle before an officer "fired a defensive shot", according to the Department of Homeland Security.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b123f84025556780f78f3572d5654867</guid></item><item><title>NetBlocks reports internet blackout imposed in Iran amid nationwide protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/internet-blackout-imposed-in-iran-amid-nationwide-protests/106213246</link><description>Human rights groups say more than 40 people have been killed in protest-related violence since last month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd286bff3887cc0397c214ae6c0c3596</guid></item><item><title>Arsenal's Gabriel Martinelli apologises for 'disgraceful' act towards injured Liverpool player Conor Bradley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/martinelli-disgraceful-act-towards-injured-liverpool-player/106213400</link><description>Arsenal winger Gabriel Martinelli has apologised for shoving Liverpool's Conor Bradley, who was down with a serious knee injury, off the pitch during their Premier League clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">249ee65a474fdfd5395e9aa04686c802</guid></item><item><title>Rio Tinto in merger talks with Glencore, takeover could create world's biggest miner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/rio-tinto-in-talks-to-take-over-glencore-mega-miner-merger/106213252</link><description>Rio Tinto and Glencore are in takeover talks that could potentially lead to a combined mega-miner worth more than $US200 billion. Analysts are questioning whether Rio will be interested in Glencore's coal assets, having sold off its own in 2018.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">045687aff3f78cbc211b52c08acfbb59</guid></item><item><title>Track temperatures live as southern states bake in heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/heat-tracker/106213390</link><description>Use our tracker to keep an eye on temperatures as a heatwave moves through the southern states.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6adc314883b18afe1a12ca120ba8523</guid></item><item><title>Diana Camacaro fled Venezuela when a friend close to Nicolás Maduro's regime texted her she was on a list to be arrested</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/nicolas-maduros-regime-came-for-these-women-who-fled-to-colombia/106207412</link><description>When a Telegram message landed on her phone, Diana knew she had to flee Venezuela. It was from someone close to Nicolás Maduro, and she says she would have been jailed, or worse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c98ade3c4b3047c53890d5f90ef7983</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios not seeking Australian Open wildcard, saying he is 'not quite ready' for grand slam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/kyrgios-says-he-will-not-be-seeking-an-aus-open-wildcard/106213610</link><description>Returning from injury, Nick Kyrgios has spoken with Australian Open organisers and made the call not to use a wildcard to play singles this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c307000e133452ec9eef5fba817b560</guid></item><item><title>What we know about Australian Teagan Croft who will play Rapunzel in Disney's Tangled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/teagan-croft-to-play-rapunzel-in-disney-live-action-tangled/106213672</link><description>Australian actress Teagan Croft will take on the lead role of Rapunzel in Disney's Tangled. The 21-year-old will star alongside Milo Manheim in the live-action remake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e23c5ae58eb08fde143d918add4210f3</guid></item><item><title>The Bondi royal commission will be a long-term test of Albanese's leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/bondi-royal-commission-test-albanese-leadership/106213854</link><description>The prime minister's critics feel he failed to meet the moment in the immediate aftermath of the Bondi attack, but with the royal commission he has a chance to get it right.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">916f58de1d1e77dad7bbbe9ffc85cf2e</guid></item><item><title>Australia's population forecast to reach 28 million in 2026 despite fall in overseas migrants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/australias-population-to-reach-28-million-in-2026/106213420</link><description>Australia's population is forecast to reach 28 million people in 2026 despite an easing of overseas arrivals following the post-COVID-19 migration peak.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f16364694bdcb7d5d4f01791e0da9534</guid></item><item><title>Total fire ban as extreme fire weather predicted for parts of eastern Tasmania this weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/total-fire-ban-east-coast-tasmania-danger/106213058</link><description>A total fire ban is in place for parts of Tasmania from Saturday, due to extreme fire weather predicted for the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0a5b1a9a096c99d5594002934f18fd4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump pulls US out of dozens of international organisations on environment and security</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/us-withdrawal-trump-united-nations-organisations/106210134</link><description>Protecting women and children, halting climate change and preventing acts of terrorism — these are the goals the White House now says go against America's goals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bb7426e5eb9ca8d42907119842b9ba5</guid></item><item><title>Police vision shows a person being rescued from a submerged car during severe flooding in Queensland.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/submerged-car-helicopter-rescue/106211994</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">747e3a9122f8203e5874113c7cdfd7f0</guid></item><item><title>Police urge drivers not to enter Queensland floodwaters and risk life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/police-ask-drivers-not-to-enter-queensland-floodwaters-risk-life/106210610</link><description>Authorities hope fines will deter motorists from driving into flooded waters, after nearly half-a-dozen vehicles are stranded in two weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c347a6c5dac263fc5c03174043fc97e2</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian author seeks to be reinstated to Adelaide Writers' Week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/sa-palestinian-author-calls-for-apology-over-writers-week-axing/106212878</link><description>Palestinian author Randa Abdel-Fattah has called for her appearance at Adelaide Writers' Week to be reinstated after it was axed, but SA's Premier has continued to back the decision, as dozens of authors cancel their appearances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bc84d20ac7f6de4042f859ef7f45602</guid></item><item><title>Grass fire burning in Wagga Wagga's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/grass-fire-burning-in-wagga-wagga-s-north/106214436</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b8856016b4a7c28344bcad2ae7feab4</guid></item><item><title>Surge in heat-related illness as temperatures continue to soar across south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/heat-illness-emergency-presentations-surge-heatwave/106213074</link><description>Emergency departments, medical centres and first responders are dealing with a surge in heat-related illness across Australia's south-east as temperatures soar to near record levels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b871b12491bc4d2dc8eaf82577c10a1</guid></item><item><title>Helicopter vision shows scale of the Longwood fire.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/longwood-aerials-bushfire/106214662</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efd17a170f35c46089275f89afd51318</guid></item><item><title>Zone RV director accused of insolvent trading as early as 2023</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/zone-rv-insolvent-trading-creditors-report/106206468</link><description>Administrators of the collapsed luxury caravan manufacturer have threatened to sue David Biggar, whose company owes customers millions of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b78bc029fd01690b692b25691ea15cac</guid></item><item><title>Senior SA government officials reject claims of political interference into algal bloom causes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/sa-department-heads-reject-interference-claims-in-algal-bloom/106213376</link><description>Four of the most senior public servants working on South Australia's algal bloom have rejected allegations that departmental staff had been instructed not to investigate the cause of the ecological disaster until after March's state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">870976f9925aebd0a33e7f1bc1020da3</guid></item><item><title>Violence against state school teachers and staff nearly quadruples in three years, new data shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/queensland-state-school-violence-against-teachers-quadruples/106214512</link><description>The data, tabled in Queensland Parliament, showed there were 20,833 occupational violence and aggression incidents reported by school-based employees last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">714d0649ede605b3bd45722cd4b4a92f</guid></item><item><title>Russia says it has fired its Oreshnik hypersonic missile at Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/russia-says-it-hit-ukraine-with-oreshnik-hypersonic-missile/106214842</link><description>Russia's defence ministry says it has carried out a massive overnight strike on energy facilities and drone manufacturing sites in the Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a8f4739db2dad29330326f7b3195830</guid></item><item><title>Family, friends pay tribute to Tasmanian man who died following alleged Hobart CBD altercation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/tas-tributes-flow-ian-cousens-after-alleged-hobart-cbd-assault/106214484</link><description>A 66-year-old Tasmanian man who died after an alleged altercation in Hobart's CBD on Tuesday night has been remembered by those who knew him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2311462f50416f9823fa8b007a671b7b</guid></item><item><title>Ruffy residents describe devastation wrought by central Victoria's Longwood bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/ruffy-residents-describe-devastation-after-longwood-bushfire/106214024</link><description>During winter the trees and hills surrounding the small hamlet of Ruffy are beautiful and green, but now it has been "decimated" by an out-of-control bushfire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91f86b02b839c5bc83a16621b222b9da</guid></item><item><title>NSW premier 'cannot remember' fundraiser at centre of undeclared donation allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/nsw-chris-minns-responds-to-undeclared-donation-allegations/106213922</link><description>Premier Chris Minns did not dispute a report that 200 people attended a fundraiser dinner, but could not recall how an event of that size raised only about $6,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd496ac70a1c6e73ae9ad81456624a2d</guid></item><item><title>Police say alleged Mullewa shooter Kenneth Giles was not a licensed firearms owner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/kenneth-john-giles-mullewa-manhunt-police-update/106211998</link><description>Police say Kenneth Giles is not a licensed firearms holder, as the search for the 58-year-old continues across hundreds of thousands of kilometres of country WA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41f19560ddd43979eeb6e959364495f0</guid></item><item><title>ACT records first road fatality of 2026 after two-vehicle crash on Monaro Highway near Royalla</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/act-man-dies-two-vehicle-crash-royalla-first-road-fatality-2026/106215054</link><description>A 25-year-old man has died after a crash between a car and a truck on the Monaro Highway, south of Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a85af37e0be34a1e48e13f6d94754256</guid></item><item><title>RFS vision of Gobbagombalin fire in Wagga Wagga's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/rfs-vision-of-gobbagombalin-fire/106215228</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0a5135e6db0f8b398fcd0a6e8be1edc</guid></item><item><title>Accused scam kingpin Chen Zhi arrives in China after extradition from Cambodia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/accused-scam-kingpin-chen-zhi-extradited-china-cambodia/106213664</link><description>Accused scam boss Chen Zhi is extradited to China from Cambodia after being indicted by the United States over an alleged multi-billion-dollar fraud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">648a0ad4bdb7733943e6779b95d8d539</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/fins-financefri-090126/106215310</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8160784fdd2d14e6759eba9d94f19c14</guid></item></channel></rss>