<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 09:45:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Australian PGA Championships round one cut short by storms, with Spain's Sebastian Garcia in the lead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/early-ace-as-big-guns-set-australian-pga-pace-in-brisbane/106074332</link><description>In-form Spaniard Sebastian Garcia shoots three strokes clear of a big-name leaderboard before Brisbane's storms halt his first-round charge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddf655b2e4ac071eda0d28e0fccbc474</guid></item><item><title>Mental health defence flagged in trial of son accused of killing father with a crowbar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/milenko-snjegota-farmborough-heights-murder-trial/106074074</link><description>A NSW court is told heard Milenko Snjegota had limited capacity for reason when he allegedly murdered his 74-year-old father in their home near Wollongong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc59c7539bdb3cb0f392152e78c697db</guid></item><item><title>Dead fish, foam seen on metro beaches despite overall low Karenia algal levels</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/foam-and-dead-fish-seen-on-adelaide-beaches/106058862</link><description>Authorities say metropolitan testing shows Karenia algal levels remain low compared with last month, despite thick foam and fish deaths seen on some beaches in recent days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5642130694d61a2e34e5915ea6b79ecf</guid></item><item><title>With a deal on Australia's environmental laws, Murray Watt has cemented his reputation as a 'fixer'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/environmental-laws-deal-watt-a-fixer-greens-negotiations/106073524</link><description>In his deal with the Greens, Environment Minister Murray Watt has just scraped off one of the biggest barnacles clinging to parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">804e194f7bdde600f65fda9cfda2ac70</guid></item><item><title>Former Townsville mayor lied about his military service, health issues and education, watchdog finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/troy-thompson-report/106051960</link><description>The Queensland Crime and Corruption Commission finds no evidence to back Troy Thompson's claims that he served in the SAS, had cancer and epilepsy, and two university degrees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b23e7f79a041125a30006f27d7f3e4cf</guid></item><item><title>Woman sentenced over Willetton hit-and-run crash that injured schoolgirl Alexis Lloyd</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/perth-hit-and-run-driver-tahira-shaheen-sentenced/106074546</link><description>A 49-year-old L-plater who kept driving after hitting a 12-year-old as she walked to school in suburban Perth, causing serious injuries, is jailed for 16 months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ece4d8bc641987441319504bb45a62b</guid></item><item><title>Neuropsychologist in 'emphatic' disagreement over whether alleged murderer had substantial mental impairment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/brendan-kantilla-murder-trial-nt-supreme-court-neuropsychologist/106073702</link><description>A neuropsychologist tells the court an NT man accused of murdering an international student was not suffering from a substantial mental impairment at the time of the alleged crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bde41a5b3ead7c1c7c08d7599b187ea</guid></item><item><title>Cameron Reginald Welsh handed extra jail time for bashing prison guards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/man-who-bashed-prison-guards-to-serve-more-jail-time/106058328</link><description>A NSW inmate who bashed four prison guards will serve extra jail time, after a judge quashed his non-custodial term on appeal, calling it "an affront to the administration of justice".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">867eb3c3dca1a5e8302b8ba422e4a017</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106075062</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b37aa8afb73f4cf1a95b7336a26a230c</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong fire kills at least 83, hundreds still missing as firefighters continue to battle blaze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/hong-kong-apartment-fire-kills-dozens-hundreds-missing/106074662</link><description>Authorities say the apartment complex blaze may have been caused by a "grossly negligent" construction firm using unsafe materials. Three men have been arrested on suspicion of manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbacd4bd18dc0d632ac34672c376e531</guid></item><item><title>Correspondent James Oaten in Hong Kong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/correspondent-james-oaten-in-hong-kong/106075604</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f52cac8cd68669593c249840062f438e</guid></item><item><title>Student paramedic wins battle with Ambulance Victoria over beard policy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/ambulance-victoria-mask-beards-ppe/106072778</link><description>A student paramedic who accused Ambulance Victoria of discrimination on the grounds of race and religion is "ecstatic" to have won his battle to allow cultural beards on the job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8603b192af88be50f617e729e0a3400a</guid></item><item><title>Patrick Lee Brown sentenced to three years in prison over 'inexcusable' Tasmanian car chases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/patrick-lee-brown-sentenced-police-chases-launceston-hobart/106074964</link><description>During sentencing, a Supreme Court Justice told Patrick Lee Brown he "completely disregarded the safety of anyone else" during two different police pursuits, including one in a stolen rental truck with blown-out tyres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f2d03e954f98247d476033a91f412b9</guid></item><item><title>Frozen rewrote the Disney princess narrative — and 12 years later, it's still relevant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/frozen-movie-elsa-anna-disney-princess-narrative/106028062</link><description>It wasn't just a box office success — Frozen introduced a new type of Disney princess: one who was strong, flawed and uninterested in romance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a85819a41d9e434e1858a6a2f98a85c8</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong residents devastated by mega blaze engulfing blocks of flats in Tai Po district</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/hong-kong-fire-tai-po-district-devastates-local-residents/106058690</link><description>Locals are in shock after fire destroyed apartment blocks home to thousands of people, as questions remain about the suitability of building materials and a lack of fire alarms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e120ab685c2b233ab8699cf50790bf4</guid></item><item><title>Social media ban implementation will 'vary' across platforms, eSafety commissioner warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/social-media-ban-implementation-to-vary-across-platforms/106075376</link><description>Not all Australians aged under 16 will "magically disappear overnight" from social media, the nation's online safety regulator says, amid a legal challenge to pause the start of the federal government's ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4031126c5650441d0b4cced144d50d67</guid></item><item><title>The flashpoints leading the US and Venezuela to the brink of a conflict decades in the making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/us-venezuela-tension-flashpoints-and-history-explained/106037756</link><description>Tensions between Donald Trump and Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro Moros have been escalating after months of launching lethal air strikes on vessels accused of shipping deadly drugs north to the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e05d0863ab82c615187bd5305ff85bb7</guid></item><item><title>Calls for states to change alcohol laws ahead of women’s ministers meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/alcohol-delivery-violence-against-women-children-ministers/106075170</link><description>A major review into preventing violence against women and children called for changes to immediate alcohol home delivery</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75de4bdd1d698ed274797ef8f19599cc</guid></item><item><title>Second storm of the year pushes tiny town of Nevertire to its limit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/storm-damage-onslaught-batters-rural-town-nevertire/106072008</link><description>A storm that hit a tiny rural NSW town, damaging one in 10 homes, is psychologically draining for residents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ee59ac88a5c7a76bc45eea502bcb1eb</guid></item><item><title>Perth Scorchers defeat Melbourne Renegades by four wickets in WBBL clash at Junction Oval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/perth-scorchers-defeat-melbourne-renegades-four-wickets-wbbl/106076168</link><description>Perth have survived a dramatic collapse to beat the Melbourne Renegades by four wickets, denying the Renegades a share of top spot on the WBBL ladder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">806f5cf45451ad7a88e7ea9dbbb0fec6</guid></item><item><title>One of Hong Kong's deadliest fires engulfed multiple high-rise towers in just hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/how-the-hong-kong-fire-unfolded-tai-po-district/106058300</link><description>Hong Kong's deadliest fire in decades tore through a group of high-rise residential towers in a densely packed housing estate, causing major issues for firefighters. This is how the catastrophe unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">795d89f719273c8195928d87916bc58e</guid></item><item><title>Greens out-step flat-footed Liberals on crucial environmental deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/labor-greens-deal-murray-watt-liberals-bowen-chalmers/106045646</link><description>The environmental deal is a major win for a government whose critics on the left are calling for it to be more reformist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbd419f5416a826abe1d7016a6c2b855</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri dismisses helping McLaren teammate Lando Norris win F1 drivers' championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/oscar-piastri-will-not-help-lando-norris-win-f1-title-in-qatar/106076210</link><description>Oscar Piastri says McLaren raised the prospect of the Australian helping his teammate Lando Norris win the Formula 1 world championship, but it was rejected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3ec980521382ffb12e9d33768384b86</guid></item><item><title>Infrastructure installed to probe Coorong storm surges and groundwater impacts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/coorong-murray-research-for-future-erosion-rising-sea-levels-sa/106013728</link><description>Infrastructure to monitor the impact of rising sea levels and storm surges on the Coorong in South Australia has been installed along the thin strip of coastline between Goolwa Beach and the lagoons of the Ramsar-listed wetland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d8134b101b12c53dff3475c445f3957</guid></item><item><title>Police arrest more people over violence at Melbourne CBD rally in October</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/vic-police-melbourne-protest-violence-arrests/106076166</link><description>Two men have been charged with assaulting police at a rally in Melbourne's CBD in October. The arrests come as police prepare for another demonstration in the city on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d1293f05bf4572cdf4a2341457f5437</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: PM declares Labor-Greens deal a 'yesalition' as environment bill passes — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/federal-politics-live-nov-28/106076192</link><description>The federal government's overhauled national environment laws have passed parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40815d49c28b138ff1c5c8d7407b4fdf</guid></item><item><title>Cool weather sets cherry crops 'weeks' behind schedule in lead-up to Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/cold-weather-cherry-delay-crops-fruit-victoria/106059072</link><description>The latest casualty in a year of delayed crops is the cherry, with cold weather in some growing regions setting the festive favourite "weeks" behind schedule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3612aa2f5f80c3dc5098162be5c662b1</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong residents react to deadly apartment block fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/hong-kong-residents-react-to-deadly-apartment-block-fire-/106076340</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7eec80d7d00058122d9124bcbb3c8d5</guid></item><item><title>Indian cricket star Deepti Sharma fetches highest WPL price, Australia captain Alyssa Healy unsold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/wpl-cricket-record-auction-price-alyssa-healy-unsold/106076270</link><description>All-rounder Deepti Sharma fetched the highest price at the Women's Premier League (WPL) auction, while Australia captain Alyssa Healy, one of the marquee players up for grabs, went unsold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f71128bee52e51ebbd4cda7fbc61351</guid></item><item><title>How a breakdown in the search for a boat named Margaret led to adventure on the Birdsville Track</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/inland-barge-reconnects-outback/106045962</link><description>The ABC's Landline crew discovers extreme kindness with a can-do attitude after a mechanical breakdown in South Australia's outback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3900ff291da27d0cba5eb67d9f84795e</guid></item><item><title>Former WA police officer Kaine Burgess relives the night his patrol car was rammed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/retired-police-officer-shares-harrowing-story/106011590</link><description>More than two years on from a serious crash that saw him medically retired, a former police officer says he can still hear the screech of tyres before the deafening bang of a car slamming into his police wagon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ee39cf3b5fdb5213f314ddcdd462d23</guid></item><item><title>'Brumby Bill' protecting heritage value of wild horses to be scrapped in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/nsw-upper-house-vote-scrap-brumby-bill/105916360</link><description>A widely criticised bill recognising the heritage value of wild horses in Kosciuszko National Park will be scrapped in a move celebrated by the Invasive Species Council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">218f14fa35313423c0ae0caa3984a13b</guid></item><item><title>Estella brings strength and resilience to her family as she navigates life with disability in remote NT</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/estella-jones-tennant-creek-fighting-spirit-sam-cameron-idpwd/106024834</link><description>Nineteen-year-old Estella Jones lives with a disability in her hometown of Tennant Creek, where she loves baking brownies, singing karaoke and spending time with good friends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a69782b87662c716e55f95068ba1a663</guid></item><item><title>Fuzzy Zoeller, Masters and US Open champion, dies aged 74</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/fuzzy-zoeller-masters-and-us-open-champion-dies-aged-74/106076532</link><description>Fuzzy Zoeller, a two-time major champion and one of golf's most gregarious characters whose career was tainted by a racially insensitive joke about Tiger Woods, has died aged 74.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecc335a023b9a3cf1ee94ed8107808ec</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners in WA's north challenge state over fast-tracking mining exploration approvals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/wa-challenged-over-fast-tracking-mining-exploration-approvals/106055862</link><description>Traditional owners in WA's north launch legal action against the state government claiming it is fast-tracking mining and exploration projects using "expedited procedure" approvals at cultural expense.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1acd9b4007bcc42af41bfabb5e31199e</guid></item><item><title>Inquest concludes into death of SA boatie Tony Higgins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/inquest-into-death-of-anthony-higgins-ends/106074014</link><description>A coroner has found Anthony Higgins, who went missing in 2020 sparking the largest and most expensive marine search in South Australian waters, died two weeks later when he went missing again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61223a88fc3bf783740e8e43e1bf7a69</guid></item><item><title>Common antidepressant helps reduce some men's domestic violence, ReINVEST trial finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/reinvest-clinical-trial-anti-depressant-reduce-domestic-violence/105999382</link><description>The findings are significant not just because of how much the trial reduced domestic violence, but because only a few years ago it drew fierce criticism from women's advocates and politicians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5ae82aa88fb1df7aebdb637f7dac70e</guid></item><item><title>Benedict Bryant found guilty of dangerous driving causing the death of Jai Kalani Wright</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/nsw-benedict-bryant-verdict-jai-wright-death/106075564</link><description>Benedict Bryant had pleaded not guilty to dangerous driving occasioning death over the crash in inner Sydney in February 2022, which killed Jai Wright.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7851b2e4abcbdfd81ad9a630d7761b1f</guid></item><item><title>Christmas prawns could be more expensive as wild-caught Australian seafood stocks drop off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/prawns-mackerel-crabs-barramundi-christmas-seafood-prices-high/106058324</link><description>Wild-caught Aussie prawn fishers are reporting a tough catch season. Here's what you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38c830975e652eab6b006f6847ad8e55</guid></item><item><title>Award-winning regional pharmacist says relationship with patients is 'unique'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/pharmacist-award-ouyen-regional-communities-rural-healthcare/105999812</link><description>A north-west Victorian pharmacist is being celebrated for his contribution to his local community after winning an award for going the "extra mile".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11825fa9764b4ae42f7505f1fb4240e6</guid></item><item><title>Super Netball could grow to 10 teams as Netball Australia invites licence bids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/super-netball-could-grow-to-10-teams-by-2027/106077068</link><description>Super Netball could have two additional teams by 2027, with Netball Australia calling for expressions of interest to expand the competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f51d1aadcd45af0382e9a8ea5524b8e</guid></item><item><title>What time is the 2025 AFLW grand final? All you need to know as Brisbane and North Melbourne clash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/aflw-grand-final-2025-what-time-does-the-game-start/106049752</link><description>Wondering what time the AFLW grand final starts and how you can watch it live? We've got you covered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c52c36fdd58c5fcf88e25fe664fef0a</guid></item><item><title>Rare West Australian seaweed scrapbooks provide glimpse into history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/wa-seaweed-scrapbooks-glimpse-into-history/106052420</link><description>The State Library of WA is running an appeal to save a set of seaweed scrapbooks made nearly 100 years ago by a renowned Kalgoorlie-born naturalist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf4174762be5bbe41b633305d0598ec1</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong building fire prompts serious questions about construction safety</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/hong-kong-fires-prompt-questions-about-construction-safety/106074568</link><description>Just months ago, Hong Kong leaders were dismissing calls for a total ban on bamboo scaffolding on construction sites. Now they are facing one of the region's worst building-fire catastrophes, and anger is growing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c1eb75c0809317b5e5c2b262e0cf8c6</guid></item><item><title>Why the banking regulator is targeting property investors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/why-the-banking-regulator-is-targeting-property-investors/106074360</link><description>It's been called a bubble for more than 15 years but the great Aussie housing price boom has barely skipped a beat, as regulators eye the threat of risky loans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ca5ec2b583890693afd566c1fef922f</guid></item><item><title>Victorian regulator imposes conditions on Monash IVF after embryo bungles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/monash-ivf-victorian-health-regulator-conditions/106077192</link><description>Monash IVF has been ordered to be more rigorous when checking the biological origin of embryos to avoid more mix-ups, in order to stay registered in Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">533e38b17ff79f4b0fa25b439eeb33a4</guid></item><item><title>Jane Edmanson hangs up her Gardening Australia hat, reflects on labour of love behind show's success</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/jane-edmanson-gardening-australia-retires/106027658</link><description>As Gardening Australia's longest-serving presenter, Jane Edmanson says farewell and shares the secrets behind the success of Australia’s favourite gardening program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">281e322ce0bc8aaface52c810fbad18a</guid></item><item><title>French prisoners escape jail using saw and bedsheets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/french-prisoners-use-saws-and-bed-sheets-to-escape-jail/106077074</link><description>The fugitives broke out of the prison in the eastern city of Dijon in the early hours of Thrusday, local time, and 100 police officers are on their trail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44771861ad99da99531611f0f5fed7b0</guid></item><item><title>Crime scenes declared in Mackay as search continues for Wayne Pedro Morseu</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/suspicious-disappearance-wayne-pedro-morseu/106077476</link><description>Wayne Pedro Morseu was reported missing on November 10, with police now upgrading his disappearance to suspicious.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0450dd9c855f793a17e6942da2790745</guid></item><item><title>F1 Qatar start time, how to watch grand prix, and drivers' championship standings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/f1-qatar-grand-prix-start-time-how-to-watch-driver-standings/105995172</link><description>Lando Norris has match point heading into the penultimate weekend of the Formula 1 season, with the British driver having one hand on a maiden drivers' championship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cf99e225205d22e6b2cdd4aec07317d</guid></item><item><title>Doctors and nurses claim ramping protocol gives ambulance patients priority access to ED, but paramedics disagree</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/tasmania-ambulance-ramping-protocol-emergency-department-nurse/106018196</link><description>Medical experts fear sick or injured Tasmanians who make their own way to emergency departments wait longer than others, due to pressures to fast-track ambulance patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2cbf4fa3c30c15c90451339cafc4607</guid></item><item><title>Dairy 'disrupter' wins science award for inventing spreadable butter in 1970s</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/farmer-who-invented-spreadable-butter-in-70s-wins-science-award/106058726</link><description>An 86-year-old farmer claims this year's Dairy Science Award for inventing spreadable butter, by mixing oils with cultured cream at a time when it was illegal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57efc9add8623d8b897b7403389e53a3</guid></item><item><title>Third renewable energy company discovers asbestos in wind farm turbine lifts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/call-for-border-force-review-asbestos-in-imported-products/106076286</link><description>An anti-asbestos advocate wants a review of import supply chains after a third renewable energy company confirmed the discovery of asbestos in wind farm turbine lifts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d7f9c928f6c8b8a0952caa7dd643ca8</guid></item><item><title>Australia names unchanged squad for second Ashes Test, with captain Pat Cummins still out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/pat-cummins-australia-second-ashes-test-england/106076408</link><description>Australia will go into the second Ashes Test against England in Brisbane next week with an unchanged line-up, meaning there is no place for captain Pat Cummins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">998b1e72e6fbe80fcf0b62145af7bc54</guid></item><item><title>Hundred of prison staff ride from Sydney to Goulburn to honour mates who have died</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/prison-officers-ride-sydney-to-goulburn/106072412</link><description>A man whose correctional officer wife was "fair dinkum about helping people" leads more than 300 prison staff on a ride honouring the lives of colleagues who have died in New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90dfab382119e2eeb9847de8c2d0a148</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's education department and RSB Travel charged over child's attempt to drink engine coolant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/education-department-bus-company-engine-coolant-charges/106077516</link><description>Tasmania's education department and a bus company have both appeared in court after a child with a disability was allegedly left unattended on a bus with access to a bottle of engine coolant in a plastic water bottle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a384e06dbe017543ba08056058f5cb2f</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Travel Management embroiled in overcharging scandal potentially worth more than $100 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/corporate-travel-management-overcharging-scandal-100-million/106077806</link><description>Corporate Travel Management helps arrange travel bookings for clients ranging from Wesfarmers to the Australian government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b6d5e0f6a21ec3ecdc711385bed0e1a</guid></item><item><title>Whadjuk Aboriginal Corporation to oversee Rottnest Island cultural services</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/whadjuk-aboriginal-corporation-rottnest-cultural-services-/106078776</link><description>A strife-torn Aboriginal corporation crucial to heritage approvals across Perth wins a contract to oversee cultural services on Rottnest Island, Wadjemup, one of Western Australia's premier tourism destinations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1ba915a0f3aa07e41791c03b661320f</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos coach Darren Crocker opens up on difficult Mia King selection call ahead of AFLW grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/aflw-grand-final-darren-crocker-mia-king-kangaroos-selection/106078850</link><description>North Melbourne coach Darren Crocker says telling Mia King she isn't going to play in the AFLW grand final is "one of the harder conversations" he's had to have.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13aae557b26efb85a64e42a9c4739658</guid></item><item><title>Victims' families of Westfield Bondi Junction attack grateful for inquest but want 'reforms'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/bondi-westfield-stabbing-victims-families-want-reform-inquest/106076576</link><description>A lawyer representing one of the bereaved families took aim at the owner and operator of Westfield, saying they were "extremely disappointed".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0403311f0e2782dcdcf3c2a15bebebe1</guid></item><item><title>A crystal Fabergé egg is expected to sell for more than $40 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/crystal-faberg%C3%A9-egg-expected-to-sell-for-more-than-40-million/106078696</link><description>A rare crystal and diamond Fabergé egg is heading to auction with a price estimate of more than $40 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6099723b7ff7cfb11af19db108b58054</guid></item><item><title>Preparing my garden for time away in summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/preparing-my-garden-for-time-away-in-summer/106051574</link><description>Leaving my garden in the heat of summer can feel worrying but some simple planning means it misses me less than I miss it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56b35dd6decc39572e5296aff34ea254</guid></item><item><title>Struggling AFLW teams GWS, Collingwood and Gold Coast receive extra picks or list spots from league</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/aflw-have-nots-receive-league-boost-on-grand-final-eve/106079622</link><description>Three of the AFLW's worst-performing clubs will receive boosts to their lists, with the help announced the day before the grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">087d6c70c437791857888893255fa45d</guid></item><item><title>Lotterywest cancels licences of seven stores across Perth found to be selling illegal tobacco or vapes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/lotterywest-cancels-licences-over-illegal-tobacco-/106079700</link><description>Seven stores across Perth found to be selling illegal tobacco and vapes have their lotteries licences terminated, as attempts to disrupt the illicit and growing trade continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">deaa16d974f977f92fc4244b10fe4aeb</guid></item><item><title>Kyra Cooney-Cross scores stunning long range goal as Matildas down New Zealand 5-0</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/kyra-cooney-cross-goal-matildas-defeat-new-zealand/106074508</link><description>A spectacular long range effort from Kyra Cooney-Cross has helped the Matildas to a dominant 5-0 win over New Zealand in Australia's penultimate game before hosting the Asian Cup in March.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ed492f5f89ed6ab1feddf18b1b73bf8</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong's aging towers face urgent questions after city's deadliest blaze in decades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/behind-hong-kong-s-skyline-thousands-of-old-towers-fire-risks/106079352</link><description>Hong Kong's worst fire in decades exposed long-standing weaknesses in its aging residential blocks. The question haunting the city is whether the disaster could happen again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e527e3cdb4fb8aec5ae2e15796f2ecc</guid></item><item><title>One of seven Rosenberg's goannas from ACT reserve is missing from home for second time in two years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/act-rosenbergs-goanna-rum-missing-ainslie-majura-conservation/106080004</link><description>One of a handful of Rosenberg’s goannas living in the ACT’s hill reserves has once again wandered off, prompting calls from a local conservation organisation for help bringing him back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d236e04ccb909529cfe855fa2a4af683</guid></item><item><title>Brodie Kostecki wins Supercars grand final sprint race as Chad Mostert narrows gap to leader Broc Feeney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/kostecki-wins-as-mostert-closes-in-on-supercars-crown/106080514</link><description>Brodie Kostecki prevails in wet and wild conditions to win the opening Supercars grand final race, as Chaz Mostert closes in on the championship lead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a600518a7d11ed23c8999092c6e4bf7b</guid></item><item><title>Wala Kooral-bi juvenile justice facility opens in northern WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/wala-kooral-bi-juvenile-justice-facility-opens-in-northern-wa/106057316</link><description>An on-country youth diversion facility has been built in the state's far north, offering a culturally grounded alternative to traditional youth justice programs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">142d8035e60293b2bfd4ea512b3d855f</guid></item><item><title>Confidence remains in WA iron ore industry despite forecast royalty drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/wa-iron-ore-royalties-forecast-down/106077818</link><description>Western Australia has long prospered off its hefty irone ore mining royalties, but new figures reveal that revenue may drop by billions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b59e6502bce4249b5b139e3efa48f011</guid></item><item><title>Qantas terminal at Melbourne Airport evacuated and flights delayed due to fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/melbourne-airport-qantas-terminal-evacuated/106080752</link><description>The Qantas terminal is re-opening after being evacuated because of a small fire inside Melbourne Airport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44f741960e995fb9479b357573d18ed2</guid></item><item><title>NT parliament hears claims of children in youth detention being transferred without families' knowledge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/nt-parliament-children-youth-detention-allegedly-moved-to-darwin/106080720</link><description>Two politicians allege NT children in youth detention are being moved from Alice Springs to Darwin without their families' knowledge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e1c0c9a0ccf30f57917a7f02d2f775a</guid></item><item><title>ICC rejects plea to release Philippine ex-president Rodrigo Duterte</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/icc-rejects-plea-to-release-philippine-ex-president-duterte/106080850</link><description>The judge says it is "necessary" for the 80-year-old to remain in detention as the conditions proposed by his lawyers do not meet the conditions for parole.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69d31e21ba06deee8c154d6e2ab9059b</guid></item><item><title>Eight arrested and 128 people dead as alarm faults confirmed in Hong Kong fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/eight-people-arrested-over-deadly-hong-kong-fire-tai-po-district/106080926</link><description>The arrests come as the probe into what caused the deadly blaze that killed at least 128 people continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce9a1003dd5cc3333427e62260e00d1c</guid></item><item><title>Imran Khan's son and political allies concerned about his health amid block on prison visits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/imran-khan-son-kasim-khan-calls-for-proof-his-father-is-alive/106081236</link><description>The family and political allies of Pakistan's former prime minister say they've not been allowed to visit him in prison for weeks but authorities say he is well.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d540ded1863177c7fec3ea7b841e6670</guid></item><item><title>Putin may laugh but Europe is taking Russian aggression seriously</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/ukraine-russia-vladimir-putin-donald-trump-european-war/106045656</link><description>Something has now been unleashed in Europe which is going to be hard to put back in the bottle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fc1c906afe2cafc664654bab4a6685b</guid></item><item><title>Albanese knows the power dynamic between Labor and mining interests has shifted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/anthony-albanese-mining-labor-greens-deal-environment/106045658</link><description>There has been a shift in the power dynamic between Labor and the mining industry. This week's environmental law reform is its embodiment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f47fba9a6d450b1c3228007e52bf0c6</guid></item><item><title>John 'Wacka' Williams labels Barnaby Joyce's resignation an 'act of treason'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/barnaby-joyce-resignation-voter-reaction/106077566</link><description>The MP's resignation from the Nationals surprised no one, but drew ire from members of the party. Those on the ground in his electorate have a more mixed view.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">405b5edf3c1f4ee76d755bb3f5b3be01</guid></item><item><title>Director Peter Weir on capturing the mood for Picnic at Hanging Rock</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/director-peter-weir-on-filming-picnic-at-hanging-rock/106074136</link><description>Renowned Australian director Peter Weir gives a rare behind-the-scenes insight into what made Picnic at Hanging Rock such a memorable and enduring film.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a0a3a9f7a11c445ebf09909341a28d0</guid></item><item><title>Cape Barren Island was returned for Aboriginal self-governance 20 years ago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/cape-barren-island-20-years-after-land-return/105916324</link><description>Twenty years ago, Cape Barren Island was handed back to its traditional owners. Today's children are proof of the life-changing power of that act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1e8123e16da228977e990ee9aa39db7</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong tower residents had safety complaints more than 12 months before deadly fires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/hong-kong-tower-fire-alarms-failed-safety-concerns-flagged/106080022</link><description>Many of the people who managed to escape the Wang Fuk Court fires in Hong Kong believe the disaster could have been prevented, saying they had flagged safety concerns more than a year ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ae6220382bd183f602e5d1bab1fffd7</guid></item><item><title>Normalisation of location sharing, tech-facilitated abuse in spotlight after Lilie James inquest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/nsw-lilie-james-murder-location-sharing-dv-tech-abuse/106072984</link><description>Experts on gendered violence have warned against the proliferation of everyday location sharing tools to control victim-survivors after NSW's top coroner found Paul Thijssen used them to track Lilie James before her murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e22e4fc827d54f6212352558e70a7129</guid></item><item><title>King Gizzard &amp; the Lizard Wizard on quitting Spotify, orchestras, raves, and world domination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/king-gizzard-on-leaving-spotify-orchestras-raves/106058570</link><description>Their rock, rave and orchestral music attracts a cult global following. But the prolific, chaotic King Gizzard &amp; the Lizard Wizard are just "at peace with failing".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fee298a5f31019c8e735f977dd540e6</guid></item><item><title>R360 launch postponed from 2026 to 2028, after players withdraw due to threats of NRL bans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/r360-postponed-until-2028-after-nrl-ban-threat/106081400</link><description>Threats of long bans for prospective R360 players prompted "a handful" of them to withdraw from the rebel league, which now says it will launch in 2028 instead of next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f9056cd6a82d72eef6485c9c07cdf99</guid></item><item><title>Crowdy Bay shark attack highlights need for first aid devices, drone surveillance on remote beaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/shark-attack-highlights-need-for-remote-first-aid-and-drones/106077444</link><description>A makeshift tourniquet may have made the difference between a shark attack on the NSW Mid North Coast this week claiming one life not two. The attack has put a spotlight on how fatalities may be prevented.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b66b310d8becee41e4ab954e7df6286c</guid></item><item><title>Australia's emissions have dropped, but we've got our work cut out to reach targets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/record-drop-in-australias-emissions/106074296</link><description>Australia's emissions had the biggest drop ever this year outside the artificial kink in the curve during COVID-19 shutdowns, but there's still a lot of work to do.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7549e00e7dd7bc370cfc65bcedc0f0ba</guid></item><item><title>Landscape around Yunta in outback SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/landscape-around-yunta-in-outback-sa/106075520</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">620dacb5ce6fa85351a0006df0af44a7</guid></item><item><title>Gus has been gone for 63 days, and searches of mines, dams and scrub have yielded no clues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/the-search-for-gus-lamont-has-included-dams-mines-and-scrub/106055504</link><description>The disappearance of Gus Lamont is one of those events that have a seismic impact on public consciousness: they distress, disturb, upset and unsettle. This week six mine shafts were searched, providing no further clues in the case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b62919d1d99b64b2df9b85158a7245c5</guid></item><item><title>Waukaringa mine ruins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/waukaringa-mine-ruins/106075580</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e20f80c2cb94c1f65eff431c39a78dfb</guid></item><item><title>Google's global data hub plan for Christmas Island gets mixed reviews from locals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/google-data-centre-stokes-uncertainty-on-christmas-island/105984092</link><description>Google's plans for a data hub could drag this remote island from a digitally starved past into an AI-powered future. But are the locals ready?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d18f6a9a2d826a770ae8e4af6f53d68b</guid></item><item><title>Trolls stole Dr Juliet Turner's joy and in doing so took their own</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/misogyny-educated-women-manosphere-juliet-turner/106045666</link><description>The saddest aspect of all this that a generation of boys may feel compelled to suppress the ordinary the joy of celebrating another's success.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3b6c544f1770a658d82fc7ad5e282ac</guid></item><item><title>Adoption support service warns against increasing adoption in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/service-warns-against-increasing-adoption-in-queensland/106074614</link><description>Queensland should overhaul "outdated" adoption laws that sever children's legal ties to their families, while ensuring adoption remains a last resort, a peak support service tells a commission of inquiry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">837f8739ea4d39173b45a9bfd38ebb06</guid></item><item><title>Inquiry into male suicide rates hears migrants left feeling 'invisible, unheard and completely lost’ in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/men-suicide-rates-in-the-spotlight-in-canberra/106079256</link><description>Men make up more than 75 per cent of all suicide deaths in Australia, but Lifeline says they only make up about 40 per cent of helpline service users — and even when men do seek help they experienced "high levels of disengagement".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">127272c79a2aaad08a877978b8b8f2e9</guid></item><item><title>Unsettled weekend ahead in south-east Queensland, with 'pretty much nowhere' without chance of thunderstorms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/more-storms-ahead-for-queensland-possible-hail-flash-floods/106078390</link><description>A wet weekend is forecast for Australia's sunshine state, with meteorologists warning that "pretty much nowhere in Queensland" is without a chance of thunderstorms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a0fb687524ab6bf4e774b76d15bc712</guid></item><item><title>World-first tournament hopes to 'break down barriers' between the golf and disability communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/queensland-golf-disability-charity-world-first-tournament-pga/106075338</link><description>People with intellectual disabilities will have roles in planning, promoting, preparing, and supporting professionals at a charity golf tournament that is the first of its kind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad28868bc3e87eb99dac4917ac4d964d</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Thunder miss out on WBBL win as Adelaide Strikers clash ended early by rain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/wbbl-thunder-strikers-game-called-off-in-rain/106081446</link><description>After rain falls for most of the Sydney Thunder's innings, umpires decide to call off their WBBL clash against the Strikers with Phoebe Litchfield one swing away from ending the game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99a82cac35ddfb1d3680e1d37e2e0c6d</guid></item><item><title>What would it be like to visit Hobart's proposed Macquarie Point stadium?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/hobart-stadium-design-macquarie-point-spectator-experience/106054654</link><description>From potential gridlock to an "immersive" viewing experience, let's set aside the politics — just for a moment — and look at what planning documents tell us about the building at the heart of Tasmania's fiery stadium debate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7091033d2c6379cd7e19e030424554ee</guid></item><item><title>About 90 Jetstar flights cancelled due to global recall of Airbus A320 planes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/jetstar-flights-grounded-delayed-due-to-airbus-a320-recall/106081408</link><description>About 90 Jetstar flights have been cancelled across Australia today due to a global recall of Airbus A320 planes for urgent software repairs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e49f058098a40deeb8a96f3caf5f71a6</guid></item><item><title>Think you're ready to own a home? Here are the costs that experts want you to consider</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/the-up-front-and-ongoing-costs-of-home-ownership/105984188</link><description>We asked three financial experts about the up-front and ongoing costs of buying a home and for their tips on how to prepare for home ownership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a044e362104441aa527db1d121dcea86</guid></item><item><title>Cricket Australia set to speak with Usman Khawaja after he labelled Perth Ashes Test pitch a 'piece of shit'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/usman-khawaja-pillories-perth-ashes-test-pitch/106081416</link><description>Usman Khawaja may face a sanction for labelling the first Ashes Test surface a "piece of shit", with Cricket Australia understood to be disappointed by the remarks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62c5c47efcba08e3a71df02e352a8f9e</guid></item><item><title>Survivors of forced adoption in South Australia call for greater recognition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/forced-adoption-survivors-call-for-greater-recognition/105946656</link><description>Decades on from Australia's forced adoption era, just two states have set up a redress scheme for the mothers who were harmed. Survivors are calling for South Australia to take similar action — warning time is running out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">883276d36b1aa0a38c589ceb338c5a55</guid></item><item><title>After suffering 'terrifying' postpartum rage, this mother wants others to know they're not alone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/mother-comes-to-terms-with-terrifying-postpartum-rage/106072456</link><description>When Ali Gossage gave birth a second time, she did not experience the constant joys of motherhood. Instead, she was sometimes filled with "terrifying" anger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d749279af4a3906951170031a067264</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Airport terminal fire under investigation after evacuation of Qantas domestic terminal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/melbourne-airport-fire-evacuation-investigation/106081444</link><description>A fire that forced the evacuation of Melbourne's Qantas domestic terminal on Friday night continues to be investigated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7842effb7970063a8123e6d16509d33</guid></item><item><title>Severe Tropical Cyclone Fina damage exposes need for new Royal Darwin Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/nt-cyclone-fina-damage-royal-darwin-hospital-need-rdh-analysis/106074054</link><description>A new Royal Darwin Hospital would cost more than $1 billion to build, and likely take a decade or more to deliver. So who has the political bravery to commit?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37551ba9b57d2f519ca4ea062b5a9376</guid></item><item><title>Who's thriving and who's barely surviving in Australia, the Land of the Parrots?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/parrots-of-australia-a-spotters-guide/106056012</link><description>Australia is the land of the parrot — few places in the world have such a dazzling array of colourful and clever members of the psittacine family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4344c3353cd2f3bf141b8ec4ca2378d0</guid></item><item><title>Crowds grow at Melbourne Airport after Jetstar flights are grounded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/crowds-grow-at-melbourne-airport-/106081616</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1d12c0080e45b2944363b7dd5074653</guid></item><item><title>Jetstar flight cancellations causes travel chaos for passengers at airports across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/vic-jetstar-travel-chaos/106081606</link><description>The cancellation of Jetstar flights due to an issue with Airbus A320 planes has left passengers stranded across Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f288cd807799adb73b68763b5971c050</guid></item><item><title>'Naughty Boy' pelican draws in visitors and locals in coastal tourist town of Kalbarri</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/naughty-boy-pelican-delights-tourists-kalbarri/106073082</link><description>Locals say this cheeky pelican has a personality unlike any bird they have ever seen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59a37b02c238ac01526a5608d9d1e8f3</guid></item><item><title>Australia's peak music exam body under fire amid claims of 'slipping standards'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/claims-standards-slipping-at-ameb-as-regions-revolt/106074654</link><description>It is held up as the "gold standard" of music testing in the country, but there are claims the Australian Music Examinations Board is letting down talented students.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbe3a51c36b4d2bc06add40728c47ad6</guid></item><item><title>South-East Asia flood deaths rise as Cyclone Ditwah hits Sri Lanka, heads towards southern India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/south-east-asia-flood-deaths-rise-cyclone-ditwah-hit-sri-lanka/106081562</link><description>Parts of South-East Asia have been hit with record levels of rain as a cyclone hits Sri Lanka, causing floods and landslides, as the system heads towards India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aac070a6e624988081f4ca440d27d6e4</guid></item><item><title>Snowy Mountains farmers call for support in managing spread of invasive weed African lovegrass</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/african-lovegrass-weed-chokes-out-native-grass-snowy-mountains/106006854</link><description>To the untrained eye, African lovegrass is just another plant in the NSW Snowy Mountains. But this golden plant is a deceptive invasive weed that is choking out the landscape, causing some farmers to leave the land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97336bfbd9984ec7e511ae69aa52d050</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri fastest qualifier for Qatar F1 sprint race, with championship leader Lando Norris third</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/oscar-piastri-pole-position-for-qatar-f1-sprint/106081654</link><description>Oscar Piastri returns to form by qualifying fastest for the F1 sprint in Qatar, as he launches an unlikely bid to catch McLaren teammate and world championship leader Lando Norris.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4c968437af1a688da3df1481b00bf56</guid></item><item><title>Conservationists worldwide scrambling for alternative funding after USAID cuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/conservationists-scrambling-for-funding-after-usaid-cuts/106053490</link><description>Citizen science and AI have never been more important to the environment after White House cuts to USAID are felt beneath the waves, a new report says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02a67830f4b18930900eb775f8ab34b6</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne teen who died after nut allergy 'let down' by health system, family says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/max-mckenzie-nut-allergy-coronial-inquest/106022338</link><description>Four years after a 15-year-old boy died due to a nut allergy, a Victorian coroner is examining if the death was preventable and whether paramedics and doctors at the Box Hill Hospital provided appropriate care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea1a2581536020cb7f1dd793ff06ac66</guid></item><item><title>RBA could hike interest rates in early 2026 as banks rewrite forecasts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/rba-interest-rate-hike-possible-within-months/106077098</link><description>Hotter-than-expected inflation figures have caught most economists and policy makers off guard. The ongoing price pressures in the economy open the door for an RBA interest rate hike in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d82eb1838ac69bb8ea36fe67f738a8cc</guid></item><item><title>Skyhooks guitarist Bob Starkie dies aged 73 after a battle with cancer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/skyhooks-guitarist-bob-starkie-dies/106081862</link><description>A statement released on Skyhooks' official Facebook page announced his passing this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9887f7f9c22df27c6c83a6df9ee2dbf</guid></item><item><title>Planning to bite into a sweet, juicy mango? Here's what to know about your favourite summer treat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/australian-mango-varieties-and-origins/106072138</link><description>What's the difference between a big R2E2, a delicate Honey Gold, and an iconic Kensington Pride? Find out before biting into a mango this season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70ee88f5621fa0e89efe9a8c714443d7</guid></item><item><title>Victorian coroner determines Mount Buller hiker missing since 2019 is dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/niels-becker-coroner-finding-mount-buller-inquest-missing-hiker-/106081758</link><description>A Coroner has determined that Niels Gunther Becker, 39, who went missing at Mount Buller in 2019 is dead but that no third party was involved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">472d867bb5bccf18ea322810f522a39f</guid></item><item><title>Terminated Bedford staff in limbo, with millions of dollars owed in entitlements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/bedford-staff-in-limbo-millions-owed-in-entitlements/106080712</link><description>Former Bedford staff have said they are owed millions of dollars in entitlements after they were made redundant when the disability employment provider entered voluntary administration earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfe87f0fcb8a8a391861ebdeb706d658</guid></item><item><title>US halts all asylum claims following the shooting of two National Guard members in Washington DC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/us-halts-all-asylum-claims-after-national-guards-shooting/106081774</link><description>Less than 24 hours after the shooting, Trump officials began ordering widespread reviews of immigration policies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6ca5d3708d013392675c37ab077e950</guid></item><item><title>No-bake chocolate and strawberry cake is the ultimate make-ahead dessert - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/no-bake-chocolate-biscuit-and-strawberry-cream-cake/105543504</link><description>Icebox cakes are retro no-bake desserts made by layering store-bought biscuits and whipped cream. A no-fuss option for summer celebrations, this one can be assembled in 10 minutes and made well ahead of time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa595533c02a1f792c1bf40a7fb5ef05</guid></item><item><title>Best books out in November, featuring Margaret Atwood's memoir and The Mushroom Tapes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/best-books-november-margaret-atwood-memoir-mushroom-tapes/106018540</link><description>Wondering what to read next? This month's best books include a novel that brings to life Britain's only named wind and a new book by the author of The Handmaid's Tale.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9716753e1b04846ee97e8f09ff9b42a</guid></item><item><title>England captain Ben Stokes dismisses 'arrogant' label amid criticism of Ashes Test loss to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/ashes-cricket-england-australia-ben-stokes-arrogant-label/106082046</link><description>Captain Ben Stokes responds to England's critics in the wake of the defeat to Australia in the first Test, maintaining his squad will not step back from its aggressive approach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cadb1c10356060c35802d310ab0fa02f</guid></item><item><title>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese marries Jodie Haydon at The Lodge in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/anthony-albanese-jodie-haydon-wedding-prime-minister-married/106080434</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese marries his partner Jodie Haydon in a private ceremony at his official Canberra residence, after details of the wedding were kept top secret.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f951cdd57ae649a668fbbb63b9787d7e</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese's wedding ends this 'killing season' with love's triumph</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/anthony-albanese-jodie-haydon-wedding/106082052</link><description>The two months preceding a wedding are notoriously hazardous. But consider the two months Anthony Albanese has just had.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24704e8755a4678cb9c739cad01c7352</guid></item><item><title>Albanese and Haydon have wed in a ceremony that will go down in history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/albanese-haydon-marry-at-lodge-history/106078430</link><description>Anthony Albanese and Jodie Haydon can trace their relationship back five years, but the historic nature of their secretly planned wedding at The Lodge runs far deeper.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e941bb6490c685f170dd1964a96fc16b</guid></item><item><title>Josh Giddey involved in heated row with NBA courtside spectator during Bulls-Hornets game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/nba-josh-giddey-confronts-spectator-bulls-hornets/106082200</link><description>A frustrated Josh Giddey has an altercation with a spectator during the Chicago Bulls' 123-116 loss to the Charlotte Hornets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7b9f42dede24813592dc0f841138486</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese and Jodie Haydon walk down the aisle at their wedding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/anthony-albanese-and-jodie-haydon-walk-down-the-aisle/106082248</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c60dd8f677864e9b8a0d959214839d26</guid></item><item><title>Police continue search for missing man Chris Thorne in Melbourne's west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/missing-man-chris-thorne-police-search/106082178</link><description>Police are searching for missing man Chris Thorne, who was last seen in Melbourne's western suburbs last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1b80e5f3ca4237e7988ac400761be34</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne becomes first AFLW team to win consecutive premierships after clinical grand final showing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/aflw-grand-final-live-north-melbourne-kangaroos-brisbane-lions/106077430</link><description>North Melbourne outclasses the Brisbane Lions by 40 points in the AFLW grand final to capture a history-making second consecutive premiership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">586359f2bee24c909c1e4fb8e69f48bd</guid></item><item><title>QLD Premier claims LNP victory in bitterly-contested Hinchinbrook by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/qld-regs-hinchinbrook-by-election/106074190</link><description>The QLD Premier has declared a crushing LNP victory in a KAP stronghold, after a bitterly contested by-election campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f29faf243797abc376bd2d7f9f560200</guid></item><item><title>Broc Feeney and Chaz Mostert set for blockbuster Supercars finale in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/feeney-mostert-set-for-supercars-finale/106082314</link><description>Supercars championship leader Broc Feeney overcomes engine dramas to take victory in the penultimate Adelaide grand final race.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89e4875bfba52ef5c0d78f2223f685d0</guid></item><item><title>WA set for scorching start to summer as state government launches new coastal CAT bus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/perth-hot-start-summer-scarborough-bus-launched/106081866</link><description>WA capital is bracing for a 38C start to December, as the state government launches a free bus service to one of the city's most popular beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37f5de49bd119fdcade43174f385744a</guid></item><item><title>Toni Lamond, known for her roles in Annie Get Your Gun and My Fair Lady, dies aged 93</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/australian-performer-toni-lamond-has-died-aged-93/106082102</link><description>Australian screen and stage actor Toni Lamond was known for her roles in Annie Get Your Gun, My Fair Lady, Number 96 and The Last Frontier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">206d4cb9f5471c455d6bd23f53ef0a58</guid></item><item><title>Meg Lanning hits 73no as Stars down Renegades, Hurricanes defeat Scorchers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/sport-wbbl-wrap-stars-renegades-scorchers-hurricanes/106082354</link><description>Former Australia captain Meg Lanning hits 73 not out to help the Stars to a convincing 45-run derby victory over the Renegades, while the Hurricanes down the Scorchers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5775eed7a3f18112a823690518d27277</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos break new ground on the field and in the history books in AFLW flag defence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/aflw-grand-final-north-melbourne-thrash-brisbane-historic-game/106082242</link><description>North Melbourne proves to be ground breakers and history makers as it extend its match-winning streak to 27 games in a comprehensive win over Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">517a5ac7cd8acc2d00cb1a81bb220754</guid></item><item><title>Trump says airspace above and surrounding Venezuela to be closed in its entirety</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/donald-trump-says-airspace-above-venezuela-closed/106082656</link><description>US President Donald Trump says the entire airspace above the South American nation of Venezuela should be considered closed in its entirety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf41be0b677e1065d1400348aa0e6fd7</guid></item><item><title>As questions around horse welfare grow, equestrian sport is facing a reckoning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/equestrian-heath-ryan-horse-welfare-fei/106049564</link><description>As questions around horse welfare grow, can equestrian sport's Olympic dream survive?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1118f951004e05a61f37db7a6295b1d8</guid></item><item><title>Why Barbados became a republic and cut ties with the British monarchy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/barbados-history-republic-commonwealth-monarchy/105958372</link><description>With countries like Australia still debating whether or not the time has come to become a republic, what prompted tiny Barbados with its population of less than 300,000, to take the leap?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e2cc0f86de1e08744b5c83a12201fa7</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: It's cute you think you can nail this quiz</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/106018230</link><description>I'm not going to stop you from trying, but it might be worth readjusting your expectations. Let's play, HARD!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6417480ddc6c8c31242d91de2aab5bf</guid></item><item><title>Crypto gaming earns users tokens but also exposes them to risks of trading and speculation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/cryptocurrency-gamification-compared-to-gambling/106045396</link><description>As the crypto sector expands its appeal beyond tech insiders, the gamification of cryptocurrencies is appealing to younger users, which experts warn is walking the line between gaming and gambling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5d0e05eba75f69efbbde51be7ed6179</guid></item><item><title>Sex work influencers call out lack of transparency as young girls targeted by viral social media content</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/nt-sex-work-influencers-social-media-content-warning-onlyfans/106050924</link><description>Sex workers say viral social media content, which often promotes a life of luxury, needs to be more transparent to avoid duping young followers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bb52b2473b18378a8e8256e046359e0</guid></item><item><title>Hobart stadium vote will determine future of historic Macquarie Point waterfront and AFL team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/hobart-stadium-vote-leaves-macquarie-point-at-crossroads/106044588</link><description>Since its inception, the stadium project has divided the Hobart community in a tug of war between development and preservation of its historic waterfront. In just days, the door will shut forever on one side of the debate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e8c699423bbbcd3d63be4f6d5dfd5e2</guid></item><item><title>The spooky First Nations movie you need to see at BIFF</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/it-will-find-you-brisbane-international-film-festival/106074274</link><description>First Nations stories are combined with modern horror scares in this new film from Australian creatives Chris Broadbent and Enzo Tedeschi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b235169fa73d8695e28eb94f33cc4ba4</guid></item><item><title>Thai PM admits flood failures after trapped victims wait days for help</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/thailand-floods-death-toll-rises/106082418</link><description>Thailand’s Health Ministry estimates that more than 160 people were killed in the disaster across nine provinces, but at least 110 of those died in Songkhla, where Hat Yai is the capital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cf3a3fd21bfc3a6f329ac4a032f0cbd</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri wins Qatar F1 sprint race, qualifies fastest for GP, edging closer to Lando Norris in standings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/oscar-piastri-wins-qatar-sprint-race-pole-position-grand-prix/106082990</link><description>Australian driver Oscar Piastri is doing everything he can to catch McLaren teammate Lando Norris in the world championship race, winning the sprint race and qualifying in pole position for the Qatar Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91fb4a7e45b5fd7c127dde77f8c1f27a</guid></item><item><title>Paul Kelly, Stella Donnelly, 5 Seconds of Summer lead November's best new albums</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/best-albums-november-paul-kelly-stella-donnelly-5sos-hatchie/106055576</link><description>Sensitive song-smiths, reinvented boy bands, rock and rap upstarts — it's all here in an Ausmusic Month edition of the best new music.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e1d5874f67515bf050b4bb16100377f</guid></item><item><title>'Awareness gap' on mental health support available for new parents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/mother-shares-experience-of-postpartum-depression/106029442</link><description>Nilupulie Karunaratne thought asking for help was a sign of weakness. Then her husband referred her to a psychologist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae82d7a972c6c3e04cabef04bfc79ad1</guid></item><item><title>Labor should theoretically be confident ahead of the 2026 Victorian election — but challenges are mounting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/labor-liberal-victorian-state-election/106074182</link><description>On paper, Labor should be confident that it will score an unprecedented fourth term in office when Victorian voters go to the ballot box in a year's time, with the Liberal opposition still scrambling to present as an electable alternative.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3a467f756b8d054f7af57490a3defae</guid></item><item><title>One man's experience with homelessness reveals another side to Sydney's 2000 postcode</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/nsw-sydney-parker-homelessness-transitional-housing/106031314</link><description>Sydney's 2000 postcode is associated with harbour views and flashiness, but Parker's seen a different side.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a7c8c03d0e578135270c41a215cd953</guid></item><item><title>The Melbourne Metro Tunnel opens today. Here's what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/melbourne-metro-tunnel-now-open-summer-train-timetable/106077452</link><description>It's the biggest upgrade to Melbourne's rail network in more than 40 years, and it's arrived — the long-awaited Metro Tunnel, along with its five new inner-city stations, opens to the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c41bf094ac195a370ddf95abec86a10</guid></item><item><title>What people with diabetes want you to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/what-people-with-diabetes-want-you-to-know/106075536</link><description>We spoke to six people with three different types of diabetes to find out what they wish more of the public knew. Here's what they had to say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b19c807e633d13b2b1f3d64a7e511f45</guid></item><item><title>Marco Rubio, Steve Witkoff to meet Ukraine delegation in Florida, US official says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/us-rubio-witkoff-to-meet-ukraine-delegation-on-peace-talks/106083006</link><description>US Secretary of State Marco Rubio and special envoy Steve Witkoff will meet with Ukrainian negotiators in Florida for talks on a deal to end Russia's war in Ukraine, a senior US official says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d513fde307420cf1f6a2385da043cde</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne Kangaroos rally around injured Mia King after AFLW grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/aflw-grand-final-mia-king-injury-north-mebourne-kangaroos/106083024</link><description>During their AFLW premiership celebrations, North Melbourne players make sure to take time for Mia King, who just missed the grand final with a knee injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63cfdda9959b2fea504952cdfd68f179</guid></item><item><title>Sterile flies rain down on Kangaroo Island as battle to wipe out sheep blowfly gets serious</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/kangaroo-island-sterile-blowfly-eradication-program/106056134</link><description>Researchers on Kangaroo Island have been breeding and releasing millions of sterile Australian sheep blowflies in an attempt to eradicate the pest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">233b4fa9b04b33e056e44ce318137bca</guid></item><item><title>Chapter closes on 'The Family' murders that stole Adelaide's innocence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/bevan-von-einem-richard-kelvin-murder-one-of-family-killings/106049658</link><description>One of South Australia's most notorious murderers was this week rushed to an infirmary on the brink of death, prompting recollections of the time when young males disappeared across Adelaide in a set of gruesome crimes dubbed "The Family" murders. Warning: This story contains details some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11b2f2f4782672c023b6d32788b7412c</guid></item><item><title>British playwright and Oscar winner Tom Stoppard dies at 88</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/british-playwright-tom-stoppard-dies-at-88/106083072</link><description>Stoppard was often hailed as the greatest British playwright of his generation, with multiple awards for his work on stage and screen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98af289ac7e02d33ea03fab0ce5d0ac4</guid></item><item><title>Queensland to become first Australian jurisdiction to allow specialist general practitioners to diagnose ADHD in adults</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/qld-adhd-reforms-general-practitioners-diagnose-prescribe/106057242</link><description>Queensland is becoming the first jurisdiction in Australia to allow specialist GPs to diagnose ADHD in adults and prescribe treatment, but some hold concerns about the lack of mandatory specific training.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e564c23a7aff66d2b7ab9df4b04f21bd</guid></item><item><title>Australia's first Mormon arrived in Adelaide 185 years ago and immediately regretted it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/australias-first-mormon-warned-others-to-stay-away/105619762</link><description>It's been 185 years this month since Australia's first Mormon arrived in Adelaide. He immediately regretted the move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a47d9fa1a7d203d7c9c7fabe76ee1ef8</guid></item><item><title>Eli Katoa shares images post brain surgery, pays tribute to partner and hopes for NRL return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/eli-katoa-pays-tribute-to-partner-pledges-nrl-return/106083174</link><description>Melbourne Storm star Eli Katoa shares an update after his brain surgery, posting images of himself in hospital and saying he hopes to return to football "soon".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5633872b100e3adeba60e027e1c85d89</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia flood death toll climbs amid cyclone devastation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/indonesia-flood-death-toll-climbs-amid-cyclone-devastation/106083102</link><description>Torrential rain causes flash floods and landslides in Indonesia, where the toll rises as authorities mount rescue operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a7d38c9d0ca4ec2f45b4cce22c32dae</guid></item><item><title>Surfers set to pay to ride Fiji's world-class breaks after repeal of surf access law</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/surfers-to-pay-to-ride-fijis-world-class-breaks/106077640</link><description>Surfers wanting to catch a wave at Fiji's world class reef breaks could soon have to pay for the privilege after the repeal of a beach access law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8725c1c26f354dbc4222afeb20470fd6</guid></item><item><title>WA Legal Practice Board slammed by lawyers in scathing parliamentary submissions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/wa-legal-practice-board-slammed-by-lawyers/106079432</link><description>In a scathing rebuke of their own watchdog, WA lawyers claim the state's Legal Practice Board is causing them psychological harm amid calls for urgent reform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e02a93cbee37fb47fb34a52275d44888</guid></item><item><title>Jetstar flights resume across Australia after Airbus A320 software issue identified</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/jetstar-flights-resume-airbus-a320-issue/106083312</link><description>The airline is warning further disruptions are possible after the issue sparked widespread delays across Australia on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15fe8812a4dde984b791c490e5f285eb</guid></item><item><title>Energy independence? It would reduce the impact of global energy shocks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/energy-independence-reduce-the-impact-of-global-energy-shocks/106081924</link><description>If Australia produced 100 per cent of its energy from renewable sources, it would reduce the impact of global energy shocks on Australia's economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73c9a333c80a9f02fbe46eaec2ce7a48</guid></item><item><title>Surfers Paradise sand 'island' to disappear by Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/gold-coast-sand-island-to-disappear-by-christmas/106074800</link><description>Curious beachgoers are being cautioned to stay off the sandbar and to swim between the flags.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5820f1c0654918d731b901b58e2485a</guid></item><item><title>Coalition floats stronger 'values' test for migrants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/coalition-value-english-language-test-migrants-visa/106083258</link><description>Sussan Ley says migration tensions in Australia are not the fault of migrants, but a stronger "Australian values" test for those seeking to move here could form part of the Coalition's coming migration policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27934064c4d24fcf8bee70405e1b0287</guid></item><item><title>The Austrian heiress giving away her entire fortune</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/rich-heiress-giving-away-all-her-wealth/106077200</link><description>When Marlene Engelhorn inherited tens of millions of dollars from her grandma, she felt she had two choices: do something about it, or confirm she was "full of sh*t".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">322ef9da6313065a06591bcb83bf9e9e</guid></item><item><title>Sydney FC great Alex Brosque fumes over alleged handball in Wanderers' 1-0 ALM win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/a-league-men-sydney-fc-wanderers-alleged-handball/106083524</link><description>Sydney FC's four-match winning streak comes to a crashing halt, but its 1-0 loss to Western Sydney has sparked debate about what constitutes a handball.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de18334568fcf4b8e3c548d6262734b1</guid></item><item><title>Massive flames, explosions rock waste facility in Sydney's west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/massive-flames-explosions-rock-waste-facility-in-sydney-s-west/106083710</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e57759e4709e4cae6f48b251b940f1b1</guid></item><item><title>Supporters of proposed Macquarie Point stadium rally ahead of crucial vote</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/tasmania-macquarie-point-stadium-yes-rally-vote/106083340</link><description>Supporters of Tasmania's proposed AFL stadium have gathered on Hobart's parliament lawns on Sunday to show their backing of the controversial build.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3629a770dccddeaa44bbecf20a1a18df</guid></item><item><title>Pilot dead after two light planes collide mid-air in Sydney's south-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/nsw-wedderburn-light-plane-crash/106083640</link><description>Emergency services were called to Napper Field, in Wedderburn about 11:50am on Sunday following reports of a crash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfafa330a83294fe96d35dae883c999c</guid></item><item><title>Australian Border Force passport system outage causes delays nationwide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/australian-border-force-passport-system-outage-delays/106083726</link><description>Long queues at international terminals have now cleared after a nationwide system outage affected all inbound and outbound passengers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8220e2d7c2870dca1ccf7a28cbd8fe4</guid></item><item><title>Ombudsman calls on NT government to urgently remove prisoners from police cells</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/nt-ombudsman-report-inhumane-oppressive-watch-house-conditions/106082108</link><description>The Northern Territory's prison watchdog has called on the government to urgently remove all inmates from police cells following an investigation which revealed prisoners sleeping between toilets and claims guards watched women showering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c94961e576d7d863edb6b43efa7326c1</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese and Jodie Haydon to honeymoon for five days after intimate Lodge wedding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/albanese-jodie-haydon-to-honeymoon-after-intimate-lodge-wedding/106083290</link><description>Anthony Albanese and Jodie Haydon will head off on a five-day honeymoon tomorrow after an intimate wedding at The Lodge among only their closest family and friends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">378902679f2d2440602f9ca0a46bb2da</guid></item><item><title>65yo diver drowns at Tank Cave near Mount Gambier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/sa-diver-emergency-death-at-tank-cave-tantanoola/106083500</link><description>Police are investigating after a 65-year-old diver drowned at Tank Cave near Tantanoola in the state's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60c8c3e129ca902e1486233b5b7d63ce</guid></item><item><title>How the Kangaroos beat the Lions to claim back-to-back AFLW flags in their perfect season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/aflw-grand-final-north-melbourne-kangaroos-brisbane-lions/106083788</link><description>Creating history by winning consecutive premierships and completing an unbeaten season is just reward for North Melbourne's boundary-pushing AFLW program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8abb438f7954cccf41f010b3f6c697ce</guid></item><item><title>Locals at Albanese's favourite pub respond to his wedding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/locals-at-albanese-s-favourite-pub-respond-to-his-wedding/106083948</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aec842cfc05a8422998e1dfaf1faf5e5</guid></item><item><title>New leader Jess Wilson to remain shadow treasurer under Victorian opposition reshuffle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/jess-wilson-shadow-treasurer-coalition-reshuffle-unveiled/106083738</link><description>New opposition leader Jess Wilson will retain shadow treasurer responsibilities under a reshuffle, while also keeping multiple former opposition leaders in the fold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e7f067f19ad04996727162f43254d37</guid></item><item><title>LNP's Wayde Chiesa promises to get to work after victory in Hinchinbrook by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/lnp-wayde-chiesa-wins-hinchinbrook-by-election/106074692</link><description>The LNP's Wayde Chiesa will be the next representative for the Queensland seat of Hinchinbrook, which had been safely held by Katter's Australian Party since 2017.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">316d56db0aad14eb566c92220ddfecdb</guid></item><item><title>Carbon dioxide import plan could see Darwin become world's climate pollution 'dumping ground', say activists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/darwin-import-carbon-capture-plan-pollution-dumping-ground/106040704</link><description>A plan for the Northern Territory to be among the first places in the world to import foreign carbon emissions has raised fears it will turn Darwin into a global pollution dumping ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24492f3ab15e31d45f7efccb5b4d740d</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania Police searching King Island for missing local teenager Lusian West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/tasmania-police-search-for-missing-teen-lusian-west-king-island/106083894</link><description>Local King Island teen Lusian West, 16, has not been seen since Friday, with Tasmania police and rescue crews to conduct aerial searches of the island's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2071093b7571de79e77d494f5309a598</guid></item><item><title>Em Rusciano on finding balance in life after her ADHD and autism diagnoses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/em-rusciano-autism-adhd-perimenopause-work-life-unwind-with/106074920</link><description>As a writer, singer, comedian, podcaster, author and single mum, Em Rusciano has become accustomed to navigating a chaotic life. The self-described "maximalist power queen" shares how she unwinds and how her approach to life has changed since going through perimenopause and being diagnosed with ADHD and autism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54a0940ddb38aa0802a5f057eb56cae2</guid></item><item><title>Photographer Lyn Alcock captures wild antics of Dryandra's numbat population over 20 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/dryandra-numbat-antics-photographer/106051162</link><description>Lyn Alcock is known as the 'Numbat whisperer', spending hours every day observing and photographing the tiny, endangered marsupials, recording behaviours that have never been seen before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50f2d4bc8d830154bacd7c73f39c8ce2</guid></item><item><title>CFMEU motion brought to Labor conference</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/cfmeu-labor-conference-motion/106083972</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a567700982402ba82ee69dcaf161e3cf</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Labor conference passes motion calling on Commonwealth to take CFMEU out of administration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/qld-cfmeu-motion-labor-conference-brisbane/106083862</link><description>A walkout was staged by members of the party's Right faction when the motion, which called for the Commonwealth to end the administration of the union, was moved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">920166156a153a3b14e8cbe308721ff6</guid></item><item><title>Pope Leo visits Turkiye’s Blue Mosque in Istanbul</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/pope-leo-visits-turkiye-s-blue-mosque-in-istanbul-/106083488</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7cf03ebfa53f7458aeb763ddb51dbf6</guid></item><item><title>Pope Leo visits the Blue Mosque in Istanbul during his first overseas trip as pontiff</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/pope-leo-visits-the-blue-mosque-in-istanbul/106083426</link><description>Leo smiled during the 20-minute visit and joked with one of his guides, but did not appear to pray.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e6661c0dbe18f5bb45c5c389f1743b1</guid></item><item><title>Anti-immigration protest met with counter-rally in Melbourne CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/anti-immigration-protest-counter-rally-melbourne-cbd/106083534</link><description>A large police presence, including riot police, was stationed across Melbourne's CBD as two countering protest groups marched through the city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f30b6e71e6ac5c3e2d006fc0888dd8a7</guid></item><item><title>Shipping movements disrupted as climate change protesters block coal ships from entering Port of Newcastle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/protesters-arrested-attempting-block-worlds-largest-coal-port/106083224</link><description>Police arrest 141 people in Newcastle Harbour for alleged marine-related offences during an anti-fossil fuel protest that began on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20331433a2345957df52cf9e31b92570</guid></item><item><title>Violent explosion during St Marys fire described as 'once in a career type of experience'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/inferno-fire-at-st-marys-generates-explosion-huge-fireball/106083492</link><description>The inferno-like fire broke out at Kurrajong Street in North St Marys overnight, generating immense heat and a huge eruption that spewed a fireball more than 100 metres up into the sky.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">493a2024159395dcf9eefccff5fe0f5f</guid></item><item><title>Is Australia Dr Jekyll and Mr Hyde when it comes to clean energy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/is-australia-dr-jekyll-and-mr-hyde/106084216</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">024af5a77da40568ad287b72b3a9d683</guid></item><item><title>Investigation underway into Deniliquin High School fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/deniliquin-high-school-fire-investigation/106083316</link><description>Alternative arrangements are being made for hundreds of students at Deniliquin High School after a fire tore through two buildings containing a library and classrooms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95f88e35235bb7bce15cab94d43e7b20</guid></item><item><title>Spain's David Puig wins Australian PGA Championship by two strokes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/australian-pga-championship-david-puig-wins/106084240</link><description>David Puig joins legendary countryman Seve Ballesteros as an Australian PGA champion after emerging from a congested field at Royal Queensland Golf Club in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">812b93393c051ab8c1803cbf9df390f6</guid></item><item><title>Anti-immigration protest and counter-rally in Melbourne CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/anti-immigration-protest-and-counter-rally-in-melbourne-cbd/106084316</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d57adb70f23bb8266eab97c16f2743b</guid></item><item><title>Chaz Mostert wins maiden Supercars title in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/chaz-mostert-wins-maiden-supercars-title-in-adelaide/106084290</link><description>Chaz Mostert breaks through for a maiden Supercars championship after rival Broc Feeney spins out on the opening lap at the Adelaide grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">061635e135f39875db9dfa9b7c103d93</guid></item><item><title>Homes under threat as bushfire bears down on properties in Geraldton suburbs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/waggrakine-moresby-fire-threatens-homes-greater-geraldton/106084318</link><description>Firefighters are defending properties in the outer Geraldton suburbs of Waggrakine and Moresby as a bushfire burned close to homes on Sunday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5208f0ff12f02163d98015c2210bd05</guid></item><item><title>The fire is burning dangerously close to homes in Geraldton.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/the-fire-is-burning-dangerously-close-to-homes-in-geraldton-/106084352</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5acc9b57c6ad991b798f1f5555ad8209</guid></item><item><title>Greenpeace activists scaled a coal ship off Newcastle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/greenpeace-activists-scaled-a-coal-ship-off-newcastle-/106084410</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f215c378999c9c5c2e2b86dbda2c3c17</guid></item><item><title>Port Lincoln sailor feared dead in Mozambique Channel off coast of Africa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/port-lincoln-sailor-feared-dead-off-coast-of-africa/106083612</link><description>The Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade says it is providing consular assistance to the family of an Australian missing in the Mozambique Channel off the coast of Africa.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c024d370def6ce048399a50a991d1bd7</guid></item></channel></rss>