<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 07:07:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Australia's driver courtesy wave dying out, say truckies, but experiment proves wave still alive on back roads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/australian-drivers-truckies-courtesy-wave/106152822</link><description>For generations, the courtesy wave has been etched into the Australian culture, but is it on the verge of dying?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab1044fced53244ab59b2127f9073c74</guid></item><item><title>Drink driver crashes car into the living room of a house in Melbourne's outer west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/drink-driver-crashes-car-into-house-kurunjang/106183644</link><description>A 24-year-old man was taken to hospital after crashing his car into a house in Kurunjang. He failed a breath test at the scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">532a355a3527e94afbb4f93df24736e4</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy says progress made on peace deal, but Donald Trump says 'thorny issues' remain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/trump-meets-zelenskyy-to-discuss-ukraine-peace-plan/106183658</link><description>Volodymyr Zelenskyy says a security guarantee between Ukraine and the US as part of a peace deal is "100 per cent agreed", while Donald Trump says there are still one or two "thorny issues" to finalise in the deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06163790a274f36391c30a19988e561a</guid></item><item><title>Concerns medical weight-loss treatments are being advertised to vulnerable eating disorder patients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/juniper-telehealth-concerns-weight-loss-treatment-glp1/106114626</link><description>Eating disorder bodies are raising concerns about weight-loss treatments being prescribed by telehealth companies, one of which ran a Black Friday sale to promote its services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d11ae8b27f1bc3eef0a9dee97b0a2f</guid></item><item><title>Young women join Country Women's Association Sydney branch in droves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/country-womens-association-cwa-in-sydney-young-women-joining/105941208</link><description>More young women are joining the Country Women's Association's city branches, with a passion for jams and scones along with social connection and purpose.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67607c13646f850e0435fa1c89495c0d</guid></item><item><title>Voter turnout lower than expected in Myanmar's first election since 2020</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/voter-turnout-low-myanmar-first-election-2020/106183648</link><description>Myanmar's election has been widely dismissed as a sham by many governments and human rights activists who have said the military will use proxy candidates to legitimise their rule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d51e58cecc72915c62d1db7781e09955</guid></item><item><title>Travis Head happy to see out Ashes as Australian opener before working out future role</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/australias-travis-head-not-fazed-on-opening-role-in-future/106183666</link><description>Australia star Travis Head says he is not precious about continuing to open the batting beyond this Ashes and will bat wherever the coaches tell him to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">922094f96e3a457a294c7309ef6a65a5</guid></item><item><title>AI powered 2025's economy to record highs. So why are only robots smiling?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/end-of-year-economics-analysis-wrap/106176480</link><description>This year saw economies survive tariff shocks and markets burst through record highs, but it doesn't feel like a party because so many people aren't invited.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6da1698c0a40d26aaf7b2833b7f573d8</guid></item><item><title>Deadly varroa mite threatens half of Canberra’s beehives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/act-varroa-mite-wipe-out-half-bees-two-years/106148658</link><description>A fast-spreading parasite is expected to devastate local bee colonies over the next two years, affecting commercial and backyard crops.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8efde471e61f47b153c0556497f33df6</guid></item><item><title>LGBTQIA+ focused boxing class combatting loneliness amid warnings about social isolation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/lgbtqia-boxing-class-tackling-loneliness/106034550</link><description>One in three adults experience social isolation in what experts say is a "dangerous" issue in society. One suburban boxing group is working to tackle the issue, focused on the LGBTQIA+ community more at risk of loneliness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be1b7e6c38093ce747c6d1f9fa059918</guid></item><item><title>Wet season's arrival prompts moves to shore up food security in Far North Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/flooded-roads-cause-food-insecurity-in-far-north-queensland/106176990</link><description>Earlier this year, a once-in-a-century flood devastated Ingham and cut the main supply route between Cairns and Townsville. Now, as intense rainfall once again triggers multiple warnings and floods roads across northern Queensland, communities are taking steps to prevent another food shortage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9171d9c772b41bbf73794cbd198be777</guid></item><item><title>How vintage black-and-white films are making a splash back in colour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/revitalising-vintage-films/105721412</link><description>Would those classic black-and-white films be the same if viewed in full colour?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">920bdb4c48f10f5d070dc6a984c533b4</guid></item><item><title>Victorian master builder transforms Warrnambool house into castle for his son</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/builder-transforms-warrnambool-home-into-castle-for-son/106176624</link><description>They say "a man's home is his castle," but one builder from south-west Victoria has taken that literally when creating a dream home for his son.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">695b846b83e8f11dbad0909f3c891cba</guid></item><item><title>NSW government sets up hub to assist those impacted by Bondi Beach terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/nsw-government-announces-bondi-hub-for-impacted-locals-re-attack/106184248</link><description>The Bondi Hub will be open to the community and those directly or indirectly impacted by the December 14 shooting at the Chanukah by the Sea event at Bondi Beach, where 15 people were killed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38290ea192f47497f85499cb84648cb0</guid></item><item><title>Australia coach Andrew McDonald says Usman Khawaja will play the final Ashes Test amid retirement speculation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/khawaja-guaranteed-for-scg-future-unclear-after-that/106184310</link><description>Usman Khawaja will play in the Ashes finale at the SCG, but Australian coach Andrew McDonald remains in the dark about the 39-year-old's future beyond that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d906fedef83a721543a674e8516f4cb</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese announces terms for Richardson review of Bondi terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/bondi-breaking-announcement/106184434</link><description>The PM says a former head of ASIO will assess whether multiple security and law agencies worked as effectively as they should have before the attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78790121282cd6631c15dcb53f6684a5</guid></item><item><title>NT police arrest woman for allegedly stealing from patients in Alice Springs Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/elderly-theft-alice-springs-hospital/106184326</link><description>A 30-year-old woman faces court after allegedly stealing from multiple elderly patients recovering from surgery in Alice Springs Hospital over an extended period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dadea0f3cdc0d06e06262cda42d00b4</guid></item><item><title>England's pace bowling stocks stripped bare with Gus Atkinson out of SCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/gus-atkinson-england-ruled-out-scg-test/106184680</link><description>England's pace bowling stocks will be stretched to their absolute limit for the final Ashes Test with Gus Atkinson ruled out with a hamstring injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22aefbd0e149e9e30254a8f87eca7bee</guid></item><item><title>Ahmed Al Ahmed recounts how he disarmed one of the gunmen in Bondi Beach terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/bondi-hero-ahmed-al-ahmed-recounts-story-of-wrestling-gunman/106183900</link><description>Father-of-two Ahmed Al Ahmed, who risked his life to disarm one of the Bondi gunmen during a terrorist attack, says he feels sorry for the 15 people who were killed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6a49f3b62dec473e7ffccc0ed4079a2</guid></item><item><title>The right way to stack your dishwasher and the verdict on rinsing beforehand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/the-verdict-on-rinsing-dishes-before-stacking-the-dishwasher/106022382</link><description>Rinsing can actually send a message to your dishwasher that your plate doesn't need as much washing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b16a5e33ffb32c5a75404f38ecdbd73d</guid></item><item><title>China launches military exercise warning against Taiwan independence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/china-taiwan-military-exercise-independence/106184600</link><description>China has moved its military to surround Taiwan warning against its independence. But Beijing's action has been condemned by Taiwan calling for regional peace and de-escalation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37ecc5e002b8f8f0e07100aae2ff9ccb</guid></item><item><title>Sydney to Hobart competitors tell of 'horrendous' conditions during 2025 race ordeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/2025-sydney-to-hobart-competitors-endure-rough-seas/106184046</link><description>Those now safely onshore after finishing the 2025 Sydney to Hobart tell of "horrendous" conditions, resulting in injuries, broken boats and seasickness — even among experienced crew members.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3d61d78845f12e1a58903944ac9f4eb</guid></item><item><title>Prosecutors wrap up bribery investigation into South Korea's former first lady</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/kim-keon-hee-bribery-accusations/106184962</link><description>Kim Keon Hee, the wife of disgraced ex-president Yoon Suk Yeol, is alleged to have accepted lavish bribes including fine art, jewellery and designer handbags, and to have meddled in state affairs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b0d782413b3369dcb0aae4239acdf2c</guid></item><item><title>Kempsey community marks 10 years since death in custody of David Dungay Jr</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/david-dungay-jr-death-anniversary-rally/106183046</link><description>A decade after his death in a Sydney prison, David Dungay Jr's family hold with a memorial rally calling for change to a corrections system they say still fails to protect Indigenous people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bdd7f9e29a766e460ae327c8d02e857</guid></item><item><title>Slow TV for kids: Relax and unwind with low-stimulation shows on ABC iview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/low-stimulation-kids-tv-shows-stream-iview-abckids/106024290</link><description>Looking for screen-time options that won't leave your kids overstimulated? 'Slow TV' shows, with their soothing visuals and soundtracks, could be the answer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">428e608956327dc581fd5e961f4708a4</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Sydney Test a golden opportunity for Cameron Green to belatedly shine in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/ashes-cameron-green-home-test-struggles/106185032</link><description>He has already proven his quality away from home, but heading into the final Test of the Ashes summer, Cameron Green remains in search of his breakthrough moment in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58a0cbd79c3cf2c39cce515515f91558</guid></item><item><title>Legal loophole in Queensland's double jeopardy law closed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/dna-double-jeopardy-cases-qld-law-changes/106184178</link><description>Last-minute amendments to Queensland's double jeopardy laws could allow for the retrial of botched DNA cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1ca9a578ce596f77c5d8a343e7e5f45</guid></item><item><title>Australia is considered a "lifeboat" region for some threatened rhino ray species, but the numbers worldwide are grim.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/rhino-ray-numbers-northern-territory-indonesia-extinction/106185030</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a7a7eaa5ae38567db7ecf4dd704011b</guid></item><item><title>Man faces court over alleged Boxing Day murder in remote NT community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/greg-shaun-williams-faces-court-over-alleged-boxing-day-murder/106185286</link><description>A 39-year-old man appears in court charged with the stabbing murder of a man in a remote Northern Territory community north of Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5478d4449ea06d23f01082c453ddfd97</guid></item><item><title>Dozens of shark heads dumped outside WA Fisheries minister's office as demersal fishing ban looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/shark-heads-dumped-outside-jackie-jarvis-office-fisheries/106184674</link><description>Hundreds of kilograms of shark heads have been left dumped outside the WA Fisheries minister's office in Margaret River, just three days before a permanent commercial demersal fishing ban comes into effect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52da2612172243bdd59c8424d34d39b0</guid></item><item><title>ICC gives MCG pitch 'unsatisfactory' rating as two-day Test fallout continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/mcg-boxing-day-test-pitch-icc-verdict-unsatisfactory/106185382</link><description>The ICC has handed down their verdict on the controversial MCG pitch which led to this year's Boxing Day Test wrapping up after just two days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3eb403942ca3ba789e82b7d7f5975ab9</guid></item><item><title>Thailand accuses Cambodia of breaching ceasefire deal after 250 drones flown over border</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/thailand-accuses-cambodia-of-breaching-ceasefire-deal/106185620</link><description>Bangkok has accused Phnom Penh of violating the peace deal that was struck on Saturday, after it claimed some 250 drones had been flown over the disputed border region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7147b1fd623dc9f4c30fa238964acc9a</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy says US offers Ukraine 15-year security guarantee as part of peace plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/us-ukraine-peace-plan-15-year-security-trump-zelenskyy/106185584</link><description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy has held talks with US President Donald Trump, and says he would prefer a commitment of 50 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0aa54df231a7cd807859e7b8cfd504cc</guid></item><item><title>Hamas confirms death of ex-leader Mohammed Sinwar and spokesman Abu Ubaida</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/hamas-confirms-deaths-of-mohammed-sinwar-and-abu-ubaida/106185808</link><description>In a statement, the Palestinian militant group also confirmed the death of spokesman Abu Ubaida.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f362a4936393650952976ac9e08b35e</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 30: Beatles star George Harrison stabbed at home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/today-in-history-december-30-george-harrison-stabbed/106171844</link><description>Unlike his former bandmate John Lennon, George Harrison survived an attack by a fan, but the musician's friends and family speculated it hastened his death less than two years later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5de21d23cf56392fd7ed419a58dc08c2</guid></item><item><title>Remembering the celebrities and public figures who died in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/celebrities-public-figures-who-died-2025-obituaries/105869472</link><description>From actors and designers to a Holocaust survivor and a broadcaster, these people made their mark.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8ff6e8e6521b3764b05e9eb7af0051d</guid></item><item><title>Your most read ABC News stories of 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/your-most-read-abc-news-stories-of-2025/106150728</link><description>It was a year that bought us a federal election, ongoing war in the Middle East and Ukraine and a trial in a small Victorian town watched keenly around the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0d7321c1ba593a47553562e53ff4f2d</guid></item><item><title>What happened when we tested a 'safe' AI mental health chatbot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/safe-mental-health-artificial-intelligence-chatgpt/106136202</link><description>Is it possible to make a "safe" AI therapy bot? We tested the limits of a new Australian-designed chatbot that's been carefully designed not to hallucinate or be your best friend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">845b6e5b1edf763fd5784d8b8777cd9e</guid></item><item><title>Household battery uptake booms on back of 'game-changer' rebate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/home-battery-uptake-soars-due-to-government-subsidy/106120730</link><description>Battery uptake is booming since the federal government rebate came into effect in July. Here's what you need to know if you are thinking of joining the thousands of Australians adding a battery to their home solar systems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30708c31c5d2c6ad77f5cc6b6d8e3c4c</guid></item><item><title>ASIC's remarkable turnaround as the tiger that found its teeth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/asic-the-tiger-that-found-its-teeth/106170504</link><description>After 20 years in the wilderness, the Australian Securities and Investments Commission's rehabilitation as a law enforcement agency seems almost complete.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f57bf412f7f38aa6ae3447a6261192d</guid></item><item><title>Josh Burns on juggling politics and fatherhood and being a Jewish MP</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/josh-burns-baby-federal-parliament-georgie-purcell-antisemitism/106162418</link><description>In a broad-ranging interview for the Politics Now podcast, the rising Labor star reveals he plans to take extended leave to care for his baby daughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79bb53732ced6ee8fa0288579b707fca</guid></item><item><title>Vision appears to show attempted carjacking in Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/vision-appears-to-show-attempted-carjacking-in-melbourne/106186022</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9049f7aaa79bd452778e836be32f0bee</guid></item><item><title>Police search for alleged carjacker who was fought off by bystanders in inner Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/vic-police-investigate-carjack-attempt-richmond/106185972</link><description>Police are looking for a man who allegedly tried to steal a woman's car in Richmond earlier this year but was foiled by bystanders, including one person wielding a golf club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26e5e8466580c32f89d01a9fa9f34ac5</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill records seven earthquakes in 2025 — the most in recorded history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/broken-hill-records-seven-earthquakes-2025-most-recorded-history/106171264</link><description>It is not unheard of for the ground to shake in Broken Hill, but what is unusual is the number of earthquakes recorded by Geoscience Australia this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">326190426ea8ff0dda00f320deaf4623</guid></item><item><title>Soft plastics recycling is back in Australia. How does it work and where does it go?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/soft-plastics-recycling-is-back-in-australia-how-does-it-work-/105912070</link><description>Australia's first large-scale soft plastics recycling facility is processing huge loads each day, turning waste into a useful raw material.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d37c808f6bf403492a2a2b8dc150e76</guid></item><item><title>South-east Queensland's largest dam is 'full'. What does it mean?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/qld-how-wivenhoe-dam-works/106166620</link><description>South-east Queensland's largest water reservoir provides drinking water and protection from flooding. So, how does it all work?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f007ea1b086bd4b4b1ac973bbf0b4df</guid></item><item><title>Hobart Hurricanes beat Melbourne Renegades thanks to vital cameo from Matthew Wade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/what-a-difference-a-wade-makes-as-canes-beat-renegades-in-bbl/106186014</link><description>Matthew Wade's fuss-free cameo helps Hobart chase down the Melbourne Renegades's 163 at Bellerive Oval, lifting the Hurricanes well clear of the pack in second spot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcdb9eef9e02f8f842aa649ae744602b</guid></item><item><title>Hiker Stella Thurbon leads herd of goats on trek through Victoria's High Country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/victorian-high-country-hiking-with-a-herd-of-goats/106119216</link><description>With bells tinkling, tails flicking, and panniers packed to the brim, adventurer Stella Thurbon has spent 26 days winding through the Victorian High Country with nine goats trotting faithfully behind her.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6002a583dc507156847c083070b68f08</guid></item><item><title>Noongar elders say WA prescribed burn went ahead despite warnings of cultural heritage sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/noongar-elders-say-sacred-site-warnings-were-ignored-before-burn/106086072</link><description>Elders on WA's south coast say they tried to warn the state government about unregistered cultural sites in the path of a prescribed burn, but the burn went ahead anyway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c864bc1e20cca2ab1cdd845af6e7a45e</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says US 'knocked out' a 'big facility' in Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/trump-says-us-knocked-out-big-facility-in-venezuela/106186078</link><description>A US strike on Venezuelan soil would be the first known land attack in the country since the Trump administration began ratcheting up pressure on its ruling regime, which Donald Trump accuses of "narco-terrorism".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f10cbadecf7188ee83cb32bce91c1d5</guid></item><item><title>Victoria Police make more than 100 arrests, seize 30 weapons during first weeks of shopping centre operations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/vic-police-shopping-centre-arrests/106186088</link><description>A 15-year-old carrying a hunting knife was among more than 100 arrests during the first few weeks of a police operation at four of Melbourne's biggest shopping centres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eebe5b8532f4619245d8ae290a1bd689</guid></item><item><title>Charles Darwin University researchers leading the way in fight to protect globally threatened rays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/rapid-decline-rhino-ray-indonesia-northern-australia/106168084</link><description>Researchers from Charles Darwin University are leading the way in the fight to protect a group of globally threatened fish species, which look like "a shark and ray joined together".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d46b9b263f05e0812c8e68978b30e6a</guid></item><item><title>Deaf people saying no to cochlear implants choosing 'different way of seeing the world'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/cochlear-implants-debate-in-the-deaf-community/106044156</link><description>Cochlear implants can be a life-changing tool for people with hearing loss, but some Deaf people argue their use risks compromising their community's identity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c2c83166ba67cdac1d4df501e80252f</guid></item><item><title>Trump says US struck facility in Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/trump-confirms-us-strike-on-alleged-drug-boat-dock-/106186202</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">873b887bd46204e985409cf5fce9dfe3</guid></item><item><title>Daria Kasatkina set for Brisbane International and Australian Open after mental health break</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/crowds-will-love-her-kasatkina-s-landmark-home-australian-open/106186126</link><description>Daria Kasatkina is being backed to return from her mental health break and quickly become a fan favourite at her new home grand slam, the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b501ed752fb06314d115d319194d988b</guid></item><item><title>The importance of preparing for death and creating an end-of-life health care plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/preparing-for-death-and-creating-an-end-of-life-health-care-plan/105886810</link><description>Dying in sudden, unexpected circumstances is not something people often consider, but there are plenty of reasons to create an end-of-life plan. So why do so few people have one?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5cd6645b8bb831142f96e95a26be9b7</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump calls for Hamas to disarm after meeting with Benjamin Netanyahu</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/donald-trump-calls-hamas-disarm-netanyahu-meeting/106186218</link><description>The US president has been hosting Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu at his residence in Florida for talks on Gaza and several other issues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32b65161fa32767ba4f01bfadf8d2ce8</guid></item><item><title>Overall Sydney to Hobart leader switches as boats race to get ahead of wind change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/tas-sydney-to-hobart-yacht-race-more-boats-finish/106186132</link><description>The two-person crewed BNC is the current favourite to secure an overall victory in the Sydney to Hobart, after crossing the finish line at 10:40 this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">156a49947e5d4819b67e8dd1ddb2c61b</guid></item><item><title>Metal detectorist discovers 1880s Zanzibar coin at Port Macquarie beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/1880s-zanzibar-coin-at-port-macquarie-beach-using-metal-detector/106184392</link><description>Metal detectorist Dale Oldham at first thought he had found a rusted Australian coin, until an online search revealed it was something much older and far more exotic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4210a4b87d548c95164d598de356af04</guid></item><item><title>Trump suggests another attack on Iran if Tehran rebuilds nuclear program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/trump-suggests-another-attack-on-iran/106186094</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b492343c5d335b86998fe1f4620270a4</guid></item><item><title>It's backed by Maggie Beer and researchers alike, so why don't we eat more offal?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/eating-offal-and-why-we-should-eat-more/106093422</link><description>Despite becoming less popular in recent years, advocates like Maggie Beer say offal can be a delicacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46c988bca4e62653baff9eaa39fa9cbb</guid></item><item><title>Record number of NSW Police officers to patrol New Year's Eve events after Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/nsw-police-increase-presence-at-new-years-eve-post-bondi-attack/106185980</link><description>More than 2,500 police officers will be out in force at New Year's Eve celebrations in Sydney in a bid to bolster revellers' confidence in the wake of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86ecb30515d3b6e2eea71ed64622d3aa</guid></item><item><title>Former boxing world champion Anthony Joshua stable, two people dead after car crash in Nigeria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/boxer-anthony-joshua-stable-two-dead-fatal-car-crash-in-nigeria/106186330</link><description>Boxer Anthony Joshua escapes serious injury in a car crash in Nigeria that leaves two of his close friends and team members dead, a week after his multi-million-dollar fight with Jake Paul.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf62d02d3343abbd3ebcd09b72e73b66</guid></item><item><title>Boxer Anthony Joshua involved in deadly car crash in Nigeria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/boxer-anthony-joshua-involved-in-deadly-car-crash-in-nigeria/106186500</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecf762deb8912bbd1a5bb88546a70a37</guid></item><item><title>China hasn't said it wants war in 2026. But it's showing the world it's ready for one</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/chinas-military-drills-around-taiwan-a-message-to-united-states/106186794</link><description>While Donald Trump was distracted, China launched its strongest-ever challenge against Taiwan. Beijing is showing it is ready for war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2396db44fea5a52c39bd09e3d8eb8a9c</guid></item><item><title>Ambulance Victoria reports increase in violence against paramedics over Christmas holiday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/violent-attacks-paramedics-christmas-period-ambulance-victoria/106186398</link><description>Ambulance Victoria says paramedics were assaulted, spat on and sexually harassed in a series of serious incidents over the festive period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6c96067a3fa4ada8769d73de5d41e88</guid></item><item><title>Shoppers spending billions on post-Christmas sales, but small retailers feel forgotten</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/spending-billions-post-christmas-sales-small-retailers-forgotten/106186838</link><description>Outlet centres around Australia were bustling on Boxing Day, but just down the road, some small retailers were feeling the sting. It's a trend that could shape the future of the Boxing Day sales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b88a27e6af003388ee98622e92bcc03e</guid></item><item><title>Donald Bradman's baggy green to go under the hammer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/donald-bradman-baggy-green-auction/106186852</link><description>A baggy green worn by Sir Donald Bradman during the 1947-48 series against India has gone to auction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45a4ea5f89b071b0f9bb4e2772af8c8b</guid></item><item><title>Nick Offerman hopes The Pout-Pout Fish delights tough child critics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/nick-offerman-hopes-the-pout-pout-fish-will-delight-children/106185350</link><description>This Australian animation stars an international and local voice cast led by Nick Offerman and Nina Oyama, who can't wait for children to see the film.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0020d02c138202fc048dfeb5e6b91b11</guid></item><item><title>Gold, silver and palladium prices pull back sharply, worrying some economists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/precious-metals-gold-silver-palladium-crash/106187288</link><description>The price of palladium — used in electronics — tumbles from recent highs while the prices of other precious metals, including gold and silver, have also sharply declined in recent days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09492488be8fcdcec44fb283fd56f0fb</guid></item><item><title>Impact of abbreviated Boxing Day Test stretches far beyond the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/mcg-pitch-boxing-day-test-two-days-losses/106184878</link><description>The economic and social impact of the Boxing Day Test reaches far past the pitch and the repercussions of the two-day finish rippled all across Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d2b4fc5df4f281402988170ecdfbd88</guid></item><item><title>Russia's claim Ukraine attacked Putin's home 'doesn't make any sense', experts say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/putin-drone-strike-ukraine-experts-say-no-evidence-russia/106187456</link><description>A defence analyst tells the ABC an attack on the Russian President's state residence would be "technically" possible but would not make sense strategically for Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0818e8fdaab6370d04a12fe2c8e511f1</guid></item><item><title>NT Environment Protection Authority orders Santos, Inpex licence conditions review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/nt-epa-santos-inpex-licence-review-emissions-error/106185488</link><description>The Northern Territory environment regulator will re-examine the licence conditions of major gas facilities in Darwin, after one of its biggest operators admitted to under-reporting potentially toxic emissions at its Ichthys LNG plant on Darwin Harbour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">366601fe83aede9fa18c4a99b62dc8eb</guid></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia, Bangladesh's first female prime minister, dead at 80</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/khaleda-zia-bangladesh-first-female-prime-minister-dead/106187666</link><description>Begum Khaleda Zia was leader of the main opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party which was seen as the frontrunner to win the next parliamentary election in February.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bbe92168a4742ebaf2972720cbe6e25</guid></item><item><title>Australian laws changed in six important ways in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/australian-laws-change-ubereats-pets-sovereign-citizens/106187302</link><description>From food delivery to sovereign citizens, Australia's laws underwent some important changes this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a18d0b9e12e643b0d2c323088a0972dd</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide public transport, stations and interchanges join list of declared public precincts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/adelaide-public-transport-join-list-of-declared-public-precincts/106187762</link><description>Police have been given expanded powers to search people for weapons on every public bus, train and tram in the Adelaide metropolitan area ahead of New Year Eve's celebrations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">152f1e795e6672267dd0734ad7fde0a8</guid></item><item><title>Here's what we know about the Coral Adventurer, the cruise ship that ran aground in PNG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/coral-adventurer-ran-aground-papua-new-guinea-explainer/106187276</link><description>The Coral Adventurer was carrying 80 tourists into the remote reaches of Papua New Guinea when it came to an abrupt halt on a reef off the Pacific nation's coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c0becda7da09f9389e9cdce6adf9424</guid></item><item><title>Bizzi Lavelle uncovers the hidden history of Blak burlesque in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/blak-burlesque-bizzi-body-lavelle/106148190</link><description>Bizzi Lavelle, a Queer Wakka Wakka and Arrernte writer and burlesque dancer known in the scene as Bizzi Body, is reclaiming the hidden legacy of this art-form one tassel twirl at a time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c77f27ecf9f0afac3611eda7ff1d27f</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian youth alleged to have 'large amount' of child exploitation material on phone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/youth-charged-child-exploitation-material-kik-messaging/106188268</link><description>Police have charged a southern Tasmanian youth after allegedly discovering a "large amount of serious child exploitation material" on his phone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5ddcacaf37a38b865771841a4fa655d</guid></item><item><title>BNC, on brink of historic Sydney Hobart yacht race victory, faces a protest by rival Min River</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/protest-lodged-against-bnc-by-min-river/106188442</link><description>The two-person crewed yacht on the brink of winning the prestigious overall handicap prize in the Sydney to Hobart race is the subject of a protest by a rival, which could potentially deny it victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d63456818dfe61babc72bd9a6cf26b7</guid></item><item><title>Woodford Folk Festival's 38th year platforming Australian artists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/woodford-folk-festivals-thirty-eighth-year/106186650</link><description>More than 110,000 people have already walked through the gates of Woodfordia to be entertained by the 450-plus acts scheduled across the six-day folk festival — now in its 38th year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34d9f8a0bd0948cdb3228890b917263a</guid></item><item><title>South Korea bans bear bile farming with jail for those who breach the law</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/south-korea-bans-bear-bile-farming/106188716</link><description>South Korea is one of the few countries that allow farming to extract bile from bears, for traditional medicine or food believed to promote vitality and stamina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0a7ab9247aa9d1b35313e29e81bf61f</guid></item><item><title>Christmas cruise ends in chaos as Coral Adventurer passengers return home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/christmas-cruise-png-passengers-return-coral-adventurer/106186660</link><description>About 80 passengers on the Coral Adventurer are flown home after the cruise ship ran aground on a reef off Papua New Guinea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a12b92f399d1d29cd366ffaec633591</guid></item><item><title>UAE withdraws personnel from Yemen after Saudi Arabia air strikes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/uae-saudi-arabia-yemen-strikes-port-weapons-shipment/106188568</link><description>The UAE has denied shipping weapons to Yemeni separatists after Saudi-led forces said they had bombed arms at the port city of Mukalla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c078ab15b8e1439c28c250f2d124813</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 31: Vladimir Putin rises to power in Russia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/today-in-history-december-31-vladimir-putin-becomes-president/106174780</link><description>Vladimir Putin has towered over politics in Russia since ascending to the country's top office, initially as president for eight years, then as prime minister until that pesky thing called the constitution could be altered to allow him to run again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">456b7f4837ec6687b85010b33b25ff10</guid></item><item><title>ABC Sports Quiz: The year that was 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/the-year-in-sports-quiz/106177164</link><description>It was another big year in sport, with Ashes series, world cups, world championships and a long-awaited comeback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ed43ddbfba2df7c7423250423ebb073</guid></item><item><title>Kakadu traditional owner says nature has long warned us about rising sea levels</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/nt-kakadu-sea-level-rise-climate-change-saltwater-intrusion/105752820</link><description>In wet season, Jonathan and his family have to drive, boat and drive again if they want to reach town. The remote NT traditional owner says nature has long been warning us about climate change, "but nobody's listening".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c61221d7a7e419755ea7ae07c0f7c52c</guid></item><item><title>Crowd-funding business campaigns falter, despite demand for tipple</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/gluten-free-craft-beer-a-healthier-option-for-drinks-investors-/106175338</link><description>Brewer Richard Jeffares's Victorian company raised about $2.5 million from 993 investors in a matter of days through a method called crowd-sourced funding, also known as equity crowdfunding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77f4b9ad49108a481dfc9b7c3a62283e</guid></item><item><title>Sportsbet pressured key watchdog into 'watering down' enforcement announcement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/sportsbet-pressure-acma-enforcement-announcement/106137264</link><description>Gambling giant Sportsbet pressured the Australian Communications and Media Authority into "watering down" enforcement announcement, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e01de2479c7e314611904a13ca22f4dd</guid></item><item><title>Human-operated Tokyo robot venture allows housebound people to work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/tokyo-robot-tourism-business-cafe-housebound-workers/106177054</link><description>Ory Yoshifuji's Tokyo business employs housebound individuals to operate robots as waitstaff at a cafe and as personal tour guides in the city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee5510266f87235181771f4e5e3fa9b7</guid></item><item><title>What should you do during a violent mass attack?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/what-should-you-do-violent-mass-attack/106179978</link><description>The mass shooting in Bondi and other incidents of mass violence around the world have highlighted that violence can strike anywhere. Here are some expert tips on how to escape, hide, and stay safe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c0de6bec2b16cb24966fa699f71bc8d</guid></item><item><title>Denmark becomes first country in world to end letter delivery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/denmark-postal-service-ends-letter-delivery/106188988</link><description>After 401 years, the Danish postal service has ended letter deliveries as the country fully embraces the digital age.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">527b1a7416978fbdc459d389b139e4a2</guid></item><item><title>Robbers steal $52 million from vault of German savings bank</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/robbers-steal-cash-jewellery-from-vault-of-german-savings-bank/106189018</link><description>According to police, the robbers drilled their way into the underground vault room of the savings bank from a parking garage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7000310909990d0892876846e48a929c</guid></item><item><title>For many South Australians, 2025 could be summarised as the year of searching for answers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/sa-2025-year-in-review-and-search-for-answers/106124586</link><description>As 2025 draws to a close and we look back at the stories that made headlines, for South Australians the year could be summarised as one where we searched for answers, with little results.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b594d8b07c4ab5c74b725ddbde48dc15</guid></item><item><title>Cameron Corner celebrates New Year's Eve three times in one night, on three state borders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/cameron-corner-celebrates-triple-new-years-eve/106186394</link><description>It's more than 1,000km from any capital city, but Cameron Corner, at the junction of the NSW, Queensland and South Australian borders, reckons it has one of the best New Year's Eve parties going around because it is a triple celebration over three time zones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3739c2c1a7356042e97ee0ec6575490</guid></item><item><title>Mechanic shortage driving Queensland businesses to look overseas for qualified workers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/qld-mechanic-shortages/106146022</link><description>The automotive repair industry says it is dealing with a major labour and skills shortage, and some mechanics are looking overseas for workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">677120ce168a39db717bbf44351334a6</guid></item><item><title>ASX ends 'stressful' year with gold and lithium stocks surging despite Trump's trade war threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/asx-ends-stressful-year-with-gold-and-lithium-stocks-surging/106188730</link><description>Several gold, lithium and other mining stocks have seen their share price double, and even triple, in 2025 as Australia's share market has had a much better than expected year despite tariffs, economic uncertainty and Donald Trump's ongoing unpredictability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d40112e062ed5ea83214da84bcdd4bb8</guid></item><item><title>Tatiana Schlossberg, granddaughter of John F Kennedy, dies aged 35</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/jfk-granddaughter-tatiana-schlossberg-dies-aged-35/106189118</link><description>Tatiana Schlossberg revealed in an essay published in November that she had a rare form of terminal leukaemia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">176bba8f13d8b78546e3a13fb3b4b903</guid></item><item><title>Perth Scorchers beat Sydney Thunder by 71 runs in Sydney, Ashton Turner stuck on 99 not out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/turner-stranded-short-of-ton-but-helps-rescue-perths-bbl-season/106189062</link><description>Ashton Turner narrowly misses out on a maiden BBL century as he helps launch Perth to a crucial 71-run win over the Sydney Thunder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8ffa1058e51dd04680c54d7caa49dc7</guid></item><item><title>Flocks of tourists dubbed the 'koala paparazzi' putting animals at risk in Byron Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/tourist-put-byron-bay-koalas-at-risk/106183054</link><description>Large crowds of tourists gather daily at the bottom of trees home to koalas in Byron Bay, leaving the animals stressed and their habitat trampled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb3d6a084b9bc480d26fa3ad7329d0bf</guid></item><item><title>Record year for Australian beef exports despite Donald Trump's tariffs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/record-year-for-aussie-beef-despite-trump-tariffs/106188120</link><description>When Donald Trump enforced a 10 per cent tariff on Australian beef, there were some concerns it would impact trade. But the opposite happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9906a7cbfa515375f6e8f5ee77ad5126</guid></item><item><title>Calls for tighter regulations after Woodside knowingly shed plastic into ocean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/woodside-knowingly-sheds-plastic-into-ocean/106184338</link><description>Documents reveal one of Australia's biggest oil and gas companies knowingly shed plastic into the ocean for two months before notifying the offshore regulator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62d064ab98b320241c481f7d14c044db</guid></item><item><title>Flooding claims a life as deluge cuts north-west Queensland roads, isolates towns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/major-flood-warnings-in-north-west-queensland-towns-isolated/106186966</link><description>Police have renewed warnings about driving in floodwaters after a tragedy in Queensland's Gulf Country as the region endures a fourth day of drenching rain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe978e32493bddcc48a21b19b4ff485e</guid></item><item><title>Aftermath of Saudi strike on Yemeni port</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/aftermath-of-saudi-strike-on-yemeni-port-/106189048</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f1adb519188eccc80b6d589e2df022d</guid></item><item><title>What are the new rules in 2026? Here's what's changing from New Year's Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/2026-new-rules-laws-regulations-come-into-effect/106186738</link><description>New Year's Day brings a host of new laws, regulations and guidelines into effect. Here's a quick breakdown of some of the changes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a403392408ee586524631c7c64585ec2</guid></item><item><title>AI technology gives swimming pool lifeguards an extra set of eyes this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/ai-system-to-help-lifeguards-in-pools-swim-safety/106172140</link><description>An AI system used in 120 public pools across Australia analyses swimmers' movements and sends an alert to a lifeguard's smartwatch if it detects someone in trouble.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4981359265166fe70bf2f7d449ec0d3b</guid></item><item><title>Max Verstappen wins F1 Driver of the Year award for fifth straight year, Oscar Piastri comes fourth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/f1-title-runner-up-verstappen-driver-of-the-year-five-in-row/106189130</link><description>Max Verstappen may not have won the F1 world title, but his fast finish to the year wins him Driver of the Year for the fifth straight year, while Oscar Piastri's disappointing end to the season is mirrored in the voting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">139a9f7e6a9116fb2078199393ba0042</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill gardeners chop down trees in battle with Queensland fruit fly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/fruit-fly-war-in-broken-hill/106179748</link><description>There was no fruit fly to be found in Broken Hill 20 years ago, but now gardeners are facing an uphill battle trying to rid themselves of the pest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce1af482ebd6c6b880eb979a75966489</guid></item><item><title>Calls for national strategy to tackle apprentice hazing and protect workers’ mental health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/tradie-apprentice-workplace-hazing-mental-health-advocates/106173610</link><description>TV presenter and former builder Barry Du Bois is lobbying Canberra for change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f8c43af3c57b7d491903a3ea007e37a</guid></item><item><title>Opening the doors to a unique collection, more than seven decades in the making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/hidden-collection-in-donnybrook-revealed/106139442</link><description>The owner of this sprawling collection of weird, wacky and everyday items hopes it will inspire an appreciation for the past in younger generations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b249edec4996e06cbca083cf038889f</guid></item><item><title>Costumes of Kylie, Rihanna, Lady Gaga, Amy Taylor and more showcased in new DIVA exhibition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/diva-at-ampa-costumes-kylie-rihanna-lady-gaga-marilyn-monroe/106037508</link><description>The exhibition at Melbourne's newest museum, featuring Kylie Minogue's catsuit and Elton John's Louis XIV-inspired 50th birthday outfit, celebrates the power of divas through time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18fbf72148bca9ca91ccd98753dab43b</guid></item><item><title>Min River takes out overall win in 2025 Sydney to Hobart Yacht Race after protest against BNC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/min-river-wins-overall-2025-sydney-to-hobart-successful-protest/106188552</link><description>Double-handed Min River makes history by becoming the first double-handed yacht to take out the overall win in the Sydney to Hobart Yacht Race and the first to do so with a female skipper.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c04f34eb3c878f18a3957e11bc219faf</guid></item><item><title>Former Australian Test batsman Damien Martyn in an induced coma with meningitis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/former-australian-cricketer-damien-martyn-in-induced-coma/106189352</link><description>Former Australian Test and limited overs batsman Damien Martyn is in hospital in Queensland in an induced coma after falling ill this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">000eccb538931e74b5a025d77acd4b72</guid></item><item><title>Promise of bumper coffee crop in 2026 fuelled by explosion of white flowers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/australian-coffee-growers-hope-for-bumper-2026-crop/106177198</link><description>Australian coffee growers are hoping for a bumper 2026 season to meet increased demand for homegrown beans following a prolific flowering season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbc7154a6a59404143386fbf87463625</guid></item><item><title>Fireworks light up cities across Australia as new year's eve celebrations face heightened security</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/new-years-eve-revellers-celebrate-across-australia/106189124</link><description>Revellers welcomed 2026 at various sites across Australia's major cities, including Sydney, where there was a heavy police presence in the wake of the Bondi terror attack earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dfee4cfec47ce3e7087223ef94f3b9c</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Alex Hartley responds to criticism for talking about period on BBC commentary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/alex-hartley-period-chat-bbc-cricket-ashes-commentary/106189540</link><description>Alex Hartley says she was stunned by the reaction to her talking about her period during the BBC's radio commentary of the third Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da608c2e7fa4ac5a89d0568184e22de6</guid></item><item><title>'White Australia' flyer letterbox drop in Newcastle sparks police investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/racist-pamphlets-spark-police-investigation/106189416</link><description>NSW Premier Chris Minns said police would "throw the book" at anyone behind flyers distributed to inner-city Newcastle letterboxes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e058794461c7b877b4797f33d91d706</guid></item><item><title>Crown casino workers in Melbourne announce New Year's Eve strike amid wage row</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/crown-casino-melbourne-workers-strike-new-years-eve/106189942</link><description>About 500 workers at Melbourne's Crown casino will stop work on Wednesday after rejecting a proposal they say will cut pay for new workers and imperil those currently employed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1995448a5ba1b50a8e7da28493f0585</guid></item><item><title>Dolphin Sands residents report looting after bushfire destroys 19 homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/dolphin-sands-residents-concerned-at-looting/106189822</link><description>After 19 homes were destroyed by bushfire in a picturesque east coast Tasmanian community, residents are now reporting instances of looting — described by the state premier as "disgraceful".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1647caee500a6e79557f02b539f1ea03</guid></item><item><title>Kimberley homes lose roofs as emergency services respond to ex-Tropical Cyclone Hayley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/ex-tropical-cyclone-hayley-clean-up-begins-as-damage-assessed/106189586</link><description>Emergency services travel to the Dampier Peninsula to assess the damage caused by the category three system, which crossed the coast on Tuesday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a30f8c7a35af88a6b89594b754b5970f</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos striker Martin Boyle in injury blow for Hibernian</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/socceroos-striker-martin-boyle-in-injury-blow-for-hibs/106190128</link><description>Martin Boyle, no stranger to the heartache of missing major tournaments with the Socceroos, was taken off after injuring his hamstring for Hibernian in the Scottish Premiership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">555f74d5c866789a8613eb2631799bd4</guid></item><item><title>Australia's top glassmakers are the focus of the exhibition Glass Chrysalis II</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/chrysalis-glassmaking-wagga-art-gallery-exhibition/105938918</link><description>The art of glassblowing was popularised in a recent reality TV series, but these Australian artists are forging their own paths in the creative process of sculpting this tricky medium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f5563b4d86d0813f53f80d3286c4f6f</guid></item><item><title>Emergency workers carry away the injured after Machu Picchu train collision</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/emergency-workers-carry-away-the-injured/106190328</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">622193914e686084171d15825d1209ad</guid></item><item><title>Sunshine Coast live music venue The Station to shut down as event bookings drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/sunshine-coast-live-music-venue-the-station-to-shut-down/106189286</link><description>The Sunshine Coast's largest live music venue is shutting down, with the owners stating that they need double the number of bookings to stay afloat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ea077bcc6921d955c042e0e909479a4</guid></item><item><title>How BNC lost the Sydney to Hobart after 'silly mistake' breaches sailing rule</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/explainer-how-bnc-lost-sydney-to-hobart-overall-prize/106189890</link><description>They should be celebrating a historic win — instead, the crew of BNC is coming to terms with how a "silly mistake" cost them the "crown jewel" prize of Sydney to Hobart overall handicap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eaef1d7662aba3eb3b6c2beed60e0a1c</guid></item><item><title>Driver in hit and run that killed woman on Darwin's Bagot road remains at large</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/darwin-hit-and-run-nt-police-investigation-continues/106190254</link><description>The search for a hit-and-run driver who allegedly struck and killed a 27-year-old Indigenous woman on one of Darwin's busiest main roads continues into its fifth day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16412ac2271ea486d0598b6b384b161b</guid></item><item><title>Pet owner's warning as dogs fall ill after beach visit amid algal bloom crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/dogs-fall-ill-ater-visiting-adelaide-beach-algal-bloom/106189458</link><description>Within 20 minutes of leaving an Adelaide beach dogs Lucy and Ella began breathing rapidly and fell "terribly sick", prompting their owner to issue a warning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6cf99b006e293aeae1a112225b2e336</guid></item><item><title>Man drowns and boy missing after boat capsizes at Palm Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/man-drowns-at-palm-beach-sydney-new-years-eve/106190220</link><description>Police confirmed one man has drowned and a 14-year-old boy is missing after their boat capsized at Palm Beach on Sydney's Northern Beaches, with a search and rescue helicopter continuing to search the area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fbf5c54becdf54104160c141ae98e91</guid></item><item><title>Felix Auger-Aliassime hopes for deep Australian Open run after career-best year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/felix-auger-aliassime-united-cup-australian-open/106190574</link><description>After his best year on tour, Canadian star Felix Auger-Aliassime is looking to keep his hot streak running in the United Cup and at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df826417b7ef14f9689a9f9bbaa440aa</guid></item><item><title>Protests in Iran as inflation takes hold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/protests-in-iran-as-inflation-takes-hold/106190568</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">915e9b51b0a209d705134b983a3bb378</guid></item><item><title>Iranian president admits protesters have 'legitimate demands' as inflation fuels unrest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/iran-protesters-have-legitimate-demands-as-inflation-unrest/106190426</link><description>Protests over soaring prices and a collapsing currency are spreading across Iran, with students joining shopkeepers in calling on the government to take action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3a939c8c47bfe3e8dec28488760218e</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday Finance with Dan Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/wednesday-finance-with-dan-ziffer/106190736</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de67f028c9f77fb97d0d9c7d55d8191b</guid></item><item><title>Thailand releases 18 soldiers held since July as part of border conflict ceasefire deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/thailand-releases-cambodian-soldiers-as-part-of-ceasefire-deal/106190984</link><description>The release is a key part of a ceasefire deal struck to bring peace to the border between the two countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c812f28d52cfe83997e8c82a1b02fb90</guid></item><item><title>Nearly 60 female Japanese MPs lobby for more toilets in the nation's parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/female-mps-in-japan-call-for-more-toilets-in-parliament/106191034</link><description>There are just two toilets for women near the main hall in Japan's parliament, with nearly 60 MPs calling for changes to the building to match growing female representation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e61f80b8b17388fbd30e026706503ab</guid></item><item><title>New Year’s 2026: Sydney Harbour celebrations sombre as Australia rings in New Year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/sydney-sombre-new-year-celebrations-/106190882</link><description>An hour before the clock struck 12, the harbour bridge glowed white with its pylons bearing a menorah to commemorate the 15 people killed at a Hanukkah celebration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae30a66cbf6f0d923f0f54cb20552084</guid></item><item><title>Previously secret cabinet documents reveal Howard government tried to mitigate 'homegrown' terrorist threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/revelations-from-previously-secret-2005-cabinet-documents/106150758</link><description>From expectations of a trade union backlash against controversial industrial relations reform, to concerns about "homegrown" extremism in Australia, here are what previously unseen cabinet documents tell us about Australian politics in 2005.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1386303f4de0972e24cc5594c2097e71</guid></item><item><title>Sydney's New Year's Eve fireworks in full</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/sydney-s-new-year-s-eve-fireworks-in-full/106191094</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64c3db7b11190488f5de796674bc8ada</guid></item><item><title>Cabinet records from the Victorian governments of John Cain and Joan Kirner released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/vic-cabinet-records-cain-kirner/106179460</link><description>Previously secret cabinet documents from the Labor governments of John Cain Jr and Joan Kirner have been released to the public for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27bbcdfa2099ea54b3fb3639d20cec0e</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, January 1: Evonne Goolagong wins her first Australian Open title</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/spotlight-evonne-goolagong-wins-first-aus-open-1974/106180298</link><description>After an extended break and a shower, Goolagong changed tactics in the deciding set to sail to victory over American Chris Evert back in 1974.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c0c3483d732ec021918d1c074dbf814</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate hikes, an AI bubble and other as-yet-unanswerable 2026 problems</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/australia-2026-economy-predictions-and-questions/106187042</link><description>Australia’s top economists talk interest rate hikes and market movements.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e627973792e1f8843cac029b60d10423</guid></item><item><title>How running helped Darwin entertainer Shalom Kaa overcome substance abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/how-running-helped-shalom-overcome-substance-abuse/106150666</link><description>Shalom Kaa used to think running was something other people did. But after a series of events that left him at his lowest, running became a big part of his recovery following years of substance abuse with crystal methamphetamines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49a738868cba6d5035490a50b6743278</guid></item><item><title>Countries adopting 'new year's resolutions' with health, economy and internet laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/new-year-new-laws-government-social-media-currency-tax/106175364</link><description>From currency changes to cleaner toilets, here's what is changing around the world in the new year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2e880078f59643f418dbd37dedc4406</guid></item><item><title>2026 quiz: Do you know what events are coming up this year?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/2026-quiz-events-sport-entertainment/106189880</link><description>There's a lot already in the calendar for 2026 in sports, entertainment and politics. Are you ready?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c82c0578a4af92942f7d45cc09c214af</guid></item><item><title>What ABC journalists will be closely watching in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/2026-geopolitics-foreign-affairs-ukraine-gaza-china-bangladesh/106156684</link><description>Disruptions to the world trade system courtesy of Donald Trump and a reshaping of historic alliances as multiple wars drag on have set the stage for a precarious year in global affairs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f73d25420c43a9cd6d2b02dfa81ebf1</guid></item><item><title>Israel banning dozens of aid organisations from operating in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/israel-banning-dozens-of-aid-charities-from-gaza/106191270</link><description>The Israeli government says the organisations have not met new requirements, which include recognising Israel as a Jewish and democratic state and banning any so-called "de-legitimisation" of Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f86f4565065b17d67a76de5724bbe1e0</guid></item><item><title>Double stabbing in popular dining strip in Carlton leaves two men in hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/vic-double-stabbing-in-carlton/106191316</link><description>Two men were taken to hospital with serious injuries after being stabbed in Carlton shortly before midnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61922543ff664e1e8cd526db60fc0121</guid></item><item><title>Australian soldier fighting for Ukraine 'killed week before wedding'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/australian-russell-wilson-was-remembered-as-corageous-soldier/106191082</link><description>Russell Allan Wilson, who spent several years fighting for Ukraine, has been remembered as someone who "gave his life so others could keep theirs".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43145c353f51ff317efa769344db8164</guid></item><item><title>Two people charged after police find explosive devices at a property in Bendigo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/vic-bendigo-firearms-explosives-arrest/106191330</link><description>A man and a woman will face court charged with numerous offences, including manufacturing unauthorised explosive devices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d3159db90fde9d3079a61c836000b7b</guid></item><item><title>Thailand releases 18 Cambodian soldiers under ceasefire agreement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/thailand-releases-18-cambodian-soldiers/106191350</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69afe6e0df676570f7e7982dcf4e453b</guid></item><item><title>Unsealed documents from 1995 Queensland Labor government cabinet detail decision-making processes 30 years later</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/queensland-wayne-goss-cabinet-documents-1995/106172192</link><description>The cabinet documents were originally sealed in 1995. Today, they shed light on the decision-making processes of the government of the day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81e99fb122c19a10408894c994b53008</guid></item><item><title>Floodwaters to linger in north-west Queensland for weeks with heavy rain forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/floodwaters-north-west-queensland-rainfall-weather-new-years/106189794</link><description>Outback towns remain cut off, and floodwaters are expected to linger in the north-west for weeks. Graziers have started to assess their properties and count stock losses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71ac83feee2c563cf465f57ac98bf41e</guid></item><item><title>Around the world people celebrate new year and hope 2026 brings peace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/people-celebrate-new-years-eve-around-world/106191346</link><description>Around the world there have been some colourful and imaginative ways of ringing in the new year, with some places forgoing traditional fireworks out of respect for disasters in 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b74c10eb721bba25dec16e8718bcdda5</guid></item><item><title>High-dose MDMA warning for revellers attending Sydney's Field Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/nsw-holder-nyd-music-festival-drug-warning/106190504</link><description>A pill testing trial has been expanded to Sydney's Field Day music festival, but authorities are urging partygoers not to be complacent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d13e73e39cd565120be97de8219ca974</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Roar coach Michael Valkanis's send-off sparks half-time clash with Central Coast Mariners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/police-called-in-roar-mariners-a-league-half-time-tunnel-clash/106191366</link><description>The fallout from Brisbane Roar's spiteful A-League clash with Central Coast continues, with the Roar "considering all options" after comments from Mariners coach Warren Moon following a send-off for Brisbane coach Michael Valkanis that prompted a half-time confrontation in Gosford.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2199dd7748597e9436c444e1885ef8c3</guid></item><item><title>Morse code lovers and navy trainers help skill live on in a world of digital technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/morse-code-navy-telegraph-station-amateur-radio/106141386</link><description>Even as digital technology continues to evolve, "Morsecodians" aim to preserve a once-essential way to communicate across the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9c6dfc4295e251063ec22df8781b036</guid></item><item><title>Amateur filmmakers remake Jurassic Park shot by shot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/amateur-filmmakers-remake-jurassic-park-shot-by-shot/106127844</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85fbc0a9536edc49699f1763f71130cf</guid></item><item><title>Jurassic Park fan fulfils childhood dream of recreating Jeep</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/jurassic-park-fan-fulfils-dream-of-building-jeep-in-film/106127626</link><description>Zakary Weyer's obsession with Jurassic Park drove him to learn different skills to build a replica of the Jeep that appears in the iconic blockbuster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbb924050916e9eae4b5101cb3ed8759</guid></item><item><title>The nudists baring it all to address misconceptions about naked beach culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/nude-beach-naturism-decline-australia/106123544</link><description>Half a century after the first nude beach opened in Australia, these naturists say they are still fighting to keep beaches open and misconceptions at bay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e2261d54bc8210798ccae948700b720</guid></item><item><title>Chris Lynn wins Adelaide Strikers' New Year's Eve BBL game against Brisbane Heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/chris-lynn-adelaide-strikers-beat-brisbane-heat-in-bbl/106191468</link><description>Former Brisbane star Chris Lynn clobbers the Adelaide Strikers to an easy victory over the Heat in the New Year's Eve Big Bash League clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56be196a0a2a8ee63d3cbd369e5efdae</guid></item><item><title>Handwritten letters among items in the unsealed case file of hanged murderer Jean Lee</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/last-woman-executed-in-australia-jean-lee-melbourne/106186652</link><description>Jean Lee and her two co-accused were executed for murder in 1950. Handwritten letters from the trio are among items publicly available for the first time since their trial captured the nation's attention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01afeaa2dc091c3b9be4a1f4e81ffb8f</guid></item><item><title>Four titan arum 'corpse flowers' to bloom in a week at Cairns Botanic Gardens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/four-titan-arums-simultaneously-flower-in-cairns-botanic-gardens/106190260</link><description>Renowned for their size and stench, blooming corpse flowers are a rare occurrence. But to have four flowering in a week is "something of a record".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb7d7cc23915ad1269387ece32f2c817</guid></item><item><title>Police happy with Victorian NYE revellers despite multiple arrests and illegal fireworks injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/police-happy-with-melbourne-new-years-eve-revellers/106191446</link><description>Police make 18 arrests and several people are taken to hospital for injuries related to illegal fireworks as Victorians see in the new year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02d7743728860292e8f187b030898c75</guid></item><item><title>Three drown, man and teenage boy missing in multiple coastal emergencies off NSW waters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/woman-dies-at-maroubra-beach-while-two-others-missing-in-sydney/106191480</link><description>A man and two women have died and two people are missing following four separate incidents on Sydney waters over the past 48 hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15f036013ff303c79a58b9e1f51234ac</guid></item><item><title>Australian woman says she is lucky to walk away from Machu Picchu train crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/australian-recalls-fatal-train-crash-machu-picchu-peru/106191182</link><description>Jo Needham was halfway through a "bucket list" trip across South America when she was flung from her seat on a train near the ancient tourist site of Machu Picchu.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afb659f64d2d7bc6b61c3930197bf09c</guid></item><item><title>New Year's Day bushfire sparked by firecracker prompts emergency warning east of Perth Airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/bushfire-emergency-in-maida-vale-kalamunda-near-perth-airport/106191548</link><description>Police charge a man who allegedly threw a firecracker and sparked an emergency-level bushfire in the Perth Hills that left thousands of people without power and threatened lives and homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12a9c8390bf948c419ac3a2a2578cd43</guid></item><item><title>The Bloomfield River cod is the world's only tropical freshwater cod</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/bloomfield-river-cod-is-worlds-only-tropical-freshwater-cod/106097432</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9445f976b28e3803a50943256b0efde</guid></item><item><title>Rare freshwater Bloomfield River cod surviving amid environmental threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/rare-freshwater-fish-bloomfield-river-cod-research/106091448</link><description>The Bloomfield River cod, found in a far north Queensland river catchment, is the world's only tropical freshwater cod, and scientists are working to have it officially protected amid threats from the climate and introduced species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00b5b370eec6e80cd550610dddb90088</guid></item><item><title>Permanent commercial demersal fishing ban begins for large part of WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/permanent-commercial-demersal-fishing-ban-begins-for-part-of-wa/106182868</link><description>From today, commercial demersal fishing is banned along hundreds of kilometres of the WA coastline in an effort to recover fish species numbers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2b9a6a2246d889c750fc2d0dcfefe13</guid></item><item><title>The Harvest at Wild Horse Plains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/harvest-at-wild-horse-plains/106171614</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">544a3b3e4885b86d54b53c2834a25812</guid></item><item><title>Farmer restores and puts vintage harvester to work 95 years after its first season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/95-year-old-vintage-harvester-restored-wild-horse-plains/106186626</link><description>While most farmers search for the newest technology to help with harvest, Leigh Baker has worked to bring a 95-year-old piece of equipment back to life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a96f456a44fb08b6bce263b2de1b4b92</guid></item><item><title>US military attacks 'narco-trafficking' boats in international waters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/us-strikes-boats-in-international-waters-looking-for-survivors/106191618</link><description>US military forces have carried out strikes against three boats in international waters in the Pacific Ocean. Eight people are reported to have survived.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">141f2172806305635f5d0cc3a93c3733</guid></item><item><title>New Year's fireworks light up Hobart as crowds celebrate at Taste of Summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/in-photos-hobart-celebrates-new-year/106191504</link><description>Thousands of Tasmanians have brought in 2026 at Hobart's waterfront and the Taste of Summer festival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9374eae97d1eb545f10982a58f5ccaa</guid></item><item><title>Unsealed cabinet records from 1995 reveals government spend on poker machines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/nt-unsealed-cabinet-records-1995-government-euthanasia-pokies/106184556</link><description>It was the year TLC's Waterfalls topped the charts and Windows 95 launched in stores, but in 1995 the Northern Territory made history by becoming the first place in the world to legalise voluntary assisted dying.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd394ece8a2651070aa39323fff4f908</guid></item><item><title>US military vision shows strikes on alleged drug boats on 30 December 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/us-military-vision-shows-strikes-on-alleged-drug-boats/106191740</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">614dc6bb2f9d14ac71a682196ae1dda7</guid></item><item><title>Lorin's father, satirist John Clarke, had a story to tell so she recorded their conversations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/capturing-memories-on-tape/106043904</link><description>When Lorin Clarke asked her father, satirist John Clarke, if she could start recording their conversations, she thought it would just be for them. But when he tragically died aged 68, one year after the recordings began, Lorin felt his story belonged to more than just her.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f795731f7aa749acc76bbe61db22fc0e</guid></item><item><title>Police praise Sydney New Year's Eve behaviour amid emotional celebrations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/police-praise-sydney-new-years-behaviour-amid-emotional-events/106191486</link><description>Sydney welcomes the new year in a display of colour, emotions and tributes almost three weeks after the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ff3db5cb8cf7ea1a31641fcb0782225</guid></item><item><title>France reportedly planning social media ban for under-15s</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/macron-proposes-under-15-socials-ban-local-media-reports/106191774</link><description>President Emmanual Macron's government will soon submit draft legislation banning children under 15 from using social media, according to French media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe89a781231d6d25ef2c3d7c9e2b54fe</guid></item><item><title>Republican Lauren Boebert suggests Donald Trump veto could be Epstein files 'retribution'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/donald-trump-clashes-with-lauren-boebert/106191788</link><description>A month after Donald Trump's spectacular falling-out with MAGA firebrand Marjorie Taylor Greene, another Republican congresswoman publicly lashes out at the US president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4388484e7524de96cc4745e912eb110e</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins, Josh Hazlewood and Tim David named in Australia's T20 World Cup squad despite injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/pat-cummins-josh-hazlewood-in-australia-t20-world-cup-squad/106191918</link><description>Pat Cummins, Josh Hazlewood and Tim David are all included in Australia's 15-player squad for next month's men's Twenty20 World Cup in Sri Lanka and India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb632060256cd1ba342303369a50676e</guid></item><item><title>Queen Camilla recalls being 'furious' after being indecently assaulted by man on train as a teenager</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/camilla-interview-assault/106191760</link><description>The monarch speaks publicly about the attack for the first time during an interview with BBC Radio 4's Today programme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b94fe21ce2e01b7117775bb29fa70e8</guid></item><item><title>Australian meat industry warns China's new beef tariff impact will be 'severe'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/china-hits-australian-beef-industry-with-tariff/106191726</link><description>Meat Industry Council says it is "extremely disappointed" as China imposes a tariff on Australian beef imports that could cost $1 billion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b621256dd48d3d4b69ad87156798c3e3</guid></item><item><title>Eight-year-old boy mints world's first coin of 2026 after winning Royal Australian Mint ballot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/royal-australian-mint-ballot-first-coin-2026/106192014</link><description>Hundreds of coin collectors forwent the late-night revelry of New Year's Eve in favour of an early morning visit to the Royal Australian Mint in Canberra, hoping to get their hands on the highly sought-after first coin of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">758d5076398daf9e6167f7de49d9a129</guid></item><item><title>Beaches closed amid search for missing swimmer, teenager.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/beaches-closed-amid-search-for-missing-swimmer-teenager/106192130</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c95759a0f79ecd556f1cf9438e88c7d5</guid></item><item><title>Rescue authorities search for missing man on Coogee Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/rescue-authorities-search-for-missing-man-on-coogee-beach/106192206</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cc9b918142f8b19e81963fc1cfb8b9f</guid></item><item><title>Boy, 15, dies in e-bike crash in Tasmania's north on New Year's Eve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/teen-72yo-killed-in-separate-new-years-eve-crashes/106191780</link><description>A 15-year-old boy has died in an e-bike crash on New Year's Eve, described by Tasmanian police as "tragic" and prompting a call for riders to comply with the law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">161ceddb5bbca6b8089d434c7b4f0c36</guid></item><item><title>Boxer Anthony Joshua discharged from hospital after car crash in Nigeria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/boxing-champion-anthony-joshua-discharged-hospital-crash/106192240</link><description>British former world heavyweight boxing champion Anthony Joshua is discharged from hospital days after a car accident that killed two of his close friends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08b751e022153430fd5153e760395f3e</guid></item><item><title>Amyl and the Sniffers singer Amy Taylor files lawsuit against photographer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/amyl-and-the-sniffers-photos-lawsuit/106191940</link><description>Punk rock frontwoman of Amyl and the Sniffers Amy Taylor has filed a lawsuit against an American photographer alleging that photos taken for a magazine photo shoot are being sold against her wishes and without her permission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a2b281bb73710fe99dc7b3ff37257b4</guid></item><item><title>Australian K-pop idol Danielle dropped from NewJeans and sued for more than $44 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/danielle-dropped-from-newjeans-and-sued-for-more-than-44-million/106192180</link><description>An Australian K-pop idol caught up in a bitter dispute with her former record label is sued for more than $44 million and dropped from her group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13768ab78af9baeb927ceb1994c871af</guid></item><item><title>SA Police arrest 72 people over New Year's Eve celebrations, including three teens over alleged stabbing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/three-teens-arrested-after-12yo-girl-allegedly-stabbed-adelaide/106191974</link><description>SA Police say 72 people were arrested and 10 were reported for offences overnight across the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1976527ab77b8921c852afb65805921</guid></item><item><title>The strategic plays that may have driven Israel's recognition of Somaliland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/israel-recognition-of-somaliland-comes-amid-tension-in-yemen/106189542</link><description>Israel, suffering international isolation, has recognised a small territory desperate for international attention. Here's why it has caused an enormous stir.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a49565f6d00a30653a30444fc34edd1b</guid></item><item><title>In Dear Life, Brooke Satchwell connects with the recipients of her late fiance's organs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/brooke-satchwell-dear-life-robyn-butler-wayne-hope/106118712</link><description>New Aussie drama Dear Life, from the creators of Upper Middle Bogan, looks at the strange and destructive ways people grieve — and how they live on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1243d86743abf674e8fbfbffb31ef0b</guid></item><item><title>Scepticism as Russia claims video proves Ukrainian drone attack on Putin residence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/russia-says-video-proves-ukraine-tried-to-strike-putin-residence/106192222</link><description>Moscow's allegation that Ukraine launched an attack on the Russian president's state residence is being dismissed as a ploy to derail peace talks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">421f0a3b49fc9a74191fd6f3d75a3d31</guid></item><item><title>Irish man, 35, drowns at Whitehaven Beach on New Year's Eve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/irish-man-whitehaven-beach-drowning-new-years-eve/106192666</link><description>Police are preparing a report for the coroner as authorities urge holiday-makers to follow safety advice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa793babfb44b038b895e4a91162b792</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says National Guard being removed from Chicago, LA and Portland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/donald-trump-says-national-guard-pulled-from-chicago-la-portland/106192734</link><description>US President Donald Trump says his administration is removing the National Guard from Chicago, Los Angeles and Portland, but added federal forces will "come back" if crime rates go up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed5e020287a9a82751927b7bab2a21b4</guid></item><item><title>Grey nurse shark rescue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/grey-nurse-shark-rescue/106190362</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4978cfeeedf89c7c5b98a8a5fe7b097d</guid></item><item><title>Millennium Falcon the last boat to finish the 80th Sydney to Hobart yacht race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/banged-up-millennium-falcon-last-in-sydney-to-hobart/106192678</link><description>A boat named after a Star Wars spacecraft is the final entry to finish the Sydney to Hobart yacht race, after facing a range of issues at sea and extremely rough weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbafe774d380dd851795fdbe8d388325</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian man charged over alleged concealed camera in Kingston Beach public toilet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/man-charged-alleged-hidden-camera-kingston-beach-public-toilet/106192780</link><description>A southern Tasmanian man aged in his 20s is charged after allegedly using a concealed video recording device to film a woman using a public toilet on New Year's Eve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02362f85f42400f5d85ff9969e2e820f</guid></item><item><title>New York City welcomes 2026 with Time Square ball drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/new-york-city-welcomes-2026-with-time-square-ball-drop/106192836</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf497dadae35895eccf2035050e50f5e</guid></item><item><title>Zohran Mamdani sworn in as NYC mayor with midnight subway oath</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/zohran-mamdani-sworn-in-as-nyc-mayor-with-midnight-subway-oath/106192224</link><description>Zohran Mamdani is officially sworn in as major of New York City in a midnight, underground ceremony, with a more public affair to take place in hours time on the steps of City Hall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6014b207fdfdf1b13807a2bb5a8552b</guid></item><item><title>Australian Winter Olympian Tess Coady fully fit for Milan-Cortina Games, after Beijing bronze medal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/aussie-coady-fit-and-firing-in-time-for-italy-winter-olympics/106192850</link><description>Fully-fit Australian snowboard medallist Tess Coady is looking forward to competing in the Winter Olympics next month in Italy after a torrid run with injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fb070f921f451b8f6b2e9bd695d9f99</guid></item></channel></rss>