<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 11:39:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>What to know about the international flotilla that sought to break Israel's blockade of Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/what-to-know-about-global-sumud-flotilla-gaza/105842900</link><description>The activists expected Israeli authorities to intercept them, as has happened in past flotilla attempts to reach Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4684825a8da0061bdbad1d685ccd055</guid></item><item><title>Tesla and SpaceX CEO Elon Musk becomes world's first person to be valued over $500 billion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/elon-musk-worlds-richest/105844954</link><description>The Tesla and SpaceX CEO's net worth hit $US500 billion ($755 billion) on Wednesday, the "Real-Time Billionaires" tracker reported.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f5f4348c0e522fc29cd9a6ee3775837</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with lighting fires after start of fire bans in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/alleged-chinchilla-fire-starter-in-court-during-qld-fire-ban/105842770</link><description>A 27-year-old man has been charged with deliberately setting fire to bushland in Blackswamp, south-west Queensland, during a total fire ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">043ca5e23eb0529cbc5cb8bf7e1966fc</guid></item><item><title>South West Aboriginal Medical Service members expelled after allegedly 'storming' headquarters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/south-west-aboriginal-medical-service-members-expelled/105835570</link><description>The South West Aboriginal Medical Service has expelled several of its members who it has accused of sowing community division.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d58f590226ffd5ec4e623b45427995e</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies bolstered by Will Skelton's return for Bledisloe Cup Test against All Blacks in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/wallabies-all-blacks-bledisloe-cup-rugby-championship/105845674</link><description>The Wallabies regain enforcer Will Skelton for Saturday night's sold-out Bledisloe Cup Test in Perth, but veteran fly half James O'Connor is dropped to the bench.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77cf19e4d52cf3a8b1ad279f6be25948</guid></item><item><title>Review finds Barkly bushfire overwhelmed authorities and killed 37,000 cattle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/barkly-fire-killed-thousands-of-cattle-review-finds/105842564</link><description>The fire threatened communities, destroyed more than 3,500km of fencing and cost the NT's cattle industry an estimated $120 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf2f515eef61b0484d09c2a9ceec4e9f</guid></item><item><title>Fertility treatments impacted by donor limit mix-up can proceed under NSW Health exemption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/fertility-treatments-to-proceed-after-nsw-health-exemption/105845260</link><description>Fertility treatments in NSW will be able to continue even in cases where the family donor limit has been breached after the state government issued a temporary exemption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7a47a0b5e094fc99008d0d76761db5b</guid></item><item><title>Colonnades, Modbury, Tea Tree and Rundle Mall among latest shopping centres to become Declared Public Precincts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/colonnades-modbury-tea-tree-plaza-rundle-mall-public-precincts/105844740</link><description>Three Adelaide shopping centres are among the latest sites where police can search for knives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e424510c86d4274f12853bc186cfbf98</guid></item><item><title>Coutts Crossing bushfire downgraded from emergency to advice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/coutts-crossing-bushfire-emergency-nsw-north-coast/105845190</link><description>A day into the bushfire season, a blaze threatening more than a dozen buildings in the Clarence Valley has been downgraded after escalating to an emergency level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">883abe4989535ef75a9a275843e0cfd0</guid></item><item><title>Canberra cyclist captures 'incredible' moment magpie plucks earphone from his ear on camera</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/magpie-swoop-pluck-earphone-from-ear-captured-camera/105845372</link><description>A Canberra man has captured footage of the dramatic moment a magpie plucked his earphone from his ear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b576bf57bf07e8e6ec534073ae5af4a1</guid></item><item><title>Demons meet with Clayton Oliver amid rumoured exit from AFL club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/afl-melbourne-demons-clayton-oliver-christian-petracca/105845936</link><description>Clayton Oliver appears set to leave Melbourne after the Demons reveal they will not stand in his way if he wants to consider a trade to another club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd9730e9523ad122afacace37169f5a2</guid></item><item><title>Broncos respond to Storm star Stefano Utoikamanu's 'stuck up' barb ahead of NRL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/nrl-grand-final-brisbane-broncos-melbourne-storm/105846050</link><description>The mind games continue in the build-up to Sunday's season decider, with the Broncos reacting to Storm front-rower Stefano Utoikamanu's sledge earlier this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">108176c74a5c4c7627684927f34b7745</guid></item><item><title>Endangered numbats stressed by over-eager nature photographers, authorities say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/photographers-urged-to-maintain-distance-from-numbats-wa/105844130</link><description>Authorities say getting to close to numbats can make them anxious enough to abandon their young and are urging photographers to give the endangered animals their space.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67cb631989ddbc5dd6344e8eb42942fe</guid></item><item><title>Mildura leaders label Qantas staff base closure a 'slap in the face' to region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/closure-of-mildura-qantas-staff-base-slammed-by-politicians/105839232</link><description>Regional politicians unanimously condemn Qantas over the impending closure of its Mildura crew base, saying it underscores the city's vulnerability to the "whims" of private transport companies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36df8aca49b62a9d5ccd4097b776a5df</guid></item><item><title>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy accuses Russia of raising nuclear risk after Chernobyl power cut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/ukraine-accuses-russia-of-raising-nuclear-risk-chernobyl/105846000</link><description>Volodymyr Zelenskyy said more than 20 Russian drones had been deployed in the attack on the town of Slavutych that cut power to the nearby Chernobyl plant for three hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdc2f2d1ffa9520461b858bd3a31e5c0</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/105846282</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40beaae9cbc027d987206ec2f8fee66f</guid></item><item><title>Review into senior NT police appointments made under ousted commissioner released to the public</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/review-into-nt-police-senior-appointments-released/105845308</link><description>An inquiry into recruitment processes for senior NT police positions recommends "significant improvements", noting there are "widely held beliefs" that "bias", "favouritism" and "nepotism" have impacted promotions within the force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">439354def5398861162db68ac6aadc7b</guid></item><item><title>BBC exposes hidden culture of misogyny and racism inside UK Police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/bbc-filming-exposes-hidden-culture-of-misogyny-and-racism-inside/105846128</link><description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer has called for a "robust" response by the head of London's Metropolitan Police after an undercover investigation exposed the force's hidden culture of misogyny and racism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a5e49ee8734de794306f0e01d0f37e5</guid></item><item><title>Protesters restrained at snap pro-Palestinian rally at Sydney Town Hall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/nsw-floatilla-protest-sydney-town-hall-police-restrain/105846204</link><description>The unauthorised event was held in response to the interception of a Gaza-bound aid flotilla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d349b964559368d88442b48dbc749c73</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm and Brisbane Broncos face off in NRL Grand Final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/melbourne-storm-and-brisbane-broncos-face-off-in/105846424</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7c17a506df456fc9c620d5c07d1e268</guid></item><item><title>Japan's top contenders for prime minister are an 'Iron Lady' and the son of a former PM</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/japan-next-prime-minister-candidates-are-starkly-different/105843004</link><description>Japan's Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba is stepping down as leader after only a year in the role. It has left his party looking for a new face — and the frontrunner options could not be more different.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a64b8b4367e615f378ad174a6e30f17</guid></item><item><title>Sexual predator taught in Brisbane schools for nine years after parents' complaints</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/brisbane-schools-sexual-predator-teacher-complaints/105822874</link><description>Even after putting a stop to their abuser's access to students, Alliyah faced an uphill battle to get basic information about what had happened behind the scenes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">995443c9f91e6f16d7611a4494aeaf37</guid></item><item><title>COP climate talks are 'heartbreak' for Pacific Islands. Here is why they want to host them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/pacific-cohosting-cop-31-climate-change/105834230</link><description>The global COP climate talks have been a source of frustration and disappointment for Pacific nations. They hope hosting the event will change that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4b14479d18ffc36161728080a2125fc</guid></item><item><title>Were you paying attention to this year's NRL season? Test your memory here</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/nrl-2025-season-quiz/105844022</link><description>There are just four halves left of the NRL and NRLW seasons this year. As we get ready for the grand final this Sunday, test your memory on the year that was.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4f239501101ad6444c2b76292a4e657</guid></item><item><title>As Dezi Freeman search goes on, Porepunkah businesses wait for government support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/porepunkah-business-waiting-financial-support-dezi-freeman/105845384</link><description>Businesses hurt by stay-away orders issued during the search for alleged police killer Dezi Freeman say they have yet to receive the government support they were promised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e19a0607dc2b3d096b10370f40e57ff</guid></item><item><title>Mascots, superfans prepare to shine in NRL grand final clash between Storm and Broncos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/qld-nrl-superfans-mascots-grand-final-broncos-storm/105845318</link><description>As the Brisbane Broncos prepare to take on the Melbourne Storm in Sydney on Sunday, fans and mascots are gearing up for the match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6603d035702db9d3ce9f7f90d88f6b54</guid></item><item><title>Superfan moved to tears after Broncos prelim win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/superfan-moved-to-tears-after-broncos-prelim-win/105846294</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fa83af8fb0313f93621ef6b79233b7d</guid></item><item><title>Hollywood director James Cameron opens up on AI, future Terminator films and the Avatar franchise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/james-cameron-ai-avatar-terminator-films/105840784</link><description>The Hollywood director has been present in the film space for many years but the emergence of AI and its power has him somewhat scared for the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5b6816d043cafca9efcdcda90714b4f</guid></item><item><title>Jane Goodall changed how we thought about chimps. Why did we know so little before?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/jane-goodall-death-why-we-knew-so-little-about-chimpanzees/105843330</link><description>In the chimp world, there was the time before Jane Goodall and the time after. This is the reason we knew so little about the great ape before 1960, according to the woman who dedicated her life to humankind's closest cousins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">572926e6282ff94c6f46f75de5805dae</guid></item><item><title>Bendigo nurses call for hospital mental health hub as ED presentations climb</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/nurses-call-for-mental-health-hub-at-bendigo-hospital/105840548</link><description>An increase in mental health and drug-related emergencies puts strain on Bendigo hospital's emergency department, prompting calls for a dedicated treatment hub.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c0de9a4d977eb2ecb8d406519aca81c</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon says he wants to get force's culture 'right'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/new-nsw-police-commissioner-mal-lanyon-stateline/105845430</link><description>The new commissioner of NSW Police does not believe there is still a "boys' club" within the force, but says behaviour that prompted a workplace culture review will not be accepted under his leadership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b9d517e4455ac65cdd6d31ceb09532a</guid></item><item><title>Community comes together as search for missing 4yo Gus enters seventh day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/search-for-missing-boy-gus-enters-seventh-day/105845972</link><description>The search for missing four-year-old Gus has entered its seventh day, with no new signs of the boy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae5919e64d67cdd5c968e28dd35f55b0</guid></item><item><title>Hawthorn beats Fremantle by 15 points as gritty performance proves AFLW top-four credentials</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/hawks-prove-aflw-top-four-credentials-with-tough-win-over-freo/105847060</link><description>Hawthorn posts a third consecutive AFLW victory to boost its top-four hopes, outlasting Fremantle in cold and windy conditions in Frankston.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a72ff41e01a7fdcc21a95c419f64182</guid></item><item><title>Mind games and magic as Maguire and Bellamy battle it out for NRL supremacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/nrl-grand-final-roy-masters-2025-preview/105838296</link><description>Craig Bellamy and Michael Maguire know each other better than most NRL coaches, and that familiarity will play a major part in how they tackle the NRL grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f0764586bc67adb2b1fd85c05e3b384</guid></item><item><title>Outback residents lose solar farm as Ergon battles push owner to close</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/normanton-solar-farm-turns-off-after-ergon-energy-negotiations/105843958</link><description>The owner of a huge solar farm in outback Queensland hits the kill switch after almost a decade, saying his contract with Ergon Energy was unfair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d66d8ac5f8725a41e5ce4bbcfda73e48</guid></item><item><title>Housing crisis, massive cows and canola fields visible from space feature in our top September news photos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/september-photo-wrap/105836854</link><description>From gargantuan cows to Canola fields visible from space, here are our top photos from WA's first month of spring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fd14132c025578a2fa6734757a965cb</guid></item><item><title>WA gold projects forecast to create more jobs than iron ore in next five years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/job-opportunities-in-gold-mining-surge-as-confidence-booms/105816580</link><description>The gold-mining sector is set to boost WA's economy, with 2,400 new jobs forecast over the next five years compared to 1,200 in iron ore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a04a633d449ab31d0999b87c11c53b3</guid></item><item><title>Vladimir Putin swipes back at Donald Trump's 'paper tiger' comment, sends warning to NATO</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/vladimir-putin-swipes-back-at-donald-trump-paper-tiger/105847048</link><description>The Russian president says it is NATO that is the "paper tiger," and "if anyone still has a desire to compete with us in the military sphere, as we say, feel free, let them try".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a18d3f1ad6b0568eb4154f5b2acf85d</guid></item><item><title>ASX rises as DigiCo surges as Telstra fined $18m over misleading customers — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/105847156</link><description>The ASX has made modest gains after trading flat early on, as a slide for energy producers offset gains for industrial, healthcare and tech stocks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81fe3fdb111272da960ac13234d5bc7a</guid></item><item><title>Zach Merrett's Essendon future in Bombers' hands despite star's apparent best and fairest farewell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/zach-merrett-future-in-essendon-hands-best-and-fairest/105847122</link><description>Zach Merrett's speech after winning Essendon's best and fairest seems like a farewell, but it will be up to the Bombers as to whether the captain is allowed to leave the club in the AFL trade period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1108ff7c2a5cc348cfe10a2a9f3b2fb2</guid></item><item><title>Family of man killed in level crossing crash says safety trial a 'waste of time'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/ethan-hunter-mum-says-level-crossing-safety-trial-waste-of-time/105830854</link><description>Ethan Hunter's mother says governments have failed to learn from her son's death at a level crossing in regional New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">272fe29f80e9b45182b8950f0bf577fc</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters tackle Brisbane bushfire, dozens of other incidents after hot weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/brisbane-bushfire-warning-issued-after-unusually-hot-weather/105847132</link><description>Queensland firefighters tackling scores of incidents, including a bushfire about 20 kilometres north of Brisbane now downgraded after police made an emergency declaration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01e2c8f64ee747e83fb700528bbcb26b</guid></item><item><title>Revised corridor for New England REZ leaves Walcha residents 'shocked'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/walcha-residents-shocked-at-revised-transmission-corridor-rez/105842964</link><description>Property owners in the path of a proposed new route for the New England renewable energy zone corridor fear their land values will plummet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec4bbfacc4b08613f739bd1cfd4c7f75</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja prepares for Australia's monumental Ashes summer, unafraid of 'the end'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/usman-khawaja-on-cricket-religion-and-the-end/105847220</link><description>Usman Khawaja is riding his late-career resurgence into another Ashes summer, and says his comfort with an inevitable end has inspired it all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01d27eb1d14f1f2ebcf664c5d5b80e2c</guid></item><item><title>Darwin businesses call for return of late-night security patrols amid violence, anti-social behaviour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/nt-businesses-want-late-night-private-security-patrols-tps/105832474</link><description>There's been a spike in reports of violent and anti-social incidents in the CBD, as Darwin businesses call for more government investment in late-night security patrols.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9129b1374b7c1fe9c3ca953bfdac1f96</guid></item><item><title>Hopes new Australian fabric will revitalise domestic clothing manufacturing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/mud-to-marle-project-australian-cotton-wool-blend-fabric/105782204</link><description>Scientists, farmers and the fashion industry collaborate to create a natural fabric that is both woven and knitted, low on emissions and set to shake up how we think about clothing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8786260615151a28c4914c124e51572</guid></item><item><title>NSW psychiatrists win 20 per cent pay rise in industrial relations commission ruling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/nsw-psychiatrists-pay-dispute-decision-industrial-relations/105847556</link><description>The NSW Industrial Relations Commission has delivered its decision in a wages dispute between the state's public psychiatrists and the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c49714cfa5671e09061595c06176ac82</guid></item><item><title>Top six bugs nominated for 2025 ABC Australian Insect of the Year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/2025-australian-insect-of-the-year-finalists/105660068</link><description>Whether you love beetles or the giant mantis it's time to cast your vote for Australia's top insect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">434faa509dab4b4572373554ad829cab</guid></item><item><title>Officers wrap up police operation in Sydney's south-west following reports of a person carrying a gun</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/nsw-police-operation-in-panania-southwest-sydney/105847752</link><description>NSW Police said a member of the public reported seeing four people, one of whom appeared to be carrying a gun, leave a dark-coloured sedan or station wagon and go into a home on the street.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">017942901920271035705460937cf26d</guid></item><item><title>New Melbourne flood mapping sparks outrage from inner-city council</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/melbourne-water-flood-mapping-yarra-darebin-council-outrage/105847310</link><description>The City of Yarra mayor has lashed the government over the mapping, saying residents will bear the costs of inadequate infrastructure investment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a80116639f6fff903b19e327a88cc5b</guid></item><item><title>Disability employment provider Bedford kept afloat with $4.4m funding injection as hunt for buyer continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/bedford-federal-government-support-as-hunt-for-buyer-begins/105847272</link><description>Australia's second-largest disability employment provider Bedford will be kept afloat by a $4.4 million federal government funding injection as it seeks a buyer for the embattled business.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ef5dcdbe0fc0107fc169a4f64467b91</guid></item><item><title>South Australian Riverland welcomes summer tourists avoiding algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/sa-riverland-welcomes-summer-tourists-avoiding-algal-bloom/105810500</link><description>An algal bloom causing toxic foam and fish kills along South Australia's beaches prompts holiday-makers to consider alternative summer travel plans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a566a7a332296798c499f3901cf5243c</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian tractor convoy unable to break stalemate on potato farmer pay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/tasmanian-potato-farmer-tractor-protest/105843374</link><description>Tasmanian potato farmers have rejected a second pay offer from multinational processor Simplot that would see farmers paid less per kilo than last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09e973a835d628032b574923d09e8ee3</guid></item><item><title>AEC launches legal action against man accused of distributing unauthorised pamphlets attacking Allegra Spender</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/aec-allegra-spender-pamphlets-court-action-alternates/105847806</link><description>The Australian Electoral Commission has launched legal action against a finance executive and Wentworth constituent in relation to 47,000 unauthorised pamphlets which were distributed in the electorate during the 2025 election campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">341176b5da5c0891e79278703f463f38</guid></item><item><title>Understanding the grief of euthanising a pet after Lewis Hamilton's dog's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/lewis-hamilton-how-to-cope-with-the-euthanasing-pet/105842858</link><description>Vets and counsellors say owners can prepare for and address the complicated grief that can come with euthanasing a pet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc284bd2d3e74988ee2cec198a7a2dcc</guid></item><item><title>Ben Hunt's Brisbane Broncos return comes full circle with shot at NRL grand final redemption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/ben-hunt-nrl-grand-final-redemption-with-brisbane-broncos/105848298</link><description>The Broncos have had their share of NRL grand final heartache over the years, but no-one feels it quite as acutely as Ben Hunt</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f065a83450971fe4e65c14394779aaf</guid></item><item><title>Is Israel breaking international law by seizing humanitarian ships bound for Gaza?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/israel-interception-of-the-gaza-bound-flotilla-international-law/105847392</link><description>According to a UN legal framework, a nation's territory does not extend beyond 19km from its shores but enforcing international maritime law is a challenge across the globe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e52292baa216c056f7d8d213ce9e2b14</guid></item><item><title>Police scale back search for missing 4yo boy Gus in outback South Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/search-for-missing-gus-remote-south-australia/105847846</link><description>South Australian Police are scaling back the search for a four-year-old boy, who disappeared in the state’s mid-north almost a week ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce6a11fb2bb0817a73aa43bb01238ef4</guid></item><item><title>South Korea’s president apologises on Facebook for poorly managed foreign adoption programs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/south-korea-president-apologises-foreign-adoption-programs/105848604</link><description>South Korea President Lee Jae Myung apologises for poorly managed foreign adoption programs that were rife with abuses and fraud, months after the country’s truth commission admits state responsibilities for such practices for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dde3e7aca4dc16cd436cdd145fb1f36</guid></item><item><title>Saints take Blues' Jack Silvagni and Tom De Koning as AFL free agency period begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/afl-free-agency-trade-period-silvagni-de-koning/105847468</link><description>Clubs move to formalise deals as the free agency period gets underway, while a series of big names could be on the move in next week's trade period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a7989f67c34d10561227e062ffc803e</guid></item><item><title>Pro-Palestinian protesters told Sydney Opera House 'off-limits' for planned rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/pro-palestine-march-planned-for-sydney-opera-house/105848564</link><description>NSW Police says the location and expected scale of the rally planned by the Palestinian Action Group poses public safety concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75e8ff7e77c0e3b00a8c435b6cb3bb22</guid></item><item><title>US investigators launch review into 2005 death of journalist and author Hunter S Thompson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/hunter-s-thompson-death-case-review/105845274</link><description>A Colorado sheriff says his office wants to address lingering questions surrounding the author's death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7c08b3f4d166f6816566d7522b8df0a</guid></item><item><title>Queensland doctors provide rural health road map at generalist forum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/queensland-doctors-provide-framework-for-rural-health-in-roma/105848602</link><description>More than 150 medical practitioners and stakeholders gather in Roma to discuss the future of rural generalist medicine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49cd92b3b374e065a8d17ebb61a6c63c</guid></item><item><title>How long will the government shutdown last? Here's what history tells us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/us-government-shutdown-history/105848348</link><description>While shutdowns have been a possibility since 1976, when Congress introduced the modern budget process, they've been a relatively rare occurrence. Here's a look at how previous shutdowns have played out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c750a0b6fd7401cde6d7c28b10bd236b</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the NBA investigation into the Clippers' Kawhi Leonard-Aspiration saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/basketball-nba-kawhi-leonard-clippers-salary-cap-drama-explained/105838906</link><description>Kawhi Leonard finds himself at the centre of the NBA's latest salary cap firestorm courtesy of a four-year sponsorship deal signed with a company that went bankrupt. Here's everything we know about the drama and the league's investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45814f2699098944a3f9d17cb6432b56</guid></item><item><title>Germany's Munich Airport reopens after several drone sightings halt flights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/munich-airport-reopoens-after-drone-sightings-stop-flights/105849094</link><description>Nearly 3,000 passengers were grounded in the latest incident in a string of drone interferences across European airports, creating heightened fears they could be linked to Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">134409750ff4eff38d8f1ba20cc2c70a</guid></item><item><title>Thriving Kids autism service causing 'significant anxiety', Labor MP warns, and may need changing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/labor-mp-significant-anxiety-thriving-kids-freelander/105848958</link><description>A Labor MP puts his party on notice after a hearing into the proposed 'Thriving Kids' autism service delivers little detail, warning that the lack of information is causing families "significant anxiety".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d5444e59993d5fd8f9596c291427db2</guid></item><item><title>Women and children stranded in Syria return to Australia after smuggling themselves from country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/isis-brides-return-australia-smuggle-syria/105850360</link><description>A small group of Australian women who travelled or were taken to Syria as partners of Islamic State members, as well as their children, have managed to smuggle themselves out of the country and have now returned home, after years of being stranded overseas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9b940bfb0cd7e5962d0d18f3ccdc04f</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds chasing polished performance against 'confident' Proteas in three-Test series ahead of 2026 Commonwealth Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/netball-test-australia-diamonds-south-africa-proteas/105850266</link><description>The Diamonds are way of South Africa ahead of their three-Test series, which kicks off in Bendigo on Saturday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a3b06b304eb0344892b3505a559ab20</guid></item><item><title>Cheryl Grimmer's family faces setback as police search ends with no result</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/police-search-fails-to-find-cheryl-grimmer-remains-balgownie/105848646</link><description>A renewed search for the remains of three-year-old Cheryl Grimmer in Wollongong ends without results, leaving her family facing fresh heartbreak.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f8726e8568dfb28b5963590438d1cd0</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested after gaining 'unauthorised' access to Amberley RAAF base</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/amberley-air-base-raaf-man-arrested-unauthorised-access/105849802</link><description>The ABC has confirmed an "unauthorised man" was able to enter the Royal Australian Air Force base south-west of Brisbane in September before being arrested by police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf206eb02f1c753fec51d9f9459a5638</guid></item><item><title>Broncos and Roosters set for 'Queensland versus NSW rivalry' in NRLW grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/nrlw-grand-final-brisbane-broncos-sydney-roosters/105850642</link><description>The Broncos expect the NRLW grand final to have a State of Origin feel as they look to halt the Sydney Roosters' perfect season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd255c873da07b23f5ed8f20a04a8a3f</guid></item><item><title>Two women found dead at Nelse, near Falls Creek in Victorian alpine region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/emergency-operation-underway-for-bodies-near-falls-creek/105850734</link><description>Police have confirmed they have located two women dead at Nelse, near Falls Creek in Victoria's alpine area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cdfa27f633d834808228adc4d2f32df</guid></item><item><title>Taylor Swift's The Life of a Showgirl in the spotlight, a track-by-track look</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/taylor-swift-life-of-a-showgirl-track-by-track-look/105849136</link><description>Taylor Swift's new album The Life of a Showgirl will be deconstructed by critics and fans alike, probably for some time to come. Here we get an expert Swiftie's initial reaction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fdfdd148587b2a9b7c1df4607511f78</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie quits shadow cabinet, citing disagreement over immigration policy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/andrew-hastie-quits-shadow-cabinet/105850958</link><description>Shadow Home Affairs Minister and Liberal leadership aspirant Andrew Hastie has quit Sussan Ley's shadow ministry, citing a disagreement over the party's immigration policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc272f42fa84628b145bc38f5e77a4a1</guid></item><item><title>Australia retains Chappell-Hadlee Trophy after rain washes out second T20I against New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/cricket-t20i-nrew-zealand-vs-australia-chappell-hadlee-trophy/105850946</link><description>The second men's Twenty20I between New Zealand and Australia is abandoned because of rain, with only 13 deliveries bowled at Tauranga's Bay Oval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b40533ad315a5fdfa4cf03d0f4496bc9</guid></item><item><title>Friday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/friday-finance-with-david-chau/105850950</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b617f451c81e86fd313667e26aafb0c2</guid></item><item><title>Former WA Health boss outlines missing pieces of puzzle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/former-wa-health-boss-outlines-missing-pieces-of/105846500</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fed0bc5657b6da20e039ca9c89e5ec2c</guid></item><item><title>Tayla Harris stars as Melbourne defeats Essendon by 14 points</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/aflw-melbourne-essendon/105850912</link><description>Melbourne has continued its pursuit of a top two AFLW finish with a 14 point defeat of Essendon at Princes Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db99de8f313630e8472819ab88c8e7f6</guid></item><item><title>Ekkalak Paenoi sentenced to life in prison for Lim Kimya's murder but his widow wants to know who ordered the killing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/gunman-sentenced-over-lim-kimyas-murder-in-thailand/105851196</link><description>Lim Kimya was gunned down shortly after arriving in Bangkok earlier this year by Ekkalak Paenoi, but his widow is questioning who is behind her husband's death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ec02d85a1f957f32c7818cb220555d9</guid></item><item><title>At least 13 people killed in Indonesian school collapse in Java as parents demand recovery work speeds up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/indonesian-school-collapse-death-toll-rises/105851242</link><description>As recovery efforts continue, some parents have argued with emergency services, demanding they speed up their work so they can bury their loved ones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3146a3e8f3184498c6049e9d252b20b3</guid></item><item><title>A West Bank town symbolises the hurdles to Palestinian statehood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/west-bank-israeli-settlers-and-palestinian-statehood-challenges/105814136</link><description>A quiet town north-east of Ramallah, is on the front line of a territorial battle in the West Bank. It is playing out against the backdrop of international recognition of a Palestinian state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39e471ebf09bc630a53cf250fc373402</guid></item><item><title>The war in Gaza has raised geopolitical tensions that extend right into our region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/gaza-israel-conflict-geopolitics-trump/105830544</link><description>On Wednesday, Donald Trump proclaimed his Middle East peace deal an "amazing thing". By week's end, things were not as straightforward as they seemed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae9e8c790621efcabcb4f7036a890568</guid></item><item><title>Don't let derangement syndrome throw shade on Anthony Albanese's global wins as steady approach pays off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/albanese-global-wins-derangement-sydrome/105830526</link><description>This week feels like it's time to officially add Albanese Derangement Syndrome to the diagnostic and statistical manual of political disorders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4970aa055a5a866fd67a141d6f05247c</guid></item><item><title>One in five girls consider dropping athletics and swimming due to periods, new research shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/one-in-five-girls-consider-dropping-athletics-swimming-period/105803342</link><description>Research by Federation University has found 63 per cent of girls have missed training, and a third have missed competitions, because of period-related challenges in athletics and swimming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77adb99dfac9e6027f0d3fc0730f1e75</guid></item><item><title>Pete Hegseth announces latest strike on boat near Venezuela he says was trafficking drugs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/us-strikes-alleged-drug-boat-near-venezuela/105851724</link><description>Without providing evidence, Pete Hegseth says the intelligence "without a doubt" confirms that the vessel was carrying drugs and that the people on board were "narco-terrorists".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64e28916ac0322747228d8e559be25c6</guid></item><item><title>Former health boss says a new hospital won't fix WA's health crisis amid record ambulance ramping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/former-wa-health-boss-leads-audit-into-hospital-maintenance-/105847632</link><description>The man tasked with reviewing WA's "old and depleted" hospitals says building a brand new one will not fix a snowballing health crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">969edfc2e2e14dbbe9c1198c4288cda2</guid></item><item><title>Sean 'Diddy' Combs sentenced to 50 months' prison after offering tearful apologies in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/sean-diddy-combs-sentenced-in-new-york-court/105847246</link><description>A New York judge says the disgraced music mogul's violence, coercion and abuse had devastating consequences on his two former partners, and he was unconvinced that Combs would not reoffend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cf4dfca9ee9f35e74ada3699a88df0e</guid></item><item><title>Why the similarities and differences between Cameron Munster and Reece Walsh will decide the 2025 grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/cameron-munster-reece-walsh-broncos-storm-grand-final/105850998</link><description>Not many players can be like Cameron Munster and Reece Walsh except for one another, and that's why they hold the fate of the 2025 NRL grand final in their hands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94b3dcbb71c509ccab94149eb3c2f0af</guid></item><item><title>Ratepayers struggle with cost of living as Qld councils increase rates to alleviate financial pressures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/cost-of-living-pressures-on-ratepayers-as-qld-councils-up-rates/105833630</link><description>Advocates say an outdated funding model and cost shifting has left Queensland councils in a risky financial position, with nowhere left to turn for cash except ratepayers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdd3ddc678b450863f4eaa2599b7ef28</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri bounces back from Baku GP disaster with sizzling practice run in Singapore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/piastri-bounces-back-from-baku-disaster-in-singapore/105851746</link><description>Australian Oscar Piastri quickly bounces back from his Baku nightmare to set the fastest time on the first day of practice at the Singapore Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa5ac6c1a882e9bdcac2c4e57b746fef</guid></item><item><title>What the NSW pill testing trial means for this summer festival season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/nsw-pill-testing-trial-music-festivals-summer/105844544</link><description>The service sits delicately at the intersection of harm reduction strategies by NSW Health and the police's work to stop illegal drug supply.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ababb1b74d875c92b23be2e4fdbbc57d</guid></item><item><title>Dave Franco film Together pulled from China over AI censorship of queer couple</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/dave-franco-horror-film-pulled-from-china-over-ai-censorship/105844328</link><description>A film starring Dave Franco and Alison Brie, Together, is pulled from China after AI censorship of a queer couple in early screenings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a41f1774dba022bd5bba37068d0faa6d</guid></item><item><title>HUMANS space project records our thoughts on life, love and the universe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/sydney-records-thousands-of-messages-for-deep-space-broadcast/105835060</link><description>A new project is collecting thousands of messages destined for the cosmos, coinciding with the anniversary of a landmark space mission 50 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2102210edbfd59f53d81e3ab6ca4abc</guid></item><item><title>Carlton's style shift has Blues knocking on door of AFLW top four</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/aflw-carlton-blues-round-eight-analysis/105848936</link><description>Carlton's emergence as a finals threat is no surprise, with the Blues now possessing the personnel to execute an effective game plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe65dbc9e2cf1f1e3370a7053994089d</guid></item><item><title>Deputy leader confident nuclear will be part of Coalition's energy policy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/deputy-opposition-leader-confident-nuclear-in-energy-policy-mix/105848854</link><description>As the federal Coalition looks to resurrect a nuclear policy, an energy analyst and a workers' union fear the impacts of parliament's inability to agree on Australia's energy future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ac20f57d9638dadc774af02f728a0e3</guid></item><item><title>The purpose of men-only clubs like Melbourne's Savage Club seems almost neurotic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/purpose-men-only-clubs-melbourne-savage-club-neurotic/105830554</link><description>These clubs, which still exist right around the country, are the weirdest anomaly. They sit jostled up against the Australia they firmly shut their doors against; their purpose in modern Australia seems almost neurotic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e3b087b2f91b60cbb3767b2b4d77398</guid></item><item><title>Olivia Dean, Nine Inch Nails, Big Thief lead September's best new albums</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/10-best-albums-of-september-olivia-dean-geese-nine-inch-nails/105843906</link><description>While Taylor Swift's new album might be dominating the conversation, some of the best records of the year also arrived in September, from Olivia Dean to Nine Inch Nails.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f5345cdf90588ae8868abca5d9e931d</guid></item><item><title>Seasonal workers' accommodation 'overcrowded' and plagued by mice, says new report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/seasonal-worker-housing-overcrowded-dangerous-overpriced/105848798</link><description>A new housing report describes accommodation provided for some seasonal workers in Australia as dangerous, overpriced and overcrowded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fb5ba7a6909579e3204e420ea329621</guid></item><item><title>The complicated messaging surrounding SA’s algal bloom summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/mike-steer-algal-bloom-stateline/105843082</link><description>The face of South Australia's algal bloom response says the natural event "is not going to ruin summer" and he is looking forward to spending more time with his kids at the beach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d97d1426ebd61b033aa4dba8f13d714</guid></item><item><title>After a week of searching, police have found no signs of missing 4yo in South Australia's outback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/how-search-for-missing-boy-gus-unfolded-in-sa-outback/105849108</link><description>A week of large-scale land and air searches have found no clues leading to the whereabouts of four-year-old Gus in outback South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdeb05521fb5b8b89aab8020bc84d684</guid></item><item><title>Backyard biobank project sets out to save Tasmania's 'spectacular' alpine plants from bushfire threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/backyard-biobanking-tasmania-alpine-plants-bushfire-threat/105730036</link><description>The backyards of ordinary Tasmanians are becoming urban climate refuges for a "biobank" of alpine plants threatened by climate change and bushfire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45c8f0b04a8f017a2c0ed2385d6ac5b5</guid></item><item><title>Queanbeyan's two female rugby league teams both fold mid-season due to player shortage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/queanbeyan-roos-queanbeyan-blues-fold-mid-season-rugby-league/105849216</link><description>Female participation in rugby league across the Canberra region has reached a record high. Despite this, both women's teams in Queanbeyan have been forced to fold mid-season due to a player shortage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2000cb94e9a7ebef412790d52dbced8</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr stuck on the bench again as Chelsea held to WSL draw by Manchester United</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/kerr-on-bench-as-chelsea-held-to-draw-by-manchester-united/105851796</link><description>Matildas skipper Sam Kerr plays just 17 minutes off the bench for Chelsea as they lose their perfect WSL record with a 1-1 draw at Manchester United.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a26e9807d129f2891aeef93602b3d044</guid></item><item><title>What you need to know when tackling Tasmania's Cradle Mountain and Overland Track</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/how-to-visit-the-overland-track-and-cradle-mountain-prepared/105848588</link><description>Tasmania's wild places continue to captivate travellers, but experts say it is easy to underestimate how quickly a sunny day can flip to life-threatening conditions. One SES rescuer shares his advice for staying safe in the wilderness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2ca8270bb0549aa4469d3d941872bfc</guid></item><item><title>BOM forecast shows hot weather and high fire danger to make way for cold front</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/bom-forecasts-summer-heat-amid-high-fire-danger-warnings/105839426</link><description>Southern and eastern Australia are forecast to see a surge of summer-like warmth, as high fire danger warnings are issued across several parts of the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">932ba99bce5415da5cdf80b587401473</guid></item><item><title>Late father inspires Melbourne Storm star Cameron Munster to win NRL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/cameron-munster-family-nrl-grand-final-melbourne-storm-broncos/105830578</link><description>After the sudden death of his number one fan this year, one of rugby league's biggest stars is hoping to lift the NRL trophy for his dad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a02d87f5c3195a27b21be62036f00e9</guid></item><item><title>Burswood racetrack plan appears to need Crown Casino land, but at what cost?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/burswood-park-racetrack-land-deal-under-microscope/105850520</link><description>Roger Cook may be planning victory laps around his controversial election-promised Burswood Park racetrack, but his government is being coy about one crucial element that could sink the whole thing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7aab3658649711ae3c376f73192a7bf9</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian woman drowns on day 5 of multi-day Franklin River rafting trip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/tasmanian-woman-dies-in-franklin-river-rafting-trip/105851884</link><description>A Tasmanian woman has drowned after the raft she was travelling in flipped on the fifth day of a planned 10-day pack-rafting adventure in the remote Franklin-Gordon Wild Rivers National Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f650273ab54265226e20931c6fdf036</guid></item><item><title>Cheesy lemon ravioli is a simple dinner with just three steps - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/easy-lemon-ravioli-with-baby-spinach-cheese/105534228</link><description>The dish is completely unfussy, relying upon two pantry staples, zesty lemon and salty Parmesan, to bring big, punchy flavours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a4daf7b3744c92fb0ea0636c88cb2f6</guid></item><item><title>Community's Big Lost Band at Pambula's Wanderer music festival 'too joyous' to ignore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/big-lost-band-at-pambulas-wanderer-music-festival-community/105839362</link><description>With more than 100 members and only four rehearsals before showtime, the Big Lost Band is the ultimate musical challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a1cb2bd9d70714d2a4c4bb2eb85e784</guid></item><item><title>Meet the pop-up rock'n'roll supergroup where everyone's invited</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/meet-the-pop-up-supergroup-where-everyone-is-invited/105841010</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">392a0256ef6149e38095baf48a33e980</guid></item><item><title>Perth Royal Show vendors upset by price hikes, say crowds are down in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/perth-royal-show-vendors-say-crowds-lower-2025/105849896</link><description>Vendors are reporting smaller attendances at this year's Perth Royal Show amid a sharp increase in prices, both for visitors and game providers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea9f578d56db957edc70368ef4c2813f</guid></item><item><title>Satellite images show razed buildings, armoured vehicles moving into Gaza City</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/satellite-images-show-israels-assault-on-gaza-city/105848138</link><description>Israeli troops are moving closer and closer to the heart of Gaza City, razing rows of buildings and converting tent cities into front lines, an ABC News analysis of satellite images shows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33b1710702f75158808d410acb921160</guid></item><item><title>How Cairns startup Rainstick is using biotech to transform farming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/rainstick-cairns-biotech-startup-seed-treatment-canola/105844476</link><description>A Cairns biotech startup is combining Indigenous knowledge of "rainmaking" with modern science to develop an electrical seed treatment hoping to improve crop growth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3bb4007ae6a425efddef231001ba667</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie says quitting frontbench not an attempt to replace Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/andrew-hastie-speaks-after-quitting-shadow-cabinet/105852056</link><description>Liberal MP Andrew Hastie insists his decision to quit the frontbench is not part of an attempt to replace Sussan Ley as the federal opposition leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46e1256eabab0a5475878a5a25ce40cb</guid></item><item><title>Small town police officer chases big country music dream</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/wa-police-officer-chases-country-music-dreams/105802288</link><description>West Australian country police officer Darren Gillis writes original music inspired by his day job and the loss of mates he met in the field.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">763fd713ddde8dd99d82cce44d965db4</guid></item><item><title>Oasis guitarist Bonehead to miss Australian shows due to cancer treatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/bonhead-from-oasis-has-prostate-cancer/105851978</link><description>Paul Arthurs, better known as Bonehead, posted on X: "I'm really sad to be missing these shows but I'm feeling good and will be back."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16296298c9da95991c1d8a096ddbd499</guid></item><item><title>Liberal MP Andrew Hastie resigns from frontbench</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/liberal-mp-andrew-hastie-resigns-from-frontbench/105852202</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b464ea8e5752271124fa55e5fc8bfc04</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie’s resignation over immigration couldn’t be worse timing for Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/andrew-hastie-resignation-bad-timing-for-sussan-ley/105852022</link><description>Hastie says he decided to quit because a letter she sent him earlier in the week made clear he wouldn't be formulating the Coalition's immigration policies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">089f946d1a6a6f1ef557a2a4a939654a</guid></item><item><title>David Speers analyses the reasons why Andrew Hastie has quit frontbench</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/david-speers-analyses-the-reasons-why-andrew-hastie/105852238</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35a6e68735f7f679278df9b5fef3d818</guid></item><item><title>More than 200 skeletons uncovered in mass grave in Sri Lanka, exposing its haunting history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/chemmani-sri-lanka-mass-graves-skeletons-discovered/105808016</link><description>A shocking mass grave discovery in Sri Lanka reignites global attention on one of the world's highest cases of unresolved enforced disappearances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39c66bb5798720a71f2f2777154fa72a</guid></item><item><title>Trump administration offers unaccompanied migrant children $US2,500 to voluntarily leave the US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/trump-administration-offers-unaccompanies-migrant-children-2500-/105852218</link><description>The move is the latest financial offer made by the Department of Homeland Security, aimed at encouraging voluntary deportations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cced096f9e891ee674c4966fffd44f1b</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos post 20th straight win as AFLW record falls, Lions romp to derby victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/aflw-saints-giants-kangaroos-swans-suns-lions-power-bulldogs/105852414</link><description>The Kangaroos' premiership defence remains on course following a 68-point thrashing of Sydney, while Brisbane snags its third consecutive win of the season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6bff69aaf2c14c2a48f0ac871b60278</guid></item><item><title>Sanae Takaichi set to be Japan's first female PM after winning Liberal Democratic Party leadership contest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/japan-ldp-leadership-election-results/105852408</link><description>The decision comes after the Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba announced his resignation last month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a720fc526dcf766496a5d9b2baba6b7a</guid></item><item><title>Queensland man charged over alleged death threat made against Prime Minister Anthony Albanese</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/queensland-man-alleged-death-threat-anthony-albanese/105852220</link><description>A Queensland man is charged with using a carriage service to make a threat to kill after he allegedly made a threat on Anthony Albanese's life on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cece643dca75f858ada9670e7970c089</guid></item><item><title>Major bushfire rages across Moreton Island, Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/major-bushfire-rages-across-moreton-island-queensland/105852462</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">070494494226aa741a291a0421536582</guid></item><item><title>Campers evacuated, residents on alert as Moreton Island bushfire intensifies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/moreton-island-campers-evacuated-bushfire-intensifies/105852368</link><description>Campers on Moreton Island, off the coast of south-east Queensland, have been evacuated and nearby residents told to prepare to leave as a large, out-of-control bushfire burns in the island's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d15486fa359047f654ce5f08bb66907</guid></item><item><title>How Roosters star Eliza Lopamaua found her way to NRLW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/nrlw-grand-final-sydney-roosters-brisbane-broncos/105852606</link><description>As she prepares for Sunday's NRLW grand final against the Brisbane Broncos, Sydney Roosters prop Eliza Lopamaua concedes she found rugby league by mistake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da8db3c1cf98f9e389ad8dda2c8eef76</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fall to 28-14 defeat against All Blacks in Bledisloe Cup contest in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/live-updates-wallabies-vs-all-blacks-bledisloe-cup-perth/105852258</link><description>Australia's hopes of an unlikely Rugby Championship triumph have been extinguished with a 28-14 loss to New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7c86ac526474fe90d71c39a421320a3</guid></item><item><title>Sam Konstas falls cheaply, Jake Weatherald boosts Ashes hopes on day one of Sheffield Shield</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/konstas-falls-cheaply-sheffield-shield-day-one/105852584</link><description>Australia's incumbent Test opener Sam Konstas is dropped and survives two LBW appeals before being dismissed for four on day one of the Sheffield Shield.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9daf06f12a5fb445516ebd9f3fb7b24d</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds attend justice march for Kaiden Morgan-Johnston in Morwell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/kaiden-morgan-johnston-justice-march-morwell/105843720</link><description>Around 600 people attend a justice march for Kaiden Morgan-Johnston, who died after he was allegedly stabbed while walking to a friend's house in Morwell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9584f7523ceef2892ca4394ae442970</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Women's World Cup match against Sri Lanka washed out in Colombo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/womens-cricket-world-cup-australia-sri-lanka-live-scores-stats/105852128</link><description>Australia's World Cup pool match against Sri Lanka in Colombo was abandoned due to rain, with no play possible due to the inclement weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2063e74bcd4e75b3a7fcd1e6afc214bd</guid></item><item><title>Russian strike hits Ukrainian passenger train at Shostka station, authorities say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/russian-attack-hits-ukrainian-train-in-shostka/105852688</link><description>A Russian drone strike has hit a passenger train in Ukraine's northern Sumy region and injured dozens of people in an act President Volodymyr Zelenskyy has denounced as 'terrorism'.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99488954239e654dcd7be031db995dec</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds defeat Proteas 64-53 in first netball Test in Bendigo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/netball-test-australia-diamonds-south-africa-proteas/105852710</link><description>Australia has overcome a promising start from South Africa to win 64-53 in the first netball Test in Bendigo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d30ac6cd4929422024452e1d1179b428</guid></item><item><title>Mitch Marsh inspires Australia to three-wicket win over New Zealand in third T20I</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/t20-international-australia-new-zealand-tauranga/105852708</link><description>Mitch Marsh's first T20I century helped the Australian men's team record a stunning three-wicket win over New Zealand across the Tasman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">deec40bd1caaefd9d7ce251cbf922de3</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle Jets defeat semi-professional Heidelberg United 3-1 to lift first Australia Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/newcastle-jets-win-australia-cup-over-heidelberg-united/105852580</link><description>The Newcastle Jets have defeated semi-professional club Heidelberg United 3-1 to claim their first silverware since 2008.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bc95933e07f6b66ac7c76d17ab84dac</guid></item><item><title>Betting companies keep millions stolen from investors by 'VIP' gambler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/betting-companies-keep-vip-gamblers-stolen-millions-four-corners/105843526</link><description>Nick and Aimee Mazza's hard-earned cash was gambled away by a man they thought was investing it. Bookmakers encouraged him to keep betting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42e39985dc4f61b535e2da312f2a4c6d</guid></item><item><title>What time does the NRL grand final kick off? When is the NRLW grand final?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/what-time-is-the-nrl-nrlw-grand-final/105851794</link><description>Kick-off times, pre-game entertainment and all the players taking the field. Here's everything you need to know for grand final day in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ead66ab694e579b3bfa116ce0cd234c4</guid></item><item><title>Fried shark and maggots: Indonesia's free meal program poisons thousands of children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/indonesia-free-meal-program-poisons-thousands-of-kids/105836302</link><description>The key election commitment of President Prabowo Subianto is facing mounting backlash over its poor oversight, questionable food sourcing and unhygienic kitchens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e2fccd95400de4be56e63556ca69126</guid></item><item><title>Sean 'Diddy' Combs has been sentenced to four years in prison. Here's a breakdown of the case and where to next</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/sean-diddy-combs-sentenced-prison-case-breakdown/105852240</link><description>Sean "Diddy" Combs may have just been sentenced to four years in prison, but he still faces a mountain of lawsuits accusing him of sexual violence and other misconduct.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46698722afdc0b8fd805bb4736cd45e0</guid></item><item><title>AI is creeping into our court system. Will it undermine justice?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/artificial-intelligence-law-robot-legal-judge-jury-ai/105545900</link><description>Artificial intelligence is coming for the law. Are we ready for robots to become judge and jury?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e1797579913bae4cb5a8a9d33306767</guid></item><item><title>Israel, Hamas and US to begin new Gaza peace talks, as Netanyahu says he wants negotiations done quickly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/new-gaza-ceasefire-talks-to-begin-in-egypt/105852826</link><description>Representatives of Israel, Hamas and the United States are set to begin fresh talks in Egypt about how to implement Donald Trump's Gaza ceasefire plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">431d17bf0343a28b6076558cc09a0c6c</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz Kids: Tom Gleeson is back grilling baby-faced brainiacs. Are you smarter than them?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/hard-quiz-kids-weekly-trivia-tom-gleeson/105829672</link><description>I find it interesting you think you could beat the know-it-all tweens on Hard Quiz Kids. How about you prove it? Let's play, HARD!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a470db20ade13459d37c1802f5f147e9</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian photojournalist Ali Jadallah wins Siena Awards Photo Festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/siena-awards-photo-festival-winning-photographs/105833578</link><description>Ali Jadallah's photo, called Leaving Home, shows three people emerging from the rubble of their damaged building.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19b2e879eed8546fc3e8fb570dff4a4f</guid></item><item><title>Will Labor's housing fund recover from its rocky start and fix decades of decline?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/labor-housing-affordability-future-fund-off-to-slow-start/105852480</link><description>It takes a long time to build anything at all in Australia's dysfunctional housing market, even for the federal government, but Labor's social housing fund is inching towards an impact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d0476c8d77c2594cc1cad40456f936b</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's Gaza ceasefire plan could become the single best hope to end the bloodshed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/donald-trump-gaza-ceasefire-plan-could-mark-an-end-to-bloodshed/105852952</link><description>For the first time since the conflict in Gaza began nearly two years ago, an American president told Israel to stop — and it did.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24f203f45bd79f84fd5259dce8d21f93</guid></item><item><title>Rowdy wartime behaviour revealed as Sydney's Luna Park celebrates 90th birthday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/anniversary-of-sydney-luna-park-90-years/105831928</link><description>Now in its 90th year, Sydney's Luna Park was not always so family-friendly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9944385925a8514f8ab944436c2988c</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's record crime wave sees the premier and police chief steering different ships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/victorian-government-mike-bush-handling-of-youth-crime/105845950</link><description>While Premier Jacinta Allan narrows in on machetes and bail laws, Chief Commissioner Mike Bush is looking to broader horizons as Victoria witnesses record levels of offending.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47749d10a9f736ac9a43c068dac0cc04</guid></item><item><title>Smaller homes in demand during regional housing crunch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/councillors-call-for-support-to-build-smaller-houses/105827748</link><description>Councillors say they recognise that small housing is needed to meet housing demand, but state government support will be needed to build key infrastructure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb09cb2e69114ad4bc11ccb82e99a549</guid></item><item><title>The changes hidden within 'cryptic' supermarket ingredient labels</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/supermarket-ingredients-changes-skimpflation/105478516</link><description>The main ingredient in dozens of supermarket products has been reduced, an ABC investigation has found, leading retail and marketing experts to call for more transparency around recipe changes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0b404c438de0f798543e14cbbbc5021</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri satisfied with advantage over McLaren teammate Lando Norris in Singapore GP qualifying</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/piastri-satisfied-with-advantage-over-norris-in-singapore/105853360</link><description>Oscar Piastri pronounces himself satisfied after finishing third in qualifying to gain an advantage over fifth-placed teammate Lando Norris at the Singapore GP.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">818e012956f585357e0cc49cb38133a0</guid></item><item><title>Populist billionaire Andrej Babiš wins Czech Republic parliamentary election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/andrej-babis-ano-wins-czech-republic-parliamentary-election/105853348</link><description>The party of billionaire and self-declared "Trumpist" Andrej Babiš wins the Czech Republic's parliamentary election, near-final results show, which could steer the country away from supporting Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebf46c1ca99f4a6100682da1f8980f37</guid></item><item><title>Sport is where the heart is, as the Irish diaspora descends on Willawong for the Australasian Gaelic Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/australasia-gaa-championships-2025/105849238</link><description>As over 400 players head to Brisbane for the Australasia Gaelic Games Championships, the bond that exists between a distant home and sport is laid bare.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56ab2ef77a268fe6afa42aa3b946ef06</guid></item><item><title>How the Tallis Scholars opened the world of sacred choral music to new audiences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/how-the-tallis-scholars-opened-the-world-of-sacred-choral-music/105849010</link><description>This English vocal group took centuries-old church music from the archives and became a hit. They're back in Australia sharing this music with local audiences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfc9ac542d3a1aa952c8f8d59dcfbf8c</guid></item><item><title>Economics rather than environmental concerns could sink Woodside's proposed Browse gas project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/economic-doubts-over-browse-gas-project/105838392</link><description>The Browse gas project is staring down the full weight of Australia's climate movement. Analysts say that is the least of its worries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecf5fc2ff00cdd38128ff1bdcd14da3a</guid></item><item><title>Australia was champion of the world three years ago, but now softball teams are struggling to find players</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/softball-decline-struggle-young-players-exposure-olympics/105851876</link><description>It was a schoolyard sport so common it once rivalled cricket as the most popular in Australia. But now grassroots teams are struggling to fill a team sheet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c27d12acae797957e866d7008cdb6895</guid></item><item><title>Some South Australian farmers facing long road to drought recovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/farmers-begin-long-recovery-after-year-long-sa-drought/105850610</link><description>Some South Australian farmers say they are still feeling the strain of drought after inconsistent winter rains left little room for recovery before the coming summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17b9cb9e734d8bd60eb0db15cbdbb695</guid></item><item><title>Alex De Minaur hits career-best mark with win at Shanghai Masters as ATP Finals loom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/de-minaur-hits-career-best-mark-with-win-at-shanghai-masters/105853398</link><description>Alex de Minaur sets a new personal record for wins in a year with a comfortable victory over Camilo Ugo Carabelli at the Shanghai Masters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc0f8ea3048522dab91e7a69c9ce7eed</guid></item><item><title>From 'snotty nose' to 'giggling goose', how language used by MPs is deemed to be unparliamentary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/history-of-unparliamentary-language-in-queensland/105847384</link><description>In Australian politics, words and phrases used in parliament that are seen as insulting, abusive, or a deliberate lie are determined to be "unparliamentary language".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08d883c55178d398acefba56ec2a755e</guid></item><item><title>Amadeo Ambrosino uses a robot at school to learn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/missing-school-robot/105852446</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4436e5eec7069762ecde26d74ef1b2ee</guid></item><item><title>Prospecting mates who found Ming Dynasty Buddha urge prime minister to help repatriate it to China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/buddha-found-in-shark-bay-urged-to-be-repatriated/105831250</link><description>A Ming Dynasty Buddha statue found on a roadside in Western Australia's Shark Bay region seven years ago could soon be repatriated to the largest Buddhist population in the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b1dda99c49d71b70e55094f4a9bda4f</guid></item><item><title>Jahrome Hughes says he 'used to hate' the Storm as he prepares for grand final battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/melbourne-storm-grand-final-jahrome-hughes/105853438</link><description>Jahrome Hughes admits to once being sick of watching Melbourne win, but now the Kiwi can help lead them to another premiership in the NRL grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb3575fddded9eff46b74687c29f66c2</guid></item><item><title>Line dancing helps Queensland community connect and keep moving</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/line-dancing-popularity-helps-queensland-community-connect-move/105815880</link><description>Organisers behind line dancing events say more people are coming to their evenings, and social media is driving its popularity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47723861c4ac72827fe3eb93195e70de</guid></item><item><title>Health workers say NT leading the nation in hepatitis B care, as diagnoses jump but mortality rates plummet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nt-hepatitis-b-diagnoses-rising-as-mortality-rates-decrease/105840336</link><description>Health workers say new data showing hepatitis B cases have almost tripled in the NT reflects better access to care, with the territory also leading the nation in reducing mortality rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5fdc774928dc47194833017cc4f13b2</guid></item><item><title>Babe's 30th anniversary celebrated in Robertson where film was shot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/robertson-celebrates-30-years-since-babe-was-shot-in-the-town/105847244</link><description>Decades after hosting film crews making a children's movie about a loveable piglet, the town of Robertson in New South Wales is transformed into a country fair in tribute.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ee021ffad919f20582293d03868a10f</guid></item><item><title>Greens leader says she is unsure about Robbins Island wind farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/greens-leader-says-she-is-unsure-about-wind-farm/105853522</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d3bbd0e6588a57622fb72045627c7ed</guid></item><item><title>Greens leader Larissa Waters 'doesn't know very much' about wind farm opposed by colleagues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/greens-leader-larissa-waters-unsure-about-tasmanian-wind-farm/105853456</link><description>Larissa Waters says she will be looking closely at the Robbins Island wind farm, which the Greens's two Tasmanian senators say will threaten several endangered species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04a1ed328b028d7562d776de27573de1</guid></item><item><title>Community saves endangered tropical sea turtle that washed up on Esperance beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/esperance-tropical-green-turtle-visitor-north-west-wa/105839222</link><description>A community has sprung into action to nurse a juvenile tropical turtle back to health as wildlife carers question how it found its way to WA's south coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4ac34391201416c37af31bac8b03de5</guid></item><item><title>Harry Lush director of Gondwana Project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/harry-lush-director-of-gondwana-project/105853556</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc052d43324e94b02a9758439e00028f</guid></item><item><title>English springer spaniels Kelly and Milo helping fight dieback in Western Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/dieback-dogs-helping-fight-deadly-plant-disease/105849444</link><description>Two dogs join the fight against one of the biggest threats to Australia's native plants, making dieback detection possible in minutes rather than weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba971c766d020d17dfa85d059b2edf3b</guid></item><item><title>I got an unexpected afternoon tea invitation, and it told me a lot about Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/analysis-on-alexander-stubb-and-donald-trump-relationship/105851222</link><description>An afternoon tea meeting with a president is not the sort of invitation you get every day as a foreign correspondent, but when I met Finland's Alexander Stubb in Helsinki, it taught me a lot about another world leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e77bd18c49c780231a41cb654add893</guid></item><item><title>Inside the 'Trinity of Chaos' group of young hackers targeting major companies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/trinity-of-chaos-hacker-groups-qantas-data-breach-cyber-security/105838370</link><description>Cybersecurity analysts warn that three of the most notorious English-speaking cybercrime groups are still operating as the "super group" known as Trinity of Chaos, despite recently announcing retirement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35c3ff9c048b8f39d6bc9637e4096f8c</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged with murder of man believed to be her partner, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/woman-charged-with-port-pirie-south-death/105853574</link><description>A woman has been charged with murder after a man was reported unconscious in South Australia's mid-north on Friday and could not be revived.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">195d8cc77414e8fdb07fdc21853e9c01</guid></item><item><title>Homicide Squad investigating 'suspicious' death of 84yo woman in Sydney suburb of Melonba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nsw-body-of-84yo-woman-in-her-melonba-home/105853626</link><description>The Homicide Squad is investigating the circumstances surrounding the death of an 84-year-old woman, who was found in her bedroom about midday Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b4f04ad76b564efa423012267ca9387</guid></item><item><title>Trump authorises deployment of 300 National Guard troops to Chicago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/trump-deploys-300-national-guard-troops-chicago/105853704</link><description>US President Donald Trump has deployed 300 Illinois National Guard troops to Chicago after Governor JB Pritzker refused to do so.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e09d2adca78710fda0a973cf63b4970</guid></item><item><title>Who is Sanae Takaichi, set to be Japan's first female PM?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/sanae-takaichi-japan-ldp-leadership-prime-minister/105853536</link><description>Sanae Takaichi has won Japan's Liberal Democratic Party's leadership contest and is likely to become the country's first female PM. Here's what we know about her.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">168ace564993b12a633f0b1f582bf714</guid></item><item><title>US Treasury unveils draft design for $1 Trump coin to mark 250th independence celebrations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/trump-coil-revealed/105853576</link><description>In 2020, the US Congress passed a law that allows the Treasury Secretary to mint $1 coins in 2026 "with designs emblematic of the US semi-quincentennial".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf499095bc04f4aa61baf295fc27ca60</guid></item><item><title>Lithuania's Vilnius Airport reopens after unknown balloon sightings halt flights over the weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/lithuania-airport-reopens-after-balloon-sightings/105853568</link><description>In total, around 30 flights and nearly 6,000 passengers were impacted by the closures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77430aaa02ac169cea6e852dfc77ce23</guid></item><item><title>Mark Latham's ex-girlfriend Nathalie Matthews charged with sharing intimate images</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nathalie-matthews-charged-with-sharing-intimate-image/105853710</link><description>Nathalie Matthews, 38, was arrested after arriving into Sydney on a flight from Dubai this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df15eecd1f673f45c221819524098f94</guid></item><item><title>NRL grand final live: Brisbane Broncos beat Melbourne Storm, Adam Reynolds injured, Brisbane ends Roosters' NRLW streak in decider</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nrl-grand-final-live-blog-melbourne-storm-brisbane-broncos/105847434</link><description>The Brisbane Broncos beat the Melbourne Storm 26-22 in the NRL grand final despite both halves to injury in the second half. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7354e645e2773f7438e3a91beca5cf8b</guid></item><item><title>More than 100 guns seized in WA Police raids targeting 'sovereign citizens'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/guns-seized-in-wa-police-sovereign-citizen-raid/105853620</link><description>More than 100 firearms are seized in a WA Police operation targeting 'sovereign citizens' in the wake of the fatal shooting of two Victorian officers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2549afbffbbe684a4f55011bd86c5acd</guid></item><item><title>The advice Ray Martin lives by and the line journalists 'shouldn't cross'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/the-assembly-ray-martin-david-attenborough-advice/105671826</link><description>After six decades as a journalist, Ray Martin says he has learnt the secret to a long and satisfying career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d8792cf6e72caa5529e12b9e6ca08e0</guid></item><item><title>Mega-team of heavy horses sets world record at Good Old Days Festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/record-breaking-feat-for-mega-team-of-heavy-horses/105853716</link><description>Scores of heavy horses have been harnessed together at a heritage festival in southern New South Wales in what organisers say is a world record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82701463d0333bf75c6cf5d657e9b923</guid></item><item><title>European Space Agency launches second space antenna in New Norcia, north of Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/space-agency-opens-second-deep-space-antenna-new-norcia/105849820</link><description>A second deep space antenna opened in a tiny monastic town in Western Australia could help unlock the secrets of the universe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">897e2da31ddeaef33af502525555b9b4</guid></item><item><title>Rescuers recover more bodies of teenage victims after school collapse in Indonesia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/death-toll-indonesia-school-rises-36-students/105854064</link><description>The number of students confirmed dead after the collapse of an Islamic boarding school building in Indonesia has risen to 37, from 16 a day earlier, the country's disaster mitigation agency says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19795b7fb5c7d14c8fbd253e1749fe5a</guid></item><item><title>Mass civil wedding in Paraguay's capital sees more than 600 couples say 'I do' in unison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/mass-civil-wedding-paraguay/105853878</link><description>The event was part of a government campaign aiming to make civil weddings more accessible across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f3c3cca78b4fbbc1b5508b945213e55</guid></item><item><title>Tigers end AFLW drought in shock 11-point win over Crows as Blues and Eagles enjoy victories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/aflw-tigers-crows-cats-blues-eagles-magpies-round-eight/105854110</link><description>Richmond's dismal losing streak is over, with midfielder Monique Conti playing a starring role in a shock win over competition heavyweights Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebb6f06da858950421d033911c808ba2</guid></item><item><title>Around 20 campers were relocated on Saturday due to the threat of a large out-of-control bushfire in the island's north.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/moreton-bay-fire-alert-/105854118</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">227e11f49c4f046d2d81ad5d73cf6409</guid></item><item><title>Authorities will investigate campfire that sparked major Moreton Island blaze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/campfire-moreton-island-bushfire-alert/105853820</link><description>A "careless" campfire lit during a fire ban sparked a rapidly moving blaze that has now burnt hundreds of hectares on Moreton Island, according to authorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce8c6a567bd717f2cc696fa8de3e838f</guid></item><item><title>Liberty Bell Bay smelter receives first shipment of ore since flagging financial woes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/liberty-bay-bell-smelter-receives-first-ore-shipment/105853550</link><description>A $20 million loan from the Tasmanian government to keep smelter Liberty Bell Bay afloat after it flagged financial woes earlier this year has led to the first shipment of ore being delivered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">091231e8b6fe5383bb688542b2c8f6b2</guid></item><item><title>Police seize 135 firearms in sovereign citizen raids across WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/police-seize-135-firearms-in-sovereign-citizen/105854230</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dcf4833c0e8d17a4c1871b43ee48f52</guid></item><item><title>Zion Williamson stars as NBA side New Orleans Pelicans defeat Phoenix 127-92</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/williamson-stars-pelicans-down-phoenix/105854226</link><description>The New Orleans Pelicans have outclassed the South East Melbourne Phoenix 127-92 to conclude their two-game Australian tour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f23f70a462e3882cf71f679fd78632fb</guid></item><item><title>Mele Haufanga's NRLW premiership-winning try now an unsolvable mystery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nrlw-grand-final-broncos-roosters-haufanga-try-decision-analysis/105854160</link><description>Brisbane and the Roosters played one of the greatest games in NRLW history, but the controversial winning try to Mele Haufanga shapes as a football mystery that might never be solved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48dd66bbbd32a2b98d0fd33bbd0bddc8</guid></item><item><title>Dozens dead after landslides, flash floods in Nepal and India's Darjeeling region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/landslides-flash-foods-kill-dozens-in-nepal-darjeeling/105854364</link><description>Heavy rains have triggered landslides and flash floods, blocking roads, washing away bridges and killing dozens in Nepal and West Bengal, authorities said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">345f8f3a313e7bc0aa314c5664cdba99</guid></item><item><title>F1 live SIngapore Grand Prix: Oscar Piastri starts third behind George Russell and Max Verstappen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/f1-live-singapore-grand-prix-oscar-piastri-lando-norris/105845638</link><description>McLaren can win the constructors' championship in Singapore, but the dominance they enjoyed earlier this season has faded, with Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris battling for the drivers' title. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e56a98a02a87c2eace2bac0d6de54efb</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested after shots fired in Sydney's Croydon Park, launching major police operation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/man-arrested-after-shooting-in-sydney-croydon-park/105854454</link><description>A man has been arrested after a number of shots were fired in the inner-west Sydney suburb of Croydon Park and four people were injured.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f80a42b7620b731f82ec58637dfdb05</guid></item><item><title>Reece Walsh wins Clive Churchill Medal to ice Broncos's NRL premiership success</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nrl-grand-final-reece-walsh-wins-clive-churchill-medal-broncos/105854358</link><description>In one of the greatest individual performances in grand final history, Brisbane Broncos star Reece Walsh was judged player of the match after inspiring his side to their victory over the Melbourne Storm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4da114fbdd73820852f227f68040d6f</guid></item><item><title>NRL grand final quick hits: Reece Walsh creates magic after avoiding sin bin as Broncos survive Hunt, Reynolds injuries to win premiership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nrl-grand-final-quick-hits-walsh-sin-bin-hunt-reynolds-injuries/105854254</link><description>Reece Walsh put in an NRL grand final performance for the ages after an early stroke of luck as the Brisbane Broncos survived the loss of both Ben Hunt and Adam Reynolds to end a 19-year premiership drought.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa2378f6001893fa3c85d8ab5c40ad05</guid></item><item><title>How the internet reacted to Brisbane Broncos winning the NRL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/internet-reacted-nrl-grand-final-reece-walsh-brisbane-broncos/105854070</link><description>The internet could barely believe what was happening as Brisbane, fuelled by Reece Walsh's brilliance, came from behind to win the NRL grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a773abe9892dbaf9421d194401021d35</guid></item></channel></rss>