<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 04:23:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Changes to Queensland's political donation laws could increase corruption risks, experts say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/queensland-political-donations-property-developers/106135566</link><description>A ban on political donations by developers, introduced by the former Qld Labor Government, will be lifted by the LNP.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d622effc6640efe205ef4fafbe6ecae8</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill community fundraises for mental health in wake of tragic loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/mental-health-fundraiser-in-memory-of-alice-wilkinson/106032394</link><description>Alice Wilkinson loved music and was the life of the party. Her death has prompted her family to help others who might be struggling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9948ad96b75034e1c1748aa31157b822</guid></item><item><title>Australia's social media ban reminds us of the power of a loving boundary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/social-media-ban-teens-roblox-son-boundary-safety/106131786</link><description>This is where we parents should remind ourselves of the power of the loving boundary: not to bind and constrain, but to properly demonstrate that we hold our kids and their safety in our mind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b63e161e0d7b0716938ae584d3056917</guid></item><item><title>New generations take to bird watching</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/bird-watching-for-everyone/106138172</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be3cd15eb3f374029864ad60e0572480</guid></item><item><title>Gen Z drawn to bird watching after growing up on Pokemon GO</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/gen-z-drawn-to-bird-watching-after-growing-up-on-pokemon-go/106136816</link><description>Raised on Pokemon GO, generation Z is finding the hobby of birding just the ticket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57a5e8f5b4102873e2ea387eb135bd1c</guid></item><item><title>Matcha's popularity a boon for Japanese farmers but counterfeits a problem</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/counterfeit-matcha-is-flooding-the-market-to-meet-demand/106115334</link><description>As Japanese matcha producers struggle with the surge in demand, the industry is facing another problem — counterfeit matcha.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b338d270f01bd62218b06c26a1978a6</guid></item><item><title>Grassroots First Nations organisation flags concern for at-risk youth under social media ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/nt-social-media-ban-indigenous-teens-darwin-aunties-place/106133746</link><description>Social media can help at-risk youth connect with support services, so what impact will the federal government's under-16s ban have on those community hubs?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">090b6a9b3a1c75a2d5531cc8512af193</guid></item><item><title>Record gold prices drive investment in exploration across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/record-gold-prices-drive-investment-in-exploration-australia/106121424</link><description>The money being spent on drilling for gold has increased 45 per cent in the past 12 months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d69ff758de9fcfef8c74baabbe66e46</guid></item><item><title>Migrant workers raise concerns at modern slavery inquiry in Coffs Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/modern-slavery-migrant-hearings-in-nsw/106130342</link><description>Witnesses have told an inquiry into modern slavery that migrant workers are being exploited in the nation's blueberry capital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad5a183a10a9cc947ab7eba5cea3574c</guid></item><item><title>Underwater microphone records humpback whale sounds off NSW south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/underwater-microphone-records-humpback-whale-sounds/106129670</link><description>Underwater microphones off the NSW south coast capture consistent humpback whale sounds throughout the 2024 migration season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cc82218726405dc2f124c6cb8f59615</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne lawyer Dean Hadjina sentenced to prison for stealing from grieving widow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/melbourne-lawyer-dean-hadjina-prison-sentence-stealing-widow/106139262</link><description>Dean Hadjina is sentenced to prison for stealing $482,154 from a vulnerable widow who spoke little English as she sought compensation payouts after her husband's workplace death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b4d1bb774295f2d85cb6eceb1c2956</guid></item><item><title>18-year-old man in critical condition after Gold Coast assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/qld-serious-assault-gold-coast/106139282</link><description>An 18-year-old man is in hospital in a critical condition after being assaulted on the Gold Coast on Friday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c56049f475d1eb150165a6fdc757cdfa</guid></item><item><title>Croc wrangler Matt Wright's prison sentence a stark warning after years-long court saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/matt-wright-sentencing-fallout-for-helicopter-industry/106136470</link><description>Crocodile wrangler Matt Wright built a television and tourism empire in the Northern Territory, but that's all come crashing down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68ab8e1dd2c64631e9d79719aeb78b86</guid></item><item><title>Federal police release nine images to help identify online child sex abuse victims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/afp-releases-images-to-identify-child-sex-abuse-victims/106139222</link><description>These photographs might look like everyday objects, but the AFP-led Australian Centre to Counter Child Exploitation (ACCCE) believe they could help identify victims of online child sexual exploitation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2c17177c4b6be426a3ba95050bff1ff</guid></item><item><title>Perth's queer nightclub, Connections, celebrates 50 years of dancing and difference</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/perth-queer-nightclub-connections-celebrates-50-years/106137800</link><description>Founded in 1975, when homosexuality was still illegal in Western Australia, Connections nightclub has seen waves of social change and kept the party going.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbfccd7dc10d5ba74db21e7a1c43fba5</guid></item><item><title>Google to build undersea cables in Papua New Guinea under Australia defence treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/google-building-undersea-cables-in-png/106139500</link><description>PNG says the measure will provide a key upgrade to its digital backbone and link the north and south of the nation with high-capacity cables.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bdcdd335abbb5327aeebb352b5456bf</guid></item><item><title>Government-formed agency recommends against NSW coal industry expansion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/independent-agency-recommends-against-nsw-coal-expansion/106139270</link><description>Coal mining extensions and expansions will continue, the New South Wales premier says, despite a government-appointed agency finding further approvals were not consistent with emissions targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9daf0baa045cb5bb4ef13da04acdb8b6</guid></item><item><title>Australian fans among most active in searching for FIFA World Cup tickets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/australian-fans-search-for-fifa-world-cup-tickets/106139824</link><description>Australia are among the countries with the most ticket requests for next year's World Cup, which is bound to please Socceroos coach Tony Popovic and his team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">316d9995db7dddc4dbd80b9b4e357dbc</guid></item><item><title>What you should know about 'Bali belly' and how to avoid it before it ruins your holiday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/what-do-you-need-to-know-about-bali-belly-and-how-to-avoid-it/106133990</link><description>Every year about 1.5 million Australians travel to Bali. Chances are either you or someone you know has caught a stomach bug after travelling to the popular Indonesian destination. So what can you do to avoid it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e5d649d03f0cad3ea98b4b637b0d8ae</guid></item><item><title>Desert Fireball Network students find fist-sized meteorite in outback WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/desert-fireball-network-students-find-meteorite-outback-wa/106139512</link><description>PhD students from Curtin University have found a 300-gram meteorite after a five-day search in remote bushland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a00682db69e225e1eeff0b8b54a44fd</guid></item><item><title>United Nations delegation warns of Australia's treatment of prisoners, detainees and breach in human rights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/united-nations-warn-australia-prison-detention-human-rights/106136950</link><description>A delegation of United Nations inspectors have raised the alarm about Australia's detention facilities and a breach of human rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">075a06b44f92126c2bd0015a8827c776</guid></item><item><title>Severe heatwave cancels event, closes popular abalone fishing spot as season begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/severe-heatwave-as-wa-abalone-season-begins/106139888</link><description>Perth is in the grip of its hottest spell so far this summer, forcing the closure of a popular tourist attraction as abalone fishing season got underway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e379757217715ba153713c1409b032d</guid></item><item><title>Jailed Myanmar leader Aung San Suu Kyi's supporters rally in Sydney to protest junta elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/aung-san-suu-kyi-supporters-rally-sydney-myanmar-junta-election/106139074</link><description>Aung San Suu Kyi's son leads a rally of supporters in Sydney as part of global demonstrations trying to increase international pressure on Myanmar's ruling military junta.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7882d7a6e0844c1867f57f204dfb409d</guid></item><item><title>Roger Rasheed slams 'battle of the sexes' tennis clash between Nick Kyrgios and Aryna Sabalenka</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/roger-rasheed-nick-kyrgios-aryna-sabalenk-battle-of-the-sexes/106140068</link><description>High-profile Australian tennis coach Roger Rasheed has questioned the value of the upcoming "battle of the sexes"-style exhibition match between Nick Kyrgios and Aryna Sabalenka.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44c26b0beab1855f4660c042d1252f87</guid></item><item><title>China Coast Guard fires water cannon at Philippine fishing vessels in South China Sea, Manila says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/south-china-sea-chinese-water-cannon-philippine-coast-guard/106140098</link><description>Manila's coastguard says nearly two dozen Philippine fishing boats near Sabina Shoal were targeted with water cannon and blocking manoeuvres on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bb328352925a9ae0fcc01bbc0e0e037</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja open to middle order role for third Ashes Test in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/khawaja-open-to-middle-order-ashes-2025/106140150</link><description>Australia batter Usman Khawaja is feeling 100 per cent fit and is open to a return to the middle order for the third Ashes Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de5665c9e9bc10d34d2ac7d2c9d8c0c7</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: It's the season of giving so I'm gifting you a chance at redemption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/106130212</link><description>Your track record doesn't leave me hopeful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">693aef896cb1373b315facefcd53f061</guid></item><item><title>'I was tricked': African athlete lured to Russia for work, ends up on front lines of Ukraine war</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/athlete-says-russia-lured-him-for-work-then-sent-him-to-war/106122770</link><description>Vladimir Putin says Russia has "no need" to recruit foreign fighters to bolster its invasion of Ukraine, but inside this prisoner of war camp, people have a very different story.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0f54e990b1e6ae1e6cd660235034b18</guid></item><item><title>Sanction-skirting 'shadow fleets' in Trump's sights. Here's how they work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/what-are-shadow-fleets/106137346</link><description>Tensions between the US and Venezuela are soaring after American forces seized an oil tanker in the Caribbean Sea. So why is US President Donald Trump targeting so-called "shadow fleets"?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28967e6fabbd1b6edbe8e8daa824b124</guid></item><item><title>How Benjamin Netanyahu's corruption trial became a struggle for Israel itself</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/israel-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-corruption-trial-and-deep-state/106124242</link><description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's backers view his corruption trial as a witch hunt — but his detractors argue it is the system finally catching up to a ruthless political operative who is prepared to do anything to hold on to power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">868ab4d48d09c7dddeca77bf4f254be5</guid></item><item><title>Two US troops killed in Syria ambush along with one American civilian</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/us-service-members-killed-in-syria/106140654</link><description>Two US service members and one American civilian are killed in an ambush in central Syria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63bd2995922c21f9ffbaed628e6b75e2</guid></item><item><title>After tragedies and rescues, Tasmanian bushwalkers urged to 'be prepared' for all conditions this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/tasmania-cradle-mountain-rescues-hiking-prep-for-summer/106028884</link><description>It has been a busy year for search and rescue operations in the Tasmanian high country. Authorities say a concerning number of visitors to the state's famous national parks are ill-prepared for the fickle weather — even during summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">366e2bd207b3ac5db65be6ca27b9bd08</guid></item><item><title>Iron deficiency is a challenge for many female athletes, like Super Netball's Zara Walters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/zara-walters-victorian-institute-of-sport-iron-deficiency/106108280</link><description>Zara Walters felt tired, dizzy and unable to recover from training sessions — then she found out she was low in iron. It's a condition that often goes undiagnosed, especially in female athletes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ee03bad452a9f38b43e0a5a4d93185d</guid></item><item><title>Gippsland teenager Ethan Monck celebrates first job after a lifetime battling cancer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/ethan-monck-gets-his-first-job-fast-food-chain-mcdonalds/106001356</link><description>Ethan Monck's health problems began the day he was born. Now aged 17, he's celebrating after starting his first job and the freedom it gives him to pursue his hobbies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d8cd975bcb08a3e9ad54c598b450043</guid></item><item><title>Earthquake due 'in foreseeable future' after 70 years of Adelaide tremors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/is-adelaide-due-for-another-big-earthquake/106126974</link><description>Adelaide sits on the most active seismic zone in Australia and has more than its fair share of tremors below magnitude-4, but it's been 71 years since it was rocked by a serious earthquake. Now, it's a matter of when, not if, it gets another one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">547eb51b5fce33d426720340f3261fa1</guid></item><item><title>The Kaurna cultural program inspiring students in Adelaide's south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/sa-students-find-connection-through-kaurna-program/106136626</link><description>Kanyanyapilla means "place of many eagles", and it's where Indigenous students in Adelaide are coming to connect with Kaurna culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2cc1db9b6981d4c5f9aed4bf8c5c018</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Sweeney transformed herself to play Christy Martin in a biopic as Hollywood struggles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/how-sydney-sweeney-transformed-herself-to-play-a-boxer/106132482</link><description>Sydney Sweeney changed a lot about herself to play Christy Martin in a biopic about the boxer. She says it was a role she had to take.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51771885fbf1fdd5558fa08cca2331b1</guid></item><item><title>Lionel Messi's India tour begins in chaos, seats ripped out in Kolkata</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/lionel-messi-india-tour-chaos-seats-ripped-out/106140692</link><description>Indian football fans ripped up seats and invaded the pitch in Kolkata as Lionel Messi's first appearance in India took a chaotic and dangerous turn.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6942144dbdac54fd6b55f6ac85693f8</guid></item><item><title>Medical groups push for consequences for freebirth 'birthkeepers' posing as medical professionals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/inside-the-freebirth-birthkeeper-movement/106137044</link><description>A number of recent deaths linked to freebirths — where a pregnant woman chooses to give birth with no registered medical professional present — is prompting health groups to speak out about rising levels of misinformation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16095bdb783bfd370331e86386a64607</guid></item><item><title>Alpha Bakery making famous pies again with family support after dementia diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/alpha-bakery-making-pies-again-family-supports-brother-dementia/106050182</link><description>Christopher Tilse has worked from dawn to dusk in a bakery most of his life. Dementia made that a challenge, but thanks to family support, he is still baking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef9efe3534ff9ae6f4fdc06349c272fd</guid></item><item><title>Three quarters of Canberra's suburbs see reduction in tree canopy despite government's 2045 goal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/decline-tree-coverage-bush-capital-canberra/106139714</link><description>It's called the 'bush capital', but three quarters of Canberra's suburbs have recorded a decline in tree coverage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a1e07b3043c41eef341fae603953e04</guid></item><item><title>UK police won't probe claim former prince Andrew asked bodyguard to investigate Virginia Roberts Giuffre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/uk-police-wont-probe-andrew-claim/106140752</link><description>London's police force says it will not take further action over claims that former prince Andrew asked his protection officer to carry out checks on Virginia Roberts Giuffre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">804859bb33197ef5054bd889c0dbd03a</guid></item><item><title>Two-thirds of women escaping violence in Broome cannot access help</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/hundreds-turned-away-from-broome-domestic-violence-refuge/106057354</link><description>In a region with Western Australia's highest rates of family and domestic violence, a Kimberley service provider says it can only help one-third of women who need it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">337b73f0f8756ae11e894af3cf8dbae2</guid></item><item><title>Pulp Fiction, The Mask actor Peter Greene dies aged 60</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/pulp-fiction-the-mask-actor-peter-greene-dies-aged-60/106140816</link><description>Peter Greene, a character actor best known for his role as the iconic villain, Zed in Pulp Fiction, has died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36ad8509e456fcf6d30148f22f003c23</guid></item><item><title>Brown University shooting in US leaves two students dead and nine injured</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/active-shooter-brown-university/106140822</link><description>Police detain a "person of interest" in connection with the Brown University shooting that left two students dead and another nine people wounded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2eefee872256923a130ecd2adf6c1ab</guid></item><item><title>Conservationist uses invasive fox fur to make ethical clothing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/conservationist-clothing-maker-turns-fox-pelts-to-coats/106049382</link><description>In six months, Emma Sinclair went from not knowing how to sew to launching her own fashion label based around fox fur.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be15a03e36974b98c27cb9abdac073ef</guid></item><item><title>Two students killed, nine injured in shooting at Brown University — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/brown-university-active-shooting-live-blog/106140862</link><description>Two students have been killed and nine other people have been injured after a gunman entered an engineering building during final exams at Brown University in the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a993b5dc81abdc518e58657733134887</guid></item><item><title>Budding musicians on NSW far south coast create songs about First Nations culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/first-nations-musicians-mentored-by-band-to-create-songs/106113948</link><description>With sounds recorded in a makeshift studio, this group of high school students produced music about First Nations culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d20d7fec8bae421ad705bc5fc8033d39</guid></item><item><title>Orchid enthusiasts call for greater protection for native species facing habitat threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/new-orchids-discovered-habitat-threat-mount-wedge/106072786</link><description>Two centuries after orchids were first documented in South Australia, photographers are still discovering new plants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d238655dc5d75962a61dc09df9c50031</guid></item><item><title>Searching for treasure in the Aussie bush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/searching-for-treasure-in-the-aussie-bush/106109214</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca8167284f0f87b8b3d3de1ba0cc8a2b</guid></item><item><title>Brett Lee backs current Australian bowling attack as greatest ever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/brett-lee-backs-current-australian-bowling-attack-as-greatest/106141014</link><description>Brett Lee ranks Australia's bowling attack as better than the one he was part of, which featured the likes of Glenn McGrath and Shane Warne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6e1aa66b31fbbd1ea5a920c9345b872</guid></item><item><title>Books reflecting remote Indigenous lifestyles and culture 'key' to students' reading success</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/improving-indigenous-students-reading-skills-with-relevant-books/106056534</link><description>An educator says books that reflect remote Indigenous cultures and lifestyles are "the key to success" in improving reading outcomes for First Nations students.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7add03b17810e2b90d8dc3cd234850c0</guid></item><item><title>Virtual fencing is now legal in NSW. This is what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/virtual-fencing-legalised-nsw/106128536</link><description>NSW farmers have been given the green light to use virtual fencing, providing an option over traditional posts and wires. Here is how it works.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e9f8e8bdd44e4f16106cd6fd01eb862</guid></item><item><title>Coles and Woolworths hit back at government's price gouging ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/coles-woolworths-hit-back-at-price-gouging-ban/106141094</link><description>Lower grocery bills are being promised within this new ban on price gouging, but giant retailers say they are the ones feeling the pinch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b22d07967f57eba637ea6d9f424f96a9</guid></item><item><title>I’m heading overseas. Do I really need travel vaccines?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/i-m-heading-overseas-do-i-really-need-travel-vaccines-/106139094</link><description>Australia is in its busiest month for short-term overseas travel. And there are so many things to consider when planning your trip. Unfortunately, it's easy to overlook the importance of pre-travel vaccinations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3487138a302c170a64988aa991484502</guid></item><item><title>Police condemn 'outrageous' Guildford West shooting as vision shows 30 bullets fired into home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/hunt-street-guildford-shooting-video/106141186</link><description>The vision shows the moment a gunman sprayed an underworld associate's home with up to 30 rounds while two women and a child were inside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e1081f69550a94e14b27afd0d282eed</guid></item><item><title>'It's cooked': Big Brother contestant quit so she could afford the dentist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/abiola-big-brother-prize-money-dentist/106135150</link><description>Data obtained by the ABC shows people are waiting months, if not years, for dental care in every Australian state and territory due to the cost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">062c6c7e609df623f810eb7822b805f4</guid></item><item><title>Australians open to dealing with AI on a Triple Zero emergency call, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/triple-zero-000-call-service-needs-ai-tech-upgrade-survey-finds/106120258</link><description>Could artificial intelligence speed up emergency responses by receiving a caller's video or smartwatch data and capturing words like "knife" and "collision"? Most people think so and welcome the technology's potential, a survey finds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9bee4df8d38455408afb5df240c0fcf</guid></item><item><title>Researchers call for water safety to be part of English education for migrants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/call-for-water-safety-to-be-incorporated-into-english-learning/106119112</link><description>As the country heads into the summer holidays, experts are again warning Australians to be aware of swim safety at beaches, pools and other waterways.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4390c5ccee6eff142d214ab84533e218</guid></item><item><title>Brendon McCullum vows against 'knee-jerk reactions' for third Ashes Test in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/mccullum-kneejerk-reactions-ashes-test-adelaide/106141442</link><description>England coach Brendon McCullum confirms his side's batting line-up will be unchanged for its must-win third Ashes Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6b4eae7c4f8a17c2ac9e7248c34c94d</guid></item><item><title>Short-form videos could be harming young minds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/how-short-form-videos-could-be-harming-young-minds/106139042</link><description>Online short-form video has shifted from a light distraction to a constant backdrop in many children's lives. But they were never built with children in mind, although many children use them daily.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0673a03803caca19c88a5d008e4686de</guid></item><item><title>Matt Wright's character references from famous singer, high-powered business person, media heavyweight released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/matt-wright-character-references-lee-kernaghan-mick-burns-/106141232</link><description>Country music star Lee Kernaghan, powerful business person Mick Burns, traditional owner Brian Tipungwuti and media heavyweight Nick Fordham all provided character references for celebrity crocodile wrangler Matt Wright ahead of his sentencing, court documents show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">278dc76daef3e70967b88f3de9193549</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting updates: Terrorist attack on Jewish community event — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/bondi-beach-shooting-terrorist-attack-12-dead/106141580</link><description>Twelve people are confirmed dead and dozens are injured in a terrorist attack on the Chanukah by the Sea celebration at Sydney's Bondi Beach. Look back at our coverage from the day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f3bc227b08c78d8902dea436fb15458</guid></item><item><title>Gunman tackled by member of the public at Bondi Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/gunman-tackled-by-member-of-the-public-at-bondi-beach/106141666</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccc71cef55c177451db89c51abb0d939</guid></item><item><title>What we know so far about the Bondi Beach shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/what-we-know-bondi-beach-shooting/106141672</link><description>Sixteen people are dead after two gunmen fired dozens of shots into crowds of people at Bondi Beach. Here's what we know so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26901ced8b258ae6960177c46c930cd3</guid></item><item><title>Law enforcement source identifies Bondi gunman as Sydney man Naveed Akram</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/law-enforcement-source-identifies-bondi-gunman-as-naveed-akram/106141750</link><description>A law enforcement official has told the ABC that police have raided one of the alleged gunman's house in Sydney's south-west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c27975b9fb669ae4eaf99f4ad3e6223</guid></item><item><title>Moment Ahmed Al Ahmed disarms gunman Sajid Akram captured on film</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/bondi-shooter-tackled-and-disarmed-by-possible-civilian/106141690</link><description>Dramatic video shows 43-year-old Ahmed Al Ahmed crouching behind a parked vehicle near one of the Bondi Beach gunmen before disarming him during the terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab2602ba86af28c27b8e903ac7a50125</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese condemns Bondi Beach terror attack as 'act of evil antisemitism'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/albanese-political-leaders-respond-to-bondi-beach-terror-attack/106142036</link><description>Anthony Albanese condemns the Bondi beach terror attack as an "act of evil antisemitism" targeting Australia's Jewish community, declaring the nation will never submit to "division, violence or hatred".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cedc87d4ab4b665da5e59ba25a648db</guid></item><item><title>More Bondi Beach shooting victims named, including 10yo girl and rabbis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-beach-shooting-victims-named-as-10yo-matilda-and-rabbis/106142362</link><description>A 10-year-old girl named Matilda has been identified as one of the victims of Sunday's terror attack at Sydney's Bondi Beach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e03ef2b7174c78ebdf7e7b8679f5bb8a</guid></item><item><title>Australia's medicinal cannabis situation leaves government in a bind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/australia-s-medicinal-cannabis-bind-is-a-political-hot-potato/106140878</link><description>There doesn't seem to be much political mileage for the government to do anything at all — whether that is cracking down and forcing cannabis users back onto the black market or fully legalising the substance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">351d59353e06489323dfd13cb834bafa</guid></item><item><title>Brain research centre The Florey sues executive, alleging he stole and erased files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/the-florey-brain-research-centre-files-claims-against-executive/106135388</link><description>Australia's biggest brain research centre is suing one of its executives, alleging he deleted troves of commercially sensitive information during a midnight incursion at its Melbourne laboratory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8345d1270fa7ecf8c2167fcfa10b7f08</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic Arts Fellowship allows artists to develop works on the ice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/australian-antarctic-arts-fellowship/106139246</link><description>Over the past four decades, the Australian Antarctic Arts Fellowship has given creatives the opportunity to travel south and develop works on the icy continent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">574f0d2516ef3270e6679d6ed8e90ea9</guid></item><item><title>Photographing penguins in Antarctica</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/leila-jeffreys-photographing-penguins-antarctica/106136800</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f292e504bf8faabeea539a3c5e5b979c</guid></item><item><title>Retiring captain Elyse Villani says Hurricanes' WBBL win shows team's potential</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/hurricanes-captain-elyse-villani-retires-after-wbbl-win/106141334</link><description>Elyse Villani has described the Hurricanes' win as a "fairy tale" ending to her WBBL career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">111f91f49499824a5d1f69e7c6e6f83c</guid></item><item><title>Superannuation funds accused of delaying disability insurance claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/super-funds-accused-of-poor-handling-of-tpd-insurance-claims/106050046</link><description>The regulator has found that while some superannuation funds have improved insurance claims response times, others are still falling short, with long delays in relation to mental health claims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed72917ef5a3d4a0f3e4254687d92da</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting death toll rises as police scour crime scene after terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/nsw-sydney-bondi-beach-shooting-hanukkah-jewish-community/106141648</link><description>Fifteen people and one of two gunmen are confirmed to have died after the attack on Sunday evening as members of the Jewish community attended a Hanukkah event in the city's eastern suburbs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f396411115ff090ddac9ce77ff86537f</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting updates: PM to strengthen gun laws across Australia following Bondi attack — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-beach-shooting-terrorist-attack/106142446</link><description>Fifteen people were killed, including a 10-year-old girl. One of the two gunmen has also died, while a further 42 people were taken to hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53ed92f5b0514ac2d2ce9a3d9c4074e1</guid></item><item><title>It's hard to imagine Bondi attack won't change Australia like Port Arthur did</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-attack-could-change-australia-like-port-arthur-massacre/106142102</link><description>For a while, it was like so many other summer Sundays in Bondi, but Australia's most deadly mass shooting in almost three decades could change the country forever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">002e5bc350add14a22451807be66fa87</guid></item><item><title>Heat to give way to more rain and storms in the south-east as school holidays kick off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/southeast-qld-weather-wrap-rain-heat-bom-storms-forecast/106137146</link><description>Parts of south-east Queensland can expect a slight easing of summer heat early this week, with the Bureau of Meteorology forecasting a 6C drop in some areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4603cfa94b2cb04a4119a9de594b8f66</guid></item><item><title>Cooper Connolly stars as Perth Scorchers down Sydney Sixers in BBL opener</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/scorchers-down-sixers-bbl-opener/106142124</link><description>Cooper Connolly leads the Scorchers to victory as star Sixers recruit Babar Azam struggles in the BBL curtain raiser at Perth Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50698296472667855f8c9cd66d6cabac</guid></item><item><title>ASIO examined Bondi Beach gunman Naveed Akram in 2019 for close ties to Islamic State cell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-beach-attack-gunmen-father-and-son/106142630</link><description>Australia's domestic intelligence agency, ASIO, examined one of the Bondi Beach gunmen six years ago for his close ties to a Sydney-based Islamic State terrorism cell, the ABC understands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61d8702038585ef6be9d3817b6662640</guid></item><item><title>Kendrick Lamar delights young fan with birthday song at Canberra Spilt Milk festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/kendrick-lamar-serenades-young-fan-at-canberra-spilt-milk/106142574</link><description>American rap superstar Kendrick Lamar brought the house down at Spilt Milk in Canberra, but it was his interaction with a nine-year-old superfan that stole the show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16ca55a20161d6ca4cbf526e3b6f236a</guid></item><item><title>England warned Adelaide pitch is not as friendly as it looks ahead of third Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/ashes-adelaide-test-england-warned-pitch-not-friendly/106142732</link><description>With England pinning its hopes on victory in the third Test, the tourists have been warned that the Adelaide pitch is not as friendly as it looks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aec1d41e99ee9fd7c4c64bcffb15282b</guid></item><item><title>Hollow Knight: Silksong, Death Stranding 2 and Donkey Kong Bananza among our best games of 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/video-games-end-of-year-wrap-2025/106038598</link><description>There are games to suit everyone, and overwhelmingly Australians are a game-playing nation. Here are some of the most important titles released this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">213c78332ceb94cd8515daaa19a2dc06</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley accuses Albanese of failing to keep Jewish Australians safe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/albanese-told-to-endorse-antisemitism-plan-after-bondi-shooting/106142578</link><description>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley says Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has allowed antisemitism to "fester" and failed to keep Jewish Australians safe in the wake of yesterday's "evil" terror attack on the shores of Bondi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b45fc7ff1574ff3e49240c068f74667d</guid></item><item><title>WA's wettest towns have had no local drinking water for 15 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/wa-wettest-towns-drinking-water-carting/106120700</link><description>Quinninup and Northcliffe in Western Australia's south-west receive an average of 1 metre of rain every year, so why has the state government spent millions of dollars trucking in drinking water?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b73df9467313d7d89bd980191d5e1a4</guid></item><item><title>Matildas star Sam Kerr impresses again for Chelsea in WSL after starting as sub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/matildas-star-sam-kerr-impresses-again-for-chelsea-in-wsl/106143024</link><description>Matildas gun Sam Kerr starts on the bench again, but makes an immediate impact for Chelsea in a 3-0 WSL victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e34c904b76ecd95d28f27217323aecd</guid></item><item><title>Jewish community leaders say 'things can't go back to normal' after deadly Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-shootings-jewish-community-response/106142772</link><description>The Australian Jewish community is in a state of shock following the Bondi shootings, with leaders calling for more to be done to combat anti-Semitism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ad2b17010a2d178bc4822ae0b4fc9af</guid></item><item><title>Kahu's been woodchopping his whole life, but a heart attack mid-competition almost killed him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/axeman-brought-back-to-life-after-heart-attack/106113688</link><description>Kahu Woolley was clinically dead multiple times, but quick actions by his friends brought him back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cf809b3bb5a37d997237793fca40e31</guid></item><item><title>Soren Copley in court over Philippines child sex abuse allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/soren-copley-philippines-sex-abuse-allegations/106143004</link><description>The Australian Federal Police says it launched an investigation into North Queensland man Soren Copley in September after a tip-off from US Homeland Security.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bd26689ae3d937711a3d87272f6fabd</guid></item><item><title>Dolphin Sands bushfire sparked by improperly extinguished burn off, Tasmanian authorities confirm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/dolphin-sands-fire-caused-by-a-landowner-burning-off/106143708</link><description>A bushfire in Tasmania that destroyed 19 homes was caused by a registered burn conducted about a week earlier, which was not extinguished by a landowner, authorities have confirmed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b23d3e099993b34951f2b4167aa81e0b</guid></item><item><title>Australians urged to give blood in wake of Bondi Beach mass shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-shooting-how-to-help-call-for-blood-donations/106142864</link><description>NSW Premier Chris Minns urges community members wanting to help the Jewish community following the Bondi terror attack to donate blood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63d91f901c3614f575701fabeb7f39f0</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Police ramp up presence at Jewish places of worship after Bondi mass shooting, as public Hanukkah events cancelled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/qld-police-meet-review-security-arrangements-bondi-shooting/106143320</link><description>Queensland Police Acting Commissioner Cheryl Scanlon says authorities are not aware of any specific threats to the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">deca6f8205be81b067e5b4bd6a025549</guid></item><item><title>Premier says Operation Shelter will be ‘inconvenient’ but necessary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/premier-says-operation-shelter-will-be-inconvenient-/106144190</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75e37e30fce5d51941239075cba2a66a</guid></item><item><title>Parole release of Snowtown murderer James Vlassakis overturned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/sa-snowtown-murderer-james-vlassakis-parole-overturned/106143062</link><description>Snowtown serial killer James Vlassakis will remain behind bars, after the South Australian Parole Board's decision to release him was overturned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54e1e8b751e40e2d894b77e66170274a</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese will face questions over Bondi Beach shooting as Australia mourns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/anthony-albanese-bondi-terror-attack-sussan-ley-mike-burgess/106143400</link><description>Anthony Albanese's first responsibility after the horrific Bondi terror attack is to lead a grieving nation. His next will be to explain how this happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6338d979d5dcf6d65657f254be1bde4f</guid></item><item><title>NFL quick hits: Patrick Mahomes tears his ACL, Micah Parsons suffers knee injury, Philip Rivers scores a touchdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/nfl-quick-hits-patrick-mahomes-tears-his-acl/106143906</link><description>Patrick Mahomes tears his ACL, the Packers suffer a major blow, Donald Trump's coin toss goes viral and Old Man Rivers scores a touchdown. Here's the five quick hits from the NFL action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">917e095a65744a38572239a34aadbcce</guid></item><item><title>Cameron Pearson admits murdering Perth lawyer Alice McShera at Crown Towers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/cameron-pearson-admits-murder-lawyer-alice-mcshera-crown-towers/106144072</link><description>A 44-year-old man admits killing Perth lawyer Alice McShera, whose body was found in a hotel room in the upmarket Crown Towers complex in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef9f1ecaf2e9fe522b333dec140916b4</guid></item><item><title>What videos tell us about the final moments of the Bondi Beach terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/abc-news-verify-bondi-beach-terrorist-last-six-minutes/106143126</link><description>In the final horrific minutes of the Bondi Beach terror attack, more than 100 shots were fired. ABC NEWS Verify has analysed footage showing how the last six minutes unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a855c002e49658b5a61e812833f1e71</guid></item><item><title>Australian luger Alex Ferlazzo makes stunning recovery during run after falling off his sled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/australian-luger-alex-ferlazzo-recovers-fter-falling-off/106144550</link><description>Australian luger Alex Ferlazzo pulls off a miracle recovery after falling off his sled halfway through a run.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da90e58ae3290114d4c144cf32e28ab1</guid></item><item><title>Inquest to probe death of Allan John Houston at Saraji mine in 2018</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/inquest-for-death-of-allan-john-houston-at-saraji-mine-in-2018/106143884</link><description>The veteran miner died when the bulldozer he was operating rolled off an embankment into a pool of mud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55c0604be4bff0f1b094511f5bc1eaa7</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong media mogul Jimmy Lai found guilty of sedition and collusion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/hong-kong-media-mogul-jimmy-lai-guilty-sedition-collusion/106143206</link><description>Jimmy Lai, a former Hong Kong media mogul and one of the city's most outspoken critics of China, has been found guilty of sedition and collusion in a landmark national security case that has drawn international scrutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b999a3880da2cb74b288fabc6b5fd306</guid></item><item><title>Deaths of Rob Reiner and wife investigated as apparent homicide, LAPD says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/two-found-dead-at-rob-reiners-home-brentwood/106145062</link><description>Rob Reiner, known for directing When Harry Met Sally... and A Few Good Men, was found dead alongside his wife inside their Los Angeles home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d04a94b290cb0635eec136bb99bef983</guid></item><item><title>Man convicted of kidnapping 19yo Charlie Gander now eligible for parole</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/danny-clarke-convicted-of-kidnapping-eligible-for-parole/106137450</link><description>A judge says the offending of a man found guilty of kidnapping a Victorian 19-year-old, who was later murdered, was "spontaneous" and "born of panic".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ead77bc71a42109697426dd3359607aa</guid></item><item><title>National cabinet agrees unanimously to strengthen Australia's strict gun laws in wake of Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/albanese-proposes-tougher-gun-laws-after-bondi-attack/106143310</link><description>An urgent meeting of national cabinet agrees to strengthen Australia's gun laws in the wake of the Bondi Beach shooting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e758b09f0c99d1348b909c0f9e2e87a</guid></item><item><title>Man charged over newborn's death in Gold Coast M1 crash granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/man-charged-over-m1-death-granted-bail/106134844</link><description>A man charged over a crash that killed a one-month-old baby on the Gold Coast has been granted bail following an 11-week police investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">390bad92c54818ff286ba65c3086d062</guid></item><item><title>Man who killed two people in Bowen Bridge crash sentenced to home detention and community service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/death-by-negligent-driving-bowen-bridge-sentence/106143712</link><description>A man who caused the death of an elderly couple while driving with methamphetamine in his blood is ordered to complete 100 hours of community service and four months of home detention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb2e47144ce2e8a2f0896e8526ff92b3</guid></item><item><title>Parents of man who wrestled gun from Bondi Beach shooter call son a 'hero'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-beach-shooting-fruit-shop-gunman-hero-parents-speak/106143864</link><description>The ABC has spoken to the parents of Ahmed Al Ahmed who was shot after he heroically wrestled and disarmed one of the Bondi Beach attackers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6a595472638fcebca399c76d7ebf9fa</guid></item><item><title>WA government meets with Jewish leaders after Bondi beach terror attack, increased police patrols</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/wa-government-meets-with-jewish-leaders-after-bondi-attack/106143968</link><description>WA Premier Roger Cook condemns the "cowardly and heinous" attack in Bondi, after meeting with Jewish leaders in Perth as police increase patrols.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aebd956f068195b9dae5bb04c75acfc7</guid></item><item><title>NSW inquest told how exploding lithium-ion batteries caused volatile fires killing three</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/lithium-battery-fire-inquest/106143100</link><description>A NSW inquest has been told exploding lithium-ion batteries caused volatile fires killing three people in separate blazes within minutes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45b2521beb7a85c63b52380d119cbe74</guid></item><item><title>Bondi shootings show Australia's gun laws slipping since Port Arthur reforms, advocate says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-shooting-proof-port-arthur-guns-laws-failing-advocate-says/106142756</link><description>Gun control advocates say the terrifying mass shooting in Bondi on Sunday shows Australia's firearms laws, reformed after the Port Arthur tragedy, have been weakened in the years since.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">661087b209c6fe9d5ab3e6f97e76a808</guid></item><item><title>Consolidated Pastoral Company buys Beetaloo aggregation in historic deal worth more than $300m</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/cpc-buys-beetaloo-station-aggregation-for-300-million-plus/106143408</link><description>Consolidated Pastoral Company spends more than $300 million to buy the Beetaloo aggregation of stations in the NT.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49aa2ab64911fd8e49ebe2728109def3</guid></item><item><title>Australian National University stabbing victim tells court she's 'riddled with flashbacks'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/act-alex-ophel-attempted-murder-two-women-anu-trial-begins/106144496</link><description>One of two women stabbed in an attack at the Australian National University two years ago tells the ACT Supreme Court she will never feel safe again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff88c54644a3807d9bb7a84803ec5b16</guid></item><item><title>Harry Brook will rein in batting technique as England confirm team change for Adelaide Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/harry-brook-adelaide-test-cricket-bazball/106145512</link><description>As England reveal their changes for the Adelaide Test, Harry Brook has conceded he will rein in his batting technique in an effort to save the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08d7ea0d4a671a1c52d26ce33f1bcc66</guid></item><item><title>From barbecues to busy weeknights, here are seven salads to prepare this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/best-easy-summer-salads/106090760</link><description>Summer is the season for salad, and in that spirit, we've gathered seven of our finest together for you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a893c2c3c550d95330f8fcc101b821c</guid></item><item><title>Bondi's antisemitic attack is the Jewish diaspora's worst nightmare come true</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/benjamin-netanyahu-anthony-albanese-bondi-massacre/106144038</link><description>Israeli politicians have blamed Anthony Albanese for the devastating massacre in Bondi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93258c51718a7305f368056d7988e502</guid></item><item><title>New Queensland hospital bed timeline reveals some pushed back to 2032</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/queensland-hospital-beds-expansion-plan-pushed-back/106142866</link><description>The Queensland LNP government says it aims to roll out 2,600 new hospital beds across the state by 2032 at a cost of about $18.5 billion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0f70e307f0a646af575be863068b029</guid></item><item><title>As medicinal cannabis approvals surge, regulation sits on the fence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/medicinal-cannabis-approvals-alan-kohler/106146088</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f52809e4d9aa8ad5a5d7986ce32b28ff</guid></item><item><title>CAR T-cell cancer therapy to be available in SA from mid-2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/cart-t-cell-cancer-therapy-sa-royal-adelaide-hospital-mid-2026/106145758</link><description>The number of critical patients having to travel interstate to receive CAR T-cell therapy will be reduced from mid-next year, with SA to launch a service at the Royal Adelaide Hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ae439e4e2397dd9c07932e389d511f8</guid></item><item><title>ASX bosses committed to reform after damning inquiry into stock exchange operator sees shares fall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/asx-limited-shares-fall-stock-exchange-operator-inquiry/106145156</link><description>ASX bosses say they are committed to reform after the corporate regulator lashes the operator's failings in a report, saying it underestimates long-term problems, is insular and defensive with deficiencies in culture and leadership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">539b7179d78b2fd2bc2e222f96aca241</guid></item><item><title>Nathan Lyon insists he has nothing to prove in Adelaide ahead of Test return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/nathan-lyon-adelaide-ashes-england/106146112</link><description>For the first time in an age Nathan Lyon is not an automatic selection in the Test side but the returning off spinner insists he has nothing to prove ahead of the upcoming clash with England in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97c540c4314a16e1aaf6f5acb8364799</guid></item><item><title>Largest Western Power outage in 15 years cuts essential mobile phone services in firegrounds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/western-power-outage-firefighters-mobile/106144026</link><description>Firefighters are left without communications while battling emergency-level bushfires as an extended power outage sees mobile phone towers fail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c3c9a457b6b4b4e000fe93d9490541c</guid></item><item><title>Jewish community mourn terror attack victims at Bondi Pavilion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/jewish-community-mourn-terror-attack-victims-at-bondi-pavilion/106146334</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de03e93fe4908934e36c7a318e2ad2cb</guid></item><item><title>How to talk to your kids about the Bondi Beach shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/talking-to-kids-about-bondi-shooting-terror-attack/106143526</link><description>This is what psychologists have to say about approaching the subject with children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9576f64cd4cb9ccb08452a02745df59</guid></item><item><title>Aerial vision of vigil for Bondi Beach attack victims at Bondi Pavilion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/aerials-bondi-vigil-beach/106146454</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f0986ba3db8be08578dcec7479742e</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106146368</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94742278037ce655405db43417aa2f4a</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with alleged murder of woman in Adelaide's parklands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/man-charged-with-murdering-woman-in-adelaide-parklands/106146510</link><description>Police have arrested a 37-year-old man for the alleged murder of a woman who was found unresponsive in Adelaide's parklands in January.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b9fdeadd6941ea76da4164d30f3f01f</guid></item><item><title>‘So many pairs of shoes’: Bondi deserted after shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/-so-many-pairs-of-shoes-bondi-deserted-after-shooting-/106146988</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89b39bea411e3896d6f0817f24e646af</guid></item><item><title>Woman recounts watching gunman fire first shots</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/woman-recounts-watching-gunman-fire-first-shots-/106146992</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eb020ff497a7997118e3296ab0ed0d3</guid></item><item><title>Suzi Milgate defends crepe attack on former NT chief minister Natasha Fyles as 'protest', during assault trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/suzi-milgate-nt-chief-minister-crepe-assault-trial-evidence/106144734</link><description>A former Darwin real estate agent charged with assaulting the Northern Territory's then-chief minister with a plate of crepes has tried to justify her actions as a "protest" against COVID-19 rules.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2ae2ac70dd50b27bd25b8dc92a5b1aa</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese acknowledges need to review gun laws following Bondi attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/anthony-albanese-bondi-attacks-interview-730/106147034</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05364217a6eb20feb7637e35b96772c7</guid></item><item><title>NSW Premier Chris Minns on the lessons that must be learned from Bondi terror attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/nsw-premier-chris-minns-interview-bondi-attacks-730/106147040</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d309729a4047a877ce3254f4f07910e1</guid></item><item><title>This fire destroyed a tractor east of Eneabba on Sunday.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/this-fire-destroyed-a-tractor-east-of-eneabba-on-sunday-/106146894</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2587a6f3abac72702bce7793d9b771c8</guid></item><item><title>Australia is in shock after a terror attack at Bondi Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/australia-is-in-shock-after-a-terror-attack-at-bondi-beach/106146612</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8024e5e3e4cc1905a3e4c79dd414c426</guid></item><item><title>Communities pay tribute to Bondi shooting victims in Sydney and Melbourne vigils</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-shooting-vigil-jewish-community/106145098</link><description>Crowds gather at Bondi to lay floral tributes and mourn, just 24 hours removed from a mass shooting that left 15 people dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45313a13879a0109b10eb980263e24e5</guid></item><item><title>10-year-old girl, Holocaust survivor and local rabbi among Bondi terror attack victims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/10-year-old-girl-holocaust-survivor-rabbi-among-bondi-victims-/106147252</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64d662304500f506f5b4a37421542dd1</guid></item><item><title>Australian National Imams Council: Bondi terror attack 'not about immigration'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/australian-national-imams-council-attack-not-about-immigration/106147264</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f31bce60cbdef7f34d192197cc791442</guid></item><item><title>McLeod's Daughters star Rachael Carpani dies aged 45</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/mcleod-s-daughters-star-rachael-carpani-dies/106147286</link><description>Rachael Carpani had recently appeared on long-running Australian soap Home and Away and frequently spoke out on a range of issues, including the need to address domestic violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b8b6b2d5bba69f83523097d1fe5e862</guid></item><item><title>Son arrested on suspicion of murder after Rob Reiner and wife found dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/rob-reiner-son-nick-reiner-arrested-in-custody/106147532</link><description>Nick Reiner is being held in custody in the US according to the Los Angeles Sheriff's Department.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">310c0afd467fe2306829cf4dea084cd5</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting live updates: Police promise 'highly visible, precise and around the clock' investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-beach-shooting-terrorist-attack-december-16/106147374</link><description>Bondi Beach will remain a crime scene, with security around Sydney's eastern suburbs bolstered. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">143eb1595903ed68600582ebb93c93e9</guid></item><item><title>US officials say Ukraine would get NATO-style guarantees in American peace deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/ukraine-hails-real-progress-in-peace-talks/106147530</link><description>Marathon talks between the US and Ukraine could see NATO-like security guarantees extended to Kyiv under a peace deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">003209d8b5f6805ea49d3dd062e0c5e0</guid></item><item><title>After being run over by a car while sunbaking, Sam reunites with paramedics who saved her</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/sunbaker-survives-car-accident-mica-paramedics-cardiac-arrest/106145824</link><description>Melbourne woman Samantha Hind was sunbaking on her lawn when her husband ran over her. After recovering from the brink of death, she is reunited with the paramedics who saved her life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c831b5ea961a7d56dd0fa761d4d7971e</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian parliament passes new sentencing laws, leading to stronger punishments for hate crimes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/tasmania-passes-new-hate-crime-laws/105767410</link><description>New laws to protect people from targeted violence have sailed through Tasmania's parliament, with experts celebrating their "innovative" approach. But some say the job is not done yet, with work still needed to implement them successfully.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4fbfd6b10cf9d60262a3a9e7792d506</guid></item><item><title>It's author Jane Austen's 250th birthday, and her books still have lessons for us today</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/this-day-in-history-jane-austen-250th-birthday/106143026</link><description>Her books like Pride and Prejudice and Emma were written hundreds of years ago, but have themes that still resonate in today's society.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">686588500f4cdb12d6f2ef95bb7c415d</guid></item><item><title>ABC timeline quiz: Guess what came first</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/timeline-quiz-dec-11/106120778</link><description>Guess the correct order or events to nail our new timeline quiz, where not all questions are created equal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">116b55cd014c164bd989d13fc24b0be6</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach terrorist attack: How two men unleashed horror on a celebration of joy and light</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-beach-terrorist-attack-maps-videos-explain-how-it-happened/106145448</link><description>From Western Sydney, a father and son made the journey east and brought terror to Bondi Beach and to Sydney's Jewish community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0384718a2b4bffc18d2d277fed59e9f</guid></item><item><title>What Australia can learn from the great Kiwi interest rate hike experiment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/rba-interest-rates-what-australia-can-learn-from-new-zealand/106143194</link><description>The RBA's interest rate-cutting cycle is at an end, and now a hardcore handful of critics say they shouldn't have cut rates in the first place. Conveniently, you only need to look across the ditch to see what could've happened if we'd followed that path.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1b2084b9bc67e4d71a38d1f785d89e5</guid></item><item><title>Bondi attack caused by 'cascading hate' left unchecked, say critics urging antisemitism plan be adopted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-unchecked-hate-antisemitism-plan-adoption/106143840</link><description>A report that has sat on Prime Minister Anthony Albanese's desk for months is being raised by critics as key evidence that the federal government has done too little, too late to respond to the rising tide of antisemitism since the October 7 terror attack in Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c19e0c4318584a39ff92f0045d5dbe37</guid></item><item><title>Bondi community members return to site of horrific shooting to offer support, comfort</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-community-members-return-to-horrific-shooting-site/106146630</link><description>On their own, with their dogs, in groups big and small, Bondi residents gathered calmly on Monday near the place where chaos erupted the night before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5168c3db60aaa9bcca9e3014db2ea606</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting: Community pays tribute to terror victims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-beach-shooting-victims-tributes/106144588</link><description>An act of terror took the lives of 15 people at Bondi. Their names, stories and legacies are held close by a shaken, grieving community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6444854282aecb8338066ba6efb222ab</guid></item><item><title>New Year's Eve bomb plot in California foiled, US authorities say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/california-new-year-bomb-terror-plot-foiled-us-authorities-say/106147534</link><description>US authorities say a New Year's Eve terror plot to bomb five sites in California and attack immigration agents has been thwarted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f056f55fc71150e5b6c343d608524e0d</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting inquiry flagged as victims mourned and injured fight for life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/nsw-sydney-bondi-beach-mass-shooting-inquiry-update/106145160</link><description>As sunset unfolded on Monday evening, mourners turned out at sites across Sydney to lay floral tributes for the victims of the Bondi Beach shooting, with the Opera House sails lit up in support of the Jewish community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6a75769e600bdbe0ef597e6f7ee7566</guid></item><item><title>Magic mushroom warning as Nimbin farmer fed up with trespassing foragers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/nimbin-farmer-warns-magic-mushrooms-sprayed-with-herbicide/106136770</link><description>A farmer is concerned for the safety of people foraging for magic mushrooms, which he has sprayed with herbicide, as a toxicologist warns about the dangers of fungi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">235afd5ea704c22d47cdfdea7d76344f</guid></item><item><title>Outpouring of grief as vigils are held across the UK for Bondi victims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/outpouring-of-grief-as-vigils-held-across-the/106147730</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc976fbe926da76e709069cb69639fb1</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Day weather forecast points to heatwave, tropical storms and festive sunshine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/christmas-day-weather-australia-heatwave-storms-sunshine/106144926</link><description>With only nine more sleeps until Christmas, we have now entered the meteorological window of predictability — in other words, forecasts are more accurate than just guessing the weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c35555d46a80393c36a4ca258163f838</guid></item><item><title>Inquest into Sonya Dutton's death in outback NSW hears of 'many unanswered questions'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/coronial-inquest-into-sonya-dutton-death-in-outback-nsw/106144034</link><description>Barkindji mother-of-two Sonya Dutton, 31, was found in her family's Wilcannia residence on March 29, 2022 — four days after she was reportedly last seen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0798f908bc137573034726977e2d0c2d</guid></item><item><title>Live markets updates: ASX wilts as sentiment turns against miners and banks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-december-16/106147810</link><description>The ASX has slipped into the red after a positive start to the session. Follow the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a267953cd9367e8e1c395d753282486c</guid></item><item><title>Bondi shooter Naveed Akram preaching Islam at Bankstown Station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-shooter-naveed-akram-preaching-islam-at-bankstown-station/106147016</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">697a254b255425150b3bf3f6908356aa</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting gunman Naveed Akram was follower of pro-Islamic State preacher Wisam Haddad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/video-shows-bondi-beach-shooting-gunman-preaching-islam-to-teens/106145626</link><description>At least one of the gunmen who killed 15 people in Sunday's Bondi Beach terrorist attack was known to authorities as a follower of a notorious Sydney pro-Islamic State cleric, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b52ae302a33646b87014607b9cbabe0e</guid></item><item><title>Richmond takes Olivia Wolmarans with top pick in the 2025 AFLW draft, Suns complete raid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/aflw-draft-2025-richmond-takes-olivia-wolmarans-at-number-one/106147828</link><description>Richmond takes Olivia Wolmarans with the top pick in the AFLW draft, as the Suns complete a stunning raid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f25b2ae36c9f9ebbabab0d92fd7d4e5</guid></item><item><title>Tony Burke heckled while paying tribute to the victim's of Sunday's terrorist attack at Bondi Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/tony-burke-heckled-while-paying-tribute-to-the-victim-s/106147890</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb6bb9c577ec165f77a173a064b2bc93</guid></item><item><title>Darwin filmmaking program gives storytellers with disabilities a platform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/disability-filmmaking-program-bus-stop-films/106123510</link><description>Aspiring Darwin filmmakers with disabilities have been getting job-ready, developing skills in scriptwriting, directing, cinematography and editing. It's the first time the program has been offered in the NT, with plans for it to expand even further.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4a1568496c0d480a3cc6808bf6132d5</guid></item><item><title>Four killed in Muckatah mini-van crash may have been farm workers, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/four-dead-minivan-muckatah-crash/106147696</link><description>Four adult passengers in a van, who are yet to be formally identified, died at the scene, north of Shepparton in Victoria. Five injured people, including three children and the male driver, were taken to various hospitals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c652501eea0b54a4454d9d91e222a691</guid></item><item><title>Manhunt for Brown University shooter renewed after police release detained man</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/manhunt-for-brown-university-shooter-renewed/106147734</link><description>With police releasing a person of interest, the manhunt continues for the Brown University shooter who killed two students and injured nine others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cda4f7b4ce792a68bca03af4dc4c2e4</guid></item><item><title>Darts player Cameron Menzies apologises after punching a table following world championship loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/world-championship-darts-player-cameron-menzies-punches-table/106147904</link><description>A Scottish darts player has apologised to fans after he punched a table during a loss at the world championship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58a18d38b7fd24e5c7ebfb7e40e3969e</guid></item><item><title>Man killed, two taken to hospital after unit fire in Brisbane suburb of Spring Hill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/brisbane-spring-hill-unit-fire-three-taken-to-hospital/106147938</link><description>Emergency services rushed to a Water Street address in Spring Hill after 3am following reports one of the units in the complex was fully engulfed by flames.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a26c7e38a9f9ba358b29fc9ba3edb535</guid></item><item><title>Advocates express concerns over ACT government wombat management plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/act-government-considers-wombat-management-plan/106146098</link><description>The ACT government is considering how to better manage the territory's wombat population, in response to challenges being experienced by farmers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b410c4eebc046f7d2b49c70d1bfa647</guid></item><item><title>Noosa region hit with minor flooding, with isolated storms, rain and cooler temperatures forecast for Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/qld-weather-rain-storms-summer-bom-forecast-brisbane/106146608</link><description>Storms and heavy rain are forecast to again hit large parts of Queensland today, with temperatures dropping across much of the sunshine state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a6e5c1436b140651eb92fbb95969cde</guid></item><item><title>London plane trees to be removed in Hamilton following infrastructure concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/hamilton-london-plane-trees-to-be-removed/106143002</link><description>Twenty-five London plane trees are set to be removed from Hamilton after they were found to be causing problems with local infrastructure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">650a4458c8203323dc2f86e1bcacfc46</guid></item><item><title>NSW cricketer banned from playing after allegations of nude photos being sent to teammates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/nsw-cricketer-banned-after-allegations-of-nude-photos/106148042</link><description>A NSW cricketer, who has played at Sheffield Shield level, is banned from playing after allegations he sent nude photos to young teammates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4afec07e7555499e2f1688d527834cd1</guid></item><item><title>Umpires pull Pakistan one-day skipper Shaheen Afridi out of Big Bash attack following full-toss drama</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/big-bash-shaheen-afridi-pulled-out-of-big-bash-attack/106148124</link><description>Umpires in the Big Bash clash between the Renegades and Heat sensationally pull Shaheen Afridi out of the attack after two full-toss deliveries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2718a28176625ac47cd21b4fba3462d</guid></item><item><title>Consent laws now protect sex workers against non-paying clients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/nsw-consent-laws-protect-sex-workers-against-non-paying-clients/106114406</link><description>Victims say NSW Police's frontline officers are still catching up with the changed legislation, which makes non-payment for sexual services a criminal offence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b8b1f11878ea34f099847c926ae3387</guid></item><item><title>The Bondi shooter only had a basic gun licence. How could he buy multiple high-powered rifles?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-shooter-legally-had-many-guns-australian-laws-explained/106145624</link><description>The Bondi shooter's gun licence entitled him to an uncapped quantity of certain kinds of rifles and shotguns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8843ad471684b6cba1aed9759fb08022</guid></item><item><title>The best board games to play (and gift) this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/the-best-board-games-to-play-and-gift-this-summer/106139214</link><description>Over the holiday period, the right game can make all the difference while spending time with friends and family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afc9ef668c6e91a92a25b0f8351ea204</guid></item><item><title>HelloFresh and Youfoodz sued by ACCC over allegedly misleading consumers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/hellofresh-and-youfoodz-sued-by-accc-for-misleading-consumers/106148656</link><description>The consumer watchdog is suing home meal delivery providers HelloFresh and Youfoodz for allegedly misleading consumers over subscriptions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">451560493899fb75f81460582ad748e7</guid></item><item><title>Bondi attack gunman had pro-Islamic State group links</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-attack-gunman-had-pro-islamic-state-group-links/106148538</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6da25e43f688af4beb9128d9c60dc6d6</guid></item><item><title>John Howard calls push to tighten gun laws in wake of Bondi attack an 'attempted diversion'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/john-howard-gun-laws-attempted-diversion/106148416</link><description>Former prime minister John Howard, whose gun reforms fundamentally reshaped Australia, says he would support further tightening, but it cannot be made into a distraction or an "excuse" not to tackle antisemitism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1ec6f3fc1f7f27d32e49292924e37f0</guid></item><item><title>What time does the Adelaide Test start? How to watch the Ashes, and Adelaide weather forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/ashes-2025-how-to-watch-and-follow-the-adelaide-test/106148302</link><description>The third Ashes Test is upon us and the series is on the line. Here's everything you need to know about the clash in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e92c26a7c6ff558c6b311e874066f635</guid></item><item><title>Hugh Jackman teaches Kate Hudson how to say words the Aussie way</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/hugh-jackman-teaches-kate-hudson-how-to-say-words-the-aussie-way/106148690</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1daffb22df61118f82272fa9978b3d49</guid></item><item><title>Former taekwondo instructor Kwang Kyung Yoo jailed for murdering three people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/former-taekwondo-instructor-jailed-for-murdering-three-people/106148710</link><description>Kwang Kyung Yoo murdered a woman and child at a Sydney taekwondo studio before killing the woman's husband at their home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a4caa5637009f4c590c06120b5e109e</guid></item><item><title>Nick Reiner, son of Hollywood director Rob Reiner, 'responsible' for parents' deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/nick-reiner-responsible-death-parents-rob-rainer-michele-singer/106148280</link><description>As Nick Reiner, son of film director Rob Reiner and Michele Singer Reiner, is arrested on suspicion of their murder, US President Donald Trump's response sparks a bipartisan backlash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2db985e8722039bee131e170b54d9019</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese speaks after visiting Ahmed al-Ahmed in hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/anthony-albanese-speaks-after-visiting-ahmed/106149046</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d35feb4af1e19243355f7803f831006</guid></item><item><title>Bondi terrorists travelled to Philippines for 'military-style training', security sources say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-gunmen-went-to-philippines-for-military-style-training/106148662</link><description>Father-son gunmen Sajid and Naveed Akram travelled to the Philippines to receive "military-style training" in the month before they killed 15 people at a Hanukkah celebration at Bondi Beach, security sources have confirmed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52edb6122488935f51e540d7c1ade39e</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese visits Ahmed Al Ahmed as Bondi hero's first video message circulates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/albanese-visits-bondi-hero-hospital/106148762</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese visits Bondi hero Ahmed Al Ahmed at St George Hospital in Sydney's south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d622416ed60be55e60141eea55520e96</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja left out of Adelaide Test as Pat Cummins and Nathan Lyon return to Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/ashes-2025-usman-khawaja-left-out-of-adelaide-test/106149056</link><description>Australian selectors stick with Josh Inglis as Usman Khawaja misses out on selection for the third Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cb08134c57fd6032acedb421aedb22c</guid></item><item><title>Bywong man pleads guilty to animal cruelty after dragging conscious kangaroo behind car</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bywong-man-pleads-guilty-after-dragging-kangaroo-behind-car/106148726</link><description>A Bywong man pleads guilty in the Queanbeyan Local Court to aggravated animal cruelty after dragging a conscious kangaroo behind his car earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be8c7e4347166b374b6e73178e43403f</guid></item><item><title>Farmers' Facebook group racks up 100,000 followers as they seek support across seasons</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/australian-farmers-harvesting-the-crop-facebook-group/106143522</link><description>A group dedicated to Australian grain farming created more than a decade ago has just cracked 100,000 followers with about 20,000 people following from overseas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45bd01ef5eb6e271490a8f818c46382c</guid></item><item><title>Tributes flow after Australian Paralympic bronze medallist Nicholas Hum dies aged 32</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/australian-paralympic-bronze-medallist-nicholas-hum-dies/106149202</link><description>Australian Paralympic bronze medallist Nicholas Hum is mourned after his shock death aged 32.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02098ca23aafbb919ccfed9462677a48</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump files $US10 billion lawsuit against BBC over documentary edit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/trump-sues-bbc-10-billion-dollars-documentary-edit/106148940</link><description>US President Donald Trump has filed a defamation lawsuit against the BBC in Miami federal court, seeking at least $US10 billion ($15.1 billion) in damages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">792fe9ca2a9764e9d53b880358f0a650</guid></item><item><title>Bendigo Writers Festival debacle continues as La Trobe University is asked to apologise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bendigo-writers-festival-la-trobe-apology-call/106142986</link><description>The debate around the failed Bendigo Writers Festival, which will not run next year, again embroils sponsor La Trobe University in controversy amid calls for more transparency and accountability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a562f742d6a8cdb21c5809d7bdab97b0</guid></item><item><title>Children pick $20,000 worth of toys for vulnerable families this Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/samaritans-childrens-gifts-christmas-appeal-hunter/106143994</link><description>A dozen children go on a shopping spree to pick presents for kids their age who otherwise may not have presents under their tree.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae1c660d3a83f9dac62965101563c3fb</guid></item><item><title>South Australia's Chief Justice Chris Kourakis retires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/sa-supreme-court-chief-justice-chris-kourakis-retires/106148240</link><description>After 13 years serving as South Australia's top judge, Chief Justice Chris Kourakis says it is "an appropriate time to retire".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f647f7488856dfa3766ed0ad851d128</guid></item><item><title>David Sharaz declared bankrupt in federal court hearing prompted by Linda Reynolds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/david-sharaz-declared-bankrupt-by-federal-court/106148670</link><description>Brittany Higgins's husband David Sharaz is declared bankrupt in the federal court, two months after former senator Linda Reynolds served him bankruptcy papers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ab52fd75c9bbaa1d85367a97b9c756d</guid></item><item><title>NT police charge man, 27, with murder after partner's 'suspicious' death in Borroloola</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/nt-borroloola-man-charged-with-woman-dv-murder/106149402</link><description>Police have charged a 27-year-old man with his partner's murder after she was found unresponsive in the remote community of Borroloola, south-east of Darwin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96f585c0dcce66c92dabe2ecf95f16c3</guid></item><item><title>Dashcam video shows second man disarming Bondi gunman.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/second-hero-identified-in-bondi-attack-/106149814</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe2879341dc008b6619974ee856b0f84</guid></item><item><title>Small plane crashes in central Mexico, killing at least 7 people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/mexico-plane-crash/106149526</link><description>Authorities say the accident took place in San Mateo Atenco, an industrial area 5 kilometres from the Toluca airport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3848244dd9521954a15670ed933c8a77</guid></item><item><title>Flu prompts postponement of A-League Women's match between Reds and City</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/a-league-women-match-postponed-because-of-flu-outbreak/106148360</link><description>An outbreak of the flu has delayed an upcoming A-League Women's match between Adelaide United and Melbourne City, as South Australia grapples with a record number of cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ebdff9d08294f39e4ad9d4a19bde8db</guid></item><item><title>Luke Lights live streams interactive Christmas display from Adelaide foothills</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/blackwood-man-live-streams-interactive-christmas-lights/106149416</link><description>With the push of a smartphone button, those watching Luke Denton's Christmas light display in Blackwood can add their own splashes of colour, or even turn the whole thing off.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71883e368f223812b0315f14da305845</guid></item><item><title>How music makes Jane Austen’s stories sparkle on the page and on screen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/jane-austen-at-250-music-in-books-and-on-screen/106136640</link><description>250 years after Jane Austen's birth, her love of music lives on in the characters from her books and screen adaptations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfa8f5b4cf66817ecbf325bf49b17967</guid></item><item><title>WA's gun laws in national spotlight with national reforms flagged after Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/wa-gun-laws-in-spotlight-as-national-reform-flagged/106147144</link><description>As Australia looks to strengthen its firearms laws in the wake of the Bondi terror attack, recent changes to Western Australia's gun rules could provide a blueprint for the nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44045f403addf2db81fcab01e301a654</guid></item></channel></rss>