<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:45:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Legal battle begins over Virginia Giuffre’s multi-million-dollar estate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/virginia-giuffre-epstein-survivor-legal-battle-over-estate/106075194</link><description>A legal battle over the reported multi-million-dollar estate of Virginia Giuffre, who was abused by US sex offender Jeffrey Epstein, is underway in Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cf112f989a06c7e502a7a21067f20aa</guid></item><item><title>Preparing my garden for time away in summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/preparing-my-garden-for-time-away-in-summer/106051574</link><description>Leaving my garden in the heat of summer can feel worrying but some simple planning means it misses me less than I miss it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56b35dd6decc39572e5296aff34ea254</guid></item><item><title>Struggling AFLW teams GWS, Collingwood and Gold Coast receive extra picks or list spots from league</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/aflw-have-nots-receive-league-boost-on-grand-final-eve/106079622</link><description>Three of the AFLW's worst-performing clubs will receive boosts to their lists, with the help announced the day before the grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">087d6c70c437791857888893255fa45d</guid></item><item><title>Lotterywest cancels licences of seven stores across Perth found to be selling illegal tobacco or vapes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/lotterywest-cancels-licences-over-illegal-tobacco-/106079700</link><description>Seven stores across Perth found to be selling illegal tobacco and vapes have their lotteries licences terminated, as attempts to disrupt the illicit and growing trade continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">deaa16d974f977f92fc4244b10fe4aeb</guid></item><item><title>Perth hacker Michael Clapsis jailed after setting up fake Qantas Wi-Fi, stealing sex videos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/perth-michael-clapis-guilty-airport-data-theft-sex-videos/105442798</link><description>A Perth hacker who copied intimate images and sex videos from women's personal online accounts and set up fake Wi-Fi on Qantas flights is sentenced to more than seven years in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">137224c08606535454faf495212728d1</guid></item><item><title>Kyra Cooney-Cross scores stunning long range goal as Matildas down New Zealand 5-0</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/kyra-cooney-cross-goal-matildas-defeat-new-zealand/106074508</link><description>A spectacular long range effort from Kyra Cooney-Cross has helped the Matildas to a dominant 5-0 win over New Zealand in Australia's penultimate game before hosting the Asian Cup in March.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ed492f5f89ed6ab1feddf18b1b73bf8</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong's aging towers face urgent questions after city's deadliest blaze in decades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/behind-hong-kong-s-skyline-thousands-of-old-towers-fire-risks/106079352</link><description>Hong Kong's worst fire in decades exposed long-standing weaknesses in its aging residential blocks. The question haunting the city is whether the disaster could happen again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e527e3cdb4fb8aec5ae2e15796f2ecc</guid></item><item><title>One of seven Rosenberg's goannas from ACT reserve is missing from home for second time in two years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/act-rosenbergs-goanna-rum-missing-ainslie-majura-conservation/106080004</link><description>One of a handful of Rosenberg’s goannas living in the ACT’s hill reserves has once again wandered off, prompting calls from a local conservation organisation for help bringing him back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d236e04ccb909529cfe855fa2a4af683</guid></item><item><title>Wala Kooral-bi juvenile justice facility opens in northern WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/wala-kooral-bi-juvenile-justice-facility-opens-in-northern-wa/106057316</link><description>An on-country youth diversion facility has been built in the state's far north, offering a culturally grounded alternative to traditional youth justice programs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">142d8035e60293b2bfd4ea512b3d855f</guid></item><item><title>Qantas terminal at Melbourne Airport evacuated and flights delayed due to fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/melbourne-airport-qantas-terminal-evacuated/106080752</link><description>The Qantas terminal is re-opening after being evacuated because of a small fire inside Melbourne Airport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44f741960e995fb9479b357573d18ed2</guid></item><item><title>NT parliament hears claims of children in youth detention being transferred without families' knowledge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/nt-parliament-children-youth-detention-allegedly-moved-to-darwin/106080720</link><description>Two politicians allege NT children in youth detention are being moved from Alice Springs to Darwin without their families' knowledge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e1c0c9a0ccf30f57917a7f02d2f775a</guid></item><item><title>ICC rejects plea to release Philippine ex-president Rodrigo Duterte</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/icc-rejects-plea-to-release-philippine-ex-president-duterte/106080850</link><description>The judge says it is "necessary" for the 80-year-old to remain in detention as the conditions proposed by his lawyers do not meet the conditions for parole.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69d31e21ba06deee8c154d6e2ab9059b</guid></item><item><title>Eight arrested and 128 people dead as alarm faults confirmed in Hong Kong fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/eight-people-arrested-over-deadly-hong-kong-fire-tai-po-district/106080926</link><description>The arrests come as the probe into what caused the deadly blaze that killed at least 128 people continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce9a1003dd5cc3333427e62260e00d1c</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy's chief of staff Andriy Yermak quits as anti-corruption probe widens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/andrii-yermak-zelenskyy-aide-home-office-raided/106080910</link><description>It come as Kyiv battles to persuade US officials to defend Ukraine's interests in peace agreement talks with Russia expected to take place in the coming days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5d4e479539240306c2c980146ac385d</guid></item><item><title>Albanese knows the power dynamic between Labor and mining interests has shifted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/anthony-albanese-mining-labor-greens-deal-environment/106045658</link><description>There has been a shift in the power dynamic between Labor and the mining industry. This week's environmental law reform is its embodiment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f47fba9a6d450b1c3228007e52bf0c6</guid></item><item><title>Family, advocates welcome 'historic' police conviction over Jai Wright's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/jai-wright-verdict-community-reaction/106077902</link><description>For the family of Dunghutti teen Jai Wright, the guilty finding against police officer Benedict Bryant for dangerous driving occasioning Jai's death lifts a "weight off their shoulders". Legal experts say it's the first time a police officer has been convicted in relation to the death of a First Nations person in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e4d309fc5f07d305ff43e37f99b82b7</guid></item><item><title>Growing concern filler doesn't break down even with hyaluronidase dissolver</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/side-effects-of-cosmetic-filler-dissolver-hyaluronidase/106050856</link><description>As more people turn towards cosmetic injectable "journeys", Lana is sounding the alarm about the risks of developing long-term side effects.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">252d91cb5f41b989c74e7ac62d70ee8a</guid></item><item><title>John 'Wacka' Williams labels Barnaby Joyce's resignation an 'act of treason'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/barnaby-joyce-resignation-voter-reaction/106077566</link><description>The MP's resignation from the Nationals surprised no one, but drew ire from members of the party. Those on the ground in his electorate have a more mixed view.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">405b5edf3c1f4ee76d755bb3f5b3be01</guid></item><item><title>Director Peter Weir on capturing the mood for Picnic at Hanging Rock</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/director-peter-weir-on-filming-picnic-at-hanging-rock/106074136</link><description>Renowned Australian director Peter Weir gives a rare behind-the-scenes insight into what made Picnic at Hanging Rock such a memorable and enduring film.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a0a3a9f7a11c445ebf09909341a28d0</guid></item><item><title>Cape Barren Island was returned for Aboriginal self-governance 20 years ago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/cape-barren-island-20-years-after-land-return/105916324</link><description>Twenty years ago, Cape Barren Island was handed back to its traditional owners. Today's children are proof of the life-changing power of that act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1e8123e16da228977e990ee9aa39db7</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong tower residents had safety complaints more than 12 months before deadly fires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/hong-kong-tower-fire-alarms-failed-safety-concerns-flagged/106080022</link><description>Many of the people who managed to escape the Wang Fuk Court fires in Hong Kong believe the disaster could have been prevented, saying they had flagged safety concerns more than a year ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ae6220382bd183f602e5d1bab1fffd7</guid></item><item><title>Normalisation of location sharing, tech-facilitated abuse in spotlight after Lilie James inquest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/nsw-lilie-james-murder-location-sharing-dv-tech-abuse/106072984</link><description>Experts on gendered violence have warned against the proliferation of everyday location sharing tools to control victim-survivors after NSW's top coroner found Paul Thijssen used them to track Lilie James before her murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e22e4fc827d54f6212352558e70a7129</guid></item><item><title>King Gizzard &amp; the Lizard Wizard on quitting Spotify, orchestras, raves, and world domination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/king-gizzard-on-leaving-spotify-orchestras-raves/106058570</link><description>Their rock, rave and orchestral music attracts a cult global following. But the prolific, chaotic King Gizzard &amp; the Lizard Wizard are just "at peace with failing".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fee298a5f31019c8e735f977dd540e6</guid></item><item><title>Social media influencers used to promote Melbourne Metro Tunnel opening</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/social-media-influencers-used-to-promote-melbourne-metro-tunnel/106078516</link><description>Documents obtained by the ABC reveal the Victorian government has targeted dozens of social media influencers to promote the Metro Tunnel rail project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">640b94a929a8896c1214bbbb78ad0100</guid></item><item><title>Lawyers warn erroneous and costly family court transcripts are impeding justice, prompting calls for change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/family-court-transcripts-viq-solutions/105904558</link><description>Obtaining court transcripts can cost thousands of dollars for a single day of proceedings, but the documents can contain errors, missing text, and even wrong attribution, frustrating legal practitioners who say the flaws impede justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d672dd564c511c8c6191b17e18fdfb5</guid></item><item><title>R360 launch postponed from 2026 to 2028, after players withdraw due to threats of NRL bans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/r360-postponed-until-2028-after-nrl-ban-threat/106081400</link><description>Threats of long bans for prospective R360 players prompted "a handful" of them to withdraw from the rebel league, which now says it will launch in 2028 instead of next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f9056cd6a82d72eef6485c9c07cdf99</guid></item><item><title>Crowdy Bay shark attack highlights need for first aid devices, drone surveillance on remote beaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/shark-attack-highlights-need-for-remote-first-aid-and-drones/106077444</link><description>A makeshift tourniquet may have made the difference between a shark attack on the NSW Mid North Coast this week claiming one life not two. The attack has put a spotlight on how fatalities may be prevented.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b66b310d8becee41e4ab954e7df6286c</guid></item><item><title>Australia's emissions have dropped, but we've got our work cut out to reach targets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/record-drop-in-australias-emissions/106074296</link><description>Australia's emissions had the biggest drop ever this year outside the artificial kink in the curve during COVID-19 shutdowns, but there's still a lot of work to do.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7549e00e7dd7bc370cfc65bcedc0f0ba</guid></item><item><title>Landscape around Yunta in outback SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/landscape-around-yunta-in-outback-sa/106075520</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">620dacb5ce6fa85351a0006df0af44a7</guid></item><item><title>Gus has been gone for 63 days, and searches of mines, dams and scrub have yielded no clues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/the-search-for-gus-lamont-has-included-dams-mines-and-scrub/106055504</link><description>The disappearance of Gus Lamont is one of those events that have a seismic impact on public consciousness: they distress, disturb, upset and unsettle. This week six mine shafts were searched, providing no further clues in the case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b62919d1d99b64b2df9b85158a7245c5</guid></item><item><title>Adoption support service warns against increasing adoption in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/service-warns-against-increasing-adoption-in-queensland/106074614</link><description>Queensland should overhaul "outdated" adoption laws that sever children's legal ties to their families, while ensuring adoption remains a last resort, a peak support service tells a commission of inquiry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">837f8739ea4d39173b45a9bfd38ebb06</guid></item><item><title>World-first tournament hopes to 'break down barriers' between the golf and disability communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/queensland-golf-disability-charity-world-first-tournament-pga/106075338</link><description>People with intellectual disabilities will have roles in planning, promoting, preparing, and supporting professionals at a charity golf tournament that is the first of its kind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad28868bc3e87eb99dac4917ac4d964d</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Thunder miss out on WBBL win as Adelaide Strikers clash ended early by rain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/wbbl-thunder-strikers-game-called-off-in-rain/106081446</link><description>After rain falls for most of the Sydney Thunder's innings, umpires decide to call off their WBBL clash against the Strikers with Phoebe Litchfield one swing away from ending the game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99a82cac35ddfb1d3680e1d37e2e0c6d</guid></item><item><title>Former premier Peter Gutwein says Hobart AFL stadium has been 'poorly' sold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/former-premier-peter-gutwein-hobart-afl-stadium-poorly-sold/106079926</link><description>Peter Gutwein initiated the push for a stadium in Hobart, but he has had to watch the drama unfold from the sidelines. He says rejecting the proposal would be the biggest "lost opportunity" in the state's history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d17e00abf2f08909b0d3296cd540598</guid></item><item><title>Former premier Peter Gutwein says he is not surprised by the 'challenging fight' over the Hobart stadium.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/stadium-stateline-gutwein/106079898</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a8212c7a7cbd596a15e70d27ca8c35b</guid></item><item><title>Peter Gutwein says it will be the biggest "lost opportunity" in Tasmania's history if the stadium is rejected.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/peter-gutwein-on-hobart-stadium-afl-team/106078804</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03e69811aea5d5ac9067ad94160f2e92</guid></item><item><title>From potential gridlock to an "immersive" viewing experience, planning documents reveal details about the building at the heart of Tasmania's fiery stadium debate.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/macquarie-point-stadium-design/106080612</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf6ee48debe608faeca9c2cd3a1b96dc</guid></item><item><title>What would it be like to visit Hobart's proposed Macquarie Point stadium?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/hobart-stadium-design-macquarie-point-spectator-experience/106054654</link><description>From potential gridlock to an "immersive" viewing experience, let's set aside the politics — just for a moment — and look at what planning documents tell us about the building at the heart of Tasmania's fiery stadium debate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7091033d2c6379cd7e19e030424554ee</guid></item><item><title>Think you're ready to own a home? Here are the costs that experts want you to consider</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/the-up-front-and-ongoing-costs-of-home-ownership/105984188</link><description>We asked three financial experts about the up-front and ongoing costs of buying a home and for their tips on how to prepare for home ownership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a044e362104441aa527db1d121dcea86</guid></item><item><title>Cricket Australia set to speak with Usman Khawaja after he labelled Perth Ashes Test pitch a 'piece of shit'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/usman-khawaja-pillories-perth-ashes-test-pitch/106081416</link><description>Usman Khawaja may face a sanction for labelling the first Ashes Test surface a "piece of shit", with Cricket Australia understood to be disappointed by the remarks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62c5c47efcba08e3a71df02e352a8f9e</guid></item><item><title>Survivors of forced adoption in South Australia call for greater recognition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/forced-adoption-survivors-call-for-greater-recognition/105946656</link><description>Decades on from Australia's forced adoption era, just two states have set up a redress scheme for the mothers who were harmed. Survivors are calling for South Australia to take similar action — warning time is running out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">883276d36b1aa0a38c589ceb338c5a55</guid></item><item><title>After suffering 'terrifying' postpartum rage, this mother wants others to know they're not alone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/mother-comes-to-terms-with-terrifying-postpartum-rage/106072456</link><description>When Ali Gossage gave birth a second time, she did not experience the constant joys of motherhood. Instead, she was sometimes filled with "terrifying" anger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d749279af4a3906951170031a067264</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Airport terminal fire under investigation after evacuation of Qantas domestic terminal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/melbourne-airport-fire-evacuation-investigation/106081444</link><description>A fire that forced the evacuation of Melbourne's Qantas domestic terminal on Friday night continues to be investigated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7842effb7970063a8123e6d16509d33</guid></item><item><title>Severe Tropical Cyclone Fina damage exposes need for new Royal Darwin Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/nt-cyclone-fina-damage-royal-darwin-hospital-need-rdh-analysis/106074054</link><description>A new Royal Darwin Hospital would cost more than $1 billion to build, and likely take a decade or more to deliver. So who has the political bravery to commit?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37551ba9b57d2f519ca4ea062b5a9376</guid></item><item><title>Who's thriving and who's barely surviving in Australia, the Land of the Parrots?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/parrots-of-australia-a-spotters-guide/106056012</link><description>Australia is the land of the parrot — few places in the world have such a dazzling array of colourful and clever members of the psittacine family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4344c3353cd2f3bf141b8ec4ca2378d0</guid></item><item><title>'Naughty Boy' pelican draws in visitors and locals in coastal tourist town of Kalbarri</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/naughty-boy-pelican-delights-tourists-kalbarri/106073082</link><description>Locals say this cheeky pelican has a personality unlike any bird they have ever seen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59a37b02c238ac01526a5608d9d1e8f3</guid></item><item><title>Australia's peak music exam body under fire amid claims of 'slipping standards'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/claims-standards-slipping-at-ameb-as-regions-revolt/106074654</link><description>It is held up as the "gold standard" of music testing in the country, but there are claims the Australian Music Examinations Board is letting down talented students.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbe3a51c36b4d2bc06add40728c47ad6</guid></item><item><title>Snowy Mountains farmers call for support in managing spread of invasive weed African lovegrass</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/african-lovegrass-weed-chokes-out-native-grass-snowy-mountains/106006854</link><description>To the untrained eye, African lovegrass is just another plant in the NSW Snowy Mountains. But this golden plant is a deceptive invasive weed that is choking out the landscape, causing some farmers to leave the land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97336bfbd9984ec7e511ae69aa52d050</guid></item><item><title>Conservationists worldwide scrambling for alternative funding after USAID cuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/conservationists-scrambling-for-funding-after-usaid-cuts/106053490</link><description>Citizen science and AI have never been more important to the environment after White House cuts to USAID are felt beneath the waves, a new report says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02a67830f4b18930900eb775f8ab34b6</guid></item><item><title>The Wiggles issue statement after appearing in Keli Holiday Ecstasy video</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/wiggles-issue-statement-after-keli-holiday-ecstasy-video/106081670</link><description>A spokesperson for the group says the band "does not condone" the use of drugs after a since-deleted video promoting Keli Holiday's single, Ecstasy, appeared on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88bf00aa8f0697112dd1631b533873f9</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne teen who died after nut allergy 'let down' by health system, family says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/max-mckenzie-nut-allergy-coronial-inquest/106022338</link><description>Four years after a 15-year-old boy died due to a nut allergy, a Victorian coroner is examining if the death was preventable and whether paramedics and doctors at the Box Hill Hospital provided appropriate care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea1a2581536020cb7f1dd793ff06ac66</guid></item><item><title>Skyhooks guitarist Bob Starkie dies aged 73 after a battle with cancer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/skyhooks-guitarist-bob-starkie-dies/106081862</link><description>A statement released on Skyhooks' official Facebook page announced his passing this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9887f7f9c22df27c6c83a6df9ee2dbf</guid></item><item><title>Planning to bite into a sweet, juicy mango? Here's what to know about your favourite summer treat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/australian-mango-varieties-and-origins/106072138</link><description>What's the difference between a big R2E2, a delicate Honey Gold, and an iconic Kensington Pride? Find out before biting into a mango this season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70ee88f5621fa0e89efe9a8c714443d7</guid></item><item><title>Victorian coroner determines Mount Buller hiker missing since 2019 is dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/niels-becker-coroner-finding-mount-buller-inquest-missing-hiker-/106081758</link><description>A Coroner has determined that Niels Gunther Becker, 39, who went missing at Mount Buller in 2019 is dead but that no third party was involved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">472d867bb5bccf18ea322810f522a39f</guid></item><item><title>Terminated Bedford staff in limbo, with millions of dollars owed in entitlements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/bedford-staff-in-limbo-millions-owed-in-entitlements/106080712</link><description>Former Bedford staff have said they are owed millions of dollars in entitlements after they were made redundant when the disability employment provider entered voluntary administration earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfe87f0fcb8a8a391861ebdeb706d658</guid></item><item><title>Colin Friels takes on his final stage role in King Lear at Belvoir in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/colin-friels-king-lear-water-rats-monkey-grip-malcolm/106051868</link><description>Colin Friels, the award-winning actor known for Malcolm and Water Rats, reflects on his 50-year career on stage and screen as he approaches what might be his final role.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">967f29bede3ba2e25f22d270ea5f4fba</guid></item><item><title>No-bake chocolate and strawberry cake is the ultimate make-ahead dessert - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/no-bake-chocolate-biscuit-and-strawberry-cream-cake/105543504</link><description>Icebox cakes are retro no-bake desserts made by layering store-bought biscuits and whipped cream. A no-fuss option for summer celebrations, this one can be assembled in 10 minutes and made well ahead of time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa595533c02a1f792c1bf40a7fb5ef05</guid></item><item><title>Best books out in November, featuring Margaret Atwood's memoir and The Mushroom Tapes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/best-books-november-margaret-atwood-memoir-mushroom-tapes/106018540</link><description>Wondering what to read next? This month's best books include a novel that brings to life Britain's only named wind and a new book by the author of The Handmaid's Tale.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9716753e1b04846ee97e8f09ff9b42a</guid></item><item><title>England captain Ben Stokes dismisses 'arrogant' label amid criticism of Ashes Test loss to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/ashes-cricket-england-australia-ben-stokes-arrogant-label/106082046</link><description>Captain Ben Stokes responds to England's critics in the wake of the defeat to Australia in the first Test, maintaining his squad will not step back from its aggressive approach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cadb1c10356060c35802d310ab0fa02f</guid></item><item><title>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese marries Jodie Haydon at The Lodge in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/anthony-albanese-jodie-haydon-wedding-prime-minister-married/106080434</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese marries his partner Jodie Haydon in a private ceremony at his official Canberra residence, after details of the wedding were kept top secret.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f951cdd57ae649a668fbbb63b9787d7e</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese's wedding ends this 'killing season' with love's triumph</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/anthony-albanese-jodie-haydon-wedding/106082052</link><description>The two months preceding a wedding are notoriously hazardous. But consider the two months Anthony Albanese has just had.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24704e8755a4678cb9c739cad01c7352</guid></item><item><title>Police continue search for missing man Chris Thorne in Melbourne's west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/missing-man-chris-thorne-police-search/106082178</link><description>Police are searching for missing man Chris Thorne, who was last seen in Melbourne's western suburbs last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1b80e5f3ca4237e7988ac400761be34</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne becomes first AFLW team to win consecutive premierships after clinical grand final showing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/aflw-grand-final-live-north-melbourne-kangaroos-brisbane-lions/106077430</link><description>North Melbourne outclasses the Brisbane Lions by 40 points in the AFLW grand final to capture a history-making second consecutive premiership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">586359f2bee24c909c1e4fb8e69f48bd</guid></item><item><title>LNP claims victory in Hinchinbrook by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/qld-regs-hinchinbrook-by-election/106074190</link><description>The QLD Premier has declared an LNP win in the Hinchinbrook by-election, in what was once a Katter's Australian Party strong-hold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f29faf243797abc376bd2d7f9f560200</guid></item><item><title>Toni Lamond, known for her roles in Annie Get Your Gun and My Fair Lady, dies aged 93</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/australian-performer-toni-lamond-has-died-aged-93/106082102</link><description>Australian screen and stage actor Toni Lamond was known for her roles in Annie Get Your Gun, My Fair Lady, Number 96 and The Last Frontier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">206d4cb9f5471c455d6bd23f53ef0a58</guid></item><item><title>Meg Lanning hits 73no as Stars down Renegades, Hurricanes defeat Scorchers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/sport-wbbl-wrap-stars-renegades-scorchers-hurricanes/106082354</link><description>Former Australia captain Meg Lanning hits 73 not out to help the Stars to a convincing 45-run derby victory over the Renegades, while the Hurricanes down the Scorchers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5775eed7a3f18112a823690518d27277</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos break new ground on the field and in the history books in AFLW flag defence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/aflw-grand-final-north-melbourne-thrash-brisbane-historic-game/106082242</link><description>North Melbourne proves to be ground breakers and history makers as it extend its match-winning streak to 27 games in a comprehensive win over Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">517a5ac7cd8acc2d00cb1a81bb220754</guid></item><item><title>As questions around horse welfare grow, equestrian sport is facing a reckoning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/equestrian-heath-ryan-horse-welfare-fei/106049564</link><description>As questions around horse welfare grow, can equestrian sport's Olympic dream survive?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1118f951004e05a61f37db7a6295b1d8</guid></item><item><title>Crypto gaming earns users tokens but also exposes them to risks of trading and speculation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/cryptocurrency-gamification-compared-to-gambling/106045396</link><description>As the crypto sector expands its appeal beyond tech insiders, the gamification of cryptocurrencies is appealing to younger users, which experts warn is walking the line between gaming and gambling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5d0e05eba75f69efbbde51be7ed6179</guid></item><item><title>Some sex workers are calling out the lack of transparency in large amounts of viral social media content being targeted at young women.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/nt-sex-work-influencers-social-media-content-warning/106082188</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30078c3ad102a3bb983abf22e781b55c</guid></item><item><title>Sex work influencers call out lack of transparency as young girls targeted by viral social media content</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/nt-sex-work-influencers-social-media-content-warning-onlyfans/106050924</link><description>Sex workers say viral social media content, which often promotes a life of luxury, needs to be more transparent to avoid duping young followers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bb52b2473b18378a8e8256e046359e0</guid></item><item><title>Hobart stadium vote will determine future of historic Macquarie Point waterfront and AFL team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/hobart-stadium-vote-leaves-macquarie-point-at-crossroads/106044588</link><description>Since its inception, the stadium project has divided the Hobart community in a tug of war between development and preservation of its historic waterfront. In just days, the door will shut forever on one side of the debate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e8c699423bbbcd3d63be4f6d5dfd5e2</guid></item><item><title>The spooky First Nations movie you need to see at BIFF</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/it-will-find-you-brisbane-international-film-festival/106074274</link><description>First Nations stories are combined with modern horror scares in this new film from Australian creatives Chris Broadbent and Enzo Tedeschi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b235169fa73d8695e28eb94f33cc4ba4</guid></item><item><title>Thai PM admits flood failures after trapped victims wait days for help</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/thailand-floods-death-toll-rises/106082418</link><description>Thailand’s Health Ministry estimates that more than 160 people were killed in the disaster across nine provinces, but at least 110 of those died in Songkhla, where Hat Yai is located.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cf3a3fd21bfc3a6f329ac4a032f0cbd</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri wins Qatar F1 sprint race, qualifies fastest for GP, edging closer to Lando Norris in standings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/oscar-piastri-wins-qatar-sprint-race-pole-position-grand-prix/106082990</link><description>Australian driver Oscar Piastri is doing everything he can to catch McLaren teammate Lando Norris in the world championship race, winning the sprint race and qualifying in pole position for the Qatar Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91fb4a7e45b5fd7c127dde77f8c1f27a</guid></item><item><title>Paul Kelly, Stella Donnelly, 5 Seconds of Summer lead November's best new albums</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/best-albums-november-paul-kelly-stella-donnelly-5sos-hatchie/106055576</link><description>Sensitive song-smiths, reinvented boy bands, rock and rap upstarts — it's all here in an Ausmusic Month edition of the best new music.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e1d5874f67515bf050b4bb16100377f</guid></item><item><title>'Awareness gap' on mental health support available for new parents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/mother-shares-experience-of-postpartum-depression/106029442</link><description>Nilupulie Karunaratne thought asking for help was a sign of weakness. Then her husband referred her to a psychologist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae82d7a972c6c3e04cabef04bfc79ad1</guid></item><item><title>Labor should theoretically be confident ahead of the 2026 Victorian election — but challenges are mounting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/labor-liberal-victorian-state-election/106074182</link><description>On paper, Labor should be confident that it will score an unprecedented fourth term in office when Victorian voters go to the ballot box in a year's time, with the Liberal opposition still scrambling to present as an electable alternative.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3a467f756b8d054f7af57490a3defae</guid></item><item><title>The Melbourne Metro Tunnel opens today. Here's what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/melbourne-metro-tunnel-now-open-summer-train-timetable/106077452</link><description>It's the biggest upgrade to Melbourne's rail network in more than 40 years, and it's arrived — the long-awaited Metro Tunnel, along with its five new inner-city stations, opens to the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c41bf094ac195a370ddf95abec86a10</guid></item><item><title>What people with diabetes want you to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/what-people-with-diabetes-want-you-to-know/106075536</link><description>We spoke to six people with three different types of diabetes to find out what they wish more of the public knew. Here's what they had to say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b19c807e633d13b2b1f3d64a7e511f45</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne Kangaroos rally around injured Mia King after AFLW grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/aflw-grand-final-mia-king-injury-north-mebourne-kangaroos/106083024</link><description>During their AFLW premiership celebrations, North Melbourne players make sure to take time for Mia King, who just missed the grand final with a knee injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63cfdda9959b2fea504952cdfd68f179</guid></item><item><title>Chapter closes on 'The Family' murders that stole Adelaide's innocence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/bevan-von-einem-richard-kelvin-murder-one-of-family-killings/106049658</link><description>One of South Australia's most notorious murderers was this week rushed to an infirmary on the brink of death, prompting recollections of the time when young males disappeared across Adelaide in a set of gruesome crimes dubbed "The Family" murders. Warning: This story contains details some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11b2f2f4782672c023b6d32788b7412c</guid></item><item><title>British playwright and Oscar winner Tom Stoppard dies at 88</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/british-playwright-tom-stoppard-dies-at-88/106083072</link><description>Stoppard was often hailed as the greatest British playwright of his generation, with multiple awards for his work on stage and screen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98af289ac7e02d33ea03fab0ce5d0ac4</guid></item><item><title>Queensland to become first Australian jurisdiction to allow specialist general practitioners to diagnose ADHD in adults</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/qld-adhd-reforms-general-practitioners-diagnose-prescribe/106057242</link><description>Queensland is becoming the first jurisdiction in Australia to allow specialist GPs to diagnose ADHD in adults and prescribe treatment, but some hold concerns about the lack of mandatory specific training.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e564c23a7aff66d2b7ab9df4b04f21bd</guid></item><item><title>Eli Katoa shares images post brain surgery, pays tribute to partner and hopes for NRL return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/eli-katoa-pays-tribute-to-partner-pledges-nrl-return/106083174</link><description>Melbourne Storm star Eli Katoa shares an update after his brain surgery, posting images of himself in hospital and saying he hopes to return to football "soon".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5633872b100e3adeba60e027e1c85d89</guid></item><item><title>Surfers set to pay to ride Fiji's world-class breaks after repeal of surf access law</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/surfers-to-pay-to-ride-fijis-world-class-breaks/106077640</link><description>Surfers wanting to catch a wave at Fiji's world class reef breaks could soon have to pay for the privilege after the repeal of a beach access law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8725c1c26f354dbc4222afeb20470fd6</guid></item><item><title>WA Legal Practice Board slammed by lawyers in scathing parliamentary submissions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/wa-legal-practice-board-slammed-by-lawyers/106079432</link><description>In a scathing rebuke of their own watchdog, WA lawyers claim the state's Legal Practice Board is causing them psychological harm amid calls for urgent reform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e02a93cbee37fb47fb34a52275d44888</guid></item><item><title>Energy independence? It would reduce the impact of global energy shocks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/energy-independence-reduce-the-impact-of-global-energy-shocks/106081924</link><description>If Australia produced 100 per cent of its energy from renewable sources, it would reduce the impact of global energy shocks on Australia's economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73c9a333c80a9f02fbe46eaec2ce7a48</guid></item><item><title>Surfers Paradise sand 'island' to disappear by Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/gold-coast-sand-island-to-disappear-by-christmas/106074800</link><description>Curious beachgoers are being cautioned to stay off the sandbar and to swim between the flags.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5820f1c0654918d731b901b58e2485a</guid></item><item><title>Coalition floats stronger 'values' test for migrants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/coalition-value-english-language-test-migrants-visa/106083258</link><description>Sussan Ley says migration tensions in Australia are not the fault of migrants, but a stronger "Australian values" test for those seeking to move here could form part of the Coalition's coming migration policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27934064c4d24fcf8bee70405e1b0287</guid></item><item><title>The Austrian heiress giving away her entire fortune</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/rich-heiress-giving-away-all-her-wealth/106077200</link><description>When Marlene Engelhorn inherited tens of millions of dollars from her grandma, she felt she had two choices: do something about it, or confirm she was "full of sh*t".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">322ef9da6313065a06591bcb83bf9e9e</guid></item><item><title>Sydney FC great Alex Brosque fumes over alleged handball in Wanderers' 1-0 ALM win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/a-league-men-sydney-fc-wanderers-alleged-handball/106083524</link><description>Sydney FC's four-match winning streak comes to a crashing halt, but its 1-0 loss to Western Sydney has sparked debate about what constitutes a handball.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de18334568fcf4b8e3c548d6262734b1</guid></item><item><title>Supporters of proposed Macquarie Point stadium rally ahead of crucial vote</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/tasmania-macquarie-point-stadium-yes-rally-vote/106083340</link><description>Supporters of Tasmania's proposed AFL stadium have gathered on Hobart's parliament lawns on Sunday to show their backing of the controversial build.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3629a770dccddeaa44bbecf20a1a18df</guid></item><item><title>Ombudsman calls on NT government to urgently remove prisoners from police cells</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/nt-ombudsman-report-inhumane-oppressive-watch-house-conditions/106082108</link><description>The Northern Territory's prison watchdog has called on the government to urgently remove all inmates from police cells following an investigation which revealed prisoners sleeping between toilets and claims guards watched women showering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c94961e576d7d863edb6b43efa7326c1</guid></item><item><title>How the Kangaroos beat the Lions to claim back-to-back AFLW flags in their perfect season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/aflw-grand-final-north-melbourne-kangaroos-brisbane-lions/106083788</link><description>Creating history by winning consecutive premierships and completing an unbeaten season is just reward for North Melbourne's boundary-pushing AFLW program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8abb438f7954cccf41f010b3f6c697ce</guid></item><item><title>Locals at Albanese's favourite pub respond to his wedding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/locals-at-albanese-s-favourite-pub-respond-to-his-wedding/106083948</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aec842cfc05a8422998e1dfaf1faf5e5</guid></item><item><title>LNP's Wayde Chiesa promises to get to work after victory in Hinchinbrook by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/lnp-wayde-chiesa-wins-hinchinbrook-by-election/106074692</link><description>The LNP's Wayde Chiesa will be the next representative for the Queensland seat of Hinchinbrook, which had been safely held by Katter's Australian Party since 2017.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">316d56db0aad14eb566c92220ddfecdb</guid></item><item><title>Carbon dioxide import plan could see Darwin become world's climate pollution 'dumping ground', say activists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/darwin-import-carbon-capture-plan-pollution-dumping-ground/106040704</link><description>A plan for the Northern Territory to be among the first places in the world to import foreign carbon emissions has raised fears it will turn Darwin into a global pollution dumping ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24492f3ab15e31d45f7efccb5b4d740d</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania Police searching King Island for missing local teenager Lusian West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/tasmania-police-search-for-missing-teen-lusian-west-king-island/106083894</link><description>Local King Island teen Lusian West, 16, has not been seen since Friday, with Tasmania police and rescue crews to conduct aerial searches of the island's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2071093b7571de79e77d494f5309a598</guid></item><item><title>Em Rusciano on finding balance in life after her ADHD and autism diagnoses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/em-rusciano-autism-adhd-perimenopause-work-life-unwind-with/106074920</link><description>As a writer, singer, comedian, podcaster, author and single mum, Em Rusciano has become accustomed to navigating a chaotic life. The self-described "maximalist power queen" shares how she unwinds and how her approach to life has changed since going through perimenopause and being diagnosed with ADHD and autism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54a0940ddb38aa0802a5f057eb56cae2</guid></item><item><title>Photographer Lyn Alcock captures wild antics of Dryandra's numbat population over 20 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/dryandra-numbat-antics-photographer/106051162</link><description>Lyn Alcock is known as the 'Numbat whisperer', spending hours every day observing and photographing the tiny, endangered marsupials, recording behaviours that have never been seen before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50f2d4bc8d830154bacd7c73f39c8ce2</guid></item><item><title>Shipping movements disrupted as climate change protesters block coal ships from entering Port of Newcastle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/protesters-arrested-attempting-block-worlds-largest-coal-port/106083224</link><description>Police arrest 141 people in Newcastle Harbour for alleged marine-related offences during an anti-fossil fuel protest that began on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20331433a2345957df52cf9e31b92570</guid></item><item><title>Violent explosion during St Marys fire described as 'once in a career type of experience'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/inferno-fire-at-st-marys-generates-explosion-huge-fireball/106083492</link><description>The inferno-like fire broke out at Kurrajong Street in North St Marys overnight, generating immense heat and a huge eruption that spewed a fireball more than 100 metres up into the sky.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">493a2024159395dcf9eefccff5fe0f5f</guid></item><item><title>Is Australia Dr Jekyll and Mr Hyde when it comes to clean energy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/is-australia-dr-jekyll-and-mr-hyde/106084216</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">024af5a77da40568ad287b72b3a9d683</guid></item><item><title>Spain's David Puig wins Australian PGA Championship by two strokes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/australian-pga-championship-david-puig-wins/106084240</link><description>David Puig joins legendary countryman Seve Ballesteros as an Australian PGA champion after emerging from a congested field at Royal Queensland Golf Club in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">812b93393c051ab8c1803cbf9df390f6</guid></item><item><title>Anti-immigration protest and counter-rally in Melbourne CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/anti-immigration-protest-and-counter-rally-in-melbourne-cbd/106084316</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d57adb70f23bb8266eab97c16f2743b</guid></item><item><title>Chaz Mostert wins maiden Supercars title in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/chaz-mostert-wins-maiden-supercars-title-in-adelaide/106084290</link><description>Chaz Mostert breaks through for a maiden Supercars championship after rival Broc Feeney spins out on the opening lap at the Adelaide grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">061635e135f39875db9dfa9b7c103d93</guid></item><item><title>Homes under threat as bushfire bears down on properties in Geraldton suburbs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/waggrakine-moresby-fire-threatens-homes-greater-geraldton/106084318</link><description>Lives and homes are again under threat from a bushfire burning in Western Australia's Midwest, with a fresh emergency warning issued in Geraldton's outer suburbs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5208f0ff12f02163d98015c2210bd05</guid></item><item><title>Ellyse Perry stars as Sixers claim Sydney Smash honours, Strikers down Heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/ellyse-perry-stars-as-sixers-down-thunder/106084458</link><description>Australia star Ellyse Perry hits an unbeaten 77 as the Sixers down the Thunder by six wickets in the Sydney Smash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfc412b172f63f123cd975991a4a186f</guid></item><item><title>Israeli PM Benjamin Netanyahu formally asks to be pardoned from corruption charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/israeli-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-asks-for-pardon/106084498</link><description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has formally asked for a pardon from President Isaac Herzog relating to corruption charges against him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6bbacb34ca0ff60ca48fb1fb25c0c36</guid></item><item><title>Property price climb continues but rates outlook removes some heat, Cotality says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/home-price-streak-continues-but-rates-outlook-takes-out-heat/106083314</link><description>National home values rose 1 per cent in November, according to Cotality's monthly index, which was the third straight month of gains above 1 per cent. But the pace of growth did moderate as the prospect of rate cuts faded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d22ace68b607605d99a09b2b6f6be5bc</guid></item><item><title>F1 Qatar: McLaren pitstop blunder costs Oscar Piastri win, Max Verstappen closes in on Lando Norris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/f1-live-qatar-grand-prix-oscar-piastri-lando-norris/105995110</link><description>Max Verstappen wins the Formula 1 Qatar Grand Prix after a McLaren pit stop error costs Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d563be605501a8b7de85bcfd8e93a4e</guid></item><item><title>Weight loss drugs are rewriting the global business of how we eat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/ozempic-glp1-munjaro-weight-loss-drugs-change-diet-share-price/106083274</link><description>The explosive rise of drugs like Ozempic and Mounjaro is shifting consumption patterns, health outcomes and pushing pharmaceutical giants into trillion-dollar valuations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">949fd22b45ee214aad7d427973f2df7a</guid></item><item><title>Albanese reached his zenith in 2025, but 2026 could test the limits of Labor's power</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/albanese-wedding-labor-zenith/106083908</link><description>It is hard to imagine a better end to the prime minister's year than this one, but realists in government know Labor can't continue to ride the wave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b950bb933b0cd1fdce9927b5780a2599</guid></item><item><title>This week in history quiz: Can you ace our test on events from the past?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/this-week-in-history-quiz-december-1/106015174</link><description>From reality TV and heist movie remakes to man's last step on the Moon — how well do you know this week in history?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b4b2f9f964287f3af5134a02dba73e4</guid></item><item><title>Early Childhood Education Minister Jess Walsh would not commit to a childcare inquiry despite growing safety concerns.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/minister-won-t-commit-to-childcare-inquiry-/106080774</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb2eb787c5b9bb56c81c704f07a908a0</guid></item><item><title>Early childhood education minister refuses to say if independent inquiry into childcare standards will happen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/childcare-safety-standards-daycare/106080572</link><description>The early childhood education minister is refusing to say whether the federal government will establish an independent review of childcare standards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">778de268781d5bb32f487861648d2744</guid></item><item><title>Tech companies advised to label and 'watermark' AI-generated content</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/ai-guidance-label-watermark-ai-content/106083786</link><description>With AI deepfakes causing confusion and harm online, the federal government tells tech developers that AI content should be clearly labelled, ahead of a National AI Plan due to be released.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8ff45b7679383652e206de7ad7ef9d1</guid></item><item><title>England's Ashes demolition job of Australia in Brisbane's first ever cricket Test match at the Ekka</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/ashes-test-brisbane-debut-1928-ekka/105922054</link><description>Australia's Ashes domination in Brisbane is almost total, with England winless at the Gabba since 1986. It wasn't always like this though, with the first visit to Brisbane resulting in the heaviest defeat in cricket history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab43081c32b914f98f525f1dcad3283b</guid></item><item><title>Incoming Australian social media ban leaves children vulnerable to phishing scams, experts say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/cyber-security-story-scam-warnings-scams/106036670</link><description>As the social media ban comes into effect, experts are worried children and families will be left vulnerable to age verification scams. Here's why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">facdfb9da6f132c95742f194e6be05d4</guid></item><item><title>Italian-Australian glass artist takes her work from Carnarvon to Venice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/sabrina-dowling-giudici-cold-glass-artist-venice/106052038</link><description>Sabrina's father warned her she couldn't make a living from art, but after decades in a sensible job she's now making waves in the world of glass art.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e85e3a710c8eb838af7e901168b7ae6</guid></item><item><title>Dicky Bill salad farms enter administration with 180 job cuts before Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/dicky-bill-salad-farm-business-goes-into-administration-job-cuts/106083434</link><description>Australian salad grower Dicky Bill enters administration, putting 180 people out of work before Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2906205cad3abfc43fee08bec407366c</guid></item><item><title>Hinchinbrook by-election a tick of approval for LNP government but no crystal ball for outcome of next election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/qld-hinchinbrook-analysis-win-for-lnp-but-no-crystal-ball/106083638</link><description>A week is a long time in politics, let alone three years, and the LNP's success at the next election is by no means assured, writes Jack McKay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa5569c66ea70291d591041c2aae0c67</guid></item><item><title>Complaints to council climb as Brisbane residents deal with stormwater runoff. But whose responsibility is it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/seq-how-to-deal-with-stormwater-runoff-property/106054680</link><description>Runoff from heavy rainfall and poor drainage can cause damage to properties and worsen flooding. So, who's responsible if your property experiences runoff, and what can you do about it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7972464377c44144ec9136fb0474a641</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Travis Head prepared to play any role in day-night Ashes Test against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/ashes-second-test-australia-england-travis-head/106085110</link><description>Travis Head says he has no qualms if he is shifted back down Australia's batting order following his exploits as an opener in the first Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e36579986c8f33bf873c39e73ac34573</guid></item><item><title>The Macquarie Point stadium decision is due this week — here's how it could play out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/decision-week-for-hobart-afl-stadium-macquarie-point-arrives/106083308</link><description>The long-running debate over whether an AFL stadium should be built on Hobart's waterfront is reaching an end, as the parliamentary vote takes place this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a9c6bb32e5fb7b1c9f738f20dc9a98a</guid></item><item><title>Parents in NSW warned of potentially more school closures due to bushfire risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/parents-warned-of-nsw-school-closures-due-to-bushfire-risk/106071876</link><description>Public school parents in New South Wales have been advised school closures may occur on days of elevated fire danger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3def3f68f8b60e1069fa8432ae6f674</guid></item><item><title>Domestic violence abusers have 'weaponised' smart cars to terrorise their victims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/smart-cars-used-as-weapons-by-domestic-violence-abusers/106079588</link><description>A new eSafety advisory warns Australians about technology-facilitated abuse and provides advice on how to protect themselves from it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3515b58cc62c387feab0abe723e1c77</guid></item><item><title>F1 standings: Lando Norris, Max Verstappen, Oscar Piastri set for Abu Dhabi decider after Qatar GP</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/f1-standings-lando-norris-max-verstappen-oscar-piastri/106085058</link><description>Oscar Piastri's hopes of winning the F1 title suffered a hammer blow after McLaren's strategy error in Qatar, but there is still hope. Here's how the Aussie can upset the odds in Abu Dhabi's decider.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a4463704d85f1accca0c659dbe24ccd</guid></item><item><title>Australia humbled by New Zealand in Dubai rugby sevens finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/dubai-world-series-rugby-sevens-australia-loses-to-new-zealand/106085186</link><description>Australia falls to its trans-Tasman rivals in both the women's and men's finals at the season-opening leg of the world series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3915790454d932fb01cbe3b215ed5df</guid></item><item><title>Big haul of 170yo Indigenous artefacts unearthed in North West Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/aboriginal-artefacts-discovered-outback-queensland-pitta-pitta/106073188</link><description>A stash of Aboriginal artefacts, dating back about 170 years, is unearthed from the red dirt of outback Queensland, bringing history to life for the local Pitta Pitta people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45b16367b7d1c261e40ee5f7a8e1de6d</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of Australians losing free-to-air tv access and facing internet outages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/losing-free-to-air-tv-access-internet-outages-opticomm/106080642</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53683f64c9322d333aea7fcb910cbcd7</guid></item><item><title>Opticomm customers across Australia losing free-to-air television and facing internet outages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/opticomm-free-to-air-television-internet-outages/106018424</link><description>About 50,000 Australians are set to lose access to free-to-air television using their existing technology. And the troubles do not end there, with many customers also reporting regular and prolonged internet outages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">933c51c03c903bfd60d6f5b3b5bbdbbe</guid></item><item><title>Eight ways to drink less during Christmas party season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/eight-ways-to-drink-less-during-christmas-party-season/106078790</link><description>If you want to drink less (or not at all) this silly season, you don't have to rely on willpower alone. Having a plan can help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a7ec6e8524b684c0abb1c0c3fe13204</guid></item><item><title>WA government commits $109.9 million for preventing family and domestic violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/wa-government-family-domestic-violence-announcement/106002122</link><description>The WA government has announced a $109.9 million package to address family and domestic violence (FDV) across the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30944e05495a01d0e0bf86fbf62c5ccd</guid></item><item><title>Energy grid not ready for Eraring coal plant's closure, AEMO says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/energy-grid-not-ready-eraring-coal-aemo/106085200</link><description>The energy grid is not ready for the closure of the Eraring coal plant, the energy operator has warned, raising the threat of widespread blackouts in eastern Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87a5df1e444ed91127127b9ddab1ebfd</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Island's last dog embraced by the remote community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/last-dog-on-christmas-island-shiloh/105722366</link><description>Dogs were banned some years ago to protect the unique wildlife of Christmas Island, but one very special chocolate Labrador remains, and she is shared by the whole community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed4a79fb8808d98d72d90b95f6cfe390</guid></item><item><title>Death toll tops 800 as intense storms hammer Asian countries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/death-toll-tops-800-as-intense-storms-hammer-asia/106085210</link><description>At least 355 people are dead and 366 are missing in Sri Lanka as floods, cyclones and torrential rain continue to affect millions of people across Asia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60704142184354f1a29416dad6213a84</guid></item><item><title>Meningococcal B scare prompts call for free immunisation program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/meningococcal-b-immunisation-program/106078982</link><description>Charlie was in a coma for days after contracting the rare but preventable disease. He was lucky to survive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3320294ab7d94e926f3bc85a11734d7</guid></item><item><title>Sensitive parliament communications handed to contractor without security clearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/parliament-communications-given-to-contractor-without-clearance/106085308</link><description>The team of a contractor that was the victim of a Russia-linked hack did not have the necessary security clearance when it received thousands of sensitive communications between politicians and parliamentary staff, in a mistake the department has now conceded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d3d7e2888d0c0bfca6d056d2250cd17</guid></item><item><title>Summer sleeps in as Melburnians endure coldest December 1 in decades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/coldest-december-1-day-in-victoria-since-1996/106085336</link><description>Melbourne's temperature is not forecast to rise above 15C today, making it the coldest December 1 since 1996.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b55d870f8982ed7eba8e5dd4a8db68d</guid></item><item><title>Mourners flock to site of deadly Hong Kong blaze as Beijing warns against protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/beijing-warns-against-using-hong-kong-blaze-to-disrupt-city/106085432</link><description>Thousands of people pay tribute to the victims of Hong Kong's deadliest fire in more than 75 years, as Beijing warns it will crack down on any "anti-China" protest in the wake of the blaze.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ab48d90a045bf56dc153fe917c75a56</guid></item><item><title>Nicola Olyslagers and Bruce McAvaney honoured at World Athletics Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/world-athletics-awards-nicola-olyslagers-bruce-mcavaney/106085566</link><description>Nicola Olyslagers becomes only the second Australian athlete to be honoured at the World Athletics Awards, while legendary broadcaster Bruce McAvaney is recognised for his contribution to the sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0835bdfac21229d7b01565f30838f2ef</guid></item><item><title>Emerson Jones and James Duckworth receive wildcards ahead of 2026 Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/tennis-emerson-jones-james-duckworth-aus-open-wildcards/106085686</link><description>Teen star Emerson Jones becomes one of the youngest Australians to receive a wildcard to the Australian Open after stellar performances at tournaments in November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1b7481b7db6d694d8ff88280aab532e</guid></item><item><title>How councils are preparing for billion-dollar wind farm projects amid renewables boom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/how-councils-are-preparing-for-wind-farms-renewables-boom/106073420</link><description>As approvals for multi-billion-dollar projects land on agendas at country local government meetings, staff and elected representatives battle to ensure their communities are prepared to benefit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7cba8fe33ffeca59eff9d3a0c7490dd</guid></item><item><title>Geraldton bushfire destroys one home as up to 200 firefighters worked to control blaze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/wa-bushfire-emergency-second-day-as-geraldton-homes-threatened/106085396</link><description>Authorities have downgraded their warning levels for bushfires burning in the greater Geraldton area to an 'advice' level after a challenging day for firefighters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d3515fd97db7af71f664858e3914f5e</guid></item><item><title>Brett Russell sentenced to 12 years, 9 months behind bars for Victorian school bus crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/loreto-college-bus-crash-brett-russell-trial-sentencing/106085408</link><description>Brett Russell was towing two trailers with faulty brakes at high speed in September 2022 when he crashed into the back of a school bus in regional Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">357cfe6ae1459054740a3b74d907de91</guid></item><item><title>South-east Queensland population to reach 4.5 million as growth outpaces that of the nation, KPMG analysis shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/south-east-queensland-population-growth-2032-olympics/106085290</link><description>South-east Queensland's population is set to reach 4.5 million by the time Brisbane hosts the 2032 Olympics, new analysis shows, despite rising property prices driven by a lack of supply.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">612f444f551a00806eeeb0d133632a55</guid></item><item><title>Ngangkaṟi share traditional healing in new edition of book that went global</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/traditional-healers-of-central-australia-ngangka%E1%B9%9Fi-book/106044308</link><description>The Ngangkaṟi in Central Australia use traditional healing techniques to draw out illness with their hands. A new edition of their book aims to share this knowledge Western health workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da3cdb0b168f3c536805a673e3da2c38</guid></item><item><title>Government unveils Department of Defence overhaul amid delays and cost blowouts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/government-to-unveil-defence-department-overhaul/106086340</link><description>Three groups within Defence will be rolled into one entity as part of a sweeping restructure of the department.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a63361148c65d5feed9950262f355645</guid></item><item><title>Man pleads guilty to manslaughter of surfer Guy Haymes in Manly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/nsw-surfer-guy-haymes-manslaughter-guilty-plea/106086352</link><description>A man has admitted to fatally bashing a well-known surfer on Sydney's northern beaches during a dispute in which he accused him of stealing $50.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01ade32e0f5b73bd192aa574175f457b</guid></item><item><title>Tiwi Islands man guilty of murdering international student, NT Supreme Court jury finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/guilty-verdict-murder-trial-bangladeshi-student-darwin/106085760</link><description>The man accused of murdering a 23-year-old international student in Darwin in 2023 has been found guilty following a week-long trial in the NT Supreme Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efad55c690286f6834cba15250a97baf</guid></item><item><title>Carbon monoxide leak at Derrimut meat processing plant leaves multiple workers in hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/carbon-monoxide-leak-meat-processing-plant-hospital/106087106</link><description>Almost two dozen workers have fallen ill after a carbon monoxide leak at a pork processing plant in Derrimut.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ed17743721441f9b5f10e2269308572</guid></item><item><title>Trump wants Venezuela's airspace closed — but international law stands in the way</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/trump-venezuela-airspace-explainer/106086368</link><description>US President Donald Trump says Venezuela's airspace should be considered closed. According to international law, it's not that simple.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9ab0ccadda2d5e485c3091ae4aa8165</guid></item><item><title>$3.4 billion Coomera Connector stage one to open after construction cracks probed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/first-stage-of-gold-coast-coomera-connector-to-open-to-motorists/106085710</link><description>Motorists will be able to use the first 4-kilometre stretch of the new Coomera Connector as an alternative to the busy Pacific Motorway from Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8460e81c37904dcb5d082750cc530da5</guid></item><item><title>Luxury caravan manufacturer Zone RV collapses into administration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/caravan-manufacturer-zone-rv-collapses-into-administration/106055816</link><description>Hundreds of Zone RV employees are out of work weeks before Christmas after arriving at work on Monday morning and being told the bad news.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4085f6da9a532e8e6c4aee2ec07c72af</guid></item><item><title>Case against teens charged over Adelaide shopping centre stabbing could move to adult court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/teenagers-court-elizabeth-shopping-centre-stabbing-lockdown/106087642</link><description>Prosecutors are "likely" to consider asking for the case against two teenagers charged over a stabbing — which sent an Adelaide shopping centre into lockdown — to be moved to an adult court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">933b6f5020596da9eb57a49bdecbf104</guid></item><item><title>Watchdog updates warnings for Ozempic-style drugs over potential risk of suicidal thoughts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/updated-warning-for-ozempic-mounjaro-glp-1-drugs/106087650</link><description>Australia's medicines regulator issues a safety warning over the potential risk of suicidal thoughts and behaviours when taking Ozempic-style drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57f9160386d3a06fca529fbf8ad4084e</guid></item><item><title>NSW government, energy company under fire after native bird habitat cleared for renewables project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/nsw-government-renewable-land-clearing-birds/106085764</link><description>The NSW government's flagship renewable energy project has come under fire after trees containing dozens of hatchlings were cut down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a196e36e5954179727a91ad5e4d82f63</guid></item><item><title>Hillcrest jumping castle court case costs sought by Rosemary Gamble</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/hillcrest-jumping-castle-court-case-costs-sought-rosemary-gamble/106086370</link><description>The operator of the jumping castle at the centre of the tragedy in which six schoolchildren died in 2021 is seeking to recoup potentially "millions" in court costs following her being found not guilty of a health and safety charge in relation to the incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1be6e8cce18506be8c4a8eb78e0e5c6</guid></item><item><title>First day of summer delivers record heat in the west, record cold in the east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/summer-record-heat-in-the-west-record-cold-in-the-east/106086392</link><description>Summer has arrived in Australia with a bang, with fire and searing heat in the west, while a sprinkling of snow accompanied record cold temperatures in the south-east of the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ddb8b5712e23bc964d3fe0513e88185</guid></item><item><title>Vinnies sends most charity waste to ACT landfill as overall disposal declines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/st-vincent-de-paul-charities-landfill-waste-canberra/106085878</link><description>Canberra's biggest charities dumped almost 600 tonnes of waste last financial year, with the declining quality of donations a key factor in goods ending up as landfill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac4967bc49b78d9cb13b1cf83c08b1a</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106086840</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee848cc76b922f3eb919fbbbe0a41141</guid></item><item><title>Businesses using 'branded identifiers' in SMS messages now need to register them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/acma-calls-on-organisations-to-register-sender-ids/106087234</link><description>Organisations using branded identifiers in their text messages to consumers will need to register them by July 1, 2026, or risk being mistaken for a scam.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d873d0b06774ceb283772747dfa9ac62</guid></item><item><title>Prosecutors call last witnesses in trial of Rajwinder Singh, accused of murdering Toyah Cordingley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/toyah-cordingley-murder-rajwinder-singh-trial/106086006</link><description>The jury in the former Innisfail nurse's murder trial has heard more than three weeks of evidence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26b7d6b56af3afef745b1382a6da047f</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr edges closer to injury return in final Matildas friendly vs New Zealand before Asian Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/sam-kerr-in-the-mix-for-matildas-return-new-zealand/106088840</link><description>Matildas captain Sam Kerr is running out of chances to make her long-awaited return from a knee injury, as the Australian team faces New Zealand's Football Ferns in their last scheduled match before next year's Asian Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">400ff4b4f8245af06660fd82ad475744</guid></item><item><title>Netting on apartment complex did not meet fire resistance code, Hong Kong officials say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/hong-kong-authorities-says-netting-on-building-did-not-meet-code/106088946</link><description>Hong Kong's anti-corruption agency has arrested 13 people, including the directors and an engineering consultant of a construction company.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc9abaf6b2b274b65a88b8bf335fcd44</guid></item><item><title>Inquest hears man likely experiencing psychosis was carrying fake gun and planning 'suicide by cop'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/nowra-shooter-coronial-inquest/106085800</link><description>An inquest into a 2024 police shooting in Nowra on the NSW South Coast hears police gunned down a man who was carrying a fake gun with the intention of being killed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c12be15e652c2d6fe6b6ffa5cd5e8bde</guid></item><item><title>Accountability sought after Hong Kong’s deadly apartment fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/accountability-sought-after-hong-kong-s-deadly-apartment-fire/106088648</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d731ddf7e301347731b7cb97d482706</guid></item><item><title>UK MP Tulip Siddiq sentenced to prison in Bangladesh in corruption case linked to her aunt, former PM Sheikh Hasina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/tulip-siddiq-sentenced-to-prison-in-bangladesh/106089100</link><description>Tulip Siddiq says the decision should be treated with "contempt", while her political party says she was not afforded due process.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dacc7199187b41ecd499ea9eb942aa8</guid></item><item><title>World Health Organization recommends Ozempic-style medications as long-term obesity treatments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/world-health-organization-guidelines-ozempic-obesity/106085946</link><description>Ozempic-style medications have been recommended as long-term treatments for obesity under new guidelines released by the World Health Organization.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cb273f1549cb54ac73ae6781ab5dc07</guid></item><item><title>Flooding in Indonesia, Thailand and Sri Lanka kills more than 1,160 people as recovery efforts continue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/more-than-1000-dead-in-flooding-in-indonesia-thailand-sri-lanka/106089220</link><description>Indonesia, Thailand and Sri Lanka are reeling from flooding that has killed hundreds in each country and destroyed communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a9a99a721f241dd969093223e3e790f</guid></item><item><title>Luigi Mangione faces key evidence hearings over US healthcare executive's killing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/luigi-mangione-faces-evidence-hearings-in-court/106089108</link><description>Mr Mangione, who was arrested in 2024, has been charged with fatally shooting UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson in Midtown Manhattan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fdfe729505da45d759578e468c98a19</guid></item><item><title>One fire, two systems: Hong Kong's grief meets Beijing's red lines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/tai-po-fire-hong-kong-mainland-grief-red-lines/106087732</link><description>The blaze that consumed Wang Fuk Court burned for two days, but its political shock waves may echo for weeks, even months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">032cd9f8796393786d4ef834423f5fba</guid></item><item><title>Pablo Escobar's final mistake and the lonely death of the cocaine king</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/today-in-history-december-2-pablo-escobar-death/105966258</link><description>More than three decades since his death in a rooftop shootout with police, the legacy of cocaine king Pablo Escobar continues to affect Colombia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14d48ef3caf2128f49fc1e97d31fba61</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanians express mix of views ahead of final Macquarie Point stadium vote</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/hobart-stadium-weighing-on-minds-of-community-before-vote/106085678</link><description>By the end of this week, Tasmania will know whether or not Hobart will have a new AFL stadium. Many Tasmanians are still making up their own minds about whether they support it or not.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6296ba9abc412578f7570cc2fbe9b3b</guid></item><item><title>Woolworths accused of exploiting affordable housing schemes to push new developments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/woolworths-accused-of-gaming-affordable-housing-schemes/106087568</link><description>The retail giant is using development fast-track schemes to push ahead with new supermarket and apartment projects opposed by local councils.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">356a2e3a4db06ae81a74322604f78430</guid></item><item><title>Maps reveal the Ukraine regions Vladimir Putin does not hold, but wants anyway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/trump-concept-for-ukraine-in-maps-as-putin-negotiations-continue/106046750</link><description>Donald Trump is expected to send his special envoy Steven Witkoff to Moscow this week to talk about a revised proposal for peace in Ukraine. There are five regions central to negotiations and Vladimir Putin wants them all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a12224be088e27d1b0d33dcaebf31199</guid></item><item><title>Is social media masking bushwalking dangers and leading to poor hiking decisions?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/is-social-media-masking-dangers-of-bushwalking/106077340</link><description>There are concerns that social media is leading to poor bushwalking decisions with trends such as "rawdogging" a hike glorifying a lack of preparedness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd9b39420efe0c6f2d65dd88023ac82c</guid></item><item><title>Tumbling Bitcoin's last useful business — money laundering — under threat from Tether</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/bitcoin-losing-to-tether-as-money-launderers-currency-of-choice/106086594</link><description>It remains a useful tool for some nefarious operators, including global crime gangs and questionable governments, but Bitcoin's role has been usurped by stablecoins — one in particular.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b433cfd36be5e5f6eb6130ac7e82d5db</guid></item><item><title>NDIS cuts Deaf man's Auslan funding, recommends he explore 'other communication methods'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/ndis-cuts-deaf-mans-auslan-funding/106051024</link><description>Disability advocates say cuts to Deaf participants' NDIS funding is a "systemic" problem that reflects a belief that Deafness can be "fixed".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ad769117b1b239b041a8a31aa5a2206</guid></item><item><title>What 17,000-plus young people think about the social media ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/what-young-people-think-about-social-media-ban-btn-survey/106058976</link><description>BTN surveyed more than 17,000 Australians under 16 about the federal government's upcoming social media ban. This is what they said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78ac4c27ccd0342c6ca880749cc4ae55</guid></item><item><title>Victoria seeks to change 'unconstitutional' donation laws amid High Court challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/victorian-donation-laws-change-after-high-court-challenge/106087938</link><description>A financial election advantage for the three biggest Victorian political parties will be removed in the face of a High Court challenge that has argued the state's donation laws are unconstitutional.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6889cb46fb6b711a42e2cb1eb2109a5f</guid></item><item><title>The numbers and narrative behind Australia's staggering pink ball success</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/ashes-australia-england-pink-ball-test-numbers/106085716</link><description>Day-night Test cricket provides Australia with one of the most potent home advantages in the history of the sport. Ten years into its existence, these are the numbers behind the format, its best performers and the ways England could spring an upset in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffa771d00a61b6e9f3aadf2b0fa603c9</guid></item><item><title>Artificial intelligence to be managed through existing laws under National AI Plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/national-artificial-intelligence-plan-growth-existing-laws/106086474</link><description>The federal government's long-awaited National AI Plan will seek to accelerate the growth of artificial intelligence in Australia, and largely leverage existing laws to protect against its worst harms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3feaddbafe2677ea608e34b845cb2273</guid></item><item><title>Why you should read the fine print when purchasing a gift card this festive season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/gift-card-expiration-activation-fine-print-christmas/105569524</link><description>If you receive a gift card for Christmas this year you might fall foul of "activation rules". Here's how.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">137d93532d66889198b9e2d1961852ba</guid></item><item><title>Two men first in SA to be found guilty of charges arising from encrypted devices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/sa-ironside-trials-guilty/106082150</link><description>Two South Australian men are the first in the state to be found guilty after standing trial for charges arising from the major police operation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa71e1612601917501fab0b6b74d6a3d</guid></item><item><title>R360's postponed launch calls to mind rebel competitions like Super League and World Series Cricket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/the-history-of-breakaway-leagues-after-r360-postpones/106083718</link><description>R360's announcement it is not going to be ready in 2026 brings back memories of previous attempts to set up rebel sporting competitions, almost all of which have failed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70c1cc362abe0365f4b74a509c1fc955</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy eyes talks with Donald Trump on 'key issues' as Steve Witkoff heads to Moscow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/zelenskyy-eyes-trump-talks-witkoff-heads-to-moscow/106081316</link><description>The Ukrainian president meets French President Emmanuel Macron in Paris as he sounds out European allies on Washington's blueprint to end Russia's war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b01d9a70eaedeae1ab9c5a4fd5b1fe6</guid></item><item><title>Two teenage boys charged over fire at Deniliquin High School</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/two-teenagers-charged-over-deniliquin-high-fire/106089568</link><description>Two teenage boys have been charged over a weekend fire that extensively damaged Deniliquin High School in the NSW Riverina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7934e174409522499b8e329f37276dee</guid></item><item><title>Uber driver says rideshare app tells workers to flout road rules as bill introduced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/new-bill-to-protect-nsw-workers-unsafe-practices-due-algorithms/106081874</link><description>The NSW government introduces legislation that would require employers to ensure their algorithms and automation practises do not risk a worker's health and safety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a86e485122c7bada3511383125d8918</guid></item><item><title>Secret government audit reveals how big travel companies can overcharge clients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/government-audit-travel-management-companies/106088404</link><description>The document, prepared for the Queensland government, has been exclusively obtained by the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">697a433bbed4b9c3ce43dbe720fe8ca9</guid></item><item><title>As teacher shortages loom across Australia these Queensland schools are trialling solutions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/teacher-shortage-nearing-crisis-point-solutions/106026086</link><description>As staff shortages "near crisis point", these Queensland schools are going to extraordinary lengths to put teachers in classrooms — and keep them there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a577430673addb35fb00c86c4dd4f38</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: Government to establish landmark probe into ADF sexual violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/federal-politics-live-blog-dec-2/106088556</link><description>A landmark inquiry into sexual violence in the Australian Defence Force will be announced today. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ae1056b55bc21631043d993d1cd0635</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Lethlean undecided on whether to challenge Jacinta Allan in Bendigo East</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/nationals-election-2026-tilt-bendigo-east-premier-jacinta-allan/106058372</link><description>Nationals favourite Andrew Lethlean is tight-lipped on whether he will challenge Premier Jacinta Allan in Bendigo East next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">721000b60bd831162f40f3b72df076fe</guid></item><item><title>Filmmaker breaks decades of silence over Yolŋu clan leader's alleged murder by police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/nt-officer-witnessed-fellow-police-murder-yolngu-clan-leader/105987868</link><description>Acclaimed filmmaker George Gittoes has revealed a former NT police officer told him he witnessed his colleagues taking a Yolŋu clan leader out to shoot him and dump his body in Darwin Harbour in 1934.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">500aeaa5e5493474fdfb9c4d9e62fe5d</guid></item><item><title>Pat Conroy on the landmark inquiry into sexual violence in the ADF</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/pat-conroy-on-landmark-inquiry-into-sexual-violence-in-the-adf/106089782</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b27adc0eefe0ccffa58a3358f435725</guid></item><item><title>Geraldton resident Nick Morgan grateful for support after losing home in bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/geraldton-bushfires-nick-morgan-lost-home-in-blaze/106088720</link><description>A home owner who lost his house and his cat to a bushfire in Geraldton, in WA's Mid West, says "karma" is looking for anyone who may have deliberately lit the blazes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9494d02854696251499de8271a43c661</guid></item><item><title>Son of drug kingpin 'El Chapo' pleads guilty in US drug trafficking case in deal with prosecutors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/son-of-el-chapo-pleads-guilty-in-us-drug-trafficking-case/106089764</link><description>A son of notorious Mexican drug kingpin "El Chapo" pleads guilty to US drug trafficking charges, months after his brother entered a plea deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd8132e655b392e6c723121ec155c022</guid></item><item><title>NT government announces childcare compliance 'crackdown', but providers unsure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/nt-government-announces-childcare-centre-compliance-changes/106087990</link><description>The Northern Territory government has announced a "crackdown" on compliance at childcare centres across the territory, following the death of a toddler at a rural Darwin centre in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33fbdd7679682a3b31d81db74342d302</guid></item></channel></rss>