<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 10:50:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Calls to reinstate organ donation driver's licence scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/calls-to-reinstate-organ-donation-drivers-licence-scheme/106102290</link><description>As the Victorian government moves to bring back the driver's licence donor registration scheme, DonateLife wants it to be nationwide, saying there is clear evidence it leads to an increase in organ donors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45c70374278a437a49de2da048cec8c4</guid></item><item><title>Rare PNG conjoined twins en route to Australia as case reaches 'critical' point</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/rare-png-conjoined-twins-flown-to-australia/106096930</link><description>A rare set of conjoined twins are being urgently airlifted from Papua New Guinea to Australia, with doctors recommending they be separated as soon as possible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">284b1ab17f3fe2186516c76dd057ac88</guid></item><item><title>Major incident causes Perth traffic chaos ahead of AC/DC concert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/major-incident-causes-perth-traffic-chaos-ahead-of-acdc-concert/106103054</link><description>A serious crash on one of Perth's major freeway's brings train services to a halt and caused traffic chaos in the city's south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76a8ae0c293b2fb51d6cb84dad82e145</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106103238</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b3e8330e565fccb72fbfead3b252309</guid></item><item><title>Alleged manslaughter victim told classmate she was 'treated like a slave' at home, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/jenni-wilmott-trial-former-classmate-gives-evidence/106102618</link><description>A girl who was allegedly criminally neglected at the hands of her mother before she died told a friend she was "treated like a slave" and was "scared to go back home", a court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">774be67b70155fe11280835620341d73</guid></item><item><title>Hobart’s new stadium likely go ahead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/hobart-s-new-stadium-likely-go-ahead/106103056</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de92cf69a05874e40648ad091328ed8f</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Nathan Lyon's axing leaves Australia struggling on docile Gabba pitch in second Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/nathan-lyon-axing-second-ashes-test-gabba/106103444</link><description>Australia leaves Nathan Lyon out of its XI for the second Ashes Test at the Gabba, marking an almost 14-year first.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a047be68f52e82cf4da3a71a299e58f</guid></item><item><title>Root notches century despite stunning run-out, non-Starc seamers struggle without Lyon — five quick hits from Ashes second Test day one</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/ashes-second-test-day-one-quick-hits-joe-root-run-out/106101422</link><description>Joe Root overcomes a horror mix-up to notch a long-awaited first Test century in Australia, while Australia's seamers largely struggle without the dropped Nathan Lyon. Here are the quick hits from the first day of the pink-ball Ashes Test in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a24f895f2e6e991ca803f11ce6c93550</guid></item><item><title>Hobart stadium at Macquarie Point gets final approval in parliament's upper house</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/tas-parliament-vote-approves-afl-stadium-for-tasmania/106103886</link><description>A $1.13 billion stadium on the edge of the Hobart CBD has been approved by Tasmania's upper house, satisfying a key condition for the state's AFL licence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c881f50449274ddd97789fe9d382154b</guid></item><item><title>Putin bears 'moral responsibility' for 2018 poisoning of UK woman, inquiry finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/uk-inquiry-findings-woman-2018-novichok-poisoning/106103644</link><description>A UK public inquiry concludes that Russian President Vladimir Putin "must have" ordered the Novichok nerve agent attack on Russian double agent Sergei Skripal in 2018.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ef9cac28206ecd99b86c43edee379e1</guid></item><item><title>Value of private health insurance 'eroding' as doctors urge reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/private-health-insurance-eroding-as-doctors-urge-reform/106095198</link><description>A new report from Australia's peak doctors' body says private health insurance is increasingly failing to deliver value to the roughly 15 million Australians who hold a policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">506ed9de17cafac299e52fb7051726a7</guid></item><item><title>What does Vladimir Putin want from his state visit to India and his meeting with Narendra Modi?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/what-does-vladimir-putin-want-from-state-visit-to-india/106104162</link><description>The Russian leader's first state visit to India in nearly four years is expected to focus heavily on trade amid a backdrop of international sanctions and Donald Trump's tariff policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2dcd3e4e81b1de6f9a515dc5b6adfa8</guid></item><item><title>New York Times sues the Pentagon over press access restrictions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/new-york-times-sues-the-pentagon-over-reporting-restrictions/106103842</link><description>The US publication has filed a lawsuit over a new policy requiring journalists to sign a pledge to refrain from reporting information not authorised for release by the Pentagon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e716cba556dd3156c1fd6365dcfb15a</guid></item><item><title>Israel to compete at Eurovision Song Contest in 2026, prompting several nations to withdraw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/israel-allowed-to-compete-at-eurovision-2026-prompting-boyott/106104460</link><description>Public broadcasters in Spain, Ireland and the Netherlands say they will not participate in next year's event and more are expected to follow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58b2f0f1f947dfe1f049f7fcb63a55d2</guid></item><item><title>AUKUS will survive Trump, says Australia's top diplomat in London Stephen Smith</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/steven-smith-prepares-to-leave-london-after-three-years/106103968</link><description>The trilateral agreement has come under significant scrutiny, but Australia's top diplomat in London says he believes its future is assured.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87cc7c62361d5c820c9adee8662b5b2e</guid></item><item><title>The best new TV shows of 2025, from The Golden Bachelor to The Studio</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/best-tv-shows-2025-golden-bachelor-the-studio-wayward/106074292</link><description>From a send-up of Hollywood studios to a chilling depiction of violence and masculinity to an age-appropriate reality TV romance, these are our favourite TV shows of 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e2b633a744ea39e8ec6696aeeafa789</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 5: How Prohibition was brought down by gangsters, bootleggers and violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/today-in-history-december-5-end-of-prohibition/105992414</link><description>Prohibition was officially repealed on December 5, 1933. But the beginning of its end can be traced back years earlier — to a highly-publicised massacre by firing squad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acabe812a0a6d147ea3eda53a2b2a0d1</guid></item><item><title>Victorian prisoners held in police stations for weeks, lawyer says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/victoria-criminal-lawyer-clients-remand-held-in-police-cells/106100524</link><description>A Victorian lawyer says a "crisis" is unfolding in the state's jails, with remand centres so crowded prisoners are instead being kept in police holding cells for up to a month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">207849410ecb673d23fcc7e3fac01014</guid></item><item><title>Corowa residents caught off guard by 'early' fire a sign of 'apathy', authorities say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/corowa-residents-caught-off-guard-by-early-fire/106096104</link><description>A fast moving grass fire almost burned through the southern NSW town of Corowa last week. Despite the extreme fire danger rating, residents say they weren't prepared for such an intense fire so early in the season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be394ebe193cc2ae42522f01a2830b84</guid></item><item><title>Is Tasmanian AFL team a holy grail or poisoned chalice? Time will tell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/tasmanian-afl-team-holy-grail-or-poisoned-chalice/106100862</link><description>When it comes to the Macquarie Point stadium in Tasmania, there is clearly something deeper at play than seats, concrete and a roof. You simply couldn't vote for it otherwise, writes Chris Rowbottom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d096c0649afaa9b8188d4c18341020d7</guid></item><item><title>Search engines will soon have to blur porn image results in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/search-engines-will-soon-have-to-blur-porn-image-results/106103600</link><description>Pornographic image results will be blurred and searches for self-harm information will redirect to mental health supports under new Australian online safety codes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d02383c63601660295ab094f6471369</guid></item><item><title>Teen becomes first nationally accredited netball umpire in a wheelchair</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/brodie-taylor-wheelchair-umpire-netball/106055516</link><description>Brodie Taylor has changed the game of netball by overturning disability preconceptions to become the first person in a wheelchair to attain national netball umpiring accreditation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dad8e91985bdccf351d89b6352cf5cb3</guid></item><item><title>Industrial relations are risky business for the Liberals after WorkChoices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/liberals-industrial-relations-workchoices-unions-labor-workers/106088082</link><description>The Liberals argue Labor's industrial relations concessions to the unions are a "handbrake on productivity" but this area has been tricky for the Coalition since John Howard's disastrous overreach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ec8241dae12cdb6d8eb1b9f8047c34a</guid></item><item><title>Australia's PALM workers are leaving their employers, becoming 'extremely vulnerable' in visa limbo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/palm-worker-disengagement-new-report/106009270</link><description>Pacific Islanders have been leaving Australia's guest worker scheme, a decision that breaches their visa conditions and leaves them "extremely vulnerable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">841c80aff565d1b60279268f926fdcf6</guid></item><item><title>Pentagon watchdog releases report on Pete Hegseth's use of Signal app</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/pentagon-inspector-general-releases-pete-hegseth-signal-report/106104450</link><description>The 84-page report finds US Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth violated policy and could have put American troops at risk when he used the Signal app to discuss military strikes in Yemen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b81f7be2d1c07cc10f66b20e47460a7e</guid></item><item><title>The Ashes are kickstarted at last by Mitchell Starc and Joe Root, but Australia's underbelly is tested</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ashes-gabba-day-one-mitchell-starc-joe-root-australia-england/106102778</link><description>A day of tough, fluctuating Test cricket kickstarts the Ashes series at last as Mitchell Starc and Joe Root carry their sides despite concerns about what lies beneath.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">226df8ba60b1cb43029c91d0a941d28d</guid></item><item><title>What is shotcrete, the material that caused Sydney's M4 tunnel closure?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/what-is-shotcrete-roof-material-sydney-m4-tunnel-closure/106102704</link><description>The issue with the commonly used substance caused delays where some motorists were gridlocked for more than four hours on Thursday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e8cb75bc69a94b8a035799e0a33f58f</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave stretches from Kimberley to Sydney as hot summer arrives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/heatwave-from-kimberley-wa-to-sydney-nsw-as-hot-summer-arrives/106102804</link><description>The burst of heat is short and sharp in southern states, sending temperatures more than 10 degrees Celsius above average and raising fire dangers to extreme, with the heat to linger into next week in the northern outback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2faa4b9ee2581ce3d2317111df449d3a</guid></item><item><title>Living with ADHD and how I make my life easier after being diagnosed as an adult</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/how-i-make-my-life-easier-after-adhd-diagnosis-personal-story/105920656</link><description>International Day of People with Disability scholar Mark du Potiers shares how attention deficit hyperactivity disorder impacts him day-to-day and what he does to make life more manageable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1ccfe4f116b86c4ddbb7dd14fdbf34a</guid></item><item><title>Impacts of working from home on mental health tracked in study of 16,000 Australians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/australian-working-from-home-mental-health-impacts-tracked/106096688</link><description>Working from home can positively impact the mental health of Australian men and women in different ways, according to a new study of more than 16,000 people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a23a31d4290c8ad43874888df90371da</guid></item><item><title>The cold supermoon will appear in the night sky tonight. Here's how to spot it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/how-to-see-the-cold-supermoon/106101342</link><description>The final supermoon of the year is set to delight stargazers tonight. Here's how to spot it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe06bd21c7eb1cda6c5df6a7292c0667</guid></item><item><title>Rheumatic heart disease cases drastically reduced in North West Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/rheumatic-heart-disease-cases-reduced-in-north-west-queensland/106099658</link><description>A lack of access to clean clothes and sheets led to high rates of heart disease in this outback Queensland town. But an Indigenous-led washing initiative is changing health outcomes in the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">513ce4de57fc29f398364fa465cc5d6c</guid></item><item><title>Alex Carey channels AFL pedigree for classic Ashes catch despite Marnus Labuschagne's tackle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/alex-carey-catch-marnus-labuschagne-tackles-ashes-test/106103934</link><description>Alex Carey's phenomenal catch late on day one at the Gabba would have been special all on its own, but it was made even more impressive after he had to "out-body" his own teammate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bc8c0c6309a235dfb1ac59547cac646</guid></item><item><title>South Australian golf course wetland is breeding site for locally extinct tiny native olive perchlet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/sa-golf-course-wetland-used-as-breeding-site-for-olive-perchlet/106102092</link><description>Golf courses around the world feature picturesque water ponds as a challenging hazard for players to avoid, but scientists are diving right in. They say golf club wetlands are an ecological safe haven to repopulate threatened native fish.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ee1f1543bd846b93c0d7845f74d1acc</guid></item><item><title>ChatGPT's owner OpenAI launches in Australia, partners with NextDC, ASX closes slightly higher — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/asx-markets-business-live-news-dec-5-2025/106104580</link><description>The company that brought AI into household vernacular launched in Australia today. It comes as other companies like Meta are struggling to make traction in this space.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97ffbb609f0db052123663cd504a92ec</guid></item><item><title>Local consortium races to rescue Sanjeev Gupta's Tahmoor mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/local-australian-bid-to-take-over-gupta-tahmoor-mine/106101390</link><description>A local consortium is rushing to put forward a bid for the mothballed Tahmoor coal mine, saying it wants the site reopened quickly to protect hundreds of jobs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ce422c06fcba8101b36e09ceeebfef2</guid></item><item><title>Compressed air energy storage is coming to Broken Hill, but how does it work?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/compressed-air-energy-storage-explainer/105999452</link><description>Broken Hill will be the location of Australia's first large-scale compressed air energy storage system. What is it and how does it work?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0efc28edd209486ddfa4f2a24046a67e</guid></item><item><title>Pentagon's AUKUS review finds areas to put nuclear submarine pact on 'strongest possible footing'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/aukus-review-pentagon-donald-trump-administration/105588512</link><description>The review has "identified opportunities to put AUKUS on the strongest possible footing", the Pentagon says. But a congressman who has seen the report says it "fully endorses" the pact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b23bce599e6ebbcf46142e953f6505eb</guid></item><item><title>Diners and commercial fishers to feel impact of WA demersal fishing ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/demersal-fishing-ban-impacts-food-security/106100994</link><description>New fishing rules come into effect in Western Australia next month, significantly reducing the amount of local fish available in the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cae795942ae953d26eb78b05cc38240</guid></item><item><title>Children risk life in prison for some violent crimes after Victorian parliament passes bill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/adult-time-for-violent-crime-prison-children-bill-parliament/106101956</link><description>Children as young as 14 years old could spend life in prison for some violent crimes after the Victorian parliament passed a controversial bill on Thursday. So what are the changes?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d97b0652c17c3cccbe3f44a04ec6ed8d</guid></item><item><title>Police officer's claim about search for Lindy Lucena in Ballina tested at watchdog hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/officers-claim-about-search-for-lindy-lucena-tested-by-watchdog/106099230</link><description>A Law Enforcement Conduct Commission is examining why it took police officers nearly an hour to respond to a Triple Zero (000) call about an assault which left Lindy Lucena dead at the hands of her partner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbaff3f6e13e94a6fadefcaba28c5d4b</guid></item><item><title>Zak Crawley says Nathan Lyon being dropped for second Ashes Test helped him find rhythm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ashes-2025-zak-crawley-on-nathan-lyon-being-dropped/106104822</link><description>Nathan Lyon speaks during an awkward TV interview as Zak Crawley says the spinner's omission helped the English batter find his rhythm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b8bb53a79743035f3a5a726208ac768</guid></item><item><title>Dozens of property damaged in Dolphin Sands bushfire on Tasmania's east coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/bushfire-dolphin-sands-tasmania-december-2025/106104816</link><description>There has been damage to at least 19 homes and shacks and 15 outbuildings at Dolphin Sands, on Tasmania's east coast, firefighters say, with residents told it is not yet safe to return.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7018dcf6e1fc46582fd14533b113bf14</guid></item><item><title>Country Hour reporters join listeners to celebrate 80 years of broadcasting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/country-hour-reporters-celebrate-80-years/106100556</link><description>Outside broadcasts highlight how the Country Hour connects with the daily life of rural Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd8300d14f1560b08c0a000ab75472dd</guid></item><item><title>Police on scene at Gregory Hills shopping centre after shots fired at man outside gym</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/gregory-hills-shooting-world-gym-police/106105080</link><description>Police swam on a shopping centre in south-western Sydney after a man narrowly avoided injury after being shot at.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">002f2252717f793570a5b82a7a052a78</guid></item><item><title>Australian red-tipped bananas go viral as social media interest ramps up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/red-tipped-ecoganic-bananas-go-viral-on-social-media/106102526</link><description>Red-tipped bananas are not new to Australian consumers, but they have gone viral on social media this month after an inquisitive post from two bewildered British backpackers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96a1afa6a1c4a4e11aa62494a6c30ebb</guid></item><item><title>Socceroo Aziz Behich excited that World Cup draw could set up rematch with Argentina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/world-cup-socceroos-and-argentina-possible-draw-and-rematch/106104608</link><description>The Socceroos cannot wait to learn who their opponents will be at the upcoming World Cup, especially if it allows them to handle some unfinished business.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">379271a3ecdcd1a5d66aca938f390eb9</guid></item><item><title>US military says it killed four men in strike on suspected drug vessel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/us-military-kill-four-in-suspected-drug-boat-strike/106105538</link><description>The US military says it has killed four men in a strike on a suspected drug vessel in international waters in the Eastern Pacific</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbdd6dd3db4413394fc38b227e838592</guid></item><item><title>Fires, heatwaves strike across Australia with emergency warnings issued — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/heatwaves-fires-live-blog-december-5/106105352</link><description>A broad heatwave is expected to spread across Australia, with short and sharp bursts of heat throughout the southern states.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8394bee0a73b0d19791eaed9f5db0d97</guid></item><item><title>WA miners build up massive gold stockpiles at Perth Mint amid record prices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/wa-gold-miners-building-up-massive-holdings-at-perth-mint/106078198</link><description>WA gold miners are stockpiling millions of dollars worth of the precious metal, believing it is more valuable than cash in the current environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9d28b648dbe3d84e262e9e016a63c16</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberal leader Vincent Tarzia steps down from leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/sa-opposition-leader-vincent-tarzia-steps-down/106106170</link><description>South Australian Liberal leader Vincent Tarzia will step down from the leadership, just three months out from the next state election. He told a press conference he made the decision on Friday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dc8becab9dacb49fbc7be525b654f96</guid></item><item><title>Smoke billows over mountains from Bulahdelah grass fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/smoke-billows-over-mountains-from-bulahdelah-grass-fire/106106372</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a478f53a57c6ab1ddaf0f2e95df21b8</guid></item><item><title>Family lose holiday home on Tasmania's east coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/shack-burns-down-at-dolphin-sands/106106584</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3cc12f6bf2ae6e87004a5755378d72b</guid></item><item><title>Ayers Rock Resort to be sold to American-owned tourism company</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ayers-rock-resort-being-sold-ilsc-to-us-company-journey-beyond/105867822</link><description>A deal for the sale of operations at Ayers Rock Resort, near Uluru, and the Mossman Gorge Cultural Centre, in Far North Queensland, is one step closer after the Indigenous Land and Sea Corporation reached an agreement with Journey Beyond, an Australian-based "experiential tourism" company owned by an American private equity firm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6ef1a0f06a4be580e3676b070b7bf86</guid></item><item><title>Victorian government defers increases to controversial emergency services levy in budget update</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/budget-update-victorian-government-jaclyn-symes-emergency-levy/106105012</link><description>The Victorian government has backed down on key parts of an unpopular tax used to fund the state's emergency services as part of its budget update.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a670b1f6d27efba52dc3ec8d3455fb1</guid></item><item><title>Will a controversial water plan lead to 'bad years' for Roper River barramundi?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/nt-roper-river-fish-barramundi-sawfish-bad-years/106096762</link><description>Documents obtained under Freedom of Information laws have revealed planned water extraction from the aquifer that feeds the Northern Territory's Roper River could lead to "bad years" for its fish populations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d7bb7831b65908d859d05539c687390</guid></item><item><title>Police search for gunman after shooting at Ballajura candy shop in suburban Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ballajura-shooting-police-search-for-gunman/106106264</link><description>A search is underway for a gunman who fired shots at a store in Perth's north in what police believe was a stand-over tactic by organised crime networks involved in the sale of illegal tobacco.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e162cd4cbb9d427bfb2f200ba1409666</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025 updates: Australia leads wasteful England by 44 runs on day two at the Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ashes-live-second-test-australia-vs-england-at-the-gabba/106105310</link><description>Will Jacks took a sensational catch, but England dropped five other chances as Australia builds a first innings lead on day two of the second Test Ashes Test at the Gabba.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e9db51099b8654b3d2221d2afdcbfc5</guid></item><item><title>Barwon Coast closes Breamlea track near Geelong after identifying asbestos-containing fragments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/asbestos-fragments-barwon-coast-breamlea-footpath-geelong-barwon/106106572</link><description>Asbestos has been discovered scattered throughout parts of a coastal town near the Great Ocean Road, prompting land managers to close a section to the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4b74efc417e2fda04fed1b6a5ca0ae5</guid></item><item><title>Six native trees poisoned along Noosa's Sunshine Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/six-native-trees-poisoned-along-noosas-sunshine-beach/106105402</link><description>Six Australian native trees have been poisoned on public land along one of Queensland's most expensive and exclusive beachside streets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e85e599f5879fce9e483dfa4f5f8d3e4</guid></item><item><title>Police return Ballarat man's stolen specialised running equipment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/stolen-specialised-running-equipment-returned-by-police/106105922</link><description>When Mick Marshall's car was stolen, he was more concerned about what was inside the vehicle than the car itself, and the training he would likely miss.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bfaf923112b802888545aaec4fcd9b7</guid></item><item><title>Israel's continued participation in Eurovision the latest in a string of contentious moments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/israel-eurovision-participation-latest-contentious-moments/106105888</link><description>Eurovision strives to put pop before politics, but it has repeatedly become embroiled in world events, particularly relating to Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9071735fa8336d50847413c7c5e2c13b</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of killing passenger in car rollover found not guilty of causing death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/sa-veering-driver-verdict/106105238</link><description>A driver accused of killing a passenger in a car rollover captured by his own dash cam has been found not guilty of causing the death, but guilty of aggravated driving without due care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5702c1f1ac05f0c33532070c85b5390b</guid></item><item><title>Unlicensed driver hears impact of single-vehicle crash that killed three friends near Tarago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/man-sentenced-over-crash-that-killed-three-near-tarago/106104704</link><description>Nowra man Lachlan Stuckey is facing three charges of dangerous driving occasioning death over a single-vehicle car crash which killed three of his friends near Tarago in July last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">116af7e4b1262197fac451a18a16f1d3</guid></item><item><title>Vape shopfronts move online amid Qld crackdown on illegal products</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/vape-delivery-services-online-after-qld-tobacconist-raids/106106928</link><description>Paper flyers are advertising same-day delivery of illegal vapes on the Gold Coast after police forced several tobacco stores to close their doors for three months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e632b87065ee2326c664681029cc7c24</guid></item><item><title>Axed Australian opener Sam Konstas lands drought-breaking century for New South Wales</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/sam-konstas-century-nsw-sheffield-shield/106108598</link><description>Almost a year on from his explosive Test debut, Sam Konstas has found form to hit his first century in 14 months in the New South Wales Sheffield Shield clash with Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd385d9dc7105beb464802c4e98b6fc2</guid></item><item><title>Chevron invests $3b to continue development of the Gorgon gas project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/chevron-to-continue-development-of-the-gorgon-gas-project/106105984</link><description>The works will connect gas fields in the Greater Gorgon Area to existing infrastructure on Barrow Island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6605d42224c13ea286e827760abcd918</guid></item><item><title>Elderly Perth accountant Joseph Papalia jailed for stealing millions from friends, family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/joseph-papalia-jailed-stealing-friends-family/106108306</link><description>An elderly Perth accountant who stole nearly $10 million from family, friends and former clients is jailed for more than 11 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de8efe4100d4713e558357614abf8a48</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106109020</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8322d7a43d0a8d690dd3f63ac6a19b7</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Usman Khawaja's Test future questioned as Travis Head, Jake Weatherald open at Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/usman-khawaja-test-future-ashes-travis-head-jake-weatherald/106107710</link><description>After another slashing partnership between openers Travis Head and Jake Weatherald, the future of Usman Khawaja in the Test arena appears to be getting murkier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d23b20fc5430b142af6fa84641c3d79a</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania Devils could play extra year in existing venues during Macquarie Point stadium construction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/tasmania-devils-prepared-to-wait-for-stadium-afl/106105976</link><description>The Tasmania Devils CEO says the club will likely play in the AFL from existing venues for a year longer than expected, while awaiting construction of the Macquarie Point stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54590a0bd459a15b3d2cf0dc2fb1bb57</guid></item><item><title>Rory McIlroy nervously avoids Australian Open cut as Min Woo Lee lights up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/australian-open-mcilroy-avoids-cut-lee-scott-impress/106104592</link><description>Much to the relief of tournament organisers and his legion of fans, Rory McIlroy survives to fight another day at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">924b88f663c80d133e8ff23959c91d46</guid></item><item><title>Cary-Hiroyuki Tagawa, actor who performed in Mortal Kombat, has died at 75</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/cary-hiroyuki-tagawa-died-at-75/106109270</link><description>Tagawa died surrounded by his family in Santa Barbara from complications due to a stroke, according to his manager Margie Weiner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f2505d88563bec72acd402c8981f1fa</guid></item><item><title>Gocs cameo leaves Smith starstruck, England mourns dropped catches, Weatherald winks — five quick hits from Ashes second Test day two</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ashes-second-test-day-two-gocs-smith-archer-head/106107888</link><description>Steve Smith is starstruck by a surprise cameo, England rues a slew of drops and Jake Weatherald announces his arrival with a wink. Here are the quick hits from the second day of the pink-ball Ashes Test in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fca052ae07b72821a3591793d738cec2</guid></item><item><title>Jacob Elordi, Nicole Kidman, Alison Brie among the 2026 AACTA nominees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/aacta-nominations-2026-jacob-elordi-nicole-kidman/106101160</link><description>Apple Cider Vinegar, a partly fictionalised retelling of accused wellness scammer Belle Gibson's public fall from grace, leads this year's AACTA nominations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95d35035fb82bef329f01389c5ded03f</guid></item><item><title>WA Police charge children over Geraldton bushfire that destroyed home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/geraldton-bushfire-police-lay-charges/106109634</link><description>WA Police allege young boys were responsible for lighting a fire in Geraldton last weekend that later reignited and destroyed a home in an outer suburb of the Mid West city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26a6ef4372cdf369a5ed6f71699e208d</guid></item><item><title>Netflix wins deal to buy Warner Bros's film and TV studio and streaming service for $108bn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/netflix-buys-warner-film-and-television-unit/106109630</link><description>The merger will see beloved shows and movies such as The Big Bang Theory, Game of Thrones and The Wizard of Oz join Netflix’s portfolio.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">981ddc6ccc5d007d5023ffd52e9e62d2</guid></item><item><title>Porridge back on the menu as budget pressures grow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/budget-pressures-anika-wells-peter-costello-porridge-senate/106088014</link><description>How does a treasurer tell households the government will no longer continue a $300 energy rebate when it's happy to blow $100,000 on three flights?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9275c262e4575f63a63a407e008ac21</guid></item><item><title>Russian manpower challenges Ukraine's technological edge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/russia-ukraine-drones-europe-warfare-technology-weapons/106088044</link><description>When it comes to weaponry, Russia has strength in manpower despite Ukraine's early technological edge while Europe's arms production efforts are running into infrastructure hurdles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1265c860b9aa0cca74479ed0aaf2a6e</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 6: The day scientists found evidence of water on Mars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/today-in-history-december-6-water-on-mars/106096326</link><description>Scientists said at the time that the flow of water would have filled multiple swimming pools.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">054766de87b60e22cc18569655b05e35</guid></item><item><title>Lebanon says it's trying to disarm Hezbollah but fears sparking internal conflict</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/hezbollah-refuses-to-disarm-as-israel-bombs-lebanon/106105328</link><description>Lebanon's government says it is trying to disarm militant group Hezbollah, but there are fears of sparking an internal conflict.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08ff3200b8808497c7b511f7adb8cdda</guid></item><item><title>Senator who backs social media ban says she was a victim of a catfishing attempt in high school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/youngest-senator-reveals-she-was-catfished-online/106107346</link><description>As the social media ban for teens looms, the parliament's most recent senator reveals she knows firsthand the dangers that can confront young people online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36f20c5139f55ad3d007ff21ef249880</guid></item><item><title>Australia delights in a familiar Ashes tale of English woe to take control at the Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/australia-delights-in-a-familar-tale-of-english-woe-at-the-gabba/106109124</link><description>Australia took control of the second Ashes Test at the Gabba on a day that carried plenty of the hallmarks of failed English tours of yesteryear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19c15eaa8e29f069a6d5569366cc2322</guid></item><item><title>Vladimir Putin offers India 'uninterrupted' fuel supplies at summit in New Delhi with Narendra Modi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/vladimir-putin-offers-india-uninterrupted-fuel-supplies/106109824</link><description>The offer is made at a summit in New Delhi, where new deals on energy, agriculture and labour have also been announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b238a3fa21ca446dc7aa3c074f7c98b</guid></item><item><title>Under deadline, Donald Trump is remaking the White House in his own image</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/donald-trump-is-remaking-the-white-house-in-his-own-image/105552330</link><description>The US president has spent much of his first year back in office changing the historic building he fought to reclaim in a bid to cement his legacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f4b9ceff316e49e4842fbae903137c2</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide Strikers - Hobart Hurricanes WBBL match called off due to hole in the pitch after ball goes under roller</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/hole-in-adelaide-pitch-complicates-wbbl-finals-puzzle/106109872</link><description>The Adelaide-Hobart WBBL match has to be abandoned after a ball goes under the roller during the innings break, creating a hole in the pitch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b795c8f5b7bd995ab59a5ef2d2d5177</guid></item><item><title>It's been a tumultuous time for SA's Liberals — they now need to find another new leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/sa-liberal-party-new-leader-analysis/106108800</link><description>SA Liberal leader Vincent Tarzia has stepped down. Pressure had been mounting in the lead-up to the 2026 state election, and predictions for the Liberal Party's chances are not looking promising.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">712c9410084cf6a74ba0ca3ce24a92a2</guid></item><item><title>First-aid advice for venomous bites and stings at your fingertips with new app</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/australian-bites-stings-app-provides-emergency-first-aid-advice/106100610</link><description>As a new app is launched to provide first-aid advice for venomous bites and stings, a reptile expert urges people to learn how to respond in an emergency ahead of an expected spike in demand for antivenom over summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ac170200b55d76f51f1e86dd2f9539b</guid></item><item><title>BNPB supply drop to remote village in North Sumatra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/bnpb-supply-drop-to-remote-village-in-north-sumatra/106109106</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9079a40c3d67c71d43b9ed7cf3e8e733</guid></item><item><title>Efforts turn to helping survivors and recovering the dead after devastating floods in Indonesia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/indonesia-sumatra-floods-landslides-weather-recovery-efforts/106097076</link><description>Landslides across Sumatra in Indonesia have cut off roads and destroyed homes, creating several pockets of isolated villages where a helicopter is the only way in.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a73b3e2b1904da69e708162f515043ac</guid></item><item><title>Sexism, harassment and inflexibility drive women out of winemaking, survey reveals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/sexism-harassment-driving-women-out-of-winemaking/106092352</link><description>Among the main factors contributing to women leaving Australia's wine industry were sexism, discrimination, and a lack of flexibility, a nationwide study has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">094e243fb1468c4e673b13fdb1a2a964</guid></item><item><title>Australian Christmas in full bloom as flora and fauna burst with colour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/christmas-flora-and-fauna/106105702</link><description>As the summer heat settles in, flora and fauna associated with Christmas in Australia can be spotted throughout the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f8a1842054bfafbb5f4f2081770f575</guid></item><item><title>State Theatre's new name speaks to the philanthropy predicament in the arts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/arts-funding-philanthropy-melbourne-state-theatre-ian-potter/106088052</link><description>No sensible organisation can now afford to turn down money or its requirements. So, cash-strapped institutions find themselves between a rock and a hard place with a big name painted on it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d39e9f43068b001c6ce3e2e947fdcc11</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane community radio station 4ZZZ celebrates 50 years against all odds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/4zzz-brisbane-radio-station-50-years/106101658</link><description>Brisbane community radio station 4ZZZ has withstood political, social and financial pressure for 50 years and it's still thriving as a loud and proud beacon of counterculture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1532fda67974c3d08f8e86892a5ce3e2</guid></item><item><title>Young people urged to join stem cell donor roll with full matches hard to come by</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/stem-cell-donor-campaign-rowan-tong-law/106086354</link><description>Rowan Tong-Law, 18, was diagnosed with acute myeloid leukaemia last year and has been searching for a full stem cell donor match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7619250c0c8fe5a61dbd35854893da66</guid></item><item><title>Woman's two-year journey advocating for Auslan support highlights cracks in aged care system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/deaf-seniors-falling-through-aged-care-cracks/106084008</link><description>One Deaf woman living with dementia has been without basic care services for two years. Advocates warn her story represents a much larger problem.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">857456218e73eb03ba41a265e65343e3</guid></item><item><title>English teenager Tommy Lamb closing in on 100-day, 21-country overland journey to Adelaide's Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/tommy-lamb-ashes-trip-to-adelaide-manchester/106109176</link><description>Tommy Lamb is taking the long way from Manchester to Adelaide for the third Ashes Test and the 18-year is closing in on a 100-day odyssey that must be seen to be believed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fef5110c9f56da13b3f39f394c0576b0</guid></item><item><title>Man, 33, charged with murder of woman in southern Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/man-charged-with-murder-over-womans-death/106109858</link><description>Police found the woman's body on Friday afternoon on Hobart's eastern shore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e1de6b5551030220ab2d3355568b41a</guid></item><item><title>When will construction begin on the new Hobart stadium?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/what-is-next-for-approved-hobart-afl-stadium/106105676</link><description>That and other questions answered now that the $1.13 billion stadium project has passed Tasmania's parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">498c74d67f1a43d39e7bfef08a626fee</guid></item><item><title>BOM says 'threshold' for fire weather warning wasn't met ahead of Tasmanian bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/bom-warnings-ahead-of-bushfires-across-tasmania/106105962</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says the initial forecasts did not meet the threshold to trigger fire weather warnings ahead of Thursday when 30 blazes burnt across Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c246f885887b104140d861380f48ad7</guid></item><item><title>Cameron Smith adopting simple approach at Australian Open as he chases victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/australian-open-golf-cameron-smith-chasing-victory/106109936</link><description>Cameron Smith did not beat around the bush when explaining how he plans to be among the contenders to claim the Australian Open at Royal Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55b6254e2df9df70d7c80d722878b011</guid></item><item><title>Coronial inquest investigates Terry Airey's death at Sunshine Coast University Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/coronial-inquest-investigates-terry-airey-death/106090278</link><description>A Queensland hospital has increased staffing and revamped its radiology protocols and systems following an 87-year-old's death from organ failure after routine surgery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bbe0dfc8c2f6c068198bdae68e0b6d1</guid></item><item><title>Life on the APY Lands where family, country and culture are protected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/apy-lands-culture-lifestyle-protected-but-calls-for-houses-jobs/105999584</link><description>The stark beauty of Australia's protected APY Lands is alive with ancient songlines and culture. But Elders see a need for change to secure the future of today's children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">353653a4d89cd1c2c5636c30029525d0</guid></item><item><title>Notorious child murderer Bevan Spencer von Einem dies in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/murderer-bevan-von-einem-dies-while-serving-life-sentence/106052480</link><description>Convicted killer Bevan Spencer von Einem — who police have linked to "The Family" — has died while serving a life sentence for the sexually motivated abduction and murder of Richard Kelvin in 1983.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f21bf483c5402b57f6074aec904c7897</guid></item><item><title>Frank Gehry, world-renowned architect who designed the Guggenheim Museum Bilbao, dies aged 96</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/frank-gehry-guggenheim-bilbao-dies-aged-96/106109892</link><description>Gehry's most memorable creations were either celebrated as works of genius or reviled as self-indulgent messes — but either way, people were looking, as he liked to say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecfb4aee4144b1097d9f9d29ef26c3fc</guid></item><item><title>Blue whale swimming off Busselton Jetty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/blue-whale-swimming-off-busselton-jetty/106105306</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d10be79b81cc7f5bcfab5c804d73069</guid></item><item><title>Blue whale calf numbers rise after slow migration start along WA's south west coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/baby-blue-whale-numbers-wa-south-west-coast/106104766</link><description>Researchers are relieved as baby blue whale numbers increase after a slow start to the migration season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce2461b0ebf884ba690caf4fa73f245f</guid></item><item><title>Blue whales off Dunsborough</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/cow-and-calf-blue-whale/106106620</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2679d706e21deadabffe76fdbb7dce0</guid></item><item><title>This tasty, veggie-filled omlette is a fast and satisfying meal - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/ejjeh-zucchini-omelette/106102824</link><description>Ejjeh is a traditional omelette made with eggs, herbs, spices and that soft zucchini flesh that would otherwise go to waste. It's simple, fresh and full of flavour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77fef1ae7c6da366ad1c89e922b140e5</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos found in new Edith Cowan University campus in Perth CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/asbestos-found-in-new-ecu-campus-in-perth-cbd/106109070</link><description>WA's parliament is told asbestos has been discovered in fire doors at Edith Cowan University's flagship new campus in Perth's CBD, and it won't be removed until after the first semester next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59fb25929fe3469ce6ffd2b649633c6f</guid></item><item><title>The National Indigenous Art Triennial in Canberra reflects on legacy, rebirth and renewal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/national-indigenous-art-triennial-after-the-rain-tony-albert/106105020</link><description>Indigenous artists from across Australia, including Alair Pambegan and Grace Kemarre Robinya, feature as part of the National Indigenous Art Triennial in Canberra: After the Rain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">298d22642d30f831c89ee4391ea7cd3c</guid></item><item><title>Up to 16 homes lost in Bulahdelah and Koolewong fires in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/strong-winds-intense-heat-thunderstorms-nsw/106109226</link><description>More than 1,500 firefighters with 300 vehicles were deployed by the RFS across eastern and central NSW amid extreme heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97594e0790a4e0dbae88468a24108d86</guid></item><item><title>Bunbury Indigenous elders write children's book in Noongar language to preserve culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/noongar-kala-bunbury-aboriginal-elders-south-west-wa/106101058</link><description>Once forbidden from speaking their local language, a group of Indigenous elders in WA use it in a children's book, hoping to breathe life into a dying dialect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8c8164c0eeec9b3ba3ab586b29b8bad</guid></item><item><title>Residents still unable to return home as north-east Victoria bushfire continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/markwood-fire-recovery-houses-lost/106110100</link><description>North-east Victorian residents are still unable to return home as firefighters assess bushfire damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b13e50e22ebfcfa29edd47ab97b690b5</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate hikes increasingly likely in 2026 but a major event would produce the opposite result</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/interest-rates-2026/106106712</link><description>Inflation is a problem as 2025 comes to a close and it's set to remain that way. Without a swift rise in productivity or a financial markets meltdown, borrowers are facing several interest rate hikes next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d746d4688a4127389fb3a4b35770ed4</guid></item><item><title>An RFS Chinook flies above the Bulahdelah fire on the Mid North Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/rfs-chinook-flies-above-the-bulahdelah-fire/106110314</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dad630d4115bb5b48c742b0992b7287e</guid></item><item><title>Controversial genetically modified mosquito release paused after backlash in Qld</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/controversial-gm-friendly-mosquito-release-paused-csiro-oxitec/106108190</link><description>An organisation that planned to sell "friendly" mosquitoes to reduce the spread of diseases like dengue withdraws its licence application after backlash from scientists and health experts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99c152b0ac25af67c26215182860c9d9</guid></item><item><title>Malaysian football in chaos after FIFA suspends national players from Argentina, Spain and Brazil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/player-naturalisation-scandal-rocks-malaysian-football/106095646</link><description>A football players' union says seven South American and European members of the Malaysian national team suspended over allegedly forged documents are "victims".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4856b0aaec28e11010c2f73e3c63280</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos far from a World Cup 'group of death' against United States, Paraguay and a European qualifier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/socceroos-world-cup-draw-analysis/106110310</link><description>Nothing can be guaranteed in a World Cup, but the Socceroos' draw alongside the United States, Paraguay and a European qualifier gives a solid shot at advancing, with the Australians avoiding most of the big names.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49c5d81bdd2e928aa1bc4fde8d7d5a0b</guid></item><item><title>2025 US National Security Strategy warns Europe faces 'civilisational erasure', does not mention AUKUS</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/trump-warns-europe-faces-civilisational-erasure/106109888</link><description>The Trump administration releases a document saying its goal is to "help Europe correct its current trajectory", adding that it faces "civilisational erasure" due in part to "mass migration".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">031ccdcf7ac49d6c2a4eaf559d9d572f</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025 updates: Mitchell Starc's all-round brilliance puts Australia on the verge of 2-0 series lead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/ashes-second-test-live-gabba-day-three-australia-vs-england/106110146</link><description>Mitchell Starc and Scott Boland torment England with both bat and ball as Australia puts itself on the verge of claiming a 2-0 series lead in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d64b4e80361f254db5f9a88be54a499e</guid></item><item><title>Whale researchers in Timor-Leste are calling for regulation of the whale watching industry following reports of operators piloting boats too close to mammals.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/whale-tourism-in-timor-leste/106108468</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">234a2971d877726ad7e5837065f4dfeb</guid></item><item><title>Rory McIlroy's Australian Open tilt hindered by discarded banana skin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/australian-open-golf-rory-mcilroy-banana-skin-third-round/106109898</link><description>Inclement weather is not the only challenge Rory McIlroy faced on his way to shooting a three-under-par 68 in the third round of the Australian Open at Royal Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d596c2f754d69973f2ccca4bc0300f50</guid></item><item><title>The gold toilet, the bags of cash and the corruption still stalking Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/latest-corruption-allegations-a-headache-for-zelenskyy/106048496</link><description>Ukraine has a history of corruption issues, but the latest allegations include close confidants of the president and many people want answers from Volodymyr Zelenskyy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">150e0fc94af50740baa09c3494745ca2</guid></item><item><title>Critics choice nominations 2026: Sinners scores 17 nods, One Battle After Another earns 14</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/critics-choice-awards-nominations-sinner/106110372</link><description>The gothic vampire period drama Sinners has topped the Critics' Choice Movie Awards, securing 17 nods, followed by One Battle After Another with 14.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a30900a46808c056c75a85fb6601196e</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government to pump $200 million into racing facilities under long-awaited industry plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/qld-government-racing-report-independent-review/106110228</link><description>The Next Lap plan will establish a $200 million infrastructure fund, streamline governance, and maintain taxation levels, and comes about two months after an independent review into the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">546690db480bac34e24c47bb307f1dbf</guid></item><item><title>Geraldton community raises funds and thanks responders as juveniles charged with alleged arson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/juveniles-charged-with-alleged-arson-following-geraldton-fires/106110454</link><description>While police say the investigation is over, the local community is still trying to move forward from the devastation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4122eb9d5167b06fe6f887df21b32420</guid></item><item><title>Jai Opetaia beats Hüseyin Cinkara in cruiserweight world title fight, Jason Moloney claims victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/live-updates-jai-opetaia-vs-huseyin-cinkara-boxing/106109620</link><description>Jai Opetaia defends his IBF and The Ring cruiserweight world titles against Hüseyin Cinkara with a savage knock out on the Gold Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">945a3204a0f94369d635a361f6e6d44f</guid></item><item><title>Cameron Smith leaps into Australian Open contention, Min Woo Lee and Adam Scott in the mix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/australian-open-cameron-smith-min-woo-lee-third-round/106110698</link><description>Cameron Smith is only two shots off the lead heading into the final round of the Australian Open, while Min Woo Lee and Adam Scott remain in the hunt at Royal Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd90928582c53778fb1c0caaf78fbcce</guid></item><item><title>Teen seriously injured in e-bike crash in Claremont after e-rideables inquiry called for widespread changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/teen-seriously-injured-in-ebike-crash-in-claremont/106110818</link><description>A 14-year-old boy suffers serious injuries in an e-bike crash in Perth's western suburbs, just two days after a parliamentary inquiry into WA's e-rideable laws made 33 recommendations in a bid to make the devices safer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beba62eb0654ea9ca6f7cebcd2e680cf</guid></item><item><title>Not all babies need a hepatitis B shot at birth, US vaccine advisers say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/us-vaccine-advisers-say-not-all-babies-need-a-hepatitis-b-shot/106110932</link><description>President Donald Trump is calling the vote a "very good decision" after US vaccine advisers recommended ending the universal hepatitis B shots at birth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df40efa82146c8a5f6816b5bc09ffc1b</guid></item><item><title>Overnight fire exchange at Afghan-Pakistan border kills five and wounds eight, officials say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/overnight-fire-exchange-at-afghan-pakistan-border-kills-five/106110986</link><description>Each side has blamed the other for triggering the clash in violation of a tenuous two-month ceasefire, with the clashes lasting until dawn Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fa740808b4ac6ddc330d6757423b6ce</guid></item><item><title>Archer's English pillow, Starc's top score and a couple of firsts for England — quick hits from day three of the Gabba Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/ashes-gabba-test-day-three-england-australia-quick-hits/106110492</link><description>A sleepy Jofra Archer cops a rinsing from Matthew Hayden, as the English finally make it through the first over of an innings. Here are the quick hits from day three of the Gabba Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c64f50b01ae250aec71536d3473f161</guid></item><item><title>India caps airfares as IndiGo flight cancellations leave hundreds stranded for fifth day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/indigo-crisis-leaves-hundreds-stranded-for-fifth-day/106111066</link><description>Thousands of IndiGo flights were cancelled this week due to a pilot shortage, which prompted government relief and extra trains to help stranded passengers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4173d35614de3272efdd6155eee80dc6</guid></item><item><title>Opposition to social media ban scores minor political points at best</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/social-media-age-ban-albanese-government-sussan-ley-opposition/106097916</link><description>Australia's social media age ban is one of the most significant attempts to rebalance the asymmetric power relationship between government and tech.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1c19bd7f93be3f2eab79e2f3c0e9566</guid></item><item><title>Politicians in South-East Asia ignore climate change at their own political peril</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/floods-thailand-climate-leadership-monsoon-torrential-rain/106097870</link><description>Accused of incompetence and apathy in the aftermath of natural disasters, governments across Asia are facing increasing backlash as the impact of global warming intensifies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17caf11fe4eac45fbe9ce13a3ecbccb6</guid></item><item><title>With the execution of Charles Brooks Jr, lethal injection became the death penalty standard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/today-in-history-december-7-leathal-injection/106031372</link><description>On this day in history, the US carried out its first execution by lethal injection — a method thought up by one doctor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ca1fd94b04940bb6186fc3a62a03018</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: So, you think you're good at quizzes? It's time to play HARD!</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/106090792</link><description>Alright, show us what you've got. I'll keep my expectations low.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1614ab325a4465d488e9f23ca9b12335</guid></item><item><title>Gearing up for the school holidays? Here's how to survive them without social media</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/social-media-ban-school-holidays-parenting-children/106018636</link><description>These school holidays, children under 16 will find themselves with less social media access as a ban comes into place. We asked the experts how parents can best support their kids with the transition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df818395897eaf31c4423307fd9381fe</guid></item><item><title>How pregnancy is being criminalised in post-Roe America</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/pregnancy-criminalisation-abortion-fetal-personhood-miscarriage/106097546</link><description>In the wake of widespread abortion bans, US prosecutors launch hundreds of cases charging people with crimes related to their pregnancy, miscarriage, stillbirth or birth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b40d723313a028093c154415c269b698</guid></item><item><title>What life's like when you're Deaf and blind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/a-deafblind-day-in-the-life/105789718</link><description>Living with vision impairment throws up many challenges. Being Deaf on top of that requires you to go to even greater lengths just to fit in with the modern world. This is how one Deafblind woman does it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a956beee6b8ee94b7a2d6c74a16d9d78</guid></item><item><title>Rare piece of Australia's Indigenous history captured on camera in the desert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/aboriginal-elders-historical-photo-of-first-contact-lost/106010316</link><description>In the 1960s, the last of the desert families were coming into contact with white people. For one woman, the moment was captured on camera.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7abee498779fc3abfdd1edf31be65f7a</guid></item><item><title>Russia's claim it has captured key Ukrainian city could be Putin 'scaremongering'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/russian-claim-it-has-captured-pokrovsk-could-be-scaremongering/106099458</link><description>Russian President Vladimir Putin this week claimed Moscow's biggest battlefield gain in close to two years: the Ukrainian city of Pokrovsk. Some experts don't believe him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c91a557935861d797674d13560ce1b3b</guid></item><item><title>Republicans just won an election in Tennessee but it's still bad news for Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/tennessee-special-election-van-epps-behn/106106326</link><description>A Republican claimed a win at a by-election in Tennessee this week, but his party colleagues are sounding alarm bells.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd1c905795a22c1d914b665c6c9e82aa</guid></item><item><title>Australia senses Ashes kill as England and Bazball face day of reckoning at the Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/judgement-day-arrives-for-bazball-australia-moves-in-for-kill/106110882</link><description>Australia was patient, mature and ruthless on day three at the Gabba, widening the chasm between it and an England side now set for its day of reckoning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d6ade1bbdc1dcdabd936b05843d9f68</guid></item><item><title>Reedy Creek Reserve's Paperbark Forest Walk in Agnes Water closed after tourist and environment concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/agnes-water-reedy-creek-reserve-closed-paperbark-walk/106100738</link><description>Bush Heritage Australia says it is still considering how to safely reopen the walk, which prior to closure was being visited by 100,000 people a year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17e00acf204351a585a62c7e2fea5b8e</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne council responds to lunch-thieving seagulls knocking food from pedestrians' hands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/seagulls-learn-to-knock-food-from-peoples-hands/106043826</link><description>Pesky seagulls snatching food from unsuspecting members of the public has spurred a Melbourne council to start canine patrols of Federation Square.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7f4a5d7dbae1847da8ae3200e1e7d33</guid></item><item><title>'Less algal influence' seen in some SA waters, divers say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/divers-notice-improved-marine-conditions-algal-bloom/106090962</link><description>Open water divers say underwater visibility has improved and marine life is returning to some areas off South Australia's coast. Experts say it's a positive sign, but warn it's "way too early" to say the environment is recovering from the state's algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfad2cccdd7bf4dc93dddc21091b37d3</guid></item><item><title>Number of homes destroyed in NSW bushfires rises to at least 20 as recovery efforts begin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/sixteen-homes-lost-koolewong-central-coast-fire-but-maybe-more/106110700</link><description>Natural disasters are declared in six areas across NSW, as the number of homes destroyed rises to at least 20, with the majority concentrated on the Central Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f545b09a363eca4e348ed86afcb4cacf</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri qualifies third for Abu Dhabi F1 Grand Prix, behind rivals Max Verstappen and Lando Norris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/piastri-only-third-verstappen-takes-pole-for-f1-finale-abu-dhabi/106111500</link><description>Oscar Piastri warns he's not out of the Formula One title hunt yet, even if many only now have eyes on a Lando Norris-Max Verstappen duel for the crown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d778222828df96a3c4c0c6798717f29</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians in West Bank's Bethlehem hold first Christmas tree lighting ceremony since 2022</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/christmas-tree-lighting-ceremony-in-bethlehem-2025/106111514</link><description>As the ceasefire in Gaza enters its second month, the Palestinian city revered by Christians as the birthplace of Jesus holds a ceremony to light up a 20-metre tree at the edge of Manger Square.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c3f868b55d8496e879c05c64cdec9cc</guid></item><item><title>Criminals are trying new methods to get drugs into Australia but authorities say they are always watching</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/attempted-drug-imports-sea-australia-mothership-smuggling/106073102</link><description>The alleged use of an international livestock ship to smuggle drugs into Western Australia last month prompted a media storm, but one expert says it is just one among a "dizzying variety" of methods criminals are trying.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4191a2f6367c22bebf14314f40b9247</guid></item><item><title>Water leaks, electric shocks force 32yo breast cancer unit off road in Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/breast-cancer-screening-bus-pulled-after-staff-electric-shocks/106090358</link><description>Tasmania's health department was aware a 32-year-old breast cancer screening bus was unsafe for years, but continued operating it up until two staff suffered electric shocks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ff63e98eda12f40f8dbbd4beb2606a5</guid></item><item><title>Insurance doctor never spoke to traumatised former NSW Police officer before challenging his mental health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/nsw-police-officer-with-ptsd-wins-insurance-case-amid-battle/106093472</link><description>A former NSW Police officer with post-traumatic stress disorder had his mental health incorrectly challenged by a doctor who never consulted or examined him during a year-long battle with the force's insurer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d5e4694754c274d6be22a3bcd766afc</guid></item><item><title>Parents urged to learn the rules about e-mobility devices as Christmas approaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/qld-e-bike-warning-for-parents-ahead-of-christmas/106090258</link><description>An e-bike will be top of their Christmas wish list this year, prompting a warning for parents to know the rules.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d8bd0d76bcfd6c2b5ddda674946abd2</guid></item><item><title>Housing squeeze hits first responders looking for homes in Noosa region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/first-responders-struggling-to-find-a-home-in-noosa/106095684</link><description>First responders say they are having to live well outside their operating regions due to lack of available housing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1a0f49e9e3897bd6e86f9929e8dd859</guid></item><item><title>Michael Neser takes two key England wickets with caught-and-bowleds as Australia in Ashes command</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/caught-and-bowled-king-neser-feared-his-test-career-was-over/106111568</link><description>Bowling all-rounder Michael Neser is back and taking vital wickets after beginning to think he had played his last Test match for Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34ca06f197f5d99c18fee149bc7f6cce</guid></item><item><title>QVMAG costs Launceston ratepayers millions of dollars every year, but there are fears reform has hit a wall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/qvmag-launceston-future-reform/106053812</link><description>More than three years after a Tasmanian council green-lit a plan to ease the financial burden of the Queen Victoria Museum and Art Gallery, stakeholders worry momentum has stalled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c2d4c946fd4053b35bac4240de05654</guid></item><item><title>Aged care in Australia under the microscope in new documentary Careless</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/careless-documentary-film-aged-care-australia-sue-thomson/106100558</link><description>Filmmaker Sue Thomson recently lost her mum. But before that, they made the beautiful documentary Careless together, which explores Australia's aged care system mess.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7eecf0bd88b748e1bbea443583c5e1e4</guid></item><item><title>Western Australia's Port Hedland marks 50th anniversary of Cyclone Joan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/cyclone-joan-remembered-50-years-on/106105218</link><description>Cyclone Joan made landfall near the WA mining town of Port Hedland a year after Cyclone Tracy flattened Darwin, and it was almost as powerful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07b2549729e7a97acaf7b3f01384c184</guid></item><item><title>Russian drone, missile attacks target Ukrainian railways and power infrastructure in overnight barrage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/russia-attacks-ukrainian-energy-infrastructure/106111570</link><description>A large-scale Russian drone and missile attack damages power facilities in eight Ukrainian regions, causing blackouts and forcing nuclear power plants to cut output.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9e28d3b538b262a66c7d54959ae2fe5</guid></item><item><title>Fire jumps a kilometre over water, disaster declared for NSW regions — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/heatwaves-fire-live-blog-december-6/106110894</link><description>NSW Premier Chris Minns says it has been a "difficult 24 hours", with more than 20 fires still uncontained across the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c18a4d1320eaa2ffec3079f7378c5589</guid></item><item><title>Researchers are teaching foxes not to eat freshwater turtle eggs, by making them feel sick</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/training-foxes-to-stop-killing-native-turtles-aversion-condition/106026320</link><description>Researchers in Victoria are using taste aversion conditioning to stop foxes eating native turtle eggs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">904402fb27dc1fd3146ccac2d254e7e0</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos FIFA World Cup 2026 times, dates and locations set, with games in Vancouver, Seattle and Santa Clara</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/socceroos-set-for-wild-west-north-american-world-cup-adventure/106111662</link><description>Australia's North American west coast adventure at the World Cup is confirmed, with matches in Vancouver, Seattle and Santa Clara in California.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7aaff72b6b041c20050aa4cde13783c</guid></item><item><title>Australia's new land clearing, regrowth laws spark concern among farmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/farmer-concerns-as-australian-land-clearing-laws-tighten/106104878</link><description>Queensland producers say a blanket approach to environmental laws will restrict their ability to manage land sustainably and responsibly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbd94438aad374b26c5da2a12aabe40c</guid></item><item><title>Prime minister's office approved Anika Wells's almost-$100,000 flights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/pmo-approved-wells-flights/106111598</link><description>The furore over Communications Minister Anika Wells's expenses continues, with just three days until the government's much-anticipated social media ban for under 16s comes into force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee55c4ecfec6b883eecfce1559d5f1b5</guid></item><item><title>Iconic Lagoon restaurant lease ends after 40 colourful and controversial years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/wollongong-iconic-lagoon-restaurant-lease-ends/106077292</link><description>For four decades Lagoon Restaurant has been one of Wollongong's most iconic and controversial establishments, enjoying a prime seaside location and a close relationship with the city's political class.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43794c1266f909517717039f3c339315</guid></item><item><title>Surf Life Saving WA brings all-abilities nippers program to regions for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/regional-first-for-all-abilities-nippers-surf-lifesaving/106093904</link><description>Catering to children with autism spectrum disorders, it is the first of its kind in regional Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08a0fa804bc4bd0a70cb58c4f3aad91a</guid></item><item><title>Cleveland Dodd inquest findings expected to unpack dysfunction in WA's youth justice system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/coroner-to-hand-down-cleveland-dodd-inquest-findings-/106105718</link><description>The coroner investigating WA’s first recorded death in youth detention is expected to hand down wide-ranging findings and recommendations following the death of 16-year-old Cleveland Dodd in 2022. Here's everything you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47288d99a3815da2fad534c77f62d2f9</guid></item><item><title>Perth Scorchers book WBBL finals spot with seven-wicket win over winless Brisbane Heat at the WACA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/scorchers-book-finals-spot-with-renegades-wbbl-defence-over/106111830</link><description>Beth Mooney's flawless 94 not out leads Perth to victory in its must-win game against Brisbane, ensuring the Scorchers will play finals again in the WBBL.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87f96387164efe42f678dbbec451dfd0</guid></item><item><title>Aerial view of bushfire destruction in northern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/aerial-view-of-bushfire-destruction-in-northern-nsw/106111894</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73a8f5b5ea93981b016a93ba7d568bdc</guid></item><item><title>Firefighting aircraft battle raging bushfires in northern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/firefighting-helicopters-battle-raging-bushfires-in-northern-nsw/106111892</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aacacb1a2f4512d4ae24f606b7415f35</guid></item><item><title>Bridget Murphy reports from fire ground in Redhead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/bridget-murphy-reports-from-fire-ground-in-redhead-/106111864</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53bd446aa3217d3c748c96da76357dc1</guid></item><item><title>At least 11 killed in South Africa hostel shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/at-least-11-killed-in-south-africa-hostel-shooting/106111814</link><description>Gunmen stormed a hostel in the early hours of the morning, shooting 25 people at the scene and killing at least 11 people, including three children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">953ce720c4b1004159c2f44281d334b4</guid></item><item><title>Train derailment closes Townsville-Mount Isa rail line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/train-derailment-closes-townsville-mount-isa-rail-line/106110724</link><description>A train locomotive is on its side and two others are off the track after a derailment on the Townsville to Mount Isa rail line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e15f34952dcbb39082e8bd05b54ba98</guid></item><item><title>Child of Stolen Generations in WA given her birth certificate after 88 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/stolen-generation-survivor-given-birth-certificate/106074930</link><description>Maisie Harkin was born on country in Western Australia's Great Victoria Desert. It has taken 88 years for her birth to be officially recognised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62e588a6410a278cd6b6455bf3e6e671</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters battle blaze in Redhead, Lake Macquarie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/firefighters-battle-blaze-in-redhead-lake-macquarie/106112010</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11fe15b5b4fe13e9b2f945014afb97dc</guid></item><item><title>Four arrested after food thrown at Crown Jewels display case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/four-arrested-after-food-thrown-at-crown-jewels-display/106111940</link><description>An organisation called Take Back Power, which describes itself as a civil resistance group, posted footage of the incident on social media and said two of its members had smothered the Imperial State Crown display case with apple crumble and custard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6548036014f4b677aeaddf17bdf3eeb</guid></item><item><title>Protesters throw apple crumble at State Crown display in London</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/protesters-throw-apple-crumble-at-state-crown-display-in-london/106112050</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2ccba64ad49b6adab749a2b5463474f</guid></item><item><title>Concerns for the future of Canberra's public pools amid closures and redevelopments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/canberra-public-pool-lovers-concerned-about-future/106110222</link><description>As temperatures soar, advocates of public pools in Canberra say they want to see greater support and investment for facilities in the national capital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4eb3e09e4377b3f87e10776d2cb6cf95</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025 live updates: Steve Smith and Jofra Archer in fiery clash as Australia wins second Test by eight wickets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/ashes-live-gabba-test-day-four-australia-vs-england/106111832</link><description>Australian captain Steve Smith lets his bat do the talking following a fiery exchange with Jofra Archer in an eight-wicket win in the second Test in Brisbane. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f1b74fe8e3fff6ef045a8fd32663c93</guid></item><item><title>The $108 billion Warner Bros and Netflix deal has sparked backlash — here's why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/what-the-netflix-warner-bros-merger-means-amid-controversy/106111948</link><description>A major deal between Netflix and Warner Bros has sent shock waves through Hollywood and sparked backlash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c5b49941b708628215a93a2b57a70ed</guid></item><item><title>Ashton Hurn to run for SA Liberal leadership following Tarzia departure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/frank-pangallo-on-leadership-as-liberal-mps-back-ashton-hurn/106110202</link><description>South Australian Liberal frontbencher Ashton Hurn will run for her party's leadership, following the shock resignation of Vincent Tarzia just months out from the next state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf9963dcfec459a7ef2f9625a2955b3d</guid></item><item><title>Unpause and rewind: Cassette tapes are making a comeback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/cassette-tapes-are-making-a-comeback/106102136</link><description>For a supposedly obsolete music format, audio cassette sales seem to be set on fast forward at the moment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44b393e1bbc4bba401dd313c21117f0c</guid></item><item><title>South Australian distillers tap into trending thirst for limoncello</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/limoncello-tradition-trend-alcohol-south-australia/106077938</link><description>South Australian distillers are tapping into a growing global thirst for limoncello and finding a new market for lemons and grape spirit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eac2197d4c58b3bca193cfa97b9fc4c2</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania Fire Service confirms 19 homes destroyed and nearly 200 assets damaged in Dolphin Sands bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/dolphin-sands-residents-weigh-up-bushfire-risk/106111658</link><description>The Tasmania Fire Service confirms 19 homes have been claimed by a bushfire that ripped through Dolphin Sands this week, while nearly 200 assets have been damaged.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26ee56f15a04beadc995bbad8e91369f</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Sixers sneak home in final-ball thriller against Adelaide Strikers to secure WBBL finals spot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/wbbl-match-report-sixers-win-thriller/106112112</link><description>Ellyse Perry produced one of the best knocks of her career but the Sydney Sixers took until the final ball to see off the Adelaide Strikers and land a WBBL finals spot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4aaecf23893063e5ba947a2651efde38</guid></item><item><title>Albanese defends Anika Wells' weekend in Thredbo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/albanese-defends-anika-wells-weekend-in-thredbo-/106112252</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8727180d3e520acd8cf54da37f35175e</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters attend to smouldering homes in Koolewong, NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/firefighters-attend-to-smouldering-homes-in-koolewong-nsw/106112296</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4757ac3a3698c678aef8d64be2412a3c</guid></item><item><title>Locals to be consulted on plan for a new Alice Springs library after council announces location</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/alice-springs-library-plan-will-consult-with-locals/106112200</link><description>The location for the new Alice Springs Public Library was announced late last month, with residents soon able to have their say on what they want included in the $20 million facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0441a709dffc0708189a7abeae6ea5e5</guid></item><item><title>Cameron Smith denied first Australian Open title as Rasmus Neergaard-Petersen claims win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/australian-open-fourth-round-cameron-smith-neergaard-petersen/106111666</link><description>A missed putt costs Cameron Smith the chance of winning his first Australian Open, as Denmark's Rasmus Neergaard-Petersen claimed a thrilling one-stroke victory at Royal Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3887655d326ad5bfe56e1aacc207aa6c</guid></item><item><title>Teenager charged after passenger killed in early morning crash at Corio</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/teen-charged-fatal-corio-crash/106112380</link><description>A 16-year-old boy is alleged to have been the driver of a car which crashed into a pole early Sunday, killing a 17-year-old passenger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69d4136a9871aea8630646e288c9f137</guid></item><item><title>Record number of temporary residents in Australia - 7 December 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/record-number-of-temporary-residents-in-australia-/106112346</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c904f5b96f0f4a168bcaa5271462f0da</guid></item><item><title>Yatala prisoner hospitalised after being 'brutally bashed', union says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/yatala-prisoner-hospitalised-after-alleged-assault/106112170</link><description>A 20-year-old prisoner was so badly bashed at an Adelaide jail on Sunday morning that he was left "barely recognisable" and had to be rushed to hospital for treatment, a union says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02215921262c0db2f1ad34fd0c26af16</guid></item><item><title>Teenager arrested, police search for second person after fatal Ascot Vale stabbing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/fatal-stabbing-ascot-vale-melbourne-north-victoria/106112432</link><description>Police are seeking out witnesses and searching for a second person believed to be involved in the fatal stabbing of a man in Melbourne's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1a75049db2df9432bb97f356046d444</guid></item><item><title>Man smashes ambulance windscreen with head in Kalgoorlie-Boulder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/amulance-windscreen-smashed-by-community-member/106112330</link><description>A video circulated on social media shows a naked male using his head to smash the windscreen of a moving ambulance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33a142b37be9a826fb48feaf00b73ca2</guid></item><item><title>A video of the incident was shared on social media.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/an-incident-involving-an-ambulance-crew-in-kalgoorlie-boulder-/106112472</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c8e6c34af8b1dd0a97efa9475b64b51</guid></item><item><title>Birch by Romeo Lane nightclub fire in India's Goa state kills at least 25 people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/fire-goa-nightclub-kills-25/106112514</link><description>Local village council official Roshan Redkar tells a news agency that authorities had earlier issued a demolition notice for the club as it had no construction permit from the government, but higher officials rolled back the order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e744d8d981c5194ad55cdd71ee568c21</guid></item><item><title>Japan and Australia urge calm after Chinese radar locks onto Japanese jets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/australia-and-japan-urge-calm-after-chinese-radar-locks-jets/106112526</link><description>Japan formally protests the incident, calling it "an extremely regrettable" and dangerous act that "exceeded the scope necessary for safe aircraft operations".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27d322c26523ac3fb38305e86556e60e</guid></item><item><title>Smith fires up, Bazball leaves the building and a miraculous grab — quick hits from day four of the Gabba Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/ashes-day-four-quick-hits-smith-archer-stokes/106112152</link><description>Smith "champs" Archer, Bazball leaves the building and the Australian captain breaks the game open with a miraculous grab. Here are the quick hits from the fourth and final day of the Gabba Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6ba650280f3a6ceb3b2e2da4950a896</guid></item></channel></rss>