<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 19:02:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>England's Bazballers finally admit they've got things wrong in this Ashes series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/england-admits-ashes-failings-after-losing-series-bazball/106168162</link><description>Losing an Ashes Test series in Australia is nothing new for England, but finally the Bazballers are looking inwards at their own failings after a stirring end to the Adelaide Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b1974fa26020f76b673a29709bd243f</guid></item><item><title>Long-awaited wine industry mandatory code of conduct too late for growers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/mandatory-code-or-wine-grape-purchases-too-late-for-growers/106159408</link><description>After 20 years, three senate inquiries and an independent review, the sale of wine grapes will be regulated by a mandatory code of conduct, but growers say it might be too late.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4fa6c637aae4071ca8cfc3af2e1984e</guid></item><item><title>Given the all clear from cancer, 6yo Laylah celebrates by ringing the bell at the Queensland Children's Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/laylah-celebrates-by-ringing-the-bell-at-the-queensland-children/106159230</link><description>When six-year-old Laylah-Jane Morton rang the bell at the Queensland Children's Hospital, it marked the end of her chemotherapy treatment for blood cancer — and she had her merry band of eight siblings with her to help her celebrate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b3aaf162cbcd84c631cb58386fed818</guid></item><item><title>Christmas bonuses boost staff morale, but employers facing 'tighter margins' may struggle to give</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/christmas-bonus-boosts-staff-morale-but-employers-may-struggle/106125160</link><description>From hams to vouchers and cash, festive bonuses vary — but do they still have a place in the Australian workforce?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbc88e61740bc5a0606df5358556f313</guid></item><item><title>Nathan Lyon and Pat Cummins likely out of Boxing Day Ashes Test with series secured</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/ashes-test-nathan-lyon-pat-cummins-boxing-day-test-injuries/106169238</link><description>Nathan Lyon's injury leaves selectors with another headache, made trickier by Pat Cummins's admission that he will almost certainly miss the Boxing Day Test now that the Ashes are won.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43362296f8e292a76395433f21d6bc73</guid></item><item><title>Heavily armed specialist police to patrol MCG during Boxing Day Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/victoria-police-presence-mcg-boxing-day-test/106169288</link><description>Officers from the Critical Incident Response Team armed with long-arm weapons will patrol outside the MCG during the upcoming Boxing Day Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4592de7a0de2a0247e85a2c234dc6299</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder after woman's death at Northfield</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/man-charged-with-murder-after-woman-s-death-northfield/106169300</link><description>A 42-year-old man has been charged with murder after a woman was found dead in a home in Adelaide's northern suburbs on Sunday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb60343fedbc20ed6ab2e59a36bffee0</guid></item><item><title>How your town can become a 'dementia-friendly' community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/dementia-friendly-town-of-ouyen-in-regional-victoria/105888288</link><description>The small Victorian town of Ouyen, 440 kilometres north-west of Melbourne, is known for its grain and sheep farms, but also for being "dementia friendly".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1eadce463b3822ae2b242c0fb8a6a6cf</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested for knife possession at Christmas carols event in Launceston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/knife-at-christmas-carols-in-the-park-launceston/106169174</link><description>Police charge a man after he allegedly produced a 30-centimetre knife at a Christmas carols event in Launceston.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87ae1007835aef391c15316c33cda722</guid></item><item><title>Nikhil Chaudhary hits six out of Kardinia Park in match-winning BBL half-century for Hobart Hurricanes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/nikhil-chaudhary-bbl-half-century-six-out-of-the-ground/106169312</link><description>Hobart star Nikhil Chaudhary launches a ball onto the roof of Kardinia Park in Geelong, but his 79 off 38 is still not enough to earn him player of the match honours in the win over the Renegades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18d33b45c3ffa356814489356f19fb64</guid></item><item><title>Seasonal workers claim unfair bonus cuts and poor conditions on NSW cherry orchard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/cherry-workers-claim-bonus-withheld/105486328</link><description>Ten pickers who worked at Hallmark Cherries' orchard in NSW complain about poorly maintained accommodation and failure to pay an end-of-season bonus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5525f59b29b8c57f2f0e3650c0121f0</guid></item><item><title>James Ransone, star of The Wire and It: Chapter Two, dies at age 46</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/james-ransone-the-wire-actor-dies/106169416</link><description>James Ransone, an actor best known for playing Ziggy Sobotka in The Wire and also starring in It: Chapter Two, has died, according to LA medical authorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f56976d3a1105eb20ac2875136566226</guid></item><item><title>Calls for urgent intervention to help Victorian teachers find affordable housing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/victoria-teacher-housing-shortage/106155540</link><description>Victorian teachers say they are exhausted, living almost 100 kilometres from work, as their salaries fail to sustain housing costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ce43e8dfa4d3310582ffffb53bebd64</guid></item><item><title>Jenny Croom thought Portrait Artist of the Year was a scam — then she won it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/jenny-croom-portrait-artist-of-the-year/106152930</link><description>Jenny Croom put her art on hold for her family; now the 77-year-old has been crowned Australia's 2025 Portrait Artist of the Year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cef6dfd3cddcb3debab871102e89add2</guid></item><item><title>Seven wind turbines provide unique canvas for Indigenous artist Sara Riches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/unique-art-project-gets-big-canvas-on-wind-turbines/106157212</link><description>A renewable energy project being built at one of Western Australia's biggest gold mines has been transformed into a unique canvas for an Indigenous artist and about 200 schoolchildren.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89410c93303c702004b3098846f43da2</guid></item><item><title>School children have inspired art works which will be installed on wind turbines in WA's Goldfields.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/vv-wind-turbines/106163026</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3579ce773f650d6bdad31d83ac7536f2</guid></item><item><title>Former chief justice urges national Bondi terror attack royal commission</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/difference-between-federal-and-state-royal-commissions/106169708</link><description>Calls for the federal government to hold a royal commission into the Bondi terror attack continue after NSW announced intentions for a state-level royal commission, prompting some confusion about the difference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df3a55da14a863f86e8d798be63d7f55</guid></item><item><title>Seven injured as car crashes into Royal Hotel Capertee, near Lithgow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/pub-crash-capertee-sees-seven-injured/106169318</link><description>A man has been charged after seven people were injured when a car crashed into a pub on the New South Wales central tablelands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa86c2c77ba299f6f07f810a24a4d6d4</guid></item><item><title>Government confirms plans for gas reservation on east coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/government-confirms-gas-reservation-plans/106170082</link><description>Chris Bowen makes a long-anticipated announcement about reserving a portion of gas on the east coast for domestic use after a cabinet meeting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24f6eb3702dbe2e4c6adb29e697ec32d</guid></item><item><title>Lake George hides an earthquake fault zone, and scientists are using your road noise to see it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/lake-george-earthquake-fault-zone-anu-research-map/106119740</link><description>Almost 100 sensors beside the Federal Highway are helping build the clearest picture yet of the fault beneath the iconic lake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba2fd8b425cff8b995d984e6eba26d74</guid></item><item><title>Building a village means showing up even when it feels hard, says Esther Perel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/esther-perel-on-building-a-village/106144018</link><description>Building and maintaining a village doesn't just happen. It takes effort. It means showing up even when it feels hard or inconvenient, says psychotherapist Esther Perel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d67bf72d30394641d123ddf4f13963ad</guid></item><item><title>Bondi gunmen filmed 'firearms training' and threw explosives into crowd, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/nsw-sydney-bondi-terror-attack-naveed-akram-court-police-facts/106170286</link><description>The Bondi gunman accused of killing 15 people conducted "firearms training" in a regional area with his father and recorded a video about their "justification" for the attack, according to documents released by a Sydney court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51c6c2bf2e8f1f744234679e5d92702b</guid></item><item><title>Measles cases almost triple in Australia as global outbreaks continue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/measles-cases-triple-in-australia-2025-global-outbreaks-continue/106017266</link><description>The number of measles cases nationwide is now approaching triple the number of cases reported in 2024 as outbreaks continue around the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82bd3ef5e517af8782bba83a8249b2d0</guid></item><item><title>Royal commission into Bondi attack appears inevitable for Albanese government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/bondi-terror-attack-anthony-albanese-royal-commission/106156706</link><description>The prime minister is undoubtedly facing tough conversations behind closed doors, but until the public gets to witness the scrutiny he will never satisfy his critics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db25d53c1beff82d36461c1213792ef4</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanians in 1971 speak about legalising cannabis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/tasmanians-in-1971-speak-about-legalising-cannabis/106092878</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e1084c0bf0b75d7237ec823e930be5e</guid></item><item><title>Why Mitchell Starc is open to playing on to the 2027 Ashes series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/mitchell-starc-ashes-2027-retirement/106170684</link><description>Mitchell Starc will be 37 by the time the 2027 Ashes kicks off in 18 months' time, but the in-form quick is open to spearheading Australia's attack in their next clash with England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eef12edca6fb499a21126506c057fe05</guid></item><item><title>Industry and musicians explore ways to make vinyl records more environmentally friendly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/vinyl-records-environment-impact-stella-donnelly-green-music/106170050</link><description>Artists like Stella Donnelly are searching for ways to cut waste and make production of their albums environmentally friendly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a59ea18d46fe6b9b07a7c95c2823ee3f</guid></item><item><title>Prince William and son George visit homelessness charity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/prince-william-and-son-george-visit-homelessness-charity-/106171302</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">764d03c1a8d8cc3ba491b17e9ac824c2</guid></item><item><title>Victorian government to crack down on hate speech, review gun laws following Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/victoria-government-antisemitism-hate-speech-law-reforms/106170386</link><description>In the wake of last week's terrorist attack at Bondi Beach, Premier Jacinta Allan unveils a five-point plan targeting antisemitism in Victoria and providing a "pathway to normal" for the state's Jewish community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bbdedb4aef4f351eaa8178e77673fea</guid></item><item><title>Stuart Broad still believes Australia's Ashes-winning team is their worst side in 15 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/broad-stands-by-worst-aussie-side-in-15-years-sledge/106171220</link><description>Stuart Broad has attracted plenty of criticism for his low opinion of the current Australian team but the England great stands by his harsh assessment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ed2d189c786b9d849804d57aa80ed70</guid></item><item><title>Family tells inquest young mother 'died of a broken heart' as system failed to protect her</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/inquest-death-assault-broken-heart/105999220</link><description>The NSW Coroners Court hands down findings into the 2023 death of a young Indigenous mother after a doctor gave evidence the woman may have died from "broken-heart syndrome".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0991818df236a4db3da682a3adc1ecf</guid></item><item><title>Prince William and Prince George help make Christmas lunch at homelessness charity in London</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/prince-william-and-george-volunteer/106171112</link><description>From America, the Duke and Duchess of Sussex have also sent out their Christmas wishes on Instagram.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7eb1ff578a59de8d44a58f2a66c7ff58</guid></item><item><title>Should I pour leftover liquids or foods down the sink?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/should-i-pour-leftover-liquids-or-foods-down-the-sink/106170720</link><description>Ever been about to pour rancid milk down the sink and thought, "Hmm, maybe I shouldn't…"? What about the tomato passata that's gone off? Or the water you washed the paint in? Or that pungent oil from a tuna can?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6924007e49f62dd2d7c58991cdf504cc</guid></item><item><title>Queensland man arrested following dozens of antisemitic graffiti offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/queensland-man-arrested-for-antisemitic-graffiti/106170620</link><description>A Coolum Beach man is charged with 25 counts of wilful damage following a spate of antisemitic graffiti incidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9326f118b79691be07229f59bd0ffa9a</guid></item><item><title>City Beach fined $14m by Federal Court over button battery safety breaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/city-beach-fined-over-button-battery-safety-breaches/106171832</link><description>The Federal Court orders the fashion retailer to pay $14 million in fines after it was taken to court by the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2071cda5c164c9599c9f0fcc18fcbfc</guid></item><item><title>Japan prepares to restart world's biggest nuclear plant, 15 years after Fukushima</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/japan-votes-to-restart-worlds-largest-nuclear-reactor-in-niigata/106171978</link><description>Japan has taken the final step to allow the world's largest nuclear power plant to resume operations with a regional vote in Niigata prefecture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64d03c90cff763f07cc05aee9c3258cf</guid></item><item><title>Festive season to bring Christmas Day heatwave to Perth and Cocos Island tropical cyclone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/wa-christmas-weather-perth-heatwave-cyclone-for-cocos-keeling/106171520</link><description>Perth is expected to hit a high of 41 degrees on Christmas Day with the Cocos (Keeling) Islands bracing for a tropical cyclone that could intensify to a category two system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">247f45e4873ba448f0af0273571c0611</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after death at Big 4 Port Willunga caravan park in Adelaide's south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/police-investigate-suspicious-death-at-aldinga/106172164</link><description>A 49-year-old man has appeared in court charged with the alleged murder of 72-year-old Gary Hallam at the Big 4 Port Willunga Tourist Park at Aldinga in Adelaide's south on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e53f6f64dbad1330e0b3a085101c9d6</guid></item><item><title>Three bushwalkers rescued from Lake Rhona in Tasmania's south-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/bushwalking-trio-rescued-from-lake-rhona-tasmania/106172212</link><description>Three "cold and wet but otherwise uninjured" bushwalkers have been airlifted out of Tasmania's remote south-west after calling for help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18e99d897f473cbe593ed4f648f9a9d8</guid></item><item><title>Kyrgios not offered Australian Open wildcard as four other Aussies named</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/tennis-australian-open-wildcards-priscilla-hon-nick-kyrgios/106172294</link><description>After a career-best year, Queenslander Priscilla Hon was among four Australian Open wildcards named on Monday, but Nick Kyrgios was not among them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c54b1b6e647fe7fa67750a19dce86c21</guid></item><item><title>Thailand and Cambodia set to resume ceasefire negotiations amid deadly border conflict</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/thailand-cambodia-set-to-resume-ceasefire-negotiations/106172396</link><description>Bangkok says the two countries will return to the negotiating table this week amid claims the initial peace deal was rushed for Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0a9248cdf5eb6362d084c7900e38b90</guid></item><item><title>Man behind deadly Taiwan metro attack planned it for over a year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/taipei-metro-attack-planned-for-a-year-police-say/106172454</link><description>Police in Taiwan say Chang Wen purchased grenades, gas canisters and respirators in the year leading up to Friday's attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2312dc62326082cd9a6cfb89bd85ee41</guid></item><item><title>Unhinged Christmas movies quiz: Can you pick the real movies from these ridiculous plots?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/unhinged-christmas-movies-quiz/106170030</link><description>Once December rolls around, there's nothing the minor movie studios love more than getting their most unhinged Christmas tropes out of cold storage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbbe198736c3d76fbaa178e1abcf739b</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 23: Uruguay legalises recreational cannabis use</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/today-in-history-marijuana-is-legalised-uruguay-cannabis/106098248</link><description>Twelve years ago today, Uruguay became the first country to legalise recreational marijuana use. The experiment is still unfolding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dbd4de94678eacea566d0fe35fb3876</guid></item><item><title>Stephen Cubis was the face of GIM Trading when investors lost millions but his story began long before then</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/stephen-cubis-gim-trading-fraud-allegations/106119304</link><description>Stephen Cubis hides behind a charming facade, but his former lover and friends say the career con man ruined them financially and emotionally long before he was caught up in allegations of a multimillion-dollar fraud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cfe5b5d8f07f80cfb8a833285485b17</guid></item><item><title>Better late than never: The gas fix to a problem that should never have been</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/the-gas-fix-to-a-problem-that-should-never-have-been/106171870</link><description>The gas export industry has cost the nation dearly. East coast prices trebled soon after exports began.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0470bd441d7d2a44b48a2ac3241cd8d2</guid></item><item><title>Videos and CCTV give fresh insight into gunmen's plot to target Bondi Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/nsw-sydney-bondi-beach-gunmen-captured-on-cctv-court-documents/106171074</link><description>Security camera footage captured the Bondi Beach gunmen carrying what appears to be firearms out of a south-west Sydney property on the morning of the terror attack, court documents reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03c6804e5c43be5c058c3ba789861201</guid></item><item><title>Beekeepers on high alert as bee-killing varroa mite spreads in South Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/beekeepers-on-high-alert-varroa-mite-spreads-sa/106169566</link><description>The varroa mite may be tiny — only a millimetre or two long — but it poses a huge threat to honey bees, beekeepers and honey producers, who are on high alert after the destructive mite's recent arrival in South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5aa3ee9662557b777ee50394594dd024</guid></item><item><title>World's largest warship looms near Venezuela as US warns of land attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/uss-gerald-r-ford-near-venezuela-trump-warns-of-land-strikes/106114524</link><description>The Pentagon moved the USS Gerald R Ford, the world's largest aircraft carrier, to the Caribbean last month. Now, President Donald Trump is repeating threats of imminent strikes against Venezuelan territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7782d940992a0022dc0e959e50dfb3a</guid></item><item><title>A chaotic 'up-crash' as markets and economic realities made for a turbulent 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/trump-tariffs-interest-rates-and-ai-2025-was-a-chaotic-up-crash/106086538</link><description>AI. Market records. Tariffs. Penguins. TACO. It's been a big year of economic shocks and surges as the international framework of global trade was shredded. Here's how key players saw the year that was.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e7ddc548ef694d8dfa1af89e65ddf89</guid></item><item><title>Liberal-linked Tasmanian public relations firm Font PR shuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/font-public-relations-liberals-linked-firm-closes/106166618</link><description>It has helped keep the Liberals in power in Tasmania and lobbied on behalf of Airbnb, the salmon industry and the Catholic Church — but the PR firm, described as having "fingers in a lot of pies", is closing down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">543f948fad5f12a7a29dcf1d485996a2</guid></item><item><title>Sisters in Sweat — the Sunday football session that grew a sporting movement of over 15,000 Indian women</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/sisters-in-sweat-football-movement-without-judgement/106099240</link><description>Eight years ago, Swetha Subbiah was asked to run a single football session for a friend. She ended up starting a sporting movement, which now has 15,000 women and girls as members across Bengaluru, Mumbai, Hyderabad and Delhi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed9651ef82e6b78ef579a015ead48f9c</guid></item><item><title>Driving Home for Christmas singer Chris Rea dies aged 74</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/chris-rea-driving-home-for-christmas-singer-dies-aged-74/106172544</link><description>The man best known for his festive hit Driving Home for Christmas died surrounded by his family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e6f7b3d1f27dcde6842162454cd7219</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of birds are dying on a remote island with no end in sight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/bird-flu-h5n1-virus-outbreak-ground-zero-no-end-in-sight/106023290</link><description>The Isle of May is the epicentre of a deadly outbreak of the H5N1 bird flu strain which has spread throughout the globe. Scientists are warning Australia could be next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7ae9b9c9bcd889396f8f2a11ed8cabc</guid></item><item><title>Two men die in separate stabbing incidents in Melbourne on Monday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/police-investigate-stabbings-clyde-fitzroy/106172720</link><description>A man died after he was stabbed during an altercation in Clyde, in Melbourne's south-east. Just hours later another man was fatally stabbed in Fitzroy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d0d6acffd1b359ac2c8a41db00e719e</guid></item><item><title>Swiss court to hear Pari islanders' climate change case against cement giant Holcim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/swiss-court-set-to-hear-pari-island-climate-case-against-holcim/106172666</link><description>Residents of the tiny Indonesian island of Pari, which risks being swallowed by rising seas, win the right to have their climate change case against cement giant Holcim heard in a Swiss court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a371896b76ac1bd1722ed1a44c061714</guid></item><item><title>Wild Christmas week ahead for Queensland with days of severe storms forecast as temperatures ease</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/qld-weather-christmas-storms-as-heatwave-eases/106172340</link><description>The weather bureau is forecasting heavy rainfall and thunderstorms for large parts of the state over the Christmas week, but temperatures are expected to ease.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f15077b12b29f33fecb2ead66526603</guid></item><item><title>Cross-border commissioner's death leaves border towns in limbo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/queensland-cross-border-commissioner-role-remains-vacant/106170830</link><description>Towns, like Goondiwindi on the Queensland-New South Wales border, wait to see who will replace the late Ian Leavers in the role of cross-border commissioner and continue his work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cefe55302dc6b2a07e9509d21744486</guid></item><item><title>WA's water regulator is probing South32's impacts on neighbouring farmland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/farmers-south32-bauxite-mine-water-issues/106172120</link><description>The owner of a farm neighbouring South32's major bauxite mine in WA claims the miner is responsible for rising salinity and reduced water availability at his property. His claims are now being probed by WA's regulator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6844be562d85205ce3246437497d87ad</guid></item><item><title>Poor sleep, unhealthy diets and stress compound to leave homeless at risk of dying decades early</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/homelessness-poor-health-life-expectancy-falls-wa-research-finds/106165168</link><description>Western Australian research is showing a strong link between homelessness and poor health, with life expectancy more than 30 years lower for people without secure housing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">082793cf40319386a9f52dfc3194b670</guid></item><item><title>In a 'complete 180', graziers get early Christmas present with significant rainfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/outback-graziers-praise-rainfall-after-long-dry-spell/106171108</link><description>The heavy rainfall is welcomed by graziers and follows months of dry conditions in the state's far-west, with hot temperatures and wind battering the land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca7b1cd17ca020e646a26fdc2cb6df3d</guid></item><item><title>Thunderstorm arrives in Broken Hill ahead of Christmas.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/thunderstorm-arrives-in-broken-hill-ahead-of-christmas/106170696</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e8ddb3436c2f5f3dad01fef3259f950</guid></item><item><title>Plans to burn red tingle trees temporarily suspended following treetop protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/treetop-protester-wins-red-tingle-trees-fight/106171960</link><description>The WA government abandons plans to burn a parcel of forest that is home to a species of rare tree after a 70-year-old man spent six nights living in the canopy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f32f2e1eea3f2aa3d9b18dd66aa61514</guid></item><item><title>Residents of The Rock, in southern NSW, take on businesses to keep town alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/the-rock-community-takes-on-businesses-to-keep-town-alive/106127058</link><description>After giving to her community for decades, Barb's town is now working hard so people like her never have to leave for necessities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e190401ee760a35bdaa21ce228f4d2a</guid></item><item><title>Serie A soccer game between AC Milan and Como at Perth Stadium called off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/ac-milan-versus-como-serie-a-game-at-perth-stadium-called-off/106173042</link><description>A historic Serie A soccer clash between AC Milan and Como at Perth Stadium in February is called off, with sanctions imposed by the Asian Football Confederation blamed for making it "impossible".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7e9b55a5baed2dfd1d19b283c89073d</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Pat Cummins, Nathan Lyon out of Boxing Day Test, Jhye Richardson and Todd Murphy in squad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/ashes-boxing-day-test-squad-pat-cummins-jhye-richardson/106173288</link><description>West Australian fast bowler Jhye Richardson comes into Australia's squad for the fourth Ashes Test, while Victorian off spinner Todd Murphy has been named, and is a chance to play his eighth match and first on Australian soil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">806287eed1927541e69f203f07a9d6dd</guid></item><item><title>Ferrari crash reportedly kills Call of Duty co-founder Vince Zampella in California</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/vince-zampella-dies-car-crash/106173016</link><description>Vince Zampella has died after a crash on a scenic road north of Los Angeles, according to local broadcaster NBC4.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1b47f1713b30f9a5548511d9072e9c6</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting updates: NSW premier defends protest laws, saying 'words lead to actions'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/albanese-national-security-meeting-chris-minns-defends-new-laws/106173660</link><description>Chris Minns says new protest laws will be introduced despite "resistance to the government's legislative agenda in recent days".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d02bbd968c1a33dec06918b6454e202a</guid></item><item><title>Newmont's Cadia Gold Mine to spend $300,000 on monitors after dust incidents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/newmont-cadia-gold-mine-buys-dust-monitoring-stations-epa/106170892</link><description>One of the country's largest gold mines in the NSW Central West will buy five new dust monitors after incidents at its tailings dam.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8b16aa24b0110d31f9b6c0be2269d84</guid></item><item><title>Historic giant sequoia tree in Hobart's St David's Park 'very, very sick' after fires and vandalism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/historic-giant-sequoia-tree-in-hobart-park-is-sick/106171168</link><description>An 88-year-young giant sequoia tree is "declining rapidly" in St David's Park in central Hobart due to a range of disturbances, including vandalism and fire, the council says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6948c23add1761505282eddcc4c6ca92</guid></item><item><title>Rain-hit orchards still producing 'best quality' lychees in time for Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/weather-impacted-christmas-lychees-are-best-quality-in-decades/106162250</link><description>After season constraints and rain-delayed harvests, this summer is producing exceptional Queensland lychees, according to the wholesalers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16e5cb33ab2fdee1026c2a58720857da</guid></item><item><title>Woman appears in court after failing to 'keep the King's Peace' and allegedly biting ACT police officer's leg</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/woman-fails-keep-king-peace-biting-police-officer/106173712</link><description>A failure to 'keep the King's Peace' and biting a police officer has almost landed a Canberra woman in jail for Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2531d9cd74672f55bbc06e81b72969cf</guid></item><item><title>Central West horticulturist supplying Australia's Christmas trees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/christmas-tree-farm/106170822</link><description>From a backyard in Wollongong to a booming farm in the NSW Central West, Christmas trees are big business for Lawrence Ranson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e22af694f47b16302ea864b1c9a24574</guid></item><item><title>Latest 'Battle of the sexes' commodifies and risks mocking historic event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/nick-kyrgios-aryna-sabalenka-battle-of-the-sexes-lose-lose/106174192</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka and Nick Kygrios' match marketed under the "Battle of the Sexes" banner makes a mockery of first era-defining match between Billie Jean King and Bobby Riggs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f9df8171a4c08b8311e5a2c2fe729eb</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese recommends changes to parliamentarians' travel rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/anthony-albanese-recommends-changes-parliamentary-travel-rules/106174182</link><description>Under the recommendations, family of parliamentarians would be restricted to economy class flights and an allowance for three annual "Australia-wide" return trips would be scrapped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dffd23670c5c0a70913dbe382d609bc</guid></item><item><title>Koala protection in south-east Queensland to be shaped by new strategy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/qld-koala-strategy/106173284</link><description>The Queensland government is inviting the public to have their say on a new strategy to protect the south-east's koala population.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">515cc2988cc82186aa02db050a98c33a</guid></item><item><title>Gregory John Walker jailed over Arthur Haines' death after 1998 Sydney firebombing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/nsw-gregory-walker-sentencing-arthur-haines-firebombing/106173498</link><description>Gregory John Walker is sentenced to at least six-and-a-half years in prison for unlawfully killing a teenager by firebombing a Sydney home in 1998 during an escalating neighbourhood dispute.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09dc039ee5b005aa683345d6db3c87cc</guid></item><item><title>Best podcasts of 2025, from Forged to Fela Kuti: Fear No Man</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/best-podcasts-2025-forged-fela-kuti-fear-no-man/106138476</link><description>Our favourite podcasts of the year include tales of art forgery, a documentary about the life of Fela Kútì and a true-crime thriller about a dead body in the ocean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ccd2f33573cb77c395b8b3bf699ea6c</guid></item><item><title>As a newly single mum, I am redefining Christmas with my kids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/spending-christmas-without-my-child-perspective/106129654</link><description>This is my first Christmas as a single mum where I will wake up without my son in the home. I won't be watching him excitedly tear into presents. It's not easy, but there's also some relief, writes Catherine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d5a38448fa2d7d2e1fb3e4cab6272b3</guid></item><item><title>No air conditioning in Shellharbour Hospital ward during heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/hospital-patients-swelter-without-air-con-during-heatwave/106173174</link><description>Patients swelter in an Illawarra hospital ward after an air conditioning unit fails during a heatwave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0799f44f22f84a2e18d9dabd6186cff</guid></item><item><title>Therapeutic Goods Administration issues warnings over heavy metals in Ayurvedic tablets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/complementary-ayurvedic-medicines-heavy-metals-safety-alert/106156510</link><description>Australia's medicine watchdog has issued another safety alert for contaminated Ayurvedic medicines. So what do consumers need to know about this multi-million-dollar industry?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f839cfc4577b67765d53fe3970548e3</guid></item><item><title>What the weather will bring in your capital city on Christmas Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/christmas-day-weather-forecast-2025/106173430</link><description>It is just a few sleeps until Christmas Day, and the weather is promising a mixed bag for Australia's capital cities. Here is what to expect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4634be3c02e26c8e9931be0a2ad75e4</guid></item><item><title>NSW oyster growers face contrasting holiday seasons as Christmas Eve rush looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/holiday-season-oyster-farms-christmas/106150290</link><description>The Christmas oyster harvest is flourishing on the NSW south coast, but further north it is a very different story as growers face the fallout of this year's record-breaking floods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f8cb8dd51a20c0fcd6787563277d3e2</guid></item><item><title>Severe Christmas heatwave scorches WA as Tropical Cyclone Grant strengthens offshore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/perth-wa-severe-christmas-heatwave-tropical-cyclone-grant/106174278</link><description>Perth, and much of WA, is enduring a severe Christmas heatwave with extreme fire danger, while Tropical Cyclone Grant intensifies offshore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2b1297740e2718b68e3eea718278a7f</guid></item><item><title>ECB managing director Rob Key to investigate England's Noosa break following Ashes failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/england-rob-key-ashes-noosa-drinking/106175002</link><description>ECB managing director Rob Key will investigate reports England's recent break in Noosa resembled a "stag do" as the tourists pick up the pieces from their Ashes defeat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12762fcf89066cd205121cc1842d1263</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins could miss T20 World Cup to manage back injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/pat-cummins-no-certainty-for-t20-world-cup/106175190</link><description>Pat Cummins could be held back from the upcoming T20 World Cup as Australia look to manage his workload following his recent back injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b31b570afd3d68bce0cd5d9eea32e598</guid></item><item><title>NSW police officer Jack Hibbert released from hospital after being shot in Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/nsw-police-constable-jack-hibbert-out-of-hospital-after-bondi/106165734</link><description>A young police officer who was rendered blind in one eye after being shot during the Bondi terror attack is released from hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">863fae5e27a1267508c77e7e0ee8c79e</guid></item><item><title>Dead fish found at Lake Macquarie in 2022</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/dead-fish-found-at-lake-macquarie/106173672</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90d355f9f30dc907957b34d3efc5755f</guid></item><item><title>Delta Electricity found guilty over 2022 fish kill near its Vales Point Power Station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/delta-electricity-guilty-for-fish-kill-near-power-station/106173120</link><description>A court rules a maintenance failure caused hundreds of fish to die near Delta Electricity's Vales Point coal-fired power station in September 2022, a month after another kill triggered by natural causes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6a3a4a71e4f4e25cab04a2f450b4dd7</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne faces its coldest Christmas weather in two decades — but Victoria's summer heat is on its way</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/victoria-melbourne-christmas-day-weather-forecast/106170980</link><description>Temperatures in the Victorian capital are unlikely to climb past 17 degrees on Christmas Day, but the state will swing back to some warm to hot days ahead of the new year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6daaea2a42458a82835b63daf56539d3</guid></item><item><title>Up to 1,700 jobs axed days out from Christmas as security firm MA Services collapses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/ma-services-security-cleaning-company-enters-administration/106175160</link><description>A "significant number" of employees have been made immediately redundant as MA Security — which provides security and maintenance services to major retailers like Coles, Kmart and Amazon — enters administration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f44180052c8f395d11dc624bad4134da</guid></item><item><title>CommBank reverses refusal to refund $68m in excessive fees for low-income earners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/commbank-reverses-bank-fee-refusal/106174050</link><description>The Commonwealth Bank of Australia will refund low-income earners receiving Centrelink payments approximately $68 million in unfair fees — just over a quarter of what was charged.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36c96e32b41f5ea3d1c941877dab0efa</guid></item><item><title>Woman treated for suspected bite after eastern brown snake became trapped in her shoe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/woman-finds-eastern-brown-snake-trapped-in-shoe/106174484</link><description>A woman has been rushed to hospital after a brown snake curled around her leg, becoming trapped in her shoe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96f7252ca6f2c8da2e9e7248ba2f775a</guid></item><item><title>Robert Donald Blackberry jailed after hay bale scam targeting Tasmanian farmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/hay-bale-scammer-robert-donald-blackberry-jailed/106173248</link><description>A judge blasts a man's "complete and utter disregard for the law" and jails him for scamming farmers desperate for feed out of money for hay bales he never delivered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae49e3a22372ec0d044afd7fcd498144</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal legal aid lawyers launch High Court challenge to NT bail laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/northern-territory-bail-laws-to-be-challenged-in-high-court/106175228</link><description>The North Australian Aboriginal Justice Agency says hundreds of people are likely being held on remand in Northern Territory jails "unlawfully and unconstitutionally".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e49a5a405e445c1c3aa1b16b1159033</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese's Christmas message for Australians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/anthony-albanese-christmas-message-2025/106175454</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19761905a562133d9fa9124375cb416b</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese and Sussan Ley release Christmas messages in wake of Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/anthony-albanese-sussan-ley-christmas-messages/106175306</link><description>Anthony Albanese and Opposition Leader Sussan Ley are urging Australians to "stand together" this Christmas in the wake of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5161d332a202792544fa6606a0dcdd23</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley's Christmas message for Australians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/sussan-ley-christmas-message-2025/106175756</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49f90687be5906462dbe1f5f4ca11d24</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide academic accused of attempting to kill her ex searched methods to kill, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/lisa-lines-bail-application/106173090</link><description>A woman accused of trying to murder her ex-husband before fleeing to Palau has made a bid in South Australia's Supreme Court for release on bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2d2b9c476702795542e404d1c34872b</guid></item><item><title>US approves Wegovy pill, giving Novo Nordisk an edge in obesity drug competition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/wegovy-pill-approved-in-us-new-obesity-treatment/106175652</link><description>A daily weight-loss pill will soon be available in the US, after the regulator gave approval to Danish drug company Novo Nordisk's oral version of the popular injectable, Wegovy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2a5ee3d3b6d8085cb49ee03f61d25e8</guid></item><item><title>NSW parliament passes tougher laws on guns and protests after Bondi Beach attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/nsw-parliament-passes-gun-reforms-after-bondi-beach-attack/106176054</link><description>After a marathon debate lasting into the early hours of Christmas Eve, the NSW government has passed controversial law reforms sparked by the Bondi massacre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">603ed5ece8d57ee166273049adef764f</guid></item><item><title>Cooler spring blamed for Tasmania's later Christmas berry, cherry harvest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/cooler-spring-blamed-tas-late-berry-cherry-harvest/106173424</link><description>Christmas is usually a boom time for Tasmanian berry producers, but this year's cold spring has slowed crops and hurt profits.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">705a5995417dbc7739b8e638b75d975b</guid></item><item><title>Gun and protest laws tighten after Bondi Beach terrorist attack. Here's what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/changes-to-nsw-gun-protest-laws-pass-after-bondi-terror-attack/106175636</link><description>The Minns government has recalled parliament to tighten laws around protests and gun ownership following the shooting at Bondi Beach that killed 15 people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4be0ef900b90fb5159d1a5d9bc98bf80</guid></item><item><title>Do you know how to make the gravy? Test your Christmas song knowledge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/christmas-songs-quiz/106133752</link><description>Which Christmas hits didn't do as well on the charts as you'd think? Test your knowledge of festive cheer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a6f069aa41b131375949561d682b968</guid></item><item><title>Christmas festivities return to Bethlehem after two years as Palestinians hope for 'better future'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/christmas-festivities-return-to-bethlehem-after-two-years/106156060</link><description>For the first time in two years, Bethlehem has restarted its Christmas festivities to "reignite the spirit that everybody needs" while Palestinians continue to live under restrictions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">959bab0c472d2bc907e8df47cab050cb</guid></item><item><title>Boxing Day sales set to be biggest on record as interest rate relief drives retail rebound</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/boxing-day-sales-australia-2025/106171474</link><description>Boxing Day spending is expected to hit a record high, supported by revived household spending after three interest rate cuts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad1a713797696e8327e634ed101ddcf6</guid></item><item><title>Australian businessman Ranjit Thambyrajah languishes in Vietnam jail after string of failed loan deals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/australian-businessman-ranjit-thambyrajah-jailed-in-vietnam/106174026</link><description>A high-flying Australian financier accused of swindling a struggling Vietnamese petroleum trading company has been languishing in a Ho Chi Minh City cell for two months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32afb45f1768c514427193990162ebc0</guid></item><item><title>Epstein files email reveal 'A' at 'Balmoral' sought 'inappropriate friends' from Ghislaine Maxwell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/latest-epstein-files-dump-reveals-emails-from-a-at-balmoral/106176014</link><description>Someone who referred to themselves as "A" at "Balmoral" emailed convicted child sex offender Ghislaine Maxwell in 2001, asking if she had found them "some new inappropriate friends", the latest Epstein files document dump has revealed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd9b0ac9c39e9860fb05a167917b3379</guid></item><item><title>A $7m unpaid tobacco fine and online sales emerge amid government crack down on illegal trade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/qld-illicit-tobacco-unpaid-fines-health-smoking/106170904</link><description>Illicit tobacco retailers have racked up millions in unpaid fines since the introduction of stronger penalties, with one owing more than $7 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">787337ed5dcf9686f03d4e519b1e3e37</guid></item><item><title>Russell Brand charged with rape and sexual assault of two women</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/russell-brand-charged-with-more-sex-offences-by-uk-police/106176040</link><description>The British comedian now faces seven charges of sexual assault involving six separate women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">798e7579f7e0a88840882f531fc78dde</guid></item><item><title>Rain on Queensland's Christmas forecast, north-west on flood watch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/rain-forecast-christmas-qld-north-west-flood-watch/106173584</link><description>It may not be the most welcome weather at the beach, but out in the west, rain is the best Christmas gift.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b341d575edef8b6616b4176339c1bf1a</guid></item><item><title>When Australia could get 6G after Trump launch of 'race' to next generation of mobile connectivity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/when-australia-could-get-6g-after-trump-us-announcement/106170702</link><description>Donald Trump says he wants the United States to lead the world in the "6G race" and has given his government one year to find out how to begin making it happen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37053cb6a573dc07d696125b84041868</guid></item><item><title>Pressure builds on Milano Cortina organisers amid climate concerns and funding issues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/milan-cortina-winter-olympics-pressure-rotation-system/106176102</link><description>The head of the FIS has raised concerns over snow and financial issues affecting the Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games, suggesting that a radical rotation system of hosts should be considered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1c1538ae355003cfb460794ad2eba12</guid></item><item><title>Runner Nancy Dickman, 83, prepares for her next marathon at 90</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/83yo-runner-nancy-dickman-preparing-for-her-next-marathon/106027164</link><description>Nancy Dickman has run marathons in London, New York, Rome and Sydney, and at 83 shows no signs of slowing down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ce23e10ca9dfe12fea5638e3ceed667</guid></item><item><title>Australian dollar jumps to 14-month high, ASX falls as gold and silver hit record highs — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/asx-markets-business-live-news/106176162</link><description>The Australian share market is down on Christmas Eve, despite the value of US stocks, gold and silver climbing to their most expensive levels ever, while the Australian dollar has jumped to its highest level since October 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c78068110747ab7aaa5444e314acc337</guid></item><item><title>Samoan weightlifters Seine Stowers and June Sipaia are breaking records and inspiring women</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/samoan-weightlifters-seine-stowers-june-sipaia-inspiring-women/106094176</link><description>Last month Samoan weightlifters Seine Stowers and June Sipaia broke World and Oceania records. Their success is due to a generational shift in attitudes to women in the sport, and a world-class facility at home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ff7f18ddc8be4a1eaf6607f4da501e7</guid></item><item><title>Woman's miraculous Arnhem Land survival story after ankle 'snapped in half'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/arnhem-land-survival-story-woman-crawled-for-help-ankle-snapped/106166278</link><description>Lying on the ground with her ankle snapped in half in the remote bushland of western Arnhem Land, her mind racing, and with no help or phone reception, Margie Moroney began to crawl.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2b76790497fb883ac74f29812ef09e4</guid></item><item><title>Mohamed Salah claims Africa Cup of Nations record as Egypt beat Zimbabwe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/mohamed-salah-claims-africa-cup-of-nations-record/106176216</link><description>Mohamed Salah scored at his fifth Africa Cup of Nations tournament in a row, becoming the first Egyptian player to do so.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f8aa2987bb15d6e3b13ebf9afa6596c</guid></item><item><title>Double-lung transplant recipient Johnnie Tumai's plea for Christmas organ donors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/double-lung-transplant-recipient-johnnie-tumai/106033118</link><description>Johnnie Tumai is preparing to spend his first Christmas at home since receiving a new set of lungs. He's urging others to register as donors this festive season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46e9d57e567decf05cbc39dff061528e</guid></item><item><title>Father of three meets bone marrow donor who saved his life for 'most special Christmas'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/wa-bone-marrow-recipient-meets-donor-special-christmas/106172104</link><description>Battling acute myeloid leukaemia, Gennaro Rapinese finally found a suitable bone marrow donor on the other side of the world in the US. And, after making a full recovery, he got to thank her in person in the lead-up to Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff6481214c7dc01941ff0685683c806d</guid></item><item><title>A US bone marrow donor is reunited with the Perth man she saved.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/us-bone-marrow-donor-reunites-with-perth-man-she-saved/106175644</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f6a78b0d2dd8bb934d9d8359a026d5</guid></item><item><title>Tarina Warren has been legally blind since she was 16, now a seeing eye dog is helping her navigate life on Moolooloo Station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/seeing-eye-dog-helping-on-outback-south-australian-sheep-station/106119816</link><description>Moolooloo station, nestled in South Australia's Flinders Ranges, might look like your typical outback farm, but the workforce at this station has one unique addition — a black labrador called Mika.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b31e319b326ff413922ba6b31841ec3e</guid></item><item><title>Convenience over tradition as gen Z and millennials favour pre-peeled prawns over the Christmas period</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/young-australians-not-peeling-christmas-prawns/106173238</link><description>New research shows younger Aussies prefer to save time and mess by buying pre-peeled prawns over the festive season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c26bc33a33387bfea269786da7f0eeed</guid></item><item><title>Bondi terror attack heroes to be recognised in new honours list</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/bondi-heroes-to-be-recognised-in-new-honours-list/106176488</link><description>The prime minister announces those who showed "extraordinary" bravery during the Bondi terror attack will be recognised in a new honours list.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51c14b2bdf7a6685f0595618026787e0</guid></item><item><title>WA farming community loses 500 sheep, thousands of hectares of crops in fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/western-australian-farming-community-loses-500-sheep-in-fires/106153256</link><description>A bushfire emergency in Warradarge is over, but farmers say the work to recover what was lost has only just begun.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80cdd9268fb9fd905e22ffb4920dd350</guid></item><item><title>Through my eyes: Jean Mitchell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/through-my-eyes-jean-mitchell/106162552</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f91acbae2647822d58a176ffd0a9be5</guid></item><item><title>Brooks Koepka leaves LIV Golf in major blow to breakaway league</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/brooks-koepka-leaves-liv-golf/106176562</link><description>Golf superstar Brooks Koepka has cited family priorities as he announces he is leaving the breakaway LIV Golf league.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">810822568c249759fa95a72196633a8c</guid></item><item><title>Kate Winslet makes her directorial debut with family Christmas movie Goodbye June</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/goodbye-june-kate-winslet-directorial-debut-movie/106150390</link><description>The actor talks about why she felt compelled to make the Christmas-themed film and why she was lucky to get Helen Mirren to play the titular role.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e87fd55db98fa5d4e281f9f4594d605</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Grant approaches Cocos (Keeling) Islands as severe Christmas heatwave scorches WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/tropical-cyclone-grant-nears-islands-amid-wa-christmas-heatwave/106176456</link><description>Preparations are underway far off Western Australia's north-west coast for the impact of a category one cyclone as Perth and much of the state continues to swelter in heatwave conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9eb942cdf56564b96e8cfcbca5123d93</guid></item><item><title>Sydney to Hobart yacht race not expecting repeat of last year's horrific conditions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/sydney-to-hobart-conditions-set-to-be-ok/106176678</link><description>The Sydney to Hobart fleet is in for milder conditions this year than in 2024, when two people died on the first night of racing, although sailors have been warned to expect strong winds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">997b2e54e1de0f06c49f224650477ac0</guid></item><item><title>'Fake' letter and 'false claims' among latest Epstein files, US Justice Department says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/epstein-files-contain-fake-documents-us-justice-department-says/106173212</link><description>The US government says newly released documents from the Epstein files contain "untrue and sensationalist" claims about Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bef3e57d6bc4b93383de3f48852bb8d</guid></item><item><title>England investigates Ben Duckett Noosa video as disastrous Ashes tour takes another turn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/england-investigates-ben-duckett-noosa-video/106176788</link><description>A video said to feature Ben Duckett is under ECB investigation in another problem for England's disastrous Ashes tour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a005c9dfc957b64f8748c248130e1b6</guid></item><item><title>Sewage leak prompts Broadwater swimming warning ahead of Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/sewage-spill-broadwater-swimming-warning-gold-coast/106176726</link><description>Swimmers and boaties are being warned to avoid part of the Gold Coast Broadwater at Biggera Waters after a sewage leak just days out from Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2552642669cb5df34e8d569632c6cb66</guid></item><item><title>'$10,000 worth of Louis Vuitton' stolen in alleged home invasion at Old Beach, Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/10k-worth-of-louis-vuitton-stolen-old-beach-home-invasion/106176766</link><description>Two armed offenders allegedly forced the occupant of a house north of Hobart to open a safe, escaping with about $10,000 worth of Louis Vuitton items, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fe38a5f969582d221e1a535ed43e97a</guid></item><item><title>Girl, 12, critical after being pulled from water at Trigg Beach in Perth's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/girl-critical-after-being-pulled-from-water-at-trigg-beach-perth/106176930</link><description>A 12-year-old girl is in a critical condition after a surfer pulled her unresponsive from the water at Trigg Beach on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dc476927fc0183985b0e8c682a29246</guid></item><item><title>Young motorcyclist warns others after surviving high-speed crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/young-motorcyclist-warns-others-after-surviving-high-speed-crash/106174926</link><description>Liam Ganter does not remember the crash that nearly killed him, but he is living with the consequences, and hopes his story will stop others making the same mistake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75be536dbd463232b2f3e35ef40ba731</guid></item><item><title>Woman accused of 'repeatedly encouraging' partner to suicide granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/jacinta-drust-accused-encourage-suicide-granted-bail/106176852</link><description>An Adelaide woman accused of repeatedly encouraging her partner to take his own life has been granted home detention bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2aecc20ffe4f6337bc27a2b2f886f23</guid></item><item><title>WA Police charge man over alleged antisemitic comments on social media</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/wa-man-charged-over-alleged-antisemitic-comments-social-media/106177056</link><description>A WA man's eligibility to hold a gun license will be reviewed after police charged him with allegedly posting antisemitic comments on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98352c8c09ced2a521975680289691f9</guid></item><item><title>Man in his 30s dies in e-scooter accident in Geraldton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/geraldton-e-scooter-death/106176946</link><description>Police say a man has died after losing control of an e-scooter in Geraldton overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6e22dae3326e39867c80d88af856799</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged over fatal stabbing of Zac McRae at Western Sydney bus station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/nsw-zac-mcrae-stabbing-charges-laid-mount-druitt/106177144</link><description>Emergency services were called to a bus station at Mount Druitt in August to find two 19-year-old men with stab wounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67fb83b44626811fc8915990df3c02da</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Santa turns to an icy esky to beat Australia's sweltering Christmas heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/tropical-santa-goes-high-tech-to-beat-the-summer-heat/106121982</link><description>Santa Claus has devised a special ice esky throne to beat the heat in outback Australia this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cac732ffb7512f7adea92fe13ceb558</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after weapons, detonators allegedly found at Dublin property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/sa-man-charged-after-weapons-allegedly-found-at-dublin/106177098</link><description>A man has been charged after police allegedly seized explosive detonators and three unregistered firearms among other weapons from his property in Adelaide's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29bedf5020f9f578b2bc51f0e8088d88</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach gunmen's phone pinged near Philippine region known for Islamic extremism: police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/bondi-beach-shooter-pinged-near-philippines-extremist-region/106176954</link><description>Mobile phone data suggests the Bondi Beach gunmen may have travelled near a region in the Philippines where Islamic State-aligned militants could still be operating, a police source has told the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d612ea3d7aa44793790596fd88c30a31</guid></item><item><title>NSW premier says tougher gun, protest laws bolster safety as reforms take effect after Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/bondi-massacre-nsw-premier-chris-minns-reforms-will-continue/106176748</link><description>Premier Chris Minns says some of the tougher laws on guns and protests in the wake of the Bondi Beach attack will go into effect immediately after the NSW Parliament passed a package of changes in the early hours of Wednesday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cd68e7ae6fe0ba7f26eac10281f7987</guid></item><item><title>Low-income adults and children in jail denied lawyers over Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/legal-aid-nt-cancels-all-grants-of-aid-for-december/106176494</link><description>Legal Aid NT pauses all grants of aid for December, meaning people in the territory held in custody over Christmas — including children — will not have access to a legal aid lawyer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">740ca74252c85286eabe0390db4e2c46</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate alleged attack of Norwegian tourist on Melbourne's St Kilda Pier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/norwegian-tourist-attacked-st-kilda-pier/106177528</link><description>Police are searching for at least seven more people allegedly involved in an assault last Thursday, which left a Norwegian tourist with a broken arm and facial injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96f28abd7068699d673afb06c3d1af5f</guid></item><item><title>Concerns over abortion, vasectomies, IVF, gender-affirming care access as Catholic organisation Calvary buys Hobart Private</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/hobart-private-hospital-sale-calvary-abortion-concerns/106177108</link><description>The operator of the Hobart Private Hospital has agreed to sell the facility to Catholic healthcare provider Calvary, leading to concerns about access to surgical abortions, vasectomies and some other legal procedures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5430d43a7cde42fec16d598dafd02f8d</guid></item><item><title>England skipper Ben Stokes defends his team as Jofra Archer ruled out of Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/england-boxing-day-ben-stokes-noosa/106177474</link><description>England's disastrous Ashes tour has received another blow with Jofra Archer ruled out of the remaining two Tests while skipper Ben Stokes has dug in to defend his beleaguered team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d30958882c35c298deebc595e0fbf384</guid></item><item><title>Duress alarms given to councillors amid violent threats from public</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/panic-buttons-for-bendigo-councillors-amid-public-threats/106174996</link><description>Duress alarms, often used by healthcare workers in high-risk settings, are being handed out by a regional Victorian council to boost elected representatives' safety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">196582eef60cd6a7875f223de11cb3fe</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs veteran Geoffrey Shaw remembered as tireless advocate for Aboriginal rights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/vietnam-veteran-land-rights-champion-geoffrey-shaw-remembered/106177422</link><description>Alice Springs war veteran Geoffrey Shaw OAM has been remembered as a tireless advocate for Indigenous rights in Central Australia, who leaves a legacy of courage and service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9eadafd0e8f634cc10d6af15eb22c34</guid></item><item><title>Bomb-making list, firearms, extremist flags seized from Perth man accused of backing Bondi attackers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/bondi-attack-supporter-charged-in-perth-raid/106177710</link><description>Police found a bomb-making shopping list when they searched the home of a man who allegedly posted on social media that he supported the gunmen behind the Bondi terror attack, a Perth court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36521dccd8b218e73f0e8c2c3deeac09</guid></item><item><title>Cocos (Keeling) Islands residents bunker down as Tropical Cyclone Grant approaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/tropical-cyclone-grant-approaches-cocos-keeling-islands/106176598</link><description>Residents on a remote Indian Ocean territory are bunkering down and scrapping Christmas plans as Tropical Cyclone Grant approaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1820ed804954b120204ea851c62b1136</guid></item><item><title>Even in the markets, it's beginning to look like Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/finance-report-241225/106177792</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b4f9300c7f3d9aad335a7ab323c356c</guid></item><item><title>US and Ukraine reach consensus on key issues to end war with Russia but territorial disputes remain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/us-ukraine-reach-consensus-on-key-issues-to-end-war/106178118</link><description>President Volodymyr Zelenskyy has said that Ukraine has reached consensus with the US on key issues to end the war with Russia but sensitive issues around territorial control, along with the management of a nuclear power plant, still remain unresolved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05c4eb8bd99fe5b814901714a1641ea9</guid></item><item><title>US sanctions five Europeans involved in regulating tech companies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/european-countries-slam-us-visa-bans/106178152</link><description>Leaders in Germany, France, Spain and the European Union slam the move as "intimidation and coercion".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64e74175013c5e059816621ae0498780</guid></item><item><title>Christmas quiz: How well do you know traditional Christmas carols?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/christmas-songs-quiz-traditional-carols/106133808</link><description>Do you know your Merry Gentlemen from you Three Kings? Your Dancers from your Prancers?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">824d802373eed7060a62552b3ca0c026</guid></item><item><title>Rental Family offers connection in an increasingly polarised world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/brendan-fraser-rental-family-hikari/106156660</link><description>Academy Award-winner Brendan Fraser speaks to ABC News about his new film and why human connection is the antidote to an increasingly polarised world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64796142ed39b4c48912a9c0e0b1a59d</guid></item><item><title>Daniyl's journey through the Carpathian mountains to escape Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/daniyl-s-journey-through-the-carpathian-mountains/106165118</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d7ab5a934f950abe14d683115d0e5b6</guid></item><item><title>These young men fled Ukraine, but found a Europe far less welcoming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/young-men-fleeing-ukraine-russia-war-find-europe-less-welcoming/106164084</link><description>Since Russia launched its full-scale invasion in 2022 thousands of men have fled Ukraine. Once welcomed, they are increasingly finding a Europe that is running out of patience.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d905f9e1324bb3c59e9004f0528c536</guid></item><item><title>Gaza's remaining Christians mark Christmas with subdued celebrations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/gaza-remaining-christians-mark-christmas-subdued-celebrations/106177982</link><description>The small number of Christians remaining in Gaza have marked Christmas early with subdued celebrations in the shadow of ongoing conflict and occupation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eda5898dfa737111276df19f9aee72c4</guid></item><item><title>How political divides are putting more pressure on Australian couples</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/political-differences-pressure-australian-couples/106048876</link><description>More Australian relationships are struggling because of political divides. But experts say this does not have to be the end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfdae25d8b39d3f18ef6996ee10d6146</guid></item><item><title>Heat to ease but possible storms forecast for Christmas Day in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/qld-weather-christmas-day-heat-storms/106177236</link><description>Queensland's heat is expected to ease on Christmas Day but severe storms are possible around the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cf741f570f7f6a196ec1d1d9a969889</guid></item><item><title>What you need to know before you buy lab-grown versus natural diamonds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/what-to-know-about-laboratory-grown-and-natural-diamonds/106167962</link><description>Diamonds are generally considered a luxury asset that holds its value, but the emergence of laboratory-grown diamonds in the jewellery industry over recent years could challenge that belief.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24202eae3fcc5aaa1137df26f99527c9</guid></item><item><title>Second-hand shopping is a sustainable alternative, but could it be fuelling consumption?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/qld-second-hand-shopping-thrifting-consumption-apps/106173026</link><description>The rising popularity of second-hand and vintage fashion has been viewed as an opportunity to reduce fast fashion consumption; however, Australia remains one of the world's highest waste producers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71947152529f5c6dfc7368acdb22a6f8</guid></item><item><title>Friendsmas and local community celebrations combat loneliness this Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/combating-loneliness-friendsmas-community-connection-christmas/106154516</link><description>Despite our screens being filled with images of happy families celebrating Christmas, some feel the festive season is lonelier than ever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">964883e221f9338a291bbb9bca09a519</guid></item><item><title>'Aussie' poster in Adelaide vandalised with white supremacist message</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/racist-vandalism-of-aussie-poster-in-adelaide/106177068</link><description>An Adelaide street artist's poster aimed at provoking thought about national identity has been vandalised with racist graffiti.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72bd030ba7fd002b69b762b1060405de</guid></item><item><title>She readies for a 23rd Sydney to Hobart as the crew honours late owner Peter Rodgers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/sydney-to-hobart-she-peter-rodgers-memorial-race/106056430</link><description>A fellowship of sailors will embark on She's 23rd Sydney to Hobart campaign. As they do they will honour one of the most resilient boats in the race's history and remember late owner Peter Rodgers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e98f67c47d1cb8aba16c38df8cad139f</guid></item><item><title>Rising airfares forcing travellers to turn to trains and buses to get home for Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/christmas-travel-public-transport-vline-cost/106171426</link><description>Budget-conscious travellers are turning to long-haul trips on public transport to get home for Christmas, but overcrowding and delays in the regions can cause headaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">037999c1235fde4affd244b30665b5eb</guid></item><item><title>Oldest known Christian hymn with musical notation resurrected into modern church song</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/oldest-christian-hymn-with-music-transformed-modern-song/105748690</link><description>Songwriters living in ancient Egypt would never have expected the words and melodies they sung would feature on Australian music charts 1,800 years later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dbc93d44990fe46fd2c47d8b338dd70</guid></item><item><title>What athletes mean when they talk about 'flow state' or being 'in the zone'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/the-science-and-art-behind-flow-state-sport-music-maths/106172880</link><description>There is a state of mind athletes talk about when they are totally absorbed in the moment and the actions of their sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3dd60dd0ec9a1fb90c71aed61ccdaf6</guid></item><item><title>Aged care centre confronts racism, improves staff retention with cultural celebrations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/aged-care-centre-starts-cultural-celebrations-to-address-racism/106085844</link><description>In 2024 a nurse reported racist abuse from some residents and family members. A year later, instances of abuse have plummeted and staff say it is because of a new program promoting respect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">106bbaf745444b130937df055a3765c6</guid></item><item><title>A million more Epstein files found, US Justice Department says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/more-epstein-files-found-by-us-department-of-justice/106178284</link><description>The Department of Justice says the release of the Epstein files will take "a few more weeks" after a million additional documents were uncovered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">864b6e61dd0c9445d283aae091533e8b</guid></item><item><title>White House orders US forces to focus on 'quarantine' of Venezuelan oil, official says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/us-forces-to-quarantine-venezuelan-oil-as-un-condemns-aggression/106178276</link><description>The White House has ordered US military forces to focus almost exclusively on enforcing the "quarantine" of Venezuelan oil, a US official says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29c3a7ae3d0bfc2c7ac85c07e2b281fc</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Grant expected to remain category one system as it passes Cocos (Keeling) Islands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/tropical-cyclone-grant-impacts-cocos-islands-christmas-day/106178056</link><description>Tropical Cyclone Grant is expected to remain a category one system as it passes just to the north of the Cocos (Keeling) Islands off the West Australian coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ee3c8641c0d4437378e06a43346d1a2</guid></item><item><title>Australia's 'outback fashion capital' promotes healing through fashion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/fitzroy-crossing-fashion-event-helps-to-heal-community/106037952</link><description>Almost three years ago, a region in Western Australia's far north was devastated by once-in-a-century floods. Now fashion is stepping in, to heal scars and promote confidence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e3fc90c6543ea536adf803f980f1417</guid></item><item><title>Christmas morning snow in Tasmania, amid Western Australian heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/christmas-day-weather-snow-in-tasmania-heat-across-australia/106178338</link><description>Snow has arrived in the island state on Christmas morning, but hotter conditions are expected around the country, including a scorcher in the west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fb3eda7326f3e7bb000780545f48802</guid></item><item><title>Pope Leo XIV, in first Christmas mass, says denying help to poor is akin to refusing God</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/pope-leo-celebrates-christmas-as-people-return-to-bethlehem/106178358</link><description>Pope Leo XIV holds the first Christmas mass of his pontificate, greeting thousands of faithful in St Peter's Square before the Christmas Eve service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1bbfae3937aecf803eae27b469b4e63</guid></item><item><title>Regional woman bakes 500 Christmas cakes as part of mission to help children overseas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/regional-woman-bakes-500-christmas-cakes-to-fundraise/106038170</link><description>As households across the world sit down to enjoy a festive feast, Faye Taylor revels in knowing 500 of her traditional Christmas cakes are bringing enjoyment and helping raise funds for people in need.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1d9272ac74d75de39afea1a766dd2ca</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate fire attack on 'Happy Chanukah' car in St Kilda East</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/happy-chanukah-car-firebombing-on-christmas-day-in-st-kilda-east/106178444</link><description>Authorities were called to a St Kilda East residence about 3am, where a car with a sign celebrating the Jewish holiday had been set alight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25fe8d829748789520bc501f02af6f27</guid></item><item><title>Why is there a massive camera in this tiny outback town?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/why-is-there-a-massive-camera-in-this-tiny-outback-town-/106178014</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ad7e44111139ee42ee84852115b69d6</guid></item><item><title>Analogue camera technicians with decades of experience retiring amid boom in film photography</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/future-of-film-as-camera-repairers-retire/106012478</link><description>As film photography surges in popularity among younger generations, technicians who repair analogue cameras are retiring, raising concerns it will become a dying art.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f2260136cba1cb406538e0cd51e9a96</guid></item><item><title>Nick Bolkus, long-time Labor senator and Hawke-Keating-era minister, dies aged 75</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/nick-bolkus-obituary/106178484</link><description>Nick Bolkus, the long-time Labor senator who played an influential role in shaping Australia's migration policy under prime minister Paul Keating, has died aged 75.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2580267b3575e4e215ac342a2ffa5f6a</guid></item><item><title>Snow falls at Lake Dobson in Mount Field National Park, Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/snow-falls-at-lake-dobson-in-mount-field-national-park-tasmania/106178560</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98cc4e692a96144dbd75476e03ddcff8</guid></item><item><title>Filipino community embraces the nine days of Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/mky-filipino-christmas-celebrations/106174360</link><description>Music, food and a festive mood are what make a Filipino Christmas Mass unique, according to organisers of a north Queensland Simbang Gabi celebration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf4b404a1c61c86d432503673fad796a</guid></item><item><title>Public assemblies banned for 14 days across Sydney as police enforce new powers under protest laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/public-assemblies-banned-14-days-in-sydney-under-new-protest-law/106178406</link><description>The NSW Police Commissioner, Mal Lanyon, has activated new powers prescribed under changes to NSW protest laws sparked by the terrorist attack at Bondi Beach on December 14.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0ffae786ed4d39fb5070328bf4f1a2a</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Australia leaves out a spinner in all-pace bowling attack for MCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/australia-boxing-day-test-12-man-squad/106178630</link><description>With up to 10mm of grass on the MCG pitch, Australia has opted for a bold and historic option and left out offspinner Todd Murphy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa9a9b3b335c8c7dde4f63a8f42f6ad8</guid></item><item><title>Man dies after Christmas Eve stabbing in Perth suburb of Aubin Grove</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/fatal-christmas-eve-stabbing-aubin-grove-perth/106178672</link><description>Homicide squad detectives are investigating the fatal stabbing of a man near a shopping complex in Perth's southern suburbs late on Christmas Eve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c638a04f15a13913bbe52f2f05fe4a5d</guid></item><item><title>Charity, church services and cheer as Australians give back on Christmas Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/australia-christmas-holiday-capital-cities/106178302</link><description>Australians have marked another Christmas Day with solemnity and celebration, with churches full and beaches packed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f70f8edfcd35f2d1720c10f99c7f9ad4</guid></item><item><title>'Scandinavian sleep method' could help your bad sleep</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/scandinavian-sleep-method-hot-cold-doona-temperature/106171152</link><description>This arrangement allows couples to continue sleeping together while meeting each person's individual needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd2b759a8a0d6dd541f517639ef58108</guid></item><item><title>Video footage captures the impact from Tropical Cyclone Grant.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/tropical-cyclone-grant-cocos-island/106178752</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">619343f5951f3bcf18f8c49719ea7569</guid></item><item><title>The fire flared up after midday on Christmas Day.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/boddington-christmas-day-bushfire/106178762</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57b6c53fa04afab1895460d012d5a5bd</guid></item><item><title>Multiple bushfires threaten homes north and south of Perth, triggering power outages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/christmas-day-boddington-bushfire-emergency/106178756</link><description>Several bushfires burning north and south of Perth have caused major power blackouts, including the entire town of Margaret River.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02cd42472ece8c0d5742158fbddf1ee2</guid></item><item><title>Police make emergency declaration after partial crane collapse on the Gold Coast on Christmas Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/qld-crane-collapse-gold-coast-christmas-day/106178834</link><description>Storms hit south-east Queensland on Christmas Day afternoon, knocking out power to thousands of homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">554a17c52ea5b34c83e1e5244c87a2a7</guid></item><item><title>A crane was damaged in the Gold Coast on Christmas Day afternoon after a storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/gold-coast-crane-collapse-christmas-day/106178856</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0b1ca785822b99d4a35df4fa8e11bf7</guid></item><item><title>Pope Leo decries conditions in Gaza during Christmas Day speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/pope-leo-decries-conditions-in-gaza-christmas-speech/106178920</link><description>During his Urbi et Orbi (city and world) speech on Christmas Day, Pope Leo XIV has called for an end to all wars and for people to think about the conditions in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1023451f4ca1f78f346c0e2c228d714b</guid></item><item><title>King Charles pays homage to acts of 'spontaneous bravery' in Christmas Day message</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/king-charles-pays-homage-to-bondi-bravery-in-christmas-message/106176872</link><description>King Charles III pays homage to those who confronted terror at the Bondi Beach massacre, acknowledging their "spontaneous acts of bravery" in his annual Christmas message.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d976b5e35ca80ce775947a9f3227240b</guid></item><item><title>The marathon mums competing in the Olympics and breaking records postpartum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/marathon-mums-competing-olympics-breaking-records-postpartum/106158638</link><description>For decades, pregnancy was seen as an "injury" that could end a career. But now, determination and growing industry support are seeing marathon-running mothers reach new heights after giving birth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">911ad6e201fbaac1ec3430b377f3fe12</guid></item><item><title>From Spongebob to Orwell: Here's your guide to Boxing Day movies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/what-to-watch-boxing-day-cinemas/106170510</link><description>The soaring mercury has you craving the cool, dark sanctuary of the cinema. But what to see? The art-house awards-season hopeful? The psychological book adaptation? The one with the big snake?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0067604e8d12d4c660cec1c700395679</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 26: Babe Ruth is sold to the Yankees to start the 'Curse of the Bambino'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/today-in-history-babe-ruth-is-sold-from-red-sox-to-the-yankees/106135072</link><description>It was the deal that changed the face of baseball for good, and set in motion the most infamous sporting curse of all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e5ab3496ff758523bc2b53626c7ae12</guid></item><item><title>Before Prince Harry fled the Royals there was love-sick Edward</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/royal-family-prince-edward-history-love-harry/105522404</link><description>Before Harry fled the Royals for Meghan and Montecito, this would-be King of England was famous for trading his title for love. And the cracks began to show on a trip to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0ca9182ddc5496c024a43a96389693c</guid></item></channel></rss>