<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:05:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Roger Allers, co-director of The Lion King, dies aged 76</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/co-director-of-lion-king-roger-allers-dies/106244066</link><description>Roger Allers was known for working on various Disney films including The Lion King, The Little Mermaid and Aladdin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a0ef8a277b8d386b9b932a2c9c5d992</guid></item><item><title>Elphinstone Engineering director sentenced for interfering with Aboriginal relics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/graeme-elphinstone-allegations-interfere-with-aboriginal-sites/106243968</link><description>Graeme Elphinstone, the founder and director of Elphinstone Engineering, avoids conviction and is fined $12,000 for interfering with Aboriginal relics on his land on Tasmania's east coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ad5307c820eb3687e361788dd9c66bf</guid></item><item><title>Storm Hunter wins at Australian Open after thinking her career was over</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australian-open-storm-hunter-reaches-second-round/106244620</link><description>A ruptured Achilles tendon threatened to send Storm Hunter into retirement, but her perseverance pays off with a first-round victory in Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fa04a6d2e7099ffe2cd1b1e136b11dc</guid></item><item><title>Petition asks Alice Springs Public Library to extend opening hours amid outback heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/nt-petition-alice-springs-public-library-weekend-opening-hours/106244058</link><description>In one of Australia's hottest towns, the library is an important air-conditioned public space offering a no-cost respite from burning summer temperatures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48234b555f036ba2f92ff1804e8371f6</guid></item><item><title>Bondi survivor Ya'akov Tetleroyd lost his father and nearly his arm in Bondi Beach terrorism event. He forgives the gunmen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/bondi-terror-survivor-yaakov-tetleroyd-speaks-naveed-akram/106238196</link><description>Ya'akov Tetleroyd's father died in the Bondi Beach shootings. He nearly lost his arm as a result of being shot, yet he told 7.30 in an exclusive interview that he forgives the gunmen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">036a2c4738ac88afd5123eda6fe48589</guid></item><item><title>WA is losing the tobacco wars as gangs target vape stores and cheap cigarettes flood market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/wa-losing-the-fight-to-control-illegal-cigarettes/106242556</link><description>Burnt out storefronts in Perth and regional cities are testament to the government's inability to control the illegal tobacco trade — and it's not clear when things will change, writes Keane Bourke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">280b53748e89776c07bee7fd574bc253</guid></item><item><title>What has caused a 'smack' of jellyfish to wash up on Melbourne's south-eastern beaches?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/lions-mane-jellyfish-melbourne-port-phillip-bay/106244362</link><description>Visitors to Melbourne's south-eastern beaches over the weekend were surprised to see an influx of crimson jellyfish bobbing in the water. One expert says a "perfect storm" of factors has brought them to the coastline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e313ec9d19ef5439121c1957e9127cd9</guid></item><item><title>Nicolas Cage shrine amid weird pranks at Mount Gambier deputy mayor's home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/mount-gambier-deputy-mayor-celebrity-letterbox-mystery/106245108</link><description>A Nicolas Cage-themed shrine is the latest of a series of celebrity-themed pranks that Mount Gambier's deputy mayor says have befallen his home in recent weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">613d4d6f79a342e68fef76235e90f105</guid></item><item><title>Monday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106245916</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bfd8c1fab3cd958260d324a03f7b0f3</guid></item><item><title>Teenage boy dies of injuries at bottom of cliff near Jerrabomberra Waterhole</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/act-teenager-dies-at-jerrabomberra-waterhole-bottom-of-cliff/106246244</link><description>A member of the public tried to perform CPR on a teenage boy suffering serious injuries at the bottom of a cliff near Canberra, but he died at the scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e11e9a0e318dcb3d76efc7eef5c7678</guid></item><item><title>Man faces court after 2kg of meth seized in Katherine roadside drug bust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/katherine-drug-bust-meth-allegedly-bound-for-darwin/106245962</link><description>A 22-year-old man has faced court after police allegedly found 2 kilograms of methamphetamine, along with large quantities of other drugs, during a traffic stop in Katherine last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98effadd199406586f274ffc8312e87e</guid></item><item><title>Helicopter at North Steyne Beach after shark attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/helicopter-at-north-steyne-beach-after-shark-attack/106246484</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">593dba8cca07aa1b05943aea09a7b2b3</guid></item><item><title>What is it like to live and work in the Antarctic?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/living-and-working-in-the-antarctic/106246052</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d13273f34a29dd8e349e41e8e456cd05</guid></item><item><title>Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi to dissolve parliament and call snap election for February 8</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/japan-prime-minister-calls-snap-general-election/106246400</link><description>Japanese Prime Minister ⁠Sanae Takaichi will ​dissolve parliament ‌on ‌Friday ‌and call a snap ​election for February 8 ⁠to seek voter backing ‌for her ​spending ​plans and ‍other ⁠policies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6762019ff9f76327ee529684d85c451</guid></item><item><title>Victim Tanya urges alleged Mullewa shooter Kenneth Giles to come home safe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/mullewa-shooting-victim-makes-public-statement/106246464</link><description>In her first statement since she was shot through the hand on January 7, Tanya says she wants Kenneth Giles to know she wants him to return home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d217f22671f03c4ca8f601a436780f7b</guid></item><item><title>Philippines star Alexandra Eala sends Australian Open crowds into a frenzy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australian-open-alexandra-eala-philippines-melbourne-park/106246520</link><description>Alexandra Eala, ranked 49 in the world, attracts a crowd that virtually brought the Australian Open to a standstill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed8e4fa5d5e748dd1e7b20e436cc5910</guid></item><item><title>Man critical after being bitten by a shark in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/man-critical-after-being-bitten-by-a-shark-in-sydney/106246594</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e136a9efd0474d1502b11b3ec4dc15a</guid></item><item><title>Prince Harry's court battle against British tabloids reaches final chapter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/prince-harry-returns-to-court-in-battle-with-british-tabloids/106246678</link><description>Prince Harry has returned to court in London in his third and final attempt to tame the British tabloids through the legal system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">370456cf33716b09f3e36a9a21e41ba5</guid></item><item><title>Italian fashion designer Valentino dies aged 93 in Rome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/italian-fashion-designer-valentino-dies-aged-93-in-rome/106247130</link><description>The fashion icon's creations were adored by Hollywood stars, royals and first ladies for his fail-safe red carpet designs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46af3ffb2731ac5d3650837108493b36</guid></item><item><title>EPA asks Victorians to check water quality before swimming in Port Phillip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/port-phillip-bay-water-quality-summer-beach-reports-epa/106158836</link><description>Victoria's Environment Protection Authority says people wanting to cool off at bay beaches this summer should stay across its regular pollution updates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea04c727cb0b034491d7cd8c93a10cc6</guid></item><item><title>Oak Tasmania issued $1.1m penalty over hundreds of NDIS compliance failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/tas-ndis-provider-1-1m-penalty-for-breaches/106246414</link><description>Oak Tasmania admits to 474 compliance and reporting failures, as well as breaches that resulted in the hospitalisation of multiple NDIS clients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9e88e8b1c262ca731e0c1c273ec6e75</guid></item><item><title>How lifting gave me back the power to feel good at sport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/how-powerlifting-gave-me-back-the-power-to-feel-good-at-sport/106234088</link><description>As a child, Julie "wasn't one of the sporty kids". A safe gym environment and then a supportive powerlifting community helped her realise that wasn't actually true.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2abbef65f571e75069d3d1abdc6f375</guid></item><item><title>Labor 'really close' to deal with Liberals on hate speech laws, Tony Burke says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/labor-coalition-hate-laws-deal-deadline-looms/106244300</link><description>Liberal MPs gathered to discuss the draft laws at a party room meeting in Canberra on Monday evening after Opposition Leader Sussan Ley and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese met to hash out an agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a2526f58a5d9b6415bdab9d0bbe190d</guid></item><item><title>China ramps up crackdown on Christians amid global political pressures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/china-ramps-up-crackdown-on-underground-christian-churches/106228908</link><description>Dozens of church leaders and members have been arrested in China in recent months, which advocates say is indicative of intensifying persecution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c54c22a63990022797415619510f9303</guid></item><item><title>China's population declines for a fourth straight year amid record low birthrates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/china-population-decline-fourth-straight-year/106245406</link><description>National data shows that in 2025, China's population shrank by 3.39 million people, as experts warn the trend is likely to continue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5e802e05f3c7a95834eb029793b0ed4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump heading to Davos as bond market vigilantes plot against him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/donald-trump-us-federal-reserve-powell-interest-rates/106245010</link><description>There are signs Donald Trump's bold strategy to artificially lower interest rates could backfire, as a level of disquiet emerges on money markets, particularly in bonds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65e936bbb965d193d01d5df138ff1bd8</guid></item><item><title>First Nations employee asked by supervisor about eating ants takes transport department to court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/sa-transport-department-federal-court-case/106231982</link><description>A First Nations employee at South Australia's Department for Infrastructure and Transport (DIT) has claimed she was sexually harassed by her supervisor and racially discriminated against when asked about eating ants before a cultural training session, court documents reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7374c2347019e1b32db9a67988ee3efb</guid></item><item><title>New Trump tariffs on European allies could push EU to use 'trade bazooka'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/trump-tariffs-european-allies-trade-bazooka/106243894</link><description>Following the Trump administration's recent tariff threat on European allies, some experts warn it may push Europe closer to China, and potentially see the European Union use its anti-coercion instrument, also known as a "trade bazooka", in response.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfd83a0c8c002868f5bb1a1d952c2109</guid></item><item><title>Victorian bushfires squeeze beekeeper access to high-quality trees for bees ahead of winter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/victoria-bushfires-beekeeper-access-restrictions/106243830</link><description>Apiarists in Victoria are wondering how they will keep their bees fed during winter after bushfires two years in a row render certain areas inaccessible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53ba80cd946bb3fbcb843855ca6d35a4</guid></item><item><title>Dissecting Donald Trump's Greenland message to Norway's PM, line by line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/donald-trump-greenland-message-analysed-line-by-line/106246964</link><description>A text message from the US president to Norway's prime minister has fanned the flames of the geopolitical dumpster fire engulfing Greenland. We've analysed Donald Trump's claims to see if they stack up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81dd92b61485bb709c037d07f0241a9b</guid></item><item><title>Women's captain departs football club after men's offensive Silly Saturday costumes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/box-hill-north-fc-womens-captain-leaves-club-after-men-behaviour/106190266</link><description>A women's senior football captain has stepped away from her local club after photos of the senior men's leadership team were posted online during their "Silly Saturday" post-season celebrations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ffb103fdb7886c68801e2562aeef8ca</guid></item><item><title>Stan Wawrinka's impressive win, a wheelchair exit and Alja Tomljanović tells off her dad — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/australian-open-2026-quick-hits/106243998</link><description>One player had to be wheeled off the courts in a wheelchair, while Alja Tomljanović was wishing her dad would be quiet in the crowd. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5d4a55ec566caaa313f28eb7c9913b7</guid></item><item><title>Ipswich residents frustrated as nickel waste stored near homes without council approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/ipswich-residents-nickelwaste-dumped-nearhomes-council-approval/106244714</link><description>The dumping of the waste is the latest in a series of similar events for Ipswich, the city which some now call "Australia's waste capital".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">098856adadd618e6d5f95435a562ca83</guid></item><item><title>Shellharbour mayor's quick thinking during call may have saved deputy's life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/shellharbour-councillor-kellie-marsh-aneurysm-emergency/106245410</link><description>A mayor's split-second decision to answer a phone call instead of heading into the surf may well have saved the life of his deputy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d92c75f46d2dd5048aa680d5e3e2bc68</guid></item><item><title>Foo Fighters are playing their only Australian show in Launceston on Saturday, here's what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/foo-fighters-launceston-concert-what-you-need-to-know/106243618</link><description>Tasmania's "biggest ever concert" is heating up Launceston this weekend, and whether you have tickets or not, there are a few things you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">756623b97549184033b8460854e8b087</guid></item><item><title>Alexei Popyrin shattered as Australian Open campaign ends in first round following thriller against Alexandre Muller</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/tennis-aus-open-popyrin-shattered-muller-defeat/106247208</link><description>Alexei Popyrin concedes he will look inwards once again to think about his career after a crushing loss sent him out of the Australian Open in the first round.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f28d48e2dc361558508277915e9e9d5c</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: PM defends action on antisemitism in QT as debate kicks off in Senate — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/federal-politics-live-blog-jan-20/106245678</link><description>The prime minister defends the government's action on antisemitism in the first Question Time of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce2a21bbf58cf609b34b039baf956196</guid></item><item><title>Man found dead in back of car near Corowa hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/dead-body-found-car-corowa-hospital/106247200</link><description>A police investigation is underway after a man was found dead inside a car near a hospital on the NSW–Victoria border.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffbe1c57c1a4bb08978725b53ff36d04</guid></item><item><title>'Promising' results for AI fish passage aiming to help stop another Menindee mass fish kill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/ai-fish-passage-fishnet-darling-river-trial-mass-fish-kill-nsw/106221776</link><description>The $6.5 million Menindee fish passage trial is now in year two and results are "promising", but not everyone is buoyed by confidence in the project's ability to prevent another mass fish kill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">189c0bfe4dba5512db02a22c6a101b9f</guid></item><item><title>ASX trades down, BHP shares slide, IMF calls out Australia's 'drawn-out' inflation — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-tuesday-20-january/106247268</link><description>The ASX trades down on Tuesday. The International Monetary Fund says Australia, alongside Norway, is projected to see persistent above-target inflation. Follow the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9583dd3a472f2001cb9f12c33d757786</guid></item><item><title>Front lines in 'ghost net' war expand to Australia's north with $25m funding boost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/ghost-nets-funding-remote-nt-blue-mud-bay-indonesia-fishing/106244780</link><description>A $25 million funding injection will help expand the Top End's war on ghost nets, as ranger groups shift focus to the heavily fished seas to Australia's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">486f3c79d2cb26ac2906752d5be6b54c</guid></item><item><title>WA Opposition Leader Basil Zempilas seizes on fishing, tobacco to challenge government's dominance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/basil-zempilas-fishing-ban-tobacco-challenge-state-government/106246436</link><description>While many West Australians were competing for parking spots at beaches on their holidays, Basil Zempilas latched onto two hot topics on which to challenge the government — the demersal fishing ban and WA's illicit tobacco trade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e3968683f38c8c701336ac2ede5ca0d</guid></item><item><title>Attempted murder charges laid, firearm recovered after Huntfield Heights shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/attempted-murder-charges-over-huntfield-heights-shooting/106247230</link><description>A man and a woman are expected to face court after each was charged with two counts of attempted murder over a shooting at a Huntfield Heights home that left two people in hospital, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">728ff3de3a647b50be77716cf4db2799</guid></item><item><title>Pilbara water sources drying up as blistering heatwave continues in Karratha</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/harding-dam-karratha-low-water-storage-levels-heatwave/106237810</link><description>Water sources are depleting in the Pilbara as the arid region endures a summer with little rainfall and temperatures close to 50C.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42ae93a704d37666b5838230f66f76df</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane suffers vaccine shortages after wall collapses at Toll Group distribution centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/brisbane-hit-by-vaccine-shortages/106247402</link><description>Brisbane parents are being turned away from GP clinics due to a shortage of childhood vaccines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95c7e8806a61ca804b73a3bea4054c5a</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026: Naomi Osaka sends a fashion statement, Dane Sweeny and James Duckworth progress</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/australian-open-2026-live-updates-jannik-sinner-naomi-osaka/106247690</link><description>Seeing Naomi Osaka don a jellyfish-inspired outfit was one highlight of day three of the tournament, however two plucky Australians — Dane Sweeny and James Duckworth also put on a show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0df00c26a62e3ee2d269780de89c116</guid></item><item><title>Eraring coal-fired power station to stay open until 2029</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/eraring-coal-fired-power-station-to-stay-open-until-2029/106247568</link><description>The operator of Australia's largest coal-fired power station is to extend the life of its plant in the NSW Hunter Valley for another two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa4566311697a925b7bfb77a6bef8f96</guid></item><item><title>Dual British-Australian citizens look to renounce UK nationality over new passport entry rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/dual-british-australian-citizens-look-to-renounce-uk-passport/106244606</link><description>Frustrated dual British-Australian citizens are weighing up their options in response to new passport rules. Here's why some are letting go of their British citizenship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f630d2fdf57d7fc38a6673bde5c08450</guid></item><item><title>How a lion crushed a Datsun with newlyweds inside in 1970s Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/lion-crushed-datsun-newlyweds-adelaide-bullens-safari-park/106245924</link><description>The pair had made an on-the-spot decision on the way home from their honeymoon to visit a drive-through safari park where lions roamed free — and their little brown Datsun came out worse for wear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43ee7f7f3d6b74a70e1cd8189e8b25db</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged with attempted murder after child allegedly stabbed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/child-with-knife-wounds-flown-to-melbourne-for-treatment/106248002</link><description>Police are investigating after a child presented to the Launceston General Hospital with serious injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a596a4f476857f12bbadc0a70f6d9bc</guid></item><item><title>Jessica Pegula reveals what goes on inside the Australian Open locker room</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/australian-open-melbourne-park-jessica-pegula-locker-room/106247748</link><description>According to Jessica Pegula, sometimes it is best to stay out of your opponent's way when you are sharing the same locker room.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a1c583886473dd9b6f5188701bb226f</guid></item><item><title>Increase in suspicious fires puts emergency services under pressure in WA's South West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/south-west-wa-suspicious-fires-arson-increase/106224380</link><description>A growing number of suspicious fires left police and firefighters under significant pressure over the Christmas period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d791a57fff1587aacc6ed5ba010c0fb7</guid></item><item><title>Labor's hate laws pass despite a divided Coalition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/hate-laws-poised-to-pass-after-labor-liberal-deal/106248432</link><description>The federal government has passed new laws targeting hate groups with support from the Liberals, while the Nationals voted against it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b34a07a73e9a13ce0ed28c59db72ba8d</guid></item><item><title>Canadian 19-year-old found dead on K'gari (Fraser Island) identified as Piper James</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/increased-ranger-patrols-woman-found-dead-on-kgari-fraser-island/106247890</link><description>The woman was found surrounded by dingoes after going for an early-morning swim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dacce30c93163641174c887bd95d813</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder over death of Maffra jeweller Steve Curtis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/maffra-death-investigation-homicide-squad/106247384</link><description>A 45-year-old man has been charged with murder following the death of a 63-year-old man in the Gippsland town of Maffra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e35864efde16cf45eb55cc09727ebd2</guid></item><item><title>Brain cancer survivor who finished year 12 hoping medication can get PBS listing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/brain-cancer-survivor-hoping-medication-can-get-pbs-listing/106163562</link><description>Just over a year ago Sienna was shocked to discover she had a rare brain cancer. She's taking a new drug to slow its growth, but it's come at great cost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21adf0d155fecef77dd6873776191137</guid></item><item><title>Man, 29, charged with bushland murder of Matthew O'Brien</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/police-nowra-suspicious-murder-man-charged/106205866</link><description>Police have charged a 29-year-old man after the alleged murder of a 60-year-old man, who was found with serious head injuries on a fire trail in Nowra in December 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1717537b3d9e2a3f71c8e00e16ab753a</guid></item><item><title>French media releases new security footage of thieves in Louvre heist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/new-security-footage-of-louvre-heist-released/106248086</link><description>The security footage shows the thieves smashing the glass on the display cases where the jewellery was kept.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9556ee4895b887312e1e10433709e155</guid></item><item><title>Gilmour Space receives federal funding boost for homegrown rockets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/gilmour-space-funding-boost-for-homegrown-rockets/106247624</link><description>The company hailed the launch of its first Australian designed and manufactured rocket a success, despite it being airborne for just 14 seconds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ef86a9d002caca346cff368daa291fc</guid></item><item><title>Parole Board seeks judicial review of decision blocking release of Snowtown killer James Vlassakis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/parole-board-judicial-review-james-vlassakis-parole-decision/106244864</link><description>South Australia's Parole Board has confirmed it will lodge an application for a judicial review of the decision to keep the youngest of the Snowtown killers James Vlassakis behind bars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5708fe33c430b65e04fbfc33b4e0012</guid></item><item><title>Writers' Week replacement likened to 'thought bubble', but backer says it is 'happening regardless'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/adelaide-council-votes-on-writers-week-alternative/106247520</link><description>Adelaide City Council commits to supporting, but not funding, a replacement event to fill the void left by Writers' Week, as the lord mayor describes the proposal as "not much more" than a "thought bubble".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03b47a20c6ad1ec840fbc6a6d97cd5de</guid></item><item><title>Brooklyn Beckham has cut ties with his famous parents. What can we learn from it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/brooklyn-beckham-statement-cuts-ties-with-family/106247778</link><description>Celebrity family rifts are not new. Experts weigh in on how they can spark negative feelings about our own family dynamics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b2cd51e90201aa458b1662acb5a3c4c</guid></item><item><title>Four shark attacks in 48 hours on NSW beaches. What do we know about them?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/nsw-what-we-know-about-the-shark-attacks/106248186</link><description>Four shark attacks are documented within 48 hours at beaches across New South Wales, lifting the anxieties of swimmers and surfers who are considering a dip in the ocean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdd09d7f88d80c01ef397e46b5b0f25f</guid></item><item><title>One Nation's ambitious plan raises stakes for major parties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/pauline-hanson-one-nation-polling-state-election-mainstream/106244024</link><description>While she's made no secret of her desire to eventually unseat Anthony Albanese, the One Nation leader's immediate electoral strategy is to gain ground at upcoming state elections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9378de660f955ea3ba520a0ae352651f</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police commissioner extends Sydney protest restrictions with 'significantly limited' scope</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/nsw-police-update-on-public-assembly-restriction-declaration-law/106248964</link><description>NSW Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon has announced restrictions on protests in parts of the state will be extended.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97b157a8e4854c3a779102cd09f55e8f</guid></item><item><title>Three federal politicians demand incoming NT administrator David Connolly apologise for 'offensive' posts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/nt-administrator-david-connolly-criticised-by-labor-politicians/106248300</link><description>Past social media posts made by incoming Northern Territory administrator David Connolly have been labelled "reprehensible" by three federal politicians, who are also demanding he apologise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5197dd5fd318bec2e8fec957cce707e5</guid></item><item><title>Maya Joint vows to 'come back stronger' after early Australian Open exit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/australian-open-maya-joint-loses-first-round/106249028</link><description>Maya Joint's first Australian Open appearance as a seed did not go according to plan, following a straight-sets defeat on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d1cfb70cdfd67e0e62683a684a60cf7</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic penguin breeding cycles changing rapidly in response to climate change, study shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/antarctic-penguin-breeding-cycles-changing-climate-change/106247472</link><description>Penguins in parts of Antarctica are breeding up to two weeks earlier than a decade ago, likely in response to climate change, according to a long-term study.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">195f7747bf8736cce5a600570b4a107c</guid></item><item><title>Surf webcam captures moment of shark attack at North Steyne beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/surf-webcam-captures-moment-of-shark-attack/106249880</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3383f67b3bfc1661108740bd4f07b134</guid></item><item><title>Valentino's legacy as 'one of the last true titans' of Italian fashion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/valentino-remembered-as-titan-of-fashion-industry-after-death/106247774</link><description>"Valentino red", now synonymous with the Italian designer, was introduced to the world in 1959. But it wasn't until years later he commanded true global attention — and with an entirely different dress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">650b53dff8ce0884258262001076422b</guid></item><item><title>Blue Mountains council closes Lincoln's Rock lookout after safety concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/popular-lookout-lincolns-rock-in-blue-mountains-closed/106245326</link><description>A council will shut an iconic Blue Mountains cliff after being overrun with tourists, sparking serious safety and environmental concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ada72b20a8c3f9c6a85fe9134a0fc19f</guid></item><item><title>Hawthorn's Will Day to miss first half of the AFL season with shoulder injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/will-day-hawthorn-shoulder-injury-return-afl/106250104</link><description>Hawthorn star Will Day is set for a lengthy stint on the sidelines after dislocating his right shoulder during pre-season training and undergoing surgery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d307d6fe71f40e6d700287b246f166</guid></item><item><title>Sydney NDIS provider director accused of $3.6m fraud as cash seized at home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/ndis-provider-director-allegedly-defrauded-millions-from-claims/106249802</link><description>Australian Federal Police allege Billal Chami submitted claims for supports and services never provided to participants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df504b690a294a5a80851df23bf1f1ff</guid></item><item><title>CCTV of kitten dumping in Adelaide's north-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/cctv-of-kitten-dumping-in-adelaide-s-north-east/106250206</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a12459f3ea305052690e39c57ca7bc71</guid></item><item><title>Thousands in Albany told to switch to LPG bottles as gas supplier ATCO decommissions network</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/albany-gas-network-to-be-decommissioned/106246382</link><description>The Albany mayor says the city has been blindsided by a decision to decommission the local gas network and transition thousands of customers onto bottled LPG gas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f1c800231c6ac81005eafc6625d1958</guid></item><item><title>Midnight Oil founder and drummer Rob Hirst dies aged 70</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/midnight-oil-drummer-rob-hirst-dies/106249816</link><description>Rob Hirst was diagnosed with pancreatic cancer in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b535d98e30538a1047c5fa6e1db1103a</guid></item><item><title>Do Woolworths shoppers want Google AI adding items to buy? We'll soon find out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/woolworths-google-ai-items-shopping-groceries/106243642</link><description>Without scrutiny, agent-led shopping risks quietly reconfiguring consumer behaviour in ways that are difficult to detect — and even harder to reverse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e87faa771f8a6692e3910d20b01de1f</guid></item><item><title>Is there a 'normal' amount of sex couples should be having?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/defining-a-healthy-and-fulfilling-sex-life/106100374</link><description>Whether it's TV shows or what our friends say, we pick up an idea of "normal" sex frequency from lots of places. But experts say how often you're having sex doesn't tell you much about whether it's satisfying or enjoyable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d933f11a6d491d896029179c92bdd34a</guid></item><item><title>Helen Manuell changed careers in her 50s from bridal design to sustainable fashion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/helen-manuell-fashion-designer-bridal-knitwear-rmit/106231758</link><description>Helen Manuell changed career paths in her 50s, swapping bridal couture for award-winning sustainable fashion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e16e712493ce4cb02d37d38df466c8c</guid></item><item><title>Maggot-infested meal halts work at $1 billion hydro project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/maggot-meal-halts-work-at-1-billion-dollar-hydro-project/106248782</link><description>An investigation into a maggot-infested meal halts work on a key pumped hydro project in North Queensland, with more than 100 workers flown out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b40fe65ed30e5a5b4dd8904eac05d5b4</guid></item><item><title>Queensland health services report financial black hole of almost $1 billion as population booms and ages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/qld-health-blowout-hospital-report/106249992</link><description>The combined deficit of Queensland's health department and 16 hospital and health services in 2024-25 was the worst ever reported in the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3746f384ecbd30edd186f8342ee71689</guid></item><item><title>WA environmental regulator recommends controversial Valhalla gas project go-ahead in Kimberley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/epa-recommends-kimberley-valhalla-exploration-program/106249136</link><description>Traditional owners and environmental groups are calling on the premier and environment minister to reject a controversial proposal to explore gas wells in the Kimberley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">683106aca3d30f27f33ee8e89400d1ee</guid></item><item><title>WA government calls for unity on firearm reforms as Liberal-led states reject national gun buyback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/wa-government-calls-for-unity-on-national-gun-buyback/106248706</link><description>The state government responsible for the Australia's toughest gun laws calls for unity on national reform, as the path forward splinters along party lines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0030b578d133022842e75741ad8e1891</guid></item><item><title>MPs can still take partners and children on work trips under new family travel rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/tribunal-sets-new-rules-for-mp-family-travel-entitlements/106249928</link><description>Politicians can still charge taxpayers for taking their partners and children on work-related trips outside Canberra under tighter new rules set independently.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35e2b1c6ca69c87c7b30de8c2a9e5b9e</guid></item><item><title>Hobart Hurricanes lose captain Nathan Ellis and Test batsman Jake Weatherald for Big Bash knockout final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/two-big-names-to-miss-bbl-knockout-final/106250756</link><description>Hobart's quest for back-to-back Big Bash titles has copped two major blows with captain Nathan Ellis and Test player Jake Weatherald to miss the Hurricanes' knockout final against Melbourne Renegades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b67761843ab9ed0f2e8dd6d75d499e78</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106250606</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b179e9dbc02bc38323324d62e839d0c7</guid></item><item><title>Shooting by ICE agents in Minnesota incites national US protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/shooting-by-ice-agents-in-minnesota-incites-national-us-protests/106250340</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01a9fa2297e01249d676f26d03b97ef0</guid></item><item><title>Farmers Federation slams WA's heritage laws as 'a complete mess' and questions enforcement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/wa-heritage-laws-wafarmers-federation-tony-maddox/106248572</link><description>A WA government department says it does not intend to prosecute media outlets for taking photographs of a protected Aboriginal site as part of their reporting on a breach of WA's controversial heritage laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ace3e524c4018e818db338a1f8c0d71d</guid></item><item><title>'Large bull camels weighing hundreds of kilos' move into NT communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/feral-camels-central-australia-remote-communities-damage/106248412</link><description>Hundreds of large bull camels descend on remote communities in Central Australia, causing damage to infrastructure in their search for water and prompting calls for federal assistance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43d75c5a1a874b826f57496ac88ef705</guid></item><item><title>Sam Watson wins Tour Down Under prologue, Jay Vine finishes fourth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/sam-watson-tour-down-under-prologue/106250080</link><description>British rider Sam Watson claimed a blisteringly quick Tour Down Under prologue time-trial victory, but Jay Vine took significant time out of his rivals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cca457f29cf44973a50c9e12485cf089</guid></item><item><title>Dame Marie Bashir, the first female governor of NSW, dies aged 95</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/dame-marie-bashir-the-first-female-nsw-governor-dies/106251006</link><description>NSW Premier Chris Minns says a state funeral will be held for the veteran public servant, who he describes as "an extraordinary Australian".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d45edad039d595addb9c09ed06d80e5e</guid></item><item><title>UK backs plan for China's new embassy in London at Royal Mint Court, despite spy fears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/chinese-embassy-in-london-approved-by-uk-government/106251004</link><description>The new embassy will sit in the city's Royal Mint Court alongside London's famous financial hub, despite experts and human rights groups raising concerns about foreign interference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e4e8511161243507bfe43ef3dc5c285</guid></item><item><title>California Governor Gavin Newsom warns US allies against 'rolling over' to Trump amid Greenland crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/newsom-mocks-european-leaders-greenland/106251248</link><description>As European leaders struggle to come up with ways to ease the US president's ambition for a take over of Greenland, a prominent Democrat is accusing them of "rolling over".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c329ff341053c9d7904a28a94d92f51</guid></item><item><title>Baby killer Lucy Letby to face no further criminal charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/lucy-letby-to-face-no-further-criminal-charges/106251330</link><description>The UK's Crown Prosecution Service says it considered the offences of murder or attempted murder in relation to the deaths of nine babies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85b230bf61be118577d731c9fc2899bf</guid></item><item><title>David Beckham breaks silence after son Brooklyn cuts ties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/david-beckham-brooklyn-davos-children-make-mistakes/106251360</link><description>The soccer superstar tells broadcasters at the World Economic Forum that "children are allowed to make mistakes" in his first public comments since his son's allegations went public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eea9ba1d2b7ca4efca871fee6767d24b</guid></item><item><title>From small cuttings to large pots, household plants are being stolen in great numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/plant-theft-greenery-being-stolen-garden-items-data/106092428</link><description>Data shows more than 2,000 items were reported stolen from gardens over a year in one state alone. So what can plant owners do to protect their beloved greenery from theft?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c928230238105d96554ef20638daf04c</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, January 21: The first time the Williams sisters faced off in a Grand Slam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/first-time-venus-serena-williams-face-off-grand-slam-1998/106200228</link><description>On this day in 1998, Venus and Serena Williams faced off for the first time at a Grand Slam tournament, starting an iconic sibling rivalry that would last two decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e3c726e7b71f131c95ac512dde4ff6b</guid></item><item><title>Home buyer says scheme does not work after setbacks buying old and building new</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/myhome-home-ownership-scheme-setbacks/106171584</link><description>Erin Bell's efforts to both buy a house and build a new one through a government scheme were repeatedly challenged — once because she had disclosed a new boyfriend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f65e498ebae764bae79b51a699f2cb9f</guid></item><item><title>The Amazon effect: Gen Z now expect same-day or next-day goods deliveries or else</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/amazon-effect-gen-z-expect-deliveries/106137160</link><description>Small retailers are scrambling to keep up with deliveries as research shows Australian shoppers are expecting the same ultra-fast delivery they get from retail giants like Amazon. But some entrepreneurs have more than a few tricks up their sleeves to satisfy gen Z.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c41c48aed166c1984ec2c9a4989947b</guid></item><item><title>Jewish leaders call for vilification offence to be revisited as Coalition splits over watered-down hate laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/jewish-groups-react-hate-law-reform-passes-senate/106248826</link><description>Labor's watered-down hate law reform has passed the Senate with the support of the Liberal Party but not the Nationals, who opposed the legislation due to freedom of speech concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fad11d06343d02b870639866f7eed592</guid></item><item><title>The trends and records to watch in triple j's 2025 Hottest 100</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/hottest-100-records-trends-preview/106194682</link><description>Here's what might go down when triple j unveils the Hottest 100 of 2025 this Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dcfd6df0cc240a6a84c9d241cc075dd</guid></item><item><title>Victorian fires set to send premiums higher in areas where insurance already unaffordable for some</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/insurers-say-premiums-will-rise-after-victorian-fires/106244640</link><description>Neighbours living on the same fire-ravaged street in regional Victoria are facing vastly different recoveries due to insurance differences, and recent disasters may push premiums further out of reach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8eba5d08ece1cd8b797fd8bef1bca4f4</guid></item><item><title>China's air force has technology that rivals the US's and it could be pivotal in any conflict over Taiwan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/chinese-air-force-rivals-us-taiwan-conflict/106212470</link><description>Certain capabilities of China's air force now seriously challenge those of the US and other Western countries, with experts saying that it could tip the balance of any war over Taiwan in Beijing's favour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14ab6258dffc6b2d55045bc2846c68fd</guid></item><item><title>Samoa's prime minister proposes ban on non-Christian faiths after vowing 'God-centred' leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/samoa-prime-minister-religion-restrictions/106225328</link><description>Samoa's prime minister has thrown the future of its religious minorities into doubt after flagging potential restrictions on non-Christian faiths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebae72323b0b85847169eb6d895b9309</guid></item><item><title>Death of Tim Picton puts spotlight on Australia's 'one-punch' laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/tim-picton-death-one-punch-law-national-state-breakdown/106245498</link><description>The death of Labor identity Tim Picton more than three weeks after he was allegedly assaulted outside a Perth nightclub has shocked Australia's political and business worlds and put the nation's one-punch laws under the microscope.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbdb1d300d1e36c3d586f70d5414bce8</guid></item><item><title>First Nations people will protest this January 26, a legacy dating back 88 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/why-first-nations-peoples-protest-on-jan-26/106248728</link><description>Invasion Day rallies will go ahead on Monday after being exempted from NSW protest bans. Here's the story of how they started in the first place.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">099647a352d14be82852c414e0e38460</guid></item><item><title>Austrian study shows a cow using tools for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/austrian-study-shows-a-cow-using-tools-for-the-first-time/106249324</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e93ee64327f2f7b329361f0c4b81d487</guid></item><item><title>Scientific study documents Austrian cow using a tool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/scientific-study-documents-austrian-cow-using-tool/106247598</link><description>A pet cow in Austria has been filmed picking up a tool and scratching herself. An Australian hobby farmer says she is not that surprised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea86ccea34accc0a1ccb2c65d9691ef0</guid></item><item><title>Queensland teenagers create coding app to bridge digital divide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/qld-teenagers-create-coding-app-code-lab-sri-lanka-students/106225842</link><description>Young coding whizzes Neth Dharmasiri and Chinmay Lal believe learning the language behind computer software shouldn't depend on where you were born.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3629ca2497c48acad1816ae6ba32176c</guid></item><item><title>Insurance industry hoping to break a major barrier to expanding cultural burning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/cultural-burning-insurance-breakthrough/106214712</link><description>Insurance has been a major stumbling block to the scaling up of cultural burning, but a breakthrough could be on the way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70b301662ea2f423238a1d5c9e30bd2f</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump, the madman theory, and why even Australia is not safe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/donald-trump-greenland-threat-madman-theory-analysis/106251358</link><description>One year into Trump's second term, something has become clear: even those who leave the Oval Office with a deal, beware. It might not be worth the paper it's written on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17a15eeef7276e5175a8d9725cbfee47</guid></item><item><title>Mitchell Starc shoulder injury concerns Sydney Sixers after BBL qualifier loss to Perth Scorchers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/sixers-sweat-on-starc-injury-after-bitter-scorchers-blow/106251462</link><description>The Sydney Sixers are thrust into a do-or-die final on Friday after losing to Perth, and star quick Mitch Starc is no guarantee to play.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eefe7c22daed676aa248b269f9e31aae</guid></item><item><title>'Riches to rags story' highlights challenges for homeless on the Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/gold-coast-socialite-homeless-housing-crisis-qld/106237724</link><description>Bethany Turner is among those struggling to find safety and stability while living on the street since the local council began issuing move-on directions to people sleeping rough in public spaces last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27a2abf59a47cd7c6aa17ed145f2f360</guid></item><item><title>Naomi Osaka brings fashion to RLA and Monfils says goodbye — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/australian-open-2026-quick-hits/106248012</link><description>Naomi Osaka took to Rod Laver Arena in a white, flowy jellyfish fashion piece on day three as Gael Monfils waved goodbye to Melbourne Park. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ad648002c1830c934b1b9a8e22a3c1b</guid></item><item><title>Dane Sweeny's Australian Open first-round win over Gaël Monfils built on sacrifice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/australian-open-dane-sweeny-gael-monfils-first-round/106250838</link><description>When Dane Sweeny triumphantly fell to the ground following his defeat of Gaël Monfils at the Australian Open, it was not just a celebration for himself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b0c1a0569a4c42adff52c8869a7aac0</guid></item><item><title>Gold crosses $US4,800 for first time, ASX falls as Trump's Greenland threats sink Wall Street — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/asx-markets-business-live-news-jan-21/106251484</link><description>The Australian share market has fallen for a third straight day as Wall Street tumbled to a one-month low on worsening relations between the US and Europe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7ffaaa5709d871e705eec87c84bd2e3</guid></item><item><title>Canegrowers celebrates 100 years of fighting for fairness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/canegrowers-100-year-anniversary/106250648</link><description>Australia's sugarcane industry looks back on a century of representation as peak body Canegrowers turns 100.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d577715ca993aecd95ab753297f6b75</guid></item><item><title>Parents of Piper James, found dead surrounded by dingoes on K'gari, shattered by loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/kgari-dingoes-and-death-of-piper-james/106251528</link><description>The body of Canadian Piper James was found on K'gari (Fraser Island) surrounded by a pack of dingoes after she told friends she was going for an early morning swim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efdd2902e34ed5279d20f59d66213d10</guid></item><item><title>Perth Fringe World to feature over 3,000 performers across venues in Northbridge, CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/perth-fringe-world-to-feature-over-3000-performers/106248818</link><description>This year's Perth Fringe World is about more than just racy burlesque shows, spicy cabaret and acrobatic performances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9272b2c44bd3bb74d2fc5018ab0043a4</guid></item><item><title>Senior Nationals quit frontbench after defying shadow cabinet on hate speech laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/nationals-ministries-doubt-coalition-split-hate-speech/106251594</link><description>Senior Nationals Bridget McKenzie, Ross Cadell and Susan McDonald quit the shadow cabinet, after defying its position on the government's hate speech reforms in a late-night vote on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe681e902b030d99c1bea78cce0b26e2</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Nationals threat of mass resignation from shadow ministry a 'live option', Liberal source says — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/federal-politics-live-blog-jan-21/106251764</link><description>A Liberal source has told the ABC that multiple Nationals resignations from the shadow ministry is a "live option" after three Nationals quit the shadow cabinet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fca17b16aaff7da2dbb84db7b9dfd8d6</guid></item><item><title>JD Vance and wife Usha Vance expecting fourth child due in July</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/jd-vance-and-wife-usha-vance-expecting-fourth-child-due-in-july-/106251768</link><description>The vice-president and the second lady have been married since 2014 and share two sons and a daughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f75227b49324959b9c5fa3a9dd75e317</guid></item><item><title>The Pool Show at Penrith Regional Gallery casts a critical eye over Australia's pool culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/the-pool-show-penrith-regional-gallery-marian-abboud/106244548</link><description>A new exhibition in Western Sydney interrogates Australia's enduring love affair with the pool.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08cbaa5bbc3726f2bead7cb0590a1c96</guid></item><item><title>Aurora australis seen across Australia as geomagnetic storms deliver spectacular light show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/spectacular-aurora-australis-seen-across-australia/106251474</link><description>A severe geomagnetic storm has hit Earth, painting a colourful cosmic display in Australia's skies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">825db3e352f03ade701fdbbad7920a6a</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026: Alex De Minaur the only Australian to progress from second round on day four</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/australian-open-2026-live-alex-de-minaur-sabalenka-alcaraz/106252014</link><description>Alex de Minaur is the first local to progress into the third round of the Australian Open after four other Australians have been knocked out today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d24074271acb5d6e11f8e618f99f10b0</guid></item><item><title>Chocolate manufacturers look to cocoa bean alternatives to tackle global market uncertainty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/cocoa-free-chocolate-alternatives-grow-cadbury/106243908</link><description>Cocoa substitutes are entering the chocolate market as the confectionery industry responds to volatile bean prices and supply.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a73b7c2268c81994845f7d663398c2fe</guid></item><item><title>National gun buyback doesn't address antisemitism and hatred, Queensland premier says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/qld-premier-gun-buyback-laws-refuse-address-hare-crisafulli/106252098</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese called on David Crisafulli to "justify" his refusal to join the national gun buyback scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a416885d2223d815784860739b56487a</guid></item><item><title>Prime minister's national security adviser Philippa Brant resigns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/prime-minister-national-security-adviser-resigns/106252214</link><description>Philippa Brant has resigned just months after the PM's top foreign policy adviser departed to run the Office of National Intelligence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">763f42a5aafcf9f8eac55afeda3e30ce</guid></item><item><title>Trash and treasure trike proves powerful tool for brain health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/trash-treasure-trike-broken-hill-brian-slater-brain-health/106234034</link><description>Brian Slater, 77, is heeding advice to "use it or lose it" as he devotes his retirement to cognitive challenges that keep his mind healthy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b18a19aba6c1c38aadd2e1cbd0a8bc9</guid></item><item><title>WA meat processor says using AI for counting livestock has improved accuracy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/ai-camera-counting-sheep-at-wa-abattoir/106249366</link><description>One of WA's largest meat processors is using AI technology to count thousands of head of cattle a day with pinpoint accuracy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3d77b876e3e1623dcb17ef294264615</guid></item><item><title>Sheep under the eye of AI</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/using-ai-to-count-sheep/106250690</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c5af840e880887503748d0dd1f0eb2a</guid></item><item><title>Naomi Osaka reveals inspiration behind Australian Open outfit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/australian-open-naomi-osaka-outfit-rod-laver-arena-entrance/106252208</link><description>Naomi Osaka reveals a visit to Japan as a 13-year-old and the Williams sisters helped inspire the outfit she wore on Rod Laver Arena.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">528ac61929a6c6ba38e1b22414ff0959</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's bushfire-affected communities remain on edge ahead of another heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/bushfire-weather-concerns-victoria-heatwave-forecast/106248072</link><description>Bushfire-affected communities remain on edge as forecasters warn of another heatwave, raising concerns about fire risk and extreme temperatures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cee291dbc6e657b9bec3616303975fb</guid></item><item><title>Towns brace for potential 50-degree days as heatwave grips Pilbara and Gascoyne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/wa-towns-brace-for-possible-50-degree-days/106244600</link><description>Towns in WA's north-west could be about to experience Australia's hottest day on record, with the weather bureau expecting temperatures of 50 degrees Celsius in some areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd0dbc66d0f14f7042e6a44511e6e27d</guid></item><item><title>NT pomelo growers fear imports from Vietnam will flood market, risk reintroducing citrus canker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/pomelo-growers-citrus-canker-disease-fears-vietnam-imports/106250118</link><description>The Top End's pomelo industry is worried about the impending importation of the citrus fruit from Vietnam. They say it will depress the local market and bring a biosecurity risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e675248017bdeb51be021cca1210a130</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane records higher fuel prices than any other capital city for third year running</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/qld-brisbane-petrol-prices-most-expensive/106252088</link><description>Brisbane's fuel prices are more expensive than any other capital city for the third year in a row, with the RACQ revealing the cheapest suburbs to fill up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f6d30fbe036c0a6002977bab4217d5e</guid></item><item><title>Angus Crichton to leave Sydney Roosters and NRL to chase Wallabies World Cup dream</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/angus-crichton-leave-roosters-chase-wallabies-world-cup-dream/106252548</link><description>Star second-rower Angus Crichton will leave the Sydney Roosters at the end of the NRL season to pursue a career in rugby union.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a295c7e2e59bb0b91dbf8ffd55deb05</guid></item><item><title>What is skimo? All you need to know about the new Winter Olympics event ahead of Milano Cortina 2026 Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/what-is-ski-mo-australia-names-2026-winter-olympics-team/106229150</link><description>Skimo is the newest sport at the Winter Olympics, but what is it? And who are the Aussies that will take on the challenge on the slopes of the infamous Stelvio climb?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3efdefa22173991050e8a1240bd089cf</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's America-first policies are pushing countries into China's embrace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/donald-trump-is-a-gift-to-china-that-keeps-on-giving/106249578</link><description>Inside China, there's a nickname for Donald Trump that tells you everything you need to know about how the US leader's actions are increasingly seen as a gift to Beijing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e84cef9503369eecbd2a2ca690b2398</guid></item><item><title>Rockhampton residents urged to avoid floodwaters as Fitzroy River approaches peak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/rockhampton-residents-urged-to-avoid-floodwaters/106251696</link><description>Police warn central Queensland residents against entering floodwaters, after several social media posts showed people in the shallows of a swollen river.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44f0448bf0b92e14824790da964db941</guid></item><item><title>Crime gangs restocking shops 'up to 10 times a day' with illegal cigarettes and vapes, WA police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/behind-the-scenes-of-wa-s-illegal-tobacco-business-model/106252960</link><description>WA's police commissioner says the restocking is happening faster than authorities can seize the products, as tobacco black market violence escalates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c85e3ad402b68eddf68bb31ca5929a65</guid></item><item><title>American rider and brumby complete 4,400km journey across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/american-rider-brumby-journey-across-australia/106238888</link><description>Gin Szagola and her brumby, Fable, have completed a coast-to-coast journey, covering 4,400 kilometres in eight months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c87bb28b98216d3d360a3f82c9d902b5</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs Mayor Asta Hill will not attend Australia Day ceremony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/alice-springs-mayor-will-not-attend-australia-day-ceremony/106252002</link><description>Asta Hill will not take part in celebrations of Australia Day, which she sees as a day causing harm to First Nations peoples — a decision described as "disgraceful" by the local member of the Northern Territory Legislative Assembly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">948bb6a11a41e328ce594aca829df759</guid></item><item><title>WA premier Roger Cook extends embattled Griffin Coal's lifeline, citing energy security concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/roger-cook-extends-griffin-coal-financial-lifeline/106250998</link><description>Since 2022, the WA government has already tipped $300 million into propping up the insolvent Indian-owned miner, which is more than $1 billion in debt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67e740016a3de5b8c9985d9a5054f374</guid></item><item><title>Canadian PM says smaller nations must 'band together' to stop larger countries overpowering them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/carney-blasts-trump-canada-davos-world-economic-forum/106252354</link><description>Canadian PM Mark Carney told the World Economic Forum "middle powers must act together".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3d402b5ff2519732956effe5b696207</guid></item><item><title>NZ Prime Minister Christopher Luxon calls for election on November 7</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/nz-pm-calls-for-election-to-be-held-on-november-7/106253286</link><description>NZ's Prime Minister Christopher Luxon has announced the election date for 2026, promising economic prosperity if New Zealanders vote for him again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2151ed94bdf31735ca532b3eee1999e3</guid></item><item><title>Liberals 'not that stressed' by leak — but Labor seizes on attempt to 'destabilise' leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/labor-liberal-war-of-words-over-sa-document-leak/106251982</link><description>The leaking of an SA Liberal document two months before the state election has been described by the Labor government as a "calculated and methodical" attempt to "destabilise" new leader Ashton Hurn — but her party says it is "not that stressed" because the policy is old.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfcdecbed89774f218970ce8605ff790</guid></item><item><title>What we know about changing UK passport requirements effective February 25</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/what-we-know-about-changing-uk-passport-requirements-explainer/106252182</link><description>Hundreds of confused UK and Irish dual citizens in Australia have written to the ABC with questions around the new changes for entry requirements into the UK. Here's what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ad4283cc2e20810a878022673bc9745</guid></item><item><title>Tobias Lund Andresen upsets sprint favourites in crazy Tanunda finish to take Tour Down Under lead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/tobias-lund-andresen-wins-tour-down-under-stage-one-tanunda/106252426</link><description>Tobias Lund Andresen out-sprinted favourites Sam Welsford and Matthew Brennan to claim a stunning victory into Tanunda and take the overall lead in the Tour Down Under.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08a6c61f04435215f6bce205f400dbd7</guid></item><item><title>Australian NATO envoy Di Turton warns North Korea has 'combat-ready troops in our region'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/turton-warns-north-korea-has-combat-ready-troops-in-our-region/106246654</link><description>Australia's outgoing military envoy to NATO is preparing to return to Canberra after two years in the role, and she is coming home with a warning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b24fa33cd95a9f83851e93c8d2239d49</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police slap bans on neo-Nazis entering Sydney CBD on Australia Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/nsw-police-ban-neo-nazis-entering-sydney-cbd-on-australia-day/106251992</link><description>Up to 12 neo-Nazis have been issued public safety orders banning them from entering central Sydney, shutting down plans to attend anti-immigration rallies on Australia Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b80afd68912726767d758f1cbdcc7672</guid></item><item><title>Man who assassinated Shinzo Abe sentenced to life in prison by Japanese court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/shinzo-abe-assassination-sentence/106250736</link><description>Tetsuya Yamagami pleaded guilty to fatally shooting Mr Abe as he stood surrounded by security, media and supporters in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15802eeddc6ea41a302a3abeff6d344e</guid></item><item><title>Why Elina Svitolina is prioritising her mental health at the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/australian-open-elina-svitolina-prioritises-her-mental-health/106253922</link><description>In the highly competitive world of professional tennis, it is refreshing to learn that Elina Svitolina has her priorities in order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">231dc2e91147acfd4cd1936346129dc9</guid></item><item><title>How Australia will mark the National Day of Mourning for Bondi victims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/national-day-of-mourning-bondi-victims-explainer/106252240</link><description>Today is a national day of mourning for the victims of the Bondi Beach terror attack. Here's what you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf3b6a1d1ea606069fbbad6560c0e513</guid></item><item><title>New South Wales man charged with allegedly threatening prime minister</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/man-charged-threatening-politician-bellingen-prime-minister/106252292</link><description>A NSW Mid North Coast man is granted bail after he allegedly threatened to shoot the prime minister, in a video uploaded to social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a162f7503002a63f89c62572cb4f408</guid></item><item><title>Midnight Oil's Rob Hirst died of pancreatic cancer. It's one of Australia's deadliest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/midnight-oil-rob-hirst-pancreatic-cancer-death/106252876</link><description>Rob Hirst was first diagnosed with pancreatic cancer in 2023. It is estimated to be the third most common cause of cancer death in Australia, and has among the lowest survival rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9ddc9310c0db0de11b44dad7f91d666</guid></item><item><title>Have you been gifted an ancestry DNA test? The results could be 'life-altering'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/why-ancestry-dna-tests-arent-just-a-bit-of-fun/106225222</link><description>If you're thinking of taking an ancestry DNA test as "a bit of fun", experts warn there is the risk of uncovering more than you bargained for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c18adfae6ecc122d7b0786df99d29aa2</guid></item><item><title>Scathing report finds Kimberley prisoners sleeping on floor, in cockroach-infested cells</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/scathing-report-released-into-broome-regional-prison/106253104</link><description>A damning report by Western Australia's prison watchdog dubs Broome Regional Prison "unfit for purpose".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41d222e773ae854c5963c5441440f706</guid></item><item><title>Police believe Mandurah teacher's baby fathered by student she allegedly sexually abused</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/wa-teacher-gives-birth-after-child-sexual-assault-charges/106254008</link><description>Police believe a Mandurah teacher gave birth to a baby fathered by a student she allegedly sexually assaulted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f8bdf15c3dbf7525b3248fd20d0c29e</guid></item><item><title>Zeynep Sönmez thrills Turkish fans with latest Australian Open win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/australian-open-zeynep-sonmez-turkiye-second-round-melbourne/106254442</link><description>In front of her loyal supporters, Türkiye's Zeynep Sönmez advances to the Australian Open third round, as her remarkable run continues at Melbourne Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22727b155241893e1895d1a9d793586a</guid></item><item><title>New hate laws have passed parliament. What do they actually do?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/what-will-new-hate-laws-do/106253754</link><description>The new laws grant powers for the government to list so-called hate groups, more easily deport or cancel the visas of individuals associated with hate groups and create new aggravated penalties for leaders who advocate violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22f42220711e3e177be96bf784d2def9</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's second presidency is about 'might makes right' and reshaping the world order be it in Venezuela or Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/donald-trumps-year-one-lays-ground-for-new-world-order/106252232</link><description>As Donald Trump celebrates one year of his second term in the White House, he is rewriting all the rules for global order, and no-one seems ready to stop his "imperial ambitions".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68e8d76ada9efedaa2427ff84102d70f</guid></item><item><title>WA gold companies 'floating on a sea of cash' as the commodity hits new price record</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/gold-price-continues-to-smash-historic-records/106252736</link><description>A Kalgoorlie miner hopes the soaring price of gold will incentivise investment into regional WA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">727c087761f0b6ae2a28d0df6ed03a2c</guid></item><item><title>Why Emmanuel Macron was wearing sunglasses at Davos World Economic Forum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/why-emmanuel-macron-wore-sunglasses-to-davos/106252204</link><description>The French president's appearance at the annual meeting of the World Economic Forum makes headlines, but not for any policy reasons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae7b6da24375daf367a7ce77fd45d66d</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106254400</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96b2d0610f77559240b421960b39fc7a</guid></item><item><title>Banned Adelaide doctor Bill Tolis in court over steroid importation charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/adelaide-banned-doctor-bill-tolis-charged-steroid-importation/106253698</link><description>A man who was banned from working as a doctor in 2022 appears in court charged with importing steroids and peptides that the Australian Border Force allegedly found in a medical clinic and at his home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15ae84013164210499851a72702a1db6</guid></item><item><title>Plane landing aborted after alleged trespassing incident near runway at Melbourne Airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/melbourne-airport-trespasser-afp/106255022</link><description>A pilot is forced to abort a landing attempt at Melbourne Airport, and two take-offs are delayed after an alleged late-night trespassing incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e0008c004dc5e6ce444d59ffa49fcad</guid></item><item><title>Benjamin Netanyahu, Azerbaijan agree to join Trump's 'Board of Peace' as Norway and Sweden reject invitations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/israel-and-azerbaijan-to-join-trumps-board-of-peace/106254994</link><description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu agrees to join US President Donald Trump's "Board of Peace" despite his office previously criticising the makeup of the executive committee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a809f7bafb25060ffc5b77861c179cb</guid></item><item><title>Father of Adelaide girl who died due to mother's alleged neglect tells court of coffin threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/jasmine-willmott-father-gives-evidence-in-manslaughter-trial/106254726</link><description>The father of a 15-year-old girl whose mother is accused of her manslaughter, tells the South Australian Supreme Court of a threat made against his daughter and punishment she was made to do.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">877e18523e326afbcffe861376220e59</guid></item><item><title>Coalition in chaos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/coalition-in-chaos/106254986</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5132ce46d2834f53a85a720e674f0fd7</guid></item><item><title>Coalition on the brink as Nationals quit shadow ministry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/nationals-coalition-littleproud-ley-hate-laws/106254676</link><description>Opposition leader Sussan Ley says the Nationals' mass resignation from her frontbench is "unnecessary" and has urged the rural party to remain in the Coalition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2506e2c3d1df8a3e6b416a4e1ad58809</guid></item><item><title>K'gari traditional owners raise dingo management issues after teen's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/kgari-traditional-owners-dingo-management-issues/106252220</link><description>The body of Piper James, 19, was found surrounded by dingoes on a beach on the island's eastern coast, but how she died may not be known for some time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac54ad630f52e053a14ca4033cf0af1e</guid></item><item><title>Real estate prices set records with six capitals now in 'million-dollar club' and Melbourne rebounding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/australian-real-estate-median-home-prices-domain-report-millions/106251932</link><description>The Melbourne real estate market is leading a "decisive recovery", according to property portal Domain, as the city hits a four-year high for its median house price after strong growth across the country last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ecae4dcc6d7b32b532b527df98b5815</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump drops Greenland tariffs threat as he heralds 'future deal' with NATO</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/donald-trump-tells-davos-he-wants-greenland-deal-with-denmark/106255244</link><description>Donald Trump says he has agreed to a "framework of a future deal" on Greenland after talks with NATO's secretary-general, and he will no longer impose tariffs on European nations that had opposed a US takeover.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f89614fd2c7c59f2ce651d55a6edb4</guid></item><item><title>Japan restarts nuclear power plant almost 15 years since Fukushima disaster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/worlds-biggest-nuclear-power-plant-restarted-after-fukushima/106255280</link><description>The world's biggest nuclear power plant has been rebooted by the same company that operated the Fukushima facility, despite concerns about safety from some locals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">449f4979bd3a97dd3cade26e5436d195</guid></item><item><title>Emotional Prince Harry says media made his wife Meghan Markle's life 'an absolute misery' at Daily Mail trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/prince-harry-gives-evidence-at-high-court-in-privacy-case/106255216</link><description>An emotional Prince Harry held back tears as he described the impact of media coverage on his wife Meghan Markle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0303b3d89bae8745f194d9374bac2748</guid></item><item><title>Why Ukrainians are shivering through their fourth winter in wartime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/energy-crisis-kyiv-winter-ukraine-russia-blackouts/106255468</link><description>The war-ravaged country has been plunged into an energy crisis as temperatures plummet below freezing, leaving millions unable to heat their homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccb3c54d802b1a2340a3cc49537ca8e3</guid></item><item><title>Children and journalists killed by Israel in separate incidents in Gaza, Palestinian medics say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/children-and-journalists-killed-by-idf-in-gaza/106255512</link><description>According to Palestinian medics, two boys aged 10 and 13 were among those killed on Wednesday in the latest violence which threatens to undermine a fragile ceasefire deal between Israel and Hamas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd3c1332546ddcee2f19fb827ee29a26</guid></item><item><title>Royal Hobart Hospital medical scan backlog creating late diagnosis risk, AMA says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/royal-hobart-hospital-medical-scans-outsourced/106250608</link><description>The Royal Hobart Hospital is facing a significant backlog of medical scans, with at least one patient experiencing a late diagnosis. The AMA and a union say it's a sign of a system facing a range of pressures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b176a825f6f77ae4bd8c9f6625b7666e</guid></item><item><title>Students have their say in disaster planning in Melbourne's bushfire-prone outer east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/school-bushfire-preparation-upwey-high-school-cfa/106180444</link><description>In a bushfire-prone area in outer Melbourne, a group of students is taking part in a two-way learning exchange to improve bushfire safety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40307f950dbaec9d8ce11741eb18b179</guid></item><item><title>How closely have you been following the 2026 awards season?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/mid-awards-season-quiz/106236836</link><description>Fancy yourself an awards season whiz? Test your knowledge as we rocket towards the 2026 Academy awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17381a39bd7b2538186d35a6037811fe</guid></item><item><title>Republicans push to hold Clintons in contempt of Congress over Epstein probe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/clintons-us-house-contempt-over-epstein/106255510</link><description>The Clintons are refusing to testify before a committee in the US House of Representatives, accusing Republicans of leading a weaponised process against them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c80ed23b03f8eb6f6c2be9bc2e08dae</guid></item><item><title>Sydney rabbi shares rituals behind how Jews grieve and heal, amid National Day of Mourning for Bondi victims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/customs-behind-how-jewish-community-mourns-bondi-attack/106244770</link><description>Amid the National Day of Mourning for the victims of the Bondi Beach terrorist attack, Rabbi Jacqueline Ninio shares what mourning looks like in Jewish culture, from the resonance of stones at gravesites to the 30-day period of grieving.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c64f0b2e186976d0ddf951bfc9023c6b</guid></item><item><title>Bondi lifeguard pictured running barefoot in viral photo recalls night of terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/viral-bondi-lifeguard-recalls-night-of-terror-attack/106253672</link><description>Much of Jackson 'Jacko' Doolan's memory from December 14 is a blur, but there is one moment that remains crystal clear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bad00cf6d586f40765e799c16046d333</guid></item><item><title>Calls to bring back hard-hitting anti-smoking campaigns to warn off gen Z</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/calls-to-bring-back-hard-hitting-anti-smoking-campaigns/106076928</link><description>Experts say Australia risks becoming complacent in the war against tobacco, with big companies pivoting to social media to "greenwash" their products to generation Z.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a3755c5faf71c4ae310c4fa1f70cef6</guid></item><item><title>Some Adelaide University students unable to enrol in courses since merger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/adelaide-university-merger-leave-students-stressed/106252460</link><description>The Adelaide University merger has been labelled a "shambles" by some students who say they have been unable to enrol in courses or receive timely communication from the new university.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a6bb8b215957d1dc4f86d8021ac4502</guid></item><item><title>Nationals walkout leaves Coalition on life support, again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/national-walkout-coalition-on-life-support/106252042</link><description>The departure of every single member of the Nationals from the frontbench is bizarrely both a failure of the Coalition agreement and a result of it functioning as intended.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87d0ee925d656b9cc5bc9005730349bd</guid></item><item><title>Australia earns global praise for economic 'soft landing' but still dependent on China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/reserve-bank-earns-global-praise-for-economic-soft-landing/106254000</link><description>A new report from the OECD says Australia's economy is returning to normal but remains vulnerable and lacks dynamism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05e404f80625145a36267752e37fcb5d</guid></item><item><title>Europe holds the trump card as the US faces a mountain of debt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/trump-us-debt-carney-davos-fractured-world-order/106254272</link><description>For decades, global investors have bought US government debt as a safe haven when things turn pear-shaped. But investor attitudes are changing, and America's financial domination is at stake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef5ba145fdb46fb1740c5e13e6f77eb3</guid></item><item><title>The shark mitigation measures in place at NSW beaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/shark-safety-mitigation-nsw-beaches/106253046</link><description>Shark mitigation measures have come a long way since the first nets were rolled out in Sydney almost 90 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">205fdea08cb53b1bf7c70de46eff47ba</guid></item><item><title>Batteries will form a larger part of the state's electricity grid going forwards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/energy-queensland-battery-flyover/106248666</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43d6145c90ab72c1755f313d1ced77ed</guid></item><item><title>Grayson Cavanagh has candles on hand for blackouts, which are expected to become increasingly common</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/preparations-for-blackouts-brisbane/106248680</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2737ef1e7162791e3fa7167ee101980f</guid></item><item><title>Microgrid trials underway as Queensland electricity grid looks to boost network resiliency amid blackouts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/queensland-smart-grids-to-help-grid-resiliency-and-stability/106204684</link><description>Tens of thousands of homes across Queensland have lost power during storms this season – an uncomfortable, expensive experience, which could become more common.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48f2450b8577bc0e23611320c908b396</guid></item><item><title>'Ten-pound Pom' vows to boycott UK over 'money grab' passport changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/ten-pound-pom-boycotting-uk-over-passport-changes/106252052</link><description>People who came to Australia as children from the UK as part of an organised migration scheme say they the UK's new regulations for dual citizens unfairly targets them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">589e215128e03f85233423439cb2ca67</guid></item><item><title>Hobart Hurricanes beat Melbourne Stars in rainy thriller to keep BBL title defence alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/hurricanes-win-in-the-rain-to-get-bbl-title-defence-alive/106255630</link><description>The Hobart Hurricanes hold their nerve to beat the Melbourne Stars in a rain-shortened Big Bash elimination final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b3de8ccef426aa4a98bc8ad84b9fc29</guid></item><item><title>Sinner weighs up Kyrgios and Kim Jong-Un, plus an Aussie exodus — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/australian-open-2026-quick-hits/106252228</link><description>Jannik Sinner was stuck in an awkward moment discussing Nick Kyrgios and Kim Jong-Un while Coco Gauff shared her top artists. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">910ec10d7ff7c87b7739ef59bc8e52af</guid></item><item><title>Taskforce set up to address ongoing power outages across SA from dust pollution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/power-outages-across-regional-south-australia-from-dust/106252096</link><description>Ongoing dry conditions across South Australia since 2024 are causing dust and salt to build up across inland and coastal power networks, polluting insulators and leading to mass blackouts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfa755b708992c638b64e4eaec702edf</guid></item><item><title>ASX to open higher, as Wall Street absorbs Trump's latest tariff remarks, live updates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-thursday-22-january/106255650</link><description>The ASX is set to open higher as Donald Trump withdraws his threat to impose new tariffs. Follow the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a80fea3eb11df624b58972b216be4e3</guid></item><item><title>Police Association says Coober Pedy and APY Lands are 'unacceptably compromised' by police shortage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/coober-pedy-police-station-shortage/106254028</link><description>South Australia's police union says some officers in the remote town are working 18-hour days and have been unable to respond to all incidents, amid an ongoing industrial dispute with SA Police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c95b2aa716dd7117122caf12eb92208</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: Nationals won't rule out Coalition split after quitting shadow ministry en masse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/politics-live-blog-nationals-coalition-liberal-ley-littleproud/106255658</link><description>After quitting the shadow ministry en masse in solidarity with three colleagues dumped for crossing the floor on hate laws, the Nationals won't rule out breaking away from the Coalition again Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a1735a6d8a7f4c354e01bf028d78b9c</guid></item></channel></rss>