<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 07:01:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NASA's Crew 11 Dragon splashdown upon returning to Earth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/nasa-s-crew-11-dragon-splashdown-upon-returning-to-earth/106234992</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0537005e847c47fca5e027cb15579f2a</guid></item><item><title>Heated Rivalry and growing sports romance genre can teach lessons about queer inclusion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/heated-rivalry-sports-romance-genre-queer-inclusion-sport/106223278</link><description>Heated Rivalry has become a massive global hit, but can the steamy ice hockey romance, and other queer love stories, help create more inclusive spaces in the real sporting world?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a30268fd639f7e0a65aec7b6af9dd321</guid></item><item><title>What is in the government's new hate speech laws?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/hate-speech-laws-labor-antisemitism-bondi/106231326</link><description>Parliament will return early next week to debate new hate speech laws. But what exactly does the legislation include?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13227a51b52cf94309e424b04cf2615e</guid></item><item><title>US legal case against Amazon Prime subscription service leads to cheque in the mail for Australian</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/australian-customer-receives-payback-cheque-from-amazon-prime/106231918</link><description>Australian woman Laura Wells was confused to find an "official-looking letter" from the US with a $51 reimbursement, but it turns out it was legitimate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e196a41d260b822af58deca7f10b30a</guid></item><item><title>These epaulette sharks are breaking the rules of biology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/epaulette-sharks-are-breaking-the-rules-of-biology/106229708</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcb0cdfb6fe2c17e2820b055802fb9f3</guid></item><item><title>Queenaland Maroons captain Ali Brigginshaw calls time on Origin career to focus on Brisbane Broncos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/ali-brigginshaw-retires-state-of-origin-brisbane-broncos/106238298</link><description>Ali Brigginshaw announces she has played her last State of Origin game for Queensland as she looks to focus on one final NRLW season with Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e0933c27558f92c46db864e2a88c3a5</guid></item><item><title>Huge European wasp nest found in Albany</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/huge-european-wasp-nest-found-in-albany/106238542</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">973dd9926c8227d4fc3ae503fedffbf5</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106239186</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">014123baf9c94a7204824cf9ccb43485</guid></item><item><title>Olympic climber Campbell Harrison happy to carry weight of being an LGBTQI+ role model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/olympian-campbell-harrison-proud-to-be-gay-role-model/106132328</link><description>Campbell Harrison was homophobically trolled in the lead-up to the Paris Olympics. It strengthened his conviction about the importance of visible queer role models in sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8b0815662be65c813bfbc7ba6f548c7</guid></item><item><title>Nelson Asofa-Solomona announces plans to 'clean up the whole NRL division' after successful boxing debut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/boxing-nelson-asofa-solomona-calls-out-nrl-rivals/106240134</link><description>Nelson Asofa-Solomona calls out his former rugby league competitors after making a successful transition to the fight game by knocking out Jeremy Latimore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06dea109ef3a0a57ec1334d3709b5729</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Aboriginal inmate's connection to country stays strong through art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/sydney-aboriginal-inmates-connection-to-country-through-art/106189742</link><description>With each paint stroke and dot placement, art gives John the opportunity to express his culture, with some of his fellow Aboriginal inmates joining him in creating artworks while incarcerated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7b5839fd6a30d886691909f21ba0d06</guid></item><item><title>Taking paracetamol during pregnancy not linked to autism or ADHD in children, Lancet study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/lancet-rejects-trump-paracetamol-pregnancy-autism-claims/106236278</link><description>Just months after US President Donald Trump warned women about taking paracetamol during pregnancy, a new study finds there is no evidence linking the painkiller to autism in children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5de1a4dfed93e58310a9ec2b4600e8f0</guid></item><item><title>Geraldton's Horizon Ball sculpture draws large crowds as international visitor numbers rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/horizon-ball-geraldton-sculpture-tourism/105874130</link><description>Geraldton's Horizon Ball sculpture is drawing huge crowds of tourists after the spot gained international attention on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eba3cf9d89c6c4bef13d23466afa00e</guid></item><item><title>Michael Zerafa has been accused of quitting against Nikita Tszyu. There is no more heinous crime in boxing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/michael-zerafa-quit-nikita-tszyu-boxing-brisbane/106240558</link><description>To be called a quitter is the lowest insult in boxing. But whether Michael Zerafa was guilty of this or not, he has successfully ostracised himself from the sport's fraternity for the second time in his career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">666c36595d1ab5ab540ee320d55b3322</guid></item><item><title>'I'm back!' Australian cricket great Damien Martyn shares heartfelt update on remarkable recovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/damien-martyn-shares-heartfelt-health-update/106240912</link><description>Australian cricket great Damien Martyn has paid tribute to the support he has received during his remarkable recovery from meningitis, while revealing he was given a "50:50 chance" of surviving the illness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eca2cb00c8f48fd37b04e0f5eb7d1a03</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr scores twice for Chelsea in Women's FA Cup, declares her best form is not far away</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/sam-kerr-comeback-continues-with-fa-cup-double-chelsea/106241588</link><description>Sam Kerr declares she is approaching her best form after scoring twice for Chelsea in a Women's FA Cup victory over Crystal Palace.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e507bcbe5096fda3243668d35e4a988</guid></item><item><title>Forgotten tracks from the 2005 Hottest 100 you need to hear again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/forgotten-songs-from-2005-hottest-100-bloodhound-gang/106146344</link><description>We've dug out some standout tracks from the Hottest 100 of 2005 that you need to hear again. Relive the mid-2000s music that defined an era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc09e85614dc423c888ef09906b13089</guid></item><item><title>Israel objects to US announcement of leaders who will help oversee next steps in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/israel-objects-to-us-announcement-of-leaders-who-will-help-overs/106241834</link><description>The committee announced by the White House includes no Israeli officials but has an Israeli businessperson, billionaire Yakir Gabay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4a79a8c03f5465bfe8d897d31920889</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's animal populations suffer as state is ravaged by bushfires, extreme heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/victoria-wildlife-animals-suffering-bushfires-heatwave/106219826</link><description>From animal shelters to "entire generations" of bat colonies, heartbreaking stories of the significant loss of animal life are beginning to emerge in the wake of Victoria's disastrous bushfires and severe heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">246fa1e142bbfb8793f30a1c3d549ee0</guid></item><item><title>Writers' Week letter shows premier backed removal of Randa Abdel-Fattah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/premier-letter-on-randa-abdel-fatah-at-writers-week-released/106241792</link><description>South Australia's premier told the Adelaide Festival board it would open itself to "accusations of hypocrisy" and "legitimate public ridicule" if it did not cancel the appearance of Randa Abdel-Fattah from Writers' Week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83b2891c320c941cac6481cb385e83d8</guid></item><item><title>Venus Williams lost in the first round. But she still gave fans an emotional evening</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/venus-williams-first-round-loss-in-emotional-return/106242736</link><description>Undisputed great of the sport Venus Williams was welcomed back to Melbourne Park with multiple standing ovations but bowed out in the first round to Serbian Olga Danilovic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2896ce50a37c4ece236ddfb91dd87fd3</guid></item><item><title>Trump asks Australia, Albanese to join Gaza 'Board of Peace'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australia-asked-to-join-trump-s-gaza-board-of-peace-/106242966</link><description>The US president is pushing for the board to preserve a fragile ceasefire between Hamas and Israel and progress the peace deal to the next phase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed5574cc0854e1096521ee6bea0d0b2</guid></item><item><title>AI platforms like Grok are an ethical, social and economic nightmare — and we're starting to wake up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/ai-grok-ethical-social-and-economic-nightmare/106242320</link><description>As 2025 began, I thought humanity's biggest problem was climate change. In 2026, AI is more pressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0956e00f7c9111bf96801d7da3854c5</guid></item><item><title>Tribunal bans senior nurse for trying to take patient's medication, altering hospital records</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/modbury-nurse-banned-stealing-patients-adhd-medication/106229238</link><description>A senior public hospital nurse has been prohibited from working for four years for attempting to steal medication from a patient and manipulating a co-worker's Facebook account in an attempt to cover it up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a458cc28e2befbbf188f607c29e61cab</guid></item><item><title>Calls for an industry-standard heat policy to be implemented on worksites as summers get hotter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/calls-for-industry-standard-heat-policy-on-worksites/106234134</link><description>It has been 13 years since Jenny Newport's son died from extreme heat while on a worksite in Queensland. She believes not much has changed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60f002407b15690de7b318b7c9777c52</guid></item><item><title>Violent crime spreading to regional towns as WA waits for strengthened tobacco laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/illegal-tobacco-vapes-violent-crime-in-regional-towns/106207292</link><description>Community leaders have called on the West Australian government to take concrete action as violence and crime associated with the illegal tobacco trade spreads to the state's Wheatbelt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7e3842f3ba51094b5b8f8d6f013ec4c</guid></item><item><title>Senegal storms off field in penalty protest, before returning to beat Morocco in mad AFCON final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/senegal-protests-then-wins-afcon-final-morocco/106243788</link><description>Senegal's players storm off the pitch in furious protest of a refereeing decision late in the Africa Cup of Nations final, but then return to score an extra-time winner against Morocco.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">610d9d94eb36d431cac87390846e0a05</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith focuses on reclaiming Australian T20 spot for Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/steve-smith-t20-world-cup-olympics/106244980</link><description>Steve Smith has lit up the Big Bash since returning to the Sydney Sixers, but concedes the ship has sailed for him to play in next month's T20 World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">840498619d37e7667d0ac59def0a7633</guid></item><item><title>Bondi survivor Ya'akov Tetleroyd lost his father and nearly his arm in Bondi Beach terrorism event. He forgives the gunmen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/bondi-terror-survivor-yaakov-tetleroyd-speaks-naveed-akram/106238196</link><description>Ya'akov Tetleroyd's father died in the Bondi Beach shootings. He nearly lost his arm as a result of being shot, yet he told 7.30 in an exclusive interview that he forgives the gunmen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">036a2c4738ac88afd5123eda6fe48589</guid></item><item><title>Monday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106245916</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bfd8c1fab3cd958260d324a03f7b0f3</guid></item><item><title>What is it like to live and work in the Antarctic?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/living-and-working-in-the-antarctic/106246052</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d13273f34a29dd8e349e41e8e456cd05</guid></item><item><title>Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi to dissolve parliament and call snap election for February 8</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/japan-prime-minister-calls-snap-general-election/106246400</link><description>Japanese Prime Minister ⁠Sanae Takaichi will ​dissolve parliament ‌on ‌Friday ‌and call a snap ​election for February 8 ⁠to seek voter backing ‌for her ​spending ​plans and ‍other ⁠policies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6762019ff9f76327ee529684d85c451</guid></item><item><title>Italian fashion designer Valentino dies aged 93 in Rome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/italian-fashion-designer-valentino-dies-aged-93-in-rome/106247130</link><description>The fashion icon's creations were adored by Hollywood stars, royals and first ladies for his fail-safe red carpet designs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46af3ffb2731ac5d3650837108493b36</guid></item><item><title>Oak Tasmania issued $1.1m penalty over hundreds of NDIS compliance failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/tas-ndis-provider-1-1m-penalty-for-breaches/106246414</link><description>Oak Tasmania admits to 474 compliance and reporting failures, as well as breaches that resulted in the hospitalisation of multiple NDIS clients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9e88e8b1c262ca731e0c1c273ec6e75</guid></item><item><title>How lifting gave me back the power to feel good at sport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/how-powerlifting-gave-me-back-the-power-to-feel-good-at-sport/106234088</link><description>As a child, Julie "wasn't one of the sporty kids". A safe gym environment and then a supportive powerlifting community helped her realise that wasn't actually true.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2abbef65f571e75069d3d1abdc6f375</guid></item><item><title>First Nations employee asked by supervisor about eating ants takes transport department to court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/sa-transport-department-federal-court-case/106231982</link><description>A First Nations employee at South Australia's Department for Infrastructure and Transport (DIT) has claimed she was sexually harassed by her supervisor and racially discriminated against when asked about eating ants before a cultural training session, court documents reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7374c2347019e1b32db9a67988ee3efb</guid></item><item><title>Women's captain departs football club after men's offensive Silly Saturday costumes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/box-hill-north-fc-womens-captain-leaves-club-after-men-behaviour/106190266</link><description>A women's senior football captain has stepped away from her local club after photos of the senior men's leadership team were posted online during their "Silly Saturday" post-season celebrations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ffb103fdb7886c68801e2562aeef8ca</guid></item><item><title>Ipswich residents frustrated as nickel waste stored near homes without council approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/ipswich-residents-nickelwaste-dumped-nearhomes-council-approval/106244714</link><description>The dumping of the waste is the latest in a series of similar events for Ipswich, the city which some now call "Australia's waste capital".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">098856adadd618e6d5f95435a562ca83</guid></item><item><title>Shellharbour mayor's quick thinking during call may have saved deputy's life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/shellharbour-councillor-kellie-marsh-aneurysm-emergency/106245410</link><description>A mayor's split-second decision to answer a phone call instead of heading into the surf may well have saved the life of his deputy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d92c75f46d2dd5048aa680d5e3e2bc68</guid></item><item><title>Foo Fighters are playing their only Australian show in Launceston on Saturday, here's what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/foo-fighters-launceston-concert-what-you-need-to-know/106243618</link><description>Tasmania's "biggest ever concert" is heating up Launceston this weekend, and whether you have tickets or not, there are a few things you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">756623b97549184033b8460854e8b087</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane suffers vaccine shortages after wall collapses at Toll Group distribution centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/brisbane-hit-by-vaccine-shortages/106247402</link><description>Brisbane parents are being turned away from GP clinics due to a shortage of childhood vaccines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95c7e8806a61ca804b73a3bea4054c5a</guid></item><item><title>UN rapporteur on allegations of crimes against humanity in Iran</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/un-rapporteur-on-allegations-of-crimes-against-humanity-in-iran-/106247870</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6af8546b9b44b0cb824c9897b817d50c</guid></item><item><title>Brain cancer survivor who finished year 12 hoping medication can get PBS listing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/brain-cancer-survivor-hoping-medication-can-get-pbs-listing/106163562</link><description>Just over a year ago Sienna was shocked to discover she had a rare brain cancer. She's taking a new drug to slow its growth, but it's come at great cost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21adf0d155fecef77dd6873776191137</guid></item><item><title>French media releases new security footage of thieves in Louvre heist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/new-security-footage-of-louvre-heist-released/106248086</link><description>The security footage shows the thieves smashing the glass on the display cases where the jewellery was kept.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9556ee4895b887312e1e10433709e155</guid></item><item><title>Gilmour Space receives federal funding boost for homegrown rockets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/gilmour-space-funding-boost-for-homegrown-rockets/106247624</link><description>The company hailed the launch of its first Australian designed and manufactured rocket a success, despite it being airborne for just 14 seconds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ef86a9d002caca346cff368daa291fc</guid></item><item><title>Maya Joint vows to 'come back stronger' after early Australian Open exit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/australian-open-maya-joint-loses-first-round/106249028</link><description>Maya Joint's first Australian Open appearance as a seed did not go according to plan, following a straight-sets defeat on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d1cfb70cdfd67e0e62683a684a60cf7</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic penguin breeding cycles changing rapidly in response to climate change, study shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/antarctic-penguin-breeding-cycles-changing-climate-change/106247472</link><description>Penguins in parts of Antarctica are breeding up to two weeks earlier than a decade ago, likely in response to climate change, according to a long-term study.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">195f7747bf8736cce5a600570b4a107c</guid></item><item><title>Blue Mountains council closes Lincoln's Rock lookout after safety concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/popular-lookout-lincolns-rock-in-blue-mountains-closed/106245326</link><description>A council will shut an iconic Blue Mountains cliff after being overrun with tourists, sparking serious safety and environmental concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ada72b20a8c3f9c6a85fe9134a0fc19f</guid></item><item><title>Hawthorn's Will Day to miss first half of the AFL season with shoulder injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/will-day-hawthorn-shoulder-injury-return-afl/106250104</link><description>Hawthorn star Will Day is set for a lengthy stint on the sidelines after dislocating his right shoulder during pre-season training and undergoing surgery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d307d6fe71f40e6d700287b246f166</guid></item><item><title>Do Woolworths shoppers want Google AI adding items to buy? We'll soon find out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/woolworths-google-ai-items-shopping-groceries/106243642</link><description>Without scrutiny, agent-led shopping risks quietly reconfiguring consumer behaviour in ways that are difficult to detect — and even harder to reverse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e87faa771f8a6692e3910d20b01de1f</guid></item><item><title>Is there a 'normal' amount of sex couples should be having?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/defining-a-healthy-and-fulfilling-sex-life/106100374</link><description>Whether it's TV shows or what our friends say, we pick up an idea of "normal" sex frequency from lots of places. But experts say how often you're having sex doesn't tell you much about whether it's satisfying or enjoyable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d933f11a6d491d896029179c92bdd34a</guid></item><item><title>Maggot-infested meal halts work at $1 billion hydro project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/maggot-meal-halts-work-at-1-billion-dollar-hydro-project/106248782</link><description>An investigation into a maggot-infested meal halts work on a key pumped hydro project in North Queensland, with more than 100 workers flown out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b40fe65ed30e5a5b4dd8904eac05d5b4</guid></item><item><title>Queensland health services report financial black hole of almost $1 billion as population booms and ages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/qld-health-blowout-hospital-report/106249992</link><description>The combined deficit of Queensland's health department and 16 hospital and health services in 2024-25 was the worst ever reported in the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3746f384ecbd30edd186f8342ee71689</guid></item><item><title>Hobart Hurricanes lose captain Nathan Ellis and Test batsman Jake Weatherald for Big Bash knockout final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/two-big-names-to-miss-bbl-knockout-final/106250756</link><description>Hobart's quest for back-to-back Big Bash titles has copped two major blows with captain Nathan Ellis and Test player Jake Weatherald to miss the Hurricanes' knockout final against Melbourne Renegades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b67761843ab9ed0f2e8dd6d75d499e78</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106250606</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b179e9dbc02bc38323324d62e839d0c7</guid></item><item><title>Shooting by ICE agents in Minnesota incites national US protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/shooting-by-ice-agents-in-minnesota-incites-national-us-protests/106250340</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01a9fa2297e01249d676f26d03b97ef0</guid></item><item><title>UK backs plan for China's new embassy in London at Royal Mint Court, despite spy fears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/chinese-embassy-in-london-approved-by-uk-government/106251004</link><description>The new embassy will sit in the city's Royal Mint Court alongside London's famous financial hub, despite experts and human rights groups raising concerns about foreign interference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e4e8511161243507bfe43ef3dc5c285</guid></item><item><title>David Beckham breaks silence after son Brooklyn cuts ties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/david-beckham-brooklyn-davos-children-make-mistakes/106251360</link><description>The soccer superstar tells broadcasters at the World Economic Forum that "children are allowed to make mistakes" in his first public comments since his son's allegations went public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eea9ba1d2b7ca4efca871fee6767d24b</guid></item><item><title>From small cuttings to large pots, household plants are being stolen in great numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/plant-theft-greenery-being-stolen-garden-items-data/106092428</link><description>Data shows more than 2,000 items were reported stolen from gardens over a year in one state alone. So what can plant owners do to protect their beloved greenery from theft?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c928230238105d96554ef20638daf04c</guid></item><item><title>Home buyer says scheme does not work after setbacks buying old and building new</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/myhome-home-ownership-scheme-setbacks/106171584</link><description>Erin Bell's efforts to both buy a house and build a new one through a government scheme were repeatedly challenged — once because she had disclosed a new boyfriend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f65e498ebae764bae79b51a699f2cb9f</guid></item><item><title>Victorian fires set to send premiums higher in areas where insurance already unaffordable for some</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/insurers-say-premiums-will-rise-after-victorian-fires/106244640</link><description>Neighbours living on the same fire-ravaged street in regional Victoria are facing vastly different recoveries due to insurance differences, and recent disasters may push premiums further out of reach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8eba5d08ece1cd8b797fd8bef1bca4f4</guid></item><item><title>Samoa's prime minister proposes ban on non-Christian faiths after vowing 'God-centred' leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/samoa-prime-minister-religion-restrictions/106225328</link><description>Samoa's prime minister has thrown the future of its religious minorities into doubt after flagging potential restrictions on non-Christian faiths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebae72323b0b85847169eb6d895b9309</guid></item><item><title>Austrian study shows a cow using tools for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/austrian-study-shows-a-cow-using-tools-for-the-first-time/106249324</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e93ee64327f2f7b329361f0c4b81d487</guid></item><item><title>Scientific study documents Austrian cow using a tool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/scientific-study-documents-austrian-cow-using-tool/106247598</link><description>A pet cow in Austria has been filmed picking up a tool and scratching herself. An Australian hobby farmer says she is not that surprised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea86ccea34accc0a1ccb2c65d9691ef0</guid></item><item><title>Queensland teenagers create coding app to bridge digital divide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/qld-teenagers-create-coding-app-code-lab-sri-lanka-students/106225842</link><description>Young coding whizzes Neth Dharmasiri and Chinmay Lal believe learning the language behind computer software shouldn't depend on where you were born.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3629ca2497c48acad1816ae6ba32176c</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump, the madman theory, and why even Australia is not safe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/donald-trump-greenland-threat-madman-theory-analysis/106251358</link><description>One year into Trump's second term, something has become clear: even those who leave the Oval Office with a deal, beware. It might not be worth the paper it's written on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17a15eeef7276e5175a8d9725cbfee47</guid></item><item><title>Mitchell Starc shoulder injury concerns Sydney Sixers after BBL qualifier loss to Perth Scorchers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/sixers-sweat-on-starc-injury-after-bitter-scorchers-blow/106251462</link><description>The Sydney Sixers are thrust into a do-or-die final on Friday after losing to Perth, and star quick Mitch Starc is no guarantee to play.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eefe7c22daed676aa248b269f9e31aae</guid></item><item><title>Naomi Osaka brings fashion to RLA and Monfils says goodbye — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/australian-open-2026-quick-hits/106248012</link><description>Naomi Osaka took to Rod Laver Arena in a white, flowy jellyfish fashion piece on day three as Gael Monfils waved goodbye to Melbourne Park. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ad648002c1830c934b1b9a8e22a3c1b</guid></item><item><title>Senior Nationals quit frontbench after defying shadow cabinet on hate speech laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/nationals-ministries-doubt-coalition-split-hate-speech/106251594</link><description>Senior Nationals Bridget McKenzie, Ross Cadell and Susan McDonald quit the shadow cabinet, after defying its position on the government's hate speech reforms in a late-night vote on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe681e902b030d99c1bea78cce0b26e2</guid></item><item><title>Nationals threat of mass resignation from shadow ministry a 'live option', Liberal source says — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/federal-politics-live-blog-jan-21/106251764</link><description>A Liberal source has told the ABC that multiple Nationals resignations from the shadow ministry is a "live option" after three Nationals quit the shadow cabinet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fca17b16aaff7da2dbb84db7b9dfd8d6</guid></item><item><title>Aurora australis seen across Australia as geomagnetic storms deliver spectacular light show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/spectacular-aurora-australis-seen-across-australia/106251474</link><description>A severe geomagnetic storm has hit Earth, painting a colourful cosmic display in Australia's skies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">825db3e352f03ade701fdbbad7920a6a</guid></item><item><title>Prime minister's national security adviser Philippa Brant resigns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/prime-minister-national-security-adviser-resigns/106252214</link><description>Philippa Brant has resigned just months after the PM's top foreign policy adviser departed to run the Office of National Intelligence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">763f42a5aafcf9f8eac55afeda3e30ce</guid></item><item><title>Trash and treasure trike proves powerful tool for brain health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/trash-treasure-trike-broken-hill-brian-slater-brain-health/106234034</link><description>Brian Slater, 77, is heeding advice to "use it or lose it" as he devotes his retirement to cognitive challenges that keep his mind healthy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b18a19aba6c1c38aadd2e1cbd0a8bc9</guid></item><item><title>WA meat processor says using AI for counting livestock has improved accuracy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/ai-camera-counting-sheep-at-wa-abattoir/106249366</link><description>One of WA's largest meat processors is using AI technology to count thousands of head of cattle a day with pinpoint accuracy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3d77b876e3e1623dcb17ef294264615</guid></item><item><title>A year into Trump's second term, the Supreme Court's docket is full of legal challenges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/trump-supreme-court-cases-breakdown/106249160</link><description>A wide range of cases challenging Donald Trump's actions have landed on the Supreme Court's docket in the past year. Here's what to know</description><guid isPermaLink="false">204d8408bab6913672663f8f59c38658</guid></item><item><title>Angus Crichton to leave Sydney Roosters and NRL to chase Wallabies World Cup dream</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/angus-crichton-leave-roosters-chase-wallabies-world-cup-dream/106252548</link><description>Star second-rower Angus Crichton will leave the Sydney Roosters at the end of the NRL season to pursue a career in rugby union.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a295c7e2e59bb0b91dbf8ffd55deb05</guid></item><item><title>Crime gangs restocking shops 'up to 10 times a day' with illegal cigarettes and vapes, WA police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/behind-the-scenes-of-wa-s-illegal-tobacco-business-model/106252960</link><description>WA's police commissioner says the restocking is happening faster than authorities can seize the products, as tobacco black market violence escalates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c85e3ad402b68eddf68bb31ca5929a65</guid></item><item><title>Canadian PM says smaller nations must 'band together' to stop larger countries overpowering them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/carney-blasts-trump-canada-davos-world-economic-forum/106252354</link><description>Canadian PM Mark Carney told the World Economic Forum "middle powers must act together".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3d402b5ff2519732956effe5b696207</guid></item><item><title>Chun Lai Yuen jailed after teenager Caitlyn Dickson seriously injured in Burswood crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/crown-perth-car-cruise-driver-jailed-caitlyn-dickson/106253204</link><description>The driver of a speeding car which hit and seriously injured a teenage girl after a car club meet-up at the Burswood Casino precinct has been sent to prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f220e6312335175671f756a46ab73f6b</guid></item><item><title>What we know about changing UK passport requirements effective February 25</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/what-we-know-about-changing-uk-passport-requirements-explainer/106252182</link><description>Hundreds of confused UK and Irish dual citizens in Australia have written to the ABC with questions around the new changes for entry requirements into the UK. Here's what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ad4283cc2e20810a878022673bc9745</guid></item><item><title>Australian NATO envoy Di Turton warns North Korea has 'combat-ready troops in our region'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/turton-warns-north-korea-has-combat-ready-troops-in-our-region/106246654</link><description>Australia's outgoing military envoy to NATO is preparing to return to Canberra after two years in the role, and she is coming home with a warning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b24fa33cd95a9f83851e93c8d2239d49</guid></item><item><title>Why Elina Svitolina is prioritising her mental health at the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/australian-open-elina-svitolina-prioritises-her-mental-health/106253922</link><description>In the highly competitive world of professional tennis, it is refreshing to learn that Elina Svitolina has her priorities in order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">231dc2e91147acfd4cd1936346129dc9</guid></item><item><title>New South Wales man charged with allegedly threatening prime minister</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/man-charged-threatening-politician-bellingen-prime-minister/106252292</link><description>A NSW Mid North Coast man is granted bail after he allegedly threatened to shoot the prime minister, in a video uploaded to social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a162f7503002a63f89c62572cb4f408</guid></item><item><title>Midnight Oil's Rob Hirst died of pancreatic cancer. It's one of Australia's deadliest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/midnight-oil-rob-hirst-pancreatic-cancer-death/106252876</link><description>Rob Hirst was first diagnosed with pancreatic cancer in 2023. It is estimated to be the third most common cause of cancer death in Australia, and has among the lowest survival rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9ddc9310c0db0de11b44dad7f91d666</guid></item><item><title>Have you been gifted an ancestry DNA test? The results could be 'life-altering'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/why-ancestry-dna-tests-arent-just-a-bit-of-fun/106225222</link><description>If you're thinking of taking an ancestry DNA test as "a bit of fun", experts warn there is the risk of uncovering more than you bargained for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c18adfae6ecc122d7b0786df99d29aa2</guid></item><item><title>Shane Marshall pleads not guilty to manslaughter charge over infant's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/shane-marshall-pleads-not-guilty-to-infant-manslaughter/106254184</link><description>An Adelaide man has been ordered to stand trial after pleading not guilty to a charge of manslaughter following the death of a seven-week-old baby who had allegedly been in his care. WARNING: This story contains details that some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a93023575c22fb9d852afd34e94351c</guid></item><item><title>Zeynep Sönmez thrills Turkish fans with latest Australian Open win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/australian-open-zeynep-sonmez-turkiye-second-round-melbourne/106254442</link><description>In front of her loyal supporters, Türkiye's Zeynep Sönmez advances to the Australian Open third round, as her remarkable run continues at Melbourne Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22727b155241893e1895d1a9d793586a</guid></item><item><title>New hate laws have passed parliament. What do they actually do?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/what-will-new-hate-laws-do/106253754</link><description>The new laws grant powers for the government to list so-called hate groups, more easily deport or cancel the visas of individuals associated with hate groups and create new aggravated penalties for leaders who advocate violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22f42220711e3e177be96bf784d2def9</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106254400</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96b2d0610f77559240b421960b39fc7a</guid></item><item><title>Banned Adelaide doctor Bill Tolis in court over steroid importation charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/adelaide-banned-doctor-bill-tolis-charged-steroid-importation/106253698</link><description>A man who was banned from working as a doctor in 2022 appears in court charged with importing steroids and peptides that the Australian Border Force allegedly found in a medical clinic and at his home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15ae84013164210499851a72702a1db6</guid></item><item><title>Father of Adelaide girl who died due to mother's alleged neglect tells court of coffin threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/jasmine-willmott-father-gives-evidence-in-manslaughter-trial/106254726</link><description>The father of a 15-year-old girl whose mother is accused of her manslaughter, tells the South Australian Supreme Court of a threat made against his daughter and punishment she was made to do.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">877e18523e326afbcffe861376220e59</guid></item><item><title>Coalition on the brink as Nationals quit shadow ministry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/nationals-coalition-littleproud-ley-hate-laws/106254676</link><description>Opposition leader Sussan Ley says the Nationals' mass resignation from her frontbench is "unnecessary" and has urged the rural party to remain in the Coalition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2506e2c3d1df8a3e6b416a4e1ad58809</guid></item><item><title>Real estate prices set records with six capitals now in 'million-dollar club' and Melbourne rebounding strongly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/australian-real-estate-median-home-prices-domain-report-millions/106251932</link><description>The Melbourne real estate market is leading a "decisive recovery", according to property portal Domain, as the city hits a four-year high for its median house price after strong growth across the country last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ecae4dcc6d7b32b532b527df98b5815</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump drops Greenland tariffs threat as he heralds 'future deal' with NATO</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/donald-trump-tells-davos-he-wants-greenland-deal-with-denmark/106255244</link><description>Donald Trump says he has agreed to a "framework of a future deal" on Greenland after talks with NATO's secretary-general, and he will no longer impose tariffs on European nations that had opposed a US takeover.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f89614fd2c7c59f2ce651d55a6edb4</guid></item><item><title>Japan restarts nuclear power plant almost 15 years since Fukushima disaster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/worlds-biggest-nuclear-power-plant-restarted-after-fukushima/106255280</link><description>The world's biggest nuclear power plant has been rebooted by the same company that operated the Fukushima facility, despite concerns about safety from some locals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">449f4979bd3a97dd3cade26e5436d195</guid></item><item><title>Royal Hobart Hospital medical scan backlog creating late diagnosis risk, AMA says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/royal-hobart-hospital-medical-scans-outsourced/106250608</link><description>The Royal Hobart Hospital is facing a significant backlog of medical scans, with at least one patient experiencing a late diagnosis. The AMA and a union say it's a sign of a system facing a range of pressures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b176a825f6f77ae4bd8c9f6625b7666e</guid></item><item><title>How closely have you been following the 2026 awards season?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/mid-awards-season-quiz/106236836</link><description>Fancy yourself an awards season whiz? Test your knowledge as we rocket towards the 2026 Academy awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17381a39bd7b2538186d35a6037811fe</guid></item><item><title>Calls to bring back hard-hitting anti-smoking campaigns to warn off gen Z</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/calls-to-bring-back-hard-hitting-anti-smoking-campaigns/106076928</link><description>Experts say Australia risks becoming complacent in the war against tobacco, with big companies pivoting to social media to "greenwash" their products to generation Z.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a3755c5faf71c4ae310c4fa1f70cef6</guid></item><item><title>Nationals' walkout leaves Coalition in tatters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/national-walkout-coalition-on-life-support/106252042</link><description>The departure of every single member of the Nationals from the frontbench is bizarrely both a failure of the Coalition agreement and a result of it functioning as intended.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87d0ee925d656b9cc5bc9005730349bd</guid></item><item><title>Australia earns global praise for economic 'soft landing' but still dependent on China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/reserve-bank-earns-global-praise-for-economic-soft-landing/106254000</link><description>A new report from the OECD says Australia's economy is returning to normal but remains vulnerable and lacks dynamism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05e404f80625145a36267752e37fcb5d</guid></item><item><title>Europe holds the trump card as the US faces a mountain of debt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/trump-us-debt-carney-davos-fractured-world-order/106254272</link><description>For decades, global investors have bought US government debt as a safe haven when things turn pear-shaped. But investor attitudes are changing, and America's financial domination is at stake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef5ba145fdb46fb1740c5e13e6f77eb3</guid></item><item><title>'Ten-pound Pom' vows to boycott UK over 'money grab' passport changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/ten-pound-pom-boycotting-uk-over-passport-changes/106252052</link><description>People who came to Australia as children from the UK as part of an organised migration scheme say they the UK's new regulations for dual citizens unfairly targets them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">589e215128e03f85233423439cb2ca67</guid></item><item><title>Hobart Hurricanes beat Melbourne Stars in rainy thriller to keep BBL title defence alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/hurricanes-win-in-the-rain-to-get-bbl-title-defence-alive/106255630</link><description>The Hobart Hurricanes hold their nerve to beat the Melbourne Stars in a rain-shortened Big Bash elimination final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b3de8ccef426aa4a98bc8ad84b9fc29</guid></item><item><title>Taskforce set up to address ongoing power outages across SA from dust pollution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/power-outages-across-regional-south-australia-from-dust/106252096</link><description>Ongoing dry conditions across South Australia since 2024 are causing dust and salt to build up across inland and coastal power networks, polluting insulators and leading to mass blackouts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfa755b708992c638b64e4eaec702edf</guid></item><item><title>Police Association says Coober Pedy and APY Lands are 'unacceptably compromised' by police shortage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/coober-pedy-police-station-shortage/106254028</link><description>South Australia's police union says some officers in the remote town are working 18-hour days and have been unable to respond to all incidents, amid an ongoing industrial dispute with SA Police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c95b2aa716dd7117122caf12eb92208</guid></item><item><title>Back-to-school budgeting a chance for kids to learn financial literacy and empathy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/how-to-involve-your-kids-in-back-to-school-budgeting/106225314</link><description>Managing back-to-school costs, especially when kids want expensive brand name items, can cause a lot of stress for families. But including children in the budgeting and decision-making process is key to helping everyone get on the same page.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37b64c02787d589912788d033586f11c</guid></item><item><title>Manchester City players reimburse travelling fans after shock Champions League loss to Bodo/Glimt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/man-city-players-reimburse-fans-champions-league-bodo-glimt-loss/106255684</link><description>Manchester City players combine to pay back the cost of match tickets to fans who travelled to freezing Norway for a shock Champions League defeat to Bodø/Glimt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3961b71b542f027eda47766f4098781a</guid></item><item><title>More than one disaster a week raises concerns over mental health support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/mental-health-natural-disasters-floods-bushfires/106248008</link><description>Mental health experts warn of significant barriers to support in disaster-affected communities, as Australia records more than one natural disaster a week since January 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1754a727c59bc8d6ab652edb65847dd</guid></item><item><title>$10 billion data centre planned for Hazelwood in Victoria's Latrobe Valley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/keppel-data-centre-latrobe-valley/106123748</link><description>Victoria's east is set to become home to a $10 billion data centre that will support the technology necessary for artificial intelligence systems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9956deb90fefb9d8c74ef249d8393b13</guid></item><item><title>Plan to rebuild world's largest living coral aquarium explained after years of delays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/townsville-reef-hq-aquarium-great-barrier-reef-australia-rebuild/106233472</link><description>The world's largest living coral reef exhibit is yet to be rebuilt five years after the Queensland aquarium closed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8a00984196c7af8a42ee31f3ff4fcb0</guid></item><item><title>Tour website's AI sends visitors to Tasmanian sites that do not exist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/ai-images-of-tasmania-on-tour-website/106253448</link><description>Weldborough in remote north-east Tasmania has lots of natural beauty. But it does not have hot springs — and it is causing headaches for locals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17596b208021bc09f69e25ce3d3ee9cf</guid></item><item><title>Administrators seek buyers for Sanjeev Gupta's Tahmoor Coal mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/tahmoor-coal-sale-gupta-administrators/106254968</link><description>Administrators have put Sanjeev Gupta's Tahmoor Coal mine up for sale, seeking buyers to recover value for creditors and potentially restart operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc73e72ea7427583d3403e8301d3c525</guid></item><item><title>AJ Ogilvy, former NBL player, comes out as gay on eve of league's Pride Round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/aj-ogilvy-former-nbl-comes-out-gay-pride-round/106255856</link><description>Former NBL player AJ Ogilvy publicly reveals he is gay in a one-on-one conversation with fellow basketball trailblazer Isaac Humphries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80eb63b342830bb88108f2a6e89f5eb6</guid></item><item><title>Coalition splits for second time since election after Nationals quit shadow cabinet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/coalition-splits-for-second-time-since-election/106255898</link><description>David Littleproud says the Nationals have been put in an "untenable" position and are not willing to serve in a shadow ministry led by Sussan Ley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da003f94bbd7e082339a8bd3ef36d5c7</guid></item><item><title>'You have no idea what fair play is': Osaka and Cirstea in tense exchange</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/australian-open-2026-live-novak-djokovic-kyrgios-kokkinakis/106256036</link><description>There is no love lost between Naomi Osaka and Sorana Cirstea after the Japanese star prevails in a hard-fought three-setter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc3dbf5886ebf502a83d62ef67ff3bdc</guid></item><item><title>Frances Tiafoe psyched up to play Alex de Minaur in Australian Open third round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/australian-open-alex-de-minaur-frances-tiafoe-third-round/106256130</link><description>It says a lot about the presence of youth in professional tennis that Alex de Minaur and Frances Tiafoe can already be considered veterans on the tour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad79a2741bd570aac7d24180c8fae85f</guid></item><item><title>Unemployment rate drops to 4.1 per cent ahead of RBA's next rates meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/abs-jobs-unemployment-december-2025-figures/106256288</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate fell from 4.3 to 4.1 per cent in December, according to seasonally adjusted figures from the Australian Bureau of Statistics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca9a4c57a25ef4052b004d05710e2490</guid></item><item><title>Young girl among several missing after landslide at NZ campsite — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/new-zealand-landslide-search-for-missing-people/106256570</link><description>Several people are missing after a landslide at a campsite in the tourism hotspot of Mount Maunganui, south-east of Auckland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23379a7a711cb4f2aedc78ee1266c283</guid></item><item><title>The optics are diabolical for Liberals and Nationals, as chaos reigns on a supposed day of mourning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/optics-diabolical-liberals-nationals-split-chaos-reigns/106256942</link><description>Littleproud and his team have now basically broken one of the most fundamental political rules of the Coalition — the Nationals are now effectively dictating to the Liberals who their leader should be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfc29a319f10b7654b1744b2408480f8</guid></item><item><title>Territorians working hard to cull cane toads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/territorians-working-hard-to-cull-cane-toads/106254792</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01dc070978534f4b990110319cca61b2</guid></item><item><title>More than 1,000 cane toads captured in first Darwin botanic gardens bust in years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/nt-cane-toads-community-bust-invasive-pest-darwin-rain/106254926</link><description>Volunteers in Darwin have chipped in to capture more than 1,000 cane toads at one of the city's main attractions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b11df1d2cdc1b23fc82c0ad1ac738a15</guid></item><item><title>Australian writer Murray Hunter apologises to Malaysian regulator over criminal complaint in Thailand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/australian-writer-murray-hunter-faces-prosecution-in-thailand/106071904</link><description>Rights groups slam Thai authorities' detention and legal proceedings against Australian writer Murray Hunter, after Malaysia's communications regulator submitted a criminal defamation complaint.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a398c92859ab9deed27a35a44ed1eedc</guid></item><item><title>What's next, as Liberals and Nationals go their own way?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/what-next-sussan-ley-leadership-coalition-split/106256498</link><description>In the wake of the Coalition's divorce, there are few options for besieged Opposition Leader Sussan Ley, who must again reshuffle her cabinet and return to parliament with a diminished Opposition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">994575ca7514db7940e29e80b787ba77</guid></item><item><title>Jay Vine climbs into Tour Down Under ochre jersey after UAE Team Emirates XRG underlines its dominance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/jay-vine-wins-tour-down-under-stage-two/106257102</link><description>Australian Jay Vine claims the overall race lead at the Tour Down Under after an awesome display of dominance on the Corkscrew climb.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb9e394e9534f79c841df8035f841ba4</guid></item><item><title>Woman who assaulted psychiatrist and other healthcare workers remanded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/woman-who-assaulted-psychiatrist-healthcare-workers-remanded-vic/106256858</link><description>A judge tells a Victorian court the safety of healthcare workers must be protected while remanding a mentally ill woman to jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9a8a342d45019c7e529a6831781d169</guid></item><item><title>Perth financial advisor Anthony Paul Torre jailed for taking more than $1 million from clients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/anthony-paul-torre-jailed-stealing-fraud-1million-from-clients/106255256</link><description>Victims of a Perth financial adviser jailed for misappropriating more than a million dollars from investors say his six-year jail term is not enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d61027d39caaea38c6adc2658d7601e</guid></item><item><title>Forbes man Lawrence Wilfred Norris intends to plead not guilty to historical child sex offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/lawrence-norris-intends-to-plead-not-guilty-child-sex-offences/104852292</link><description>A NSW court hears the former vice-president of a local show society intends to plead not guilty to dozens of historical child sexual assault charges if he is found fit to stand trial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f13bb702d228f8cf1e73d4fef38f24e</guid></item><item><title>National Party's Coalition split timing deemed 'unbelievable' on National Day of Mourning for Bondi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/regional-voters-react-to-national-party-liberals-coalition-split/106256646</link><description>The second messy break-up between the National and Liberal parties is concerning regional voters across the country, even in diehard conservative heartlands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70ea918e48b086454d41c22e7c84bed8</guid></item><item><title>City of Perth probe lays bare workplace 'crisis', erosion of trust between Mayor and CEO</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/city-of-perth-workplace-behaviour-probe-/106250502</link><description>The City of Perth has rapidly descended into a workplace of psychological harm, according to a secret report obtained by the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64fc50ebb57a43747397b8920642f9ac</guid></item><item><title>From Bone Temple to Oscar hopefuls, here are January's best movies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/what-to-watch-in-cinemas-january/106233164</link><description>Multiple Oscar hopefuls are finally hitting Australian shores this month, as well as the return of zombie franchise 28 Years Later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2272f4f6ef3115ef6805bda843c70c9</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106258766</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e59c5ef1942298829e1214a0c64fd5dc</guid></item><item><title>First LNG cargo from Santos Barossa gas project bound from Darwin to Japan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/nt-first-cargo-lng-santos-barossa-gas-leaves-darwin-for-japan/106258638</link><description>After a series of delays, Santos announces the first gas from its $5.6 billion Barossa project will be shipped from Darwin bound for Japan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd8bba37d4f040d1881712e836830e01</guid></item><item><title>Maddison Inglis wins epic Australian Open second-round match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/australian-open-maddison-inglis-wins-second-round-melbourne/106258820</link><description>With a 10-point tiebreaker to decide her Australian Open fate, Maddison Inglis knew there was only one avenue to victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7da89e4d1adfe1038099cca78fbd4468</guid></item><item><title>Nationals senator Matt Canavan questions if government and agencies can be trusted on hate speech laws and attacks Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/matt-canavan-coalition-split-attacks-asio-government-ley/106259282</link><description>Nationals senator Matt Canavan has questioned why anyone should trust any government when it comes to the powers over hate speech laws, and unloaded on Sussan Ley's leadership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9a65ee94a1a53fc1f7f43539a06fa28</guid></item><item><title>Naomi Osaka apologises for 'disrespectful' post-match comments aimed at Sorana Cirstea after tense Australian Open exchange</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/tennis-naomi-osaka-apologises-sorana-cirstea-aus-open-exchange/106259566</link><description>Naomi Osaka walks back her aggressive retort to a tense handshake between her and second-round opponent Sorana Cirstea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09581ba0cb5ce587403760bbfce3cced</guid></item><item><title>Oscars 2026: Sinners break record with nominations, Jacob Elordi and Rose Byrne receive nods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/oscar-nominations-2026-academy-awards-sinners-jacob-elordi/106259128</link><description>Vampire film Sinners broke the Academy Award record for nominations with 16, while Rose Byrne was recognised for If I had Legs I'd Kick You and Jacob Elordi got a nod for his role in Frankenstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48c475fdedf71590ecb11f7edcbff1a8</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan shopping centre fire in Karachi kills at least 55 people as recovery efforts continue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/death-toll-from-pakistan-shopping-centre-fire-rises/106259932</link><description>Investigators are continuing to search for others who died in the disaster, with authorities yet to announce what caused the blaze.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5675475904019bb62a9711d4410804c</guid></item><item><title>France seizes suspected Russian 'shadow fleet' oil tanker in Mediterranean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/france-seizes-oil-tanker-that-left-russia-in-mediterranean-sea/106260102</link><description>The move is the latest by Western allies to crack down on a so-called "shadow fleet" of tankers suspected of carrying Russian oil against international sanctions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43d6477f8aa1dc4292de5def3f75e127</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy flags trilateral Ukraine, Russia and US talks, while slamming 'lost' Europe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/zelenskyy-announces-ukraine-talks-with-russia-us/106260134</link><description>The Kremlin has confirmed the Ukrainian president's announcement, made at the World Economic Forum in Davos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7545f1ac1fc90719bebdd764e896542e</guid></item><item><title>Death toll from Spanish high-speed train disaster rises to 45</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/spain-train-death-toll-hits-45/106260198</link><description>Train drivers in the country are striking after a string of rail accidents in less than a week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">143c5b51c32ad15e4cd58f05c34af47d</guid></item><item><title>Questioning your relationship in the new year? You're not alone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/why-the-new-year-exposes-relationship-problems-/106224924</link><description>The fresh start of a new year causes us to reassess many parts of our lives, including relationships. Knowing whether it's time to call it quits or give things more time requires reflection — and support — as our experts explain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a8679e8fb180c317100f0812cb15f67</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: A political break-up, a fashionable entrance and Macron's aviators</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/weekly-news-quiz-january-23/106258548</link><description>Another week, another quiz. Are you ready to test yourself?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54cbf4b01ab6495cdb58b22385dc9242</guid></item><item><title>The Nationals split shows the foundations of right-wing politics are shifting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/liberals-nationals-split-coalition-right/106257774</link><description>It is impossible to view this week’s events without the broader context of the relationship between the Liberals and the Nationals, how the electoral map is changing and what that means for right-wing politics in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e5d77a30c76d5a35cb630af005cbb89</guid></item><item><title>Trump touts 'total access' Greenland deal as NATO asks allies to step up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/trump-greenland-deal-access/106260210</link><description>The leaders of both Denmark and Greenland say they don't know what's in the deal, announced by the US president after he backed away from threats of tariffs and military force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c54c670db00f8511a0c0a5ef5e47e881</guid></item><item><title>Australia names second-largest Winter Olympic team in history for 2026 Milan-Cortina Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australia-names-athletes-for-2026-winter-olympics-milan-cortina/106257140</link><description>From five teenagers making their Winter Olympics debut to five-time Olympian and gold medal hopeful Scott James, Australia has named its second-largest team in history for the Milan-Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9364382cbf12d3eab2d2239d3c30bf50</guid></item><item><title>Anger and confusion after Australian courier Sendle collapses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-courier-tech-sendle-collapses/106237380</link><description>The Australian company's customers feel like they have been "ghosted", while investors and shareholders are angry and confused about what happens next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75d4d8cc352fa82cac285f1a0bcac529</guid></item><item><title>Venezuela's El Helicoide was built as a world-leading retail hub. Then it became a notorious 'torture prison'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/venezuela-el-helicoide-history-from-shopping-centre-to-prison/106232826</link><description>Nestled among shanty homes, mountains and forestry, a giant building once touted to become Venezuela's world-leading retail mecca later turned into a centre for alleged human rights abuses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76e6bc139f10a583017d798a7f71355c</guid></item><item><title>Seven-day heatwave to engulf south-east states, raising bushfire danger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/seven-day-heatwave-for-south-east-australian-states/106258360</link><description>South-east states are predicted to bake through a prolonged severe heatwave from Saturday onwards, which has the potential to break all-time temperature records and fuel another round of dangerous bushfires.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e206661f047d7153c78444b4bf38fcc</guid></item><item><title>Fiji police allegedly seize $780m cocaine shipment in drug operation targeting Pacific Ocean 'narco sub'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/fiji-vatia-alleged-cocaine-bust/106252766</link><description>Fijian chiefs reported suspicious activity along their stretch of coastline to law enforcement agencies — which then swooped on an alleged $780 million drug operation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7b65c9bfdd418c9e913eeb19db1490c</guid></item><item><title>Daylesford op shop may permanently close after donation causes bed bug infestation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/daylesford-op-shop-closed-after-bed-bug-donation/106257322</link><description>The future of a Victorian op shop is in doubt after a worker opened a bag containing the stuff of nightmares, leading to the destruction of stock and hefty cleaning bills that may prove to be a deadly financial blow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92343d5a6b3a6f9e91a7d081f2faf352</guid></item><item><title>Six people confirmed missing in landslide at New Zealand's Mount Maunganui</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/new-zealand-landslide-search-at-mount-maunganui-continues/106259556</link><description>Specialist officers have worked through the night with earthmoving equipment to try and find those trapped under the rubble at a popular tourist spot on New Zealand's North Island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b56c3c64c991749e723a32a089f025b8</guid></item><item><title>Gunman wanted over triple shooting could be difficult to find, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/police-search-for-lake-cargelligo-gunman-after-three-shot-dead/106260214</link><description>Police have warned residents in villages neighbouring Lake Cargelligo to remain vigilant after three people were shot dead in a domestic violence attack on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6237034df4c10ee4887c72324b79c0b</guid></item><item><title>David Speirs not entitled to public campaign funding, electoral commission says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/david-speirs-not-entitled-to-campaign-funding-commission-says/106252588</link><description>Former opposition leader David Speirs would "not fulfil the nomination requirements" if he applied to be a candidate at the upcoming state election, the state's electoral commission says, raising significant doubts about his chances of a political comeback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b51d1258f01f889f9ffa8d09f9b01925</guid></item><item><title>Solid start to AI camera trial with rock fisher rescue at one of NSW's deadliest locations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/ai-camera-rescue-rock-fisher-kiama-blowhole/106252572</link><description>Surf Life Saving NSW says the successful rescue of a rock fisher at Kiama Blowhole using two AI-enabled surveillance cameras proves the technology works.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e967a1d1c2cfc39de99b807ffaa9f852</guid></item><item><title>triple j's Hottest 100 of 2025 — when it happens, how to listen and more</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/triple-j-hottest-100-of-2025-date-start-finish-time/106255830</link><description>Australia's favourite music poll is back for another year — here's when it happens and how to listen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1040e2c0baec6105e30c997bf6a0c8f8</guid></item><item><title>Wawrinka's post-match recovery beer and an 'elite coffee snob' — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-open-2026-quick-hits/106256482</link><description>Madison Keys praises Melbourne coffee, Stan Wawrinka says he deserves a beer and Nick Kyrgios back to racquet throwing ways. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdb19a2b8f7adeb672b77b643c9797c4</guid></item><item><title>Albanese predicts 'at least one more' Coalition MP will defect to One Nation — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/politics-live-blog-coalition-nationals-liberal-ley-littleproud/106258084</link><description>The PM's comments came after Nationals leader David Littleproud said he was open to working with Liberal leader Sussan Ley again "at some point", but right now the two parties need "a bit of time apart".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">654dbfefff1e7fe6f19497082344c400</guid></item><item><title>DNA found in an ancient Colombian skeleton may hold answers to origin of syphilis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/ancient-dna-in-colombian-skeleton-syphilis-finding/106257238</link><description>A previously unknown strain of syphilis bacteria has been discovered in human remains in Colombia, dating back 5,500 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">761f4136bcbedf14e3f88cb864e27b50</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios and Thanasi Kokkinakis lose first round Australian Open men's doubles clash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/special-k-nick-kyrgios-thanasi-kokkinakis-aus-open/106260326</link><description>After playing like "shadows of our former selves", Nick Kyrgios and Thanasi Kokkinakis are out of the Australian Open men's doubles and into an uncertain future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c0855d44f970a7bd97e76435b181e56</guid></item><item><title>ASX slightly up, Aussie dollar hits 15-month high — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/asx-markets-business-live-news-jan23-2026/106260382</link><description>The Australian share market has finished slightly higher after a rally on Wall Street, as investors showed signs of relief a day after US President Donald Trump dropped tariff threats against eight European countries. Look back on our Friday business blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40932dc245b230489389510db47af34d</guid></item><item><title>Inside the Syrian city of Raqqa, once known as Islamic State's 'Roundabout of Hell'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/inside-raqqa-syrian-government-kurdish-fighters/106259928</link><description>Syrian government forces have wrested back control of vast parts of its territory in recent weeks, as a new president moves to assert control over the war-torn country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7976dc278e108c80f77b0c705e6920d</guid></item><item><title>How cool rooms and cold storage work to keep fruit fresh year-round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/cool-rooms-keep-apples-fresh-year-round/106244706</link><description>Apples only grow for three months of the year — but thanks to an ancient technique, that doesn't stop us grabbing one from the grocery store year round.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18d4e3c1e52e7cd899af23bc7bc1ad00</guid></item><item><title>Defiant Sussan Ley downplays Nationals' split, vows to remain leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/defiant-sussan-ley-vows-to-remain-leader/106260460</link><description>The Liberal leader did not speak about the Nationals' decision to terminate the Coalition on yesterday's National Day of Mourning, but on Friday insisted her focus was on the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a7f9d5a8b73b778d178181d0ad4f49c</guid></item><item><title>Clermont couple build online flood tracker in just hours to warn neighbours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/clermont-flood-tracking-website/106243686</link><description>The 'Gauge' site was built in just four hours by IT professionals Steve and Emma Coochin and has expanded to include river and rain data from across Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf95207740915c40a8c0727439d39906</guid></item><item><title>Oscar nominations 2026: All the snubs, successes and surprises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/oscar-nominations-2026-snubs-successes-surprises/106260530</link><description>Hybrid horror Sinners came up as the big winner in the 98th Academy Award nominations, with Aussie actors also eyeing up gold, and Wicked: For Good wiped off the map.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d761bb2879eaa9851b2172d6c644d374</guid></item><item><title>Live: 'A bit unnecessary': Putintseva mocks fans after knocking out crowd favourite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-open-2026-live-sabalenka-alcaraz-de-minaur-osaka/106260854</link><description>Yulia Putintseva mocks Turkish fans after knocking out qualifier Zeynep Sönmez in the third round, while three-time runner-up Daniil Medvedev pulls off a comeback from two sets down for the fourth time at the Australian Open. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a04cafe18c649afd498aa7f1f3f47fbb</guid></item><item><title>NBL star urges middle ground on Pride Round after Breakers jersey boycott</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/nbl-star-urges-pride-round-middle-ground/106260522</link><description>As the NBL's Pride Round begins, Marcus Lee warns an all-or-nothing approach could shut down the very conversations the round is meant to start.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58242609ac0484472fb20c7700974f98</guid></item><item><title>Australian-born dual citizens confused, frustrated over new UK passport rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/british-australians-caught-up-in-passport-bungle/106252142</link><description>Confused dual citizens are voicing their frustrations as they grapple with changes to the UK's entry requirements, which roll out next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">425f1782f91f4a16c4bb6da1d72f8e07</guid></item><item><title>Taylor Fritz pays tribute to 40-year-old Stan Wawrinka ahead of Australian Open match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-open-stan-wawrinka-taylor-fritz-third-round/106261080</link><description>It was meant as a compliment, rather than a show of disrespect, when Taylor Fritz answered a question about Australian Open rival Stan Wawrinka's age.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c2e005d319489a9f8a0eccc72657f11</guid></item><item><title>1,000 cakes and eight complaints: Brisbane picnic event under investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/qld-cake-swap-food-safety/106254312</link><description>An investigation has been launched into a viral Brisbane 'cake swap' event after attendees raised concerns over food safety and hygiene, with cakes reportedly left uncovered in hot weather for hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1e5dc3e8811ac8635e15909c20516d4</guid></item><item><title>ICE officers detain five-year-old Minnesota boy as he arrives home from preschool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/ice-officers-detain-5-year-old-minnesota-boy/106260888</link><description>School officials and the family's lawyer say the boy and his father were taken to a detention facility in Texas, making the boy the fourth student from Minneapolis detained by immigration officers in recent weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f1e66129057f445bb42e4ec7cae6d7</guid></item><item><title>Illegal dumping creates eyesore and hard work at Sunshine Coast op shops</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/sunshine-coast-op-shops-frustrated-with-illegal-dumping/106247800</link><description>Volunteers say they are tired of "lazy" residents dumping their unwanted goods outside op shops to avoid paying tip fees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">871279b041aa2167b88a4b69d8849176</guid></item><item><title>$17 million announced to push Wollongong sports and entertainment precinct closer to reality</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/wollongong-sports-entertainment-precinct-funding-announced/106261074</link><description>The NSW government has unveiled long awaited plans for the redevelopment of Wollongong's sporting precinct as it commits $17 million to develop a business case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff60335d34dbbef747d64f935b214079</guid></item><item><title>Paris Hilton brings sex tape story to Washington for AI deepfake porn fight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/paris-hilton-returns-to-washington-for-deepfake-porn-fight/106260660</link><description>The party girl turned anti-abuse advocate throws her glamorous celebrity heft behind a push to tackle deepfake pornography.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be3bdab756405b29eee8fe4b96735764</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone warning extended as tropical low edges closer to Kimberley coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/tropical-low-cyclone-kimberley-coast-weekend/106257742</link><description>A tropical cyclone warning has been issued for residents along the far north WA coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40b1ded951323489c7af96436cdb5857</guid></item><item><title>US and China sign off on TikTok agreement to avoid ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/us-and-china-sign-off-on-tiktok-agreement-to-avoid-ban/105946464</link><description>Social media giant TikTok reaches a deal for a new joint venture in the United States to avoid being banned for American users. The platform's Beijing-based parent company, ByteDance, will retain a 19.9 per cent stake in the company.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98db492f98dbae94336107116f99f2ec</guid></item><item><title>What Bernard Fanning and Ben Lee's Hottest 100 topping hits tell us about them in 2005</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/ben-lee-bernard-fanning-2005-tea-sympathy-precocious-awake-sleep/106254430</link><description>In 2005, Bernard Fanning and Ben Lee were very different men with very similar struggles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4104fb0576195f6d49333b282b330b1c</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump is obsessed with Greenland, but now his comments point to the 'entire Arctic'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/donald-trump-greenland-maps-explain-battle-for-arctic/106248192</link><description>After a week of escalating rhetoric over Greenland, Donald Trump says he has now secured "total access" to the Arctic island. This is why that region is so important.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80258e25c9b73d3a371cfd33873c0456</guid></item><item><title>Queensland brothers charged with child abuse material offences after US tip-off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/ashley-and-kaden-millard-gladstone-charged-child-abuse-offences/106260552</link><description>Australian Federal Police investigators allege the men accessed child abuse material on social media platforms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b379ecc2a299291d7b0566fdc26d53e</guid></item><item><title>Who is Indra Brown, the 15-year-old Melbourne schoolgirl going for gold at Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/indra-brown-australia-15-year-old-freeski-halfpipe-star/106220172</link><description>When 15-year-old Indra Brown reached the podium in her first World Cup event, she needed help from global superstar Eileen Gu to pop the cork on her champagne. She's had plenty more practice since, as she heads into the Milan Cortina 2026 Winter Olympic Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1bd2a59bbb1851f70a1c81a87c262dc</guid></item><item><title>Regional NSW principal to stand aside amid antisemitism investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/riverina-principal-to-stand-aside-antisemitism-investigation/106260992</link><description>The principal of an Islamic school in regional NSW has stood aside while investigations into alleged antisemitic comments continue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66bbf4776663885e6118d7122c516844</guid></item><item><title>Letter sent to Lakemba Mosque threatening violence on Australia Day investigated by police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/nsw-australia-day-mosque-threat-police-investigation/106260802</link><description>The note, seen by the ABC, incited violence against several groups, including Middle Eastern communities, Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islanders and a number of political figures from Labor, the Greens and "socialists" were also singled out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40a93d7c9c85c5131545560539c3e2e1</guid></item><item><title>Decision to suspend Tasmanian councillor Louise Elliot for 'child-like' comments upheld in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/councillor-sanctioned-over-clown-man-comments/106261958</link><description>A Tasmanian councillor says she is being "censored and unfairly punished" after being sanctioned for social media posts she made regarding a fellow councillor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15db2611739d68e4253bc14a8e7bf7f6</guid></item><item><title>Trump sues JPMorgan Chase for $US5 billion, alleging bank closed accounts for 'political reasons'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/trump-sues-jp-morgan-chase-jamie-dimon-closes-accounts-political/106260598</link><description>Donald Trump is suing banking giant JPMorgan Chase and its chief executive for $US5 billion ($7.3 billion) over allegations that JPMorgan stopped providing banking services to him and his businesses for political reasons in January 2021.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89430bef8f415825580494dd7adb60f5</guid></item><item><title>US officials tout 'New Gaza' plans filled with shiny luxury skyscrapers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/us-touts-new-gaza-filled-with-luxury-real-estate/106261524</link><description>US officials have presented their vision for a "New Gaza" that would turn the shattered Palestinian territory into a glitzy resort of skyscrapers by the sea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">332468f105e8f38eeb197372324b59be</guid></item><item><title>Townsville mother says she warned authorities before suspected drownings at north Queensland swimming hole</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/townsville-mother-warns-over-suspected-drownings/106260772</link><description>Local mother Jordan Pryce says she witnessed multiple near-drownings at the swimming hole on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f99789714191e9b4596c2d89b1fb66f4</guid></item><item><title>Track temperatures as heatwave sweeps across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/temperatures-heatwave-tracker-australia-day/106261904</link><description>Use our tracker to keep an eye on temperatures as a heatwave moves across much of the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e57e1f2214ee021677fa9f1ede08fbdd</guid></item><item><title>Final report urges Queensland to opt out of building accessibility requirements, government says it won't</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/qld-building-accessibility-standards-productivity-construction/106261950</link><description>A final report by the Queensland Productivity Commission recommended the state opt out of standards outlined in the National Construction Code.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44412ebf5637154213ddf0ac0f84d478</guid></item><item><title>Launceston City Council staff to vote on four-day, full-pay work week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/council-seeks-to-usher-in-four-day-work-era-on-full-pay/106261380</link><description>Launceston City Council and the Australian Services Union have reached in-principle agreement on a deal for employees to work 30.4 hours over four days, and be paid their full salaries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6de6e4998c9225528e97f7a38ee2254</guid></item><item><title>Who is the Neo-Nazi who was booed at Hobart's March for Australia rally?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/who-is-neo-nazi-nsn-member-at-hobart-march-for-australia/106243774</link><description>With the organisers of March for Australia rallies saying they "are in no way concerned by the presence" of members of the National Socialist Network, the ABC can confirm a Tasmanian man whose words were too extreme for many in the Hobart crowd is believed to be a leader within the state's Neo-Nazi movement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dd9e1cf44e49a7d888aa48587dc3692</guid></item><item><title>Labor identity Tim Picton remembered at Perth Stadium memorial service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/tim-picton-memorial-service/106255116</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is among political figures and business leaders who travel across the country to pay their respects to Mr Picton.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5d7055f3334cbd3e08a1546f091c39f</guid></item><item><title>Federal Court finds extended Victoria Police stop-and-search declaration was unlawful and invalid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/federal-court-police-designated-area-designation-unlawful/106262240</link><description>The Federal Court has found a Victoria Police move to give officers greater powers in Melbourne's CBD for six months was invalid and unlawful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff906739ce6790b737ba6a47ae4879b9</guid></item><item><title>What is a landslide, how do they happen and where are they most common?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/how-landslides-happen-and-where-they-are-most-common/106261240</link><description>Two people have died after a landslide hit their home in New Zealand and authorities are searching for several others feared dead in another slip nearby. Here's how landslides occur, the warning signs and where they are most common.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">851733bbedf99ceab4b1c59174b2194c</guid></item><item><title>How to attract native wildlife and birds to your garden</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/how-to-attract-native-wildlife-and-birds-to-your-garden/106042150</link><description>There are simple things we can all do to encourage more native wildlife to our gardens, backyards, balconies and shared spaces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a86ce4b9695adc5a6d1286749a33f7cf</guid></item><item><title>Video of bull shark washed up on Brisbane River bank sparks debate over AI technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/qld-bull-shark-brisbane-river-ai-speculation/106261868</link><description>A video posted to social media of a bull shark washed up in the Brisbane River went viral and prompted speculation that it was AI-generated, but experts say it appears to be legitimate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79cee32b8f5ede448241764cbe5b102e</guid></item><item><title>Former Broome pub manager jailed for six years over rape of staff member</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/broome-pub-manager-stewart-burchell-sentenced/106037710</link><description>Stewart Patrick Burchell is jailed for six years, found guilty by jury trial of raping a staff member and indecently assaulting several others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfd31eca85588a6872ef20bdd2788feb</guid></item><item><title>Sam Welsford wins Tour Down Under stage three, fears for riders with 42C temperatures Saturday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/sam-welsford-wins-tour-down-under-stage-three/106261424</link><description>Sam Welsford claimed a brilliant Tour Down Under stage victory, the seventh of his career, as experts fear for riders ahead of 40-degree Celsius temperatures predicted for Saturday's fourth stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38187f744e5d2eca7d5d7ad509f0a094</guid></item><item><title>Bail accommodation facility for women opens in Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/bail-accommodation-facility-for-women-opens-in-alice-springs/106257182</link><description>There are hopes the Salvation Army-run facility will keep women safe and help them reintegrate into the community while easing pressure on the prison system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9c1101d12ec87a4bb68bf62658eebdb</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania to introduce new gambling reforms, including mandatory facial recognition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/tasmania-to-introduce-new-gambling-reforms/106261384</link><description>The Tasmanian government has announced a suite of new harm minimisation measures to be implemented across hotels, clubs, and casinos, aiming to "reduce red tape and regulation".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3654d29a075aacd0656bac99b985bda</guid></item><item><title>Lake Cargelligo residents in shock after three people shot dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/lake-cargelligo-urged-indoors-a-neighbours-recall-gunshots/106260708</link><description>Residents of a remote NSW town of just 1,500 residents have expressed shock at a deadly shooting spree where three people were shot dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d8d66d4d35e438eccff0c1e13a7f7fa</guid></item></channel></rss>