<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 14:07:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Teenager accused of electric motorbike death in Perth's north pleads not guilty to manslaughter charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/boy-accused-of-e-bike-death-denies-manslaughter-charge/106278852</link><description>A teenage boy accused of killing a 59-year-old woman while riding an unlicensed high-powered electric motorbike in Perth's north has pleaded not guilty to manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27244f675dcca5226051f20e404ba7f4</guid></item><item><title>'One-off' literary festival, Constellations, to go ahead in lieu of Writers' Week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/alternate-literary-festival-constellations-in-adelaide/106279364</link><description>A community literary festival will go ahead in the wake of the cancellation of Adelaide Writers' Week, but those involved say it is not a replacement for the original event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef44bb2df86cdb6c803ede79ea9f26e4</guid></item><item><title>Counterfeit Botox still being imported into Australia, months after regulator first raised alarm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/counterfeit-botox-items-detected-by-tga-in-australia/106278732</link><description>Counterfeit Botox vials were packaged in branded boxes that appear like a genuine product, according to a renewed warning from the Therapeutic Goods Administration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">776747f9c945055009f9d210c84c6b7e</guid></item><item><title>Iranian doctor who fled to Australia after operating on massacre victims estimates death toll in tens of thousands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/doctor-operated-on-wounded-during-iran-massacre-protests/106277548</link><description>In one of the most harrowing accounts yet, a doctor who fled Iran for Australia recounts trying to save bullet-riddled victims of the government crackdown on protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16fae7ededa33199f7a195a02a8ea18e</guid></item><item><title>Rain has transformed the outback from parched to puddles.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/from-thirsty-camels-mud/106279410</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38a8b5daea7a9f23748c75a79557e4d4</guid></item><item><title>Jim Chalmers has rejected responsibility for high inflation but will have a tough sell if rates rise again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/chalmers-says-inflation-is-not-his-fault/106279808</link><description>Less than a year after the Reserve Bank started cutting rates, the prospect of a rate rise is a political nightmare for a treasurer hoping for clear air.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c548b41b8cc890d99129d352e74eaa6f</guid></item><item><title>Former member of National Socialist Network fights for return of weapons licence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/former-national-socialist-network-member-weapons-licence-appeal/106279468</link><description>A man, who was stripped of more than a dozen guns after police found multiple copies of Adolf Hitler's manifesto at his home, is fighting to have his weapons licence reinstated by a court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb80f484ffa0fbb8d33a0e771ae0749c</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106280098</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcbcc22000a85ac613cdbde4d932e0fc</guid></item><item><title>Doctors failed to tell authorities of driver's vision impairment before fatal Adelaide crash, inquest hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/sa-inquest-into-doctors-conduct-before-crash-that-killed-woman/106278662</link><description>A coronial inquest will investigate why three doctors failed to alert relevant authorities that a man was unfit to drive due to vision impairment in the years before he caused a crash which killed a mother of four.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da7be28c4f70d432f4edbdb020b928da</guid></item><item><title>Gem hunter receives suspended prison sentence for illegally mining turquoise at NT sacred site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/gem-hunter-illegal-mined-turquoise-ore-nt-sacred-site-sentencing/106278496</link><description>A gemstone dealer has received a four-month suspended prison sentence for illegally mining more than 8 tonnes of turquoise ore at a Northern Territory sacred site.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f3a9d472c461f3385d63d0404569b85</guid></item><item><title>First Nations urge stronger response after alleged Invasion Day rally attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/first-nations-reactions-to-perth-rally/106278632</link><description>First Nations leaders have urged governments to take stronger action in response to the alleged attack at an Invasion Day rally in Perth on Monday. Social Justice Commissioner Katie Kiss says failing to do so "sends a message that Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander people do not matter".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d788783b2f2b1d9210b64763272a33fb</guid></item><item><title>Victorian man faces court over alleged assault in SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/police-charge-victorian-man-over-alleged-assault-in-sa/106280464</link><description>A Victorian man has faced court after allegedly stabbing a man before following him to an Adelaide hospital where he allegedly made threats toward paramedics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c613de2e822b75b0731caebcd5936a5</guid></item><item><title>Authorities investigate bomb allegedly thrown into Perth Invasion Day rally crowd as 'potential terrorist act'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/authorities-investigate-alleged-perth-bomb-as-terrorist-act/106280668</link><description>A joint statement by WA Police, the Australian Federal Police and domestic security agency ASIO say the agencies' investigations are ongoing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f67cb75199536da0fae24b70fd1f55b5</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic gets lucky break in Australian Open win over Lorenzo Musetti</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/australian-open-novak-djokovic-lorenzo-musetti-quarterfinal/106279982</link><description>As he trailed Lorenzo Musetti, 10-time champion Novak Djokovic knew he was on the ropes as he looked to keep his Australian Open campaign alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6989483c04e6e616d14a6022e57d9acd</guid></item><item><title>Concerns domestic tenants required to share excessive personal data to secure leases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/concerns-tenants-sharing-excessive-data-to-secure-lease-ahuri/106269564</link><description>Tenants are being forced to hand over excessive personal data when applying for rental properties, with new research warning that applicants' personal information could be at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">203f59b7aa7b6ce7128c5459c2aee8d1</guid></item><item><title>Trump threatens Iran with 'major destruction' as US fleet arrives in Gulf</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/us-donald-trump-threatens-iran-with-major-destruction/106280948</link><description>The US president says Tehran should make a deal or face military strikes as tensions between the two countries escalate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10e6c332f60229c131b7f3edac7e63e8</guid></item><item><title>'Bring them home' answered at last as Israel buries final hostage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/final-israeli-hostage-laid-to-rest-after-843-days-in-gaza/106280912</link><description>Many people who turned out to Ran Gvili's funeral hope this will allow the country to start to move forward and heal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94eee45d930fe78188eb5a0e0451899e</guid></item><item><title>Amazon accidentally announces further 16,000 layoffs in AI pivot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/amazon-accidentally-announces-layoffs/106280800</link><description>A misfired internal email was the first time many employees found out about a second round of job cuts in just six months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86b1eaba850241fba6bf277d009edc28</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Greens MP Tim Read to retire from state politics to focus on cancer battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/brunswick-greens-mp-tim-read-reveals-cancer-diagnosis/106278032</link><description>Victorian Greens MP Tim Read reveals he will retire from politics at this year's election after he was diagnosed with metastatic cancer — but not before one last political fight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bd4bd27af283ebfca28c70c7e951c88</guid></item><item><title>The US wanted to ban TikTok over national security concerns. Does a deal with China fix that?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/what-does-china-tiktok-deal-mean-for-us-national-security/106270748</link><description>US politicians — both Republican and Democrat — had worried TikTok's Chinese ownership could mean American user data was vulnerable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">829a0db74e3349f33087c609ec8bdd2d</guid></item><item><title>Rate hike pain is on the way for Australian borrowers, but will they be able to tolerate it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/inflation-higher-than-expected-rba-now-likely-to-raise-cash-rate/106278844</link><description>The Reserve Bank cut interest rates three times last year, betting inflation would moderate. But that hasn't happened, and now a rate hike looks likely next month — and possibly another in May.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df000fb90ee59b24891f02660da6ab94</guid></item><item><title>As Jannik Sinner and Carlos Alcaraz dominate, straight-sets matches are skyrocketing at the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/tennis-sinner-alcaraz-aus-open-competitiveness-dominance/106280732</link><description>The gap between the top seeds and the rest of the players in both the men's and women's draws has resulted in another day filled with straight-sets wipeouts at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d69272a825653b32b8365f5533ec617c</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic disrespected as Serena Williams offers Coco Gauff racquet smashing tips — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/australian-open-day-11-quick-hits-coco-gauff-novak-djokovic/106277850</link><description>Serena Williams offers Coco Gauff some tips on how to smash a racquet properly, while Novak Djokovic gets a dose of luck on court and a little disrespect off it. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">697d054373a3857b053e1b782af5c2d7</guid></item><item><title>These are the sticking points as phase two of the Gaza ceasefire arrives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/sticking-points-of-phase-two-gaza-ceasefire-explained/106280740</link><description>The body of the final Israeli hostage has been returned, but uncertainty remains about the future of the strip, including who will oversee its administration, whether Hamas will disarm and the withdrawal of Israeli assets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ecc7a06704d6f781879db3af446e3be</guid></item><item><title>Health courses the most popular area of study for Australian university students in 2026, as IT enrolments fall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/university-degrees-australian-students-picking-2026/106247426</link><description>Data from the country's tertiary admissions centres shows health courses are again the most popular area of study for university students in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">139a0ca6dd78a91330e6c5f3629e5bb4</guid></item><item><title>Missing records in ACT childcare documents prompt concerns about scale of issues in sector</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/missing-records-act-childcare-documents-prompt-concerns/106273400</link><description>An ABC investigation has found some parent complaints and incident reports were excluded from a major release of ACT childcare documents, raising concerns about the scale and severity of problems in the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c95c200a5a330934622e47dee782f4b</guid></item><item><title>Rising bike thefts inconveniencing the nation but police say it's 'opportunistic'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/rising-bike-thefts-affecting-the-nation/106275258</link><description>If it hasn't happened to you, you likely know several people who have had their bikes stolen, and it isn't just those that are worth a lot of money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6dc1484206db416c099441a5f468dd9</guid></item><item><title>Phoebe Litchfield out of WPL with injury, raising concerns for India multi-format series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/injured-litchfield-leaves-wpl-concern-for-home-india-series/106281146</link><description>Australian batting star Phoebe Litchfield has to abandon her Women's Premier League season because of injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0792bab34432b61c7a12dbc112228057</guid></item><item><title>Two Teabags bringing joy and connection to aged-care residents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/two-teabags-bringing-joy-and-connection-to-aged-care-residents/106278704</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ecac7ffd26aa483d679b08a466272ab</guid></item><item><title>The Two Teabags bringing joy and connection to residents in aged care homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/two-teabags-bring-joy-and-connection-to-aged-care-residents/106189520</link><description>Former aged care workers Marina Lee-Warner and Julie Joy have created a live show tailored to older Australians, including those facing cognitive decline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">788bee98eb47096ea22ff0306404d812</guid></item><item><title>As Trump threatens Iran, a US naval strike group arrives in the Middle East</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/iran-us-navy-strike-group-donald-trump-middle-east/106276852</link><description>A US aircraft carrier, supporting warships, fighter jets and air-defence systems have arrived in the Middle East, as the world waits to see to what action — if any — Donald Trump will take against Iran.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72c7775fcee2488ef071234da78470a7</guid></item><item><title>Talison lithium mine blasts in regional WA ignite calls for home buyback scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/talison-lithium-mine-greenbushes-residents-want-home-buybacks/106262764</link><description>Home owners living beside the Greenbushes lithium mine in Western Australia are calling for a buyback or relocation scheme amid the mounting toll of blasting, dust and noise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c14dc3318797e8e1079726c364b0ca3</guid></item><item><title>What is India's Nipah virus outbreak, what are the symptoms of the illness and how can you protect yourself from it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/what-do-we-know-about-india-nipah-virus-outbreak/106280738</link><description>Two cases of the Nipah virus have been detected in India, prompting a raft of screening measures to be enacted in countries across Asia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1450cb0be69b0ff6f046cde421748e6</guid></item><item><title>Sophie Molineux named Australian cricket captain, succeeding Alyssa Healy ahead of India series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/molineux-named-healy-successor-as-australian-captain-cricket/106281600</link><description>Sophie Molineux becomes Australia's new multi-format captain, taking over from Alyssa Healy ahead of a home series against India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3c004078c58d9d0e5319eb299a36155</guid></item><item><title>Firm behind cryptocurrency Qoin fined $14m for 'misleading' and 'condemnable' conduct</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/cryptocurrency-qoin-company-fined-14m-misleading-conduct/106278720</link><description>The company behind the Gold Coast-based crypto token Qoin has been fined $14 million by the Federal Court following long-running legal action by the corporate watchdog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9d146e42d41f5066717f6f68e96b4a5</guid></item><item><title>Man convicted of London assault after Barron Trump witnessed attack on video call from US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/barron-trump-intervention-helps-convict-russian-man-of-assault/106281372</link><description>A Russian man who became jealous of a woman's friendship with the youngest son of US President Donald Trump has been found guilty of assaulting her by a London court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f7973448815ecf8425118beefc2065b</guid></item><item><title>Canberra woman faces court for allegedly assaulting stranger's newborn baby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/baby-allegedly-thrown-from-pram-by-stranger-in-canberra/106281532</link><description>A woman aged in her 50s has faced the ACT Magistrates Court over the incident. WARNING: This story contains distressing details about an alleged assault on a baby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9793a142556574294d48d0dbe72e45ba</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026: Aryna Sabalenka the familar face in women's singles semifinals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/sabalenka-has-single-focus-with-open-trophy-beckoning/106282116</link><description>The Australian Open has lost the regular women's grand slam heavyweights from the draw but world number one Aryna Sabalenka remains a Melbourne Park constant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">304d87b0efed370b633f496682ae96cb</guid></item><item><title>First Nations leaders welcome Perth Invasion Day rally terror probe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/first-nations-leaders-welcome-perth-invasion-day-terror-probe/106281330</link><description>First Nations leaders say WA Police's investigation of Monday's alleged Invasion Day rally attack as "a potential terrorist attack" is a step in the right direction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">569d29cfb9373ce563d6e6a1fa8b83d1</guid></item><item><title>Farmers want permanent solution after 200-tonne landslide closes Waterfall Way</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/farmers-call-long-term-solution-waterfall-way-landslide/106257220</link><description>The NSW government has announced a fresh assessment of a key transport route recently closed by a 200-tonne landslip, but residents say it has all been done before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82584941049f0bda9e1a83bec4d70df4</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania takes control of ore stockpile after Liberty Bell Bay defaults on $20 million loan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/liberty-bell-ball-loan-default-tas-to-take-ore-stockpile/106281912</link><description>The Tasmanian government appoints receivers and managers to protect the manganese ore stockpile paid for by taxpayers at the Liberty Bell Bay smelter in the state's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9b3c04fb5b2a166cf60f6125f2fa151</guid></item><item><title>Tears of pride for Aryna Sabalenka as she makes Australian Open history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/australian-open-day-12-live-blog-sabalenka-svitolina-rybakina/106282372</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka is into her fourth straight Australian Open final after beating Elina Svitolina in straight sets in their semifinal, where she will meet Elena Rybakina. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13a3254c51c4da4f38c73f93e6a5fdb4</guid></item><item><title>David Speirs sees 'pathway' to standing for election amid eligibility questions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/david-speirs-pathway-to-election-amid-eligibility-questions/106281982</link><description>Former South Australian Liberal leader David Speirs says there is a way he could stand for the upcoming state election — but is yet to declare whether he will — despite the electoral commission declaring he is ineligible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fae2aef5067464d9cc7ec98c01ec275</guid></item><item><title>Malaysian football executives resign over player naturalisation scandal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/malaysian-football-executives-resign-over-player-naturalisation-/106282446</link><description>A scandal in which foreign players were improperly granted citizenship to play for the national team leads to the "voluntary" resignation of the executive committee of Malaysian soccer's governing body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e02d9a276c2f62056f0ea9525e1dc247</guid></item><item><title>Why it took nearly half-an-hour for police to start evacuating Perth’s Invasion Day rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/wa-invasion-day-explosive-police-response-analysis/106280370</link><description>As police face criticism for their handling of Perth's Invasion Day rally bomb scare, a law enforcement expert says they faced a "no-win situation".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d01ca40c394e758ea661c68dbe75a21</guid></item><item><title>Former employee accused of defrauding three NSW local councils by more than $1 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/nsw-martin-dimec-accused-defrauding-three-local-councils/106282160</link><description>Martin Thomas Dimec is facing more than 40 charges of fraud after police allege he stole the money from Murrumbidgee, Shoalhaven and Goulburn councils across 12 years of employment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f04f54fbda6336f24a525726db0fb900</guid></item><item><title>Australian government fund to invest $75m in company producing material critical to AI supply chains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/75-million-investment-high-purity-alumina-ai-gladstone/106281688</link><description>An Australian government fund will invest $75 million in Alpha HPA, helping it build the world's largest single manufacturing facility for high-purity aluminium materials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68738f60c938ecaa61726eb30f9acdbd</guid></item><item><title>Police release CCTV as part of Lake Cargelligo shootings manhunt.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/police-release-cctv-lake-cargelligo-shootings-manhunt/106283512</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d86e277f924ee26bb63f482dcc3b2d4c</guid></item><item><title>Coalition chaos drags on ahead of first official sitting week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/coalition-pauline-hanson-liberals-nationals-one-nation/106278234</link><description>Former prime minister John Howard once observed that Pauline Hanson was an "electoral gift to the Labor Party". His words proved relevant this week as the Coalition's chaos dragged on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e55fe948ed9cac9dfbe249d4a750510</guid></item><item><title>Hastie and Taylor fail to agree on plan to oust Ley despite clandestine meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/hastie-and-taylor-fail-to-agree-who-should-challenge-sussan-ley/106283820</link><description>The two conservative men vying to replace Sussan Ley as leader of the Liberal Party met in Melbourne before attending a memorial service for their former colleague Katie Allen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48442b172bb5d4d73b9254f6ca7c0381</guid></item><item><title>United Nations special rapporteur seeks to join challenge to NSW government's protest restrictions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/un-expert-seeks-to-join-challenge-nsw-govt-protest-restrictions/106283462</link><description>A United Nations expert is seeking to join a constitutional challenge to the NSW government's protest restrictions brought in after the Bondi terrorist attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b18300f51ba0611dd1a38a500e33cb00</guid></item><item><title>Parramatta provided with emails from Zac Lomax's lawyer as contract drama plays out in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/zac-lomax-eels-contract-case-lawyer-agent-storm/106284054</link><description>Parramatta has been given nine emails sent by Zac Lomax's lawyer as the case between the former Eels winger and his former club prepares to hit the courtroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6fab00ca9fdf9b673ff2ad88952bce4b</guid></item><item><title>'Predatory' former Logan teacher jailed for child sex offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/predatory-teacher-jason-seung-hak-lee-logan-child-sex-offences/106283910</link><description>The former Logan teacher, 30, has been handed a 5-year sentence after pleading guilty to multiple child sex offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8da2c6ce2847559254b32f4c3916b7f</guid></item><item><title>UK wants 'sophisticated relationship' with China, Keir Starmer tells Xi Jinping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/keir-starmer-seeks-stronger-china-ties-after-meeting-xi-jinping/106283366</link><description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer tells Chinese President Xi Jinping he wants to build a "sophisticated relationship" aiming to boost growth and security, signalling a breakthrough in ties after years of acrimony.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a77c9b43792c1a41f5d3872183e6859</guid></item><item><title>How farmers help keep their livestock and produce alive during a heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/farming-through-a-heatwave-how-farmers-stay-cool/106281292</link><description>How farmers make sure their livestock — and produce — stay safe during a heatwave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aabaf9f0bf0f0b845aba873eaf89c73c</guid></item><item><title>Most AI assistants are feminine — and it's fuelling dangerous stereotypes and abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/ai-assistants-female-dangerous-stereotypes-abuse/106281652</link><description>The design choices behind AI technologies — female voices, deferential responses, playful deflections — create a permissive environment for gendered aggression.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52aba3fc8e780a3a444023a722041f1a</guid></item><item><title>Queensland farm cashing in on US wellness industry demand for camel milk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/farmers-celebrate-us-interest-in-queensland-camel-milk/106283200</link><description>Camel milk is in hot demand in the wellness industry, now one Queensland farmer is seizing the moment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">441b865e5599c229e2ffa3008cb77db4</guid></item><item><title>China executes online scam ringleaders from Myanmar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/china-executes-online-scam-ring-leaders-from-myanmar/106284248</link><description>China executes 11 people linked to Myanmar criminal gangs, including "key members" involved in online scam operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a76abd16aad858c6ca8150d5841334a</guid></item><item><title>Planning to breastfeed? Preparation can help you meet your goals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/what-to-know-about-breastfeeding-before-your-baby-arrives/106220406</link><description>While most mothers in Australia start breastfeeding, by the time babies are five months old, exclusive breastfeeding drops to 15 per cent. Knowing what to expect — before bub is born — can increase the chances of meeting your breastfeeding goals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74803b6ee63f792d44b8c092db9dbd1e</guid></item><item><title>Police shoot at allegedly stolen car during chase in Geelong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/police-shoot-at-allegedly-stolen-car-during-chase-in-geelong/106284648</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">360fae01305c75faeb1bdb5909dcce0a</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026: Tennis Australia boss Craig Tiley listening to Coco Gauff player privacy complaints</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/australian-open-2026-player-privacy-craig-tiley-coco-gauff/106284528</link><description>The Australian Open will listen to complaints from players like Coco Gauff about behind-the-scenes cameras but remain convinced of their value, Tennis Australia chief executive Craig Tiley says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbe1d3a7a95c6a69cf43b391f66f0cb6</guid></item><item><title>Canadian backpacker Piper James's family and friends to visit Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/backpacker-piper-james-family-to-visit-australia/106283172</link><description>The heartbroken parents of Canadian backpacker Piper James will travel to Australia next week to visit K'gari, the island where their beloved daughter lost her life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e079dad83b3f8d3cb0ffd9b2196ec944</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106284468</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8d8acf018ab6475c2015fa2a7d33813</guid></item><item><title>'Never seen magnitude' of foreign vessels in Far North Queensland, as government defends border security</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/island-residents-reject-gov-border-security-investment/106284502</link><description>Torres Strait Island leaders say federal government claims of strong border protections do not match what communities are seeing on their doorstep in Queensland's far north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2d2d7fac8c95f3b44ad51bf9aec3f0c</guid></item><item><title>Bluey tops streaming charts in US for second year running</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/bluey-tops-streaming-charts-in-us-second-year-running/106284782</link><description>Americans tuned in to watch 45.2 billion minutes of Bluey, Bingo, Bandit and Chilli last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">359b77f5544572ac6d4f3b8653a634d0</guid></item><item><title>Former senior Mackay police officer sentenced over child abuse material</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/former-police-officer-sentenced-over-child-abuse-material/106282896</link><description>The court heard Mark Andrew Lewer had created profiles on four 'dark net' websites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78aaf37e0af7a758214fcaf544ce1516</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka manages anger to book fourth consecutive Australian Open final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/aryna-sabalenka-books-aus-open-final-fourth-consecutive-year/106284842</link><description>World number one Aryna Sabalenka books her fourth consecutive Australian Open final, defeating Ukraine's Elina Svitolina in straight sets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57f2c93fd324f785507cbc9e507cf448</guid></item><item><title>Democrats strike funding deal with White House as Trump undercuts border tsar on Minnesota drawdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/border-tsar-tom-homan-speaks-in-minneapolis-minnesota/106285350</link><description>Donald Trump says he has struck a deal with Congressional Democrats to temporarily fund the Department of Homeland Security, heading off a political brawl that seemed inevitable after the Senate voted down the latest package of government spending bills.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f31c3c2125dcc02174fa3cfda2dbb834</guid></item><item><title>EU labels Iran's Revolutionary Guards a terrorist organisation in policy shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/eu-designates-iran-revolutionary-guard-a-terror-organisation/106285596</link><description>European Union foreign policy chief Kaja Kallas says "repression cannot go unanswered" as the bloc looks set to categorise the IRGC alongside Islamic State and Al Qaeda.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9a14f02b677056cb22457aff09b5981</guid></item><item><title>What could have happened to Celine Cremer, the Belgian tourist who went missing in Tasmania in 2023?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/celine-cremer-what-could-have-happened/106283120</link><description>Celine Cremer went missing in 2023 from a track in a remote part of Tasmania's north-west. With several recent discoveries in the area, these are the theories of what could have happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fa46b028409bdd47ade634a0a74b296</guid></item><item><title>Trump says Putin agrees not to fire on Kyiv for one week, as freezing cold grips Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/putin-agrees-not-to-attack-kyiv-for-one-week-trump-says/106285676</link><description>Ukrainians, including residents of the country's capital, are experiencing their toughest winter of the war as Russian attacks target electricity infrastructure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b95e6b9ba98482a847a4af1c52c81d6</guid></item><item><title>February interest rate rise will be a 'bitter pill' for those struggling with cost of living, advocates say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/interest-rate-hike-to-hurt-amid-cost-of-living-crisis-fca-says/106282550</link><description>Consumer advocates fear a rate hike when the RBA board meets next week could be the "straw that breaks the camel's back" for borrowers in mortgage stress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d8d8f6bfb26ee5e5a784163fc3fa2fb</guid></item><item><title>GPS trackers in e-waste from Australia reveal 'likely' illegal exports to South-East Asia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/gps-in-e-waste-from-australia-reveal-exports-to-south-east-asia/106196324</link><description>A not-for-profit environmental group put GPS devices in 35 e-waste items and dropped them off at recycling locations in four Australian capital cities. Here's what they found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aca5cebf2406f07e87dae8d61746ccda</guid></item><item><title>The curious case of Pritam Singh, Singapore's ousted opposition leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/singapore-opposition-leader-pritam-singh-deposed-by-pm/106271192</link><description>Even for a de facto one-party state, the ruling People's Action Party's decision to dictate who runs Singapore's opposition is remarkable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fa2f090a4baa201df980d8ba10a1641</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic feels disrespected ahead of Australian Open semi against Jannik Sinner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/australian-open-novak-djokovic-jannik-sinner-semifinal/106284616</link><description>Playing with a chip on his shoulder or feeling slighted is often when 10-time Australian Open champion Novak Djokovic produces his best results.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e4e42d306849efa5a2fc671b18e697a</guid></item><item><title>As Donald Trump weighs up actions, Iranians send the US a message to 'please help'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/iranians-begging-donald-trump-intervention/106278760</link><description>Protesters in Iran are begging US President Donald Trump to launch military action to help topple the Islamic regime. But could it happen?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0104644f2ea8023284ca1e0ce13e8e0</guid></item><item><title>Two aspirants who are unlikely to suit the times vie for Liberal leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/coalition-leadership-angus-taylor-andrew-hastie-sussan-ley/106252048</link><description>Andrew Hastie and Angus Taylor both want to run against Sussan Ley. But the two right-wingers cannot afford to split the conservative vote on which their tilts would rely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba51f7fb24d29cbbec7cd19701ea84b9</guid></item><item><title>Elena Rybakina takes the long road back into Australian Open final and best in the world conversation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/tennis-elena-rybakina-aus-open-final-analysis/106285234</link><description>After being the forgotten figure when it comes to conversations about elite women's players, Elena Rybakina has put her name back up in lights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">051e6d02ab7256e11d03f0982faada6d</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide median house price grows $50,000 in a quarter, reaching $925,000 according to Valuer-General data</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/median-adelaide-house-price-inches-closer-to-1-million/106247930</link><description>Experts are forecasting continued growth this year as Adelaide's metropolitan median house sale price inches closer to $1 million, according to Valuer-General data.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f5fc36214dede0fbcb20494fda824d7</guid></item><item><title>The makers of AACTA-nominated movies and TV shows discuss the Australian screen industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/aacta-nominations-bring-her-back-kangaroo-apple-cider-vinegar/106274762</link><description>Ahead of next week's AACTA Awards, the makers of frontrunners Bring Her Back, Kangaroo and Apple Cider Vinegar share their thoughts on the state of the local screen industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bce16781a3b4a5eeb30978d95ccc0b3</guid></item><item><title>Steven Johnson to stand trial for alleged Victorian cold case murder of Christopher Jarvis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/steven-johnson-trial-alleged-murder-of-christopher-jarvis/106283412</link><description>A landlord has been ordered to stand trial over the cold case death of his tenant Christopher Jarvis, who disappeared from his home near Warrnambool 20 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">caa90199513892529dc287febc0c6eb8</guid></item><item><title>A mid-match coffee break, Aryna Sabalenka's hindrance and a finalist's flashback — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/australian-open-day-12-quick-hits-aryna-sabalenka/106284124</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka's abnormal sound is punished, an Aussie has a mid-match coffee break and a women's finalist has an unsettling flashback. Here are the quick hits from day 12 at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">377325548b4589d070e7dd6f71ee3896</guid></item><item><title>Shoppers remember 'old days' at grocery store that has operated since late 19th century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/shoppers-memories-at-maclean-grocery-store/106093338</link><description>A New South Wales grocery store has been operating since before there was refrigeration, electricity and even Vegemite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13022bd7c8867c23fb979d67f3523425</guid></item><item><title>Hastie says he doesn't have support to challenge for Liberal leadership — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/federal-politics-live/106282604</link><description>Andrew Hastie will not contest the Liberal leadership, clearing the way for a possible challenge to Sussan Ley from Angus Taylor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d21429c4a876b692acc686fb3842a875</guid></item><item><title>Trump tariffs could 'isolate' the US and create new trading blocs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/trump-tariffs-isolate-united-states-creating-new-trading-blocs/106279190</link><description>In the past fortnight, US President Donald Trump has threatened tariffs against at least 10 countries. Some experts say the Trump administration's tariff policy is leading to the creation of new trading blocs, and isolating the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d680083e4bdd5f1c248ec52b9f8477d2</guid></item><item><title>Gold, silver plummet ahead of Fed chair announcement — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/asx-markets-business-live-news-jan30-2026/106283750</link><description>The prices of gold and silver have plummeted in Asian trade as markets prepare for a surprise Federal Reserve announcement, and the ASX 200 has finished the week on a negative note. Look back on the day's finance news in our business blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b8022ddef8840fb50b933476c1e329d</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of flying foxes die, hundreds rescued, amid record-breaking SA heatwaves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/thousands-of-bats-in-sa-killed-after-heatwaves/106283058</link><description>A deadly combination of heatwaves has all but decimated a colony of flying foxes in SA's south-east, with surviving bats taken in by conservationists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dc9d83483a1198cfab5c4f68d8ace11</guid></item><item><title>SA Arts Minister Andrea Michaels to quit politics after state election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/andrea-michaels-to-quit-politics-after-sa-election/106285782</link><description>Andrea Michaels will not recontest her seat of Enfield, in Adelaide's inner north, but will remain in the cabinet until the March election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e5816633168f19eb7900aaffb75bb37</guid></item><item><title>Inpex under investigation after suspected sulphur dioxide exposure leaves worker in hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/nt-worker-hospitalised-potential-sulphur-dioxide-exposure-inpex/106283830</link><description>The Australian Workers' Union has raised concerns after a worker at Inpex's Ichthys gas facility was allegedly exposed to sulphur dioxide and hospitalised, prompting an investigation by the NT workplace safety watchdog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb31e475b4a1845ff9a7e9b9a6bf5dcc</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan down Australia by 22 runs in first match of T20 World Cup warm up series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/australia-pakistan-t20-world-cup-zampa/106285786</link><description>Despite the best efforts of evergreen spinner Adam Zampa, Australia have suffered a 22-run defeat to Pakistan in the first T20 of their World Cup preparations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5b6797ab9e5e0e0753ce33df51981bf</guid></item><item><title>Men flee four-wheel drive at flooded Cape York crossing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/men-flee-four-wheel-drive-at-flooded-cape-york-crossing/106284024</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba0f5aa5a6c6860752d4400e87f4980c</guid></item><item><title>Queenslander launches petition to charge drivers for dangerous rescues amid wild flooding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/queensland-petition-flood-driver-swiftwater-rescues/106258426</link><description>A flood victim is leading a campaign to force drivers who knowingly enter floodwater to pay for their rescue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da8fc48f6130854fda8658eedcce7bd7</guid></item><item><title>From Bondi to Perth, questions are being raised about the safety of public events</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/could-perth-invasion-day-rally-incident-signal-new-normal/106284214</link><description>As the Invasion Day rally incident and Bondi terror attack shatter expectations that people should be able to gather peacefully in public places, Australians may be facing a new normal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">539e7ccf9d8939fd21e1cb916140fd5c</guid></item><item><title>WA heatwave causes almost $1 million in crop losses to Gascoyne fruitgrowers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/carnarvon-growers-mangoes-wiped-out-by-heatwave/106273574</link><description>Growers in WA's Gascoyne food bowl have lost an estimated $1 million of fruit, with another heatwave on the way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8f8570aede49cc27fffd82e86a4981d</guid></item><item><title>Genetically modified purple tomatoes bound for fruit shops after regulator approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/gm-purple-tomato-approved-for-australian-growth-and-sale/106262696</link><description>The purple tomato was altered to make it taste better and boost nutrition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5bd1ac2234b9c2c680495f600b02f6f</guid></item><item><title>Polar bear walks on ice with cubs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/polar-bear-walks-on-ice-with-cubs/106285916</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">821b321e4da3c5195e26ac0fa30cfeb5</guid></item><item><title>'Good news' for Norway's polar bears, which are growing fatter despite loss of sea ice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/fat-polar-bears-svalbard-norway-despite-loss-of-sea-ice/106285810</link><description>Polar bears of the Svalbard archipelago have surprised scientists by growing fatter, despite shrinking sea ice, with one theory that the bears are including reindeer and walrus in their diet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9286b0e2cae46a331f15a2787d19d49d</guid></item><item><title>Kevin Muscat's Shanghai Port one of nine Chinese Super League clubs hit with corruption sanctions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/kevin-muscat-shanghai-port-chinese-super-league-corruption/106286038</link><description>Kevin Muscat's chances of steering Shanghai Port to a third successive Chinese Super League title have taken a hit with the club to start the season on minus five points after the Chinese FA completed a wide-ranging investigation into corruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29a24b977d37515cfff1103f297ccadc</guid></item><item><title>Look back at historic V-Set passenger service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/look-back-at-historic-v-set-passenger-service/106285056</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5964ba6b411025766ad372cc45b4be7f</guid></item><item><title>Rare earths mine at centre of Trump-Albanese deal yet to materialise after years in the making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/trump-albanese-arafura-rare-earths-mine-facing-further-delays/106285164</link><description>It is the Central Australian mine promised to help upset China's dominance of the rare earths market worldwide, and bring hundreds of jobs to Australia. But where is it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76c503f1ba23d8a96c79b1c3396b51b5</guid></item><item><title>The US wants to control Venezuela's finances. These armed groups could make it difficult</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/venezuelan-armed-groups-could-challenge-us-recovery-plan/106207132</link><description>The US plan to "recover" Venezuela could spark a domestic backlash in a country that is already heavily divided among various armed groups that have political interests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e60395cd057395211a12f4e84aa39d3b</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump has Iran in his sights, but what is his endgame?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/donald-trump-poised-to-strike-iran/106275390</link><description>As the "massive armada" of the United States approaches Iran to be in place for a possible military attack, a key question remains: what can such firepower actually achieve?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b87d627b2e6226212e6ab3126fac4f59</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Lions coach Chris Fagan says Lachie Neale having his 'best pre-season in a long time'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/lachie-neale-brisbane-lions-pre-season-marriage-breakdown/106286732</link><description>Lachie Neale has been in the spotlight all summer after giving up the Brisbane co-captaincy amid his highly-publicised marriage breakdown but the Lions brass believe the premiership winner is physically in the midst of his best pre-season in some years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa8155609cd081098a4e996ae177fd39</guid></item><item><title>Djokovic, Alcaraz win epic five-setters to set up Australian Open final showdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/australian-open-day-13-live-blog-alcaraz-zverev-djokovic/106286224</link><description>Novak Djokovic will face Carlos Alcaraz in the Australian Open men's singles final after winning another epic semifinal against Jannik Sinner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c4b896e4b47fb27ee95df0a2b0dea4d</guid></item><item><title>Australia closely monitoring Nipah virus, no change to border control</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/nipah-virus-no-border-control-changes-australia/106286138</link><description>The federal government is closely monitoring an outbreak of Nipah virus in India but has not received any advice to tighten border controls at this stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b3834c00079c11cd5b5192636589a57</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley issues ultimatum to David Littleproud as she announces temporary shadow ministry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/sussan-ley-announces-acting-shadow-ministers/106287014</link><description>The under-fire Liberal leader has given seven existing frontbenchers carriage of the portfolios vacated by Nationals, with a threat to leader David Littleproud the arrangements could be made permanent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">495aa296e1f1293c4b1df88740ff1415</guid></item><item><title>Nine Radio sold for cut-price $56m to pub tycoon Arthur Laundy as it spends $850m on outdoor ad company QMS</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/nine-radio-sold-to-arthur-laundy-talk-radio-shrinking-audience/106286352</link><description>Arthur Laundy's Laundy Family Office acquires a network that includes Melbourne's top-rating talk station 3AW, Sydney's 2GB and outspoken conservative presenters such as Ben Fordham and Tom Elliott.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e00eed476a238801bf56a342da10e5b</guid></item><item><title>SA man arrested for allegedly lighting multiple fires during Riverland heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/multiple-riverland-south-australia-bushfires-heatwave/106286030</link><description>A 49-year-old South Australian man has been arrested for allegedly lighting multiple fires in the state's Riverland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77106a453774cdd4f20e9ea14092dd10</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump shares video of Alex Pretti confrontation with agents 11 days before shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/trump-shares-video-of-alex-pretti-confrontation/106286246</link><description>United States President Donald Trump has shared a video on Truth Social showing Alex Pretti in a confrontation with federal immigration agents 11 days before the intensive care nurse was fatally shot during a separate encounter with Border Patrol agents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5757815551c408c0f12cded050106ea</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide Hills man completes 23-year steam locomotive build</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/adelaide-hills-man-completes-23-year-steam-locomotive-build/106284306</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49c54e955468672d703d64312892b926</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Springsteen releases anti-ICE protest song Streets of Minneapolis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/bruce-springsteen-ice-trump-protest-song-streets-of-minneapolis/106286788</link><description>The Boss has blasted the Trump administration and ICE agents in a new song responding to "the state terror being visited" on Minneapolis and dedicated to Renee Good and Alex Pretti.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">900ff7596a77bbcf1626fbb586bcf484</guid></item><item><title>Government lands last-minute hospital funding deal with states</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/albanese-government-deal-hospital-funding-states-territories/106282208</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has bowed to mounting pressure from the states, promising an extra $25 billion for public hospitals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a19c82d245f496322cebe40598b78f9</guid></item><item><title>Machine capable of making millions of illegal cigarettes seized in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/sydney-illegal-cigarette-operation-uncovered-by-abf/106286376</link><description>A machine which can produce millions of black market cigarettes has been seized in a raid in north-west Sydney, as the fight against the illegal tobacco trade heats up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f81cd8fd0d0362ae79d65dfb6d3c2379</guid></item><item><title>Cannington greyhound racing 'carnage' prompts phase out calls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/calls-to-end-greyhound-racing-after-cannington-carnage/106287412</link><description>Four dogs were injured and two euthanased after a greyhound racing event in Cannington this week, escalating calls to end the sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7562d7b386c0d7e42127924c7b652841</guid></item><item><title>'Devastating tragedy': Perth family dead in suspected murder-suicide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/mosman-park-murder-suicide-four-people-dead/106287630</link><description>WA Police are investigating a suspected murder-suicide in suburban Perth after finding two teenage boys and two adults dead in a home in Mosman Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c0026c695591fc80f5c70c3d863255f</guid></item><item><title>Charges laid after allegedly stolen vehicle crashes into Geelong school bus, officer opens fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/charge-laid-allegedly-stolen-vehicle-crash-police-shooting/106286358</link><description>A 37-year-old man and a 43-year-old woman have been charged after a dramatic incident that saw police open fire at a vehicle that allegedly drove at officers after crashing into a bus on Thursday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc6465c8a964f47bc0d206bd1ed9d8c0</guid></item><item><title>Families frayed by NDIS cuts brace for more change ahead of defining 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/families-frayed-by-ndis-cuts-brace-for-more-change-in-2026/106269362</link><description>Families frayed by NDIS cuts are bracing for even more change ahead of a year that is set to reshape the scheme into something more sustainable, write Nas Campanella and Evan Young.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2050bfad4e5d8c7178bb64a2e3c25249</guid></item><item><title>Fugees, Weezer, Spiderbait's classic albums turn 30 in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/albums-1996-30-years-weezer-fugees-you-am-i-spiderbait/106126108</link><description>From Weezer's raw emotion to the Spice Girls's pop revolution, revisit 10 iconic albums that made 1996 a landmark year in music. Thirty years on, they still define the era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8077fe8e16e49d742fd093cbca15bb86</guid></item><item><title>Why your sunscreen application might be putting your good intentions to waste</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/how-often-should-you-be-reapplying-sunscreen-this-summer/106079324</link><description>This is what three experts had to say about how to get the best protection from your sunscreen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbf13c6aa015eb074cae6c36de35d329</guid></item><item><title>Canberra woman charged with murder after man found dead in her Braddon unit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/act-woman-charged-murder-braddon-unit-court/106286114</link><description>A 37-year-old woman from Canberra's inner north is charged with murder after the body of a 44-year-old man was found in her unit in December.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d77375ab44d27f619cd86da776c91ba</guid></item><item><title>FBI seizes Georgia ballots as Trump pursues 2020 election grievance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/fbi-seizure-fulton-county-election-ballots-explainer/106286198</link><description>Fulton County, which votes overwhelmingly Democratic, has been a target of President Donald Trump since he narrowly lost the 2020 presidential election in Georgia to Democrat Joe Biden.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9425b33668c5262e1537b345d487501b</guid></item><item><title>Man jailed for injecting girlfriend with meth 24 hours before she died</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/ethan-ross-jailed-for-giving-meth-to-girlfriend-amy-bowden/106286368</link><description>A man who injected his girlfriend with methamphetamine in the 24 hours before her sudden death has been jailed for just over nine months — but his sentence was backdated, meaning he will be eligible for release in May.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afc51ced00b73e89e597a72c663492e7</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand has refused to join Donald Trump's 'Board of Peace'. What about the rest of the world?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/nz-refuses-trump-invitation-board-of-peace-gaza/106286460</link><description>New Zealand has declined Donald Trump's invitation to join his Board of Peace and is calling for "clarity" over the proposal. Here's where other countries stand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3104f6ed696845404ac34be7ab22385e</guid></item><item><title>Hastie rules out challenge to Sussan Ley for Liberal Party leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/hastie-rules-out-challenge-to-sussan-ley/106287872</link><description>The West Australian backbencher had made no secret of his desire to lead the Liberal Party but says he will not run against Sussan Ley next week, a move which could pave the way for Angus Taylor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fbd66676329dfbdf22f30190cab58fe</guid></item><item><title>Man jailed over antisemitic graffiti spree in Sydney fails to have sentence overturned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/mohommed-farhat-to-stay-in-jail-antisemitic-graffiti-arson/106287870</link><description>Mohommed Farhat's lawyers were urging the court to overturn the sentence on appeal and replace it with an intensive correction order which could have seen him released.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04208019012c5ce98bcb3942c8df4375</guid></item><item><title>More than $370 million now allocated for Victorian bushfire recovery support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/bushfire-funding-albanese-allan/106288080</link><description>The state and federal governments will substantially increase financial support for 23 Victorian local government areas devastated by bushfires this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a10d4fbc334d4b4942a4f0a34da5abb</guid></item><item><title>Gold and silver prices collapse ahead of announcement of new US Federal Reserve chair</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/gold-silver-prices-drop-us-federal-reserve-chair-announcement/106289302</link><description>Gold and silver prices have plummeted, sparked by reports US President Donald Trump is set to announce a new US Federal Reserve chair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4830e74ecebdb3c2571478a59c1104f5</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government urged to use careful diplomacy to defuse Darwin Port row with China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/farmers-urge-careful-diplomacy-in-darwin-port-row-with-china/106288346</link><description>Industry groups that suffered three years of damaging Chinese trade tariffs on products including barley are appealing to the federal government to exercise careful diplomacy to defuse tensions with China over the ownership of Darwin Port.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d329f53011599b0e1e704d744857ffe</guid></item><item><title>Gambling billionaire Laurence Escalante charged with family violence, assault, burglary offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/gambling-billionaire-laurence-escalante-family-violence-offences/106289792</link><description>Australian online gambling billionaire Laurence Escalante has appeared in a Perth court, accused of a slew of family violence, drugs and burglary offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9941b5fba82788a9d1dc4080c16f077d</guid></item><item><title>Port Augusta and Andamooka hit 50C with temperatures set to drop across SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/temperature-change-sa-power-outages/106287992</link><description>For the first time in four years, Australia has recorded temperatures in excess of 50C, with both locations in South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">319b258c15fc183e677c12b61b703c46</guid></item><item><title>Friday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/fin-financefri-30012026/106289892</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b307ba853ee3a4166926148a931cfbee</guid></item><item><title>Jury finds New South Wales man Gregory Carr guilty of indecently touching two WA girls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/gregory-carr-guilty-broome-child-sexual-abuse/106282220</link><description>The 23-year-old man has been found guilty of indecently dealing with two girls in northern Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84b31de32f0d0ad8b56d0ddb263c3cc3</guid></item><item><title>Carlos Alcaraz downs Alexander Zverev in ultimate match of margins as Australian Open finally delivers epic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/tennis-alcaraz-zverev-australian-open-semifinal-analysis/106289980</link><description>The margins can prove to be razor-thin when it comes to the business end of grand slam tournaments. Carlos Alcaraz and Alexander Zverev found out firsthand in an all-time classic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eeb290aeba5fdb53b420ba13316b74a1</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026: Alexander Zverev takes issue with Carlos Alcaraz's injury timeout during semifinal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/zverev-avoids-alcaraz-medical-timeout-question-aus-open-semi/106290020</link><description>Alexander Zverev says he "didn't like" that Carlos Alcaraz was allowed a medical timeout for a cramp during their semifinal match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">099fe81349ab85d763be500e82f562d9</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump announces Kevin Warsh as next Fed chair, replacing Jerome Powell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/donald-trump-nominates-kevin-warsh-next-fed-chair/106290084</link><description>Mr Warsh will replace current chair Jerome Powell when his term expires in May.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf0ccf4dd26923772e9e5ead7926883c</guid></item><item><title>Former CNN anchor Don Lemon arrested on charges related to anti-ICE protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/cnn-anchor-don-lemon-taken-into-custody/106290312</link><description>The arrest comes after Don Lemon live-streamed a demonstration that interrupted a church service in St Paul, Minnesota, earlier this month while protesting against President Donald Trump's immigration crackdown in the area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">864b65510f876536adb92779c3d4373f</guid></item><item><title>Luigi Mangione will not face death penalty if convicted over UnitedHealthcare CEO's murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/luigi-mangione-murder-weapons-charges-dropped/106290600</link><description>A judge in Manhattan throws out federal murder and weapons charges against the 27-year-old, saying they are not legally compatible with the other charges of stalking he faces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b465d3204a8a28380b11a93181e3013</guid></item><item><title>More than 3 million new 'Epstein files' released by US government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/more-epstein-files-released-by-us-department-of-justice/106021136</link><description>The US Department of Justice says it is releasing more than 3 million new documents from the "Epstein files", but Democrats question why millions more are being withheld.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dcd9d89c56fd204a3d8b70a9f82e96b</guid></item><item><title>Taylor Liberals' leading man as leadership spill looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/andrew-hastie-sussan-ley-angus-taylor-leadership/106288160</link><description>One Liberal source told the ABC a challenge to Sussan Ley's leadership is now a "matter of when, not if".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cd579f61af4b0fac93337f6e0c59978</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's many foreign policy bluffs come at a political price</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/donald-trump-iran-nuclear-foreign-policy-greeland-tariffs/106288164</link><description>As the US president faces domestic consequences for his violent immigration crackdown, his geopolitical bluffs across the world also come at a price.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b214da89e9b1ae9893f26e3535f5d06</guid></item><item><title>US official insists DoJ 'did not protect' Trump as new Epstein files released — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/three-million-jeffrey-epstein-files-released-by-us-doj-live-blog/106290612</link><description>More than 2,000 videos and 180,000 images have been released as part of the batch, which comes weeks after a legally mandated deadline signed by Donald Trump. Look back on how the day unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d14f4cc849176fb3b40600749d5329e</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic hits out at critics after epic Australian Open win over Jannik Sinner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/australian-open-novak-djokovic-jannik-sinner-carlos-alcaraz/106289146</link><description>After beating two-time defending champion Jannik Sinner in five gruelling sets, Novak Djokovic sets his sights on those who doubted whether he could still be an Australian Open contender.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">597951c5e6457144797da6350dc35629</guid></item><item><title>Consumer advocate warns mobile phone and network failures will 'keep occurring' if regulator doesn't step up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/apple-iphone-telstra-connectivity-triple-zero-bushfire-emergency/106286194</link><description>A resident in a bushfire zone says they were left in a "blind panic" after their mobile phone couldn't connect, as an advocate warns of more system failures if major changes aren't made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de886b44c725e5a7b63eba00ced9f5d3</guid></item><item><title>Children living in makeshift tents in Gaza are dying from hypothermia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/children-in-gaza-are-dying-from-hypothermia/106282834</link><description>Mohammed died from hypothermia while in his mother's arms after a cold night in Gaza. His family are one of hundreds of thousands of Gazans enduring harsh winter conditions in flimsy tents across the enclave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0698cb5df9dc0d548e9155e7493036e8</guid></item><item><title>Mimili artists talk of Country, community, survival in remote APY Lands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/anangu-stories-of-country-community-survival-in-mimili-apy-lands/106202804</link><description>The artists of Mimili, in the APY Lands of South Australia, are using new methods to share crucial knowledge of Country and culture, including repurposed car parts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c5e67167d4609e2c95c63251d94e76a</guid></item><item><title>Australia's solar panel waste is mounting. Will the government's recycling scheme solve it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/australia-solar-panel-waste-federal-government-recycling-scheme/106284016</link><description>Australia is on the brink of a solar panel waste crisis. Experts say there's much to do before a national recycling program can stand on its own two feet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9676686494de807a5ff198f63021f08</guid></item><item><title>Keith, Barry Hall and a c-bomb: How Playlunch tore through the 2025 Hottest 100</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/playlunch-keith-hottest-100-triple-j/106283612</link><description>Keith, the incendiary single from Melbourne seven-piece Playlunch, has ripped through the hearts, minds and ears of fans around Australia and the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74c0ecebf6768331c156269f3b74dca1</guid></item><item><title>To understand Melania Trump's movie we might need to follow the money</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/melania-trump-movie-and-why-we-might-need-to-follow-the-money/106285248</link><description>Dire box office sales surrounding the US first lady's bio-doc have made headlines, but some argue there's likely a good reason Jeff Bezos's Amazon MGM Studios has splashed so much cash on MELANIA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dfd4c5f61c5577ffee9b4f0946b9751</guid></item><item><title>Catherine O'Hara from Home Alone and Schitt's Creek dies aged 71</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/catherine-o-hara-from-home-alone-and-schitts-creek-dies-aged-71/106290662</link><description>The Canadian-born actress died at her home in Los Angeles at the age of 71 "following a brief illness", according to a statement from her agency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cec17b0e9c8d5e5c57455b7b63492832</guid></item><item><title>Push for retailers to play role in 3D-printed gun crackdown after Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/3d-guns-retailers-and-the-bondi-aftermath/106286252</link><description>Hardware stores would report customers suspected of building 3D-printed guns to the authorities under fresh calls for corporate Australia to play a role in thwarting access to the deadly weapons</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c6ac0fc6d7819fd48f5e27a930359de</guid></item><item><title>Ensay's annual Mountain Calf Sale moved to Bairnsdale for animal welfare</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/ensay-mountain-calf-sale-moved-bairnsdale-due-to-animal-welfare/106286930</link><description>The tiny Victorian town of Ensay has proudly hosted the annual mountain calf sale for decades, but the yards will be empty this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0862129768c2c7973f043a1b434c3fe</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026: Cramping Carlos causes controversy, an AO ultra marathon and Aussies win mixed doubles — quick hits from Melbourne Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/australian-open-day-13-quick-hits-djokovic-alcaraz-sinner-zverev/106288180</link><description>Gadecki and Peers make their own bit of history and "old man" Djokovic turns back the clock to reach his 11th Aussie final. Here are the quick hits from day 13 at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79f0750c218c15fc2261700051401767</guid></item><item><title>Relief on the horizon for south-east Australia after record heatwave delivers 50C</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/record-heatwave-south-east-australia-but-change-on-the-horizon/106288238</link><description>For the eighth consecutive day Australia's south-east inland will bake in temperatures well above 40 degrees Celsius.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42d8514d382c2ab887520df200cf0002</guid></item><item><title>Man jailed for introducing amphetamines to 'vulnerable' teenagers in state care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/man-jailed-supplying-methamphetamine-to-teens-in-state-care/106283524</link><description>A man who introduced teenage sisters in state care to amphetamines was "well-aware" the drug was "dangerous, addictive and can destroy lives", a judge has said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd4d443499edea646616db7a4a5f81a7</guid></item><item><title>Families continue fight for railway crossing upgrades 25 years after horror Gerogery fatalities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/level-crossing-upgrades-25-years-on-from-gerogery-fatalities/106268960</link><description>Barry Wooden has spent decades trying to honour the lives of his son and four mates who died in a horror railway crossing crash 25 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab01cec4c23050c8817b61b868af0887</guid></item><item><title>Crochet octopus toys bring tactile comfort to premature babies at Western Sydney NICUs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/octopus-toys-for-premmie-babies-sydney-hospital-and-trauma-teddy/106087638</link><description>With materials, time and love, Bernice Joy Luxford has brought comfort to the sick infants and their emotionally and physically exhausted caregivers via over 700 octopus toys.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a0ad7f948807f27d784f15492d6c3f6</guid></item><item><title>Beckham saga is an age-old heartache with an uncomfortably modern twist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/virginia-trioli-template/106252054</link><description>Cutting ties with your parents isn't a new phenomenon but having it painstakingly documented across social media is a contemporary problem.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab0df9a75b077d3b19090787e9d7ff93</guid></item><item><title>Celine Cremer case shows role of private investigators in helping families find answers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/celine-cremer-private-investigator-search-helping-families/106287758</link><description>Facing extreme weather and limited resources, Tasmania Police had to stop its search for Celine Cremer. But with her disappearance unresolved, loved ones turned to a private investigator instead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c6d09b0b03547dfffbe8bad94c8f4f2</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the suspected murder-suicide of a Perth family of four</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/murder-suicide-for-perth-family-of-four-mosman-park/103234930</link><description>An entire family has been found dead in their own home — a mother, a father and their two teenage boys, with police describing the event as "highly distressing" and a "devastating tragedy".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9e0af84e0c05da7804ee93fb5894219</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka the Australian Open final favourite but Elena Rybakina pledges 'fight to the end'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/sabalenka-the-favourite-rybakina-pledges-to-fight-to-the-end/106290682</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka and Elena Rybakina are poised for a heavyweight bout in the Australian Open women's singles final, a rematch of a the classic 2023 decider.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">975be72412645bd675b9a08f69a9e5d6</guid></item><item><title>Much of Queensland set to sizzle ahead of cooler, wet change next week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/high-temperatures-forecast-for-qld-ahead-of-cool-change/106286996</link><description>The worst of the heat has moved into south-west Queensland, while temperatures in the south-east could still hit 40 degrees Celsius before a cooler change early next week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55d92e7026c523386155ab738bc5cc6f</guid></item><item><title>It was an audacious idea for a Liberals-Greens government, but did anyone stop to ask what Canberra voters would think?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/act-audacious-idea-of-liberals-greens-government-put-on-hold/106288268</link><description>The idea of a coalition between the ACT Greens and the Canberra Liberals appears to be on hold for now — but a quick history lesson is important to understand how both sides were willing to consider it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8d003aa84955f287891eff45b28627a</guid></item><item><title>ABC 50/50 quiz: This week we're testing your knowledge of Dirty Dancing, Scrabble and an unnerving horse statue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/abc-50-50-quiz-january-31/106281814</link><description>Every question has only two options: One is right and the other is wrong. You have an even chance of guessing correctly each time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc6e84a2638e7880bc65d2c6209c73f8</guid></item><item><title>The tide takes away his work each day, but learning to let go has transformed this artist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/sand-art-helps-surfer-connect-community-gold-coast/106214956</link><description>Mal Leckie has spent every morning over the past 50 years at the beach, but when illness hurt his ability to surf, he had to find a new reason to get out of bed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e0faa4b4547e6aea40cd6eb9ea1f00c</guid></item><item><title>Ballroom performance at the State Library Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/ballroom-performance-at-victoria-state-library/106278776</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1eb573c6f726cb1292c8af08bcc40b1a</guid></item><item><title>Ballroom community takes over State Library of Victoria for LGBTQIA+ Fantasy Ball</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/state-library-of-victoria-hosts-lgbtqia-fantasy-ball/106272364</link><description>From a fairy-themed beginners' performance to the revered "sex siren" category, participants vied for 10s on a night celebrating queer and trans people of colour at the State Library of Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc893da09642dd35b5bafeea17823dc1</guid></item><item><title>This easy zucchini, corn and feta dish packs a punch - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/baked-zucchini-with-charred-corn-and-whipped-feta/106282642</link><description>With tender roasted zucchini, salty feta, charred sweet corn and crunchy seeds, this dish will satisfy a veggie craving and is the perfect balance of taste and texture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fd66a774361e18d38014bd4f34248f8</guid></item><item><title>Millions of dollars projected for flood-affected north-west Queensland graziers to rebuild</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/millions-in-grazier-recovery-costs-after-queensland-flooding/106277762</link><description>Graziers are looking at a tough few years and millions of dollars to restock cattle herds as recovery begins in outback Queensland after widespread flooding hit the north-west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42c30ba80965acc0380ac0eaa26d3959</guid></item><item><title>Fruit tree netting installations to increase over next decade as heatwaves persist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/heatwaves-mean-netting-installations-for-fruit-crops-to-increase/106278420</link><description>Sales of netting to protect fruit crops from extreme weather have increased in the past five years as researchers warn heatwaves will continue to impact agriculture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">687d8d67030a8be834892249633a7b71</guid></item><item><title>Kakadu National Park's Jabiru Airport slated for demolition from October</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/kakadu-national-park-jabiru-airport-demolished-rio-tinto/106288904</link><description>Kakadu's main airport, which services a wide and remote corner of the Northern Territory, has been slated for demolition as the deadline for the nearby uranium mine's rehabilitation looms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28006235c13265760063d0975d7885c0</guid></item><item><title>Tweed's Dreamtime Beach is a drowning danger zone and an Instagram hot spot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/dreamtime-beach-a-social-media-dream-but-a-safety-nightmare/106280158</link><description>As influencers draw crowds to a notorious drowning danger zone, surf lifesavers and researchers are thinking about how unpatrolled beaches can be managed in the age of social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9868e5f67acc7990c53d034c240aaebc</guid></item><item><title>Kambalda's future unclear on 60th anniversary of nickel discovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/kambalda-discovery-led-to-australias-first-nickel-mine/106159740</link><description>This week marks 60 years since one of Australia's biggest mineral discoveries put Kambalda on the map. But now all the WA town's nickel mines have closed and the prospect of a future restart is unclear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a48d18e1f675cd44daf142bf9d8c42a4</guid></item><item><title>Bruny Island to get childcare solution but too late for the Archers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/bruny-island-to-get-childcare-solution/106290778</link><description>After fighting for years for a childcare solution for her community, Teisha Archer says the news it will be happening is "wonderful" — but will come too late to help her and others in her situation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29b0eedaed503b8b897f5fcf5c6433ba</guid></item><item><title>Farmers reeling as estimated $20 million in livestock perish in Victorian fires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/victoria-fires-20-million-dollars-in-livestock-losses/106286870</link><description>The fires wiped out swathes of farmland and killed tens of thousands of livestock.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f4f9c7afa70e9016b09cfa15b85d082</guid></item><item><title>As anger boiled over the Invasion Day rally bomb threat, some politicians were uncharacteristically silent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/opposition-holds-back-on-perth-invasion-day-attack/106289970</link><description>As more details about the explosive device in Perth's Invasion Day rally emerged, opposition leader Basil Zempilas has only given limited responses on the issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">954cb8a87e9a780de8623178d87a9798</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man extradited from Cooktown over alleged involvement in bulgaries, home invasion and vehicle theft</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/act-man-extradited-over-burglaries-home-invasion-car-thefts/106290824</link><description>The Taylor man is alleged to have been involved in the incidents in early December, which included a home invasion in Conder in which a 72-year-old woman was tied up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7facfc82dfa1987fabcac1ffdc6501b9</guid></item><item><title>Prime minister and SA premier announce $800 million deal for 17,000 new homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/prime-minister-and-sa-premier-announce-800m-housing-deal/106290888</link><description>Funding for water infrastructure, urban renewal projects and first-home buyer schemes has been announced in a partnership between the Commonwealth and the state government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f79ccb35961ad839a0f5eeea304cfbeb</guid></item><item><title>Journalist Don Lemon charged with federal civil rights crimes over anti-ICE church protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/journalist-don-lemon-is-charged-with-federal-civil-rights-crimes/106290910</link><description>Former CNN news anchor Don Lemon enters a not guilty plea and is released from custody after being arrested during an anti-ICE protest he says he was covering as an independent journalist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9930505d4a6f8af7be82ef6df10510b6</guid></item><item><title>Darwin Lord Mayor Peter Styles says NT Electoral Commission lost his election donations disclosure information</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/nt-darwin-lord-mayor-peter-styles-ntec-lost-donations-return/106289926</link><description>Darwin's Lord Mayor, Peter Styles, says the Northern Territory Electoral Commission lost an envelope containing his campaign donations disclosure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca8f7ab8f3d62b5b023928d665cd97c3</guid></item><item><title>Albany surf school finds a way to ignite NDIS participants' passion for sport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/albany-surf-school-finds-a-way-to-ignite-ndis-passion-for-sport/106267650</link><description>A unique surf school on Australia's southern coast merges an NDIS life skills program and a surf coaching program to have a blast in the waves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">954987630352ded678432b51518a43a7</guid></item><item><title>Charity founder Yas Daniel Matbouly charged over alleged sexual assault, rape</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/qld-police-charge-gold-coast-charity-founder-yas-daniel-matbouly/106287188</link><description>The 50-year-old founder of the Serving Our People charity, headquartered on the Gold Coast, has been charged with more than 50 offences following investigations into multiple allegations of sexual assault.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f8ca087a6732ef462d52911ae32c23e</guid></item><item><title>First Nations people say 'silence' on alleged Perth bomb attack weighs heavily</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/perth-bomb-attack-analysis-first-nations-people/106289032</link><description>Underwhelming public responses in the wake of the alleged attack on an Invasion Day rally in Perth leave First Nations people across Australia feeling their "pain matters less".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26210817d2dec571fe2f10b0a8a13636</guid></item><item><title>Woman found outside Woodlands house with life-threatening injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/woman-critical-after-woodlands-assault/106291092</link><description>A 44-year-old woman is rushed to hospital with life-threatening injuries after allegedly being assaulted at a home in suburban Perth overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b701a1983ebb4946f7cc5acd315121b</guid></item><item><title>Why Asian countries are joining Trump's Board of Peace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/asian-powers-join-trump-board-of-peace/106277784</link><description>Analysts say Asian countries such as Indonesia and Vietnam have signalled support for US President Donald Trump's new Board of Peace, not because they expect changes in Gaza, but to gain access to US trade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54bcd99c95f91eae912c5147f3036cd4</guid></item><item><title>Tyra Banks's 'hot ice cream' went viral. Don't expect to see it called that anymore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/hot-ice-cream-tyra-banks-sydney-food/106283144</link><description>Reviews have said it "tasted like soggy biscuits" and was "a weird sensation to sip through a straw". Taste aside, something bugged me. How can you call something ice cream if it's not iced?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3f517f5dea71c2574d23fd042540f1e</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump signs executive order for Indycar Washington street race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/trump-announces-indycar-race-washington-past-white-house/106291114</link><description>The capital of the United States will get an IndyCar street race as part of the nation's 250th anniversary of independence celebrations, and President Donald Trump is pushing hard for the race route to pass the White House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51f21e80e337ee6224ce679ec1298209</guid></item><item><title>Mosman Park murder-suicide described as 'heartbreaking' by WA premier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/mosman-park-murder-suicide-update/106291350</link><description>WA Premier Roger Cook says the deaths of a family of four at their Perth home in an apparent murder-suicide is both "heartbreaking" and "unimaginable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4812bbd856390ab2fac934a1f31c8951</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle surfer Josh Levey catches 7,000 waves in one month for charity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/surfer-catches-7000-waves-in-month/106255708</link><description>Newcastle surfer Josh Levey goes to extraordinary lengths to raise money for a local homeless charity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed809b676a7658339db71a332d7a6c86</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar election won by military-backed party in widely condemned poll marred by violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/myanmar-election-won-by-military-backed-usdp-party/106290376</link><description>The military's political party wins the vote in a result regarded as a forgone conclusion, with critics arguing threats and violence forced people to the ballot box in a country wracked by civil war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4d99c203ab0a5661b5ba91b73c4e306</guid></item><item><title>Why is my migraine worse in summer?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/why-is-my-migraine-worse-in-summer/106281460</link><description>For people with migraine, summer can be a double-edged sword. You may be able to relax but glare, heat, and changes to sleeping and diet can make attacks more likely or more severe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d8c4e5b1b9584c8c07b53821e59f20c</guid></item><item><title>Cricket NSW announces coach Greg Shipperd sacked from state, Sydney Sixers roles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/legendary-coach-axed-by-sydney-sixers-cricket-nsw/106291418</link><description>Legendary cricket coach Greg Shipperd is sacked from his dual state and BBL roles in a major shake-up at Cricket NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d533075b7de708058edc0e511918889</guid></item><item><title>Niels Vink wins Australian Open quad wheelchair singles title</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/australian-open-niels-vink-wins-quad-wheelchair-final/106291488</link><description>Paying tribute to his long-time mentor, Niels Vink claims the Australian Open quad wheelchair singles title for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00cfa0cc97460dccc1d5380dd8357d39</guid></item><item><title>Former PM Kevin Rudd says he declined Epstein invitation after latest document dump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/kevin-rudd-refred-to-in-latest-epstein-files-dump/106290858</link><description>The newly released Epstein documents show the New York sex offender sought a wide-ranging network of political and financial contacts, including former Australian prime minister Kevin Rudd.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab133de8921b728263a8f5e7ac34dbc4</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of posing as talent agent to lure young actors into sex acts granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/sydney-man-allegedly-posed-as-talent-agent-to-lure-actors/106290734</link><description>The 57-year-old told a Sydney court he posed as a Disney executive because he was "lonely" but only ever shouted people coffee or dinners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da67a7f8f3533ef02db0099d4ef523ba</guid></item><item><title>Rybakina takes down Sabalenka in stunning Australian Open final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/australian-open-womens-singles-final-live-sabalenka-rybakina/106291584</link><description>Elena Rybakina wins the Australian Open with a stunning three-set victory over world number one Aryna Sabalenka, who loses in the final for the second straight year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d06b709129739c4503a437369e16fa0a</guid></item><item><title>England cricketer Harry Brook says he lied about New Zealand nightclub incident to protect teammates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/brook-says-he-lied-to-protect-england-teammates-in-nz-incident/106291544</link><description>England's ODI and T20 captain Harry Brook issues a statement admitting he lied over the nightclub incident on his side's tour of New Zealand last year, saying other teammates were present when he was hit by a bouncer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64ae042267d6a7bbb7770372074c7055</guid></item><item><title>Venezuela announces amnesty bill that could lead to mass release of political prisoners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/political-prisoners-venezuela/106291540</link><description>The government did not release the text of the bill on Friday, leaving it unclear who will qualify for release.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74a46326579e9090f1375ef006068c95</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins ruled out of T20 World Cup as Steve Smith snubbed despite strong form</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/cummins-and-smith-out-of-t20-world-cup/106291628</link><description>Pat Cummins will miss the T20 World Cup after failing to recover from his back injury, while Steve Smith, fresh from a blistering BBL cameo, isn't named in Australia's final 15-man squad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e543265a51a8eca00555db2df533a2bb</guid></item><item><title>Elena Rybakina's Australian Open final win over Aryna Sabalenka proves she's no one-hit wonder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/rybakina-no-one-hit-wonder-australian-open-triumph/106291474</link><description>A consistent and composed Elena Rybakina claims her maiden Australian Open title by beating world number one Aryna Sabalenka in a thriller three years after her breakout Wimbledon win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c1517e375519258beec806f2d5275af</guid></item><item><title>Israeli strikes in Gaza kill at least 27 Palestinians in one of deadliest days since ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/israel-strikes-gaza-highest-death-tolls-since-ceasefire/106291744</link><description>Israeli strikes have killed at least 27 Palestinians, marking one of the highest death tolls since the ceasefire last October aimed at stopping the fighting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae771290eb599854c2a54335d0e9921c</guid></item></channel></rss>