<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 07:45:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Demonstrators begin march across Melbourne's CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/demonstrators-begin-march-across-melbournes-cbd/105770140</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a63374f36b6233fa96d7a21ec56f5966</guid></item><item><title>Aerial video shows protesters marching in Melbourne's CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/aerial-video-shows-protesters-marching-in-melbourne-s-cbd/105770182</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f49c6905e1a1d7f18d86e6e2e9cf8e89</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fall to 28-26 defeat against Argentina in The Rugby Championship in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/live-updates-wallabies-vs-argentina-the-rugby-championship/105753320</link><description>The Wallabies have fallen just short of a magical comeback against Argentina, losing 28-26 in a thrilling Rugby Championship Test in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac9963693b81c061d5a7137f7874121c</guid></item><item><title>Erika Kirk makes first public statement after assassination of husband Charlie Kirk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/erika-kirk-pays-tribute-to-late-husband-charlie-kirk/105770008</link><description>Charlie Kirk's widow, Erika, delivers her first public remarks since the fatal shooting of her influencer husband.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a3e797f573f130d4cdaa37fc918652a</guid></item><item><title>Advocates call for action on brain health as AIHW reveals dementia is leading cause of death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/australians-dying-from-dementia-more-than-any-other-cause/105768682</link><description>Advocates warn the number of people with the condition could exceed 1 million without government intervention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b35bf8bb29f6390428b007c4fc10877</guid></item><item><title>Penrith Panthers, Cronulla Sharks win NRL elimination finals against Warriors, Sydney Roosters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/nrl-finals-live-warriors-panthers-sharks-roosters/105770330</link><description>The Sharks are looking to correct the mistakes of the past, as they advance to the semifinals with a 20-10 victory over the Roosters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8453f95a136416a45ec4efe167c5d81f</guid></item><item><title>Supreme Court gives Queensland hospital permission to terminate 12yo girl's pregnancy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/qld-hospital-gets-court-permission-for-abortion-on-12yo-girl/105770196</link><description>A 12-year-old girl in residential care in Queensland should be allowed to have an abortion, a court rules, after a judge found she was not capable of making the decision herself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86cd5589ba9855a3f68a146a74e238ad</guid></item><item><title>NRLW wrap: Brisbane Broncos thrash the Cowboys 50-4, Gold Coast grab last finals spot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/upton-hat-trick-leads-broncos-to-big-nrlw-win-over-cowboys/105770416</link><description>It's a big day for Queensland sides in the NRLW, as the Broncos — led by skipper Tamika Upton — are far too good for the third-placed Cowboys, while the Titans clinch the last finals spot with a win over Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0af6a0f9bdb8ae75a28c6c7e963ce856</guid></item><item><title>WA Health issues measles warning as two more cases linked to Bali travel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/two-more-measles-cases-in-wa-linked-to-bali-travel/105770492</link><description>West Australians planning to visit South-East Asia are being urged to get vaccinated against measles, with two more cases linked with travel to Bali.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1897bbaf4493022b86af465fcc949ac6</guid></item><item><title>Labor win Kiama by-election as voters replace disgraced MP Gareth Ward</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/kiama-byelection-polls-close-votes-counting/105770414</link><description>The NSW Premier said Kiama now has the ear of the government after it claimed victory in the by-election triggered by the resignation of convicted rapist Gareth Ward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f8148eb8e329e6cf74190c6118a0a8f</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane far too good for Gold Coast in QClash semifinal, setting up Collingwood prelim date</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/afl-finals-brisbane-lions-gold-coast-suns-live-blog/105768034</link><description>Bouncing back from a resounding loss to Geelong, the Brisbane Lions comfortably dispense of the Gold Coast Suns to advance to the preliminary finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35fd90e486aa2532889961cd9ae474b8</guid></item><item><title>Air strikes kill at least 32 in Gaza City as Israel ramps up its offensive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/israeli-strikes-kill-at-least-32-across-gaza-city/105770758</link><description>Israel in recent days has intensified strikes across Gaza City, destroying multiple high-rise buildings and accusing Hamas of putting surveillance equipment in them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a19cccd4d36d16c4736f44ec0be6998</guid></item><item><title>From Formula One to creating the 'world's best' croissant, how baking saved Lune founder Kate Reid's life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/cars-to-croissants-kate-reid-and-the-lune-empire/105750472</link><description>Kate Reid's Lune croissants have been called the world's best. But how did a young woman struggling with a near-fatal eating disorder end up perfecting pastry?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d09b350f758690100795053d1425df1</guid></item><item><title>Children missing out on early intervention for language delays due to shortage of speech pathologists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/australias-speech-pathology-therapy-language-delay/105658306</link><description>One in four children starting school now has a speech or language delay. It can hold back their learning, affect their friendships and harm their mental health. Speech therapists are struggling to find ways to support them all, but one school is leading the way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fd8643f474de3cb897a95d95769fb75</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's health chief, RFK Jr, is dividing Republicans on vaccines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/trump-health-chief-rfk-jr-divides-republicans-on-vaccines/105763060</link><description>US Health Secretary Robert F Kennedy Jr's anti-vaccination agenda is gaining ground, but resistance is coming from all sides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">550382bc4a2dad860c2ebd332ba5da22</guid></item><item><title>Trump hits out at Florida's 'tough stance' on vaccines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/trump-hits-out-at-floridas-tough-stance-on-vaccines/105767070</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">411cbb4e0109999f07a638bac1bb9e45</guid></item><item><title>Understanding the literal bin fires in Europe's 'magical mystery summer' of inaction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/drone-attack-on-poland-shows-europe-is-not-equiped-for-war/105769208</link><description>Moscow's drone incursion into Polish airspace this week may have just laid bare how fruitless Europe's summer of talkfests has been.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ad36c5f8aa76037acc9c47d200ab7bb</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Think you're contestant material? Prove it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/105746846</link><description>It's time to show me your exceptional trivia knowledge. Ha!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03f61e05a2d928ef5dd5a855914f188a</guid></item><item><title>'Bone lady' who helped find Daniel Morcombe still unearthing stories of the dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/life-of-qld-police-forensic-anthropologist-donna-macgregor/105757258</link><description>From the search for Daniel Morcombe to a flaming roadside torso, Queensland's top forensics cop deals with some of the state's worst crimes — when she's not identifying fallen Australians on WWI battlefields.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">756451363a24944c71314b39d4ee9da4</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal artist Emily Kam Kngwarray becomes first Australian with solo exhibition at London's Tate Modern</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/emily-kam-kngwarray-nt-artist-solo-exhibition-tate-modern/105748722</link><description>Emily Kam Kngwarray has been recognised as "one of the world's leading artists" after becoming the first Australian whose work is the subject of a solo exhibition at the Tate Modern Gallery in London.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80742075f005deb3851d847eafa37b21</guid></item><item><title>Wallaroos' Rugby World Cup hopes dashed by dominant Canada in 46-5 loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/rugby-world-cup-wallaroos-canada-quarterfinal/105771382</link><description>The Wallaroos miss the chance to reach the Rugby World Cup semifinals, losing heavily 46-5 to Canada in Bristol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eeea51af32489f3175d1f115a728a37</guid></item><item><title>The Pacific won a stunning climate victory at the International Court of Justice. What's next?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/whats-next-after-pacific-icj-climate-victory/105747794</link><description>Pacific Island nations are weighing up how to use a historic international court ruling in their fight to bring about stronger emissions reductions and climate justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4d5352fd2872714b73915e90a078b57</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk's accused killer Tyler Robinson awaits formal charges in Utah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/tyler-robinson-awaits-formal-charges-over-charlie-kirk-murder/105771364</link><description>Tyler Robinson, jailed on suspicion of fatally shooting right-wing activist Charlie Kirk, faces formal charges in Utah early next week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">388d30366d16f1bf3aebb0058cc923e8</guid></item><item><title>World-famous bee sanctuary on Kangaroo Island under threat from Varroa mite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/world-famous-bee-sanctuary-under-threat-from-parasite/105766650</link><description>Beekeepers on Kangaroo Island are demanding that biosecurity measures be boosted to prevent a deadly parasite from wiping out the island's world-famous bee sanctuary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dc81d0494e04695ce39dafec86cab57</guid></item><item><title>'White-hot anger' in the bush as Victorians fight government on multiple fronts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/why-regional-victorians-are-angry-at-state-government/105761034</link><description>Rural residents and local councils are deeply unhappy with new taxes, renewable energy, bad roads and mining companies, accusing the state government of "city centric" policymaking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">975ae86896e7894f15dfe756b7e0f4f9</guid></item><item><title>Carlton AFLW side has reached a 'turning point' after challenging years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/with-a-few-added-pieces-carlton-have-flown-up-the-ladder-aflw/105770732</link><description>Inaugural Carlton player Gab Pound says the club has reached a turning point after not making the finals since the 2020 COVID-interrupted season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4746581d3adeb6ddbdb1c2e40b060a32</guid></item><item><title>Brick-pit frog recovery another win for green and gold at Sydney Olympics site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/green-and-golden-bell-frogs-thrive-at-sydney-olympics-site/105762124</link><description>Twenty-five years after the Sydney Olympics, an important Homebush planning decision has led to successful conservation efforts for a species born in the green and gold. But a deadly fungus poses a threat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7163e13b015cd649bd1282f9f989c65e</guid></item><item><title>'Where to now?' Liberals soul searching after heavy loss in Kiama by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/nsw-kiama-by-election-analysis/105768772</link><description>For a party that had just suffered a heavy defeat, the mood at the Liberals' post-election event was surprisingly upbeat on Saturday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0324f2b1e17e0afe58c8b2fdb2342585</guid></item><item><title>Wombat makes home in Robe's main street as numbers increase despite habitat loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/wombats-take-over-robe-south-australia/105763680</link><description>A wombat has made its home in the main street of Robe, evidence of an influx of the animals in the South Australian fishing town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd75f8c80d7887020cad44750ebb3000</guid></item><item><title>Wombats in Robe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/wombats-in-robe/105762994</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b3220b0971b015745735ee5063bf7e0</guid></item><item><title>The Franklin River rescue was extreme. Here's how medics prepare for the wilderness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/expedition-medicine-frontline-wilderness-rescue-tasmania/105647214</link><description>The Franklin River rescue was an extreme test for the skills of medics. In remote Tasmania, here's how they train for "chaos".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ad6b3276dc3d97f9e83daaf4447dd1e</guid></item><item><title>Police clash with anti-immigration protesters in London</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/police-clash-with-anti-immigration-protesters-in-london/105771538</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f624fc78fd6ee39a07fa2a3279d4573b</guid></item><item><title>Outback nurse transforms remote diabetes care with cans, rocks and bush tucker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/collarenebri-hosts-pilot-diabetes-and-holistic-health-program/105600544</link><description>When Rishoniy Caine arrived in a remote NSW community with one general store and no gym, she knew fixing its diabetes problem would need a different approach to what had already failed the locals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">222ba35951a8a4a1e2c0a8f063f85b5b</guid></item><item><title>The federal press gallery is ceding power to the Albanese government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/australias-press-gallery-problem-with-political-coverage/105762464</link><description>The federal press gallery is ceding power to the Albanese government. It needs to take it back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ab87f4785a2cdb321543f771c1d84de</guid></item><item><title>How to watch the 2025 Primetime Emmys in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/how-to-watch-the-emmys-2025-primetime-awards-los-angeles/105751936</link><description>Your pocket guide to watching the Emmy awards in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec791c67cc32865ea8679b33207acf56</guid></item><item><title>Victorian farmers welcome spring forecast despite long-term climate concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/farming-faces-global-warming-challenges-bom-csiro-forecasts/105698854</link><description>As spring brings a flicker of hope, some farmers cautiously embrace optimism while others face mounting pressures and climate uncertainty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eefc8f08701a2e9f48f36a96143be8ca</guid></item><item><title>Residents in flood-affected communities want more warning technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/flood-hit-residents-call-for-more-automated-river-gauges/105724942</link><description>For generations, farmers and outback communities have relied on the bush telegraph during floods but it has fallen silent in recent years, leaving residents without up-to-date information.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c31e8ba3a792f16088d132fc493aa4e1</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump threatens new sanctions on Russia if NATO suspends all oil purchases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/donald-trump-demands-nato-stop-all-russia-oil-imports/105771434</link><description>US President Donald Trump says he is ready to impose sanctions on Russia, but only if NATO members agree to do the same, as well as set massive tariffs on Russia's main ally, China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d06ea199ed9911761efa00cca6ba9712</guid></item><item><title>All Blacks forced to re-group after 43-10 loss to Springboks in Rugby Championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/all-blacks-regroup-after-springboks-defeat/105771568</link><description>After a demoralising 43-10 loss to the Springboks on home soil, the All Blacks are looking to rebound against the Wallabies in the upcoming Bledisloe Cup Tests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14cb19776ed7e08739a74354c2afa92e</guid></item><item><title>Creamed honey nostalgia helps producers find niche market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/meilbee-honey-producers-adapt-to-new-normal-with-varroa-mite/105666254</link><description>Some New South Wales beekeepers are determined to stay the course in the face of varroa mite, turning to childhood memories for inspiration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b04ab4401117d12b619bbf4390eaafa6</guid></item><item><title>Sharp drop in Gouldian finch sightings sparks worry in WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/gouldian-finch-sightings-drop-northern-wa/105763736</link><description>Numbers of the brightly coloured Gouldian finch appear to be dropping in Western Australia's East Kimberley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6772c4e9c00b75c099803dcbbf782b7</guid></item><item><title>Victoria set to have first new national parks in more than a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/victoria-set-to-have-three-new-national-parks/105762596</link><description>Conservation groups are celebrating proposed legislation for three new national parks in Victoria but not all bush users are happy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d36bb38c879de78daf8fd739801d0718</guid></item><item><title>Albanese announces new AUKUS facility in WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/albanese-announces-new-aukus-facility-in-wa/105771780</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">351395ae5e354677773f0fc914b78d26</guid></item><item><title>Platypuses found dead in illegal fishing traps in regional Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/two-platypuses-found-dead-in-illegal-fishing-traps-in-gippsland/105770064</link><description>Anglers are urged to dispose of illegal fishing nets and stick with safer open-top traps, after two platypuses are found drowned in regional Victorian waterways.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa94e78e7c284c127ba7cfde9ae4e257</guid></item><item><title>'World's biggest' hockey game in York fundraises for cancer research</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/eliza-reynolds-hockey-game-cancer-fundraiser/105763156</link><description>More than 370 people participate in a hockey game lasting more than eight hours in honour of a little girl who died from a rare form of cancer earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6940b0964bbe2ae1724b08b2a97f81f</guid></item><item><title>Police condemn 'brazen' Sydney shooting after three people escape injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/merrylands-sydney-shooting-three-people-avoid-injury/105771760</link><description>Police believe the target of a shooting in Merrylands on Sunday no longer lives at the home but allegedly has links to a splintering Sydney crime family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ba3b4dbdeada147ebf8528b70c3ee87</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley reshuffles frontbench in wake of Jacinta Nampijinpa Price saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/coalition-frontbench-reshuffle-melissa-price-claire-chandler/105771468</link><description>West Australian MP Melissa Price will replace Jacinta Nampijinpa Price as the shadow minister for defence industry and personnel, after the outspoken senator was sacked for refusing to back her leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5afabc2037eaede8864df8e5a67e0e3f</guid></item><item><title>How to give your indoor plants a spring clean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/how-to-spring-clean-indoor-plants/105754044</link><description>As gardens, parks and nature strips start showing signs of spring, our indoor plants might need a little help to jump into the new season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7041345f64a52b3d64fb6ac2ef82f3b</guid></item><item><title>In the midst of destruction in Gaza, these parents found 'paradise' through adoption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/palestinian-couple-adopts-baby-who-survived-israeli-strike/105691626</link><description>A newborn baby was left in a Gaza hospital, the sole survivor of a deadly Israeli strike which killed her family. A couple who had struggled to have children of their own knew they had to provide her with a home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d91dd396d69c59c3b40cbd1f35b154a2</guid></item><item><title>Lachie Neale gives himself '50 per cent' chance of improbable grand final appearance after calf injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/afl-brisbane-lions-lachie-neale-50-per-cent-chance-gf/105771982</link><description>Lachie Neale admits medical professionals are not holding out much hope of him recovering from a calf injury in time for the grand final, but he is not giving up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a19957fc35f1ad280cdb57d03a33c7d3</guid></item><item><title>Ben Hunt's Golden Point field goal sends Brisbane Broncos into NRL prelims after downing Canberra Raiders in all-time classic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/nrl-live-updates-finals-canberra-raiders-brisbane-broncos/105767630</link><description>Jamal Fogarty scores a try in Golden Point to send the Raiders to a preliminary final only for it to be disallowed before Ben Hunt delivers a dagger field goal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6df4f99fbc4ba21354c9bf49bf40731</guid></item><item><title>FBI director Kash Patel to face congressional hearing amid missteps on Charlie Kirk assassination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/kash-patel-faces-congressional-hearing/105771606</link><description>Kash Patel faces a clear test of whether he can convince the country that the FBI, under his watch, can avoid compounding its mistakes in a time of political violence and deepening distrust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff3edf3e8615beb76880722256515f03</guid></item><item><title>One woman, eight men charged with child abuse offences following NSW raids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/nine-people-charged-nsw-child-abuse-offences-homes-raided/105772116</link><description>Eight men and one woman have been charged across with more than 30 online child abuse offences during a two-week child protection blitz.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4bb1db6e528250a9ee913e555d290fc</guid></item><item><title>AFLW Round 5 Sunday wrap: Kangaroos claim grand final rematch against Lions as Saints and Cats record big wins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/aflw-round-5-sunday-wrap-kangaroos-beat-lions-gf-rematch/105771940</link><description>North Melbourne continues its blistering start to the AFLW season as Geelong and St Kilda also record big wins in Round 5.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cee53d3f18feb5d3f6fa788a7a48b761</guid></item><item><title>Belgians break Australian hearts in Davis Cup classic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/tennis-de-minaur-australia-belgium-davis-cup-wrap/105772264</link><description>Beligum's Raphael Collignon wore down late stand-in Aleksandar Vukic in the deciding rubber to lead Belgium to the quarter-finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48108db3db36157632582610dcc8f4ed</guid></item><item><title>Reece Walsh grabs the Sun to lead Brisbane to an all-time victory over Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/canberra-raiders-brisbane-broncos-nrl-finals-reece-walsh/105767838</link><description>Brisbane and Canberra went to the great beyond in their golden point finals match and it was Reece Walsh who led the Broncos to the promised land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">863df8dd52133df36ae1790ea450fe7c</guid></item><item><title>Liberal Party immigration fight is a battle over how the party wants to position itself</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/liberals-mass-immigration-debate-protests/105771786</link><description>Immigration has become a new fault line inside the Liberal Party that will erupt again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a99f0ce667959a16433080650b5d2dc</guid></item><item><title>The year Australia is due to blow its carbon budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/australia-carbon-budget-2035-emissions-target/105341080</link><description>Unless Australia lifts its ambitions, its "fair share" of carbon emissions will be spent 14 years early. With the government announcing a 2035 climate target this week, there is intense debate on how high the government should aim — and whether it will be enough to help limit global warming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92c26486065559e6e68fc907f4300c31</guid></item><item><title>The higher Australia's 2035 emissions target, the more necessary a carbon tax will be</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/albanese-government-2035-climate-emissions-target/105771566</link><description>Australia's emissions reduction number is, in short, a laugh-or-cry-o-meter, or perhaps more accurately, a tax-o-meter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5aae41b286ff6b7c3400069e180e67f</guid></item><item><title>GIM Trading accused of defrauding millions from ordinary Australian investors with 'low risk' bonds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/gim-trading-alleged-fraud-investors-bonds/105747410</link><description>A Gold Coast musician approached by a man he knew from a local bar went on to front a trading company, later accused of defrauding millions from ordinary Australian investors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef7a680d03253010b78fa5b88e06a4f0</guid></item><item><title>Dads leaving sex education to mums, report finds, with concerns young boys are missing out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/dads-leaving-sex-education-to-mums-boys-missing-out/105761172</link><description>New report finds mothers do more of the sex education at home, raising concerns that young boys are missing out on key information from their dads.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09373ae607cb293f5028b7499dce7b5a</guid></item><item><title>Family violence survivors waiting years for social housing as demand surges in Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/social-public-housing-wait-times-victoria-family-violence/105655044</link><description>As family violence survivor and mother-of-two, Maya was assessed as a high priority for social housing. Eight years later, she's finally moved into a suitable home in outer-suburban Melbourne, with vulnerable Victorians left waiting for years as the social housing waitlist soars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e74302190404e5284428c6e45ccbce8a</guid></item><item><title>Weather to warm up in Queensland, as more rain forecast for the north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/warmer-weather-tipped-for-much-of-queensland-as-spring-sets-in/105771650</link><description>The southern half of Queensland can expect fine weather at least for the first half of the week, while more rain is on the way for the north of the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44a26254dc8a8890086a64f319e0fce8</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic expeditioners join research project to help astronauts on space missions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/antarctic-expeditioners-join-astronaut-research-project/105767136</link><description>Expeditioners at Australia's Antarctic stations are taking part in a research project to better understand the cognitive and physiological impacts of extended deployments — which can include actual "brain shrinkage".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d57ace742d2dab72c8470091d9eea61</guid></item><item><title>SA government error in your favour — collect $1 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/sa-government-erroneously-hands-1-million-to-small-business/105767306</link><description>Political parties usually get in trouble for breaking their election promises. But what happens when they keep a promise that never actually existed?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea597ae377c0e7662d5bf4f001c30c70</guid></item><item><title>Bankruptcy law reform push after paedophile protects assets in superannuation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/paedophiles-using-bankruptcy-loophole-to-avoid-payouts/105765918</link><description>Edan van Haren, a victim of child predator Maurice Van Ryn, says legal loopholes are allowing the confessed paedophile to protect his assets in superannuation to avoid paying compensation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">598df1c8747bfb8132eaed82ca93974e</guid></item><item><title>Residents say former Moe Hospital could become public housing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/moe-hospital-newborough-derelict-building-social-housing/105637366</link><description>A retired nurse who worked at Moe Hospital says the closed facility could be used for housing rather than left to further rot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d6259927cc7b3ea15a9fcb2704c8b7c</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk shooting suspect not cooperating with authorities, Utah governor says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/charlie-kirk-shooting-suspect-not-cooperating-with-authorities/105772848</link><description>Investigators are working to piece together why Tyler Robinson allegedly scaled a rooftop at Utah Valley University during an outdoor event and shot Mr Kirk in the neck at long range.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84a96eb58021324ea7568c8d91e90253</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr scores 100th goal for Chelsea in long-awaited WSL return from knee injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/sam-kerr-makes-wsl-chelsea-return-from-torn-acl/105772878</link><description>Matildas star Sam Kerr scores her 100th goal for Chelsea just minutes after returning to the pitch for the Blues for her first game since 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bae5f25a567be7986ec4489f569f5f25</guid></item><item><title>Road repairs after flood delayed by 'excruciating' eligibility criteria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/buloke-shire-flood-funding-pot-holes-delays-unsafe-roads/105733714</link><description>Victorian councils say they are required to provide before-and-after photos of every 100 metres of road in order to be eligible for flood recovery funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d6870a6663a3b8139b0e567866cd586</guid></item><item><title>Nepalese migrants in Australia turning to parents to help with childcare and culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/canberra-nepalese-community-family-tradition-and-culture/105772020</link><description>For many Nepalese families living in Canberra, the arrival of parents from overseas is both a helping hand with raising children and a connection to their homeland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83d7bb8c245d2e5d11433eda0c9b3fd1</guid></item><item><title>Documents reveal unauthorised sediment releases at Blackwater Coal Mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/blackwater-coal-mine-contamination-sediment/105769922</link><description>A report obtained by lobby group Lock The Gate under right-to-information laws reveal a mine in central Queensland was releasing sediment into environmentally sensitive areas for more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c0e5d78e0e78c7d0e25c51e02aed43f</guid></item><item><title>Fortunes change quickly in AFLW as round of upsets shakes up ladder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/round-of-upsets-shakes-up-aflw-ladder-mid-season/105772256</link><description>After a tough start to the year, Geelong sit just outside the top eight and equal on points with the reining grand finalists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a314ed873d6767758eb39088f9f9e0f6</guid></item><item><title>Traditional custodian readies for 'challenge' over North West Shelf gas project extension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/traditional-custodian-fights-north-west-shelf-approval/105770306</link><description>Environment Minister Murray Watt approved the extension of Australia's biggest gas project last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fff78b1c904abb60057a8fd295536c56</guid></item><item><title>Specialist GPs to diagnose ADHD in WA amid calls for further easing of restrictions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/wa-gps-soon-start-diagnosing-adhd/105759814</link><description>As a select cohort of WA GPs begins to diagnose ADHD in people older than 10, parents of younger children and some medical professionals have expressed concerns about the scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32f743c6d37c23f14438dac29a9eb199</guid></item><item><title>Reece Walsh fined for headbutt, Pat Carrigan banned for high shot in NRL finals win over Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/reece-walsh-headbutt-pat-carrigan-bans-from-broncos-raiders/105772942</link><description>Superstar Broncos fullback Reece Walsh will be free to play in the NRL preliminary finals after avoiding suspension for a headbutt on Hudson Young in Brisbane's epic win on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69bc0f4f4df315eed7d8c781e1acb538</guid></item><item><title>Emmys 2025 red carpet: Jenna Ortega, Lisa, Sydney Sweeney, Aimee Lou Wood, Walton Goggins, Selena Gomez and Pedro Pascal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/2025-emmys-red-carpet-fashion/105752046</link><description>The stars of the television industry are bringing the drama with their fashion choices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85981e3d6d9c2977cda8244d6580248c</guid></item><item><title>WA's expanded container deposit scheme to cost wineries, distilleries millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/container-for-change-wa-wine-expansion-hits-small-business/105763914</link><description>Producers in Western Australia's premier wine region say the state government's expanded bottle recycling scheme is set to cost them millions of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16ff8a6ec9140b73f0af3e85a003dec0</guid></item><item><title>Australia beats India in first of three ODIs before Women's Cricket World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/australia-beats-india-in-odi-world-cup-warm-up/105773182</link><description>Australia's Cricket World Cup preparations are in full swing as three batters score half-centuries in a big run chase in the first of three ODIs against India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a29f09f0be7bd9b554de11bd5f4906d1</guid></item><item><title>Emmy Awards 2025: The Pitt, Adolescence and The Studio win big as Owen Cooper makes history — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/emmy-awards-2025-live-blog-latest-updates/105757172</link><description>The Pitt wins Best Drama at the 77th Annual Primetime Emmy Awards, with The Studio, Adolescence and even Stephen Colbert walking away as the biggest winners of the night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f0dab0d1494400d0b01fc6483c43b32</guid></item><item><title>Port Hinchinbrook marina remains inaccessible despite dredging project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/port-hinchinbrook-marina-remains-inaccessible-after-dredging/105739106</link><description>Mud and silt continue to choke the channel connecting the controversial development to the Great Barrier Reef, once again putting industry and conservationists at odds over the fix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00377919955e2acc697f9565f436b2a9</guid></item><item><title>Outback ringmaster Fred Brophy takes his boxing tent to Birdsville for last time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/fred-brophy-takes-boxing-tent-to-birdsville-for-last-time/105761756</link><description>Fred Brophy will sell you a ticket, spin you a yarn and dare you into the ring, but at 73, the outback ringmaster is slowing down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9c596e0ff31abe53e3cdc3f15b54fcc</guid></item><item><title>First climate risk assessment finds 1.5m Australians at risk from sea level rise by 2050</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/climate-risk-assessment-sea-level-rise-2035-target/105765456</link><description>One and a half million Australians are at risk from sea levels rising by 2050 unless climate change can be limited, Australia’s first national climate risk assessment warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84bc65afd0d8a3b350ab90314dff5f21</guid></item><item><title>Nepal's Gen Z demands reform as country begins new political path</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/nepal-generation-z-anti-corruption-protests-kathmandu/105773042</link><description>Protesters in Nepal say their Gen Z-led movement was not just about removing one leader, but about reforming the system to ensure accountability and protect Nepal’s future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">836ee3f4801e6cf8e546d51627e6e4b8</guid></item><item><title>From Tantanoola to Essendon, Angus Clarke reflects on AFL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/angus-clarke-on-south-east-sa-breakfast/105773582</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32b5ad4ec4dbc2210f1b5997bfa6ec36</guid></item><item><title>Australian rules football and SANFL administrator Max Basheer dies aged 98</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/sanfl-administrator-max-basheer-dies-aged-98/105773500</link><description>Max Basheer — the football administrator who oversaw the creation of the Adelaide Crows and the purpose-built stadium Football Park — has died aged 98.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">594325c3e747906c91d2cd8c90983d6f</guid></item><item><title>AFL State of Origin will return, with Western Australia-Victoria clash confirmed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/afl-announces-state-of-origin-return-with-wa-vic-clash-confirmed/105773392</link><description>AFL chief executive Andrew Dillon confirms Western Australia will play Victoria in Perth next February in the first State of Origin match since 1999.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d22aa23c3e429a537fcaf8a6093051d</guid></item><item><title>Prince Harry says he has no regrets about 2023 memoir Spare</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/prince-harry-defends-his-memoir/105773344</link><description>Prince Harry has defended his tell-all autobiography Spare, insisting he has no regrets about its publication.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">822f9b8bfc9e038c4a05c240f351b362</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with giving Nazi salute at Brisbane Lions v Gold Coast Suns AFL game at the Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/qld-man-charged-nazi-salute-at-afl-game-banned/105773522</link><description>A 39-year-old man has been charged with giving a Nazi salute at the AFL semifinal in Brisbane on Saturday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10247763ed0af9c91511f307aea12cd7</guid></item><item><title>Inquest to probe police action before Kelly Wilkinson killed by husband</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/coronial-inquest-into-death-of-gold-coast-mother-kelly-wilkinson/105767910</link><description>The actions of Queensland police will be put under the microscope at an inquest into the death of Gold Coast mother Kelly Wilkinson, who was killed by her estranged husband.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">717d0c00c1a3ba02425db620f8ba0fdd</guid></item><item><title>Indian cricketers refuse to shake hands with Pakistani counterparts at Asia Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/indian-cricketers-refuse-to-shake-hands-with-pakistanis-asia-cup/105773820</link><description>Indian captain Suryakumar Yadav refuses to shake hands after his side's seven-wicket win over Pakistan at the Asia Cup in the latest controversial episode between the two rivals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e14fcc55b27a2d660ff4a5b3250b9de6</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Roosters confirm ACL injury for Tarryn Aiken on eve of NRLW finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/sydney-roosters-confirm-tarryn-aiken-acl-injury-nrlw/105773930</link><description>Tarryn Aiken will miss the Sydney Roosters' NRLW finals campaign, with scans confirming a knee injury that will require a knee reconstruction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">880a495525ca619936ce2de16f4379d3</guid></item><item><title>Alphonce Felix Simbu wins marathon gold at World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/athletics-simbu-wins-marathon-world-championship-in-photo-finish/105773524</link><description>After running for more than two hours, the winner of the men's marathon at the World Athletics Championships was decided by less than a second.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31ac3c362b03dfada2a8044af1523882</guid></item><item><title>Police charge man with assisting suicide while investigating 20 other deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/three-people-charged-over-alleged-assisted-suicide-on-gold-coast/105773946</link><description>Police allege the death of a man on the Gold Coast earlier this year was an assisted suicide and are investigating the deaths of other people as far back as 2021.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f268d99b5f6b08e8bd88d36f26aadbc5</guid></item><item><title>Inquest hears prison system failed Aboriginal inmate before he died</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/inquest-examines-clinton-austin-death-loddon-prison/105735924</link><description>A coronial inquest hears the system failed First Nations prisoner Clinton Austin before his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3728f892b4b408407004793ea3dc66f</guid></item><item><title>Emmys 2025 winners: Adolescence, Severance, The Pitt and The Studio win big</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/primetime-emmy-awards-ceremony-winners-list/105752034</link><description>The 77th Primetime Emmy Awards are honouring the best and brightest in the US television industry. Here are the shows that picked up the trophies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d8d75f9c20e7825a51aab42eb0d2ca3</guid></item><item><title>Man jailed until at least 2028 for importing and producing a child-like sex doll</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/geoffrey-mew-sentence-sex-offences/105774224</link><description>The actions of a man who imported a child-like sex doll to his family home have been labelled "morally and legally repugnant" by a District Court judge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f6206491dd3bc63887246620afb01d0</guid></item><item><title>NFL week two: Dallas Cowboys win thriller, Steelers botch kick-off, Travis Kelce drops</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/nfl-week-two-quick-hits-dallas-cowboys-colts-dance/105774608</link><description>The second Sunday of NFL football for the season did not disappoint, with rivals producing a classic and a rematch of the Super Bowl.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49955e25536bb305d54d6c7ce1b181d1</guid></item><item><title>Arhab Haque sprayed fart gas at restaurants for TikTok clout, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/arhab-haque-sentenced-over-fart-gas-prank-gone-wrong/105774764</link><description>An amateur mixed martial arts fighter sprayed fart gas in a fast food restaurant so he could make TikTok prank videos, a Perth court hears.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b3e5750b5b7883a158b5adc9cf27be0</guid></item><item><title>Teenager charged as police search continues after Moree motel stabbing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/police-search-for-more-suspects-after-moree-hotel-stabbing/105773180</link><description>A 13-year-old boy has been been granted bail as police search for four others suspected of being involved in the stabbing of a 52-year-old man in Moree.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1025adafd9e7210de8f9878ff0d879d3</guid></item><item><title>Starving wallabies at The Briars spark urgent Mornington Peninsula Shire council meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/the-briars-mornington-peninsula-wallaby-overpopulation-council/105773468</link><description>A study prompted by the deaths of wallabies at a beloved wildlife reserve south of Melbourne finds the population has grown five times larger than what The Briars sanctuary can sustain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">424a62aaec22ec8d6b644d8c878fed7b</guid></item><item><title>SA to roll out ChatGPT-style AI app in all high schools as tech experts urge caution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/education-chat-gpt-style-ai-app-to-roll-out-to-sa-high-schools/105772944</link><description>A ChatGPT-style app to be rolled out at all South Australian high schools next term has been welcomed by tech experts, who are also warning its use should be carefully managed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd8111de02cfad378cd6bbaeb5b75896</guid></item><item><title>2025 Emmys key moments: From Hacks star Hannah Einbinder's acceptance speech to chants for Stephen Colbert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/emmys-2025-key-moments-from-hannah-einbinder-to-stephen-colbert/105773412</link><description>From a rallying political cry from Hacks star Hannah Einbinder to standing ovations for Stephen Colbert, here are your Emmys 2025 key moments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5949a0290fa0abaf999a6b633f1291cd</guid></item><item><title>Police identify pair who allegedly stole car at gunpoint at Morayfield</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/police-identify-pair-who-allegedly-stole-car-at-gunpoint/105773736</link><description>Police are searching for a man and a woman who allegedly stole a car at gunpoint from a Bruce Highway service station and crashed it on the Sunshine Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4a6802c695294b44d3d2fbe03ecf3eb</guid></item><item><title>How much fish is in tinned tuna, and how to shop for your needs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/packaged-foods-content-supermarkets/105707244</link><description>When you're at the supermarket, do you wonder how much much tuna you're getting in a can? A series of popular social media has been comparing how much food there is in some packaged items.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c07e1af76a9ce085f39b2e2924bc18d</guid></item><item><title>How is Australia affected by climate change? The National Climate Risk Assessment models the future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/national-climate-risk-assessment-and-why-it-matters-explained/105773936</link><description>For the first time, the government has modelled the threats from climate change on Australia's future. What's the point of a document like this, and can it help us avoid the worst-case scenarios?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ad84229da5de3e8a79b28e4eacc8cab</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of pigs feared dead in fire at Dublin's Andgar piggery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/fire-dublin-andgar-piggery-animal-cruelty-sa/105775484</link><description>It has taken all day for a fire at a controversial piggery north of Adelaide to be put out. RSPCA inspectors are attending the piggery, which was already under investigation over cruelty claims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa9cf9f12e59456af1cd840c58c97688</guid></item><item><title>Cricket Tasmania seeking ways to make proposed Macquarie Point stadium 'compatible' for matches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/cricket-tasmania-support-macquarie-point-afl-stadium/105774588</link><description>After initial concerns that the roof design of the proposed Hobart AFL stadium at Macquarie Point would hinder cricket matches, sporting authorities have thrown their support behind the build, saying "we will find a way".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52fc9b1b49c5b01644f528cf1efb60b0</guid></item><item><title>Australia's richest person among hundreds of donors to NT senator's legal fund</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/gina-rinehart-jacinta-nampijinpa-price-defamation-legal-fund/105775036</link><description>Australia's richest person, Gina Rinehart, has helped fund Senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price's crowd-funded defence to a defamation action brought by the head of a Northern Territory land council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d91909126ee3a35177e1e241ad2e0c3</guid></item><item><title>Defence dilemma facing Anthony Albanese as he heads to New York</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/the-defence-dilemma-facing-albanese-as-he-heads-to-new-york/105775954</link><description>Amid uncertainty over whether the prime minister will secure his first one-on-one meeting with Donald Trump, the political test is whether his recent defence commitments will be seen as a genuine step-up on capability or a sidestep from American calls to spend more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30bac552ea1477bb6ea09d9f427e1a77</guid></item><item><title>Support announced for businesses affected by Dezi Freeman search</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/support-package-for-porepunkah-businesses-dezi-freeman-search/105775570</link><description>Funding has been welcomed by Porepunkah businesses that were struggling after visitors were urged to stay away.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb03e8c7796ce1fb16265ed75fd408b1</guid></item><item><title>Inmate tells inquest guards referred to Indigenous man who died in custody with derogatory slurs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/guards-referred-to-tj-denniss-with-derogatory-slurs-inquest-told/105775100</link><description>An inmate, who cannot be named, provided details of an Indigenous man's treatment in custody, as an inquest into the man's death continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48ae914a843526cfeb88ffed2cbfb41d</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle Knights announce Justin Holbrook as new NRL head coach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/-newcastle-knights-justin-holbrook-nrl-head-coach/105776208</link><description>Sydney Roosters assistant coach Justin Holbrook has been named the new head coach of the Newcastle Knights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1dd4d58f20f4f23adda8178a9bef8c9</guid></item><item><title>Shadow minister Andrew Hastie says he will be 'without a job' if Liberals don't abandon net zero</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/andrew-hastie-flags-resignation-or-sacking-over-liberal-net-zero/105776432</link><description>Liberal frontbencher Andrew Hastie indicates he will quit or be dumped from the shadow cabinet if the Coalition does not abandon the target of achieving net zero greenhouse gas emissions by 2050.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d65a81fca15feb36d2a53c3d3bdd85a3</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump vows national emergency in Washington DC after ICE dispute with Democrat mayor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/trump-vows-national-emergency-in-washington-dc/105776222</link><description>The US president's threat comes after Washington DC Mayor Muriel Bowser said the district's police would not cooperate with Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29a70dad39dbb57f35f5b6c01aafca9b</guid></item><item><title>Whispering Jack: The John Farnham Musical to premiere in Sydney Theatre Company's 2026 season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/whispering-jack-john-farnham-musical-sydney-theatre-company-2026/105766868</link><description>Whispering Jack: The John Farnham Musical is one of 13 plays coming to Sydney Theatre Company next year, alongside shows starring David Wenham and Miranda Otto.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ade2dd75f87979058d05fced4a9318</guid></item><item><title>NRL announces preliminary finals dates, Melbourne Storm on Friday, Brisbane Broncos play Sunday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/nrl-preliminary-finals-dates-melbourne-brisbane/105776416</link><description>The NRL has shaken up its preliminary finals weekend, electing to host one of its grand final qualifiers on a Sunday for the first time in 18 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29c35159922bc6cf9a11532627c3c244</guid></item><item><title>Armand Mondo Duplantis breaks world record, Kurtis Marschall wins pole vault bronze at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-2025-in-tokyo-day-3/105774960</link><description>Kurtis Marschall wins bronze in the men's pole vault final on day three of the World Athletics Championships in Tokyo, as Armand Duplantis soars to a 14th world record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a75c97c2c4e50d1aabaf437d14731d7d</guid></item><item><title>All the latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/all-the-latest-financial-news/105776480</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f073c7f7020949078deb2eb0c7a85c</guid></item><item><title>Final rules for social media ban revealed, with no legally enforceable effectiveness standard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/social-media-ban-final-rules-announced/105776730</link><description>While substantial fines would apply to social media platforms that make no effort to ban under-16s, they would not need to test the age of every user.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bf25735e4356b3846b028a3101595a6</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste students protest government plan to buy new cars for parliamentarians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/timor-leste-protesters-demand-repeal-of-plan-to-buy-cars-for-mps/105776898</link><description>About 1,000 students hit the streets of the capital to rally against the plan, before police clashed with some protesters who reportedly threw rocks and damaged properties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ce414e161409b0fcdd72ce826062fbc</guid></item><item><title>Israel's Benjamin Netanyahu won't rule out striking Hamas 'wherever they are' as Marco Rubio visits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/benjamin-netanyahu-talks-hamas-as-marco-rubio-visits-israel/105776816</link><description>The remarks were made as US Secretary of State Marco Rubio visited Israel seeking answers from Mr Netanyahu about how Israel intended to proceed in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c254873aa4a240907d518a5f986b7f76</guid></item><item><title>US and China agree to TikTok 'framework' ownership agreement at trade talks in Spain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/us-and-china-agree-to-framework-for-tiktok-sale/105776964</link><description>US Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent says the framework would see the platform switch to US ownership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5792446bfea9843c09b316ffd472ee8e</guid></item><item><title>Poland arrests two Belarusians after drone flown over president's residence in Warsaw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/poland-arrests-belarusians-over-drone-flying-in-warsaw/105776824</link><description>Polish authorities neutralise a drone flying above government buildings in Warsaw on Monday night, as the country remains on high alert following recent Russian drone incursions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16f13039b7a56a80aca2829fad88bf9d</guid></item><item><title>Former MMA fighter Conor McGregor drops out of Irish presidential race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/conor-mcgregor-drops-out-of-irish-presidential-race-/105776960</link><description>Critics say the former MMA fighter's pre-emptive dropout was to save face in a likely knockout at the hands of Dublin City Council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60f1b0734e35fba4e5506343df9a6d2a</guid></item><item><title>Australia-PNG defence treaty will require countries to 'act' if either one is attacked</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/australia-and-png-defence-treaty-could-oblige-military-action/105776214</link><description>Australia and Papua New Guinea will be legally obliged to defend each other from a military attack on either territory under a landmark defence treaty, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a01cbea51a11c9d04e1bcff45aa8aa5</guid></item><item><title>DNA at crime scene matches Charlie Kirk murder suspect, FBI says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/charlie-kirk-crime-scene-dna-matches-murder-suspect/105777360</link><description>Tyler Robinson, 22, was arrested last week over the death of conservative influencer Charlie Kirk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7cf3e37a6ee22b7ae5bb477725734fa</guid></item><item><title>Lawyers urge Australians to ensure valid will in place as house prices rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/lawyers-urge-australians-to-ensure-valid-will-in-place/105767604</link><description>Lawyers urge Australians to ensure they leave behind a valid will to avoid legal disputes as surging house prices and superannuation balances increase the size of inheritances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a89e25f073724834a4daf823bb8d4cd</guid></item><item><title>Fewer Aussies would need NDIS if government boosted mental health support, expert says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/psychosocial-disability-mental-health-ndis/105773308</link><description>As the Albanese government seeks to rein in the cost of the NDIS, a former Australian of the Year says money could be saved with this one shift.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5bca27cbb4ae9aab43ea5684315161e</guid></item><item><title>In the UK's summer of immigration unrest, this small town chased its migrants away</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/ballymena-northern-ireland-banished-migrants-roma/105767632</link><description>Months before anti-immigrant unrest broke out on the streets of London, it erupted in this small UK town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bff30481ed5b241846692c959af2ad81</guid></item><item><title>Climate Risk Assessment's 'high risk' warning for 1 million Australian homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/climate-risk-assessment-million-homes-insurance-gdp-costs/105774418</link><description>One in 10 homes could be effectively uninsurable by 2050, while lost labour productivity to extreme weather could wipe $211 billion in household wealth, the Climate Risk Assessment warns, with tourism, trade, and property values forecasted to take a dive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">801dfb5f2bac8394e795c9893975dce2</guid></item><item><title>ANZ commits bank errors in its favour. Is there any other kind?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/anz-slammed-for-bank-errors-in-its-favour/105775702</link><description>ASIC has lived by that aphorism in its decision to strike a settlement deal with ANZ over a raft of wrongdoing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eab85143099e30eb989aba207539b011</guid></item><item><title>These Plymouth Brethren members stepped out of line, then the threats and intimidation started</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/exclusive-brethren-plymouth-former-members-threats-four-corners/105766026</link><description>The Plymouth Brethren Christian Church is fiercely protective of a multi-billion-dollar business which supports the church. These men found out the extraordinary lengths it will take to keep it safe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f185e31ae155fb6ec535b8575cf57c39</guid></item><item><title>Use constitutional power to raise age of criminal responsibility nationwide, lawyers tell PM</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/pm-letter-raise-the-age/105748868</link><description>Forty years ago, the federal government used the constitution to halt construction of the Franklin Dam. Now lawyers want the Albanese government to do the same to keep kids out of jails.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7b875978506038b9b93d5a66cdfdece</guid></item><item><title>How Melbourne mosquitoes are being used to fight dengue fever and save lives in Laos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/melbourne-mosquitoes-fight-dengue-fever-laos-save-the-children/105773926</link><description>They are the deadliest animals in the world, and millions of them are being sent from Australia to the Laos capital Vientiane in a bid to save lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a24e6c7c32402fe5603b887c428f2552</guid></item><item><title>Pathological Demand Avoidance, a little-known profile of autism affecting kids and adults</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/pathological-demand-avoidance-awareness-of-autism-subtype/105772066</link><description>A surge of professional and personal interest in Pathological Demand Avoidance (PDA), an autism subtype — which in children can affect everything from cleaning teeth to attending school — has led to Australia's first-ever PDA conference, to be held in Perth in November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21dc9dcc25ab99ec13266f4d172f1692</guid></item><item><title>What to expect from Donald Trump's state visit to the UK</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/what-to-expect-donald-trump-uk-state-visit-king-charles/105776968</link><description>The US president will arrive in London on Tuesday evening, local time, for an unprecedented second state visit to the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19d933d53256fb1c8c6c8419ba9dba94</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull believes in world championship 1,500m glory against serial winner Faith Kipyegon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/jess-hull-believes-in-world-championship-1500m-victory/105772376</link><description>Australia's Jess Hull has self-belief, despite facing an uphill task to beat three-time world and Olympic champion Faith Kipyegon over 1,500m at the World Athletics Championships in Tokyo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">101bafefa4e4f1f51f1ac514223465df</guid></item><item><title>WWII-era bombs are killing and injuring thousands in PNG. Now trainees will learn how to remove them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/png-world-war-2-unexploded-ordnance-removal/105774308</link><description>Trainees in Papua New Guinea will learn to remove unexploded ordnance, as fading memories of World War II expose more people to the conflict's dangerous legacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8bf240cd5378047327fc404a9e7f897</guid></item><item><title>Building industry wants more skilled migrants to address housing crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/queensland-building-industry-lobbies-more-skilled-migrants/105774824</link><description>It comes in the wake of anti-immigration rallies held around the country where some blamed "mass migration" for families not being able to afford a home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74f5a976815d824b4a753eec30251425</guid></item><item><title>Victorian childcare worker denies abusing toddlers, says he is appealing ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/victorian-childcare-worker-denies-abuse-appeals-ban/105702584</link><description>A Goodstart worker who allegedly abused toddlers at a Ballarat centre speaks out for the first time and says he is appealing after being banned from working with children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77e6b47d221359d2363dbff039a62a30</guid></item><item><title>Western Sydney is set to dramatically heat up, this is how communities are preparing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/western-sydney-plans-to-address-climate-change-warming/105775030</link><description>A "shocking" warning that heatwave deaths could skyrocket brings the issue of urban heat back into sharp focus, particularly in the city's west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8587e0ed7880e781adeb84da2b9f99da</guid></item><item><title>Will it happen? Crunch time imminent for Tasmania's proposed Macquarie Point stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/macquarie-point-stadium-planning-decision/105759040</link><description>It's not the be all and end all — but the impending delivery of the Tasmanian Planning Commission's final report is a major moment for the Macquarie Point stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b39f129ad1988ebe3b71971d4e7bb065</guid></item><item><title>Residents encouraged to attract native bees amid varroa mite spread</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/backyard-owners-encouraged-to-attract-native-bees-gardening/105767140</link><description>A pollination ecologist says it is important people play their part in preserving native bees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2de85a81cf81cdc683c925dfd059c30</guid></item><item><title>US strikes another suspected Venezuelan drug vessel at sea, killing three men</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/us-strikes-venezuelan-vessel-at-sea/105777504</link><description>United States President Donald Trump says the American military carried out a strike on a Venezuelan drug cartel vessel that had been on its way to the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c162ac70f715827468acaca152e97175</guid></item><item><title>Lisa Cook and Stephen Miran set for US Federal Reserve meeting, ASX gains — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/asx-markets-business-live-news-september-16-2025/105776832</link><description>The ASX gained ground on Tuesday, while markets now have greater certainty about the make-up of the US Federal Reserve board for this week's key rates meeting. Look back on the day's events and insights on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1b63a55aee1200f8bf11f3ef182b626</guid></item><item><title>Tia-Clair Toomey-Orr's eighth CrossFit Games title confirms her GOAT status</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/tia-clair-toomey-on-motherhood-and-becoming-the-crossfit-goat/105774312</link><description>Tia-Clair Toomey-Orr has been considered the CrossFit GOAT for some time, and she is not slowing down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b1bf3278129b6f1f5eae0776b29f16f</guid></item><item><title>Jacinta Nampijinpa Price and Kerrynne Liddle a 'unity ticket' on Indigenous affairs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/kerrynne-liddle-backs-jacinta-nampijinpa-price/105776102</link><description>Kerrynne Liddle speaks for the first time since Jacinta Nampijinpa Price was dumped from the frontbench, saying the pair are "on a unity ticket" when it comes to Indigenous affairs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">baf6de4a9c0796b996abab3ba46e1810</guid></item><item><title>Fears parts of Queensland will have to 'retreat' amid predicted sea level rise and increased severe weather events</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/climate-report-national-climate-risk-assessment-queensland/105775976</link><description>The warning comes amid a national report finding up to 185,000 residential buildings in Queensland could be in "very high-risk areas" if climate change is not addressed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c13eb12a1db1234d6f66dae28d2620c</guid></item><item><title>Spanish prime minister calls for Israel to be banned from sport after La Vuelta a España finale called off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/vuelta-a-espana-final-stage-cancelled-pro-palestinian-protests/105777508</link><description>Pro-Palestinian protests sparked by the inclusion of an Israeli team in La Vuelta a España prompt the cancellation of the last stage of the race, with Spain's prime minister calling for Israel to be treated like Russia by sporting organisations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac0ef3fdcf72c0008f752df151d4c3f8</guid></item><item><title>The hidden impact of injuries costing AFL clubs millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/the-hidden-costs-of-injuries-costing-afl-clubs-millions/105777624</link><description>New research highlights the financial impact of injuries in the AFL, with one club losing $13 millions over six seasons, nearly 17 per cent of its total player salaries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1df9a60d5e14380c28dd088a5cbf203a</guid></item><item><title>Rex Airlines apologises after wheelchair-using passenger stranded for six hours at Perth Airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/rex-passenger-issues-albany-perth-wheelchair-user-/105774708</link><description>Albany woman Debby Butler says she had to ask strangers to help her to the bathroom after Rex delayed her flight home from Perth Airport and left her without a wheelchair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbfe858ddf70fc0694fbe80e02bdc22a</guid></item><item><title>Trump announces crackdown on crime in Memphis and potentially Chicago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/trump-announces-crackdown-on-crime-in-memphis-and/105777884</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0ba18c5a8036c7a65716b099a960d11</guid></item><item><title>Future of Bendigo Writers Festival unclear amid calls for transparent review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/bendigo-writers-festival-future-unclear-after-boycott/105773484</link><description>A councillor is demanding answers from his own executive over the botched Bendigo Writers Festival, asking colleagues whether they want to be remembered as the council that "killed" it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a2675a41175e051c99bd70c72ebf69a</guid></item><item><title>Opponents react to Trump's crackdown on crime in Memphis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/opponents-react-to-trumps-crackdown-on-crime-in-memphis/105778000</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afb3ae0109a5af6fae1efda3a3fd4422</guid></item><item><title>Nikki Webster sings with her children for 25th anniversary of Sydney Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/nikki-webster-sings-with-her-children-for-25th/105778014</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c83bf0274f16a9fa314e120145c3d8f</guid></item><item><title>Cathy Freeman and Ian Thorpe among Stadium Australia's first hall of fame inductees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/cathy-freeman-ian-thorpe-stadium-australia-hall-of-fame/105777908</link><description>The first golden group of inductees were honoured at an event that threw back to the Sydney 2000 games with Nikki Webster reproducing her iconic opening ceremony performance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdef62442b745f1023ee6848ed55f9e3</guid></item><item><title>Shire of Coolgardie awaits decision on future after giving evidence to minister</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/shire-of-coolgardie-show-cause-notice-response/105774072</link><description>The embattled Shire of Coolgardie waits to hear whether it will be suspended ahead of local government elections over concerns about financial and managerial mismanagement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a60af1587b72855d0965e133f66c3a65</guid></item><item><title>Vantara wildlife facility cleared of wrongdoing by court-ordered probe in India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/vantara-wildlife-facility-cleared-of-wrongdoing-by-indian-probe/105777330</link><description>Conservationists had raised concerns about Vantara but investigators say the issues raised are "devoid of merit".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ae8a80b362270975ef42f54dcbd8c5</guid></item><item><title>Lisa Reihana's exhibition, Voyager, recasts history through an Indigenous lens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/lisa-reihana-ngununggula-exhibition-voyager-indigenous-maori/105760474</link><description>The internationally renowned Maori artist's technically complex, visually mesmerising exhibition spans nearly a decade of artwork.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ed46a76298102094bcf604b8536fb9b</guid></item><item><title>How to determine if your kid is well enough for child care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/the-advice-around-sending-a-sick-kid-to-child-care/105734762</link><description>Work demands and a lack of village mean keeping a child at home from care every time they have a sniffle can be a dilemma for many parents. So when it it OK to send them?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3431c0d66326982196374e9a6c348b5f</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese celebrates 50th anniversary of PNG independence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/anthony-albanese-celebrates-50th-anniversary-of/105778136</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">175953adaef8312193079caaa0c78740</guid></item><item><title>Family comes first for Queensland newsreader Rob Brough after months off-air</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/newsreader-rob-broughs-family-battle/105775464</link><description>The long-time nightly newsreader says it was an "instant choice" to leave work as his daughter faced a battle with cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23d10f83e00ccce3717d0f0a569d4a1c</guid></item><item><title>Why are young people protesting in Indonesia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/why-are-young-people-protesting-in-indonesia/105778564</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">938bf4850cb8dd03b1d7ea4be7b245c2</guid></item><item><title>One dead, seven hospitalised after gas leak at Sydney restaurant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/nsw-sydney-riverstone-gas-leak-restaurant/105778610</link><description>One person has died and several others, including police officers, are receiving medical treatment after a gas leak at a restaurant in north-west Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76b6419455a92ca2c50b00a13fd21c01</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump to send National Guard into Memphis to combat crime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/donald-trump-to-send-national-guard-to-memphis-to-combat-crime/105777774</link><description>Donald Trump signs a memorandum to send the National Guard into Memphis to combat crime, setting up another major test of his presidential power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c86283160022e1f0e8600e6a1f66f14</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Olympics inflatable art reappears after 25 years in rural NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/sydney-olympics-reg-mombassa-inflatable-art-reappears-in-nsw/105735020</link><description>A Coonabarabran artist made a lucky find at an online auction two years ago when she recognised a Reg Mombassa art piece from the Sydney Olympics mixed in with advertising devices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f4eacf145efc7f64bf56ffdaca13099</guid></item><item><title>Which Centrelink payments will be increasing (slightly) over the weekend?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/centrelink-pension-carer-payment-disability-support/105777756</link><description>Certain Centrelink payments will be increasing with inflation from Saturday. Check to see if you're affected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e79f140d0b4167604ec1dbdef40cb82</guid></item><item><title>As the Trump administration blows up suspicious boats, legal experts raise red flags</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/trump-administration-lethal-force-drug-cartels-international-law/105778434</link><description>Donald Trump is using the US military to bomb boats suspected of carrying drugs in international waters. But little is known about who is being killed, and military and legal experts are raising several red flags.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f45edea7a8f89a760d2113ff13065ce7</guid></item><item><title>Former Bankstown nurse who appeared in video with Israeli content creator has one charge dropped</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/bankstown-nurse-in-video-israeli-content-creator-charge-dropped/105778390</link><description>Sarah Abu Lebdeh appeared in a video chat with an Israeli content creator that allegedly included threats to Israeli patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ac6ca3277f66dd115c844ff1b073096</guid></item><item><title>Trump confirms US military carried out strike on drug boat from Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/trump-confirms-us-military-carried-out-strike/105777688</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac78de1cdb120bc010d65f78e27d2742</guid></item><item><title>Victoria to push for national machete ban as amnesty sees hundreds of weapons surrendered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/victoria-machete-weapon-amnesty-push-for-national-ban/105778266</link><description>The state's police minister vows to urge other states and territories to ban the weapons after more than 1,300 machetes and dangerous knives were surrendered at disposal bins during the first two weeks of his government's machete amnesty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c799d399d5ef8249c46906599105cfd</guid></item><item><title>Craig McLachlan withdraws from Cluedo stage show following backlash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/craig-mclachlan-withdraws-cluedo-the-play/105779280</link><description>Less than a week ago, Craig McLachlan was announced to play Colonel Mustard in the forthcoming national tour, making his return to the theatre after The Rocky Horror Show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2abe05c441b509ea22995eb926f87711</guid></item><item><title>Planning commission rejects bid to turn Redbank Power Station into bioenergy hub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/planning-commission-rejects-redbank-power-station-biofuel-plan/105777592</link><description>The Independent Planning Commission of NSW knocks back plans to restart Redbank Power Station in the Hunter Valley, fuelling it with biomass instead of coal tailings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">149bdcd14f72ed4787e50322861090cb</guid></item><item><title>Australia Diamonds announce netball squads for Test series against New Zealand, South Africa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/australia-diamonds-announce-test-netball-squads-new-zealand-sa/105779230</link><description>Goal-shooter Lucy Austin is a shock selection in the Australian netball squad to face South Africa, winning a place after initially being included as an "invitee" to their training camp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f84722b6abee542504171a8343b1b82</guid></item><item><title>Laura Gerber accuses Labor of mudslinging following questioning over exits of chiefs of staff</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/laura-gerber-labor-mudslinging-exit-chiefs-of-staff-queensland/105779106</link><description>Three chiefs of staff have left Gold Coast MP Laura Gerber's office since the LNP was elected almost 11 months ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b19db082c3650245dd46470537514bf2</guid></item><item><title>Central Queensland included in fire ant biosecurity zones</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/fire-ant-biosecurity-zones-introduced-in-central-queensland/105777728</link><description>New restrictions in place on moving materials into five central Queensland sites to reduce the spread of the invasive species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f62a27c6d9e79b642f55fa3dab985fb8</guid></item><item><title>Where and how to watch the 2025 Primetime Emmy award-wining shows in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/where-and-how-to-watch-the-emmy-award-wining-shows/105778142</link><description>From The Studio to The Pitt, here's how to stream the biggest winners of the 2025 Primetime Emmy Awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3034e31269c6f5feac0ed68921c317c</guid></item><item><title>Jennifer Aniston and Reese Witherspoon say their show explores ‘a lot of stuff that is happening in our world today’</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/jennifer-aniston-and-reese-witherspoon-say-their/105779044</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b043867be6a6485d0051591b1c941bd</guid></item><item><title>Perth childcare worker Robert David Reti faces court for allegedly indecently touching two girls at separate centres</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/perth-childcare-worker-robert-reti-accused-of-indecent-acts/105778920</link><description>A male childcare worker indecently touched two young girls in his care at separate childcare centres in the Perth metropolitan area, a court hears.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8773ffc337006c01be69dfa51723999</guid></item><item><title>Victoria delays Gippsland offshore wind auction, stalling developers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/victoria-offshore-wind-auction-delay/105778708</link><description>The Victorian government pushes back its timeline for new offshore wind farms in the state's east in a blow to developers looking to move their projects to the next stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80c982b89a58ea8f9bc5c06f098af297</guid></item><item><title>Aaron Chen talks comedy, faith, and moving to New York</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/aaron-chen-take-5-comedy-interview-music-tonight-fisk/105773602</link><description>How Aaron Chen went from being booted out of Sydney pubs to winning Logies and chasing global stardom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd43f88c371be470e8b83b1b925f650a</guid></item><item><title>Papua New Guinea celebrates journey to independence, 50 years after parting with Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/papua-new-guinea-50-years-independence-from-australia/105775268</link><description>On the foreshore of Papua New Guinea's capital city, Ela Beach is where locals come to exercise, mingle and unwind at the end of a long day. But it wasn't always this way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7147eb3a5bc7c7f0eca073099802ceb5</guid></item><item><title>Does washing your fruit and veggies remove chemicals?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/best-way-to-wash-fresh-produce-fruits-veggies-remove-chemcials-/105773664</link><description>This is what experts have to say about washing fruit and veggies, with removing chemicals and reducing the amount we consume in mind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57b4d4864180c3c11eed8be0eca03f20</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump files defamation and libel lawsuit against The New York Times, claiming 'massive economic damage to his brand value'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/trump-files-us15-billion-lawsuit-against-new-york-times/105779782</link><description>In a lengthy post on his social media platform, the US president accused The New York Times of lying about him, his family and his business.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">025394af4103f19c4c76069f86680f4b</guid></item><item><title>Concurrent disasters will overwhelm responders, stress ADF, risk report warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/defence-forces-disaster-response-climate-risk-assessment/105778304</link><description>A dedicated disaster recovery force is needed, or else responders and defence forces could be "overwhelmed" by multiple concurrent natural disasters, the National Climate Risk Assessment warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79a82e7988ce64cb47e2aea9d939b300</guid></item><item><title>Breastfeeding Gold Coast mum says she was asked to leave Virgin Australia lounge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/virgin-australia-apologises-mother-pumping-breast-milk/105779738</link><description>Mother-of-two Elise Turner says she was asked to leave the Virgin Australia business lounge after refusing to go to a bathroom to pump breast milk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a5d01ae6ec3bc3224e376127e761ff5</guid></item><item><title>How Isabelle Kelly shook off getting her 'teeth pushed back' to return for Roosters' NRLW finals charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/isabelle-kelly-injury-jaw-teeth-roosters-nrlw-finals/105780582</link><description>Isabelle Kelly was meant to rest up for a few weeks after suffering an oral fracture that nearly cost her several teeth but the Roosters skipper missed just one match and has now returned to lead the club's premiership charge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">062a7201f7cd32cadeb54c8069a61337</guid></item><item><title>China has a 'chokehold' on the rare earth supply chain. Could Australia offer an alternative?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/china-rare-earths-monopoly-australia-alternative-supplier/105748058</link><description>Rare earths are critical for manufacturing everything from electric vehicles to wind turbines and defence equipment, and with China's dominance over the supply chain, they have also become inextricably enmeshed in geopolitics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7e66c6df15c930bf8fa103970dac05b</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of pigs die as Andgar Proprietors piggery catches fire with two sheds burning for over 12 hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/andgar-piggery-fire-kills-200-animials-sa/105780636</link><description>The Department of Primary Industries and Regions says about 200 animals died in the blaze while another 45 pigs were euthanised by the department and RSPCA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8d637dff0fa3ce0bdf9aee2457db201</guid></item><item><title>Search underway, exclusion zone set up after person flees crash on Bruce Highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/bruce-highway-crash-exclusion-zone-search/105780234</link><description>The person is understood to have fled into bushland after a two-vehicle crash on the Bruce Highway north of Rockhampton.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54a442e63f7aca822ab3b38555814424</guid></item><item><title>Former Exit International coordinator Elaine Arch-Rowe accused of euthanasia drug supply</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/elaine-arch-rowe-euthanasia-drug-accused-granted-bail/105777878</link><description>The 81-year-old woman is charged with attempting to assist suicide, trafficking and possession of dangerous drugs, and the sale of potential harmful things.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da47d7e327f5a22bd9ff1575495f4fee</guid></item><item><title>Israeli military launches ground offensive to occupy Gaza City, Axios and CNN report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/idf-launches-military-offensive-to-occupy-gaza/105777948</link><description>The Israel Defense Forces have reportedly launched a new ground operation in central Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80bfd937165cc59a068b4d0ad85e2045</guid></item><item><title>CCTV of a pair allegedly involved in a violent carjacking on Sunday.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/cctv-of-a-pair-allegedly-involved-in-a-violent/105780742</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbb33709a7957a94054008b811aa9d99</guid></item><item><title>Queensland police release vision of pair accused of violent carjacking on Sunshine Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/qld-armed-carjacking-sunshine-coast-cctv-vision-released/105780504</link><description>Police allege the pair assaulted three people and attempted to steal multiple vehicles while armed early on Sunday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">227cbcd18812b3783432cb3061566399</guid></item><item><title>Israel is committing genocide in Gaza, major United Nations report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/israel-committing-genocide-in-gaza-un-report-says/105780230</link><description>Israel has committed and is continuing to commit genocide in Gaza, according to the "most authoritative assessment" to date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e547fcd275b42fb12bbaa7d9028fd7aa</guid></item><item><title>James O'Connor still hopeful of playing Bledisloe Cup for Wallabies against All Blacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/james-oconnor-still-hopeful-of-playing-bledisloe-cup/105780738</link><description>James O'Connor has flown to England with his Test future still up in the air, but the Wallabies playmaker has not given up on playing in his first Bledisloe Cup match in five years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fe6060cfa537dad8e49fa78e8c41f63</guid></item><item><title>A UN report says Israel is committing genocide. Experts hope it spurs Australia to act</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/un-report-on-israel-genocide-msg-to-nations-including-australia/105777232</link><description>What ultimately determines whether the UN's report joins the list of other shocking but overlooked inquiries is whether this latest finding moves any governments, including Australia's, to take further action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fb5a1cc5ffb6a04a620f69e884c0b48</guid></item><item><title>A UN report says Israel is committing genocide. Experts hope it spurs Australia to act</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/un-report-on-israel-genocide-msg-to-nations-including-australia/105777232</link><description>What ultimately determines whether the UN's report joins the list of other shocking but overlooked inquiries is whether this latest finding moves any governments, including Australia's, to take further action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">121775c05df3d7bd0ed0b0d63cee2c23</guid></item><item><title>Simon Lviev, the Tinder Swindler on Netflix, arrested after allegedly scamming victims out of $15 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/the-tinder-swindler-simon-lviev-arrested-in-georgia/105780320</link><description>Simon Lviev, 34, rose to notoriety after a pattern of romance fraud and financial crimes, with victims scammed out of an estimated $15 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">408e01733332e7bcef8aa275d501d586</guid></item></channel></rss>