<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 09:19:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rugby fans furious over 2027 Rugby World Cup ticket website crashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/rugby-world-cup-tickets-website-crash/106363344</link><description>Rugby fans from around the world are furious after failing to get tickets to the 2027 Men's World Cup due technical glitches and website crashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4827688c1be1b5c4bd7a18a7c04671b5</guid></item><item><title>Hanson digs her heels in, Taylor goes on tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/pauline-hanson-barnaby-joyce-angus-taylor-anthony-albanese/106349216</link><description>This week, the new opposition leader revealed his shadow cabinet while Pauline Hanson spun through a cycle she knows well.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ea3a4f2179a8b0064925ee07ccfca6c</guid></item><item><title>Two WA childcare providers fined after high-needs children wander off from care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/samson-primary-school-after-school-care-fined-over-child-leaving/106360960</link><description>One of Australia's biggest providers of before-and-after-school care penalised after a five-year-old neurodivergent child escapes supervision unnoticed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e0decf99cf8c863e11323748cea5d84</guid></item><item><title>Long-awaited rapid bus plan fails to reveal construction timeline or routes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/tas-rapid-bus-network-for-hobart-business-case/106363452</link><description>After about a year of delays, the Tasmanian government has released its strategic business case for the Greater Hobart Rapid Bus Network, but a lot of the detail has not been included.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a15721768f97446098853eb2e67cfa6</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of 'controlling' the lives of Venezuelan youth group granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/bail-granted-over-alleged-youth-group-servitude/106363616</link><description>An alleged religious leader accused of "controlling every aspect" of the lives of a Venezuelan youth group has been granted release on strict home detention conditions by a South Australian court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91bc9f195f669d568f2a90e1fe9c2a44</guid></item><item><title>Collingwood apologises after asking elderly members for donations via their wills</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/collingwood-magpies-afl-will-elderly-members-donate/106364978</link><description>The Magpies have come under fire after a letter campaign asking elderly members to amend their wills to donate to the AFL club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f43cc50e873d456431eb853f09b69899</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/thursday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/106364470</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4c5b51e530a659b7487c6517551d5d1</guid></item><item><title>Abandoned Antarctic base is now a pollution threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/abandoned-antarctic-base-is-now-a-pollution-threat-/106365360</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49846b03030ffc2b913431f02159b7f8</guid></item><item><title>Former prince returns home as police investigation continues — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-epstein-police/106365802</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor has returned to his Sandringham home after being arrested and questioned on suspicion of misconduct in public office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5fc074cadfc2697a563fee6e91b29af</guid></item><item><title>What we know about ex-prince Andrew's arrest on suspicion of misconduct in public office</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/what-we-know-about-former-prince-andrew-arrest/106365894</link><description>Police are searching two addresses in the UK, including Royal Lodge on the Windsor Estate where the former prince lived until last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8039d5e6abc316002657b559e90ee456</guid></item><item><title>Former premier joins community calls for speed reduction at 'dangerous' fatal intersection in Newham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/community-calls-for-speed-reduction-newham-intersection-victoria/106364280</link><description>A community in central Victoria is calling for a 20 kph speed limit reduction at a "terribly dangerous" intersection after four major accidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d28bf645384eca294d072c5b45849511</guid></item><item><title>Sisters Lisa and Rachael Maza reunite on stage for the world premiere of Black Light</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/lisa-rachael-maza-sisters-black-light-malthouse-theatre/106357630</link><description>The former head of Indigenous theatre company Ilbijerri teams up with her sister Lisa for the world premiere of Black Light, which tells the story of three generations of Blak women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1799e84905988608fb42c35ca34a445</guid></item><item><title>Calls for protection of Tasmania's penguins amid reports of birds 'handled by the neck'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/people-interacting-with-tasmanian-penguins-and-harming-them/106361614</link><description>Each summer, tourists flock to Tasmanian beaches to marvel at penguins, but for some, admiring the birds from afar is not enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a8bc422a73f9012a025e072732b4fbb</guid></item><item><title>Police say 'hope is fading' in hunt for kidnapped Sydney grandfather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/chris-baghsarian-kidnapping-dural-update/106366514</link><description>Police believe they have found a "stronghold" used by the kidnappers of Chris Baghsarian in Dural as the search for the 85-year-old continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc8967c1b1d6ddfb449c5911301dc1f2</guid></item><item><title>As electric car prices fall, will affordability win over drivers?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/cart-electric-vehicles-becoming-more-affordable/106348534</link><description>The price tag of EVs has been a barrier to uptake. As cheaper models hit the market, will more drivers go electric?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8e8609bc047b4700deb6c7a5c8c5aa4</guid></item><item><title>Voters divided as Barnaby Joyce considers contesting New England for One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/new-england-divided-over-barnaby-joyce/106353714</link><description>One Nation MP Barnaby Joyce says he might recontest his seat of New England as a candidate for One Nation if the party needs him to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8216e2cb0110f0bcd4db9bab70757914</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's arrest could end monarchy's 'never complain, never explain' mentality</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrest-a-problem-for-monarchy/106365934</link><description>British royals have lived by the adage "never complain, never explain", but these days, many of their subjects are demanding answers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69ce80bb0d80419516702662a1c32494</guid></item><item><title>Youth justice experts warn over-policing of residential care children is 'manufacturing criminals'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/over-policing-residential-care-children-fast-tracking-criminals/106352902</link><description>Experts say over-policing and South Australia's youth criminal justice system is helping turn children in residential care into criminals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18308ad8258e1668e4b639d5c38e6dcf</guid></item><item><title>Study to test whether a new helmet will significantly reduce risk of concussion in football players</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/helmet-studied-to-see-if-it-reduces-concussion-risk-footballers/106358372</link><description>A lot of research has gone in to treating concussions, but now scientists are testing a new helmet to see if it can prevent them before they happen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f22fb72db16b8951d854fc6dc06f4c17</guid></item><item><title>More rainfall expected for parts of northern Queensland after wet week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/more-rainfall-forecast-for-northern-qld/106362726</link><description>A risk for further heavy rainfall and thunderstorms is possible in northern parts of the state today and into the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e9add29fa1f01a82340402c2e1aad56</guid></item><item><title>First NT women's prison opens in Alice Springs with focus on rehabilitation to break 'cycle of reoffending'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/first-nt-womens-prison-opens-in-alice-springs/106357580</link><description>Thirty-five female prisoners have moved into the Northern Territory's first women's prison, near Alice Springs, with more expected in the coming months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b13e3f1982f1c6fef53a91ff356eabb1</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor released under investigation after almost 10 hours in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrested-misconduct-in-public-office/106366200</link><description>The former Duke of York has been released under investigation by British police, as officers continue to search his former Windsor home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94a6bbd07a298ae5c28f71caf5061d5c</guid></item><item><title>Bangarra Dance Theatre wins Golden Lion at international dance festival Venice Danza 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/bangarra-dance-theatre-golden-lion-venice-biennale/106366904</link><description>Indigenous dance company Bangarra Dance Theatre has become the first company and first First Nations performers to receive the Golden Lion at Venice Danza, the international festival of contemporary dance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1e2f7d948461775c920779a3628e602</guid></item><item><title>'Dying' NASA satellite leaves Australia's north waiting hours for latest fire information</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/dying-satellite-delays-nafi-fire-detections/106353398</link><description>A NASA satellite used to detect bushfires in real time across two thirds of Australia is "dying" and it could be months before a replacement is online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">816ad33b117b9b0c1f1a67a375fa58e4</guid></item><item><title>Canadian skier Cassie Sharpe's horrific crash in the halfpipe reminds us of Winter Olympics dangers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/cassie-sharpe-canadian-freeski-halfpipe-crash/106366818</link><description>As Cassie Sharpe lay motionless on the base of the Livigno halfpipe, the excruciating tension reminded us all that winter Olympians are only ever seconds from disaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca8a04bde9604f081e69e3f402a12a68</guid></item><item><title>Fiji, Palau and Tuvalu set to show world leaders climate change impact ahead of COP31</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/pacific-nations-set-to-host-world-leaders-on-climate-change/106366110</link><description>Fiji, Palau and Tuvalu look set to host world leaders and climate change ministers in the lead-up to COP31 in a bid to encourage larger countries to accelerate cuts to emissions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efb0153cc3ad4a4f839fc3664ed151a9</guid></item><item><title>Is it OK to feed Australia's wild birds?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/is-it-ok-to-feed-australias-wild-birds/106349168</link><description>Many of us love interacting with and feeding wild birds, but experts say giving them the wrong types of food can do more harm than good.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eec910366a2f5aeb070b335682010295</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos lose World Club Challenge to Hull KR 30-24</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/brisbane-broncos-lose-world-club-challenge-to-hull-kr/106367354</link><description>After pulling off three straight comebacks to win the NRL premiership, the Brisbane Broncos fall just short of another miracle against Hull KR in the World Club Challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">226460c361ffc36183702882e85cf411</guid></item><item><title>Eric Dane, star of Grey's Anatomy and Euphoria, dies aged 53</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/eric-dane-star-of-greys-anatomy-and-euphoria-dies/106188556</link><description>The star was best known for his role as Dr Mark Sloan in long-running medical drama Grey's Anatomy, and as the patriarch of the Jacobs family in teen hit Euphoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38f5c65f82f5e42103bcfbd84e4e18ea</guid></item><item><title>WA councils could make laws to stop cats roaming under proposed state legislation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/wa-councils-could-soon-have-power-to-stop-cats-roaming/106365476</link><description>The WA government announces plans to give local councils the power to require cats to be contained to owners' properties, to protect native birds and other wildlife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9304ac0385f2634a77bf6bab016498b8</guid></item><item><title>Racist hate mail sent to politicians bears hallmarks of Lakemba Mosque letters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/racist-hate-mail-politicians-hallmarks-of-lakemba-mosque-letters/106367872</link><description>The ABC can reveal two of the threatening, hate-filled letters sent to Lakemba Mosque this month bear close resemblance to similar racist letters sent to multiple politicians since 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6e986afd5bf4027ac11562bd322c9fa</guid></item><item><title>Darwin prisoner Clinton Daylight found, returned to custody two days after being freed from jail by mistake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/clinton-daylight-prisoner-mistakenly-released-nt-darwin-found/106368724</link><description>A 52-year-old inmate who was mistakenly released from the Darwin Correctional Centre two months before his sentence was due to end, due to an "administration error" by prison staff, has been found following a police search.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ab77d54005b5f557cf182cfc9c9d924</guid></item><item><title>MotoGP Adelaide move raises concerns about rider safety, transport and trees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/motogp-adelaide-move-raises-safety-concerns/106368608</link><description>A rider, a reporter and a road safety expert say it will be difficult to make it safe for motorcycles to race around the Adelaide Parklands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25090531a9db489ad194e965a6815079</guid></item><item><title>Port Pirie's toddlers record highest blood lead levels in a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/port-pirie-blood-lead-levels-toddlers-highest-in-10-years-sa/106369868</link><description>The percentage of two-year-old children above the blood lead level threshold in Port Pirie is the highest in a decade, according to the latest figures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8f014a4524a788f30a87b5122219935</guid></item><item><title>Ellyse Perry's evolution cements greatness as Australian cricket milestone looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/ellyse-perry-australia-cricket-350-matches/106369982</link><description>Cricket superstar Ellyse Perry will become the first woman to play 350 matches for Australia across all formats on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">588cdbd7c7f7eac8850144d63f6e89e7</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's new chief health officer Marianne Gale outlines future priorities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/chief-health-officer-queensland-marianne-gale/106367180</link><description>Marianne Gale reminisces about her time working for Doctors Without Borders to emphasise how she wants to shape the public health of the state – with a strong focus on equity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6f0812de7c10d62a596512830e7846b</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand man Tamaohungia Joseph Tepatu-Edwards jailed for 26 years for attempted cocaine importation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/new-zealand-man-jailed-attempted-cocaine-importation/106368264</link><description>A man who tried to smuggle more than 800 kilograms of cocaine into WA – and was only caught when his boat broke down — will spend two decades in jail and is "likely" be deported.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe96af322e56c9cc85664c9573f21026</guid></item><item><title>Rottnest Channel Swim cancelled due to strong winds, choppy seas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/rottnest-channel-swim-cancelled-amid-weather-concerns-/106367682</link><description>Perth's iconic Rottnest Channel Swim has been cancelled as forecast strong winds and unfavourable ocean conditions leaves thousands of swimmers and support crew disappointed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e022e3393793fa2b5ca1e4a824be305b</guid></item><item><title>Police receive 'reports of crime' in relation to Pauline Hanson interview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/police-investigation-pauline-hanson-afp-one-nation-muslim/106370420</link><description>One Nation senator Pauline Hanson accuses the government of trying to put her "back in jail", after police received reports of a crime in relation to the senator's inflammatory comments about Muslims during a media interview.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">185dd63416cc7c6d747e0e5e37316352</guid></item><item><title>NSW Waratahs defeat Fijian Drua in Super Rugby Pacific round two, Pete Samu plays after birth of child</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/nsw-waratahs-vs-fijian-drua-super-rugby-pacific-round-two/106370446</link><description>Wallabies veteran Pete Samu has helped the NSW Waratahs to consecutive wins to start the Super Rugby Pacific season, just hours after the birth of his child.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26c7e757c5bf325353099df43d6d8f38</guid></item><item><title>Australia blows Oman away to end T20 World Cup campaign with a bang</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/t20-world-cup-australia-vs-oman-live-blog/106371016</link><description>Australia has flogged Oman, chasing down 105 in less than 10 overs to end a disappointing World Cup campaign on a high. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48a66d916c759b65504e92b5f344bd88</guid></item><item><title>Man whose girlfriend froze to death after he left her on mountain convicted of manslaughter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/austria-manslaughter-after-woman-froze-to-death-on-mountain/106371008</link><description>A man who left his girlfriend to freeze to death on an Austrian mountain has been handed a five-month suspended sentence for manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">effae5ababb3ac61ba124a96f11fe003</guid></item><item><title>Jeffrey Epstein's estate agrees to pay up to $US35 million to settle class action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/epstein-estate-agrees-to-pay-up-to-us-35m-to-settle-class-action/106371194</link><description>Jeffrey Epstein's estate has agreed to pay as much as $US35 million to resolve a class action lawsuit, according to a court filing on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">883c1ed664dc93038eba1c101323e85d</guid></item><item><title>UK government to consider removing Andrew from succession line, as royal protection police face grilling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/royal-protection-police-to-be-grilled-over-mountbatten-windsor/106371406</link><description>The UK government is to look at removing Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor from the line of succession, an official says, as royal protection police face a grilling on "anything they saw or heard".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3493cf1504035f8670aff82102e21ef1</guid></item><item><title>Should Labor do its own refresh after Angus Taylor's Liberal 'rebrand'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/angus-taylor-shadow-cabinet-albanese-government/106337018</link><description>In the past few days, in a series of largely ignored milestones overshadowed by news of Angus Taylor's new frontbench, Albanese overtook Scott Morrison and John Curtin to become the 12th-longest serving prime minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">070d46246d34302a081ac085940a13ec</guid></item><item><title>Andy Griffiths, author of the Treehouse books, named new Australian Children's Laureate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/andy-griffiths-author-australian-childrens-laureate/106331360</link><description>Famous for writing stories about toilets and tree houses, the bestselling kids' author is taking on a new challenge on the national stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4faf4f52c970006ea1d74e0f15c753b</guid></item><item><title>Tell us what is going on in grassroots footy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/cart-investigations-hometown-boys-call-out/106349718</link><description>Do you have a story about the culture at a footy netball club in your community? ABC Regional Investigations wants to hear from you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d3774ef0a474dc81a9e4470bd880506</guid></item><item><title>The town that turned its back on a rape victim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/balmoral-home-town-boys-rape-divides-football-farming-town/106145646</link><description>A local footy star and his mate are convicted of raping their friend. In the tiny town of Balmoral, where the footy club reigns, the town makes it clear whose story they believe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcced53be78cf23e4251d66c753ae52d</guid></item><item><title>Heaviest outback rain in decades forecast to reach SA, NSW and Victorian farmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/widespread-rain-forecast-for-south-australia-riverina-victoria/106370362</link><description>The driest belt of Australia sees its wettest month in decades, and weather modelling tips the outback rain will reach southern Australia this weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b35300dccc79d36c4562bf0324972fa</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's future uncertain under monarch willing to let 'the law take its course'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/andrew-arrest-will-go-down-in-history-books/106367696</link><description>Like so many of the elite caught in Epstein's web, Andrew believed he would escape scrutiny for his behaviour. But it is precisely because of his name and position that his alleged wrongdoing has now delivered him into the hands of the law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">876a05a2e2317a3aa1a9f28c7c53ce70</guid></item><item><title>Why Pacific Islands are rapidly de-flagging Russia's fleet of 'shadow tankers'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/pacific-islands-flags-of-convenience-shadow-vessels/106357172</link><description>Pacific Islands are rapidly de-flagging vessels on their shipping registries after gaining international attention for their role in Russia's "shadow fleet".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f072b9260e3417979d4a703c003d41e0</guid></item><item><title>Nathan Cleary facing two-match suspension over high hit in Panthers' trial loss to Wests Tigers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/nrl-cleary-facing-ban-panthers-lose-tigers-trials-match/106371458</link><description>Nathan Cleary can accept a two-match suspension with an early plea after his high hit on Wests Tigers star Heamasi Makasini.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0688e0c927d67a68c51d9c5a5808dcf7</guid></item><item><title>The art and origins of the courtroom sketch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/the-art-and-origins-of-the-courtroom-sketch/105817718</link><description>They're a small and curious cohort in a line of work rapidly evolving. Welcome to the world of courtroom artists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5051373d22a373be7ac83c73f3f9a4bb</guid></item><item><title>Peter Malinauskas is heading for a landslide win in SA. How crushing a victory will it be?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/sa-election-lots-to-learn-despite-predicted-labor-landslide/106363808</link><description>Even if it's a Labor landslide, we'll learn a lot from next month's South Australian election, writes Casey Briggs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2475f1de36b7f53be3206611dfb848d</guid></item><item><title>Manchester United owner Jim Ratcliffe avoids sanctions after saying UK has been 'colonised' by immigrants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/football-man-united-owner-not-charged-colonised-call-ratcliffe/106371480</link><description>Jim Ratcliffe is reminded of his responsibilities as a participant in English football but is not handed any penalties from FA after his controversial call.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69bf802509648780c979dcba937fb0a8</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's arrest shows money talks louder than women's testimony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrest-jeffrey-epstein/106349250</link><description>Why is an email about the trade trip apparently more compelling than the detailed and painful evidence of a woman?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c126708b2400a064fec41430e0ad12c1</guid></item><item><title>Man and 15yo boy charged over shooting of former NRL player Matt Utai</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/nsw-two-charged-shooting-nrl-player-matt-utai-greenacre/106371512</link><description>Police allege a 25-year-old man was responsible for the shooting of former NRL player Matt Utai, while a 15-year-old drove the getaway car.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82625733d6500d322cd94c0445cb3979</guid></item><item><title>Research sparks renewed calls for needle exchange programs to be introduced in Australian prisons</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/prison-needle-exchange-illicit-drugs/106332450</link><description>Researchers and advocates are calling for needle exchange programs to be introduced in prisons to help combat the risks of sharing needles and using unsafe devices to inject illicut drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">745c7eea1087ddfcb664f3f277845906</guid></item><item><title>Community Emergency Response Team volunteer paramedics fill care gap</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/community-emergency-response-team-volunteers-assist-paramedics/106282858</link><description>In parts of rural and remote New South Wales, groups of volunteers are brushing up on high-level first aid skills to become first responders when an ambulance crew cannot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccfb86354ff0d75fd8e01bc9d88f17b1</guid></item><item><title>Farmer's hands-off approach creates unusual lamb with distinct flavour chefs say is like nothing else in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/braidwood-farmer-new-lamb-cooked-local-restaurant-expat-chefs/106358970</link><description>When Frank was forced to sell the sheep he'd been farming for more than 20 years, something had to change. His "experiment" is helping expats feel at home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">193e31303ed2bfa342879871031db171</guid></item><item><title>After 60 years, there are fears Myer may walk away from Launceston's CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/concerns-myer-may-leave-launceston-shopping-strip/106367746</link><description>Community and business leaders say the possible departure of retailer Myer would leave a "giant hole" in the heart of the city's shopping district.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c928733eebf54cd5eadca8fc44e69d7</guid></item><item><title>Queensland woman wakes from coma after contracting meningitis and septic shock on ski holiday to Japan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/queensland-woman-coma-meningitis-septic-shock-in-japan/106367880</link><description>When 24-year-old Anna Gallo woke up shivering in a Tokyo hotel, she thought it was food poisoning. Hours later, she was in a coma fighting for her life against a disease she thought she was vaccinated against.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df154e4e3de16e61796b2871c5c9fe9b</guid></item><item><title>Cattle tick outbreak raises questions over Queensland's biosecurity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/tick-outbreak-raises-questions-over-queenslands-biosecurity/106367970</link><description>Queensland is known for its hardline biosecurity stance against foreign pests, but farmers say a recent cattle tick outbreak has exposed systemic weaknesses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11798db4c4a29dca21b6773386e53cb7</guid></item><item><title>Bayern Munich coach Vincent Kompany says José Mourinho made 'huge mistake' attacking Vinícius Júnior's character after alleged racist insult</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/football-kompany-criticises-mourinho-over-vini-jr-racism-call/106371656</link><description>Bayern Munich manager Vincent Kompany dissects the racism row involving Real Madrid and Brazil star Viní Jr with a passionate 12-minute speech.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">612aa3df4ab705ac95b277d2f9bcadb5</guid></item><item><title>Herby potato salad with green beans and tuna - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/herby-potatoes-with-green-beans-and-tuna/106252480</link><description>Turn a potato salad into a tasty meal with pantry staples and fresh greens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bf3639cafb3b89fadd2f76dbfd84322</guid></item><item><title>Why economists hate low unemployment for inflation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/why-economists-hate-low-unemployment-for-inflation/106367852</link><description>The theory goes that if you have just the right amount of workers on the unemployment scrap heap, you can keep inflation in check. The problem is that no-one knows exactly what the magic unemployment rate is.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43e029d93818ef09b173d99095546fef</guid></item><item><title>Potential release of carp control virus into waterways delayed until 2028</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/national-carp-control-plan-decade-delay-carp-herpes-virus/106348408</link><description>Release of a virus to control carp in Australian waterways has been delayed until 2028, a decade after it was initially slated for release.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dbde53e8280f083aef35066d7c03374</guid></item><item><title>How Reuters captured that photo of former Prince Andrew leaving custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/how-reuters-captured-the-photo-of-former-prince-andrew-leavi/106371770</link><description>The image, taken by Reuters photographer Phil Noble, went viral when it was published on Thursday. He says capturing the moment came down to a tip-off and more than a little luck.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23d31204491246cc184daea89e905d39</guid></item><item><title>I had a miscarriage over the summer. It was nothing like I expected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/miscarriage-loss-grief/106308830</link><description>My understanding of miscarriage was built on a handful of Hollywood representations and snatches of stories I'd read. Outside of this, I had few reference points.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a18951e43e4efa639be7b2845bc9d57e</guid></item><item><title>Adam Zampa says claims Australia does not care about T20 cricket 'totally false' after World Cup flop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/cricket-zampa-defends-australia-t20-prep-world-cup-exit/106371894</link><description>Adam Zampa hits back at claims that Australia does not care about T20 cricket after a disappointing World Cup campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47ff9ce19c56b6ba685a684eb3b125df</guid></item><item><title>The shamans and designer handbags before Yoon Suk Yeol's insurrection conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/the-scandalous-downfall-of-yoon-suk-yeol/106358072</link><description>Former South Korean president Yoon Suk Yeol's sentence for insurrection comes after a tumultuous era of shamanism, Chanel bags and conspiracy theories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c392edec639f36481f4ec7269ef84031</guid></item><item><title>How a Belgian techno producer with some old synthesisers has reimagined Terminator 2</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/terminator-2-new-score-hear-my-eyes-mess/106369562</link><description>Terminator 2: Judgment Day is getting the live score treatment, but not in the way you might expect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">689c4da252c634c2c4554ed5d31bba80</guid></item><item><title>Viral AI videos raise questions about how we view reality</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/viral-ai-videos-raise-questions-about-how-we-view-reality/106307568</link><description>For a bit of a laugh, Travis Marshall uses artificial intelligence to create wacky videos about his hometown, but his light-hearted content also raises serious questions about reality in the age of AI.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cbd3a6d66eeb25ca5cb5d78fb34fba0</guid></item><item><title>Drugs with estimated street value of $1.45 million seized in traffic stop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/nabiac-traffic-stop-leads-to-drug-seizure-police-say/106372078</link><description>A traffic stop on the Pacific Highway on the NSW Mid North Coast has led to the seizure of hundreds of thousands of dollars' worth of cocaine and cannabis, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52ce47c8e206ebeeccdec73dced1e56e</guid></item><item><title>Farmer builds chapel for Tongan workers, the 'backbone' of her banana farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/lakeland-chapel-tongan-workers-palm-scheme-queensland/106362494</link><description>A Queensland banana farmer spent 10 years saving to build a chapel for the Tongan workers who form the backbone of her family’s operation on Cape York Peninsula.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9129d4087a3dedd75e8c65e58a866cf</guid></item><item><title>The US Supreme Court's take-down of Trump's tariffs explained</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/explaining-the-us-supreme-court-takedown-of-trumps-tariffs/106372118</link><description>The ruling on tariffs is a hugely consequential decision that has infuriated the president, who is now looking for workarounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d66c597b8db50bd67f75d00125911020</guid></item><item><title>Punch the baby macaque draws a crowd at Japan's Ichikawa City Zoo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/punch-baby-macaque-japan-zoo-soft-toy-orangutan/106371376</link><description>The six month old macaque's relationship with a soft toy orangutan has become an internet sensation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76354b2a83722acb0b827836893c9d71</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after allegedly throwing 'lit incendiary device' during Navy chief's speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/man-charged-fake-explosive-hotel-window-navy-chief/106371970</link><description>A man faces court accused of throwing a fake explosive device through a Canberra hotel window during a speech from the Chief of Navy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95b8a361b3e4aba53d93366cf6307112</guid></item><item><title>Auckland FC defeat Wellington Phoenix 5-0 in A-League Men, goalkeeper Josh Oluwayemi own goal begins rout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/auckland-fc-defeat-wellington-phoenix-5-0-in-a-league-men/106372300</link><description>Wellington Phoenix goalkeeper Josh Oluwayemi commits one of the worst howlers this A-League Men season, heading a clearance kick into his own net as Auckland FC romps to a big win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c520681fd47bae4fe6c8395992f4c0c7</guid></item><item><title>South Australian election countdown officially begins, campaign kicks off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/south-australia-election-2026-campaign-begins/106371978</link><description>Election campaigning in South Australia is officially underway, with candidates seizing the opportunity to begin making their formal pitches to voters before they head to the ballot box in March.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9242c102760eb4813ef7943f0f70998b</guid></item><item><title>Hungary and Slovakia threaten Ukraine over stalled Russian oil shipments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/hungary-and-slovakia-threaten-ukraine-russian-oil/106372526</link><description>Hungary and Slovakia, which have both received a temporary exemption from an EU policy prohibiting imports of Russian oil, have accused Ukraine of deliberately holding up supplies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e8c5eda8272aceae2a467ae014b516a</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government bears inflation pressure while premiers spend big, poll well</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/albanese-government-premiers-peter-malinauskas-david-crisafulli/106349260</link><description>High-spending premiers remain popular and seemingly impervious to the rising cost-of-living anxiety piling pressure on the Albanese government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0ff2d992e25fd6ee865c92e0a78f4e5</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Think you're a trivia boss? Show us what you've got</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/106366918</link><description>Well, this is cute — you thinking you're a quiz pro. It's time to play … HARD!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa1afae586e91600568a748b64e08b37</guid></item><item><title>Bridgerton's Yerin Ha is living her own Cinderella story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/bridgerton-season-four-part-two-yerin-ha-interview/106363336</link><description>Yerin Ha built a name for herself in local and international productions for almost a decade before transforming into Bridgerton's newest paramour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99b5fbc19663ba58a0fb1032c0e7fedf</guid></item><item><title>On the front lines of Australia's fight against vaccine hesitancy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/australia-vaccine-hesitancy-fight-restore-confidence/106353012</link><description>With immunisation rates declining and outbreaks of infectious diseases like measles increasing, the consequences of vaccine hesitancy in Australia are becoming clearer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8359da5691e58e050b22964baecf814e</guid></item><item><title>More assault allegations surface against footballers in tiny town of Balmoral</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/hometown-boys-culture-of-football-misogyny-called-out-balmoral/106358784</link><description>More women come forward with allegations of sexual assault in a small Victorian town, years after a rape victim was shunned by the town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e4baf80ef8954cf91ddfdc29c6843b8</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump hikes global tariff rate to 15pc after Supreme Court loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/trump-hikes-tariff-rate-to-15pc-supreme-court/106373116</link><description>Donald Trump says he will raise to 15 per cent the global tariff he imposed after the US Supreme Court ruled against previous tariffs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5312a29068d4db1c715343da579c334a</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor was the Queen's rumoured favourite. Did she do too much to protect him?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/queen-elizabeth-former-prince-andrew-and-epstein/106371728</link><description>It will be up to King Charles to shepherd his family's institution through its darkest hour. But could his own mother have done more to snuff out this crisis before he inherited it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75d2f85e2faea6fba90af13bf1129d78</guid></item><item><title>A visual guide to the prices that landed Coles in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/coles-grocery-pricing-down-down-accc-court/106355492</link><description>The pricing patterns of these six products show how Coles stands accused of using its Down Down marketing campaign to dupe shoppers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6972c0ae544a3d055ce6b66632f8a24d</guid></item><item><title>Coastal communities weigh costs and potential retreat as erosion batters SA's Limestone Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/beach-communities-battling-coastal-erosion-costs-south-australia/106349638</link><description>With costs and damage mounting, councils are considering all options, including pulling back from the beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">358ed68ef9f52813ec32ea720e241852</guid></item><item><title>India claims series win over Australia in Ellyse Perry's historic 350th international match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/cricket-perry-milestone-ruined-india-beats-australia-series/106373140</link><description>There is no fairytale for Ellyse Perry in her 350th international match as Smriti Mandhana stars to lead India to a series win over Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22813ee6d5f524e54f265a57bbca0060</guid></item><item><title>SA Labor mulls One Nation's rise as Liberals fight for campaign oxygen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/peter-malinauskas-aged-care-comments-analysis/106365716</link><description>In the final week before the election writs were issued, the SA Premier trained his sights on One Nation while the Liberals fought for oxygen. Is it a sign of the campaign ahead?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28d074d0aa52fc3f4a0dea405c714d5a</guid></item><item><title>Patients three times more likely to escape from Cumberland Hospital, data shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/escape-rates-cumberland-mental-health-three-times-nsw-average/106372126</link><description>Cumberland Hospital is under investigation after two patients who escaped from its care within 24 hours allegedly caused three people's deaths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b82d4403f4e38173fcf38362aff2421</guid></item><item><title>Daly Cherry-Evans and Sam Walker show promising signs as Eels down Roosters in NRL trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/nrl-cherry-evans-walker-combine-roosters-beaten-eels/106373172</link><description>Daly Cherry-Evans shows immediate signs of a strong combination with new Roosters halves mate Sam Walker in his first match for his new NRL club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">652b9b70e5dcf7d760e9ffc868488ab3</guid></item><item><title>After 20 years as the only town listed on the NSW State Heritage Registry, Braidwood is at a turning point</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/braidwood-nsw-heritage-listed-town-turning-point-future/106362514</link><description>A walk along the main street of this town is stepping in the footsteps of bushrangers, movie stars, artists and migrants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d656e7e9b2917ee3f3461fd7337804e</guid></item><item><title>Farmers on tenterhooks as trade deal with the European Union edges closer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/farmers-anxious-about-imminent-european-union-trade-deal/106348868</link><description>Australia is on the cusp of signing a landmark free trade deal with the EU, but will it come at a cost?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82cfad3ff6256c29ffde29e8e2faf1ba</guid></item><item><title>Johannes Høsflot Klæbo becomes first athlete to win six gold medals at one Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/winter-olympics-h%C3%B8sflot-kl%C3%A6bo-gold-medal-record/106373216</link><description>Johannes Høsflot Klæbo adds to his legacy as the greatest Winter Olympian of all-time by winning his sixth gold of these Olympics and 11th overall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">510c61228b9a195419d4335632366049</guid></item><item><title>Lighthouse keepers' cottages on Pine Islet to be demolished by reef authority</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/lighthouse-keepers-cottages-on-pine-islet-to-be-demolished/106368846</link><description>The remnants of a lighthouse station close to 100 years old on an island off the Mackay coast are set to be dismantled due to asbestos concerns, sparking fears important history will be lost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14976cd654b70d0078ff8d722e349265</guid></item><item><title>Massive goat trap in remote WA merges new technology and old ideas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/nine-kilometre-feral-goat-trap-murchison-station/106368604</link><description>When their station's fragile landscape needed protection from feral goats, Calum and Belinda Carruth seized on an idea that has become marvel of technology and pest management.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e4dab5480ecabc73e64d29b22876250</guid></item><item><title>Punk's boom began 50 years ago in Brisbane — and the scene is still thriving</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/50-years-of-punk-brisbane-the-saints-im-stranded/106363856</link><description>The Saints released their single "(I'm) Stranded" in 1976, kicking off the punk movement in Australia. So how did it all unfold?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ff7aba07da49374830b95165bce08cb</guid></item><item><title>Miner MMG puts forward alternative Rosebery tailings dam site in Exe Valley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/tailings-dam-new-approach-from-mmg/106372128</link><description>Global mining company MMG has long been seeking to build a third tailings storage dam at its mine on the Tasmanian west coast, in the face of strong opposition from environmentalists. It's now put forward an alternative which conservationists say they won't fight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aaf7bb61abe5724fd547643fb34b7f0e</guid></item><item><title>UK passport changes leave Australians with dual citizenship scrambling before border rules kick in</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/uk-passport-changes-dual-citizenship-scramble/106358092</link><description>There's been a last-minute scramble for some Australians with dual British or Irish citizenship, as new UK border rules come into force within days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0132530ce764a5648b973f42e492ac9f</guid></item><item><title>What is the bare minimum when it comes to packing kids' lunch boxes?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/easy-ways-to-pack-a-nutritious-healthy-school-lunch-box-/106358546</link><description>This is the bare minimum you should aim for to cover the nutritional basics for your children's school lunches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f3a4974aba1f9fb1b9b53bdb3f9662c</guid></item><item><title>Rap program aims to reduce reoffending among young people in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/prison-rap-workshop-reduce-reoffending/106367348</link><description>The musical genre is helping young offenders at a juvenile detention centre in southern NSW find their voices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">495a5e078b7fbe73bfa1d3968a35bef1</guid></item><item><title>Child psychiatrist Benjamin Wen indecently touched boys while doing 'puberty checks', court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/benjamin-wen-aaron-voon-trial-indecent-dealing/106370582</link><description>A former child psychiatrist who changed his name after being convicted of child exploitation touched young neurodivergent boys indecently at his practice, a Perth court hears. WARNING: This story contains details that may distress some readers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc7200b0badd5692276a5f2501ebaa54</guid></item><item><title>Eating disorder clinic to open near Mandurah as frustration grows over residential facility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/eating-disorder-clinic-to-open-near-mandurah/106371852</link><description>As an eating disorder clinic prepares to open its doors near Mandurah south of Perth, a residential eating disorder clinic is still in the planning stages despite being on the cards for years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2d5ed404ab21a793c92326ae065626b</guid></item><item><title>Minister reveals process has started to ban Hizb ut-Tahrir under new hate laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/minister-reveals-process-has-started-to-ban-hizb-ut-tahrir/106373384</link><description>Tony Burke has also provided an update on the cohort of 34 Australians seeking to leave a Syrian refugee camp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c92753a52307b8887ca37f5a769a82c</guid></item><item><title>Alisa Camplin-Warner calls for more funding after historic 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/australia-winter-olympics-2026-more-funding-alisa-camplin/106373014</link><description>Australia's chef de mission Alisa Camplin-Warner says the successful team deserve more funding for future Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f2634dfe4b1f91b79a479b5888bf5d3</guid></item><item><title>What the Bad Bunny in Australia tour means for Puerto Ricans far from home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/bad-bunny-australia-sydney-puerto-rico-live-concert-latino/106333062</link><description>This weekend Bad Bunny offers Australia a lesson in community, identity and how to belong without diluting your true self.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a17020b4ce51c2572315a7851d6ffd5</guid></item><item><title>Great-grandmother's garlic mushroom artwork puts new spin on managing food waste</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/wa-artist-turns-garlic-stems-old-teabags-into-art/106221554</link><description>Meet the country artist putting a slightly unexpected spin on garlic mushrooms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14ba8dc8bb3072d0a4f0467157374b25</guid></item><item><title>After a rare Supreme Court loss for Trump, here's his record with the bench</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/rare-loss-for-trump-before-the-supreme-court-his-record/106004520</link><description>Donald Trump was furious when the US Supreme Court ruled that his use of tariffs was illegal. Here's how earlier cases in that jurisdiction have fared.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2df862b3b607bed8e4ebdf16a4c5baec</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of 'toxic' poppies stolen from Victorian farm triggers health department alert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/police-investigate-poppy-plant-theft-from-ballarat-area-victoria/106373608</link><description>About 1,700 poppy plants grown for the pharmaceutical industry have been stolen from a regional property north-west of Melbourne, prompting a warning from the state health department.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b46a31ecf8cf87dbc14593028504000c</guid></item><item><title>Labor launches SA election campaign with land and housing promises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/labor-launches-sa-election-campaign-with-housing-policy/106373392</link><description>SA Labor's state election campaign launch is framed around housing, with the premier committing to a scheme for the purchase of land that would then be on-sold to the private sector for development.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f964067ff2a9ebef115ba389630f01ce</guid></item><item><title>How construction corruption is affecting housing affordability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/how-construction-corruption-is-affecting-housing-affordability/106373524</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab4d32700bd69f3f974cf74be9ad9ecc</guid></item><item><title>Nathan Cleary to risk missing first three Panthers games by challenging ban at NRL judiciary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/cleary-to-risk-missing-first-three-panthers-games-nrl-judiciary/106373966</link><description>Nathan Cleary will either be available to play Brisbane in round one or will miss the opening three rounds after Penrith decided to challenge his high tackle ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf8618780a44487cf3b6b5a9403ca8c3</guid></item><item><title>East West rail corridor cut by flooding amid heavy rain in northern SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/east-west-rail-corridor-cut-by-flooding-and-downpours/106373490</link><description>The cross-country rail line connecting Australia's east and west has been closed after heavy rain and flash flooding washed away significant sections of track, the corridor's manager says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fe5dd9fbf3f5419283e4e472a07177d</guid></item><item><title>USA beats Canada in overtime to end 46-year gold medal drought</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/winter-olympics-day-16-live-updates-indra-brown/106372016</link><description>Team USA beats Canada 2-1 in overtime to win the country's first men's ice hockey gold medal since 1980 in the last event of the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games, after Australian 16-year-old Indra Brown finishes fifth in the freeski halfpipe final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf4fef30a439dba6841e8f6da19912f4</guid></item><item><title>Coalition calls to criminalise assistance to ISIS-linked Australians seeking to return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/calls-to-criminalise-assistance-to-isis-linked-australians/106373812</link><description>The federal opposition proposes a new criminal offence to punish those who help Australians with links to Islamic State to return home, accusing the government of being complacent about the possible return of 34 wives and children of former fighters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22737ed2a7264d24948e5baf55fd9cb3</guid></item><item><title>Indra Brown's phenomenal fifth in freeski halfpipe at 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics a sign of her rapid rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/indra-brown-medal-freeski-halfpipe-2026-winter-olympics/106373982</link><description>Four months ago, Indra Brown had not even competed in a senior World Cup event. Her fifth-placed finish in her maiden Winter Olympics proves her meteoric rise is no fluke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29490707d1fa9c27fa01eea7ea13b644</guid></item><item><title>US Secret Service agents shoot dead armed man entering Donald Trump's Mar-a-Lago resort</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/man-shot-dead-unlawfully-entering-mar-a-lago/106374424</link><description>United States Secret Service agents shoot dead a man carrying a shotgun and a fuel can after he breaches the secure perimeter at Mar-a-Lago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84e4e7b7b6d6c48eb1badc0a20139a24</guid></item><item><title>Australian Antarctic Program relies on ice runway at Wilkins Aerodrome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/ice-runway-wilkins-aerodrome-australian-antarctic-program/106369198</link><description>The ice runway at Wilkins Aerodrome is a critical asset in the Australian Antarctic Program, but getting it ready for flights is nothing short of extreme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8c0ef758fa888d872b5a9505e1c4d00</guid></item><item><title>Micro-interventions to reduce stress in your day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/small-interventions-to-help-relieve-or-reduce-stress/106354572</link><description>Experts say we don't need to overhaul our lives to reduce our stress effectively. Here are some tips you can use right now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e0daa9fa68a0484a3e03818686a4267</guid></item><item><title>'Fearless, full of passion': Winter Games end with stunning ceremony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/winter-olympics-closing-ceremony-live-blog/106373682</link><description>The Milano Cortina Games are farewelled in style as the closing ceremony brings the 2026 Winter Olympics to an end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e3789f87af828de66fe9fd714a971af</guid></item><item><title>Simon Gordon's endometriosis surgeries were gynaecology's open secret. Now colleagues and patients are speaking out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/endometriosis-gynaecologist-simon-gordon-complaints-four-corners/106361726</link><description>Complaints had been made about this gynaecologist for years. Only when hospital management discovered that Four Corners was looking into his practice, did it start investigating further.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">546c584366e52080d406c7acee3f13ac</guid></item><item><title>Albanese changes tune on immigration and 'ISIS brides' as One Nation effect hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/one-nation-coalition-labor-isis-brides/106369478</link><description>A lot has been written about One Nation cannibalising the Coalition's vote, but less attention has been given to how the rise of the once-fringe party is also activating Labor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8211d1541a72fd4ec12b613f76841ed</guid></item><item><title>Energy watchdog to force retailers to offer struggling customers help in overhaul</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/australian-energy-regulator-flags-hardship-overhaul/106354338</link><description>Amid soaring prices and rising levels of energy hardship, the regulator wants to strengthen the protections for vulnerable customers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d59db989cd3aa84c99bfe1e25b0c8453</guid></item><item><title>Reducing inequality means taxing capital more — including inheritances</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/reducing-inequality-means-taxing-capital-more/106369480</link><description>Intergenerational inequality will only be dealt with by taxing the people that have the money, not by cutting the taxes of those who don't have it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44b5a5f423885727fd91c6525a98d8c9</guid></item><item><title>Home owners struggle as insurance premiums rise more than 50 per cent in five years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/home-insurance-premiums-increase-51-per-cent-in-five-years/106308824</link><description>Home insurance premiums continue to rise, with properties in natural disaster-prone areas paying the most.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26e5815da54050b913be5dc0278140a0</guid></item><item><title>Three-year wait for national criminal history checker makes parents 'sick'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/working-with-children-check-parents-sick/106370632</link><description>A key government commitment to protect children from sexual predators will not be "fully functional" for at least three years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ef6a6547bd96861340c2a14311ce45d</guid></item><item><title>Arab and Muslim nations condemn Mike Huckabee's suggestion Israel could claim biblical right to territory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/arab-muslim-nations-condemn-us-ambassador-comments/106374092</link><description>Mike Huckabee suggests Israel could claim a biblical right to territory far beyond its borders in the Middle East.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44a371a1a79bb3c2f684a2b60ce8bfc8</guid></item><item><title>Marshall Islands launches first universal basic income scheme to stop outward migration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/marshall-islands-launches-first-ever-ubi-scheme/106363230</link><description>Citizens of the Marshall Islands will receive "free money" as the government launches a world-first universal basic income scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8121cbae8fdb05c2899cdba536aa36b</guid></item><item><title>Andrew's arrest leaves questions for Sarah Ferguson but daughters could be protected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/the-future-of-sarah-ferguson-and-princesses-beatrice-and-eugenie/106368232</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's arrest has cast another long shadow over the York family. While his ex-wife, Sarah Ferguson, has vanished from public view, their daughters Beatrice and Eugenie face an uncertain future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98853504bf3e6f3631be59392fa5b973</guid></item><item><title>Film about new mother wins as Tropfest returns to Sydney with crowd of 35,000</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/nsw-tropfest-resurrected-results/106372220</link><description>Out of more than 700 entries, only 16 shorts made the premiere, but it was Sydney mum Lianne Mackessy who won the $50,000 award.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1394a433ae586fbcc962d8ff06197793</guid></item><item><title>School, university blindsided by child abuse allegations against teacher and academic Michael James Carty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/la-trobe-university-child-abuse-material-allegations-mildura/106373470</link><description>A Victorian teacher and casual academic has resigned after being charged with possessing and distributing child abuse material.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f3362300909352ca3f999eb81c93c88</guid></item><item><title>From OKCupid to community wedding: Jackie and Aimee's love story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/love-story-jackie-aimee-sydney-gay-lesbian-mardi-gras/106359548</link><description>Neither Jackie nor Aimee wanted something serious when they met, but a COVID-19 lockdown helped them take the plunge. Now they're married, and had to tackle the "in sickness and health" part of their vows sooner than they expected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8db8d9d1a454d94b7a7f004f04535e01</guid></item><item><title>Queensland real estate agents prepare for Anzac Day trading shutdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/qld-anzac-realestate-holiday-trading-restrictions/106369770</link><description>With Anzac Day falling on a Saturday this year, trading restrictions mean open houses and auctions will need to be rescheduled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0aceab4327f17cf886569b65d0667af0</guid></item><item><title>Eight rescued from floodwater as severe weather warning continues for western Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/severe-weather-flood-warning-western-queensland/106373516</link><description>A tropical low is sitting over the south-eastern part of the Northern Territory, bringing the risk of heavy rainfall to parts of western Queensland that are already flooding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e87f07279e89161db752ab6870018f7</guid></item><item><title>ASX slides, gold jumps and bitcoin slumps as Trump's new regime hits — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/106373894</link><description>The ASX lost ground across the session as concerns about the new tariff regime hit home and disappointing results were punished.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f6fd3ee9ed165ea66f5a57e1239ab74</guid></item><item><title>South Africa defeats India in T20 World Cup Super Eight by 76 runs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/south-africa-defeats-india-in-t20-world-cup-super-eight/106374804</link><description>South Africa bulldozed defending champions India by 76 runs in their Super Eight group one clash in the T20 World Cup, underlining their title credentials and sending a strong signal to their rivals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7ed58870a1d6e4bc5dc7eb957bf5427</guid></item><item><title>Kurdish official casts doubt on how quickly IS-linked Australians could try to return home again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/kurdish-official-puts-doubt-on-isis-families-return-to-australia/106374728</link><description>A Kurdish official says the Australian government's criticism of the group that attempted to return to Australia will frustrate the process of them trying to return again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c8edcef47063e6565ff9c22a9c3e567</guid></item><item><title>BAFTAs Film winners: Robert Aramayo wins best leading actor, Aussies miss out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/bafta-winners-key-moments-best-actor-upset/106368824</link><description>British actor Robert Aramayo has beaten frontrunners Timothée Chalamet and Leonardo DiCaprio to take the leading actor BAFTA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1433445240a650817b8aadb64bbfa76e</guid></item><item><title>Mount Gambier man given three months to live documents battle with rare lymphoma</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/mount-gambier-man-ben-whitehead-lymphoma-battle/106358942</link><description>Mount Gambier man Ben Whitehead's world changed when he was diagnosed with lymphoma and initially given three months to live, but he's doing his best to stay positive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5780e1ceb108b1454083b68992c2b911</guid></item><item><title>Nauiyu / Daly River flood evacuees assess damage after returning home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/daly-river-nauiyu-flooding-evacuees-return-home/106372304</link><description>Flood evacuees from the remote community of Nauiyu / Daly River have returned to their homes to survey the damage after two weeks hunkered down in Darwin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acd3df69dd405a5a3476f655f333c1ba</guid></item><item><title>Matildas Sam Kerr and Mary Fowler receive boost before Asian Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/sam-kerr-mary-fowler-matildas-asian-cup-boost/106374902</link><description>Australia's two superstar Matildas will fly home for the Women's Asian Cup in buoyant mood after Mary Fowler made her first start in 315 days and Sam Kerr proved once again she's the queen of the FA Cup with a smartly taken goal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28734bf459e7285c48e325391e7635f3</guid></item><item><title>Michael Rowland to leave ABC after 39 years in front of camera</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/michael-rowland-to-leave-the-abc/106365868</link><description>After almost four decades in front of the camera, former News Breakfast host Michael Rowland announces he is leaving the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">435cad640706a8aa58623b48aede6bf0</guid></item><item><title>Australia's golden 2026 Winter Olympic Games could just be the latest step towards sustained glory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/australia-s-most-successful-winter-olympic-games/106374682</link><description>Australia's medal-filled 2026 Winter Olympics campaign will live long in the memory. Not as the peak of this sunburned nation's snowy achievements, though. Just the beginning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">159f4c3efe19b2b2305545869a4455ae</guid></item><item><title>Disposable cameras in focus for Perth photography project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/disposable-camera-project-perth-northbridge-common/106337692</link><description>A unique community exhibition in Perth is celebrating the "messiness and spontaneity" of the disposable camera.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61bfde116a91127ff739dc100ce528a5</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Eileen Gu reveals grief after gold medal, closing ceremony ends Games — quick hits from the final day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-closing-ceremony-eileen-gu/106374312</link><description>Chinese superstar Eileen Gu claimed gold while nursing the pain of loss, as Sweden's curling "circus" team triumphed. Here are the quick hits from the final day of the Milano Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d33e973156f3fd80db3a043280e566b4</guid></item><item><title>'Tough road ahead' for Burleigh Bears player Jacek McLaurin hospitalised by tackle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/burleigh-bears-jacek-mclaurin-hospitalised-tackle/106374948</link><description>Burleigh Bears outside back Jacek McLaurin was rushed to Princess Alexandra Hospital in Brisbane on Saturday and remains in a critical condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c604450f3e3601d08b95551b7120f53d</guid></item><item><title>For the Olympics to remain relevant, it is essential it embraces sustainability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/olympic-games-relevant-sustainability/106374848</link><description>Olympic Games chief executive Christophe Dubi tells ABC Sport that in order for the Olympics to remain relevant, it simply has to embrace sustainable practices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e0b88796cec3f7d546896144f8e3b64</guid></item><item><title>Taliban vows retaliation after Pakistan claims to have killed at least 70 in air strikes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/pakistan-launches-deadly-strikes-against-afghanistan/106374946</link><description>Pakistan's military claims to have killed at least 70 militants in air strikes against neighbouring Afghanistan, but the Taliban in Afghanistan says this is false.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b4675f201c79a38acbb89aaefb31600</guid></item><item><title>Mexican army kills 'El Mencho', leader of powerful Jalisco New Generation cartel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/cartel-boss-el-mencho-killed-by-mexican-army/106375040</link><description>Powerful Mexican drug lord Nemesio Oseguera Cervantes, known as "El Mencho", is killed in a military raid, sparking a wave of unrest and violence in several Mexican states.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f04b5e4339182072b655d11a426e6f02</guid></item><item><title>Police scour bushland for kidnapped Sydney man Chris Baghsarian</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/police-search-glenorie-bushland-for-kidnapped-chris-baghsarian/106374950</link><description>Police officers are scouring dense bushland in Sydney's north-west for the missing 85-year-old grandfather, following a police operation overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9131aac5977e0d02c076f3c6cbd5a249</guid></item><item><title>Adam Scott finishes fourth in US PGA Tour event at Riviera Golf Course</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/adam-scott-finishes-fourth-pga-tour-riviera/106375616</link><description>Adam Scott produces a terrific final round to finish fourth in the US PGA Tour event at Riviera Golf Course.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eba74d600890ce8c0e08794152d28558</guid></item><item><title>Arson attacks in Mexico after 'El Mencho' killed by military</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/arson-attacks-in-mexico-after-el-mencho-killed-by-military/106375696</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f7676673ebeabec1577f8eb76111ebe</guid></item><item><title>US and Iran to meet for third round of nuclear talks in Geneva</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/iran-and-us-to-meet-for-third-round-of-nuclear-talks/106375208</link><description>The third round of talks between the US and Iran comes amid growing tensions between the long-time adversaries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e61218b9a7d0b8d4c421e180a8829081</guid></item><item><title>Pole vaulter Kurtis Marschall becomes the fourth Australian to clear 6 metres in pole vault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/pole-vaulter-kurtis-marschall-pole-vault-six-metres/106375924</link><description>Pole vaulter Kurtis Marschall becomes the fourth Australian to clear 6 metres, achieving the landmark feat at an indoor meet in France.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9983679537b65ffe8d863175db0464ca</guid></item><item><title>Scone breaks daily rainfall record in 2 hours but farmers say more is needed to rid region of drought</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/scone-breaks-daily-rainfall-record-in-two-hours/106374816</link><description>A NSW town in the grips of a dry spell breaks its daily rainfall record, but farmers say much more rain is needed to save the season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d447d62e4f137be8e55140c66db199c</guid></item><item><title>ACT Brumbies keeping cool after historic win over Crusaders in Christchurch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/act-brumbies-keeping-cool-after-historic-win-over-crusaders/106375922</link><description>ACT Brumbies coach Stephen Larkham has said his team "won't get ahead of ourselves" after producing a stunning win over the Crusaders in Christchurch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdf53d7337654e9cd6c959c369163e56</guid></item><item><title>Younger people reflect on untapped 'wealth of knowledge' in intergenerational friendships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/intergenerational-friendships-bridge-divide/106360088</link><description>Headlines often highlight the divisions between older and younger Australians, but research suggests intergenerational friendships can help to reduce age-based discrimination in both directions, while offering other benefits.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1e12bd41d56796981258d041fed071b</guid></item><item><title>Heavy rain soaks the Barkly and Central Australia, closing roads and inundating cattle stations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/nt-rain-barkly-central-australia-roads-closed-stations-inundated/106375970</link><description>A tropical low circling over south-eastern parts of the Northern Territory is continuing to bring damaging winds and heavy local rainfall in the Simpson and parts of the Barkly and Tanami areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6db61caa4b48c362f565819a981adb8a</guid></item><item><title>Denmark and Greenland reject Trump's offer to send naval hospital ship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/denmark-greenland-reject-trump-offer-naval-hospital-ship/106376252</link><description>Denmark and its territory Greenland reject Donald Trump's offer to send a naval hospital ship to the Arctic island coveted by the US leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da6be898edb441a8825b6acb38f78a19</guid></item><item><title>Neighbouring farmers say overwhelming fire risk from Lake Magenta Nature Reserve in WA's south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/farmers-raise-concerns-over-lake-magenta-nature-reserve-fire/106370154</link><description>WA farmer Doug Giles has warned that parts of Lake Magenta Nature Reserve haven't been burned in 25 years, raising fears of a dangerous fire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2867bfbdd2ae8c4f834614c7020a00e2</guid></item><item><title>What worked for Milano Cortina may not work for Brisbane 2032, but this is the new Olympic norm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/winter-olympics-2026-dispersed-brisbane-2032/106374852</link><description>The 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics Games was the first to follow a dispersed model. With Brisbane 2032 also set to have this set up, there are plenty of things to be aware of.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78a78efc5fe1523a1302d7511d5ec830</guid></item><item><title>Man pleads not guilty over alleged home invasion shooting police say followed road rage incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/noah-wrigley-road-rage-home-invasion-shooting-pleads-not-guilty/106375326</link><description>A 25-year-old man pleads not guilty to causing grievous bodily harm in the Hobart Magistrates Court, following an alleged home invasion shooting incident last month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77a8f7793b9022616fbcb377ee0c9fe2</guid></item><item><title>MAGA figure tells Australian conservatives Angela Merkel did more damage to Germany's fabric than Nazis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/advance-lobby-group-conference-centre-right-mass-immigration/106371720</link><description>Benjamin Harnwell, the "international editor" of Steve Bannon's War Room podcast, says centre-right politicians have "betrayed" the West by supporting "mass immigration".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c036dfffbc94d642235a37ef1b6e3399</guid></item><item><title>Wayne Klingberg avoids jail over crash that killed his employee in rollover near Hamley Bridge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/wayne-klingberg-sentenced-for-killing-employee-in-rollover/106373394</link><description>A man has been spared jail time after his "substandard" driving resulted in a crash that caused the death of his passenger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d7bc8a2fcdc95df3c711a87a46252bb</guid></item><item><title>What experts want you to know about endometriosis, diagnosis and surgery as treatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/endometriosis-surgery-treatment-explained-four-corners/106375904</link><description>Allegations about endometriosis surgery have alarmed experts and distressed women living with the condition. Here's what to know about the chronic disease that affects about one in seven Australian women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbaf9bd04ca59cd113da66ade8586963</guid></item><item><title>Portion of IS-linked Australians in Syria could resettle in NSW, premier says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/is-linked-australian-women-children-syria-could-return-nsw/106376110</link><description>Up to a third of Australian families of Islamic State fighters currently in a Syrian refugee camp could resettle in NSW if they eventually return to Australia, the state premier has said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10c755a6432a4fea5ac88890cfacacf3</guid></item><item><title>More details emerge after man shot dead by Secret Service at Mar-a-Lago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/mar-a-lago-trump-secret-service-shooting/106375912</link><description>Austin Tucker Martin was seen at the Mar-a-Lago resort's north gate at about 1:30am on Sunday, local time. He has been described as being from a family of "big Trump supporters".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1045783573ad7d46acaca41e63ff72fb</guid></item><item><title>Ex-police officer Jonathan Andrew Beard cites 'cop's sixth sense' over allege knock and run assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/jonathan-beard-kings-cross-commander-assault-hearing/106376466</link><description>A former senior Sydney police officer accused of assaulting two men with a baseball bat who played a drunken game of knock and run at his house has told a court he "wasn't there to play" with home invaders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67cb7bed6b105f41f70b392fee95ea8a</guid></item><item><title>Two men charged after man stabbed during confrontation in Kambalda</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/two-men-charged-stabbing-kambalda-wa-goldfields/106376558</link><description>Two men are charged and another is flown to Perth with life-threatening stab wounds, after a weekend altercation in Kambalda.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a765daef73dcbfd6cf5eecd71ab51d08</guid></item><item><title>Darcy Moore downplays Collingwood's injury woes, Patrick Dangerfield optimistic on Jeremy Cameron's health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/afl-darcy-moore-patrick-dangerfield-downplay-pies-cats-injuries/106376972</link><description>Several of Collingwood's defensive stalwarts have suffered interrupted preseasons, but skipper Darcy Moore isn't concerned just yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bf987fc7214ac5f9d00e1721ab4492b</guid></item><item><title>Nine newspapers says printing The Age and The Australian Financial Review in Tasmania 'no longer sustainable'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/nine-newspaper-no-longer-printed-in-tasmania/106375940</link><description>Rising production costs and growing digital audiences are behind the company's decision to no longer print and distribute its newspapers, which includes The Age and The Financial Review, in Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25cae1fca86ac4853c65b1e371f919cc</guid></item><item><title>SA pastoralists receive more than 60mm of rain in 24 hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/pastoralists-rain-drought-destocking-south-australia/106375318</link><description>South Australian pastoralists are preparing to buy livestock after the weekend's downpours brought more than 60 millimetres to some areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a993832dd084d2ff3fd4c53c14abfc0b</guid></item><item><title>Cyber attack takes major chicken processor Hazeldenes offline leaving businesses without meat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/cyber-attack-takes-major-chicken-processor-hazeldenes-offline/106376184</link><description>A cyber attack at Hazeldenes chicken processing plant in central Victoria has stalled production and left butchers and pubs across the state without chicken.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad7275d3ac33e822d86835f8e8ca6b93</guid></item><item><title>Trump Tower deal set for Gold Coast as developer pushes against 'misconceptions'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/trump-tower-deal-signed-for-gold-coast-says-developer/106376738</link><description>Plans are afoot for a $1.5 billion, 91-storey Trump Tower in Surfers Paradise, which would be one of Australia's tallest towers if it goes ahead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18c1cdee0af4cce35ab4ac6f53e53ee0</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man jailed for 20 years for fatally stabbing his ex-wife in 2023</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/van-thanh-vu-jailed-20-years-murder-ex-wife/106375068</link><description>A 73-year-old man who fatally stabbed his former partner in their kitchen in 2023 has been sentenced in the ACT Supreme Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">046788bd6980dd463533c9c0710036bc</guid></item><item><title>Death of Kelly T'Hart inspires shake up of WA driving laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/wa-new-driving-bans-for-people-charged-with-driving-offences/106376430</link><description>Tougher WA driving laws are expected to be introduced to parliament after a drunk driver, who was charged with killing a 32-year-old, was allowed to drive just two months after the incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">865da2fafb865e027a4d14fd8445adfa</guid></item><item><title>Former UK PM Gordon Brown urges police to investigate if Andrew used RAF bases to meet Epstein</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/brown-urges-andrew-police-probe-over-epstein-raf-bases/106375734</link><description>Former British prime minister Gordon Brown urges British police to investigate whether Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor used taxpayer-funded jets and Royal Air Force bases to meet with convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b76c410513462e9b98bba684536256cd</guid></item><item><title>Reo Te Whetu Marama Marsh given life sentence for murdering Mary Benedito on Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/qld-court-reo-te-whetu-marama-marsh-mary-benedito/106375280</link><description>Reo Te Whetu Marama Marsh, who was then 34 years old, was charged In November 2021 over Mary Benedito's death after she was found unresponsive in a Southport apartment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a561aa52664c78d8fb78e4dba685c3e</guid></item><item><title>These four salads are tasty and substantial meals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/these-four-salads-are-tasty-and-substantial-meals/106363054</link><description>If you’re after a healthy and summery dinner, these salads are a meal in a bowl and will tempt even the salad avoiders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b43ee09ed451f0e7f6420ed3472fbdff</guid></item><item><title>Teenager says he was verbally abused and punched in alleged antisemitic attack at scouts event in Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/vic-police-investigate-antisemitic-attack/106377024</link><description>A teenager says he was verbally abused and punched at a scouts event in regional Victoria for wearing a kippah and Israeli flag.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d7cc882bf918f3859f8a7bb511e82c8</guid></item><item><title>Richmond forward Mykelti Lefau suspended for two matches over drink driving charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/afl-mykelti-lefau-suspended-two-matches-drink-driving-charge/106377438</link><description>Mykelti Lefau is banned for two matches after a drink driving charge that will see him miss a pre-season clash as well as round one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c4ea2f9071e3790d91763c3026a1489</guid></item><item><title>Road closures as heavy rain floods Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/road-closures-as-heavy-rain-floods-alice-springs/106377556</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">231ee50c7ede81508f5c869a843b6104</guid></item><item><title>Kalgoorlie-Boulder Airport's potential $100m redevelopment on agenda as FIFO activity soars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/kalgoorlie-boulder-airport-expansion-fifo-boom/106368120</link><description>A long-awaited feasibility study investigating the potential for a major expansion, estimated to cost up to $100 million, at one of Western Australia's busiest regional airports, is set to be delivered this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec57aef109eed981158c46ca0aaefcf7</guid></item><item><title>Muslim Australians fear rising Islamophobia as Ramadan begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/muslim-australians-fear-rising-islamophobia-as-ramadan-begins/106362392</link><description>Muslim Australians fear Islamophobia is rising following comments made by One Nation leader Pauline Hanson and in the wake of recent threats against one of Australia's largest mosques.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b723dd3a0916898353b26e7d5ff39e4</guid></item><item><title>Killing of Mexico's biggest drug lord 'El Mencho' sparks chaos among cartel members</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/el-mencho-mexico-drug-cartels-leader-death-sparks-chaos/106376506</link><description>Nemesio Oseguera Cervantes died after a gunfight with military personnel. Hours later, vehicles were set alight, roads blocked and shopfronts torched as retaliation in eight states.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de6870093b1b45c610786d67eaf2b099</guid></item><item><title>UK government quietly updates passport rules for dual citizens — again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/more-uk-passport-rule-changes-electronic-travel-authorisation/106377682</link><description>Travellers with both an expired UK passport, issued in 1989 or later, as well as a valid passport from a country that can issue an Electronic Travel Authorisation, may now be allowed to enter the UK.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bc4865b7fce78befb4706098bab1927</guid></item><item><title>Lesbian group takes fight to Federal Court in bid to exclude transgender women from events</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/lesbian-group-transgender-exemption-federal-court/106375606</link><description>A Victorian-based lesbian group is seeking an exemption to the Sex Discrimination Act so it can legally discriminate against transgender women when it holds public events.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86011188a6449ec4a3f53945d7ead4da</guid></item><item><title>Childcare chief executive not aware of number of breaches at centres, Brisbane senate inquiry told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/qld-childcare-senate-inquiry-breaches/106375162</link><description>The Affinity Education Group chief executive Glen Hurley told the Brisbane inquiry — which is examining the quality and safety of early childhood education and care systems — he would have to take the question on notice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">307b567cdbdeeca318c6165e049f272d</guid></item><item><title>Bodycam footage shows tactical police officers using force on a handcuffed hit-and-run driver</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/body-camera-tactical-police-force-hit-and-run-driver/106377912</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">840067a62466a8723d5a50ce3878a332</guid></item><item><title>Police bodycam footage captures 'retributive' force used on St Edmund's College hit-and-run driver</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/act-tayler-hazell-police-bodycam-footage/106375728</link><description>Body-camera footage released by the ACT Supreme Court shows tactical police officers using force on a handcuffed hit-and-run driver outside St Edmund's College.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bc70d8008462d11e48f5dbd54482057</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106377930</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cd201e4cab12a1e8d9109dec7af0e4f</guid></item><item><title>Toddler found unresponsive at Sydney day care may have died from a bacterial infection, inquest hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/nsw-arianna-maragol-coronial-inquest-family-speaks-bacterial/106377282</link><description>A baby who died after being found unresponsive at a Sydney day care may have had a bacterial infection, an inquest has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfdde31cd10ef6f3a585059f10bac008</guid></item><item><title>SA Police to scour mine shafts in renewed search for missing Andamooka woman Trisha Graf</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/sa-police-scour-mine-shafts-search-for-missing-trisha-graf/106377578</link><description>Police will scour several mine shafts near the outback South Australian town of Andamooka in the latest search for missing mother Trisha Graf.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3ebd687d259d0790dfd4051686dccaa</guid></item><item><title>Arvind Ajay Singh extradited from Fiji to Sunshine Coast on rape charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/arvind-ajay-singh-returns-to-sunshine-coast-faces-rape-charge/106375712</link><description>A Fijian national charged over the alleged rape of a child four years ago returns to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3bfb5887669e3fe34e8697fcf80e78e</guid></item><item><title>Tabatha Badger angling to replace outgoing Greens senator Peter Whish-Wilson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/tabatha-badger-senate-tilt-to-replace-peter-whish-wilson/106377994</link><description>The ABC understands Tasmanian Greens MP Tabatha Badger is among the names vying to replace outgoing federal senator Peter Whish-Wilson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70b94d5a4e222251fa22d9491cae6035</guid></item><item><title>The Lion King musical makes its return to Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/the-lion-king-musical-makes-its-return-to-sydney/106378128</link><description>The Lion King musical makes its return to Sydney in April with the cast and crew opening its doors to rehearsals for a sneak peak.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cd895f5c24c035246533ab2c99be933</guid></item><item><title>Former youth worker Geoffrey Guest pleads not guilty to historical child sex abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/former-youth-worker-pleads-not-guilty-historical-abuse-charges/106376946</link><description>Geoffrey John Guest is standing trial in Cairns after being charged with the abuse of a child in the 1970s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be44341c902da3949f56ff003343bcbf</guid></item></channel></rss>