<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 19:41:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NRL finals updates: Cronulla Sharks defeat Canberra Raiders 32-12 in semifinal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/nrl-finals-live-updates-canberra-raiders-cronulla-sharks/105780662</link><description>An out-of-place nose doesn't hurt Joe Tapine as much as Canberra's NRL finals exit, but he hopes the pain of defeat will drive them to greater things next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2af84c91f7e4b5942651511648ab086f</guid></item><item><title>Republicans seize on Charlie Kirk's death to crack down on liberal dissent that puts freedom of speech 'in peril'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/republicans-trump-seize-on-charlie-kirk-death-to-target-liberals/105785372</link><description>The Trump administration saw an opportunity to crack down on liberal groups in the wake of the death of conservative activist Charlie Kirk. But not all conservatives are onboard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e9d2990ada472892c8d338b81a74b82</guid></item><item><title>What is 'Solastalgia' and how are climate-affected communities tackling it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/climate-change-anxiety-first-nations-communities-respond/105793766</link><description>If you're overwhelmed by emissions targets, climate change and environmental collapse, start small and look to First Nations practices to help your wellbeing and the world around you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bff8375209835a394c77e6936900b17</guid></item><item><title>Antinatalists say human suffering, and climate change, makes having children unethical. Are they right?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/antinatalism-child-free-climate-change-human-suffering-baby/105695328</link><description>Elon Musk believes the collapsing birth rate is humanity's biggest danger. But antinatalists argue having kids is little more than a procreational Ponzi scheme, and the risks are real.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28999cb939ddfbe63b4a8339d72f435e</guid></item><item><title>Asia's protests grew from social media where misinformation also spread</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/nepal-indonesia-gen-z-social-media-misinformation/105779038</link><description>These movements may be separated by time, distance and language, but they were all born on social media, led by a new generation of activists fed up with the old systems of corruption and nepotism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">553dda439e393b87eb7b6bc4eff754a9</guid></item><item><title>What makes China confident enough to ban microchips made by US firm Nvidia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/what-makes-china-confident-to-ban-nvdia-microchips/105795486</link><description>Beijing's decision this week to ban Chinese companies from using microchips made by US firm Nvidia indicates the country is increasingly confident about replacing them with domestically produced chips, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c451e4e0710bc1516100c22ae7e23289</guid></item><item><title>Pirate attacks and sea robberies surge in key South-East Asian shipping lane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/piracy-sea-robberies-rise-malacca-strait-asia/105736740</link><description>Piracy and sea robberies are increasing in the strategic straits of Malacca and Singapore, which could have implications for Australian imports and exports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2b3b37fb5cc2fee69c406b2aa0ccdc5</guid></item><item><title>Former nurse shares devastating experience of attempts to get urgent cancer surgery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/hospital-logjam-blamed-for-delays-to-cancer-surgeries/105724218</link><description>Karenne Mosley was diagnosed with aggressive uterine cancer in March. She was booked in for surgery twice but is now in palliative care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">322dfad9007ac7be6793c351ff5df832</guid></item><item><title>'We should kill him': AI chatbot encourages Australian man to murder his father</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/ai-chatbot-encourages-australian-man-to-murder-his-father/105793930</link><description>Experts are calling for new regulations on artificial intelligence chatbots, after a triple j hack investigation uncovered a disturbing example of a chatbot encouraging a man to murder his father while engaging in paedophilic role-play.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">046595a368ebd4097697482ef340ab85</guid></item><item><title>Scrubs is getting a reboot just in time for the hospital procedural revival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/scrubs-reboot-the-pitt-cheat-sheet/105793612</link><description>In a sea of hospital-based TV, long-running sitcoms Scrubs is often highlighted as one of the most realistic options. Now the reboot has been confirmed, and off the back of The Pitt’s big Emmy wins, we look back at the beloved show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f7cc2efbfa7b3a4841ebb5cb0fb4b85</guid></item><item><title>Chronic pain makes life hell for kids, but it's impacting work productivity as well</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/chronic-pain-in-children-parent-carer-productivity-impacts/105789208</link><description>Chronic pain has devastating effects on those who suffer from it, including children, but it has wider impacts and they are costing Australia billions, a survey has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc7072c1bd6ae66e4eb5c779aecdb466</guid></item><item><title>Street artist Rone's new 90-metre mural a visual love letter to Geelong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/tyrone-rone-wright-new-mural-captures-geelong-faces/105762354</link><description>The faces of 14 people will be immortalised in an enormous mural on the side of a new building in Geelong by locally born, globally renowned artist Rone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28ac13e735d6c51ed4a4df9593e87271</guid></item><item><title>How skateboarding became a family affair for Townsville single dad Jay MacAskill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/qld-skateboarding-becomes-family-single-dad/105774582</link><description>For almost eight years, Jay MacAskill's skateboard was collecting dust at home — until his daughter found the skate park around the corner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ab26eabc2acb19d8f736401a36cb5d2</guid></item><item><title>Jay MacAskill and his daughters — Skylah and Ava — are building a strong bond over a new found love of skateboarding.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/jay-builds-skate-family-with-two-daughters/105795194</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bf33bd10464222df6899d961b643aff</guid></item><item><title>Addressing Australia's housing crisis is a mammoth task. Is making housing a human right the answer?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/housing-human-right-law-act-analysis-what-does-that-mean/105797726</link><description>The ACT government has passed legislation enshrining housing as a human right. What does that mean, and should other states follow?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ddf114810459395b3a99bce81b68b05</guid></item><item><title>Republicans warn Anthony Albanese of 'punitive measures' over Palestinian recognition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/republicans-warn-australia-over-palestinian-statehood/105798830</link><description>As Anthony Albanese touches down in New York ahead of the UN General Assembly, Republicans issue a warning against formally recognising Palestinian statehood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebe5c9ff00ace1a2ffdeee5ad7a40913</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberals' star candidate in spotlight after AI algal bloom 'admin error'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/ai-liv-golf-algal-bloom-comments-put-frank-pangallo-in-spotlight/105787864</link><description>When Frank Pangallo announced he was joining the Liberal party, he vowed to put the blowtorch on a first-term government riding high in the polls. But barely four weeks later, the blowtorch is firmly on Pangallo instead, writes Leah MacLennan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bd3524d93d528173e52862abfbcd325</guid></item><item><title>Women celebrate vintage glam, self-love and healthy body image with pin-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/women-embrace-modern-pin-up-culture/105574140</link><description>Women are embracing modern pin-up culture as a way to express confidence and joy in their own skin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccb73a345a28b69e567f342e489c58be</guid></item><item><title>Baby dies after ute hits Jeep on the Pacific Motorway at Gaven on the Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/qld-m1-baby-death-gaven-crash-gold-coast-police/105798930</link><description>Police say initial investigations indicate a silver Jeep was parked on the side of the northbound M1, near the Smith Street on ramp, when it was struck by a grey utility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">273eb30fbfa76f395ab5069c0ef654d9</guid></item><item><title>The Adelaide Crows have been the powerhouse of the AFLW. Now they are being challenged</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/aflws-rapid-evolution-has-been-a-double-edged-sword-for-crows/105798110</link><description>The AFLW's rapid evolution has been a double-edged sword for Adelaide, which is the most successful club in competition history, having won three of the eight premierships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fca7baecebf0b1b986bd2de9e15eea87</guid></item><item><title>Man formally charged with murdering TikTok influencer Sana Yousaf in Pakistan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/sana-yousaf-murder-pakistan-man-indicted/105798922</link><description>A Pakistani court charges a 22-year-old man with murder for shooting a teenage social media influencer, Sana Yousaf, after refusing his offer of friendship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1eb11b4917ab879362f102711a80d0c5</guid></item><item><title>Inside Ninga Mia, a forgotten community in the shadow of Kalgoorlie the city of gold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/ninga-mia-kalgoorlie-mining-aboriginal-reserve-homelessness-gold/105774862</link><description>There's an eerie silence in Ninga Mia, a once thriving community on the edge of Kalgoorlie. The Aboriginal reserve is a microcosm of the cycle of displacement endured by many First Nations people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eafa5daeccecbae05c7c9ef093e72c5</guid></item><item><title>Cockchafer worm wreaking havoc on West Australian grain crops</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/cockchafer-pest-costing-wa-grain-farmers-thousands/105783068</link><description>Growers and scientists have teamed up in a bid to combat the rapidly increasing population of the voracious pest, which is devastating crops in WA's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a33788626f5c22861ceddd417b44c658</guid></item><item><title>Government has not set 2035 renewables target, downplays 90 per cent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/government-yet-to-set-2035-renewables-target/105798906</link><description>In New York for the UN summit, Energy Minister Chris Bowen declines to offer a renewable energy target for 2035 after the Climate Change Authority projected more than 90 per cent would be needed to hit its recommended emissions target.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4880a6213f11733719ca49464957e58</guid></item><item><title>Symbio Wildlife Park emu chicks being raised by hens after father walks out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/symbio-wildlife-park-abandoned-emus-raised-by-chickens/105795380</link><description>Birds of a different feather are flocking together at a wildlife park in New South Wales, where the chickens have been given the responsibility of being foster parents to a pair of abandoned emu chicks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6846407eac281053e23e77b5a99c248</guid></item><item><title>Koori Court marks 20 years in Mildura as Victoria approaches treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/twenty-years-of-koori-justice-in-mildura-victorias-north-west/105784288</link><description>Mildura marks two decades since its Koori Court opened, as Victoria sees mixed results in the push to reduce Indigenous incarceration and offending rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d57275cbeb1abf5d81f15d9fb2c32b08</guid></item><item><title>UK fighter jets begin NATO air defence mission over Poland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/uk-fighter-jets-begin-nato-air-defence-mission-over-poland/105798964</link><description>British fighter jets fly their first NATO air defence unit over Poland as part of a mission to bolster the Western alliance's defences following a Russian drone incursion this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c68471ff237392537d4d015d338c7ef</guid></item><item><title>Crocodiles on the move in northern Australia as breeding season arrives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/crocodiles-on-the-move-breeding-season-arrives-north-australia/105766898</link><description>It's crocodile breeding season and at one central Queensland farm, the drama is on par with a reality television dating show as keepers try to work out the best pairings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab50329a1039618670babc23784c4980</guid></item><item><title>Life on Aboriginal reserve remembered by Carnarvon traditional owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/aboriginal-reserve-memories-carnarvon-traditional-owners/105510728</link><description>In 1975, an anthropologist wrote his thesis on Carnarvon's rich Aboriginal reserve. Decades later, traditional owners revisit the work to contribute to "big truth-telling" documentary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecf8bb607751e84f71648e4dfa5cd44a</guid></item><item><title>Australian-born singer drops out of Russian-hosted Intervision song contest after 'political pressure'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australian-born-singer-drops-out-of-russian-hosted-song-contest/105799020</link><description>Vassy dropped out of the contest at the last minute after coming under what Russian organisers said was "unprecedented political pressure from the government of Australia".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6f53824a2ed40b9ae66bd7ebdb25e1a</guid></item><item><title>How Brisbane, Hawthorn, Geelong and Collingwood stay on top of the AFL world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/afl-analysis-geelong-brisbane-collingwood-hawthorn/105797710</link><description>The 21st century has been dominated by four AFL clubs — Geelong, Hawthorn, Collingwood and Brisbane — but there's no single secret to their success.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0de8258f95182f2d73692053694b3fa</guid></item><item><title>Penola High School's agriculture program revives community and enrolments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/penola-high-school-ag-program-revives-falling-enrolments/105787042</link><description>Cory O'Connor's three-week teaching placement turned around his hometown high school. Now he's receiving an award for the agriculture program he started there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">800678cadea15a18ec482186c893d046</guid></item><item><title>Explaining Aussie driving culture to make roads safer for recent arrivals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/safe-driving-temporary-migrants-short-stay-visa-roads/105752446</link><description>Driving a car or riding a bike may be essential for temporary migrants studying or working in Australia, but hook turns, wombat crossings, and roundabouts can be unfamiliar territory. Here are some locals working to change that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7459dc32dfaf72a6f90efe2c1755b962</guid></item><item><title>Pistachios are the latest food trend and a lot of work goes into predicting what's next</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/pistachios-are-everywhere-but-how-was-that-decided/105680106</link><description>Pistachios have become the food flavour of the season, and a lot of work goes into predicting what the next big thing will be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5eba132db24b42ad0a82c8f2ec02621</guid></item><item><title>Cats star Tyson Stengle desperate to win second AFL premiership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/afl-grand-final-geelong-cats-brisbane-lions-tyson-stengle/105799288</link><description>Three years after Tyson Stengle capped off his remarkable AFL career resurrection with a premiership, the Geelong forward believes a second premiership would hold greater significance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4c3712d165c2a42a93ac12de61b5a9d</guid></item><item><title>Penrith Panthers hammer Canterbury-Bankstown Bulldogs to keep NRL premiership five-peat hopes alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/nrl-semifinal-live-updates-bulldogs-vs-panthers/105799314</link><description>Penrith has crushed Canterbury-Bankstown after a phenomenal first half to claim a 46-26 victory, keeping their hopes of a fifth-consecutive NRL premiership alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73ad6ec14b559cb36a842edc842a9431</guid></item><item><title>Demons defeat Eagles as Crows, Giants, Lions and Saints score AFLW wins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/aflw-demons-eagles-giants-swans-bulldogs-lions-saints-tigers/105799148</link><description>The Demons' Eden Zanker enjoys a day out with five goals to help defeat Daisy Pearce's young Eagles squad by 51 points, while the Crows launch a final-quarter fightback to get past the Suns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da04417bb1dcf00ff78c602f53360a77</guid></item><item><title>How to clean out your wardrobe as the seasons change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/how-to-spring-clean-wardobe-clean-out/105780140</link><description>It's the kind of task that can seem overwhelming, but the change of season is the perfect opportunity to review what's in your wardrobe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf9c7f0a36323b3457588962f5d0b0b0</guid></item><item><title>Optus CEO confirms further customer report calls, service outage at NSW-SA border.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/optus-ceo-confirms-further-customer-report-calls,/105799496</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99f2ad74ac543864780c38476c5a3384</guid></item><item><title>Dayne Zorko fined by AFL for targeting Mason Cox's glasses in Lions' win over Magpies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/afl-brisbane-lions-collingwood-magpies-dayne-zorko-mason-cox/105799528</link><description>Brisbane Lions stalwart Dayne Zorko is punished by the AFL after he ripped off Mason Cox's glasses during their fiery preliminary final clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34b6f6c464fdb14a9fdb5f312f87feab</guid></item><item><title>Penrith's win over Canterbury was a reminder there is no team like them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/panthers-bulldogs-nrl-finals-cleary-galvin-too/105799368</link><description>Canterbury is a team built in Penrith's image, but the Panthers served Canterbury a stark reminder that there can be only one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43391fdd3b75eadfd140d1ee7f293931</guid></item><item><title>Multiple people hospitalised after bus and car crash on busy M2 in Sydney's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/multiple-people-hospitalised-car-bus-crash-m2-macquarie-park-nsw/105799552</link><description>A bus driver is among 11 people hospitalised after a bus and a car crash on the M2 at Macquarie Park in what emergency responders described as a "complex incident".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d57f90b97722bfa3b85dfbc44e6814ab</guid></item><item><title>Australia formally recognises state of Palestine as Anthony Albanese arrives in US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australia-formally-recognises-state-of-palestine/105799238</link><description>The historic decision foreshadowed last month has now become a reality, as Australia moves with Canada and the United Kingdom to join the growing list of countries to recognise Palestinian sovereignty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f7f36cbe6b5b1fbaaf3e78efd2951a2</guid></item><item><title>Can recognising the state of Palestine achieve a two-state solution as Israel continues bombing Gaza?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australia-recognises-state-of-palestine-two-state-solution/105799276</link><description>While the Israel Defense Forces bomb Gaza and bulldoze the West Bank for settlements, moves to recognise Palestine in pursuit of a two-state solution may appear like something of a sick joke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfa3467335da07f9ce07cf8e87421ac9</guid></item><item><title>Is artificial intelligence overhyped or is AI the 'fourth industrial revolution'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/is-ai-the-fourth-industrial-revolution/105790912</link><description>It's estimated 30,000 people are working in the AI industry in Australia, and fanfare is growing with start-ups tapping into billions of dollars of venture capital. Yet there are concerns about hype and a lack of regulation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26daac2bce5f986abcbf545a3ec82df2</guid></item><item><title>Older Australians to pay up to $50/hour for basic care at home under aged care changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/older-australians-to-pay-for-showers-under-home-care-changes/105796118</link><description>Older Australians entering the aged care system will have to pay for "non-clinical" services such as showers and help with medication under wide-ranging changes taking effect in November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fad2ebda86259a9a52aff0b346c39071</guid></item><item><title>Gene editing is being sold on the promise of healthier babies — but what are the ethical concerns?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/ethics-of-gene-editing-designer-babies/105496228</link><description>The race to advance gene editing tech continues, spurred on by starry-eyed Silicon Valley investors, entrepreneurs and even pronatalists. But it is still deeply controversial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">073c888cabd844776c0f78ddf6d9f91a</guid></item><item><title>Brownlow Medal 2025 — when is it, how to watch and who are the favourites for AFL's best-and-fairest award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-medal-2025-explainer-how-to-watch-who-might-win/105799236</link><description>The AFL's big night is here, as the league's best and fairest player is honoured with the Brownlow Medal. Here is everything you need to know about the big event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a533b478e86cba0a5d23c3da7fd118e4</guid></item><item><title>The government says its 2035 climate targets are achievable but mathematics suggests a different story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/climate-target-2035-2050-carbon-emissions-global-warming/105799080</link><description>The problem with an emissions reduction target is that its mere existence implies it is achievable and that if we do achieve it, we will be fine. The truth is more complex.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55dd3a3450e5da05cd2e7e786ef836f8</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Kopp's teacher Paul Grealy groomed her at 15. As an adult, she held him to account</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/sarah-kopps-teacher-paul-grealy-groomed-her-from-15/105775958</link><description>Sarah Kopp's life was up-ended when a charismatic teacher twice her age started grooming her. Then they married and had children. When she sought justice 20 years on, she faced an impossible choice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">329e0e5fdb603a2e16d3f7e31513666e</guid></item><item><title>In an Australian first, chip company recycles leftover cooking oil into packaging to reduce emissions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/chip-packet-oil-recycling-snackbrands-australia-viva-energy/105788230</link><description>Hundreds of litres of used cooking oil is disposed of every year as a by-product of making some of Australia's favourite snacks, like chips — but one company is trialling a method to reduce waste.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ff59f9aa179f301bfc7d9f1c6d8480c</guid></item><item><title>Lachlan Murdoch involved in possible TikTok deal, Donald Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/tiktok-deal-involves-murdoch-trump-says/105800256</link><description>The deal would see TikTok's American assets transferred from China's ByteDance to American owners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da7908cffd99b9ae76881cabbe2df158</guid></item><item><title>Dementia-linked protein lower in people reporting vigorous exercise, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/how-exercise-can-reduce-risk-of-developing-dementia/105783238</link><description>Scientists have, for the first time, linked exercise with a particular protein in the blood that is associated with brain health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1927e46b141094965051ff5e6c95b5c2</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump calls Charlie Kirk a 'martyr' at memorial service, widow Erika Kirk forgives alleged assassin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/thousand-gather-charlie-kirk-memorial-service-donald-trump/105800038</link><description>US President Donald Trump says Charlie Kirk was a "martyr to American freedom", while his widow says she forgives his alleged assassin during a memorial to the right-wing activist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a195c5eaab3b46f9f8c92705e3433bbb</guid></item><item><title>Australia has been free of endemic measles since 2014. Could that change?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/measles-cases-on-the-rise-australia-explainer/105799284</link><description>So far this year, there have been 121 measles notifications across Australia — the highest number since 2019, when there were 284 notifications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cebd25abdddc63773dde66358f7395f</guid></item><item><title>Pensioners left 'waiting to die' in regional Victoria as specialist healthcare costs rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/pensioners-cant-afford-specialist-health-care-costs-victoria/105713416</link><description>Victorian pensioner Eddie Rushforth says he does not know whether his bowel cancer has returned because he cannot afford the cost of the scans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2bc72941774215310fee9627fe967a3</guid></item><item><title>BOM forecasts sunny skies ahead for Queensland school holidays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/sunny-skies-ahead-for-queensland-school-holidays/105799388</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says the weather will be as good as people in the Sunshine State can hope for at this time of year, with another wet summer on the horizon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de4b1e56c2c94f0650974a071e492fdb</guid></item><item><title>Murray River flood may not be to blame for SA algal bloom, Senate inquiry hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/murray-river-flood-link-to-algal-bloom-questioned-senate-inquiry/105733848</link><description>Scientists have questioned the link between the 2022-23 floods and South Australia's ongoing harmful algal bloom, despite the state government listing it as one of the three primary causes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e88db31a70e241e8774222579aebebdc</guid></item><item><title>Storm-damaged turbine at NSW Central West wind farm raises safety concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/storm-damaged-turbine-at-nsw-central-west-wind-farm-concerns/105782400</link><description>After a wind turbine blade snapped in half during a storm, the NSW National Party has called for a safety audit into the renewable technology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">020cbe7c7b785e21c8f3c2fd850c4be9</guid></item><item><title>Short-term stays are swallowing up housing stock in these WA coastal havens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/wa-coastal-towns-for-rent/105628728</link><description>With one of the nation's highest proportions of Airbnbs, some of WA's most popular tourist towns face a dilemma. Tourism is their biggest breadwinner — but with a housing crisis in full swing, short-term stays are pushing more and more locals away.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42e3387b3cda80c2ffd9d9842d5c1c42</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr earns a standing ovation in home game return as Chelsea defeats Leicester 1-0 in WSL</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/wsl-sam-kerr-returns-home-to-standing-ovation-in-chelsea/105800446</link><description>Chelsea fans stand and applaud Australian superstar Sam Kerr in her long-awaited return to Kingsmeadow in the WSL.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da70332495135e59ba3b6176d03d566d</guid></item><item><title>This program could be the blueprint for helping kids fleeing domestic violence stay off the streets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/homeless-kids-domestic-violence-solution-politics/105793902</link><description>Every night, thousands of Australian kids are homeless without an adult to look after them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e17c22bd4e0bdb7ea0d6cd380a87fbf</guid></item><item><title>Protesters in Philippines clash with police in rallies against corruption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/protesters-in-philippines-rally-against-corruption/105800512</link><description>Thousands of Filipinos marched in the capital to vent their anger over a ballooning scandal involving bogus flood-control projects believed to have cost taxpayers billions of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffa83e3c2e5be80abb8e2dcb772951a9</guid></item><item><title>Police charge woman with allegedly defrauding four elderly residents at aged care facility where she worked</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/queensland-police-fraud-charges-rothwell-aged-care-residents/105800700</link><description>Police allege the woman defrauded four elderly residents at an aged care facility where she worked and used their bank details to make personal purchases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2725d37a3ace6ec371c99b16fc7b5d20</guid></item><item><title>World leaders are meeting at the UN General Assembly this week. Here are four things to watch for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/united-nations-general-assembly-what-to-watch-for-in-new-york/105800440</link><description>World leaders are arriving in New York for the UN General Assembly — and for the first time, Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is among them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">761958b8abcd8c47c96a8d78d674b211</guid></item><item><title>Optus triple-0 outage investigation underway as minister warns of 'consequences'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/optus-investigation-triple-0-outage/105800556</link><description>The Australian Media and Communications Authority begins its investigation into the Optus triple-0 outage that has been linked to multiple deaths in South Australia and Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64e8d943c326b70c38e9b095d514da19</guid></item><item><title>Germany sends planes to track Russian military aircraft as Trump vows to defend Baltic states</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/german-sends-planes-over-poland-as-trump-vows-to-defend-baltic/105800452</link><description>President Donald Trump says he will defend the Baltic states if Russia intensifies hostilities following Moscow's incursion into Estonia's airspace in recent days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5204fff459f01296ee960b38ecc71bf0</guid></item><item><title>Queensland CHO on state's measles outbreak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/queensland-cho-on-states-measles-outbreak/105801130</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">651d78f7433d688b560566682a3c8124</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder of Queensland mother Crystal Beale, whose body was found in the Brisbane River</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/qld-man-charged-murder-domestic-violence-crystal-beale/105801310</link><description>Ms Beale's body was found in the Brisbane River by a member of the public in the early hours of February 22.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b57a9a5abde994d1da426ed287896e9d</guid></item><item><title>'We want more GPs': Federal government seeks expressions of interest for three new bulk billing clinics in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/seed-funding-three-new-bulk-billing-clinics-canberra-eoi/105800968</link><description>The federal government says $10.5 million is being invested as "seed funding" to establish three new bulk billing clinics in Canberra, but the Australian Medical Association says it's not clear if this will resolve the issues facing the ACT long-term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">440a81ef8c790af5117fdb57d1c85f35</guid></item><item><title>Jacqui Lambie calls on independent MLCs to 'block' the proposed Macquarie Point stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/jacqui-lambie-calls-on-independent-mlcs-to-block-hobart-stadium/105797716</link><description>Senator Jacqui Lambie tells the independents in Tasmania's upper house — who hold the fate of the Macquarie Point stadium in their hands — to "find the courage the premier can't" and stop the project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b78160dbac88202c3169fcc945ea29c</guid></item><item><title>Australians can't trust the triple-0 network after 13-hour Optus outage results in deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/optus-triple-0-failure-analysis/105800592</link><description>The Optus failure is shocking and no doubt a massive fine and other sanctions could be on the way, but experts say it raises further questions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2edd7465f8b9851c69c1b7efadb1f5f1</guid></item><item><title>'Turning it up to eleven': Spinal Tap returns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/turning-it-up-to-eleven-spinal-tap-returns/105792970</link><description>The new film follows the fictional heavy metal band reuniting for one final gig with cameos from Elton John and Paul McCartney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4608648fffc66e4e36ba98d635f1990</guid></item><item><title>Easy and healthy dinner recipes for spring</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/easy-healthy-recipes-for-spring-dinners/105660408</link><description>If you're looking for light dinner ideas as the weather warms up, we have plenty of easy options. Think veggie-filled frittatas and beef taco bowls with a few healthy swaps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c28e2a7be5345c5402fc685acca89162</guid></item><item><title>Shalom House drug rehab centre CEO Peter Lyndon-James to step down over immigration views</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/peter-lyndon-james-steps-down-shalom-house-ceo/105801198</link><description>The head of a controversial WA drug rehabilitation service says he will resign so he can speak out against "mass migration".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f37d78dd839c3af15e6c8564d4e771f2</guid></item><item><title>Two men charged after alleged assault of referees following junior rugby grand final in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/junior-rugby-referee-in-hospital-after-alleged-coward-punch/105801788</link><description>Two men have been charged with assault after an alleged coward punch attack during a junior rugby sevens grand final on Sunday in which a referee was knocked unconscious.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87fdb730cde332a506fd7ccf1b011e9e</guid></item><item><title>NT Police complete Kumanjayi White death in custody autopsy, with brief of evidence handed to prosecutors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/kumanjayi-white-death-in-custody-alice-springs-autopsy-completed/105801756</link><description>The autopsy into the Aboriginal man's death in custody in Alice Springs has been completed, with the police brief of evidence handed to prosecutors to determine whether any charges should be laid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b34f78ebd2e7994895d35c509e3ce63</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast man sentenced over former partner's traumatic brain injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/man-sentenced-over-former-partners-traumatic-brain-injury/105801732</link><description>A man is sentenced over a 2023 incident in which his former partner jumped from a moving car to escape him, leaving her with a traumatic brain injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e9c37ba116765f615c221f6c4108a07</guid></item><item><title>Is AI impacting your career or life plans? Has its rapid rise got you rethinking your future? The ABC wants to hear from you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/ai-artificial-intelligence-future-job-career-impact/105762606</link><description>Whether you’re a student halfway through a degree or a mid-career manager planning the next five years, artificial intelligence (AI) is reshaping lives across the country. If you've been feeling its effects, the ABC wants to hear from you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc9fb0b057b73e053ee1ce795957b20a</guid></item><item><title>Masood Zakaria asks court to permanently stay his murder trial over 'unlawful' deportation from Türkiye</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/masood-zakaria-trial-vacated-re-alleged-illegal-deportation/105802494</link><description>A major Sydney murder trial is at risk of falling over as a Supreme Court judge ruled there was evidence the man charged was deported back to Australia unlawfully.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50b9900e4915898991b85033dca86795</guid></item><item><title>'It is do-able': How interim vice-chancellor Rebekah Brown plans to balance ANU's expenditure and revenue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/interim-vice-chancellor-rebekah-brown-interview-plan-reputation/105800874</link><description>Eight days into her new role as interim vice-chancellor at the Australian National University, Rebekah Brown sat down for an exclusive ABC interview to share her plan for getting the institution back on track.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94bab8bb94646b877de5b418d1b0614e</guid></item><item><title>Court hears details of final hours of murdered children as Hakyung Lee murder trial nears end</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/hakyung-lee-trial-week-three/105801212</link><description>Hakyung Lee admits killing her children but claims she is not guilty by reason of insanity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8bb6b299ff32e2539915e7831b1952d</guid></item><item><title>Nasal spray flu vaccine becomes available for young SA children next year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/nasal-spray-flu-vaccine-for-children-in-south-australia/105801696</link><description>Three-year-old Clive has a brain injury after contracting influenza B. His mother is urging others to be immunised as SA announces it will make a nasal spray vaccination available to young children next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3127ec54f20dbb0732907c3206a26170</guid></item><item><title>Geelong star Max Holmes admits missing 2022 grand final hurt relationship with coach Chris Scott</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/i-was-pissed-with-scotty-cats-star-holmes-eyes-afl-flag/105802834</link><description>Geelong speedster Max Holmes is desperate to put his previous grand-final week anger and heartbreak behind him as the Cats eye AFL premiership glory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd1f4bd169de77ac34368207d9141381</guid></item><item><title>From Donald Trump's speech to Erika Kirk's forgiveness: What you missed at the Charlie Kirk memorial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/charlie-kirk-funeral-arizona-trump-erika-and-other-takeaways/105802396</link><description>From Donald Trump's wide-ranging speech to a potential reunion between former foes, here are the main takeaways from Charlie Kirk's memorial service in Arizona.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3eb1b27c764c94c12dc9506fd3a5f2e</guid></item><item><title>Hunter woman claims self-defence over fatal stabbing during street fight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/lily-ridgeway-claims-self-defence-raymond-terrace-stabbing-death/105800848</link><description>Hunter woman Lily Ridgeway pleads not guilty to manslaughter over the stabbing death of Jason Adams at Raymond Terrace in 2020, claiming she acted in self-defence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c627f1928a1c4af96c0f00a2c6f4d75</guid></item><item><title>Super Netball's Sunshine Coast Lightning enters new Global Sports Fund Management Group ownership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/super-netball-sunshine-coast-lightning-new-ownership/105801344</link><description>Almost a decade after being co-founded by the Melbourne Storm and University of the Sunshine Coast, Super Netball's Lightning is entering a new era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">725e5769d7aa41a90979ec4d3e47f5bd</guid></item><item><title>Three alleged kidnappers denied bail after 'hostage situation' in front of kids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/alleged-kidnappers-hostage-situation-baseball-bat-monash/105803486</link><description>Three alleged kidnappers were trying to recover a $200,000 debt from a 52-year-old man in Monash on September 21, a court has heard, while rejecting their bail application.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d541b8975b82abbe25815a1c564cffb0</guid></item><item><title>Paper Australia sues Victorian government for $402 million over timber supply failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/paper-australia-sues-victorian-government-timber-supply-failure/105666676</link><description>Paper Australia alleges the state government failed to provide enough raw materials for its Maryvale mill, causing substantial loss and damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3966e123ebc206895cb857b760514b64</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos undecided on halves combination ahead of prelim final against Penrith</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/hunt-on-for-broncos-as-mam-mind-games-begin/105803392</link><description>Brisbane coach Michael Maguire continues to experiment with his halves combinations on Monday as Ezra Mam takes another key step towards a return from injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94b206b4a39973e74852b877af401757</guid></item><item><title>Alexander O'Sachy faces Brisbane court charged with manslaughter of Angela Godwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/manslaughter-sentencing-domestic-violence-upper-mount-gravatt/105802410</link><description>The court heard the 47-year-old had a criminal history spanning more than 20 years for more than 50 offences, including the unlawful wounding of a former partner in 2008.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b4cf8d12fdea5712adde0cc2c477aae</guid></item><item><title>Potato mop-top virus detected in Victoria for first time, industry says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/mop-top-potato-virus-detected-in-victoria/105802514</link><description>The infected potato seeds, transported from Tasmania to Victoria, were found in cold storage and none have been planted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0acc254b768995af9724c767cc070527</guid></item><item><title>Endangered Littlejohn's tree frog finally bred in captivity amid habitat threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/endangered-littlejohns-tree-frog-finally-bred-in-captivity/105799502</link><description>Scientists have achieved a breakthrough in their work to save the Littlejohn's tree frog species which only exists in three isolated regions in New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">242f7f349ef09c427b4a7b8724bf30e1</guid></item><item><title>Labor reaffirms support for Hobart's proposed AFL stadium, in wake of Planning Commission report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/tas-labor-reaffirms-support-for-macquarie-point-afl-stadium/105803688</link><description>Tasmanian Labor has reaffirmed its support for Hobart's proposed AFL stadium, despite being "deeply concerned" about cost blowouts — and says the "power" of having a state team in the AFL "cannot be underestimated".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95a13cfb304b653812e1dcae4d79afb2</guid></item><item><title>Brownlow Medal 2025: All the best fashion looks from AFL's night of nights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-red-carpet-wrap/105802436</link><description>Just after the fashion from this evening's Brownlow Medal? We've got you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8922390581e8430e878c1aa384dd8e2d</guid></item><item><title>Matt Rowell wins 2025 Brownlow Medal as Gold Coast star beats out Nick Daicos and Bailey Smith</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-medal-2025-live-blog-daicos-smith-dawson-rowell/105798968</link><description>Matt Rowell becomes the second Gold Coast player to win the prestigious AFL award, as a questionable voting call regarding Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera leaves the room stunned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08247d0fedaa413c59c8aea7818c6570</guid></item><item><title>Leopard sharks recorded mating by researcher in rare event off New Caledonia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/leopard-sharks-mating-rare-event-new-caledonia/105803858</link><description>A Sunshine Coast marine biologist has captured unique footage of two male sharks mating with a female in waters off New Caledonia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d272a5e23486cc628261c514c7180fe</guid></item><item><title>David Jenkins murder trial hears from co-accused who says he was unaware victim had been stabbed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/david-jenkins-murder-trial-paul-shaw-evidence-over-stabbing/105801088</link><description>A Tasmanian man on trial for murder has told a court he "attacked" and swore at his brother, after learning his younger sibling had allegedly stabbed a man who later died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc5d9c125eb63ef91e0417a2b5e95f3d</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong prepares for 'serious threat' from Super Typhoon Ragasa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/typhoon-ragasa-closes-hong-kong-airport-suspends-flights/105803976</link><description>Hong Kong rushes to prepare for the arrival of Super Typhoon Ragasa with officials warning of a "serious threat" comparable to some of the most destructive storms in the city's recent history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e5d42a70ec597715a4e95e20afc30ba</guid></item><item><title>UN General Assembly president Annalena Baerbock concerned about future of UN and funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/annalena-baerbock-united-nations-concerns-trump/105804036</link><description>UN General Assembly president Annalena Baerbock fears for the organisation's future as she seeks a resolution in Gaza and on funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c1e1c6c9c37ff6ec98759d98babf00a</guid></item><item><title>Latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/latest-financial-news/105804002</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a2a0a2b0118f619ddf3cb8e2061e8e4</guid></item><item><title>Non-profit multiple sclerosis organisation MS Society SA &amp; NT in voluntary administration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/ms-society-sa-nt-voluntary-administration/105803788</link><description>Non-profit organisation MS Society SA &amp; NT, which supports almost 3,000 clients living with multiple sclerosis, has gone into voluntary administration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e24b724079885d2734e6959f8fc726da</guid></item><item><title>Ley writes to Republicans vowing to revoke Palestine recognition ahead of Albanese's UN address</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/albanese-un-palestine-address-ley-republican-letter/105803078</link><description>In an unorthodox move, Opposition Leader Sussan Ley writes to a group of Republicans reassuring the Coalition would withdraw recognition of Palestine, ahead of a major United Nations address to be delivered by the prime minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98f3481476a06e3c9782e1032f1893d8</guid></item><item><title>Russia reviving Soviet-style coercive psychiatry measures to quash dissent, says UN expert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/russia-using-soviet-era-tactics-to-quash-dissent-says-un-expert/105804510</link><description>The UN's special rapporteur on rights in Russia says the Kremlin is resorting to coercive psychiatry measures to suppress anti-war dissidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21ce0b298bf27ebd899c6c429768f1f9</guid></item><item><title>Moldovan authorities arrest 74 people over alleged Russia-backed election plot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/moldova-election-arrests-russia-backed-plot/105804776</link><description>The widespread raids came ahead of the country's parliamentary elections on Sunday, expected to determine whether the country will pursue closer ties with the European Union.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a647be00ecfc0d387fa0b9a153bf4406</guid></item><item><title>Multiple UK charities cut ties with Duchess of York over email to Jeffrey Epstein</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/uk-charity-dumps-sarah-duchess-of-york-epstein/105804606</link><description>The decisions come after British media reported that the Duchess had described the disgraced financier as a "steadfast, generous and supreme friend" in a 2011 letter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c20e28d80c8779c49ad3426a6872fc0</guid></item><item><title>Russia warned airspace violations 'risk direct armed confrontation' with NATO</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/nato-russia-un-security-council-incursions/105804662</link><description>Allies say they will not hesitate to shoot down Russian jets which violate NATO airspace in future siutations, after two jets entered Estonia's skies last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1aa9acc3a9b3f24c9641962857f8602d</guid></item><item><title>The kids growing up in 'the most dangerous place in the world to be a child'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/children-living-in-gaza/105789464</link><description>There are a million children living in Gaza through the war between Israel and Hamas. Foreign Correspondent follows one young family trying to survive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17536ed0e05730b47651936db408187f</guid></item><item><title>Artificial intelligence to dominate Australia's future economy, but who will reap the benefits?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/australias-future-economy-will-be-dominated-by-ai/105802364</link><description>From robots to supercomputers, artificial intelligence is set to become an integral part of the Australian economy, with tens of billions in benefits to be gained … but for whom?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12e16358f1d06001f22c8315b12c996c</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar junta revoking citizenship of actors, singers and other celebrities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/myanmar-celebrities-left-stateless-after-criticising-junta/105787574</link><description>Myanmar's military junta is using citizenship as a weapon, targeting political opponents, activists and even celebrities who speak out against the regime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df5568a6e89118d9a0c2db08ec61854c</guid></item><item><title>Three Australians lay dead as investors of Optus's parent company Singtel were buying up its shares</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/three-australians-lay-dead-investors-buy-up-shares/105803922</link><description>The actions by Optus management in the hours following a series of failed attempts by its customers to call triple-0 raises questions about the telco's fitness to operate in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24e9f1bc9c2b8e3b2e1bdab5ae2ccb23</guid></item><item><title>Meeting between Anthony Albanese and Donald Trump unlikely ahead of UN address</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/meeting-unlikely-between-albanese-and-trump/105804978</link><description>The US president's itinerary for his 24-hour visit to New York makes no mention of Anthony Albanese, all but confirming a one-on-one will not be happening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9178055a02eb3b7f78d5f3fc4d772a8c</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: 'No doubt' Trump and Albanese will meet soon, acting PM says — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/federal-politics-live-sept-23/105803300</link><description>Richard Marles says he has no doubt the prime minister and US president will meet soon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2770399e32c9257f91ff03c40ec31e7</guid></item><item><title>Italian police use tear gas against pro-Palestinian protesters demanding end to war in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/pro-palestinian-protests-in-italy/105804908</link><description>Italy's right-wing government, led by Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni, says it does not plan to recognise Palestine at this stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">238da06b96f16fe6239df6799ed5ab79</guid></item><item><title>Calls for long-term plan to address Tasmania's 'concerning' school attendance level</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/tasmania-school-attendance-level-concerns/105770010</link><description>Australia's school attendance levels have dropped since the pandemic but education experts are particularly concerned about Tasmania — a state with an already notoriously low literacy rate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81f75b3e7bbb3bc0d144997482f5d7c9</guid></item><item><title>The public hospital patients who ended up paying abortion clinics for miscarriage care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/qld-mater-miscarriage-care-catholic-hospital-abortion/105781022</link><description>Brisbane women have told the ABC they paid an abortion clinic for their chosen miscarriage care rather than getting it at their large public hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34accc25ffd487a2e3cb32cdcd8a582d</guid></item><item><title>Moment Matt Rowell announced as 2025 Brownlow medallist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/moment-matt-rowell-announced-as-2025-brownlow-medallist/105805032</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4336530cc59f3c10ad2c74d7b058cebe</guid></item><item><title>Matt Rowell delivers Brownlow Medal acceptance speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/matt-rowell-delivers-brownlow-medal-acceptance-speech/105805042</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2002bf4ac5caada0dc95c1432e61966</guid></item><item><title>Sydney's inner west residents pack into forum on high-rise apartment plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/sydney-inner-west-fairer-future-plan-housing-council-forum/105799454</link><description>Community members who showed up for the meeting on the Inner West Council's Fairer Future Plan were turned away at the door after being told the venue was full.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9616c9ea6e30d981b8478ab8be2118e3</guid></item><item><title>Greyhound Racing SA faces trainer boycott after animal re-homing staff departure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/greyhound-racing-sa-facing-trainer-boycott-over-staff-treatment/105799536</link><description>More than 30 South Australian greyhound trainers have threatened to boycott races after the departure of two animal re-homing staff who raised concerns about a dog's welfare.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4019e8251044b560a74ee51d63e73c1a</guid></item><item><title>Staff at Flinders University increasingly concerned as department restructure looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/sa-flinders-uni-jobs-restructure/105795002</link><description>Six internationally recognised marine scientists who are researching South Australia's toxic algal bloom are set to lose their jobs at Flinders University, the ABC understands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9deed8a5706e27e0f9c904dab0347341</guid></item><item><title>Turtle strandings and soft-shell syndrome cases fall as seagrass beds recover</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/soft-shell-syndrome-in-turtles-decline-as-seagrass-beds-recover/105789276</link><description>Soft-shell syndrome had been devastating green sea turtle numbers since flood events began impacting their seagrass food source in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af2746d8c73bc7e2cae2f8fde2fd2c13</guid></item><item><title>Doctors concerned easily accessible illegal cigarettes are causing smoking rates to increase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/act-easy-access-to-illegal-cigarettes-seeing-high-smoking-rates/105803450</link><description>Doctors say smoking rates are at levels they haven't seen in a decade due to easy access to illegal cigarettes that are a "quarter of the price" of legal cigarettes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">150ad4af75b20ef2e67ba79a215e5c20</guid></item><item><title>Byron Bay's 60-day holiday rental cap yields mixed results in first year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/60-day-caps-in-byron-bay-results-uncertain-after-one-year/105799696</link><description>A year after controversial holiday rental caps were introduced in Byron Bay to boost rental availability, the data is unclear about whether the endeavour has been a success.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66035aa0e00835cc39a9f24d118bed47</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel reinstated after hundreds of stars back free speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/jimmy-kimmel-back-on-air-disney-says/105805048</link><description>US comedian Jimmy Kimmel's late-night show will be reinstated after being taken off air, following remarks he made referencing right-wing activist Charlie Kirk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">868e8a8d3b8279fa34a833b46463ee3f</guid></item><item><title>Man Ray and Max Dupain's photography on display together for the first time in new Heide exhibition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/man-ray-max-dupain-photography-exhibition-heide-melbourne/105790024</link><description>Surrealist photographer Man Ray revolutionised 20th-century visual culture. In Australia, a local photographer was exploring similar territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">318bfee371103375fcc23430352eccfd</guid></item><item><title>Have Your Say — The Digital Dilemma</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/your-say-social-media-ban/105751900</link><description>The ban on social media for under 16s is around the corner and could have wide-reaching impacts. Are you in favour? Will it work? Have Your Say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4aae05270f4098b1533ed0e2733be3af</guid></item><item><title>Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera being robbed overshadowed Matt Rowell's Brownlow Medal win, and could change the voting process forever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/afl-matt-rowell-nasiah-moment-brownlow-medal-voting-analysis/105804320</link><description>It is not often that the AFL's night of nights gets hijacked by a moment not involving the winner of the Brownlow Medal. This is exactly what took place when Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera was seemingly robbed in broad daylight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dfdde5b406fc68132f52c264d89b4c9</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane drivers face longer delays at level crossings as rail network expands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/qld-boom-gate-down-times-of-up-to-50-minutes-of-peak-hour/105733700</link><description>Level crossing boom gates are expected to be down for much longer as Queensland adds more trains to its rail network.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ffc25dcd4adb09d1c9e3a74a2e7a425</guid></item><item><title>Experts say paracetamol safe for pregnancy, no proof for autism link made by Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/trump-administration-links-autism-to-paracetamol-tga-says-safe/105803566</link><description>Australia's medicines regulator says paracetamol remains safe to use during pregnancy despite Donald Trump's administration linking its use to an increased risk of autism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9575c0f36522e77b42eccc5329990b40</guid></item><item><title>ASX rises again as gold miners rally, Myer slumps on large loss — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/asx-markets-business-live-news-sept23-2025/105805154</link><description>A rally on Wall Street sent Australian stocks higher on Tuesday, but Myer shares slumped after big write-downs drove a huge loss. Catch up on the day's business and economics news on the ABC's live blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8371a2395c2d6eea7b5796d934bbfd1</guid></item><item><title>Dave Barham steps down as Essendon president as Zach Merrett apologises to fans over Hawthorn meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/afl-zach-merrett-essendon-fans-hawthorn-meeting-shame/105805134</link><description>Essendon president Dave Barham hands over his role to his understudy, continuing an off-season filled with change at the club as Zach Merrett speaks publicly for the first time on his flirtation with Hawthorn.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3289cc328afab23fef3d55a2fb2fddc1</guid></item><item><title>Darwin dancer with dislocated knee left waiting for ambulance for six hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/darwin-dancer-left-waiting-for-ambulance-over-six-hours/105803840</link><description>A 20-year-old dancer was left waiting for an ambulance for more than six hours after dislocating her knee during a competition in the Darwin CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e282340089a62fe29ce12b5bbe0cdbb8</guid></item><item><title>Paddleboarder gets too close to whales to film them, gets nudged away</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/paddleboarder-gets-too-close-to-whales-to-film-them/105801626</link><description>Drone footage shows a paddleboarder getting too close to film a southern right whale mother and calf, and being nudged away by the whale, off Point Ann.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccd42678f7b40484099efe1f5126dddd</guid></item><item><title>Ousmane Dembélé wins men's Ballon d'Or as Aitana Bonmatí joins elite club featuring Lionel Messi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/football-ousmane-dembele-ballon-d-or-bonmati-salah-yamal/105805184</link><description>French forward Ousmane Dembélé caps off a dream season with football's most prestigious individual award as Spain's Aitana Bonmatí continues to add to her legacy as one of the best women's players of all time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e69e7f3a1af9871429f380161b57a49e</guid></item><item><title>Women band together to create community for rural mums feeling lonely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/women-create-community-for-rural-mums-suffering-from-loneliness/105803024</link><description>After raising biological and foster children on a farm 60 kilometres from the nearest major town, Tracey Angwin says being part of a community is essential for rural mums.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da92ce9d728ad981483651f9d4c38527</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese joins nine world leaders recognising Palestinian statehood at historic UN summit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/anthony-albanese-united-nations-palestinian-statehood-conference/105804994</link><description>Australia's position has been matched by the UK, Canada, France, Andorra, Belgium, Luxembourg, Malta, Monaco and Portugal. But it is attracting fresh criticism from the White House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17600ad15d70de99a64a9c7966a2716a</guid></item><item><title>Sydney train network review finds fallen live cable wire risk identified years ago, service recovery too slow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/sydney-train-network-review-live-cable-wire-incident-government/105805558</link><description>An independent review into how a live cable came down on top of a Sydney train in May found the overhead wire that failed had been identified as a risk in 2020 but was never repaired.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3ff214447a533644533cf8b9dc52a28</guid></item><item><title>Chronic pain sufferer donates knitted goods for babies in intensive care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/thousands-of-donated-knitted-items-for-premmie-babies/105762552</link><description>Knitting has become an outlet for Port Stephens woman Kim Franks, who is mostly housebound after a diagnosis of debilitating psoriasis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f81a9667430db32dc168a444fd30d209</guid></item><item><title>Deeming rates have increased after a five-year freeze. Here's how that could impact pension payments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/deeming-rate-freeze-ends-impact-on-pension-payments/105798966</link><description>The changes impact people on Centrelink payments who earn an income from financial assets, but pensioners are the biggest group to be affected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2a6081a58d1e888118022ad40f5fcfd</guid></item><item><title>As a doctor I'm choosing self-care over resilience</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/doctor-choosing-self-care-over-resilience/105728568</link><description>As a doctor who advocates for self-care, it took me a surprisingly long time to look after myself. Now I'm trying to be a good example for my patients and other doctors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96d1bd7d0cdf02ba7b181e19ec630701</guid></item><item><title>Childcare boss unsure if bonuses were docked over rise in safety breaches, inquiry told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/nsw-childcare-inquiry-ceo-questioned-over-bonuses/105805562</link><description>The CEO of Affinity Education Group appears at a state parliamentary inquiry into the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3ece1d8ebaeed33106cbc2f0f9066d1</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Alumina fined $1 million after caustic chemical release in Gladstone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/qld-alumina-fined-caustic-spray-gladstone/105805526</link><description>The chemical release saw people's homes and cars covered in caustic spray and triggered more than $800,000 in insurance claims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0952d3f4408a370e448e01a3c126abf2</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police officer charged with assault over protest arrest of former Greens candidate Hannah Thomas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/nsw-officer-charged-assault-hannah-thomas-greens-arrest/105805966</link><description>Hannah Thomas was among a group of pro-Palestinian protesters who demonstrated outside a manufacturing facility in June when she sustained a serious eye injury during her arrest for failing to comply with a move on direction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ffd2b5888a415cc414e269d4943cf29</guid></item><item><title>EPA investigates disturbing hum sound keeping north-west Sydney residents up at night</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/epa-investigates-disturbing-hum-sound-parramatta/105805278</link><description>One sleepless resident said he drove around his local area to find the source of the disturbance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b07ecb0776d08afdd32e2f257e0a26f</guid></item><item><title>Experts say it is safe to use paracetamol during pregnancy and Trump's autism declaration is 'baseless'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/taking-paracetamol-during-pregnancy-does-not-cause-autism/105806092</link><description>Donald Trump's advice that pregnant women should limit the use of paracetamol in pregnancy has been criticised as "baseless". So what does it mean for you?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81c81571674ce6c676915af2ca81de9b</guid></item><item><title>Hakyung Lee found guilty over deaths of children found in Auckland storage unit suitcases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/nz-suitcase-verdict-hakyung-lee-trial/105658224</link><description>Hakyung Lee admitted to giving her two children an overdose of prescription medicine before changing her name and leaving New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76f153f712f5238ae870dbe2b49d9150</guid></item><item><title>Siosifa Talakai says Cronulla Sharks players 'at each other's throats' before revival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/nrl-siosifa-talakai-cronulla-sharks-season-revival/105806244</link><description>Sharks star Siosifa Talakai gives an insight into the heated player meetings that came during Cronulla's mid-season slump before the team's spectacular charge to an NRL preliminary final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5df9ad45da27441d21ee6e4e6523186c</guid></item><item><title>ICC prosecutors charge Phillipines' former leader Duterte with crimes against humanity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/icc-prosecutors-charge-duterte-3-counts-crimes-against-humanity/105806448</link><description>Former president of the Philippines, Rodrigo Duterte, is accused of being involved in the murder of dozens of people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">186fbab29d9070e10f640592f7123774</guid></item><item><title>Bill Gates pledges $US912 million to AIDS and malaria non-profit as US cuts funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/bill-gates-foundation-pleaged-millions-to-global-fund/105806406</link><description>The tech entrepreneur's announcement follows deep cuts from governments around the world, led by the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd0e8c660df290dadbcdf29a13957875</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane bus driver charged over fatal CBD crash thought he was pressing brakes before he mounted footpath, trial hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/bus-driver-charged-death-brisbane-teen-tia-cameron-cbd/105806472</link><description>A Brisbane bus driver charged over a fatal crash in the CBD last year thought he was pressing the brakes before he mounted a footpath and killed a pedestrian, a court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b04c56f204a9178efca4f6b96879527</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Lions star Lachie Neale trains strongly and looks on track for a grand final spot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/neale-trains-as-lion-s-grand-final-return-hopes-gather-pace/105806698</link><description>The 31-year-old dual Brownlow medallist, who has been battling a calf injury, took part in training drills in front of 2,000 Brisbane fans at the team's Springfield home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c61b547c00f1a6df00fecccb68dde8b8</guid></item><item><title>ASIC accuses RACQ of misleading customers over insurance renewal notices in Federal Court action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/racq-insurance-premiums-regulator-action/105805622</link><description>The corporate watchdog alleges RACQ knowingly misled over 500,000 customers in insurance renewal notices since 2019.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f51ab0965ff2e6958953913e6360ca6b</guid></item><item><title>Man known as 'Moore Park Rapist' pleads guilty to series of sexual assaults in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/moore-park-rapist-glenn-cameron-pleads-guilty-sexual-assaults/105806986</link><description>Glenn Cameron has remained in custody since he was arrested in February last year and charged with more than 30 offences in relation to eight victims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c631b0b48e05bf34d6cd7b4127803d77</guid></item><item><title>Egyptian activist Alaa Abd el-Fattah released from prison after nearly 12 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/egyptian-activist-alaa-abd-el-fattah-released-from-prison/105805902</link><description>Pro-democracy activist Alaa Abd el-Fattah has been released from prison, following a pardon from the Egyptian president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d429202c47e43999510999e5ea936c5c</guid></item><item><title>Father charged with manslaughter of seven-month-old son during camping trip in Queensland granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/qld-jaye-lee-walton-granted-bail-manslaughter-baby-son/105806058</link><description>Jaye Lee Walton, 42, has been charged with the manslaughter of his seven-month-old son Reef Hunter Walton in July.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1c7d659fa35821d1c36f548378d9a1f</guid></item><item><title>Rare nitazene discovered at Canberra pill-testing site believed to be an Australian first</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/illicit-substance-detected-in-single-pill-in-australia-first/105806232</link><description>The capsuled white powder was presented to the pill-testing site on Friday and, when chemists there couldn't make an identification, transferred to the Australian National University for analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b72ec734407c867bfaacfbd97980d07</guid></item><item><title>MS support agency MS Society SA &amp; NT outlines three-year losses, $2.5m debt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/ms-society-sa-nt-facing-millions-in-debt/105806282</link><description>Non-profit organisation MS Society SA &amp; NT, says it has debts of about $2.5 million and has been facing losses for three years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">170d075b7f4176d41d4a209cb5faf5bc</guid></item><item><title>Northern Territory CLP government is reviewing sentencing laws. But will it change anything?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/jake-danby-hit-and-run-nt-sentencing-act-changing-clp-government/105801232</link><description>The case of hit-and-run driver Jake Danby has brought renewed focus to the NT's legal system and the problems it faces. But will changing sentencing laws help?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">181ee879b9bbed91231a5952dddf97e9</guid></item><item><title>Judge finds Queensland businessman Dave Hodgson had 'magic pudding' approach to valuing company</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/dave-hodgson-queensland-businessman-asic/105806258</link><description>The Australian Securities and Investments Commission took Dave Hodgson and two of his companies to the Federal Court, alleging they were operating without the required financial services licence, and had made misrepresentations to investors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b76b44db373c2fc9fcb92493156971a6</guid></item><item><title>Kevin Bacon on the importance of music, philanthropy and acting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/kevin-bacon-take-5-actor-music-philanthropy-interview/105793360</link><description>He's a prolific fixture on our screens who's famously six degrees from almost anyone. But Kevin Bacon is also a passionate musician and philanthropist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45104e05b24001759cca6f2985a81b97</guid></item><item><title>Why many Palestinians are underwhelmed by countries like Australia only now recognising statehood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/palestinians-react-to-statehood-recognition-australia-un/105805514</link><description>Australia joined nine other nations in formally recognising Palestinian statehood at the UN this week. But Palestinians have mixed feelings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57a8a3d3134b09135ecae50caa8ec2a8</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu plans to sign police deal with China while Nakamal pact with Australia is left hanging</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/china-vanuatu-police-agreement-equipment-training/105806934</link><description>Vanuatu declares it will sign a new policing agreement with China as the landmark Nakamal pact between Australia and the Pacific Island nation hangs in the balance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e015a5946bffafc3e5c33cd1d8fa895e</guid></item><item><title>Concerns 'off-brand' cigarettes easy to access and cheaper</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/concerns-off-brand-cigarettes-easy-to-access-and/105807734</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e1d889cc16fa1dfacac6368020592c5</guid></item><item><title>Sean 'Diddy' Combs's lawyers pitch shorter prison term, therapy ahead of sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/sean-diddy-combs-lawyers-try-to-impose-14-month-sentence/105807480</link><description>The disgraced hip-hop mogul is expected to be sentenced on October 3.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a3eba260c2608ab5712fd146ba5a4b4</guid></item><item><title>Former AFLW player claims she was spat at as ex-players targeted at local leagues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/former-aflw-player-alleges-she-was-spat-at-local-grand-final/105807282</link><description>Former AFLW player claims she was spat at during her community grand final as ex-players are being targeted at local leagues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d6a2eaa36a8640a26a9d3c7ca905b54</guid></item><item><title>Optus triple-0 outage tragedy: What we know and how events unfolded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/timeline-on-optus-triple-0-outage-what-we-know/105805890</link><description>The first sign something was wrong came late on Friday afternoon. Now we have a clearer picture of how the triple-0 outage unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c548c42002e87e4dd015358e8d8279e9</guid></item><item><title>Unproven autism claims like Donald Trump's risk undoing decades of progress</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/trump-unproven-autism-claims-risk-undoing-decades-of-progress/105807344</link><description>The Trump administration's rhetoric only adds to the noise around autism and will make it harder for the community to feel understood and accepted, write Nas Campanella and Evan Young.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00fa47bf5ec49c44ed4dd1852e1689f4</guid></item><item><title>Debate over Macquarie Point stadium rages in Tasmanian parliament following release of damning report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/macquarie-stadium-debate-tasmanian-parliament/105806814</link><description>In the first Question Time since the release of the Tasmanian Planning Commission's damning report on the Hobart AFL stadium, the Labor Party questioned the government's ability to deliver the stadium, while an independent labelled it a "dud deal".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">accf0e157a3f7bdf9cc737117f4b639c</guid></item><item><title>How Sydney Trains's lacking communication issue can be overcome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/nsw-sydney-trains-communication-issues-new-report/105806734</link><description>A scathing report into Sydney Trains has put a "disturbing" spotlight on the "absence of effective communications" and "information voids" on the network, but one transport expert says this was not always the case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b7a173dc56a72adad406543107b5381</guid></item><item><title>Victoria Police dog on the road to recovery after horror collision in Melbourne's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/victoria-police-dog-injured-car-accident/105805824</link><description>A man has been charged following a collision in Tullamarine that left a police dog and his handler with injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63e90f91a0b55706b1f1ae1fb7432821</guid></item><item><title>Sale of Australia's biggest sheep station at Rawlinna finally gets WA government approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/sale-of-australias-largest-sheep-station-at-rawlinna-station/105807106</link><description>The WA government has finally signed off on the sale of Australia's largest sheep station almost seven months after UK-based Consolidated Pastoral Company announced plans to buy Rawlinna Station.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">453798f3baadfee94d513f7ea0e7efc3</guid></item><item><title>Cedric and Noelene Jordan lose appeal over conviction for murder of former son-in-law Shane Barker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/cedric-noelene-jordan-lose-appeal-over-murder-sentence/105807794</link><description>Cedric and Noelene Jordan's attempt to overturn their conviction for the murder of their former son-in-law in 2009 has failed, with the Court of Criminal Appeal rejecting it on all grounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d80214da46831af19f2e7cd071adf8a4</guid></item><item><title>Swarm of bees outside Wagga Wagga dumpling restaurant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/swarm-of-bees-outside-wagga-wagga-dumpling/105807566</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">287cb2981f6a9f964ae70f19fb695d7c</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of bees swarm Wagga Wagga CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/thousands-of-bees-swarm-wagga-wagga-cbd/105808258</link><description>Thousands of bees appear without warning in the regional city, alarming locals and causing a commotion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27722e02bcf2c9eb1efacb7eed1b7299</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie's spray at 'muppet', 'coward' Liberal colleagues after post bemoaning loss of Aussie car making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/andrew-hastie-car-making-coward-muppet-liberals/105808280</link><description>Senior Liberal Andrew Hastie has taken aim at colleagues who questioned a social media post where he bemoaned the loss of Australian car making, calling them "nameless cowards" and "muppets".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa8f233e21c3cb087597a2e4648810dd</guid></item><item><title>Khapra beetle found in Woolworths nappy pants poses $15b threat to grains industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/khapra-beetle-15b-dollar-threat-to-grains-industry/105807350</link><description>The estimated cost of the invasive khapra beetle to Australia's grains industry could be more than $15 billion if it became endemic across the country after being discovered in imported nappy pants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">028e1416aef9b2bb3928cd6f4f4fd1fb</guid></item><item><title>WA rental protections second-worst in nation, National Shelter report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/wa-rental-protections-second-worst-in-nation/105805970</link><description>Calls to ban no-grounds evictions in WA are rejected despite a new report finding the state has the second-worst protections for renters in the nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee624d070108b4891871de914a709154</guid></item><item><title>Teenaged girl to stand trial for alleged Hervey Bay caravan park murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/girl-to-stand-trial-for-alleged-hervey-bay-caravan-park-murder/105805474</link><description>One of the youngest Australians ever to be charged with murder will face a jury trial over the stabbing death in a Hervey Bay caravan park of a 24-year-old man in August 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14ee4913dd0bfa32590ddaa5163670af</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm's Jahrome Hughes and Ryan Papenhuyzen return for NRL preliminary final against Cronulla</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/storm-jahrome-hughes-against-cronulla-broncos-panthers/105808480</link><description>Melbourne recall three big guns, led by star half Jahrome Hughes, as their NRL title hopes go on the line in Friday night's preliminary final against Cronulla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1926a9906773436f42474dc790c296f5</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105809052</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2291dde89e5f6f2e800c553bd2118818</guid></item><item><title>Two teenagers sentenced to detention over attacks on Perth men lured via Grindr app</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/teenagers-detention-grindr-attacks-men-perth/105807670</link><description>Two "lawless" and "cruel" teenage boys who used social media to lure gay men to isolated locations in Perth before attacking them will remain in detention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04ac3ca89cb5b2ff893be3071e8400f4</guid></item><item><title>Hawthorn's Mabior Chol has three-match ban overturned at AFL tribunal as rough conduct charge dismissed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/hawthorn-mabior-chol-afl-tribunal-hearing/105808298</link><description>The AFL tribunal quashes Mabior Chol's three-match ban for rough conduct, finding he did not act unreasonably in his tackle which left Geelong's Tom Stewart concussed and out of this weekend's grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a927a04bec9e6ad920a7713d7f32bccf</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump has linked paracetamol in pregnancy with autism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/donald-trump-has-linked-paracetamol-with-autism/105809090</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64616a565f25d3c8f659a3fda3b034dc</guid></item><item><title>UN General Assembly focuses on Palestinian recognition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/un-general-assembly-focuses-on-palestinian/105809094</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">394a814e2b0bfa243bc948f938e60249</guid></item><item><title>"Recognition of the state is a catalyst towards action to save Gaza": Majed Bamya</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/recognition-of-the-state-is-a-catalyst-towards/105809100</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0756a1d264a9526d46e585115e62fb7</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel to return after highly criticised suspension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/jimmy-kimmel-to-return-after-highly-criticised/105809104</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37c5d5f9db35ad2e3b47f5645ee99b63</guid></item><item><title>Top stories from ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/top-stories-from-abc-news/105809182</link><description>Listen to ABC News interviews and commentary and analysis from radio programs like AM, PM and The World Today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c87439ca850c3883ae3568887af2356a</guid></item><item><title>Denmark links drones at Copenhagen airport to hybrid attacks across Europe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/denmark-investigates-drone-activity-at-copenhagen-airport/105809166</link><description>Denmark links incident involving drones over its main airport to a series of recent suspected Russian drone incursions and other hybrid attacks across Europe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebee7e7802e9046c39907e2c6a3957b7</guid></item><item><title>Super Typhoon Ragasa lashes Taiwan, with two dead and 30 missing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/super-typhoon-ragasa-taiwan-dead-missing/105809264</link><description>The storm, which is the most powerful so far in 2025, is now heading towards the Chinese mainland, prompting widespread disruption and warnings of sea surges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e86c797982ae3107e7d7d8203132df06</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump uses United Nations speech to lay out the US's complaints with the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/united-nations-general-assembly-donald-trump-speech/105809190</link><description>Donald Trump uses a speech at the UN to criticise US allies' moves to recognise Palestine and chastise the international community over a range of other American grievances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">251d1ac533cc88fd01a9540772aff365</guid></item><item><title>Russia systematically torturing Ukrainian civilians, UN says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/russia-systematically-torturing-ukrainian-civilians-un-says/105809316</link><description>The report is based on detailed interviews with 215 former detainees captured since Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b3ec3854b230344943aa0ea9a1c50f</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese to meet Donald Trump in Washington next month, White House confirms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/trump-and-albanese-to-meet/105809460</link><description>The prime minister is expected to travel to Washington to hold talks with the US president on October 20.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c3bc2495519a8885ce870e5014596b8</guid></item><item><title>Incoming triple-0 reforms may not have helped prevent Optus failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/triple-0-reforms-may-not-have-helped-optus-failure/105807524</link><description>The federal government has yet to pass legislation to empower a new coordinator for the emergency services line, but experts say tougher conditions are needed on the telco itself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">196d665b157a51d6ce3440ca5be81bfc</guid></item><item><title>Record number of calls to poisons hotlines for children ingesting melatonin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/melatonin-poisons-hotline-kidshealth/105802406</link><description>The ABC has analysed data from poisons hotlines across the country, revealing almost 1,500 calls were made about children taking melatonin last year, a dramatic rise on previous figures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6379f1180fb83dd59536f7b7017c4f87</guid></item><item><title>Legal fights are brewing over which online social platforms will have to ban under-16s</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/digital-dilemna-social-media-age-ban-platforms/105807302</link><description>WhatsApp, Roblox, Reddit and Discord are among an expanded list of platforms which may be covered by the teen social media ban, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49c528ea0f6a4ded1982839adcac767b</guid></item><item><title>When does daylight saving start in Australia? Here's everything you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/when-does-daylight-saving-start-australia-2025/105800906</link><description>It's the same question every year: Do we gain or lose an hour when daylight saving times comes into effect in October? Here's what you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8230a1782698d65a195531595ca7a771</guid></item><item><title>Could artificial intelligence and a universal basic income eliminate 'meaningless jobs'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/will-we-need-a-universal-basic-income-to-deal-with-ai-job-losses/105747954</link><description>COVID showed just how "fragile" our economic security is. As artificial intelligence potentially takes jobs from humans, a universal basic income might be a solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5953e2ae7f84df41d0ff5021a284652b</guid></item><item><title>Ryan Routh faces life in prison after guilty verdict in Donald Trump assassination attempt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ryan-routh-guilty-of-donald-trump-assassination-attempt/105809490</link><description>A man accused of trying to assassinate Donald Trump at his Florida golf course last year has been found guilty on all charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0214a8b817cf4108f24678a4dba1f80a</guid></item><item><title>Australians are moving to Tasmania to escape climate change, but the island state is not immune</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/australians-moving-to-tasmania-to-escape-climate-change/105785996</link><description>Jack and Anna swapped the humidity of Queensland for chilly days in Tasmania, but is Tasmania really the climate refuge many think it is?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0ff7fbad477aed99626b4746b82c14c</guid></item></channel></rss>