<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 19:45:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>UN Security Council backs US plan for an international stabilisation force in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/un-security-council-approves-plan-for-gaza/106021610</link><description>The UN Security Council approves a US plan for Gaza that authorises an international stabilisation force to provide security in the devastated territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a081270b2d27b47e9bf8ea92b87f75a</guid></item><item><title>Emotional scenes at Moss Vale site hearing over proposed plastics factory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/moss-vale-site-hearing-over-proposed-plastics-factory/106019648</link><description>Normally confined to four walls, the Land and Environment Court holds a site hearing in the NSW Southern Highlands to hear residents' concerns about a proposed recycling plant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abec674d125082e6230833490d7485b7</guid></item><item><title>When is the ARIAs awards ceremony? Where can I watch it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/arias-australian-music-awards-where-to-watch/105995312</link><description>The Australian music industry awards will be celebrating some of the best acts in the country this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07890810d76bc99b56d9f7bcd6df57e4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says he will sign bill to release Epstein files if it passes Congress</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/donald-trump-would-sign-jeffrey-epstein-files-bill/106021282</link><description>The bill — to direct the US Justice Department to release its documents about late sex offender Jeffrey Epstein — now looks set to sail through the House of Representatives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64ce961156f1d882a2423edba210e6b1</guid></item><item><title>Rio Tinto to cut production at Gladstone Yarwun Alumina Refinery, impacting 180 jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/rio-tinto-cuts-production-at-gladstone-yarwun-alumina-refinery/106021782</link><description>Rio Tinto reveals it will cut alumina production at its Gladstone refinery by 40 per cent, as concerns are raised about the future viability of the facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d83c713d69add3a3e357e66a7f50abe9</guid></item><item><title>Coloured sand is being disposed of across the country due to asbestos contamination concerns. How much risk does it actually pose?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/type-asbestos-found-coloured-sand-schools-closed-act-sa-tasmania/106021238</link><description>Dozens of schools remain closed in the ACT, Tasmania and South Australia today as the clean-up and disposal of potentially asbestos-laced coloured sand continues. What risk does it actually pose?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f754e246024da0a3576ac2c3c64e511</guid></item><item><title>Jake Paul and Anthony Joshua's boxing match is a dangerous betrayal of the sport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/jake-paul-vs-anthony-joshua-boxing-match-netflix/106021412</link><description>Nobody plays at boxing. But Jake Paul's upcoming contest against a bona fide, former two-time unified heavyweight champion of the world smacks of a game about to go seriously wrong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">236aee0df8d9b848b87e56b1ef80d128</guid></item><item><title>AFL draft 2025 club by club preview: Your team's picks and potential targets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/afl-draft-2025-club-by-club-preview/105992174</link><description>With the AFL draft just around the corner, see which picks each club has to work with and the players they could select.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dd86e4ed42dd2930cabb8c36b4aff59</guid></item><item><title>The Australian music groups celebrating major milestone anniversaries in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/australian-music-groups-major-milestones-2025/105999894</link><description>Improvising with headlights, a sold-out debut and championing new music are some of the impacts these Australian music groups have made in their decades-long existence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">645e25ee987fda0c6bf4553d7cd6f8f6</guid></item><item><title>Gippsland's Willem Duursma set to become fourth family member to join AFL/AFLW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/willem-duursma-tipped-for-top-afl-national-draft-pick-west-coast/105999938</link><description>Willem Duursma's dancing feet could carry him all the way to the number-one pick at tomorrow night's AFL National Draft.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc905c920ae77b121913d5fcd4067338</guid></item><item><title>'Chronic' understaffing leaves Canberra's ambulance service on a 'knife's edge'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/act-ambulance-staffing-shortage-internal-review-knifes-edge/106023944</link><description>An internal review has revealed the service needs at least 80 additional ambulance officers, response times are worsening, and night shifts are failing to meet minimum staffing levels 96 per cent of the time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89b28c2537b0fd6e53e8f4b0b8d367d8</guid></item><item><title>Eli Katoa to miss 2026 NRL season after Melbourne Storm star's brain surgery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/eli-katoa-to-miss-2026-nrl-season/106024440</link><description>Melbourne Storm star Eli Katoa will miss the 2026 NRL season as he continues his recovery from head knocks that forced him to have brain surgery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5232341e3582eed41e32b4e562d739c</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu council repeals law banning menstruating women from selling food</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/vanuatu-menstruating-women-ban-selling-food-markets/106017328</link><description>A Vanuatu provincial government says it will repeal parts of its new bylaw banning menstruating women from preparing and selling food at markets and roadside stalls after the decision sparked a public outcry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">034f538d5d412c8217577c70505f422b</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos contamination of children's sand was a fluke discovery in an Australian lab</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/asbestos-sand-contamination-chance-discovery-in-australian-lab/106022486</link><description>An Australian lab discovered asbestos in children's play sand by chance and regulators only found out about it because of a podcast interview, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62364137d29d39242b79167919e508a9</guid></item><item><title>Inside The Hood Contender, Australia's controversial amateur fighting competition trying to save men's lives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/inside-the-hood-contender-controversial-amateur-fighting/106006086</link><description>The organiser of this fight club says it saves lives. But critics say it is putting young men at serious risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72aefa26eb296ef6083bcca281a4094a</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Lions recruit Neasa Dooley wanting to add more Irish success in AFLW preliminary final against Carlton Blues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/neasa-dooley-brisbane-lions-aflw-preliminary-final-carlton/106024288</link><description>No stranger to the big stage, Brisbane's Neasa Dooley wants a piece of what her fellow Irish imports have been selling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b39d76b6c1f3e81e97d4b65690c26dad</guid></item><item><title>Judge blocks use of National Guard in Memphis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/judge-blocks-use-of-national-guard-in-memphis/106023888</link><description>A Tennessee judge has blocked the use of the National Guard in Memphis, but also put the order on hold, giving the government five days to appeal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf7c320ab23bd2b565bb5781058f9dba</guid></item><item><title>What it's like being a male early childhood educator amid the childcare crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/what-it-is-like-being-a-male-educator-amid-the-childcare-crisis/105995392</link><description>While the childcare crisis has left me concerned about my own child's safety, as a male early childhood educator, I'm also worried about the future of men in the sector, writes Ben.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a62aba2abcb529305bf54887ade96ce5</guid></item><item><title>Parents in 'childcare desert' left scrambling as Playtime Preschool enters voluntary administration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/playtime-preschool-broken-hill-enters-voluntary-administration/106021714</link><description>One of the few childcare operators in Broken Hill has closed its doors indefinitely with 24 hours warning after entering voluntary administration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">645912bd0d8354ef6ba596b69e3361b2</guid></item><item><title>Defence inspector inadvertently omitted 10 consultations held with NACC chief Paul Brereton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/defence-inspector-omitted-consultations-with-nacc-chief/106023634</link><description>A previous disclosure that the head of the federal corruption watchdog had been consulted 11 times has been corrected to 21.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1781d5607362739f541e7ff802db05f6</guid></item><item><title>Sydney waste water likely origin of debris on Central Coast beaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/beach-greaseballs-likely-from-sydney-waste-water-system/106022634</link><description>Sydney Water is working to determine the source of high levels of grease and oil that caused debris balls to wash up on beaches across Sydney and the Central Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c33b5671c318dc726c5b28ea01fd417</guid></item><item><title>COP30 decision by South Korea to shut down coal a reckoning for Australian exports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/south-korea-coal-plant-closure-warning-on-australian-exports/106021660</link><description>In a move that has been welcomed by climate campaigners, South Korea has vowed to phase out coal, sparking a warning for Australian exporters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a1e49f91f32ca80234fe2254283c60c</guid></item><item><title>Numerous Tasmanian public, Catholic and independent schools to close from Wednesday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/catholic-public-independent-tasmanian-schools-closed-asbestos/106022702</link><description>More than 50 Tasmanian schools will either close or be partially closed from Wednesday in response to ongoing public health concerns relating to asbestos in coloured sand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f7a4638311fad228f17b1ee6e4650f</guid></item><item><title>Remote Aboriginal community of Tjuntjuntjara challenges local government election result</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/tjuntjuntjara-election-dispute/106019700</link><description>A remote Aboriginal corporation lodges a formal dispute over the outcome of a local government election decided by just one vote.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9ca57d6c316de3bf92b08f85b9f4912</guid></item><item><title>Most restrictive abortion bill in the US being considered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/most-restrictive-abortion-bill-in-the-us-being-considered/106024856</link><description>Restrictions on IUDs and IVF and decades of imprisonment for having an abortion could become the reality for some women living in South Carolina if the legislation passes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ef3cb80551fe490d0f6301954d7ffb7</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos contamination identified in imported coloured sand products</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/asbestos-contamination-identified-/106025112</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45782c7e825f6e9ae891619789b5b041</guid></item><item><title>Are tiger prawns labelled as being Australian, really from Australia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/are-your-australian-tiger-prawns-really-from-australia-/106025136</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b04250e60ba47b3ca2f1c4c23e21254</guid></item><item><title>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese heralds WA gallium project as 'game changing'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/anthony-albanese-hails-wa-role-in-us-critical-minerals-deal/106024178</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese visits the future West Australian gallium processing plant site, central to the United States critical minerals deal, heralding it as a "game changing" project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c597633a766fbe2ac505dfff6094f877</guid></item><item><title>Public hospitals wasting $1.2b a year and hindered by 'bogus budgets', Grattan Institute says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/public-hospital-wastage-grattan-institute-report/106019006</link><description>A new report recommends Australia’s public hospitals stop wasting money and adopt efficiency measures seen in other countries amid governmental tensions over a new funding deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fb764f3d78d4b1ae4ff6ec601222e32</guid></item><item><title>Poland says Russian intelligence likely behind railway sabotage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/poland-says-russian-intelligence-likely-behind-railway-sabotage/106025554</link><description>Polish authorities say "everything indicates" Russian involvement in a blast along a railway line used to transport goods to Ukraine, as they identify two people believed to be responsible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa547069580b98e715786b936d0c32b1</guid></item><item><title>Britain's MI5 spy service issues alert to MPs over Chinese espionage threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/britain-s-mi5-spy-service-warns-lawmakers-of-chinese-spy-risk/106025666</link><description>MI5 has warned that Chinese agents attempt to collect information and influence activity, posing the latest spy threat to the nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbfe6d820186bd439b3183c99fa6d171</guid></item><item><title>Japan warns citizens in China to be careful as diplomatic spat continues over Taiwan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/japan-warns-citizens-in-china-as-diplomatic-spat-continues/106025668</link><description>Authorities have told Japanese people in China to avoid large crowds, as tensions between Tokyo and Beijing continue to simmer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56948e21a448507e1c8128eabd1d690a</guid></item><item><title>Jess Wilson is the Victorian Liberals’ survival strategy. Are federal Liberals listening?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/victoria-liberal-party-gamble-jess-wilson-survival-federal/106024478</link><description>The Liberals in two big Australian states are realigning themselves — shifting to what Sussan Ley once described as the sensible centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b848213f89e676a20bde80e4634f44e</guid></item><item><title>How the Nintendo Wii's remote control changed gaming — one strike at a time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/nintendo-wii-release-anniversary/105971384</link><description>Innovative motion controls and accessible design made the Nintendo Wii one of the most popular consoles of all time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed1b3832f564dd508a1196eea55005ce</guid></item><item><title>Booker Prize quiz: Test your knowledge of the prestigious book award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/booker-prize-2025-quiz/105950622</link><description>The prestigious Booker Prize, worth $100,000, announced its 2025 winner last week. Do you remember who won? Test your knowledge of the world's favourite book awards with our quiz.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">744594b38b052e94f8b8562ab648c256</guid></item><item><title>Industry experts say TPG Telecom should have done more to address Triple Zero issue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/tpg-telecom-contact-customers-triple-zero-death/106022250</link><description>There are growing questions about whether one of Australia's largest telcos could have done more to ensure customers would be able to call Triple Zero.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c43bd54bc8b0f41677f4d307b5e3cc5b</guid></item><item><title>As Donald Trump's plan for Gaza gets UN approval, development proposals are circulating</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/rebuilding-gaza-donald-trump-plan-investment-potential/106006900</link><description>As Donald Trump's plan for Gaza gets UN approval, the proposals for how the territory might be developed are circulating and advocates are worried about who they ultimately benefit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebb4457531a367904752bce1bd7c9a88</guid></item><item><title>How often should you pay your mortgage to save?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/mortgage-repayments-frequency-fortnightly-or-monthly/105996588</link><description>Switching to fortnightly repayments from monthly — if you can afford it — can help you pay down your mortgage faster. Here’s why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6f78dfdd43c67b57f8f07db843eb41b</guid></item><item><title>Trainers of Melbourne and Caulfield Cup winner, Half Yours, welcomed home to Streaky Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/streaky-bay-mcevoy-melbourne-cup-half-yours-horse-racing-sa/106018384</link><description>Horse trainer Tony McEvoy returned to his hometown of Streaky Bay, on South Australia's west coast, with trophies in tow after his horse Half Yours' recent wins at the Caulfield and Melbourne cups.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c15e256c04df4da3fe3d8663c7da3931</guid></item><item><title>ACCC traces some coloured asbestos sand to 'a particular quarry in China'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/coloured-sand-with-asbestos-traced-to-china-quarry/106024514</link><description>Some of the coloured sand found to contain asbestos has been traced to a quarry in China, according to the ACCC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bd4812eb24af1cb61c507559c41dc9d</guid></item><item><title>US politics: Congress agrees to force release of Epstein files and paves way for Trump sign-off — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/blog-congress-to-vote-on-release-of-epstein-files/106017700</link><description>Both houses of the US Congress have agreed to force Justice officials to release documents relating to the investigation into convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein. Look back on the day's events here.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be2ca4287ee5d7258f85d4005953a1ae</guid></item><item><title>Family of missing schoolboy Terry Floyd accuse government of breaking promise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/family-of-terry-floyd-accuses-government-of-breaking-promise/106024176</link><description>The brother of schoolboy Terry Floyd, who disappeared 50 years ago, has accused the Victorian government of breaking its public promise to fund the search for his remains.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edc7716e2290375f31b58757b011a642</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos sand contamination leaves families seeking clearer house cleaning, disposal guidance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/safely-clean-homes-sand-recall-australia/106022792</link><description>One Queensland grandmother says her daughter had vacuumed, and even replaced her vacuum cleaner, after removing the asbestos-contaminated sand following "confusing" advice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf0f5c8480339c7e164cc723d6544c74</guid></item><item><title>US Senate passes bill to release Epstein files in win for defiant Republicans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/epstein-files-bill-passes-us-congress/106023130</link><description>The bill's passage marks a major win for a small group of Republicans who defied pressure from the Trump White House to drop their crusade for the release of the Epstein files.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d8a9ed2bd40d382bfe0031c7709ed40</guid></item><item><title>England's Joe Root backed to make first Ashes Test century in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/ashes-cricket-england-australia-joe-root-first-test-perth/106025838</link><description>With the first Ashes clash only two days away, Joe Root's England teammates are unfazed by the fact he has not scored a Test century in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a56c37032f0d2b050fb2a8565664b59</guid></item><item><title>The AFL draft might be broken for the league's biggest strugglers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/the-afl-draft-might-be-broken-for-leagues-strugglers/106011254</link><description>The AFL draft is more complicated and compromised than ever before, meaning clubs rebuilding from the bottom of the ladder are doing so with one arm tied behind their backs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b049c7cc8c0729242481a853525bc9b3</guid></item><item><title>Understanding ADHD symptoms such as RSD, hyper-focus, task paralysis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/adhd-symptoms-signs-rsd-task-paralysis-hyper-focus-mental-health/104803078</link><description>Some people refer to attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder as "a superpower" while others describe their ADHD symptoms as debilitating. Can both be true?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f5dc0dc0e577bb893421a05d4dcc8d9</guid></item><item><title>ABC host Sharnelle Vella expecting a baby after fertility struggle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/abc-presenter-sharnelle-vella-pregnant-ivf-struggles/106023456</link><description>The ABC Radio Melbourne breakfast co-host and her husband say they are overjoyed but terrified as they prepare for the birth of their baby girl in March.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd8fbc9127dd022b28d103cbdade634e</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies star Joseph-Aukuso Suaalii in contention for prestigious World Rugby award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/wallabies-joseph-aukuso-suaalii-nominated-for-world-rugby-award/106025892</link><description>Wallabies outside centre Joseph-Aukuso Suaalii is recognised for his performances since switching codes from rugby league late last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75eb964d2b6306bc3f841f2b522ed648</guid></item><item><title>As autism diagnoses rise, experts caution against 'non-evidenced treatments'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/caution-over-oxygen-therapy-as-autism-treatment/106019362</link><description>Experts warn against signing up for autism therapies that are not evidence-based, as diagnoses rise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d6fcccbaf2f52bbf378787f7c54bf00</guid></item><item><title>NSW government to bring in tougher laws to combat public displays of Nazi ideology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/nsw-government-nazi-laws-amendment-parliament-rally/106025436</link><description>Police and courts will be given greater powers to combat public displays of Nazi ideology in NSW following a rally outside state parliament earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47706493835ce08f5a7f9523a999135f</guid></item><item><title>Mechelle Turvey leads calls for more Indigenous community liaison officers in WA Police Force</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/call-for-more-indigenous-community-liaison-officers-in-wa/106010684</link><description>Cassius Turvey's mother Mechelle is leading the call for WA Police to hire more Indigenous community liaison officers, saying just 20 officers to serve the entire state was nowhere near enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd1c8df65d5719800a3d0daad43de243</guid></item><item><title>Stephanie Gilmore announces World Surf League Championship Tour comeback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/surfing-australia-stephanie-gilmore-announces-wsl-comeback/106025994</link><description>Two years after stepping away from the tour, Australian surfing legend Stephanie Gilmore will make her return in 2026 after being awarded a season wildcard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">191d6532923bf7bc7499f3b4cb9f69bf</guid></item><item><title>West Coast's rebuild is at a critical juncture. This draft could make or break it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/west-coast-eagles-2025-afl-draft-preview/105866808</link><description>The worst performing team in the AFL has a bumper hand in this year's national draft. How it uses it will shape the club's fortunes for the next decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da644df515da05cd845c47dbe806b5f4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump insists visiting Saudi crown prince knew nothing about Jamal Khashoggi killing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/donald-trump-defends-mohammed-bin-salman-jamal-khashoggi-killing/106025864</link><description>US President Donald Trump warmly welcomes the Saudi crown prince to the White House where he deflects journalists' questions about Mohammed bin Salman's role in the killing of reporter Jamal Khashoggi, saying: "Things happened, but he knew nothing about it."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2635a8708158f7659bb93c0b10e90738</guid></item><item><title>Legislation to stop councils rating some mining land passes lower house of parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/miscellaneous-rate-local-government-reform-bankrupt-mount-magnet/106019936</link><description>The Mount Magnet shire says its reserves would shrink from $3 million to $300,000 if a bill to block shires from rating certain mining land is passed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">215fea21433337ed7027887199ccecf3</guid></item><item><title>How to watch the 2025 AFL draft and what time does the coverage begin?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/afl-draft-2025-how-to-watch-and-what-time-does-it-start/106026096</link><description>Another AFL draft has arrived, offering dozens of teenage footballers the chance to realise their dreams. Here is everything you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16bb0a1d8942d9c358894ebf311bd860</guid></item><item><title>Trump defends Saudi crown prince at Washington talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/trump-defends-saudi-crown-prince-at-washington-talks/106026110</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d05262cc217e7f8b3724d79edd5c2ce8</guid></item><item><title>Carlos Alcaraz withdraws from Spain's Davis Cup Finals campaign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/davis-cup-finals-carlos-alcaraz-pulls-out-of-spain-campaign/106026144</link><description>Just days after going down to Jannik Sinner in the ATP Finals decider, world number one Carlos Alcaraz is forced to pull out of Spain's Davis Cup campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58bfba26ee9d97cc72b3617f6853d27e</guid></item><item><title>Game designed to save dying Aboriginal language wins global awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/aboriginal-language-game-wins-global-award/105975448</link><description>With only eight fluent Nyiyaparli speakers remaining, an Aboriginal group is racing against time to save its 41,000-year-old language.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ae26c1d700be95bac9b13ea5fb11781</guid></item><item><title>Tongans are heading to the polls for just the fifth time. Is their young democracy on the line?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/tonga-election-king-democracy-noble-votes/106022830</link><description>Tongans are heading to the polls this week amid concerns that democratic reforms in the country could be short-lived.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90d8fec4a58c871d7b2f35edf9dfb0a4</guid></item><item><title>Scotland defeats Denmark 4-2 to qualify for World Cup finals after stunning goal by Scott McTominay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/fifa-world-cup-scotland-beat-denmark-scott-mctominay/106026514</link><description>A breathtaking goal from Scott McTominay paves the way for Scotland to qualify for the World Cup finals after a 28-year absence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3d2b6eb3ace5d406a2886b25849f494</guid></item><item><title>Israeli air strike on a Palestinian refugee camp in Lebanon has killed 13 people, Lebanese ministry says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/israel-strike-palestinian-refugee-camp/106026280</link><description>It was the deadliest strike on Lebanon since a ceasefire in the Israel-Hezbollah war a year ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69b213869d4ad1126549bd9e9b5b98e4</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos coach Tony Popovic fumes at penalty decision in 3-0 friendly loss to Colombia in New York</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/socceroos-vs-colombia-new-york-live-blog/106026972</link><description>Socceroos coach Tony Popovic laments a "disappointing" penalty decision as the Socceroos fall to a 3-0 loss to Colombia in New York.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7d3fc982270b2839d0e5643620424f0</guid></item><item><title>Now that US Congress has voted to release the Jeffrey Epstein files, here is what happens next</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/where-does-the-jeffrey-epstein-files-bill-go-from-here/106023134</link><description>The Epstein Files Transparency Act sailed through both the US House of Representatives and the Senate in a single Washington afternoon. This is how we got here, and what could happen next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">983bc3fe7484c4765b07d5ee8bbedb7b</guid></item><item><title>Through dust and drought, these women are redefining resilience</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/through-dust-and-drought-these-women-are-redefining-resilience/106024268</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15ec73793bc09515a28939cf16fbf8df</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide University co-vice chancellors share complexities of uni merger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/sa-adelaide-university-co-vice-chancellors-on-uni-merger/106022624</link><description>The co-vice chancellors of the new Adelaide University says the mammoth task of merging two universities has its own complexities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb603c46b9a5c5d629e8740bb5354491</guid></item><item><title>ACT joins SA in calls for urgent national inquiry into how asbestos sand entered Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/sa-minister-calls-for-urgent-national-inquiry-into-asbestos-sand/106026188</link><description>The SA and ACT education ministers are calling for a national inquiry into how coloured play sand contaminated with asbestos was imported into the country, with more than 450 SA Department for Education sites now impacted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">325123170c9d15d9ae9fab868a3931a8</guid></item><item><title>Cristiano Ronaldo and Elon Musk among special guests at dinner with Donald Trump and Saudi crown prince</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/cristiano-ronaldo-elon-musk-attend-white-house-dinner-with-trump/106026916</link><description>Elon Musk made his first visit to the White House since leaving his role in the Trump administration earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c6371da04de34d6b3e6e8274701ed2e</guid></item><item><title>Singapore's world-first sustainable flights tax will see some Australians pay more to travel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/singapore-sustainable-aviation-fuel-levy-costs-explained/106018080</link><description>Passenger flights from Singapore are set to become more costly after the announcement of a world-first sustainable fuel tax to be included in travellers' ticket prices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3b8ecfebbce340233bee01dc6c768ed</guid></item><item><title>ARIAs 2025 red carpet: Olivia Dean, Emma Watkins, Abbie Chatfield and Tkay Maidza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/2025-arias-red-carpet-australian-music-awards/106027182</link><description>The best and brightest on the Australian music scene have gathered at Sydney's Hordern Pavilion. Here's a wrap of the awards show looks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04e317e4f18eccf6c9508a574d55557e</guid></item><item><title>Tony Award winner Marg Horwell turns classic opera into technicolour spectacle in Carmen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/marg-horwell-the-picture-of-dorian-gray-tony-award-carmen/105399248</link><description>Growing up, Aussie Marg Horwell wanted to be an actor, but soon found she had an affinity for set and costume design that has taken her to Broadway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9d28b2c0fef079e1666ea65b681e1ae</guid></item><item><title>ABC managing director tells journalists not to 'second-guess' their work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/abc-managing-director-addresses-national-press-club/106027282</link><description>In an address to the National Press Club, Hugh Marks says he inherited a "fearfulness" within the public broadcaster but that it is improving in its response to mistakes and external scrutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30fa8df2acb0c7d4cd665d2905619cab</guid></item><item><title>Only three schools to remain closed in the ACT while 13 partially open as asbestos clean-up continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/schools-closed-in-canberra-thursday-sand-update/106026448</link><description>One school which had earlier been re-opened will now be closed for the rest of the week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">463476aff0a256987aeda8403d1493c9</guid></item><item><title>ARIAs 2025: Stars arrive for Australian music's night of nights — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/arias-2025-live-red-carpet-kicks-off-australian-music/106021634</link><description>Amyl and the Sniffers took home four awards, including Album of the Year, while Missy Higgins and Ninajirachi also claimed gongs at this year's ARIAs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7648db90a9977c2fa24b1ec93ff5a3fa</guid></item><item><title>Curaçao and Haiti defy the odds to secure qualification for 2026 FIFA World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/curacao-smallest-nation-qualify-fifa-world-cup/106028664</link><description>With a population of just over 150,000, the Caribbean island nation of Curaçao will become the smallest nation ever to play at the World Cup after a scoreless draw with Jamaica secured its passage to next year's tournament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ed66b16180fb1f8ca7328f88816e81b</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Fina tracker map: Where the cyclone is now and when it will hit NT coastline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/cyclone-fina-tracker-map/106027654</link><description>The system has the potential to make landfall on the Northern Territory coast by Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e7090ae318e11feb953638159042ae6</guid></item><item><title>Have the Epstein files 'ripped MAGA apart'? Maybe not, but there will be fallout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/donald-trump-epstein-files-unlikely-series-of-events/106022276</link><description>Before the Epstein files vote, Washington woke to a zero-degree morning, and Marjorie Taylor Greene could see the symbolism. "My first thought was: hell has froze over," she said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8fa2d68e358b4d999b0eb88aee5f304</guid></item><item><title>States launch coordinated attack on federal handling of public hospital negotiations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/states-launch-attack-on-hospital-funding-negotiations/106029008</link><description>State and territory leaders hold an emergency meeting over public hospital funding, declaring they cannot sacrifice hospital care to bolster the Commonwealth's finances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">217244d2b953af692ad03226c3cb9187</guid></item><item><title>ARIA Awards 2025 winners' list: every winner at this year's ceremony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/aria-awards-winners-list-2025/106029368</link><description>Catch up on all the trophy winners at the 2025 ARIA Awards, which took place at Sydney's Hordern Pavilion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c88fe3a46cb9338fd3656bdbb425bdce</guid></item><item><title>New survey reveals mass coral death at Ningaloo Reef as critical summer looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/ningaloo-reef-coral-mortality-survey/106023012</link><description>Scientists say they are "speechless" after witnessing significant coral death at the World Heritage-listed Ningaloo Reef.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d23aba9c243a71558bd4993f8fc9234e</guid></item><item><title>As the clean-up of coloured sand continues, how long will Tasmanian schools to be closed for?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/coloured-sand-asbestos-schools-tasmania/106026868</link><description>Schools closed as a result of the coloured sand recall are starting to reopen, however some will remain closed on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10656cef5bbbfb4a7a7ec576c72f2276</guid></item><item><title>AFL draft 2025 first round recap: Willem Duursma joins Eagles as Suns and Bombers emerge big winners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/afl-draft-2025-first-round-live-blog/106029566</link><description>After being selected as the first overall pick in the AFL draft, Willem Duursma is excited about the prosect of teaming up with Eagles star Harley Reid next season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45e3a6390b0d8382b9f8d4a68f2b52b4</guid></item><item><title>Odours from Ipswich industrial estates, west of Brisbane, are offensive and negatively impact residents, inquiry finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/queensland-government-releases-swanbank-new-chum-odour-inquiry/106028374</link><description>Residents who have been raising concerns about the odours for more than a decade say the findings have vindicated what they have been saying all along.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15005718c9819c61a73322e59ef483d7</guid></item><item><title>WA environment minister green-lights $300 million Cockatoo Island aviation and marine hub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/cockatoo-island-aviation-and-marine-hub-approved/106028934</link><description>A $300 million multi-user supply base is set to be built on Cockatoo Island, off the northern West Australian coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6592852bcfd92ca02968bb7b82abfef2</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106028300</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5f151ed57282a34ff987e5288c757e8</guid></item><item><title>Mary Fowler reveals she experienced depression, self-harm and racism during time with French club Montpellier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/mary-fowler-reveals-she-experienced-depression-racism-in-france/106030002</link><description>Socceroos star Mary Fowler says she dealt with depression and self-harm, as well as racism from her teammates during her time with Montpellier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f2e389d1f9b053418758ad588bc0dc0</guid></item><item><title>PFAS inquiry hands down 47 recommendations to better regulate 'forever chemicals' in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/pfas-inquiry-hopes-to-strengthen-regulation-human-health/106026416</link><description>The federal inquiry into "forever chemicals" has asked the federal government to review its health advice on PFAS in light of the growing international consensus of its health risks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16c9f4d1e8356866711da7747cbb2870</guid></item><item><title>SA opposition pledges $21m fishing licence buyback amid toxic algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/sa-liberals-fishing-licence-buyback-plan-amid-algal-bloom/106028960</link><description>The South Australian opposition has pledged a $21-million voluntary fisheries buyback scheme, if it is elected next year, to allow commercial fishers to leave the industry amid the harmful algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cf61e92e71e5ec09bc996fff28ea4ac</guid></item><item><title>Cricket’s oldest rivalry begins again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/cricket-s-oldest-rivalry-begins-again/106029462</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c16b281edce652d4e9aef0b986db027</guid></item><item><title>Family that used potentially asbestos-contaminated coloured sand at Diwali want clear action points</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/potentially-asbestos-contaminated-coloured-sand-at-diwali/106027712</link><description>A Canberra mother who used coloured sand to celebrate Diwali in her backyard wants more help from WorkSafe ACT after being advised to cordon off the area, a thoroughfare to her home, and call an asbestos company.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af8530e2f06c12d82beb834e36041e2b</guid></item><item><title>Government canvasses Pacific leaders on backdown option for COP31</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/australia-canvasses-backdown-option-on-cop31-bid/106029536</link><description>The federal government has begun to contact Pacific leaders to canvass a COP31 "Plan B" which would see Adelaide abandon its bid for the global United Nations climate summit so long as Pacific nations are guaranteed a role in next year's conference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a062d4677ea143a8fd04aa299fbf8e3</guid></item><item><title>ARIA Awards 2025 winners: Amyl &amp; The Sniffers and Ninajirachi dominate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/aria-awards-2025-arias-amyl-sniffers-ninajirachi/106030024</link><description>The ARIAs belonged to two relative underdogs this year. Don't know who they are? It's time to pay attention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06a4864d529f3ee2e752cc3a92cb73de</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia's Semeru volcano erupts prompting aviation warning in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/indonesian-volcano-semeru-erupts-prompting-ash-aviation-warning/106030342</link><description>Indonesia's Mount Semeru volcano erupts, spewing ash several kilometres into the air and prompting an aviation warning in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91afb5744cd1d11e50f864001aebe71d</guid></item><item><title>Russian barrage kills 25 in Ukraine city as Zelenskyy holds talks with Turkish leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/russian-barrage-kills-25-in-ukraine-city/106030344</link><description>A Russian drone and missile barrage has killed 25 people, including two children, in a western Ukrainian city, around 200 kilometres from the Polish border.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acb8918f200b1e693b818bfa4c54a715</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley to call for urgent action on defence in Menzies Institute speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/sussan-ley-speech-defence-energy-national-resilience-menzies/106030370</link><description>The opposition leader will pledge to spend 3 per cent of GDP on defence during a speech at the Menzies Institute in Melbourne on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71bf778a383dedad35ad14debc7ae286</guid></item><item><title>Fire kills at least one person and damages 170 buildings in city of Oita in Japan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/one-person-killed-170-buildings-damaged-by-fire-in-oita-japan/106030480</link><description>Authorities are still working to extinguish the blaze, which has spread to nearby woodland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">953b9612c1eebfd98f2231ee226a5728</guid></item><item><title>The EU's been accused of caving to big tech on AI regulation. Here's why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/eu-ai-big-tech-proposals/106030486</link><description>Artificial intelligence could be trained using the sensitive health data of European citizens under proposed changes to the EU's rules on the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9533adc8e882f6ee94594b6bf47709d6</guid></item><item><title>UK 'ready to act' as Russian spy ship nears British territory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/uk-vows-to-act-as-russian-vessel-strays-close-to-territory/106030534</link><description>The Russian vessel had directed lasers at pilots of surveillance aircraft monitoring its activities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5f105e3a3da77133c610722c4fc142a</guid></item><item><title>CSIRO cuts highlight which jobs government protects in national interest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/tomago-smelters-science-csiro-funding-cuts/106026312</link><description>The prime minister, when in opposition, accused the Coalition of "hollowing out" the CSIRO. Now, following the announcement 350 research positions at the organisation will be cut, he is being accused of being "worse than Abbott".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a48ad6eb307918a7a0fbedd8ad51df8</guid></item><item><title>Can you guess the distance between Australian cities? It's not as easy as you think</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/australian-cities-distance-quiz/106018708</link><description>Warning: this quiz is tough — how good are you at guesstimating how far apart Australian cities are?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb6a902ea73b0236c6c9e85aa0814112</guid></item><item><title>The International Space Station made colleagues out of Cold War rivals in a new space era</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/today-in-history-november-20-international-space-station/106029526</link><description>It was November 20, 1998, and a rocket wasn't an unusual sight in this remote part of Kazakhstan. But today's cargo was a piece of history that would have seemed impossible just years before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b107d78810ceafa636fffbea5b00f5a5</guid></item><item><title>Cricket Tasmania and stadium proponent say they've found a solution to roof concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/cricket-macquirie-point-stadium-roof-solution/106028094</link><description>Cricket Tasmania and the Macquarie Point stadium proponent believe they have found the solution to concerns about how the stadium's roof could affect cricket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1568eec0cb6e7395d72f32f0d6164871</guid></item><item><title>Home owners say insurance firms failing to pay plumbing works claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/plumbing-insurance-claims-fail-despite-ministerial-order/106017148</link><description>Home owners are demanding action after years trying to access insurance payouts for failed plumbing work that has left properties a mess and, in some cases, unliveable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa639fed7e56490249b8962baf15f9b0</guid></item><item><title>Coloured sand recall to cost Stroud after-school care operator thousands of dollars for small clean-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/coloured-sand-asbestos-removal-cost/106029248</link><description>A regional NSW after-school hours operator says an asbestos removal company wanted to charge her more than $14,000 to vacuum up a small amount of coloured sand that spilled onto a carpet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08758b1448ee208283595c9d094d84b4</guid></item><item><title>UWU boss Tim Kennedy accused of 'misleading' members about links to slush fund</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/uwu-national-secretary-tim-kennedy-accused-of-slush-fund-links/106028936</link><description>The head of one of Australia's most powerful unions has suffered a vote of no confidence amid claims he was aware of allegedly improper use of members' resources to raise money from bosses for an election slush fund.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f50189b9c9d42087f275770ffc707321</guid></item><item><title>Small-town cleaner in legal battle with EnduroShield over product packaging</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/enduroshield-takes-action-against-window-cleaner/106004284</link><description>A multinational company is taking a small-town Australian cleaner to court, claiming his glass-cleaning product is deceptively similar to its own.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b964056656fd7bf29d5ab94c84134ec</guid></item><item><title>New mining laws frustrate farmers but mining companies say they are a step forward</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/mining-law-changes-farmers-uncertainty-south-australia/106014860</link><description>South Australia's mining minister now has the power to extend mining leases, which farmers say makes the future of their land "uncertain".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6906c8398ce8b82ced740196f4b43a8</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Fina tracker map: Where the cyclone is now and when it will hit NT coastline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/cyclone-fina-tracker/106029170</link><description>Tropical Cyclone Fina, currently packing sustained winds of 95 kilometres per hour near its centre, is expected to turn south towards the Top End coast today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39b91e34f476c33060e4570ca93f0658</guid></item><item><title>FOI data shows Australian mining and manufacturing sectors take months to detect cyber breaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/delays-detecting-data-breaches-australian-mining-manufacturing/105978234</link><description>Australia's mining and manufacturing sectors are taking up to two years to notice and report cyber breaches to authorities, prompting concerns about the data security of industries critical to the nation's economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9e3c9e78e3c97ec12b11b398f2f9b97</guid></item><item><title>Nangs to be seized under new Queensland laws cracking down on sale of illegal tobacco and nicotine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/authorities-to-seize-nangs-illegal-tobacco-nicotine-laws/106026300</link><description>Nitrous oxide bulbs and canisters, known colloquially as nangs, can lead to paralysis when consumed in large quantities over an extended period of time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2e91f330142e71a52375ec4bce5d68c</guid></item><item><title>England names Jofra Archer and Mark Wood in squad for first Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/ashes-cricket-england-names-jofra-archer-mark-wood/106030626</link><description>England is yet to confirm its final XI, but damaging fast bowlers Jofra Archer and Mark Wood may team up to take on Australia in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ea1cd9e5fd7cbb04f21b9c4d1f7e8d8</guid></item><item><title>Wicked: For Good captures the spirit of the stage musical’s second act — for better and for worse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/wicked-for-good-review-ariana-grande-cynthia-erivo/106027036</link><description>Ariana Grande and Cynthia Erivo shine in Wicked: For Good, but does the sequel live up to the thrill of its predecessor?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2a3cdab2d324d4c0600c6ee28d1ab74</guid></item><item><title>Calls for NSW Police to end high-speed pursuits for minor offences after crash deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/nsw-police-high-speed-pursuit-deaths-call-for-end/106029986</link><description>Harri Jokinen is one of several people who died from accidents during pursuits involving NSW Police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fc10670b1bd0c030f1d3f89d19c3c18</guid></item><item><title>NSW government refuses to lift licence restriction until Tahmoor Coal pays $29.4 million royalty debt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/nsw-refuses-tahmoor-lease-charge-gupta/106028250</link><description>A restriction on Tahmoor Coal's licence will not be removed until $29.4 million in outstanding royalties are paid to the NSW government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f08c04450f11aac2ab2ed76caa9badc</guid></item><item><title>Israeli air strikes kill 25 in Gaza as military continues attacking Lebanon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/israel-strikes-kill-palestinians-in-gaza-and-hit-lebanon/106030644</link><description>The Israeli military says its forces struck Hamas targets across Gaza after members of the Palestinian militant group fired on its troops in violation of the nearly six-week-old ceasefire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5b8952a0fa5b9fc588da4aa330feb1a</guid></item><item><title>NT prepares for Tropical Cyclone Fina as it tracks towards coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/tropical-cyclone-fina-natural-disaster-preparing-north-australia/106025350</link><description>Residents along the NT coast are preparing for a rare November cyclone to make landfall on Saturday by cutting down tree branches, stocking up on goods and making decisions about where to bunker down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f39e22af4d6e390481b30fd9c8c6b054</guid></item><item><title>ASX, Nikkei jump despite Japanese bond jitters, DroneShield falls again — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-20-november/106028890</link><description>The ASX posted its strongest gain since mid-July, while the Nikkei soared as Japanese government bonds were sold off and the yen fell sharply.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7c3ea2ea9bbeead65cc15eba5b812a2</guid></item><item><title>Stronger Tasmanian dog welfare laws to help prevent puppy farms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/stronger-tasmanian-dog-laws-to-prevent-puppy-farms/106027218</link><description>A position paper sets out limits for breeders and proposes an information sharing system for better regulation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0494615272ccf8bde5ac70d0d76b8fff</guid></item><item><title>These semi-pros are changing the face of international football</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/semi-pros-npl-changing-face-of-international-football/105978140</link><description>Although only semi-professional footballers, these players are helping reshape the face of the game for less-established football nations, while representing their heritage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09d427e2378ea489214dee66baeb2ea9</guid></item><item><title>Boarding students worry government's social media ban will isolate them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/boarders-social-media-ban-will-isolate-them/106024722</link><description>Boarders living thousands of kilometres from home, already vulnerable to isolation, are coming to terms with the government's under-16 social media ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b7ae5f10b5a0da2b854ade70d9665c8</guid></item><item><title>Ash spews from Indonesia's Semeru volcano</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/ash-spews-from-indonesia-s-semeru-volcano-/106030764</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f6f66f92f1747fb2c8397657da8689a</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri tipped to fight back in F1 championship at Las Vegas Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/f1-las-vegas-oscar-piastri-mclaren-lando-norris/106030732</link><description>Oscar Piastri is backed to regain form in the final three races of the F1 championship, despite the Australian trailing teammate Lando Norris on the drivers' standings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75407edc2c2f29c4799c37caac473093</guid></item><item><title>Alternative protein sector expected to triple worldwide by 2032 but struggles for investment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/australia-stunted-in-growing-alternative-proteins-market/105897824</link><description>The world is facing a crisis in food production and alternative sources of protein can be part of the solution, but the fledgling Australian sector is struggling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8131a0abdf6bde7d19075756fa94b347</guid></item><item><title>NASA unveils close-up pictures of Comet 3I/Atlas in our solar system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/comet-31-atlas-new-images/106030712</link><description>Discovered in July this year, the comet known as 3I/Atlas is only the third confirmed object to visit our corner of the cosmos from another star.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddacb7ecb880b6ea372716a2c3bf1722</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr set to be fit for Matildas internationals against New Zealand despite Chelsea omission</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/matildas-captain-sam-kerr-left-out-by-chelsea/106030886</link><description>Sam Kerr will miss Chelsea's Women's Champions League match against Barcelona on Friday, just days after her club manager said she was likely to play.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67401b26c31a3593fda924b14c8d8eaf</guid></item><item><title>Rupertswood: The Birthplace of the Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/rupertswood-the-birthplace-of-the-ashes/106027000</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0c80d09c33301400a6b208ac0a58a03</guid></item><item><title>Major retirement developments approved for Bundaberg coastline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/retirement-housing-boom-bundaberg-coastline/106019174</link><description>Thousands of retirement and relocatable homes are either under construction or have been approved along a regional Queensland coastline known for its pristine beaches and "affordable" lifestyle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a9bc2be410c478e881db6ef438e014e</guid></item><item><title>Police pulling Aboriginal teenager from bus at gunpoint was 'racial profiling', family alleges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/aboriginal-17yo-pulled-bus-gunpoint-mistaken-racial-profiling/106029782</link><description>The family of a 17-year-old Indigenous boy says he was racially profiled when he was pulled from a Canberra bus by police officers who handcuffed him before realising he was the wrong person.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b705f0c8b73fdd3a28a5627c29d87576</guid></item><item><title>Kempsey to host New South Wales first trial of in-home mental health treatment service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/hospital-at-home-mental-health-trial-in-kemspey/106026032</link><description>NSW will run a state-first trial that will offer mental health patients care in their own home, but it will mean the town trialling the system loses its hospital-based mental health unit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53def224e416326d184ce0d7f3c67b5a</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Fina set to impact NT coastal communities between Cape Don and Maningrida from late Friday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/cyclone-fina-thursday-watch-area-extended-to-darwin/106030822</link><description>The BOM's latest track map shows that Tropical Cyclone Fina has been temporarily downgraded to a category one system, but is set to intensify again by 7am Friday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e97bc5634f82f09c58cecf87bf81b862</guid></item><item><title>G20 leaders are 'saving the furniture' as Trump leads a boycott</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/g20-trump-boycott-albanese-save-furniture/106031090</link><description>Trump's absence could neuter the forum's ability to move the dial on the summit's priorities, including helping nations adapt to weather disasters, the transition to clean energy, cutting excessive debt costs and working together in the global rush for critical minerals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e98646c243827f50217859135024b87</guid></item><item><title>Reserve prices to be published under Victorian government underquoting crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/victorian-government-announces-real-estate-underquoting-laws/106031070</link><description>Real estate agents in Victoria will be required to publish a property's reserve price at least seven days before it goes to auction, under new laws the state government says will stamp out illegal underquoting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2554ec0f2c51a8214785261d30228c6</guid></item><item><title>Australia hands COP31 to Türkiye but Chris Bowen to lead negotiations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/australia-withdraws-bid-to-host-cop31-in-adelaide/106031148</link><description>Adelaide will not host next year's COP summit, but Australia's energy minister, Chris Bowen, will lead the negotiations, and a pre-event will be hosted by a Pacific Island nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dba1ce2d18da474e58c8c313d67f6cee</guid></item><item><title>Is it possible to build a flood-proof house on the banks of the Brisbane River?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/grand-designs-australia-sherwood-flood-house-design/105862434</link><description>Only someone whose family has long lived next to a river famous for catastrophic flooding would dare to build on this block. Here's what we can all learn from Richard and Janette's new home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d49fe0f182145d4a9e668db17f74da5</guid></item><item><title>Blaithin Mackin loves playing Gaelic and AFLW but it means living a double life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/blaithin-mackin-double-life-of-an-irish-aflw-player/106017896</link><description>Melbourne premiership player Blaithin Mackin loves playing both Gaelic and AFLW — but it means living a double life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c2c14d671cb052509722c0c5be0d8d</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump signs Epstein files bill into law, triggering 30-day deadline for document release</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/donald-trump-sign-jeffrey-epstein-files-release-bill/106030528</link><description>US President Donald Trump says he has signed off on legislation to force the release of the "Epstein files" — the final step required to turn the bill into law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee7566ccad4fd6aa209cec5818dbd086</guid></item><item><title>Meta's teen ban is looming — here's how you can download your content</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/meta-teen-ban-looming-download-content/106031186</link><description>Meta warns it will start axing the Meta accounts of under 16s from December 4. Here's how you can download your data before then.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07aaf7fb89d7b224c51ec76c8072e531</guid></item><item><title>Man charged over allegedly abandoning Arnie the German shepherd in car after claiming dog and vehicle were stolen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/qld-man-charged-for-leaving-dog-in-car/106031602</link><description>Queensland Police had been investigating the alleged theft of a vehicle and Arnie the German shepherd, from Brisbane's bayside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97431c8dbfd546506c7b8b7aa4db3c4a</guid></item><item><title>Kumanjayi White's family says NT DPP too slow to deliver death in custody findings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/kumanjayi-white-family-waiting-six-months-to-hear-from-nt-dpp/106031194</link><description>Kumanjayi White investigation continues six months on from his death as the Department of Public Prosecutions awaits "the provision of further material" from NT Police. But the family says the findings are taking too long.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0983ab3f0d64b0518ca80bb75c9ff80f</guid></item><item><title>F1 Las Vegas start time, how to watch grand prix, and drivers' championship standings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/f1-las-vegas-grand-prix-start-time-how-to-watch-driver-standings/105995164</link><description>Oscar Piastri enters the third-last grand prix of the season further away from the drivers' championship lead than he has been all year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">513745de325ae8be77700ff5e180fe3d</guid></item><item><title>Australia names first Ashes Test team, with Jake Weatherald and Brendan Doggett set to debut in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/ashes-cricket-australia-england-perth-weatherald-doggett/106032328</link><description>Australia is set to blood two debutants in a Test for the first time since 2019 as the Ashes get underway in Perth on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f79b45dcdb0e02ab9643759464cc527d</guid></item><item><title>Mexican woman jailed in connection with killings of Australian surfers Jake and Callum Robinson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/mexico-surfer-killings-robbery-accused-in-court/106030690</link><description>A woman has been sentenced to 20 years in jail for her role in a robbery in which three men, including two Australian brothers, were killed in Mexico last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e41dfec47788e6a1b4ae8abfc69c4301</guid></item><item><title>The big names and shows coming to the ABC in 2026, from Julia Morris in Class Clowns to Guy Sebastian in The Piano</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/abc-showcase-2026-julia-morris-class-clowns-guy-sebastian-piano/106019564</link><description>Stars including Anne Edmonds, Sam Pang and Shaun Tan are attached to the ABC's 2026 line-up with old audience favourites and new series coming next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">387388f746e85eb1a8acf54aa5d5acbc</guid></item><item><title>Hotels 'disappointed' by COP31 loss, but SA Premier suggests future bid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/adelaide-wont-host-cop-31-after-hosting-rights-ceded-to-turkiye/106030902</link><description>South Australian Premier Peter Malinauskas has not given up hope for Adelaide to potentially host the UN climate summit in the future, after Australia ceded the hosting rights for next year's event to Türkiye.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef322dfa7ce099b28a13f9b0582762c7</guid></item><item><title>Joe Root's century drought in Australia could end this Ashes — but where is it most likely to happen?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/the-ashes-can-joe-root-end-his-australian-century-drought/106030856</link><description>He's one of the best batters in the world right now, but Joe Root is yet to score a century on Australian soil — can he finally end that drought this summer?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">985568a0f0c7fd5ed25c14b93900f746</guid></item><item><title>Docklands to be ready for BBL cricket as Melbourne Renegades consider move</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/docklands-to-be-ready-for-bbl-as-renegades-consider-move/106033196</link><description>The boss of Docklands Stadium insists a decision to pivot to entertainment events will not lead to lacklustre BBL pitches, as the Melbourne Renegades weigh up their future at the ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fb23fbded45f15c55bce8032e6cb3a0</guid></item><item><title>EPA investigating after hundreds of fish found dead in Victoria's Tarwin River</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/hundreds-of-fish-dead-berrys-creek-tarwin-river/105802950</link><description>The Environment Protection Authority investigates the death of hundreds of fish in the Tarwin River in Victoria's South Gippsland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f8b92b2f9c4a4b2d66447d414f6a566</guid></item><item><title>Why celebrity scandals can leave us feeling shattered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/why-celebrity-scandals-can-leave-us-feeling-shattered/105991484</link><description>Whether it's controversy around a jeans ad, voting for a political party you disagree with, or criminal allegations, it can feel confronting to learn more about a person you admire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">203139f74d1c4e9da21f147451a6c068</guid></item><item><title>Narco subs appear in Pacific amid warnings cartels are ramping up trafficking to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/narco-subs-pacific-cartels-trafficking-drugs-to-australia/106018290</link><description>The discovery of narco subs bearing the hallmarks of boats used by Mexican and South American drug cartels has intensified warnings that international syndicates are increasingly targeting the lucrative Australian and New Zealand illicit drug markets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b00ad2bef188e759a8275575619863</guid></item><item><title>Mother allegedly locked manslaughter victim in alarmed room, neglect trial hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/jenni-wilmott-jasmine-trial-child-police-interview-locked-door/105938536</link><description>A mother standing trial for the alleged criminal neglect and manslaughter of her daughter made the girl hit herself, locked her in an alarmed room and cut off most of her hair, a court has heard. Warning: This story includes references to child abuse and self-harm, which may be distressing to readers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c352a2f0db73321fa9dfcb9332e61551</guid></item><item><title>Environmental, noise impacts from Burswood racetrack plan not significant, EPA decides</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/wa-epa-decides-not-to-assess-burswood-racetrack-plan/106032478</link><description>The path is cleared for a controversial racetrack to be built in Perth after Western Australia's environmental watchdog decides against launching a formal project assessment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d611fa964d070c2f975be3ba73f18cfb</guid></item><item><title>Gunmen kill vice principal, abduct female students in attack on Nigerian school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/attack-on-nigerian-school-kidnapping-female-students/106029940</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22711f52fb1288d77379870bd34ee5b4</guid></item><item><title>Schoolgirls the target of mass abductions in Nigeria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/nigerian-schoolgirls-abducted-by-gunmen-kebbi-sate/106028716</link><description>The kidnappers arrived on motorcycles, scaled the school fence and shot the vice-principal as he tried to protect his students.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8de6656198dfb903f5466933b0b3fd1f</guid></item><item><title>Albanese cops summit loss, Liberals go hunting and Hanson gets cooking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/cop26-chris-bowen-anthony-albanese-liberals-sussan-ley/106026298</link><description>The prime minister didn't seem too bothered as he sold Australia losing out on the rights to host a major climate summit as a win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5ee1174fee337b25e166b72187d631a</guid></item><item><title>Mark Speakman resigns as NSW Liberals leader, endorses Kellie Sloane to replace him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/mark-speakman-media-conference-leadership-liberal-opposition/106033434</link><description>NSW Opposition Leader Mark Speakman had declared he would need to be "blasted out" of the role, but his stance shifted this afternoon when it became clear his support had eroded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c88d6c8bf2c511ec6b1a51c81f72528</guid></item><item><title>Anti-corruption police raid APY Lands administration office in Umuwa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/sa-police-raid-several-apy-lands-premises-investigation/106033644</link><description>South Australia police say several searches have been carried out on multiple premises in the Anangu Pitjantjatjara Yankunytjatjara Lands, including the administration offices in Umuwa.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4b7404c47a05c057c2c0922c004519a</guid></item><item><title>England wicketkeeper Jamie Smith could be the tourists' unlikely Ashes secret weapon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/why-jamie-smith-could-be-englands-unlikely-ashes-hero/106032894</link><description>England's wicketkeeper for the Ashes series may look unassuming but as Russell Jackson writes, if Australia underestimates Jamie Smith, they will do so at their peril.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">718e2d7155b3df24ce31ec8e834bfbc6</guid></item><item><title>How politicians could combat doubts about Epstein files release</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/epstein-files-release-redaction-doubts/106033524</link><description>As a 30-day timer begins for the US Department of Justice to release its Epstein files, questions remain around whether this will be the definitive release.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">760123228c222a6fa9a3daa64315fa77</guid></item><item><title>Daly Cherry-Evans unveiling as a Sydney Rooster is a look into a strange new world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/daly-cherry-evans-sydney-roosters-manly-sea-eagles/106033680</link><description>After a rugby league lifetime in maroon and white, Daly Cherry-Evans pulled on his new colours for the first time, and the veteran's move to the Sydney Roosters was a look into an uncanny valley beyond.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89f64b97fa626abf00e7b9e906105966</guid></item><item><title>Federal government funding extends cohealth GP services until July 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/victoria-cohealth-gp-clinics-federal-funding-lifeline/106032814</link><description>The Commonwealth will provide $1.5 million in temporary funding to keep the community health clinic's GP services running until July next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d15665592f945b0d0118e5448b70ccc</guid></item><item><title>Councillors oust Sue Scarman as mayor of Northern Areas Council</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/mayor-sue-scarman-dismissed-northern-areas-council-sa/106032240</link><description>With 12 months still left of her term, a well-known South Australian mayor has been ousted by fellow councillors, but she has challenged them to offer a "legitimate reason" for her dismissal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9337c9200591cf3cb82b541d1d727e9c</guid></item><item><title>The presence of large white sharks has Esperance locals concerned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/large-white-pointer-sharks-a-concern-for-wa-locals/106029686</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ee1afb289dc661fe8ddd56dd17f342d</guid></item><item><title>Increased shark activity around Esperance coastline has locals conflicted about solutions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/increased-shark-activity-around-esperance-coastline/106029580</link><description>Vision of sharks off the Esperance coastline ahead of its busy tourist season has some locals concerned and conflicted about solutions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e751e96a75bc54ca9883dfa04cd1704a</guid></item><item><title>Former Olympic snowboarder Ryan Wedding on FBI's most wanted list</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/canadian-olympic-snowboarder-ryan-wedding-fbi-most-wanted-list/106033842</link><description>Ryan Wedding once represented Canada at the Winter Olympics. Now he's one of the FBI's most wanted people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d99871d5830bc522b6e616a1f0f8386e</guid></item><item><title>Mark Speakman endorses Kellie Sloane after announcing he will step down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/mark-speakman-endorses-kellie-sloane/106034172</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fff1cd10d5c2f0eb784abd94d5c85971</guid></item><item><title>AFL draft 2025 night two recap: Archie Ludowkye gives up hope of being picked and misses drafting moment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/afl-draft-2025-second-round-live-blog/106029678</link><description>Archie Ludowyke goes to his bedroom thinking he is not going to get his AFL dream realised, only to to hear an eruption from his living room as his name is called out by the Adelaide Crows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b3f9e16985db104f8daadd3d46d1a48</guid></item><item><title>Queensland aquaculture company and CEO fined $300k for illegal barramundi farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/illegal-barramundi-farm-sentencing/106027364</link><description>The company was sentenced to pay the fine, with the chief executive also given a $60,000 penalty as well as payment of court costs for the environmental breach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bf7b3d8844c1a249582da7268be33a7</guid></item><item><title>Animal Justice Party MP Georgie Purcell shares sexual harassment incidents in parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/sexual-harassment-allegations-georgie-purcell-parliament/106033446</link><description>The Animal Justice Party MP detailed her own experiences during a debate over legislation to restrict the use of non-disclosure agreements in workplace sexual harassment cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">067f08122d6bdaa8ac065329941d6e56</guid></item><item><title>EU 'optimistic' about breakthrough in free trade agreement negotiations with Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/australia-europe-free-trade-agreement-optimistic-negotiations/106034206</link><description>A breakthrough in long-stalled negotiations over a free trade deal between Australia and the European Union could come as soon as this weekend, sources have told the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e444a0ca255a016485ab328f707b1428</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106031650</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8e2fdcc5cd594466797ed720c24a798</guid></item><item><title>Tivoli Drive-In closes amid rising operating expenses and low attendance numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/qld-ipswich-tivoli-drive-in-closure/106033632</link><description>Rising expenses and poor weather are to blame for the closure of one of Queensland's last remaining drive-in cinemas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c187aa66aa3e495ef0457680fe61dc99</guid></item><item><title>Prominent neo-Nazi figure Joel Davis arrested in Sydney, group leader says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/nsw-neo-nazi-joel-davis-arrested-sydney-bondi/106034504</link><description>Joel Davis, who spoke at a rally outside NSW parliament earlier this month, was referred to the Australian Federal Police over a message about a Sydney MP.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">361915873f1da26ae2cef12d223efefd</guid></item><item><title>Sanjeev Gupta's Liberty Bell Bay smelter could be further pursued by ASIC, even as Georgian bailout proposed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/asic-warning-sanjeev-guptas-liberty-bell-bay-smelter/106033084</link><description>The manganese smelter in Tasmania has ore sitting untouched as Sanjeev Gupta turns to a Georgian company for a bailout, but an ASIC investigation looms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60f9900adfc08fe099fbb2d787364169</guid></item><item><title>WBBL leaders Hobart Hurricanes beat second-placed Melbourne Renegades by six wickets at North Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/hurricanes-extend-wbbl-lead-rain-affected-win-over-renegades/106034452</link><description>Hobart Hurricanes are five-from-five to start the WBBL season, after beating the Melbourne Renegades by six wickets in a rain-impacted match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80e1687863c675c5f652ccc7178eb20f</guid></item><item><title>Who is Kellie Sloane, the frontrunner to lead the NSW Liberals?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/nsw-liberals-who-is-kellie-sloane-vaucluse-frontrunner/106034422</link><description>The first-term MP has been endorsed by outgoing leader Mark Speakman ahead of the NSW Liberal party room meeting on Friday. Here's what to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5ac7915b86fde95ee01ecdf6d90bf5e</guid></item><item><title>EU trade commissioner says he's optimistic about FTA negotiations with Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/eu-trade-commissioner-iv-laura-tingle/106034532</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0d31c77e7598ff33f7adffa45276d7e</guid></item><item><title>NZ government's puberty blockers move attracts strong reactions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/nz-government-puberty-blockers-move-attracts-strong-reactions/106034502</link><description>The New Zealand cabinet signs off on plans to halt new prescriptions for puberty blockers for young people with gender dysphoria from mid-December.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1db4ef05c9cbde070afca9a3ddf1bf0d</guid></item><item><title>Future of Liberty Bell Bay smelter in limbo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/future-of-liberty-bell-bay-smelter-in-limbo-/106034132</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e26fa7821d462f9b60f61c4df695892</guid></item><item><title>Commissioner for Aboriginal Children and Young People to resign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/ccyp-aboriginal-children-commissioner-resign/106034770</link><description>Commissioner Meena Singh will step down from her role on Friday after three and a half years in the job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43ea058e05ffe69393dc720b45c61768</guid></item><item><title>Woman fined for animal cruelty over attempt to hide drugs in dachshund's body</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/woman-fined-after-attempt-to-hide-drugs-in-dog-body/106034692</link><description>A 44-year-old woman is fined almost $2,000 after she tried to insert a bag of methylamphetamine into her dog's body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60b40394701658d419b664e70e4024bd</guid></item><item><title>Coalition would back Labor's environment laws with 'sensible' amendments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/coalition-would-back-labors-environment-laws-with-amendments/106034196</link><description>The opposition has identified seven key areas where change would be required for the Coalition to support Labor's proposed reforms to the Environment Protection and Biodiversity Conservation Act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0726b07c2ced853a3fc984282d99880</guid></item><item><title>South Korean ferry crashed because operator was on his phone, authorities allege</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/south-korea-ferry-crash-operator-distracted-by-phone/106034862</link><description>South Korean authorities have detained two crew members after the ferry carrying 267 passengers crashed into an island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8989165451eeab8d78550252117f880</guid></item><item><title>The US has a fresh plan to end Russia's war in Ukraine. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/what-is-the-new-ukraine-peace-plan-explained/106034920</link><description>European allies of Kyiv say "peace cannot be capitulation" as details of a new plan to end the Ukraine war emerge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca8c7a5f4d39c564ceaebe640714d156</guid></item><item><title>Princess Diana enters Paris waxwork museum in 'revenge dress'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/princess-diana-enters-paris-waxwork-museum-in-revenge-dress-/106035030</link><description>The late Princess is displayed wearing a copy of the black gown by designer Christina Stambolian that she wore for a public appearance in 1994 amid a media frenzy about the breakdown of her marriage to Charles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fe1e529c11f77b3c233dd58e8da85fd</guid></item><item><title>Trump floats death penalty for Democrats urging military to refuse illegal orders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/trump-floats-death-penalty-for-democrats-military-refuse-orders/106035314</link><description>Six Democratic politicians, all of whom are veterans, are urging members of the military not to obey unlawful orders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ccf85ac83f706c8ff037b6e03e9be2a</guid></item><item><title>More than 170 people rescued off Mount Semeru after eruption as 1,000 locals evacuated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/climbers-rescued-locals-evacuated-after-mount-semeru-eruption/106035320</link><description>Mount Semeru's sudden eruption left more than 170 people on its slopes in danger, while nearby residents fled for safety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">009ab8ce5425e9810c9703e6963aee93</guid></item><item><title>How Elon Musk's Cybertruck dreams quickly went pear-shaped</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/today-in-history-november-21-cybertruck/106029340</link><description>Elon Musk hinted at his dream for a battery-electric pick-up truck for years before, finally, on November 21, 2019, Tesla unveiled a prototype for its Cybertruck.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8d304d1f0d001700bede354ae8fb5d6</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: The ARIA Awards, a golden auction and aurora australis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/weekly-news-quiz-november-21/106031690</link><description>Did you catch the finer details of this week's news? Quiz yourself!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c88af141d6e12bbf731a6c54c110335</guid></item><item><title>Our family made an emergency plan. Here’s how it went</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/emergency-plan-natural-disasters-here-is-how/106027454</link><description>I sat down with my family to make an emergency kit and an emergency plan. Here's how we did it and what we spent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73c0e54da54826bd427b79034f96a5ff</guid></item><item><title>Boris Johnson oversaw 'chaotic' UK response to COVID that led to more deaths, inquiry finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/boris-johnson-covid-chaotic-response-death-toll-higher/106035374</link><description>The inquiry's chair finds that more than 23,000 deaths could have been avoided had the British government acted sooner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2648116aa461cf2c5f0387ebd0204fba</guid></item><item><title>US honours Republican titan Dick Cheney, while Donald Trump and JD Vance not invited</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/dick-cheney-funeral-trump-vance/106035422</link><description>Joe Biden, George Bush and every living former vice-president — Kamala Harris, Mike Pence, Al Gore and Dan Quayle — were in attendance, along with generals, foreign dignitaries and Supreme Court justices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cadd8f1ad1b71c816c55d49fc654798</guid></item><item><title>Virgin and Qantas to ban use of portable power banks after string of fires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/airlines-virgin-australia-qantas-ban-power-banks/106033982</link><description>Virgin Australia and Qantas will ban the use of portable power banks from next month following a string of international incidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd7768cb78f9615d22c938dc101aa79b</guid></item><item><title>How much will Tasmanians actually be paying for the stadium proposed for Hobart's Macquarie Point?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/macquarie-point-stadium-hobart-cost-questions/106033990</link><description>There are many questions still to be answered when it comes to how the stadium will be paid for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c5a1c38c81ca672b598e9b700203914</guid></item><item><title>Rare earth header B</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/rare-earth-header-b/106011714</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c271a51fae11d1a8453de78662b34bb5</guid></item><item><title>How critical minerals power our daily lives from the moment we wake up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/how-critical-minerals-rare-earths-are-used-in-everyday-life/105980350</link><description>Take a tour around the house and see how everyday life is powered by critical minerals and why we will keep hearing so much about them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45cadb27240800c30df396aa4dbd11b8</guid></item><item><title>Bulk-billing rates flatline, despite billions tipped into Medicare</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/bulk-billing-rates-flatline-medicare-billions/106032104</link><description>Medicare figures quietly published online show bulk-billing has not improved from a year ago, despite billions being tipped into the scheme. As out-of-pocket costs rise, GPs are delivering 10,000 fewer services every day compared to last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbab951050ea668dba6ac2a335732595</guid></item><item><title>The pre-Ashes chatter has been predictable. The cricket will be anything but</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/the-pre-ashes-chatter-has-been-predictable-the-cricket-will-be-a/106018376</link><description>The build-up to this Ashes series has been long and often painful, but will quickly be forgotten when the first bowl is bowled and all hell breaks loose today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bac7a318debdb03545ba27ad44d8f627</guid></item><item><title>Combating Neo-Nazis is a 'wicked problem' for governments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/neo-nazis-governments-antisemitism-rally-nsw/106026512</link><description>Neo-Nazis exploit feelings of alienation among a section of the community and making martyrs of them could play into their hands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a935ae0d75b16cdb471819b9261716cb</guid></item><item><title>Australia's race to rewire the country amid a global transmission boom is not unique</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/transmission-line-projects-faces-massive-challenges/106029214</link><description>Countries across the globe are racing to rewire their electricity systems for a decarbonised future. In Australia, delays are mounting, along with doubts about whether it can meet goals on schedule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11696a7028bbd801d9aebbc02fd63d0c</guid></item></channel></rss>