<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:56:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nine candidates running for Townsville mayor at postal by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/nine-candidates-for-townsville-mayoral-by-election/105911262</link><description>Townsville residents will select from a field of nine candidates at a mayoral by-election next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3206cb66668d5116b32d85034a5d70d5</guid></item><item><title>Russian envoy says Trump, Putin meeting will likely happen 'at a later date'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/russian-enoy-trump-putin-meeting-later-date/105933554</link><description>A top Moscow official says he believes the US, Ukraine and Russia are close to a "diplomatic solution" on the conflict.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41b7e47edfc88fba084e614deabb2a19</guid></item><item><title>Best books out in October, from Jane Harper, Kiran Desai, Bri Lee and more</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/best-books-what-to-read-october-jane-harper-kiran-desai-bri-lee/105915138</link><description>Wondering what to read? This month's best books include the latest from Jane Harper, Bri Lee and Booker Prize winner Kiran Desai.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10b0699202501075721adcc8ff9e71b4</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania remains free of H5 bird flu, but returning migratory birds could pose a risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/tas-bird-flu-fears-for-tasmania/105932858</link><description>With migratory birds returning to Tasmania during a period of increased bird flu, the chance of the virus affecting the state's coastal areas is on the rise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e402485fa51b43661822628f486c21d1</guid></item><item><title>ADF sexual assault class action ignites hope for reform and lasting change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/class-action-targets-sexual-violence-in-defence/105932520</link><description>After countless reports, inquiries and investigations, a class action against Defence is reigniting calls for cultural reform and accountability within the Australian Defence Force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">987424070a8c5b33d2df8ec0c308aa4b</guid></item><item><title>How the star of lost silent film Jewelled Nights went from the limelight to selling sweets for cinemagoers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/tas-silent-film-louise-lovely-bjelke-petersen-jewelled-nights/105417108</link><description>Australia's first Hollywood star, a famous romance novel by Joh Bjelke-Petersen's aunt and a rare alloy mined from Tasmania's west coast put the island's wild places on the big screen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef0fd77808ed2c9dbcd21fa23b196c76</guid></item><item><title>Fire ant eradication program under scrutiny as woman left fighting infestation alone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/queensland-fire-ant-funding-calls-communication-errors/105888208</link><description>A Queensland woman says she has been left to fight a fire ant infestation with virtually no support, as experts warn funding gaps and slow responses risk wider spread.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db05075d077e0e0067b727fdb57e0980</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur beats Matteo Berrettini in Vienna, sets up Jannik Sinner clash for place in final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/i-m-always-ready-mate-demon-set-for-sinner-exam-in-vienna/105933604</link><description>Alex de Minaur reaches his 30th ATP tour semifinal in Vienna with a big win over Matteo Berrettini -- but he will have to get past his nemesis Jannik Sinner for a place in the final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4860e960e8a946da026f96e130c34054</guid></item><item><title>Nationwide Bug Hunt to capture Australia's insect, invertebrate underworld</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/australian-bug-hunt-announced/105926406</link><description>Australia's photographic natural database is about to get a big boost as citizen scientists are urged to join a national search.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0ca7159e6a29be7018f238949242eab</guid></item><item><title>'Castle Law' petition closes with record support in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/castle-law-petition-record-support-queensland/105923936</link><description>A second attempt to put "castle law" before Queensland parliament has generated record support, with some legal experts concerned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6861c40e3ccadd150b641bc22c1554a</guid></item><item><title>Trailblazing mining engineer remembered as pioneering transgender woman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/transgender-mining-engineer-rebecca-norton/105904044</link><description>The mining industry is notoriously "bloke-centred". Rebecca Norton transitioned gender and kept going.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae28811392ff71f213c9b10197bfd2b0</guid></item><item><title>NSW seeks federal support for world-first mRNA foot and mouth disease vaccine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/mrna-foot-and-mouth-disease-vaccine-federal-support-needed/105931398</link><description>Scientists in NSW develop a potential world-first mRNA vaccine to protect cattle from foot and mouth disease.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd622ba9005c5b8cb3fd6a5045475ca9</guid></item><item><title>What does it mean if a deadly strain of bird flu has been found on Australia's Heard Island?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/bird-flu-h5n1-likely-present-in-heard-island-elephant-seals/105931840</link><description>Scientists suspect a deadly strain of bird flu, H5N1, has infected wildlife on Heard Island after observing a high mortality rate in elephant seals on the Australian territory in the sub-Antarctic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b7bdc89237fb02e04da24a97d2cc27b</guid></item><item><title>'Balenciaga Bikie' Tarek Zahed arrested in Sydney's north-west after month-long manhunt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/nsw-balenciaga-bikie-tarek-zahed-arrested-month-long-manhunt/105933646</link><description>Tarek Zahed was arrested at a property in Dundas Valley on Friday night, NSW Police said. Warrants for his apprehension had been issued in two states.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04370ca7cb1dcbf21c1a21358d858a6b</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr set for Matildas return against Wales after nearly two years out with injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/would-be-a-dream-come-true-sam-kerr-s-big-asian-cup-ambition/105933704</link><description>Sam Kerr is back with the Matildas and ready to start taking big steps towards a dream of lifting silverware with the current group of players.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32c7a2084439a095d98b3e94b72bb03a</guid></item><item><title>Trump sending US carrier to Latin America as war fears rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/trump-sending-us-carrier-to-latin-america-as-war-fears-rise/105933798</link><description>It is a major escalation in a US military build-up in the Caribbean, with Venezuela's leader warning the Trump administration is "fabricating a war".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1374689bd3ea21c2609a998cc2e4998e</guid></item><item><title>Menindee Lakes birdwatcher, the 'Birdman', has recorded 200-plus bird species</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/menindee-lakes-birdman-geoff-looney-photography-birds/105919896</link><description>For 50 years Geoff Looney has called the remote Indigenous community of Menindee in Far West New South Wales home. Thirty years ago he started recording information about birdlife in the region which has grown to more than 209 species recorded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f19372fb3d08c42ba70b8791eb513f48</guid></item><item><title>Perth Festival venues include vacant offices, bridges, secret locations in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/perth-festival-announces-2026-lineup/105927414</link><description>Perth Festival unveils a diverse program making use of unconventional event spaces, but large-scale opening and closing events are markedly missing this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ac3d662e7e0a00be0956db62010efe8</guid></item><item><title>New York Attorney-General Letitia James pleads not guilty in mortgage fraud case pushed by Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/letitia-james-pleads-not-guilty-mortgage-fraud-case-donald-trump/105933866</link><description>Speaking to supporters outside the court following brief arraignment, Letitia James said the Trump administration is using the justice system as a "vehicle of retribution".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfc8bdf98d1d6ed39d4a69725a16a9c4</guid></item><item><title>Thailand's Queen Mother Sirikit dies after blood infection, aged 93</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/thailand-former-queen-sirikit-dies-93/105933802</link><description>Sirikit, who succumbed to a blood infection, is remembered as a champion of the poor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df3a1027ff61c5fc4c09f55165fb9306</guid></item><item><title>Study tracks how foxes 'colonised' Australia and grew to a population of 1.7 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/first-fox-origins-mapping-introduced-to-australia-research/105903156</link><description>A nationwide program has traced how foxes spread from south-eastern Australia to as far away as the Pilbara in just 70 years, as part of efforts to revive native species populations decimated by the pest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6ec944a7b43d79e669b3062ac59eccc</guid></item><item><title>Surfing with the Mob connects Indigenous teens to country and language on NSW far south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/surfing-with-the-mob/105901276</link><description>It started with a surf lesson, but these these Indigenous teens found something far deeper in the ocean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">525be2b9d37d48b57cf3e2b3633f99d7</guid></item><item><title>Jon Bon Jovi uses football analogy to describe vocal surgery rehab — and meets the Kangaroos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/jon-bon-jovi-vocal-chord-surgery-kangroos-nrl-wembley-stadium/105933860</link><description>The US rocker says getting back to form after the surgical procedure was a long, slow process.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ded40ad1a8b7169ca63222c5e327eae</guid></item><item><title>Bon Jovi meets Australia's national rugby league team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/bon-jovi-meets-australia-s-national-rugby-league-team/105934108</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">602a664ed34ae313d5f62c186a861e4f</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos vs England, kick-off time and how to watch, Australia meets Bon Jovi at Wembley before Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/kangaroos-vs-england-kick-off-time-and-how-to-watch-bon-jovi/105933996</link><description>The countdown is on for the first Ashes series in 22 years, as the Kangaroos look to retain the title they have held since 1973.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df694b4c587c0f961ae403205dd86c5b</guid></item><item><title>Marking 40 years since the historic handback of Uluṟu-Kata Tjuṯa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/nt-uluru-handback-40th-anniversary-indigenous-land-rights/105927200</link><description>When you drive towards Uluṟu and see the stark, red monolith on the horizon, or stand at its base and look up at its striking, powerful enormity, time stands still.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c64ba3456cc462427185d5ab8b457e5</guid></item><item><title>Perth Zoo's Sumatran tiger Jaya dies of cancer, seven years after tumour removed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/perth-zoo-sumatran-tiger-jaya-dies-of-cancer/105934036</link><description>Perth Zoo's beloved Sumatran tiger Jaya dies, seven years after being diagnosed with cancer and nine years after his mother also died of the disease.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf8ee41326cfb3a782bdbc8102f7b07c</guid></item><item><title>Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma lead India to nine-wicket victory over Australia in third ODI</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/australia-india-third-odi-kohli-sharma/105934264</link><description>Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma conclude their Australian farewell tour with an unbeaten 169-run partnership in India's commanding nine-wicket victory at the Sydney Cricket Ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">525e153b4cf2743f9494e9dd27a0b1ed</guid></item><item><title>Popular podcasters are calling out Trump — will young men follow suit?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/popular-podcasters-calling-out-trump-male-listeners/105863690</link><description>Wildly popular podcasters such as Joe Rogan, Andrew Schulz and Theo Von have distanced themselves from the Trump administration in recent months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24ea41796bdf86658c15a4f8d5e0862f</guid></item><item><title>Community gathers in Gladstone for woman, two boys allegedly murdered in house fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/community-gathering-gladstone-house-fire-alleged-murder/105924080</link><description>A central Queensland community gathers to mourn a mum, her son and his best friend who died in a house fire. A woman has been charged with murder and arson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d9a75682928481f60847432488bb646</guid></item><item><title>Swans keep season alive with 17-point defeat of Eagles as Hawks, Lions and Dockers notch victories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/aflw-r11-swans-eagles-bombers-hawks-dockers-tigers-lions-demons/105933950</link><description>The Sydney Swans beat the West Coast Eagles by 17 points to keep their hopes of playing in this year's AFLW finals series alive, while Fremantle, Brisbane and Hawthorn also pick up wins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1da8e0a3afe22a5d565106104d79eb60</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies defeat Eddie Jones's Brave Blossoms 19-15 in opening Test of spring tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/rugby-union-test-wallabies-japan-updates-live-blog/105934092</link><description>In the first stop on their spring tour, the Wallabies hold on for a gritty 19-15 victory over Japan in wet conditions at Tokyo's National Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97e83ba8a96107003311b8ef41b8215a</guid></item><item><title>Halloween toys fail safety tests, prompting warning to parents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/halloween-toys-products-fail-safety-tests/105934324</link><description>Authorities warn parents of the dangers of Halloween-themed toys bought online, after testing reveals 80 per cent fail to meet safety and information standards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">005617b9d2c2e706dc9377c19b39d222</guid></item><item><title>Trump says he ‘won’t forget’ Rudd’s negative comments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/trump-says-he-won-t-forget-rudd-s-negative-comments-/105934388</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cdf597aee25ce2963e02996ebf86787</guid></item><item><title>Cricket Australia says two Women's World Cup members were 'touched inappropriately' in India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/cricket-australia-women-touched-inappropriately-india/105934466</link><description>Cricket Australia says two members of the Australian Women's World Cup cricket team have been "touched inappropriately" in India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6a6e524625ac1911df42f9041afa364</guid></item><item><title>Worker dies at Merredin grain property owned by WA farmer John Nicoletti</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/worker-dies-at-john-nicoletti-grain-site-in-merredin/105934480</link><description>A man in his 60s died at a property owned by prominent farmer John Nicoletti in Western Australia's Wheatbelt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c86a792f3287abfd78b6bbf3ce1f660a</guid></item><item><title>Alana King spins Australia to crushing seven-wicket victory against South Africa in ODI World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/australia-crushes-south-africa-odi-world-cup/105934114</link><description>Alana King claims the best figures by an Australian woman in ODI history as Australia defeats South Africa by seven wickets to book a semi-final clash with India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e881d2580f2ee147a3a3fc57e5048a6c</guid></item><item><title>'Change is hard, but progress occurs': Albanese chats land rights on NT visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/prime-minister-anthony-albanese-40-years-since-uluru-handback-nt/105934262</link><description>Crowds gather to celebrate the anniversary of a pivotal moment in the Aboriginal land rights movements, as the prime minister speaks from Uluṟu for the first time since the failed referendum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18b697b66607d55d5b504df36f0d8c12</guid></item><item><title>Matildas beat Wales 2-1 in Cardiff as Sam Kerr makes successful return from injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/matildas-vs-wales-international-friendly-live-blog/105934608</link><description>Sam Kerr makes a successful return to action with the Matildas, starting and playing an hour in Australia's 2-1 win over Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a5995cae322115d167923932307ef82</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos crush England 26-6 to claim 1-0 series lead in rugby league Ashes series at Wembley stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/live-updates-england-vs-kangaroos-ashes-international-league/105919936</link><description>Reece Walsh scored two tries and saved two more as the Kangaroos belted England 26-6 in front of a record crowd at Wembley Stadium in London.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0094b724fa2404f30fb3ef62beb92d87</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese heads to Malaysia for ASEAN and East Asia Summit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-25/anthony-albanese-heading-to-asean-summit-malaysia/105934102</link><description>Speaking ahead of the trip, Mr Albanese said he would use the summits to discuss economic growth, security, and stability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78eb1fbe9a98a113d9782ca4e009a3dc</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar too low on agenda as regional leaders meet Trump for summit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/myanmar-asean-agenda-thailand-cambodia-donald-trump/105928700</link><description>Instead of talking about Myanmar, the US president and his regional counterparts will be congratulating themselves for helping Thailand and Cambodia strike a peace deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">357366ae6e37a136832fe715b04bfc85</guid></item><item><title>Year 12 exams have started for the Class of 2025 who began high school in COVID lockdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/school-year-12-exams-vce-hsc-sace-wace-tce/105895538</link><description>They started high school as the world went into lockdown, interrupting their young lives at a pivotal moment. Now they’re graduating year 12 and figuring out what to do next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4c148e0a37d6c84d59a43a5f0ac98ad</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew has been excised from the royal family. Should the monarchy do more?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/prince-andrew-titles-royal-family-monarchy-do-more/105929144</link><description>The Prince Andrew debacle is shameful for the monarchy — it's not a pile-on, it's alleged paedophilia. So should the royals do more, here?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c8f61b3baf2b8e37d799b8e8cc13b11</guid></item><item><title>Shooter Jennings releases unheard Waylon Jennings recordings on new album Songbird</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/waylon-jennings-songbird-shooter-jennings-interview/105922010</link><description>Shooter Jennings unearthed a treasure trove of unreleased recordings from his legendary father Waylon, revealing a tender, soulful side of the outlaw icon that history forgot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f34df56f1bb5d145aa4f89beffe0c977</guid></item><item><title>Amid anger over corruption and inequality, Asia's gen Z turns on political 'nepo babies'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/gen-z-turn-on-asia-political-nepo-babies-wealth-flaunting/105884288</link><description>Gen Zs in several Asian countries launch an online war against political "nepo babies" who flaunt their wealth on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7205896f2bcebb1e12718a8d6d807442</guid></item><item><title>DV victim and Brisbane Lions member calls for more privacy after alleged stalking incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/lions-support-on-being-found-at-gabba/105929960</link><description>Two years after she took out a domestic violence order against her ex-partner, Aurora realised he was working 10m from her reserved seat at the Gabba — she believes he accessed her details by calling the club’s membership line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c121a7391e20cbed8a19e4109a57f7e</guid></item><item><title>Zohran Mamdani may soon be NYC's first Muslim millennial mayor. It's part of his appeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/zohran-mamdani-new-york-success-is-more-than-social-media/105474246</link><description>If Zohran Mamdani wins, he will become New York's first Muslim and millennial mayor. It's something his campaign has been acutely aware of as he taps into new voting bases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35a5e3f32b70c2582fdc2e938ef186c2</guid></item><item><title>Child sex doll heads sold as model mannequins to harness loophole</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/temu-shein-shipping-child-sex-dolls-to-australia/105636720</link><description>Child sexual abuse doll heads are being sold on Temu as hairdressing model mannequins to harness a legal loophole, according to experts who say it is part of an "unhealthy culture".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71e80ed19552e65773831c678b45fa2f</guid></item><item><title>Farmers buy local pub to help foster connection in country NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/farmers-buy-bemboka-pub-to-foster-connection-in-country-town/105783916</link><description>Operating a pub is no mean feat, but try doing it while running a farm at the same time. That is exactly what farmers Karen and Rowan Alcock have done in their town of Bemboka on the New South Wales far south coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecdb848df7312b1db1240fbc07cbc3bb</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur loses to Jannik Sinner in Vienna Open semifinal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/alex-de-minaur-loses-to-jannik-sinner-in-vienna-open-semifinal/105935156</link><description>Alex de Minaur's Vienna Open ends at the semifinal stage, with the Australian falling to world number one Jannik Sinner for the 12th time in as many meetings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0623b189bf656dc23c1e6fceca311bf7</guid></item><item><title>Lauren Huxley's brutal attacker Robert Black Farmer is up for parole next year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/lauren-huxley-sydney-home-attack-random-robert-farmer-parole/105922226</link><description>It has been 20 years since Lauren Huxley was brutally attacked in her home as a teen in a crime that shocked Australia. She has built a life no-one thought possible, but now her hard-won peace could be tested.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e5b1aa00b99012139193c0a90f0b0d0</guid></item><item><title>Tens of thousands pack stadium for Punjabi singer Diljit Dosanjh's Western Sydney show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/punjabi-artist-diljit-dosanj-australia-tour-parramatta-concert/105925932</link><description>The pop sensation has an army of fans all over the world who see him as an artist who bridges cultural gaps — Diljit Dosanjh's music loved by both Indians and non-Indians alike.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f080ffd3b321d209120aaeaaaaf3ca30</guid></item><item><title>Runner Sissy Austin reunited with paramedic who helped her after horrific assault near Ballarat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/sissy-austin-paramedic-reunite-ambulance-victoria-aboriginal/105927734</link><description>When Sissy Austin, a young Aboriginal woman, was left dizzied and bloodied by an unprovoked assault while running, a small gesture from an attending paramedic helped her feel safe. It's a lesson that underpins a small but significant change in how paramedics treat patients across Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2fcb5d91b52a701d678c0134b259015</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Convinced your losing streak is finally over? We'll see about that</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/105925868</link><description>We both know you're hoping for the best with this week's quiz. Just remember, hope will get you nowhere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac696c49dee64885c32f095f04de0cc5</guid></item><item><title>Ex-MP Troy Bell will spend time in prison, joining short list of jailed politicians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/troy-bell-joins-list-of-jailed-former-sa-politicians/105912672</link><description>Hard-working and charismatic former politician Troy Bell was so well liked, he was twice re-elected while awaiting trial for stealing public money. Now, he joins a short list of former SA politicians who have served time for crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e72966c961a8a5b5dc35b9be4c83fcaf</guid></item><item><title>Will the art of biography be lost when AI and algorithms control our data?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/biography-ai-algorithm-letters-diaries-digital-world/105923770</link><description>How will the work of biographers change as letters, diaries and photographs are replaced by emails, texts and snapshots on the cloud?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">583e972eb2e93006858183a75f1465e7</guid></item><item><title>Thai cave rescuer Richard Harris explores risk-taking in the film Deeper</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/richard-harris-deeper-jennifer-peedom-thai-cave-rescue-diving/105919694</link><description>A new documentary by director Jennifer Peedom delves deep into the attraction of cave diving, and why Richard Harris says risk-taking is crucial for resilience.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6649f5eb681c26f5b8bed4ac3324e77</guid></item><item><title>Logan City Council resident concerned about flood map accuracy as review draws to a close</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/qld-logan-flood-mapping-concerned-residents-plan-consultation/105930402</link><description>Concerns that draft flood maps don't reflect historical accounts from residents have informed some of the submissions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c123475a6473f72677873fc07b724e4f</guid></item><item><title>Trump punishes Canada with 10pc tariff increase over TV ad stoush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/trump-punishes-canada-with-10pc-tariff-increase-over-tv-ad/105935220</link><description>US President Donald Trump says he plans to hike tariffs on imports of Canadian goods by an extra 10 per cent because of an anti-tariff television ad aired by the province of Ontario.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd2d016acfef0c7fde752a37ddb8a4d0</guid></item><item><title>Man dies after stabbing in car park near Hobart's Salamanca Place</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/tas-stabbing-death-hobart-salamanca-place/105935228</link><description>The stabbing death of a 20-year-old man is being treated as murder. Police say another victim is in hospital in a stable condition and two people are in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c479ec8ddce3b1a40bc764237c8bf6b8</guid></item><item><title>Staff at Tasmania's public hospitals say physical and verbal abuse a normalised part of the job</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/tasmania-public-hospital-staff-physical-and-verbal-abuse/105847902</link><description>Staff at Tasmania's public hospital emergency departments say they experience violence and aggression "all the time". Data released under right to information laws shows how often these incidents are occurring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc46341484b76d500c138a2c29f58ebf</guid></item><item><title>Walking netball adaptation helping players stay on the court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/walking-netball-masters-games-active-inclusive-sport/105934176</link><description>Before they take the court, the Magnolias strap on knee braces and tie bows in their hair. But don't be deceived, they're playing one of the 'most competitive games', and there may be elbows thrown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcba91251592e68fb53952910d872d63</guid></item><item><title>Return to traditional birthing practices brings joy to Bundjalung mothers, elders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/bright-future-for-jarjums-on-bundjalung-country/105719430</link><description>Bundjalung babies get the ceremonial treatment as proud elders welcome them to country for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9975841b4189ec090d99615b2aa486b8</guid></item><item><title>Winter weather exposes ancient tree stumps</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/ancient-tree-stumps-at-esperance-beach/105931462</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49efb669c70727f9322a3a615cac5bd5</guid></item><item><title>Ancient tree stumps showing sea level change exposed on popular Esperance beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/ancient-wetland-exposed-on-popular-esperance-beach/105898762</link><description>Harsh winter weather has exposed almost 100 preserved trees from an ancient wetland on an Esperance beach, but there are fears over protecting the site on a popular four-wheel drive stretch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59cc2762bc05a0b7434915fef286b795</guid></item><item><title>It's been 20 years since the Cronulla Riots. So what have we learned?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/20-years-on-from-the-cronulla-riots/105686104</link><description>It's been 20 years since violence erupted on the streets of Cronulla after thousands gathered in a public display to "reclaim their beach" from specific migrant communities. So, what has changed?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5291ffd93a63ad0e832d23653b8d0062</guid></item><item><title>Soccer program creates change for young people in remote communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/john-moriarty-football-program/105933040</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d65271ca42c78e74863ac54857fe9364</guid></item><item><title>Father and son grow delicate citrus blossoms for niche liqueur market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/father-and-son-grow-citrus-blossoms-to-make-boutique-drinks/105889538</link><description>Farmers and distillers collaborate to capture a delicate flower's flavour for the boutique drinks market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7019fd97ca776f07a2f552eb001335fe</guid></item><item><title>June Lockhart, beloved mother figure from Lassie and Lost In Space, dies aged 100</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/lassie-and-lost-in-space-star-june-lockhart-dies-aged-100/105935288</link><description>Lockhart died on Thursday of natural causes at her home in Santa Monica, a family spokesperson says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bf879243bbf38deb78596b01b91a445</guid></item><item><title>Albany woman wins international wildlife photography award for second time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/five-headed-caterpillar-wins-photo-award/105926608</link><description>An Albany photographer has won an international wildlife photo award for her image of a five-headed caterpillar that was in her backyard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d1b26042df7faa5d99f630e1842c0c1</guid></item><item><title>Driving simulator assists people with disabilities to get behind the wheel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/driving-simulator-assists-people-with-disabilities/105758844</link><description>More than 20 regional NDIS clients have gone on to get their L-plates since completing a course with a unique driving simulator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35670f40fc377e11843fed94a8063cb3</guid></item><item><title>Exoskeletons including high-tech glove trialled to reduce workplace injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/exoskeleton-trials-in-australian-workplaces/105924332</link><description>An ordinary worker puts on a power suit and gains extra strength. It sounds like the plot of a superhero film, but this is no work of fiction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4068d4c9455ba09f23412bfaa030dd2</guid></item><item><title>In the housing debate between NIMBYs and YIMBYs, a map of Sydney shows what's at stake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/nimbys-yimbys-housing-debate-heritage-conservation-area/105931706</link><description>In the debate about Sydney's housing situation and the protection of the city's heritage buildings and suburbs, there's a map that does the rounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c529c2b3eb11b7e242f53ab13eeac0ac</guid></item><item><title>Nationals' net zero review has not undertaken economic modelling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/nationals-net-zero-report-canavan/105935222</link><description>Nationals Senator Matt Canavan will present parts of his and Ross Cadell's net zero review to the party room when parliament resumes on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5cef9cefc44ebe8a33fdcf3382c1f96</guid></item><item><title>Tiny home dream shattered for WA woman with epilepsy as council orders removal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/tiny-home-dream-shattered-for-woman-with-epilepsy-by-council/105922162</link><description>A tiny home which began as a dream for Kathryn Payne becomes little more than a $130,000 storage unit in her dad's front yard as a local council in Perth's north demands the structure be removed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62fa25b02950a65b0bfe678b039aeb06</guid></item><item><title>10yo boy holds toy train exhibition at local pub to raise funds for sick children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/boy-holds-toy-train-exhibition-to-raise-funds-for-sick-children/105899456</link><description>In the main room of a local pub in the western Victorian town of Natimuk, Brock Mewett shows off his toy trains to raise money for the Royal Children's Hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6168bf8c839b4871dd82d0c8958493b7</guid></item><item><title>11yo boy from West Australia's Wheatbelt restores FJ45 LandCruiser</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/farm-boy-restores-vintage-toyota-landcruiser/105927368</link><description>After-school restoration fun wins 11-year-old Wheatbelt mini-mechanic Harry Strange best in show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f971f09312152b8f0fa8b92fe5dd71c</guid></item><item><title>Kamala Harris says she may run for US presidency again but hasn't made up her mind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/kamala-harris-may-run-us-president-interview/105935364</link><description>The former US vice-president won't commit to making another bid for the White House yet, but reiterates she's "not done" with public service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba1339fbbed7afd9a5a1b6ff8a8b53d8</guid></item><item><title>Meet the 2025 Agrifutures Rural Women's Award national finalists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/agrifutures-rural-womens-award-2025-finalist/105924530</link><description>Meet the national finalists in the running for the 2025 AgriFutures Rural Women's Award celebrating change-makers in rural, regional and remote Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb6ab8630d27b8886ca61c15ea6e605e</guid></item><item><title>Death of child trapped in fence at childcare centre ruled 'preventable'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/nt-toddler-childcare-death-ebony-thompson-inquest-findings/105935362</link><description>The family of a 22-month-old girl who died at a Northern Territory child care centre last year are calling on the government to ban the type of fencing that caused her death under the banner of "Ebony's Law".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c31dc6c6e76d16c0b8c042bf9edef08</guid></item><item><title>Reece Walsh hailed a 'freak of a player' after Kangaroos defeat England 26-6 in first Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/rugby-league-nrl-reece-walsh-kangaroos-england-ashes-first-test/105935528</link><description>Nathan Cleary and Cameron Munster heap praise on Kangaroos teammate Reece Walsh following his stunning Test debut against England at Wembley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d9fd164e0d9418dc85ecfe804ab91e3</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder over alleged stabbing of woman in Broome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/man-charged-murder-woman-death-broome-/105935516</link><description>A 56-year-old man is charged with murder over the death of a woman in Western Australia's far north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75eee24a2ffccff67e0cea59615a2384</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese dismisses lingering questions about relationship between Donald Trump and Kevin Rudd</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/albanese-dismisses-trump-comment-fake-media/105935518</link><description>The prime minister batted away concerns over Kevin Rudd's future after Donald Trump said he does not forget when people "say bad" things about him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7131b2409407125a9860a46223b6310</guid></item><item><title>What you told us about receiving mail for a previous home owner or renter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/readers-share-frustration-responsibility-return-to-sender-mail/105375268</link><description>From feeling "harassed" to fraudulent activity, this is what you had to say about how receiving mail that is not yours has impacted your life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f761ea778900d1fd2394e24272fbbbe1</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump and Anthony Albanese arrive in Kuala Lumpur ahead of 47th ASEAN Summit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/donald-trump-lands-in-kuala-lumpur-ahead-of-asean-summit/105935552</link><description>US President Donald Trump and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese touch down in the Malaysian capital of Kuala Lumpur ahead of the annual summit of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">babf3ed90d28f7b682a87f0688f4cb1a</guid></item><item><title>Trump’s reception at Kuala Lumpur airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/trump-s-reception-at-kuala-lumpur-airport-/105935776</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fae9db5247ed8d0cc2e1d94c574b803</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Diamonds lose to New Zealand's Silver Ferns 61-52 in Constellation Cup third Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/netball-constellation-cup-third-test-diamonds-silver-ferns/105935836</link><description>Australia misses the chance of wrapping up the Constellation Cup in the third Test, with New Zealand recording a 61-52 victory in Hamilton.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ff4c810a230de46a3bee5f847361f90</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos equal winning record with 46-point Saints drubbing, Cats down Dogs, Pies and Blues notch wins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/kangaroos-saints-bulldogs-cats-blues-giants-pies-suns-aflw/105935848</link><description>North Melbourne equals the VFL/AFL record for consecutive wins and claims the AFLW minor premiership with a 46-point drubbing of St Kilda.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26cb9ad1bd1bdbbd858ee61573eb1549</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Jillaroos defeat Fetū Sāmoa 60-0 in Pacific Championships Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/rugby-league-pacific-championships-jillaroos-fetu-samoa/105935934</link><description>The Jillaroos show why they are world champions, recording a dominant 60-0 victory over Fetū Sāmoa in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48a9c9ce3d0ee976de3492e52b404528</guid></item><item><title>Large hail and strong winds as severe thunderstorm hits south-east Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/qld-severe-thunderstorm-warning-bureau-of-meteorology/105936082</link><description>South-east Queensland's energy network was "absolutely smashed" as severe thunderstorms brought large hail and strong winds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d39e61005245c82a9f0c0ff28a6882d</guid></item><item><title>Woodend, Ipswich hit with strong winds and hail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/woodend-ipswich-hit-with-strong-winds-and-hail/105936100</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d460a70347377110ebbd844863535a0</guid></item><item><title>Thousands left without power as tornado hits Melbourne, bringing the biggest rainfall in 18 months</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/victoria-thunderstorm-damage-weather-rain/105936056</link><description>Tens of thousands of Victorians were left without power and a tornado swept through Melbourne's west on a wild day of weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6be44d46feb8195bb0e246229d6bee9b</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese arrives at ASEAN summit in Malaysia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/anthony-albanese-arrives-at-asean-summit-in-malaysia-/105936144</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ade57c2adcbb46da92f51ae7092fbff</guid></item><item><title>Minjee Lee, Hannah Green and Steph Kyriacou lead Australia to International Crown glory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/lee-green-kyriacou-lead-australia-to-international-crown-glory/105936170</link><description>Minjee Lee and Hannah Green hold their nerves to guide Australia home against the USA in the final of the International Crown in South Korea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">955ac80a27d76f22a416a42f191179e7</guid></item><item><title>Suspects arrested over theft of crown jewels from Louvre heist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/louvre-suspects-arrested/105936180</link><description>One of the suspects was arrested at Charles de Gaulle Airport airport, with plans to fly to Algeria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6f973a602468cebd460ce670a357396</guid></item><item><title>Samoa defeats Tonga 34-6 to qualify for Pacific Cup final as lightning wreaks havoc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/samoa-overcomes-lightning-defeats-tonga/105936182</link><description>Samoa defeats Tonga 34-6 after a 95-minute lightning delay at Lang Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab66c45227d2bac734c63018e0fd3fb1</guid></item><item><title>F1 Mexico: Lando Norris wins and leads Formula 1 standings, Oscar Piastri fifth in Mexico City Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/f1-live-mexico-city-grand-prix-oscar-piastri-lando-norris/105916700</link><description>Oscar Piastri has lost the lead of the Formula 1 drivers' championship, as Lando Norris wins the Mexico City Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">206b13f048f8bcd67bb82d824ee4180f</guid></item><item><title>Surfboard found intact in New Zealand after being lost in Tasmania in 2024</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/surfboard-found-intact-after-drift-from-tasmania-new-zealand/105935392</link><description>A barnacle-covered surfboard that spent 17 months at sea and travelled from Tasmania to New Zealand after it was lost off a boat appears set to be reunited with its owner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4556a9efda030f8bf593120cbae32456</guid></item><item><title>Paedophiles exploiting Australia's broken childcare system as safeguards crumble</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/childcare-centres-paedophiles-abuse-four-corners/105926324</link><description>The true scale of abuse in Australia's childcare centres has been hidden. With 200,000 pages of previously confidential files, police tip-offs, and evidence from whistleblowers, Four Corners exposes the reality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b34a569c90c6532a78a67065e62f6fc</guid></item><item><title>Trump's rare earths deal to counter China was a badly needed 'Sputnik moment'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/trump-china-rare-earths-ai-bellbots-communism/105935300</link><description>To remind the US president: China is both communist and working passably well, something he and the United States generally are being forced reluctantly to confront.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f839e60b1b0a40adbecff2f60c3a3193</guid></item><item><title>'Bad for humanity, good for business': Australian firms help Europe arm for war</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/ukraine-war-sends-australian-drone-tech-manufacturers-soaring/105911352</link><description>As European countries rush to shore up their defences amid relentless fighting in Ukraine and a growing Russian "shadow" threat, companies here are capitalising on the age of drone warfare.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">137f6e5e0e5f7c4942c3d1e3dd03bd5f</guid></item><item><title>Senior Queensland doctor suspended for more than a year on full pay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/senior-qld-doctor-suspended-for-more-than-a-year-on-full-pay/105919532</link><description>Chief medical officer Charles Pain vows to clear his name after going to the Industrial Relations Commission to find out the allegations against him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d99c65b33a194f00bc36bdde0fe7263</guid></item><item><title>Environment laws are biggest test of parliament since Albanese's win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/environment-laws-coalition-division-joyce/105935474</link><description>The Coalition goes into the sitting fortnight managing grievance and division. Labor carries the weight of needing to prove it can manage the parliament. It is not hard to work out who you would prefer to be this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f4259aa0c8aedcec239962d36421e32</guid></item><item><title>Labor rejects Coalition request to split environmental reforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/labor-rejects-coalition-plea-to-split-environmental-reforms/105935738</link><description>Opposition leader Sussan Ley wrote to the government on Sunday to suggest its environmental reforms be split into two to prioritise "practical measures to streamline approvals".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c4c3c7ecc10e6bbc94078704dde6cbc</guid></item><item><title>Australia outpaces regional neighbours as Pacific's largest donor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/australia-cements-position-pacific-largest-donor-development-aid/105935742</link><description>Australia has cemented its position as the Pacific's largest donor by far as other countries pull back on lending and prepare to cut back on foreign aid, according to the Lowy Institute.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6fe3b5bd2d3f3f56669b01ce4cf3bcbd</guid></item><item><title>Federal government rules out changing copyright law to give AI companies free rein</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/labor-rules-out-ai-training-copyright-exceptions/105935740</link><description>Labor has ruled out changing copyright laws to give tech giants free rein to train artificial intelligence models on creative works after the proposition was met with widespread backlash from artists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66b4703c47bd54b24c427a241643fc3d</guid></item><item><title>Israel names Iranian it says is responsible for attacks in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/israel-allege-iran-official-responsible-aus-antisemetic-attacks/105936396</link><description>Israeli spy agency Mossad publishes details about an alleged Iranian official it claims is responsible for leading a unit promoting antisemitic attacks around the world, including in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a90e05b935eddaabab30c038fb5ce1da</guid></item><item><title>Peter Sellars prepares Adelaide Festival comeback 24 years after controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/peter-sellars-returns-to-adelaide-festival-as-program-launched/105916826</link><description>The Adelaide Festival is launching its line-up for its 2026 instalment, and the program will feature both fresh and returning faces, including British rock band Pulp, French actor Isabelle Huppert and American theatre director Peter Sellars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dcc56b9dbdd71fa03a1b9ee5f3f8eaa</guid></item><item><title>Growing calls to introduce dog day care, walking and training mandatory standards in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/pet-dog-day-care-walking-training-regulation-nsw/105908954</link><description>Animal welfare experts are calling for mandatory qualifications and regulation of dog day care, walking and training services in NSW, as the industry booms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a59b2768b910d3603628039bb988072c</guid></item><item><title>Call for mandatory qualifications and regulation of dog day care, walking and training services.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/dog-day-care-qualifications-services/105931902</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea4812d2d33af556fc4163e7a7f9bfb6</guid></item><item><title>Trump, trade and security on agenda for Anthony Albanese at ASEAN summit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/trade-trump-and-security-asean-summit-/105936256</link><description>Anthony Albanese arrives in Kuala Lumpur, following in the footsteps of US President Donald Trump, who is also at the summit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cb28606f155452c4100dd6d124ac541</guid></item><item><title>Could species-specific fish 'hotels' help save Australia's freshwater populations? This spring could hold the answer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/freshwater-fish-blackfish-bungalows-breeding-season-saving/105929108</link><description>This spring offers a critical window to see if man-made "bungalows" installed in rivers can help a struggling fish species. If they work, they could provide a path forward for restoring other battling Australian freshwater fish populations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9753058cff7f306490d8d0cfc88a34d5</guid></item><item><title>How ecologists turned fish 'hotels' into 'bungalows' to save a species</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/ecologists-turn-fish-hotels-into-bungalows-to-save-blackfish/105930762</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b66bd254aea089c1d3f60e46ed92a356</guid></item><item><title>Occupational Therapy Australia survey finds two in five Australians had to pause work, education, hobbies due to injury or illness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/occupational-therapy-australia-report-participation-gap/105913244</link><description>A new survey lays bare what Occupational Therapy Australia describes as the "participation gap".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a9a2c275e5f9900d56b34cdde3d6d15</guid></item><item><title>Ms Dean goes camping and 4WDing after years of rehab.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/leonie-dean-wheelchair/105932978</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">449f203e0727045ff54ba5afd27ddc4b</guid></item><item><title>Teenagers struggle to tell if videos are real or fake as AI floods social media</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/teens-struggle-to-tell-if-social-media-videos-are-real-or-ai/105924186</link><description>BTN High puts teenagers to the test to see if they can spot if videos are fake or real. It was harder than the high schoolers thought.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a16db8716554ccf5e0953ef8fa369b14</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand's Sophie Devine plays her final ODI in Women's World Cup loss to England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/nz-says-farewell-to-devine-odi-talent-at-women-s-world-cup/105936754</link><description>New Zealand's Sophie Devine, one of the stars of international women's cricket, plays her last ODI, suffering defeat to England at the World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1305f62f940c93e77e04bc6a3ced1a18</guid></item><item><title>ASX gained on 'constructive' trade talks, rare earths dumped, ACCC hauls Microsoft into court over Office 365 subscriptions — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/asx-markets-business-news-live-blog/105936204</link><description>"Constructive" talks between US and Chinese trade negotiations ahead of a meeting between Trump and Xi have lifted global share markets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24617f1d688d05f315ae1f5bb4ef8902</guid></item><item><title>North West Queensland is rich in critical minerals. Will it benefit from the Trump deal?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/what-trump-critical-minerals-deal-means-for-north-west-qld/105928800</link><description>A multi-billion-dollar critical minerals partnership between Australia and the US is touted as a landmark industry deal and is expected to speed up projects in minerally rich outback Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e351ead1f879dec58a227920e43f3d6b</guid></item><item><title>Chess grandmaster Vladimir Kramnik files complaint over online threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/vladimir-kramnik-files-complaint-over-online-threats/105936764</link><description>Former world chess champion Vladimir Kramnik has asked Swiss authorities to investigate threatening messages posted online following the sudden death of US grandmaster Daniel Naroditsky.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4739f4ba3c791e631af431c5cd042dd</guid></item><item><title>British MPs consider motion to strip Prince Andrew of Duke of York title</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/prince-andrew-could-lose-royal-home-face-parliamentary-debate/105936712</link><description>It comes amid mounting speculation that King Charles III may force his younger brother out of his long-time home on Windsor Castle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06641201bae3f26fe89639dfad4d9e92</guid></item><item><title>Family demands answers after patient with dementia found dead in river</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/walgett-family-heartache-after-death-of-patient-with-dementia/105861582</link><description>The family of a 73-year-old man, who was found dead in a river after leaving a New South Wales hospital, believes his death was preventable and that it has been let down by the medical system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">559f5a4ba430056c34fffc362113ec55</guid></item><item><title>Car speeds through crossing in Melbourne's south-east, inches away from pedestrians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/mornington-pedestrian-crossing-near-miss/105936744</link><description>Victoria Police releases vision of a car which sped through a pedestrian crossing in Melbourne's south-east, narrowly missing a number of pedestrians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c93747926c35a01c041f95b4fef7620</guid></item><item><title>Vehicle nearly misses pedestrian while speeding through red light</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/vehicle-nearly-misses-pedestrian-while-speeding/105936912</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1084e9218b63f8500a12674e9042472</guid></item><item><title>Five simple questions the NT government won't answer after ABC investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/nt-racing-and-wagering-commission-questions-four-corners/105931622</link><description>Three weeks after an ABC investigation raised allegations against the NT's gambling commission, the government is refusing to answer straightforward questions about what's being done – if anything.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75bfe982143fb3af3e52e13531c9a581</guid></item><item><title>Former diplomat Lachlan Strahan shares insider's take on Solomon Islands-China deal in memoir</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/lachlan-strahan-diplomat-solomon-islands-china-foreign-affairs/105933764</link><description>Former diplomat Lachlan Strahan used his memoir to criticise parts of the Coalition government's response to Solomon Islands' 2022 deal with China, while revealing some Australian officials pushed to impose "punitive" measures on Solomon Islands if it deepened security cooperation with China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf134e4675c198721ad176dca54b11e1</guid></item><item><title>Planetarium and observatory planned for Australia's only dark sky reserve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/river-murray-international-dark-sky-reserve-seeks-planetarium/105885452</link><description>Amid the global rise of "noctourism", the country's only officially listed dark sky reserve is working on an ambitious proposal for an underground planetarium and observatory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8302a3373ea1184cf83fd7462b5c0c1c</guid></item><item><title>WA neurosurgeon shortage delaying surgery for vulnerable spinal patients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/perth-neurosurgeons-leading-to-delays-for-spinal-treatment/105709668</link><description>A Perth man's wait for surgery to treat painful pressure sores exposes delays and specialist shortages in Western Australia's spinal care system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed3e21f3d000d1ad436756bdde17f96e</guid></item><item><title>Thousands without power as Brisbane swelters through 39-degree heat after wild storms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/brisbane-power-outage-storms-hot-weather/105936886</link><description>Tens of thousands of homes remain without power after destructive storms, as south-east Queensland swelters through another scorcher. The mercury in parts of Brisbane reached 39.1 degrees Celsius, on par with the hottest October day since 1957.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a190eb2c1291abce338a7de03f3c2d0</guid></item><item><title>Dangerously Modern at the Art Gallery of New South Wales re-centres women in the history of Australian art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/dangerously-modern-exhibition-art-gallery-of-new-south-wales/105886336</link><description>At the turn of the century, Australian women artists travelled to Europe and returned with new styles and techniques. Their long-overlooked contribution to Australian art is celebrated in Dangerously Modern.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b9097ba58d930dd82435feeac3eff0b</guid></item><item><title>Australia looking for improvement in second Ashes Test, despite losing skipper Isaah Yeo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/roos-ready-to-roar-on-in-ashes-without-their-captain/105937008</link><description>Isaah Yeo's head knock will keep him out of the second Ashes Test with England but Australia is determined to improve, even without their inspirational leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9130aae2e71ce53fcacb9eba8ab54ecd</guid></item><item><title>Tributes flow for New York Jets legend Nick Mangold after former NFL star dies aged 41</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/nick-mangold-tributes-flow-for-new-york-jets-champ/105937056</link><description>An emotional Rex Ryan pays tribute to New York Jets champion Nick Mangold, who died aged 41 on the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55b61630049d42486162f1b3969d3d4c</guid></item><item><title>Australian captain Pat Cummins out of first Ashes Test, will return to bowling this week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/pat-cummins-ruled-out-of-first-ashes-test/105937328</link><description>Pat Cummins is officially ruled out of the first Ashes Test against England, with Steve Smith named to step in as skipper in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c652c7853992ac952640d437f2fed3f</guid></item><item><title>ACCC sues Microsoft for allegedly misleading millions of Australians with Microsoft 365 subscription hikes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/accc-sues-microsoft-allegedly-misleading-365-subscriptions/105937436</link><description>The consumer watchdog is suing Microsoft for allegedly misleading about 2.7 million Australians over its Microsoft 365 subscriptions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1b43c5f2624e452c623dda79f288e10</guid></item><item><title>Carbon credit profits used to fund restoration around UNESCO biosphere reserve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/fitz-stirling-corridor-restoration-with-carbon-credits-profits/105722304</link><description>A decades-long conservation project restoring vegetation between two renowned national parks could be accelerated using the carbon economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de970b2dfc8457c2ac7362f54eb03cd0</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged with attempted murder after allegedly shooting at Tasmanian police in Collinsvale driveway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/woman-charged-attempted-murder-shot-allegedly-fire-at-police/105937384</link><description>Police say officers had arrived at a southern Tasmanian property when they noticed something had struck their unmarked vehicle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77c9e09a3326078d3a63a7df0220c36d</guid></item><item><title>Golden golfers a hit in the red dirt of this Broome backyard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/golden-golfers-hit-it-out-of-the-park-on-backyard-course/105931466</link><description>A daily round of golf and gardening in the red soils of Broome keeps this chipper couple on a healthy course.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4df98a09ffb2d22c7622d00fb2378805</guid></item><item><title>Coastal repairs underway for eroded beach on NSW far south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/surfside-beach-erosion-repairs-dredging-beach-scraping/105929262</link><description>Scientists hope the ocean current will help to replenish sand missing from a NSW beach decimated by recent storms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b603923a231337c5a230df22c60ba2f0</guid></item><item><title>Snow lands at low altitudes across Hobart suburbs and surrounding areas in 'uncommon' sight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/tas-snow-low-around-hobart-too-cold-for-tomatoes/105937192</link><description>Snow has fallen in Hobart suburbs, including Sandy Bay and Glenorchy, in a "relatively uncommon" sight, the weather bureau says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">536b18de4b3e5494b581b71bb5dd6b39</guid></item><item><title>Australian Facebook users could claim part of this $50m privacy breach payout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/facebook-meta-privacy-breach-claim-payout/105937290</link><description>Right now, more than 311,000 Australian Facebook users can apply for a slice of a $50 million compensation fund from tech giant Meta — the largest ever payment for a breach of Australians' privacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">715d6faf0823f092c292a4f4408ad236</guid></item><item><title>Mum suffers 'chemical exposure' after moving into Housing Trust property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/housing-trust-meth-problems/105936030</link><description>An Adelaide mum says she and her son experienced wheezing, dry-retching and burning in the throat after moving into a drug-contaminated Housing Trust property she was told had been cleaned and maintained.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d81b5e919fa0692a79334dc93a488e3</guid></item><item><title>Northern hairy-nosed wombat joeys mark conservation success for rare Queensland animal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/conservation-success-for-rare-queensland-wombat/105934066</link><description>Three wild-born northern hairy-nosed wombats born in Powrunna State Forest mark a new chapter in the species' recovery from near extinction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e68d048f9a6286559c35c0d7fb94219d</guid></item><item><title>Liam Lawson narrowly misses track marshals running across F1 Mexico City Grand Prix track</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/track-marshals-on-track-f1-mexico-city-grand-prix/105915750</link><description>A camera captures the terrifying moment two track marshals run in front of Liam Lawson's car during Formula 1's Mexico City Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">287ded2791cd3c3cda2264a2b7a52de2</guid></item><item><title>Moto3 rider Noah Dettwiler facing 'multiple surgeries' after horrific crash at Malaysian MotoGP</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/moto3-rider-noah-dettwiler-faces-multiple-surgeries-after-crash/105937792</link><description>One Moto3 rider is facing "multiple surgeries" after an horrific crash at the Malaysian MotoGP. Warning — graphic footage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">337c62bdf6e7f2bdceba2bf2193e02c8</guid></item><item><title>US says no federal food aid will go out from next month</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/us-federal-food-aid-stopping-november/105937556</link><description>The US Department of Agriculture says funds have run dry for its monthly food aid program, which more than 41 million Americans depend on to buy groceries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57b57132be7b1e6404739bda4da6692c</guid></item><item><title>Bill attempts to shield NT backbenchers from Freedom of Information laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/nt-government-changes-freedom-of-information-foi-laws-explained/105929520</link><description>The Northern Territory government has moved to restrict Freedom of Information request laws which, if passed, would block an environment group's long-running attempt to seek historic documents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3101fd89ff04859f6d516d2ae044816</guid></item><item><title>Can you expect a refund from your travel agent if flights get cancelled or delayed? We asked experts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/can-you-get-refund-for-flight-cancellation-or-delays/105787646</link><description>Readers share their challenges in getting flights refunded when booking through a third-party travel agent. We asked experts what that process should look like, what your rights are, and where to get additional support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ae66b446f0db1258be4a2dfdf9d713f</guid></item><item><title>Russia tests nuclear-powered Burevestnik cruise missile, Vladimir Putin wants to deploy it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/russia-tests-nuclear-powered-burevestnik-cruise-missile/105937742</link><description>Russia says the 9M730 Burevestnik "Storm Petrel" is "invincible" to current and future missile defences, with an almost unlimited range and unpredictable flight path.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3682d0a5b5c87ca1f6b85acc15235522</guid></item><item><title>Lani Pallister reveals Katie Ledecky autograph inspired her to break short-course world record</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/dream-big-how-an-autograph-inspired-swim-ace-lani-pallister/105937894</link><description>Australia's Lani Pallister says an autograph she got as a 12-year-old helped inspire her to set a swimming world record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1147fd961f88b02ba98862891c70fc3a</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne's AFLW dominance is a tide to lift all boats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/north-melbourne-aflw-dominance-and-success-a-good-thing/105937080</link><description>While some suggest that this year's AFLW premiers being all but known has caused some to lose interest, commentators say North Melbourne's dominance is inspirational.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">335c6b92348194b0870ec521f6919778</guid></item><item><title>Two US Navy aircraft based on USS Nimitz carrier crash within 30 minutes in South China Sea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/us-navy-aircraft-crashes-south-china-sea/105938082</link><description>Both aircraft went down while conducting "routine operations", the US Navy said, adding that five personnel were "safe and in stable condition" after the crashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e264620615eb560ef0214b466b183353</guid></item><item><title>Ski Patrol captain sounds alarm on uncertain future of Mount Stirling resort</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/ski-patrol-captain-volunteers-mount-stirling-alpine-resorts/105933846</link><description>A volunteer ski patrol captain raises concerns for public safety as part of measures to cut costs at Victoria's Mount Stirling Alpine Resort, which has operated at a deficit for years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7752db6f5fbbb32a38ae640e2f1bc449</guid></item><item><title>Senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price denies involvement in 'coup' to overthrow central land council CEO</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/jacinta-nampijinpa-price-defamation-trial-land-council-boss/105937412</link><description>Senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price has denied being involved in a leadership "coup" to remove the chief executive of the Central Land Council while giving evidence in the Federal Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d1d952cf596571e82aefca05c5f1304</guid></item><item><title>ACCC sues over Microsoft 365 subscription hikes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/accc-sues-over-microsoft-365-subscription-/105938346</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e1bd221e9ce68bfa7c62d546c6fab8a</guid></item><item><title>Woman killed after two cars smash into Perth CBD building in Hay Street</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/woman-critical-after-perth-cbd-crash-in-hay-st/105938338</link><description>A woman is killed when two cars smash into an office building in Perth's central business district.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cfe0617f9e0f5e5130de4e348007622</guid></item><item><title>Spirit of Tasmania operator sent wrong fender specs, leading to $9 million ferry fix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/spirit-of-tasmania-fender-error-9-million-dollar-fix/105917002</link><description>The head of Tasmania's state-owned ferry operator blames "human error" for a berth problem that needs a $9 million fix and modification to the hulls of the two new Spirit of Tasmania ships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8840425c9caf922aa890ec5754f4572d</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with domestic violence offence after Gold Coast crash that killed 3yo boy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/man-denied-bail-after-crash-that-killed-three-year-old-boy/105937646</link><description>A man arrested following the death of a boy in a Gold Coast car crash remains in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c80586ce639c4fc1d18a3d56c4bf4cba</guid></item><item><title>Who is Catherine Connolly, Ireland's new left-leaning, independent president-elect?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/irish-president-catherine-connolly-left-wing-independent-/105937490</link><description>The 68-year-old former barrister is known for being one of the leading pro-Palestinian voices in the Irish parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c146f44190fe609d309fd832757a120a</guid></item><item><title>As South-East Asia reels from tariffs, Donald Trump's flashy 'peace' deal falls short</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/trump-s-flashy-peace-deal-falls-in-short-south-east-asia/105937684</link><description>The US president, who is on a lightning tour of South-East Asia this week, casts a long shadow in the region. But even as he signs deals, nations are contemplating a future without him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">561a3f5c774016694bbebec7813b784f</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri loses F1 lead, but hope remains in his battles against Lando Norris and Max Verstappen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/oscar-piastri-f1-championship-battle-lando-norris-max-verstappen/105896154</link><description>Oscar Piastri has lost his lead in the Formula 1 drivers' championship. Despite momentum working against the Australian, there are still plenty of reasons to believe he can win the world title.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a3dc10cd0a69d64210c5198b4bc41dd</guid></item><item><title>Hurricane Melissa strengthens into Category 5, threatening catastrophic flooding in Jamaica, Haiti</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/melissa-strengthens-into-category-5-hurricane/105937990</link><description>US forecasters believe the Category 4 hurricane could reach Category 5 status, unleashing torrential rain and threatening to cause catastrophic flooding in the northern Caribbean, including Haiti and Jamaica.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2eab8985928c77d6934f1b3d80dbf4e6</guid></item><item><title>Courtroom filled with disgust for Hannah McGuire's killer, Lachlan Young</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/lachlan-young-hannah-mcguire-pre-sentence-hearing/105937608</link><description>Loved ones of Victorian woman Hannah McGuire looked on with shock as a prosecutor told the Supreme Court of her 2024 murder and the events leading up to it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0033dbf829596c623c924a11669c6eb</guid></item><item><title>NSW inquiry into unsolved murders, missing persons will divert police resources, Homicide Squad chief says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/nsw-inquiry-unsolved-murders-to-divert-police-resources/105938468</link><description>NSW Police Force Homicide Squad boss Joe Doueihi is concerned the state parliamentary inquiry will create an "excessive or extra workload" for investigators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b26227da4324ed8a1c35d25552f5f747</guid></item><item><title>What do we know about the investigation into the jewel heist at the Louvre?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/louvre-museum-heist-suspects-arrest-explainer/105937020</link><description>What do we know about the investigation into the jewel heist at the Louvre and what are some of the possible consequences?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef0d91db1ef53761176bab16ee15626f</guid></item><item><title>Cost-of-living crisis and 'weight of the world' means we're socialising less than ever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/decline-in-socialising-rates-impacting-our-wellbeing/105865064</link><description>Data from the latest HILDA survey indicate socialising rates have dropped over the past two decades, and, more recently, have not returned to pre-COVID frequency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f951e2d72f61ad15c8286e0e578eec68</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese raised concerns over 'unsafe' military encounter with Chinese premier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/albanese-chinese-premier-military-encounter/105938890</link><description>Anthony Albanese sat down with Premier Li Qiang — China's second most senior leader — on the sidelines of the ASEAN meeting in Kuala Lumpur on Monday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d652b34fd1cf7a1f9e0089fb86ceb461</guid></item><item><title>WA tops State of the States economic performance report, despite weak economic growth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/wa-tops-economic-performace-report/105938214</link><description>Western Australia again secures the top gong as Australia's best performing economy according to a new report by the Commonwealth Bank, despite the state recording some of the country's weakest economic growth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f2d994b134f9fb71852cd5b8f3b4b4b</guid></item><item><title>Proposal to change building height restrictions in Adelaide CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/adelaide-cbd-high-rise-rules-relaxed-with-airport-approval/105937690</link><description>Adelaide's skyline will be "sent soaring" by changes to building height rules that will make it easier for developers to add extra storeys to CBD construction projects, the SA government says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01f961367413d03886436aa1a134532b</guid></item><item><title>The NuvaRing contraceptive is going on the PBS. Here's how that may impact you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/nuvaring-going-on-pbs-from-november-1-expained/105938344</link><description>Including the NuvaRing on the PBS will slash the cost of contraception for tens of thousands of Australians by around two-thirds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd37cb390e553909164065dd802acebb</guid></item><item><title>The Western democratic world is at a 'civilisational moment'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/john-anderson-boyer-lecture-democracy/105937514</link><description>In his 2025 Boyer Lecture, former deputy prime minister John Anderson reflects on democracy and the end of the liberal global order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d15cbd4e99378b82bf4285e2366df73</guid></item><item><title>Four teenagers plead guilty to manslaughter over deadly Warrawong brawl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/warrawong-brawl-teens-plead-guilty-manslaughter/105939298</link><description>Four teenage girls have pleaded guilty to the manslaughter of Kristie McBride, who was fatally stabbed during a street brawl in Warrawong near Wollongong in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a26803388d07ccbe88e31a4e7f149a95</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters stop spread of out-of-control Bushfire in Northern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/warning-issued-for-out-of-control-bushire-near-drake/105938434</link><description>The warning for a bushfire in northern New South Wales has been downgraded after it threatened to reach Emergency Warning level amid deteriorating weather conditions on Monday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fdc2fa0a0bf0f205e6fbc513a5c6313</guid></item><item><title>California Governor Gavin Newsom to consider 2028 US presidential run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/california-governor-gavin-newsom-2028-us-presidential-run/105939000</link><description>The California Governor says he will make a decision after the 2026 midterm elections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f2ee686c0e73a115d3efa6780f7437e</guid></item><item><title>Alex Greenwich details mental health battle after being targeted by Mark Latham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/alex-greenwich-opens-up-mental-health-after-latham-defamation/105937006</link><description>A Sydney MP has told a gay magazine about his battle with post-traumatic stress disorder and how he turned to exercise and medical cannabis to manage it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf25cebbdee6d0d2dae134d7af12ced3</guid></item><item><title>Sanjeev Gupta urged to pay debts or sell Tahmoor mine as workers go unpaid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/sanjeev-gupta-tahmoor-coal-mine-workers-unpaid/105938924</link><description>More than half the workforce at a coal mine owned by embattled British billionaire Sanjeev Gupta have been stood down without pay, with the union demanding immediate action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ef8c2e3ecf14aa341761bf65b63e7a8</guid></item><item><title>Australia's crumbling childcare safeguards put kids at risk. How can parents make sure they're safe?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/checking-safety-of-childcare-centres-parents-four-corners/105931674</link><description>The scale of Australia's childcare crisis is deeply distressing for parents. These are the simple questions to ask any childcare provider to know if your child is safe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a7e1f6c81a2491a7cc8a9c98bd3c4a8</guid></item><item><title>Virginia Roberts Giuffre's brothers say Jeffrey Epstein's cameras captured crimes, they're demanding they be released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/virginia-giuffre-brothers-jeffrey-epstein-camera-tapes/105930786</link><description>Virginia Roberts Giuffre's brothers are calling for the Epstein files, which they believe include videotapes, to be released. One says he knew for years about her allegation against their father.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3ccb923cd2087a61cb3cdebd75b6826</guid></item><item><title>Environmental watchdog drops charges against company responsible for burning Kealba landfill fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/kealba-landfill-fire-charges-dropped/105926760</link><description>A company responsible for a tip that has been on fire for nearly six years may be allowed to keep its landfill licence, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f535c02cd2782fb95a28530dce2d8fb1</guid></item><item><title>Arnold Schwarzenegger accuses US states of trying to 'out-cheat' each other under Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/arnold-schwarzenegger-criticises-surge-in-gerrymandering/105939400</link><description>Former California governor Arnold Schwarzenegger has expressed concern over the "crazy gerrymandering" that is taking place across the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">098d062f73db15abc818799307f668dc</guid></item><item><title>Why Cam Green staying at No.3 could help get the best out of Steve Smith during the 2025/26 Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/cameron-green-steve-smith-no-3-ashes/105895392</link><description>With Cam Green and Steve Smith shaping as the mostly likely candidates to be selected as Australia's No.3 for this summer's Ashes, selectors face a choice between pragmatism and tradition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a24e1615df4a3d0f5970efa8bbca9252</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of lighting Mount Gambier Valley Lake bushfire while wearing mask and cape denied bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/man-accused-of-lighting-mount-gambier-bushfire-denied-bail/105938734</link><description>Police allege a 37-year-old man lit six fires at Valley Lake, near Mount Gambier, at night while wearing a silver cape and a black mask, after allegedly stealing a cask of wine from a liquor store.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a67ad0e1ac6907998e7c2eca7e5000d</guid></item><item><title>Joshua Berrigan sentenced to 10 years' jail for fatal one-punch attack on Nathan McPherson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/joshua-trevor-berrigan-sentenced-for-maryborough-assault/105937194</link><description>The family of a 43-year-old one-punch attack victim told his killer their lives "have been shattered beyond recognition" during an emotional Queensland court hearing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ac42e4d501c26f63226d7a933811de9</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after Darwin priest stabbed in face with pen while setting up for mass</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/man-charged-with-stabbing-darwin-priest-in-face-with-pen/105937868</link><description>Police charge a 38-year-old man who allegedly stabbed a Darwin priest in the face with a pen while he was setting up for evening mass.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a2edc4c98da0e14fddf35ee83bc56f2</guid></item><item><title>Police scale back search for man missing in waters off Mornington</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/mornington-boat-capsize-missing-man-search-scaled-back/105939572</link><description>The family of a man who was on a small boat that capsized on Friday night say they are mourning the loss of their uncle, brother and friend, as police scale back their search.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6af5532ce13e55d879f276780e6775ed</guid></item><item><title>Argentina's Javier Milei wins in decisive midterms as Trump loan looms large</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/javier-milei-wins-argentina-midterm-elections/105939600</link><description>Argentina's libertarian President Javier Milei has won decisive victories in the midterm elections, in an election where Donald Trump loomed large.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a40f1ae4089cfd4b458c56a0bc2369cb</guid></item><item><title>Fans miss Diljit Dosanjh's Western Sydney concert over 'hurtful' religious dagger ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/nsw-diljit-dosanjh-sikh-concert-denied-entry-kirpan/105938442</link><description>Concertgoers who had tickets to see an Indian music superstar have been offered a refund after refusing to leave their Sikh dagger at the gate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51523a1957e4531d00a35c5428059782</guid></item><item><title>17-year-old charged over alleged stabbing murder near Hobart's Salamanca Place</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/17-year-old-charged-over-alleged-stabbing-murder-near-hobart/105939916</link><description>A youth has been charged by Tasmania Police after a 20-year-old man died in an alleged stabbing near Hobart's Salamanca Place late on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34dc7895c9822dbdc7e9602e749f045b</guid></item><item><title>Aerial water-bombing Sugarbag Road fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/aerial-water-bombing-sugarbag-road-fire/105939682</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f81aee8d2bc37b373adaf8b3a177a117</guid></item><item><title>Neo-Nazi leader Thomas Sewell claims Ballarat rally was political but not offensive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/sewell-contest-hearing-ballarat-rally-political-not-offensive/105931344</link><description>Photos and videos shown to a Victorian court capture a racially charged speech given by Thomas Sewell before he leads a group of 30 masked men through Ballarat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb75038daf38909906d975bfff5fd8d2</guid></item><item><title>Damage control as Bureau of Meteorology defends widely criticised new website</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/bureau-of-meteorology-pushes-ahead-with-new-website/105937612</link><description>In a week of wild weather across the country, the Bureau of Meteorology's new website missed the mark.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b085c26f2584c59928410edf091a234</guid></item><item><title>Police have charged a man for driving dangerously in Kununurra, with a video of the incident posted on Facebook.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/police-pursuit-kununurra/105938422</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1368122caa4b06bd67fe685b8ffd4900</guid></item><item><title>Leaders in West Australia's far north believe a safe night place would help reduce youth crime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/kimberley-youth-crime-kununurra-solutions/105938268</link><description>As juveniles in Kununurra continue to be arrested over car thefts, community leaders and the government are looking for solutions</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0481da295f617e70262942e012830378</guid></item><item><title>Caboolture bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/caboolture-bushfire/105939366</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9801f5c541ce03ba0b404811b0aac0c7</guid></item><item><title>Attempts to move a tree branch led to a powerline sparking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/powerline-sparks-car-pulls-tree/105939846</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c376272dacada1903716f3f1ebaed07</guid></item><item><title>Tens of thousands of people without power as South-east Queensland suffers heat, fires, smoke a day after storm hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/south-east-queensland-heat-fires-smoke-after-storm/105939780</link><description>More than 30,000 people are without power after south-east Queensland has been hit by storms, smoke, fires and winds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57307c2cabdb2507a4b1a96bc52d2e5d</guid></item><item><title>Perth and WA faces sliced bread shortage after fire disrupts Tip Top factory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/sliced-bread-shortage-after-tip-top-bakery-fire/105939360</link><description>A fire at an industrial bread facility in Perth's south causes a shortage of sliced bread on supermarket shelves across Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4989ce3789f7387210e0acd9a6162148</guid></item><item><title>Virginia Giuffre's brothers pledge to fight for justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/virginia-giuffre-s-brothers-pledge-/105939632</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">138ebf35dce8f5e57a6f29d45f6ff622</guid></item><item><title>RBA governor Bullock says a severe market downturn would raise financial stability concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/rba-governor-michele-bullock-interest-rates-jobless-rate/105937584</link><description>The Reserve Bank governor tells a Sydney gathering of economists she and her overseas counterparts are perplexed by what they call "sanguine" financial markets. They question is whether it will "all end in tears".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8efa2e944fb48aa5c5aaf377c3f93f8</guid></item><item><title>ACT 'beginning to see change' two years on from the introduction of drug decriminalisation laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/act-two-years-on-from-drug-decriminalisation-laws/105938834</link><description>Advocates say since the ACT decriminalised "personal use" amounts of some illicit drugs, the territory has seen a shift toward meaningful harm reduction, but others are calling for those laws to be repealed, saying they are not working as intended.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25e6b1c652ddf2cae70975c51d12aff4</guid></item></channel></rss>