<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 07:08:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>SA man pleads guilty to manslaughter of wife, not guilty to murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/sa-man-pleads-in-court-over-wifes-death/106228606</link><description>A South Australian man is due to stand trial after admitting to the manslaughter of his wife at a northern suburbs home, but has told a court he is not guilty of her murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b23e43e02119b10893bf0c2253cc4fba</guid></item><item><title>These were the most-borrowed books from Brisbane libraries in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/qld-most-borrowed-books-from-brisbane-libraries/106226112</link><description>New data has revealed there were 5.9 million physical items — including books, CDs and DVDs — checked out of Brisbane libraries in 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4938839de3a26241ffe9c1436684ed69</guid></item><item><title>Investigation launched into man's death at Wide Bay hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/man-death-under-investigation-in-maryborough/106228736</link><description>An investigation has been launched into the sudden death of a man in the Fraser Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">676250179ee2aed8ad6e2380d4efc7cf</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos midfielder Jackson Irvine ruled out 'until further notice' with recurrence of foot injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/jackson-irvine-socceroos-ruled-out-injury/106229002</link><description>Socceroos midfielder Jackson Irvine is facing an extended stint on the sidelines heading into this year's World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a899b9198b56795ad8a2f3d43f9b63d9</guid></item><item><title>Pilbara home to five animal species most impacted by habitat loss, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/does-mining-help-endangered-pilbara-animals-conservation/106213512</link><description>The Australian Conservation Foundation says tens of thousands of hectares of land were approved for clearing last year, double that of 2024, putting already endangered species at further risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a52728535cce5680a3394bb8b041dd3</guid></item><item><title>Farmers hurt by Victorian fires to receive $50m state and federal support package</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/50-million-dollars-support-fire-affected-farmers-victoria/106228120</link><description>The Allan government says it will provide grants and loans to support farmers who have lost homes, livestock, infrastructure and feed in the Victorian fires.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">821ad905b108ac86e9708990e9a911a1</guid></item><item><title>Man hoarding footballs convicted of dangerous driving and fined after years-long 'pranking' by kids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/tasmanian-man-hoarding-footballs-convicted-of-dangerous-driving/106223894</link><description>A Tasmanian man who had "had enough" after becoming the target of "pranks" by kids, had hoarded "hundreds" of footballs kicked into his yard from the neighbouring school, a court hears.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c34abd9c23a6b71e06f818f0cce401c2</guid></item><item><title>China reports $US1.2 trillion trade surplus in 2025 despite Trump trade war</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/china-recorded-us-1-2-trillion-trade-surplus-in-2025/106229232</link><description>A shift away from the United States toward South-East Asia, Africa and Latin America has helped Chinese exports remain strong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e212ba4c1a39c4795b6b2f9eea38bd34</guid></item><item><title>New project at old Port Augusta power station site to create 150 jobs and 'green cement'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/port-augusta-fly-ash-power-station-green-cement-project-sa/106228256</link><description>About 150 jobs will be created by a new "green cement" project at a power station site which has sat vacant for nearly a decade, the SA government says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae55a6d21699148c071eefec985cfca1</guid></item><item><title>Peak Jewish group urges Labor to 'get rid' of hate exemption for religious texts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/jewish-groups-warns-against-religious-text-defence/106228086</link><description>Representatives of the Jewish community and Australian National Imams Council front a snap parliamentary hearing called to probe Labor's legislative response to the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3482552ddaf1300743d253e83b03b4f2</guid></item><item><title>'Significant' theft of toxic poppies could cause death, Tasmanian authorities warn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/warning-poppy-thieves-of-potential-death-injury/106229422</link><description>The theft of a "significant quantity" of medicinal-grade poppies could result in a "life-threatening" situation if they are ingested in pursuit of a high, Tasmanian authorities warn.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">215e5f0380d3d16c97d7b5ca3f94a9d2</guid></item><item><title>US needs Greenland for purpose of national security, says Trump ahead of talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/trump-says-us-needs-greenland-for-purpose-of-national-security/106229044</link><description>Greenlandic and Danish foreign ministers will meet US Vice-President JD Vance and Secretary of State Marco Rubio in Washington after the US renews threats to take control of the Arctic island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5887168a02c47aa70981fcac835d7a49</guid></item><item><title>Taylah Preston makes Hobart International quarterfinals after upset win over Rebecca Sramkova</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/taylah-preston-hobart-international/106229720</link><description>The 20-year-old world number 204, who also has a wildcard at the upcoming Australian Open, won the match against the world number 72 6-4, 6-1.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e51920ec87b8e4ca27d7cdc51b9c1b96</guid></item><item><title>Alyssa Healy taken aback by reaction to commentary stints as post-retirement career seems assured</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/alyssa-healy-taken-aback-retirement-announcement/106229710</link><description>After calling time on her decorated 15-year career, a spell in media commentary looks inevitable for Australian cricket star Alyssa Healy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66dd158844b47bc8dcef39e4b8f15a79</guid></item><item><title>Police search for $140k boat stolen from Mooloolaba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/police-search-for-boat-stolen-from-mooloolaba/106228356</link><description>Police search for a boat worth about $140,000 that was stolen from the Sunshine Coast after its keys were left on board while the owners were overseas on holiday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6773d539e70fdaf8b2990425201b4056</guid></item><item><title>ABC News report on London Bridge collapse in 1990</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/abc-news-report-on-london-bridge-collapse-in-1990/106227652</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113b4a75783053250071b90218303d52</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide United says Josh Cavallo never raised homophobia concerns with A-League club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/adelaide-united-says-josh-cavallo-never-raised-homophobia/106229066</link><description>The head of Adelaide United says the former Reds player Josh Cavallo never raised concerns about homophobia or not being selected to play based on his sexuality while at the A-League club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05f953d597b8a916958cc3e90b11000e</guid></item><item><title>Central Queensland graziers share livestock survival stories amid flood devastation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/cow-survives-80km-swim-in-floodwater-to-beach/106228566</link><description>Amid the damage from flooding in central Queensland, tales of livestock surviving are emerging, including one cow's incredible waterlogged journey.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6677c4fbfa14eae9c671d2b96b64de7f</guid></item><item><title>Arrest warrant issued for man in NSW over alleged murder of Brisbane carer Velvet Pesu</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/qld-police-issue-warrant-over-alleged-murder-velvet-pesu/106230010</link><description>Velvet Pesu was found dead at a house in Logan on Monday while police were conducting a welfare check.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92c53e68b5a601dd1a53377fab7ffccb</guid></item><item><title>Office evacuated after old explosives found in Kalgoorlie backyard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/old-mining-explosives-kalgoorlie-police-responding/106229626</link><description>Builders working in the rear yard of a surveying company got a shock when they came across a hessian sack full of old mining explosives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e0472fe1c9259c93218726b8a31799f</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106230046</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fb5bd6a65b0dccbba4c91afd2db760e</guid></item><item><title>Indonesian fishermen who 'should have known better' jailed after repeat offences in Australian waters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/illegal-fishermen-jailed-in-darwin-after-repeat-offences/106228410</link><description>The men will serve four months in prison after being caught off the WA coast with 40 kilograms of sea cucumber and an array of fishing gear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e466a2696254e19c31669e5065a2ddf6</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide Writers' Week move prompted 'wildfire' worry in festival director</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/festival-director-and-former-board-member-on-writers-week-saga/106227320</link><description>As the Adelaide Festival director reveals he had urged the festival's board not to cancel Palestinian Australian author Randa Abdel-Fattah, a former board member opens up about his very different concerns about the Adelaide Writers' Week program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74bc53b0155fa33cfa82ff9f27e97fe8</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian commercial fishers warned about potential antibiotic contamination from salmon pens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/salmon-antibiotic-florfenicol-warning-to-commercial-fishers/106227966</link><description>Tasmania's Natural Resources and Environment Department has warned commercial fishers that driving their boats near some salmon pens could result in their onboard catch absorbing traces of the antibiotic florfenicol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a02cfb1aaa300f834a36f4ef99ce0822</guid></item><item><title>Pipe bombs found on Canberra footpaths, public urged not to touch suspicious items</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/pipe-bombs-found-on-canberra-footpaths/106230350</link><description>Police are urging Canberrans not to touch suspicious objects after pipe bombs were discovered in Belconnen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">981fe9a6a28c3a5e89c6f3c734dda4f2</guid></item><item><title>Australia investigating options to assist search for missing diver in Antarctica</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/search-for-missing-diver-in-antarctica/106230320</link><description>Australian authorities say they are "investigating all the options available" to assist a search operation for a diver missing in Antarctica.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e8f86a247454a2f865cccbd59abbbe5</guid></item><item><title>Iran warns of retaliation as US withdraws troops from Middle East bases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/iran-judiciary-signals-fast-executions-for-protesters/106230222</link><description>It comes as Iran's judiciary defies US warnings and says those detained over anti-regime protests could face execution, although the Iranian foreign ‌minister says there is no plan to hang people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5072e86f4a6a02117d544b7bca5b3907</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open One Point Slam winner Jordan Smith beats professional tennis players to take home $1 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/australian-open-one-point-slam-winner-jordan-smith/106230542</link><description>Sydneysider Jordan Smith has beaten grand slam champion Jannik Sinner and dual grand slam finalist Amanda Anasimova to take home the prize in the novelty format.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c0967b66001ffb7aaa79e5bc8e54dc1</guid></item><item><title>X to change AI chatbot after outrage over sexual deepfake images</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/x-changes-ai-chatbot-sexual-deepfake-images/106230564</link><description>New laws in the UK that would outlaw the generation of sexual deepfakes are set to come into force this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de315c4712c9db8b27a692a28ce594d4</guid></item><item><title>FBI raids home and seizes devices of Washington Post journalist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/fbi-raids-home-of-washington-post-reporter/106230658</link><description>The reporter had previously reported on the Trump administration's efforts to fire hundreds of thousands of federal workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd257074b9bd6d03701249e742f649e6</guid></item><item><title>What it's like working at Casey Station in Antarctica</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/life-in-antarctica-at-casey-station/106196216</link><description>From 6,000 applications each year, only about 300 make the cut to travel down to Antarctica and experience a workplace like no other.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c37ab8ea61fbe9b0251d13a8dbb60f6e</guid></item><item><title>Tens of thousands of livestock confirmed dead as Victorians return to bushfire-ravaged communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/victoria-bushfires-homes-destroyed-farmers-support-package/106229098</link><description>Around 260 homes have been confirmed destroyed and 20,000 head of livestock killed by bushfires across Victoria, with authorities warning the total is likely to rise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de7a7ce9f8a50123edc0b3db824696bb</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley signals Liberals won’t back 'unsalvageable' hate crime and gun control reforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/coalition-backs-away-from-hate-and-gun-law-reform/106230306</link><description>Liberals are backing away from a push to tackle antisemitism with stronger racial hatred laws, with some senior figures in the party also voicing freedom of speech concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fe03e843add5cc7db046019a4dbbdfd</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine's former PM Yulia Tymoshenko, formerly a rival to Volodymyr Zelenskyy, facing allegations of bribery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/former-ukraine-pm-yulia-tymoshenko-facing-bribery-allegations/106230680</link><description>Anti-corruption watchdogs in Ukraine have searched the offices of the country's former prime minister Yulia Tymoshenko amid allegations of a major bribery scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">412ca99065bbad595c00252a4ab124c8</guid></item><item><title>Who to see at Tamworth Country Music Festival 2026 — top artists and event details</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/tamworth-country-music-festival-2026-bands-performers-acts/106225466</link><description>Discover the must-see artists at the 2026 Tamworth Country Music Festival — from breakout stars like Lane Pittman to legends such as Felicity Urquhart. Your ultimate guide to shows, dates, and insider tips.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">829ffa2e34cca51a61b79f1804ff6360</guid></item><item><title>From inside Iran, a young protester says the people 'are waiting for America to intervene'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/from-inside-iran-protester-asks-donald-trump-to-help/106228502</link><description>A defiant voice bravely breaks through Iran's internet blackout to detail the horrors she has witnessed and to tell the president of the United States "the people are waiting for America to intervene".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9892ccf8e7e6f402026538890ae55608</guid></item><item><title>Rental market growth stalls in some capital cities as household budgets stretched to limit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/rental-market-capital-city-rents-domain-lack-of-affordability/106223682</link><description>Australia's rental market is "starting to rebalance" with prices flat in some capital cities but affordability remains a concern, according to Domain, which says an annual salary of $100,000 is needed to live comfortably.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dc5cb614893519f34c81170bb986043</guid></item><item><title>Writers' Week cancellation highlights SA premier's uneasy relationship with the arts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/writers-week-cancellation-hits-the-festival-state/106226674</link><description>After backing the Adelaide Festival's decision to drop a Palestinian Australian author from Writers' Week, Peter Malinauskas is now trying to distance himself from a crisis that threatens to do untold damage to South Australia's festival reputation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">666a3079a0050792b8a7daebf44a9e06</guid></item><item><title>Jafar Panahi is ready to go to prison for the film the Iranian government doesn't want you to see</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/jafar-panahi-iran-it-was-just-an-accident/106227500</link><description>Would you face prison for what you believe in? Iranian filmmaker Jafar Panahi already has and, following the release of his latest film, he may again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35c0b0def4e6061343a9627eb9dc73c9</guid></item><item><title>Reopening Gulgong Medical Centre a 'lifeline' for the community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/gulgong-gp-clinic-reopening-lifeline-for-the-community/106174008</link><description>Gulgong went 18 months without a GP clinic. It has now reopened, giving residents a reprieve from travelling hundreds of kilometres to see a doctor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97e72d7354fd5c48a9d73ce8f95f3acd</guid></item><item><title>Controversial group Hizb ut-Tahrir says it 'cannot be banned' despite proposed laws targeting hate speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/islamic-group-hizb-ut-tahrir-responds-to-new-laws/106229340</link><description>Controversial group Hizb ut-Tahrir says the government "cannot ban" its ideas, despite its members facing the threat of jail under proposed hate speech laws to go before parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4007c184f28517413c81eb2f0147169c</guid></item><item><title>Trauma medics warn over-60s against climbing ladders as 6,000 people hospitalised in a year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/doctors-urge-caution-ladder-falls-ageing/106204082</link><description>Thousands of people present to Australian hospitals each year for ladder and roof falls, with doctors urging caution — particularly for ageing Australians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c12a493ae6335c72bd54f967726d7834</guid></item><item><title>Trump to write next chapter of US relations with Iran after decades of tensions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/us-iran-history-explained/106227524</link><description>From a CIA-led coup to a hostage crisis and air strikes, here are some of the defining moments in seven decades of relations between the United States and Iran.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">837a93e06d529274409eb52bbbb4e58d</guid></item><item><title>Tree bark microbes play a role in eliminating greenhouse gases, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/tree-bark-microbes-play-a-role-in-eliminating-greenhouse-gases/106211008</link><description>Tiny, gas-eating microbes hidden in the bark of trees offer scientists a crucial clue in the fight against global warming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c78775ba4ebdfdc2b54039a64dd8a98</guid></item><item><title>Bark microbes removing greenhouse gases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/bark-microbes-removing-greenhouse-gases/106211384</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98ef3d0bf74c65bc0f1e360c985ba734</guid></item><item><title>Denmark, US fail to agree over Greenland after high-level talks at White House</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/greenland-denmark-us-meeting-on-territory-future/106230646</link><description>The United States and Denmark continue to disagree over the future of Greenland after a meeting at the White House amid ongoing threats from President Donald Trump threatening to seize the semi-autonomous Danish territory for national security reasons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c913885d1dbaaa29e711759fda0bc6c</guid></item><item><title>NT set to fall short of Indigenous law and justice target despite early success</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/nt-aboriginal-law-justice-groups-lagging-despite-initial-success/106199228</link><description>Despite the NT government signing on to establish 20 Aboriginal Law and Justice Groups by 2027, just five are up and running with less than 12 months to go.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19d4325a995d5e72e0363b4dda9e72a8</guid></item><item><title>Danish foreign minister says Trump wishes to 'conquer' Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/trump-s-wish-to-conquer-greenland/106230838</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21762560f5a673fa6997e6d355ee2a6f</guid></item><item><title>US to suspend immigrant visa processing for 75 countries, including Fiji</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/us-suspend-immigrant-visa-processing-75-countries/106230746</link><description>The US State Department will suspend processing of immigrant visas for people from 75 countries, including Fiji, Cambodia, Thailand, Somalia and Brazil, from January 21.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3517211b7332fae0797d4eec46fea553</guid></item><item><title>As Adelaide Writers' Week is cancelled, what is the future of writers' festivals in Australia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/adelaide-writers-week-cancelled-literary-festivals-in-crisis/106229240</link><description>The shock cancellation of Adelaide Writers' Week has left many concerned about the future of writers' festivals in an increasingly polarised political world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72de9874946b6461b539a4126df66bc5</guid></item><item><title>Regulator investigates alleged breach of Alcoa's mining exemption conditions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/dwer-alcoa-investigation-alleged-breach-mining-exemption/106216754</link><description>WA's environmental regulator is investigating an alleged breach of Alcoa's state-imposed mining conditions which, if proven, would make it illegal for the company to continue some of its mining operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">969cfab590e44b025727a4c514525299</guid></item><item><title>Australia's vet access deserts where an hour's drive is the difference in life and death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/australia-vet-care-access-deserts-life-and-death-for-animals/106229268</link><description>More than 250,000 people do not have ready access to a vet in Australia, and according to the industry, it is not completely down to a shortage. It is also a distribution issue, which is putting biosecurity at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">282f5263cdcd396906a0564b8389e190</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Heat beat Hobart Hurricanes in stunning BBL finish</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/brisbane-heat-pull-off-stunning-bbl-upset-over-hobart-hurricanes/106230892</link><description>A spectacular bowling effort in the final overs and a key contribution from Marnus Labuschagne help the Brisbane Heat to an upset win over the Hobart Hurricanes to keep their BBL finals hopes alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71ad3d19ce7da3e1b821c9b0a739b303</guid></item><item><title>Drought-hit grain growers make every drop of rain count</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/drought-hit-grain-growers-make-every-drop-of-rain-count/106207304</link><description>New techniques and technology are allowing southern NSW grain growers to produce a harvest, despite significantly below-average rainfall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">408dff5d16fb21cc039faec44c0873b1</guid></item><item><title>Police say 11 explosive devices found on Canberra streets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/police-say-11-explosive-devices-found-on-canberra-streets/106231010</link><description>Eleven explosive devices have been found next to footpaths in the city's north-west in the past two days, ACT police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6408b18b499e3f801b7a2c4f3154cde0</guid></item><item><title>What is the next phase of the Gaza ceasefire deal?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/us-announces-second-phase-of-gaza-ceasefire-plan/106161108</link><description>With little fanfare, the White House has announced "phase two" of the Gaza ceasefire has begun — at least, in terms of how it views the situation with the war-ravaged territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f695ceab1700367d7a52f9958b4ef0b6</guid></item><item><title>Coalition asks Albanese for the grace he was not afforded in the wake of Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/coalition-sussan-ley-bondi-terror-attack-nationals-gun-control/106231054</link><description>Federal Liberals are discovering the price of having been so brazen in their politicisation of the Bondi terror attack and many appear to have buyers' remorse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c1d9bdb9f2dd264e766d6364eb33aab</guid></item><item><title>Why Alice Springs has become one of Australia's most prolific literary towns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/alice-springs-is-home-to-very-high-number-of-authors/106227808</link><description>With many local authors, Alice Springs is no longer just a setting for stories by writers from elsewhere. It is becoming one of Australia's most distinctive literary centres with homegrown talent inspired by the Red Centre's landscape.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">464f7ed2216e336d939327f0d085cab7</guid></item><item><title>Calls for greater transparency as WA government's annual reports into youth suicide delayed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/aboriginal-youth-suicide-reports-delayed/106116618</link><description>Fearing more lives will be lost, Kimberley Aboriginal leaders call on the WA government to release updates on parliamentary and coronial recommendations into youth suicide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e72a6d20dc2a9a9392d6e514e0de5648</guid></item><item><title>SpaceX capsule begins return to Earth from International Space Station with sick astronaut on board</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/capsule-return-earth-international-space-station-sick-astronaut/106231168</link><description>The Crew Dragon capsule has undocked from the International Space Station carrying four astronauts, one of whom has a "serious medical condition", and is on its way back to Earth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d25be9004e38cad26b2fb726a3d2942c</guid></item><item><title>Moment SpaceX spacecraft with sick astronaut undocks from ISS</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/moment-spacex-spacecraft-with-sick-astronaut-undocks-from-iss/106231342</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1f400b1ef73bd4f0bb7caadd41b8d36</guid></item><item><title>Two French men to plead guilty over alleged $10m luxury theft in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/french-men-plead-guilty-theft-10-million-canberra/106231644</link><description>Lawyers say the value of the allegedly stolen luxury goods, including a $5 million Richard Mille watch, is disputed as the case returns to court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88c8319584a840b4daa47398747b60ed</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide Festival Corporation apologises to Randa Abdel-Fattah over Adelaide Writers' Week call</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/adelaide-festival-corporation-apology-randa-abdel-fattah/106231602</link><description>The Adelaide Festival Corporation, which oversees Adelaide Writers' Week, has apologised to Palestinian Australian author Randa Abdel-Fattah and says she will be invited to speak at its next event in 2027.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67ee9d20379baccfdff18eb5873319de</guid></item><item><title>River Murray, Coorong, Lake Alexandrina listed as critically endangered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/sa-river-murray-coorong-listed-as-critically-endangered/106230452</link><description>Environmental protections along a huge stretch of the River Murray will be boosted, following a decision to officially list the area as "critically endangered", the federal government says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad87655898be0de59a6ce147c98cec32</guid></item><item><title>Stolen Generation artwork discovered in trunk of regional WA museum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/carrolup-mission-artwork-identified-after-decades-in-a-trunk/106149992</link><description>An artwork drawn by a child of the Stolen Generations more than 70 years ago is discovered after decades in the trunk of a regional museum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e32581936684d153cd6ed55b03e3b3e7</guid></item><item><title>Workers on Melbourne farm supplying Woolworths, Coles chase unpaid wages worth $260,000</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/wage-theft-farm-workers-victoria-corrigans-farm-khmer-community/106208768</link><description>According to court documents, at least 20 workers are owed money for the work they did in late 2023 on Corrigan's Farm in south-east Melbourne, which experts say is part of a bigger problem that sees tens of millions in missing cash disappear into the black economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b410ff4079f385d1ce426e5b9d8c8090</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026: Record crowds for 'Opening Week' leave some fans frustrated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/australian-open-record-crowds-opening-week-confusing-marketing/106230520</link><description>The Australian Open has smashed attendance records in what is being marketed as "Opening Week", featuring fan events and qualifying matches, but the main draw does not start until Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc06fa71b4659f85c1225a22e5788fc2</guid></item><item><title>Jordan Smith on winning One Point Slam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/jordan-smith-on-winning-one-point-slam/106231542</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f35fce6022c24e931c19994db040bf66</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026: Who is Jordan Smith? The 1 Point Slam winner who beat Jannik Sinner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/australian-open-2026-who-is-jordan-smith-1-point-slam-winner/106231406</link><description>Jordan Smith comes from a tennis-mad family in Sydney and is now a millionaire thanks to a couple of days' work at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">002abdfc7627705e68441efee36ef427</guid></item><item><title>From dumped shark heads to rising fury — how WA's demersal fishing ban turned ugly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/wa-demersal-fishing-ban-leaves-fishers-frustrated/106229426</link><description>Western Australia's ban on demersal fishing has left fishers frustrated. Will the government be able to soften the blow for an angry industry?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b641c0b367c639c58057e28322f15fa1</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026 draw puts Alex de Minaur against former Wimbledon finalist in tough first round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/australian-open-2026-main-draw-live/106227978</link><description>In the first round, the world number six will face off against Matteo Berrettini, a former Australian Open semifinalist — a place De Minaur has never progressed to himself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13e19ae1d27bc6ae3daae5c2b6bf9ac7</guid></item><item><title>How new passport rules for UK and Ireland dual citizens will work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/new-uk-dual-citizenship-passport-rules-explained/106227516</link><description>Your guide to new UK and Ireland passport rules for dual citizens and general entry changes beginning in February.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">968f21149e61f93d96e475115a59531e</guid></item><item><title>Antonio Arena scores for Roma, raising questions over whether he will play for the Socceroos or Italy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/antonio-arena-international-allegiance-socceroos/106231676</link><description>In Italy, he has earned the nickname Il Baby Bomber because of his size, strength and impact on the game. But where do his international allegiances lie?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0299d4874a4a4c4065f1f4012f488ab3</guid></item><item><title>Neo-Nazi figure Joel Davis denied bail over alleged threat to federal MP</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/nsw-neo-nazi-figure-joel-davis-bail-denied-in-court-again/106232472</link><description>High-ranking neo-Nazi Joel Davis has told a Sydney court the Nationalist Socialist Network "no longer exists" as he was again denied bail for allegedly threatening a federal MP.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee04e57420533ec83490c06e79f2737f</guid></item><item><title>Tom Silvagni, son of AFL star, outlines rape conviction appeal grounds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/tom-silvagni-conviction-appeal-grounds-released/106232440</link><description>Details of the 23-year-old's appeal bid have been released, with Silvagni arguing a judge erred in describing certain evidence as "incriminating conduct" during his rape trial late last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bccaa4f4a6d124582a6a895c3f2c43f</guid></item><item><title>Blooming corpse flower at Adelaide Botanic Garden set to attract thousands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/corpse-flower-at-adelaide-botanic-garden/106231108</link><description>A corpse flower at the Adelaide Botanic Garden is generating excitement but it is actually among five of the rare plant to bloom in the city this summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c9a889ad9cac27a4c0d04f20789d1fb</guid></item><item><title>WA health infrastructure audit delivers scathing assessment of hospital maintenance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/wa-health-infrastructure-review-findings-handed-down/106232198</link><description>An audit of WA's health infrastructure finds the state's aging public hospitals are too reliant on reactive maintenance, with no dedicated funding to keep them up to scratch and little data to inform future decisions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">533de40d7b62c99a7fd9bf0f6f82ecb4</guid></item><item><title>Why Australia is investing in defence infrastructure at five military sites in the Philippines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/australia-defence-investment-bases-philippines-us-china/106220666</link><description>Experts say these agreements are clear signs of how important an ally the Philippines is becoming in the Indo-Pacific region amid jitters of US security guarantees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6341dbed95599c9a4100899d85f47316</guid></item><item><title>Man charged over alleged social media death threats against PM Anthony Albanese, NSW Premier Chris Minns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/teenager-charged-over-alleged-threats-to-kill-prime-minister/106232860</link><description>WA Police charge a 19-year-old man after he allegedly uses social media to send messages, threatening to kill Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and NSW Premier Chris Minns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96f7cfecd4c240124d52c50ae382483e</guid></item><item><title>Iran internet blackout enters seventh day as US President Donald Trump says violence has 'stopped'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/trump-claims-violence-in-iran-has-stopped/106231934</link><description>Washington could intervene militarily in Iran, the Trump administration has suggested, but it remains unclear whether that will happen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b7fef24243f07390ba939d25f94bf57</guid></item><item><title>Greens won't support Labor's sweeping hate law reform in current form</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/greens-wont-support-labor-hate-and-gun-laws-in-current-form/106232006</link><description>The Greens have thrown up a roadblock for Labor by declaring it will not support the government's sweeping changes to hate and gun laws without amendments as the Coalition also backs away from the reforms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8734d3500be7e2552b8d1f4b11e0ca2e</guid></item><item><title>Surgeons appear in court over alleged secret payments in Queensland hospitals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/three-men-accused-of-qld-hospital-fraud-in-court/106232710</link><description>Two surgeons and the co-owner of a medical device company face Brisbane Magistrates court over their alleged involvement in public hospital fraud, allegedly involving secret payments to surgeons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aabe2dbb7fe392008dd3d32fbc42418f</guid></item><item><title>Federal officer shoots man in leg in Minneapolis after being attacked during arrest, officials say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/federal-officer-shoots-person-in-leg-during-minneapolis-arrest/106232696</link><description>A federal law enforcement officer has shot a man in the leg in Minneapolis after being attacked with a shovel and broom handle during an arrest, US officials say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81dd53b2c5112cb5eb38ab88a206ad7d</guid></item><item><title>Dane Sweeny battles into Australian Open main draw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/dane-sweeny-battles-into-australian-open-main-draw/106233154</link><description>A delighted Dane Sweeny will play in the Australian Open main draw for the second time after winning his third and final qualifying match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8d67e8714ce3c8a2f9abbaa2046affe</guid></item><item><title>Anxious business owners fear collateral damage from WA's illegal tobacco violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/illicit-tobacco-neighbours-businesses-fear-damage/106224842</link><description>Business owners neighbouring suspected illegal tobacco stores are calling for a crackdown amid a spate of violent incidents alleged to be targeting the illicit tobacco trade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae757a54121bea10a5c4152366506105</guid></item><item><title>Multiple cars were swept into a bridge at Cumberland River by floodwaters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/bridge-wye-river/106233530</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51eb53e5d524151fd96f2806c01f07e6</guid></item><item><title>Behind Grok's mass digital undressing lies an 'unsurprising' cohort of 'men eager to violate women'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/grok-x-ai-chatbot-sexual-deepfake-images/106227360</link><description>The X AI is not creating sexually explicit images of women on its own, but the software "facilitates their abuse" acting on the requests of men "eager to violate women".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0b645f13a9bed5666cc72f2290bed6c</guid></item><item><title>Thanasi Kokkinakis pulls out of Australian Open singles, hopeful Special Ks can still play doubles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/thanasi-kokkinakis-out-of-australian-open/106233466</link><description>Thanasi Kokkinakis has pulled out of the Australian Open singles before the draw could be announced after suffering a shoulder injury playing in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bd02d4b7ea76ef6be46dbb7ee06cadc</guid></item><item><title>Name change for viral app Are You Dead, designed for young people living alone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/are-you-dead-app-changes-name-demumu/106228484</link><description>A viral Chinese app named Are You Dead aimed at people living alone has been rebranded to avoid controversy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb05616600b298befb0440e70dc4f3f4</guid></item><item><title>Police investigating fraud claim against director of liquidated caravan manufacturer Zone RV</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/zone-rv-in-liquidation-as-police-confirm-fraud-investigation/106227746</link><description>The luxury caravan manufacturer will be wound up, with liquidators promising to step up their investigation into allegations against Zone RV director David Biggar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bd577cea0740db3aa8061c09ee62176</guid></item><item><title>Laura Stein appointed as South Australia's new Chief Justice, replacing Chris Kourakis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/laura-stein-replaces-chris-kourakis-chief-justice/106233288</link><description>Supreme Court Justice Laura Stein has been announced as South Australia's new Chief Justice — the first woman to be appointed to the role.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bc78142ffdec92a223837f30b29eaeb</guid></item><item><title>United Employment collapse leaves disability workers $6 million short in missing pay, super and entitlements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/united-employment-ndis-company-collapse-millions-owing/106148800</link><description>Up to 500 workers are fighting to recoup pay, super and entitlements after the collapse of a large disability support provider operating in New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7ac7f37c5c5fa00e1f1295adb01285e</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian Liberals share, then delete image of two Labor MPs at Taste of Summer festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/tasmanian-liberals-share-then-delete-image-labor-mps/106232506</link><description>The Tasmanian Liberal Party has deleted a photograph it posted on social media that showed two female Labor MPs at the Taste of Summer festival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12df1c1595180c9cabe2b32fee256cce</guid></item><item><title>Three-year-old Ineza King dies following Banya truck crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/three-year-old-ineza-king-dies-following-banya-truck-crash/106233596</link><description>A three-year-old girl who suffered critical head injuries in a horrific multi-vehicle crash last week in regional Queensland has died in hospital, with her family remembering her as a "beautiful spirit".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01c3e297e5de1ee1c343e93d37412a49</guid></item><item><title>International Grammar School teacher Peter Adam in custody over child sexual abuse claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/international-grammar-school-peter-james-adam-child-abuse-charge/106234036</link><description>A Sydney school teacher accused of plotting the sexual assault of two children he was allegedly "pimping out" to another man is refused bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdaf7b7b167ef74305857f329b18422b</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs residents waiting 10 years for public housing while homes sit vacant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/nt-public-housing-waitlist-vacant-homes-in-disrepair/106228236</link><description>Public housing in Alice Springs is sitting vacant and in disrepair while residents wait up to a decade to be allocated a home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3986e4f96e32fd063afafa52d798e11d</guid></item><item><title>Driver's licence suspended after dog dies in alleged hit and run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/licence-suspended-after-dog-dies-in-alleged-hit-and-run/106234270</link><description>A man's licence is suspended as police investigate the death of a dog in an alleged hit and run near Newcastle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17a4c352b350bb23fd802a2db8cb0554</guid></item><item><title>Second fatal crane collapse tied to same company, Thai minister says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/second-crane-collapse-linked-to-same-thai-italian-company/106234382</link><description>A second fatal crane collapse in two days has been linked to the same construction company, a Thai minister says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1060bb9c16eb77efca965d36a1743941</guid></item><item><title>Negin Ghadimi wanted to share her voice in protest with Iranians. She died in her father's arms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/iran-protests-negin-ghadimi-dies-speaking-out-blood-in-streets/106233624</link><description>Negin Ghadimi, a 28-year-old bio-electrical engineer who wanted to be "the voice" of Iranians, was shot in the stomach and killed in anti-government protests last week, her bereaved uncle says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c0d6b16a13a40c2a41a880a47db61f7</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106234344</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ab11f97f2b9463eff70962933bb3d46</guid></item><item><title>Wikipedia is 25, but some old fights are still going</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/wikipedia-marks-25th-anniversary/106219256</link><description>Wikipedia is celebrating 25 years of the online encyclopedia and the enormous impact its had, while looking forward to its future. But some controversies from the past refuse to die.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11c1247adaaff07587cd0e72f90d3077</guid></item><item><title>Ecologist Dr Faith Coleman steps down from government panels after allegations of political interference</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/faith-coleman-resigns-algal-bloom/106231600</link><description>South Australian ecologist Dr Faith Coleman has resigned from two state government algal bloom panels and criticised the state government's approach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">425c45008458b1de287667ba261596c0</guid></item><item><title>Space station astronauts splash down after first-ever medical evacuation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/four-astronauts-splashdown-to-earth-after-medical-evacuation/106234844</link><description>A capsule carrying four International Space Station crew members has splashed down in the Pacific, bringing their mission to an end more than a month early.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">803e4cb04d21cb153d8b5be4641a1c5c</guid></item><item><title>Astronauts return from ISS with sick crew member</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/astronauts-return-from-iss-with-sick-crew-member-/106234958</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a56a4c6ac1b935461069e912c38d188</guid></item><item><title>Astronauts return from ISS with sick crew member</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/astronauts-return-from-iss-with-sick-crew-member-/106234176</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89ef9157730e0c7150a148ceac1237e1</guid></item><item><title>NASA's Crew 11 Dragon splashdown upon returning to Earth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/nasa-s-crew-11-dragon-splashdown-upon-returning-to-earth/106234992</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0537005e847c47fca5e027cb15579f2a</guid></item><item><title>More than 4.7m social media accounts closed in two days after ban began, data reveals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/social-media-ban-data-millions-of-accounts-closed/106232768</link><description>More than 4.7 million Australian social media accounts have been deactivated since laws banning children aged under 16 took effect in December, according to data released by the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16dce5d234729a65a91b7a8646afa7a0</guid></item><item><title>Antidepressants less effective for many living with atypical depression, new study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/antidepressants-less-effective-atypical-depression/106231014</link><description>A major Australian study finds standard antidepressants are not effective for about 20 per cent of people, who may need alternative treatments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a8c18b09b97e2adcc11ee550e10e19a</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong fire at Wang Fuk Court killed 168 people, local authorities announce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/hong-kong-fire-at-wang-fuk-court-tai-po-killed-168-people/106235288</link><description>The final death toll is seven higher than previously reported and comes months after the fire tore through the apartment complex.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fce4181054efb6c2951dbecd213c5e8</guid></item><item><title>Pulp agree to Adelaide Festival show after apology to Randa Abdel-Fattah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/pulp-proceeds-adelaide-festival-show-board-apology-to-author/106235328</link><description>In a social media post, British indie band Pulp says it had previously informed festival organisers of its decision to withdraw but was asked "to delay an announcement while [organisers] sought to resolve this crisis for all sides", and it had now agreed to perform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bcfb9126e8b7e2063766a882de8350f</guid></item><item><title>Trump threatens to invoke Insurrection Act over Minnesota anti-ICE protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/trump-threatens-to-invoke-insurrection-act-on-ice-protests/106235416</link><description>Such a move would allow the president to deploy troops to quell persistent protests in the city of Minneapolis, where two shootings connected to immigration crackdowns are fuelling public anger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be4e94b31dca5813481f12275c1e066b</guid></item><item><title>Great Ocean Road flash flooding leaves beach towns to count the cost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/flooding-great-ocean-road-victoria-wye-river-lorne/106232918</link><description>The Lorne caravan park will be closed for weeks after record-breaking rains turned into "terrifying" floodwaters, sweeping cars into the ocean and inundating holiday parks along Victoria's Great Ocean Road.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3aa2fee47d1168fed51b0f5139b46f4c</guid></item><item><title>Australia's notorious Bass Strait was once conquered by two men in a 4.5m dinghy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/bass-strait-crossing-dinghy-steve-harris-doug-fleming/106197878</link><description>With whisky and lollies for sustenance and pigeons their only means of communication, Steve Harris and Doug Fleming crossed Bass Strait in a 4.5m dinghy in 1974.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddb182d612c9ba27e40d9cb3ed42ea40</guid></item><item><title>Heated Rivalry and growing sports romance genre can teach lessons about queer inclusion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/heated-rivalry-sports-romance-genre-queer-inclusion-sport/106223278</link><description>Heated Rivalry has become a massive global hit, but can the steamy ice hockey romance, and other queer love stories, help create more inclusive spaces in the real sporting world?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a30268fd639f7e0a65aec7b6af9dd321</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: An early departure, an Aussie Golden Globe win and a space mission</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/weekly-news-quiz-january-16/106232770</link><description>Test your knowledge of this week's news cycle here.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a1d2e87f8334aac267d0a6caeb570f1</guid></item><item><title>Fight brewing on national gun reform as states splinter on party lines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/gun-reform-fight-as-states-splinter-on-party-lines/106233538</link><description>A split is emerging at a state level over the government's plan to establish a national gun buyback scheme following the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3728858ed3485104747f8d49716f518b</guid></item><item><title>What is in the government's new hate speech laws?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/hate-speech-laws-labor-antisemitism-bondi/106231326</link><description>Parliament will return early next week to debate new hate speech laws. But what exactly does the legislation include?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13227a51b52cf94309e424b04cf2615e</guid></item><item><title>Energy giant AGL offers cash for conservation amid grid strains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/agl-offers-cash-for-conservation-amid-heatwave-stress/106224032</link><description>In a move labelled a sign of the times, energy firm AGL was last week offering customers money to cut use during a heatwave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38a062f99596aa6253f7fd7500a2f770</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of satellite images capture Victoria's destructive bushfires erupting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/victoria-bushfires-weather-satellite-capture-images-of-blazes/106225070</link><description>Hundreds of images captured by an orbiting weather satellite, and stitched together by the ABC, show the scale and destructive force of the Victorian bushfires.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2940d34e70d1a5381295f69625e97b0</guid></item><item><title>Former Whyalla steelworks owner's $18.5 million royalties debt revealed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/whyalla-steelworks-onesteel-owed-millions-in-royalties/106209554</link><description>The former owner of the Whyalla steelworks, Sanjeev Gupta's OneSteel Manufacturing, owed $18.5 million in royalties when it was forced into administration last year, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93905101bb64aca4064376c56df1e364</guid></item><item><title>Locals oppose tearing down of Bondi terror attack bridge at Waverley Council meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/bondi-shooting-locals-oppose-bridge-tear-down-at-council-meeting/106234010</link><description>Waverley Council held an extraordinary meeting last night, but the future of the footbridge used by the Bondi gunmen remains undecided.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e15760b24f9466906e5458edc5b84916</guid></item><item><title>Calls for greater public awareness about battery dangers after fires at regional landfill sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/battery-tip-fires-public-awareness-landfill-sites-disposal/106231770</link><description>People are being urged to dispose of their batteries properly, after a series of fires at landfills across New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a28007b15a8fc25ff738f7bf9f5375f</guid></item><item><title>Queensland woman wakes up to find carpet python on top of her</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/qld-woman-wakes-to-find-python-on-top-of-her-snake-season/106233916</link><description>It's fair to say when a Brisbane resident woke up to discover a carpet python curled up on top of her, she was rattled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8a5b9ada8ae5962eb7ed5b2a5e7161f</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan families wait in hope for release of political prisoners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/venezuelas-political-prisoners-loved-ones-wait-in-hope/106227698</link><description>Venezuela's new leader says political prisoners are being freed, but hundreds remain jailed, with families clinging to hope that America's intervention and ongoing pressure will eventually secure their loved ones' release</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ce7cf96cd12a20c7865b7b95c6d9310</guid></item><item><title>Who could lead Iran if the Islamic Republic falls?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/who-could-lead-iran-if-the-islamic-republic-falls/106221022</link><description>Names frequently raised include an exiled prince, a former president, and the leader of a leftist movement, but experts say no single figure has the power and legitimacy to take control alone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e0d1638b7162fb93b3554fe45f77822</guid></item><item><title>Child slapped in the face among inappropriate educator discipline exposed in Canberra childcare document dump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/act-inappropriate-educator-discipline-childcare-documents/106233002</link><description>Documents detailing five years' worth of childcare breaches in the ACT reveal cases of educators slapping children, forcibly shaking them, throwing them, and possessing child exploitation material.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71672d028fc50d1d0f8c5baf88613893</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Fish Market vendors to prepare for 'teething problems', ferry wharf still to come</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/sydney-fish-market-teething-problems-concerns-ferry-wharf/106232864</link><description>More than $600 million over budget, the Sydney Fish Market will open its doors, but traders and visitors are being warned to prepare for teething issues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0352d503aa8e33fcdbb6c3f2e22c2510</guid></item><item><title>Investigation proposes ban that could see high-speed waterski racing leave Murray River</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/ban-proposed-for-waterskiing-on-rivers/106199448</link><description>A report into the safety of ski racing on rivers is proposing to ban river racing events and limit speeds following multiple fatalities in recent years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea7d0aa4ae45900dce179b1e43b44dc2</guid></item><item><title>Finn Allen smashes maiden BBL century as Perth Scorchers book finals spot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/cricket-bbl-finn-allen-century-scorchers-renegades/106235726</link><description>Finn Allen saves his best ever BBL innings for when it matters most as the Perth Scorchers out-duel the Melbourne Renegades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f37b3bb00c4fa7487544b60156232085</guid></item><item><title>'Apocalyptic Christian cult' Shincheonji using 'special force teams' to spread across the country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/apocalyptic-christian-cult-shincheonji-spreads-across-australia/106202480</link><description>Documents leaked to the ABC reveal an "apocalyptic Christian cult" is targeting Ballarat, Bendigo, Geelong and Darwin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50f71e383557ba70d1c352778384c418</guid></item><item><title>Hamnet's historical figures are brought to life, only to be robbed of depth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/hamnet-review-jessie-buckley-chloe-zhao-paul-mescal/106225262</link><description>Chloé Zhao's retelling of the life of William Shakespeare is on the fast track to the Academy Awards, but at times feels like Oscar-bait.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf139532041ebe12e88692783526230d</guid></item><item><title>The NT's last private obstetrician walks away as maternity services face collapse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/nt-last-private-obstetrician-walks-away-maternity-collapse/106214806</link><description>A growing number of women in the Northern Territory are travelling interstate to give birth — or leaving the territory altogether — following the sudden closure of the only private hospital maternity ward. Now, the NT's last private obstetrician is closing her practice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc9291c6c8d7a2224bcdd96e4c1d35dd</guid></item><item><title>Wall Street rallies on Taiwan chips, Jim Chalmers backs Michele Bullock over US Fed chair — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/asx-markets-business-live-news-january-16-2026/106235816</link><description>Federal Treasurer Jim Chalmers has come out in support of Michele Bullock after the Reserve Bank governor signed a joint statement in solidarity with Mr Powell, who is facing criminal prosecution driven by US President Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c7302d4b1860cd392ad8e28dfba5dca</guid></item><item><title>European troops won't change Trump's ambition for Greenland, says White House</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/european-troops-in-greenland-do-not-affect-donald-trump-plan/106235716</link><description>As European countries send small numbers of troops to Greenland, the White House says their presence will not affect US President Donald Trump's ambitions for the island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab529e950b13b11d4fb0ac48b2c67c19</guid></item><item><title>Storm Hunter fights tears after overcoming injury heartache to reach Australian Open main draw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/tennis-storm-hunter-qualifies-aus-open-main-draw/106235830</link><description>Storm Hunter books her spot in the main draw of the Australian Open — something that was inconceivable last year as she battled injuries that left her in tears mid-match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69e71babd8fc677ba01522cb381a8bed</guid></item><item><title>Queensland family demands answers after grandmother dies from 'preventable' bloodstream infection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/family-demands-answers-after-sue-smith-hospital-death/106211264</link><description>Struggling to find answers about what happened in the week leading up to her death in hospital, Sue Smith's loved ones say they want hospitals to put more resources into investigating these types of incidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fc4ff40a7ce82a9a499473fecb11cf2</guid></item><item><title>City of Canning Mayor Patrick Hall wins defamation case over ratepayer's social media posts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/canning-mayor-patrick-hall-wins-defamation-battle-with-ratepayer/106232150</link><description>City of Canning Mayor Patrick Hall is awarded a quarter of a million dollars in a lengthy defamation fight with one of his own constituents over a series of social media posts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91951c18c943a87f55ee7cec82c792d3</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Island welcomes 'twice-in-a-decade' return of millions of baby red crabs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/christmas-island-welcomes-twice-in-a-decade-return-of-red-crabs/106228008</link><description>Wildlife officials on Christmas Island, the remote territory 2,600 kilometres north-west of Perth, are welcoming the final chapter of its famous red crab migration — the return to shore of millions of baby crabs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">406c81c826588f6c7fc224723bf31ab3</guid></item><item><title>Winemakers hit hard losing homes, vineyards and stocks in Victorian fires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/strathbogie-winemaker-loses-house-vineyard-and-sheep-in-fire/106227452</link><description>Two wineries in the Strathbogie Ranges have lost a combined 150 hectares of vines, 3,000 sheep and three homes in the Victorian fires.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1108e6fdb84495fe9ad6d42537088c66</guid></item><item><title>Maria Corina Machado greets supporters outside the White House after meeting with Donald Trump.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/machado-greets-supporters-outside-white-house/106235852</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8846ad1928b51cea1d47145d4a12bc76</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan opposition leader María Machado gifts her Nobel Peace Prize medal to Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/donald-trump-meets-marina-machado-venezuela-opposition/106235644</link><description>The US president says he has accepted María Corina Machado's Nobel Peace Prize at a meeting in the White House, on account of "the work I have done".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dcdf94f89defb2531f2b33e9f27334d</guid></item><item><title>Ralph Fiennes says new film 28 Years Later: The Bone Temple is a story of 'monstrosity and empathy'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/ralph-fiennes-says-new-film-28-years-later/106235818</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31a8206402c5fdb4c66f2bef22ce31f6</guid></item><item><title>NSW government unveils $3 billion plan to combat debris balls washing up on Sydney beaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/sydney-water-3-billion-plan-for-debris-balls-on-sydney-beaches/106235746</link><description>The NSW Environment Protection Authority identified the Malabar wastewater treatment system as the origin of the debris balls plaguing beaches in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa8a0741bc28d6be820b3991bbb436cf</guid></item><item><title>Paul Mescal on why we keep coming back to Shakespeare over 400 years later</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/paul-mescal-on-why-we-keep-coming-back-to-shakespeare-/106235874</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e517f5462d0699b834c3839fc785d470</guid></item><item><title>Farm workers chase $260,000 in unpaid wages, some from major supermarket suppliers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/farm-workers-chase-260-000-in-unpaid-wages/106236000</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5fdb80f9e38ee2ef248283b2739577d</guid></item><item><title>75pc of feedlot cattle now have access to shade, industry says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/75pc-of-feedlot-cattle-now-have-access-to-shade-industry-says/106224914</link><description>Once seen as barren landscapes, feedlots across Australia have been reshaping their image. With industry encouraging its operators to install shade, uptake has been widespread.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c824888ff6400824be9622e7ab8a75d8</guid></item><item><title>Nikita Tszyu and Michael Zerafa separated by security in fiery weigh-in clash ahead of boxing clash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/boxing-tszyu-zerafa-weigh-in-clash-brisbane-fight/106235908</link><description>There is no love lost between Nikita Tszyu and Michael Zerafa as they meet for one final time before their much-anticipated fight in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f91081a7d75bae985dd5ef33b75b042</guid></item><item><title>WA farmers grapple with three-month BOM radar outage ahead of planting season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/kimberley-farmers-face-bom-radar-outage/106232438</link><description>A key weather radar in WA's north is expected to be offline for at least three months, leaving farmers and pastoralists facing financial losses and safety risks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87ed3f9b450c8bcd9efc12604ae4b8d3</guid></item><item><title>US says Iran has halted executions but 'all options remain on the table'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/us-says-iran-executions-stopped-but-military-force-an-option/106235854</link><description>The White House says it will hold off on military action in Iran after the regime halted executions, but "all options remain on the table" if the killing of protesters continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c3f20adff78df732db0283624389661</guid></item><item><title>Artificial reefs among options in coastal SA town's erosion battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/artificial-reef-among-robe-erosion-options-south-australia/106224506</link><description>As erosion threatens roads and even homes in Robe in South Australia, artificial reefs and other options are on the table to fight back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82a555804b4f42f58908469efda1812e</guid></item><item><title>Machado says she presented Trump with her Nobel Peace Prize medal.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/trump-with-her-nobel-peace-prize-medal-machado/106236178</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3004acaa0401b9d69540873e35ee48d</guid></item><item><title>Walgett residents furious after 100-year-old Anzac statue smashed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/walgett-devastated-after-century-old-anzac-statue-smashed/106232204</link><description>Residents of a north-west NSW town are angry and heartbroken after a statue with more than 100 years of history was unceremoniously shattered in the middle of the night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3df3049c078091778478c5954df1e11b</guid></item><item><title>Daniel Sanders shrugs off broken collarbone to complete 11th stage of Dakar Rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/motorsport-dakar-rally-daniel-sanders-return-collarbone/106236054</link><description>Daniel Sanders returns to complete the 11th stage of the Dakar Rally less than 24 hours after suffering a broken collarbone and sternum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e03583e93320c8126c9c4e2075c87b65</guid></item><item><title>World champion Shelley Taylor-Smith runs swim group for women at Mettams Pool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/world-champion-shelley-taylor-smith-runs-swim-group/106233342</link><description>They call themselves the "Sea Shells Teabaggers" — and with marathon swimmer Shelley Taylor-Smith at the helm, this ocean swim group has built something much stronger than good technique.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88fe7e0aea361e5c54721018e20ef4fc</guid></item><item><title>Twenty-four parkruns in 24 hours no sweat for Albany runner Ben Castlehow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/ben-castlehow-ran-24-parkruns-in-24-hours-in-albany/106229186</link><description>An Albany man runs roughly three marathons in laps of a hilly parkrun to raise funds for a charity that helped him through a tough time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4d7ae86cfa2992a2d74c0dc629c557b</guid></item><item><title>US legal case against Amazon Prime subscription service leads to cheque in the mail for Australian</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/australian-customer-receives-payback-cheque-from-amazon-prime/106231918</link><description>Australian woman Laura Wells was confused to find an "official-looking letter" from the US with a $51 reimbursement, but it turns out it was legitimate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e196a41d260b822af58deca7f10b30a</guid></item><item><title>Four more pipe bombs found in north-west Canberra as police investigation continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/act-four-more-pipe-bombs-found-belconnen/106236362</link><description>ACT police say they have found four more pipe bombs in the Belconnen area, after 11 explosive devices were discovered close to Lake Ginninderra earlier in the week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">513644bab0fb5075a7e6f982a0508f96</guid></item><item><title>Office workers driven batty by relentless computer updates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/office-computer-updates-slowing-down-productivity/106236080</link><description>Have you turned on your work computer after a holiday, only to find so many updates and security enhancements that you may as well take a break before you start?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d2240a89a0a1e91341167ca0d1bdd6f</guid></item><item><title>North Queensland redclaw farmer looks to science to meet overwhelming resturant demand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/north-qld-farmer-redclaw-demand/106232620</link><description>The freshwater crayfish is becoming more popular in restaurants across Australia, but the industry faces challenges boosting production as more farmers retire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2256de9c6f162818b07e35efb9cdbd55</guid></item><item><title>Trump administration announces 'major sporting event' exemptions from US visa ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/sporting-event-exemptions-us-visa-ban-trump/106236490</link><description>The Trump administration reveals the sporting events that athletes, coaches and support staff can attend in the US despite recent visa bans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2472e4db465099cc44894335ecd051fe</guid></item><item><title>Australian who escaped Iran recalls protesters being shot and says the crackdown is 'different this time'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/iranian-australian-escapes-crackdown-says-different-this-time/106232882</link><description>On a visit to his home town outside Tehran, this Iranian Australian joined the protests last Thursday night, then the regime's suppression methods turned from tear gas to live fire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e702a21a98e7e01de8b0469feaa978d0</guid></item><item><title>Campers told to reconsider travel as severe weather lashes NSW south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/south-coast-rain-floods-camping-travel-risk/106235862</link><description>Campers have been evacuated from low-lying areas as damaging wet weather makes its way along the NSW south coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beab4eb7db994e1d9be52eebe3dc6f83</guid></item><item><title>Engaged Aussie couple Inglis and Kubler through to Australian Open main draw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/engaged-couple-kubler-inglis-through-aus-open-main-draw/106236722</link><description>Maddison Inglis and Jason Kubler were able to celebrate their Australian Open qualifications together in a heartwarming moment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2e3f686eb156eec88655c6bbe6a3f6a</guid></item><item><title>Perth Glory ALW coach Stephen Peters calls out lack of investment in women's A-League football</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/stephen-peters-calls-out-lack-of-investment-in-women-football/106234734</link><description>In recent years, the Glory's women's side has been Perth's saving grace, as the men's team suffered back-to-back wooden-spoon finishes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e182844844c4a8cf8cd4112743394f5a</guid></item><item><title>Convicted fraudster David Prince-Popovich registered as Tasmanian lobbyist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/tas-fraudster-on-official-lobbyist-register/106236786</link><description>David Prince-Popovich registered as an official lobbyist in Tasmania despite being a convicted fraudster, against the register's rules.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e68b84327d549bf1a8c63b98c7609bbd</guid></item><item><title>Flooding in NSW town of Eden on 15th January, 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/flooding-in-eden-on-15th-january-2026/106237324</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac7faeaa76241d7b401a4139b1255535</guid></item><item><title>Belle Brockhoff, former snowboard cross world champ, forced to retire weeks before Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/brockhoff-forced-to-retire-weeks-before-winter-olympics/106237366</link><description>Former snowboard cross world champion Belle Brockhoff announces her retirement just weeks out from the Milan-Cortina Winter Olympics, due to a series of significant long-term injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ead512bff4116118ea78bc86043bf9eb</guid></item><item><title>Japan begins test mining seabed for rare earth minerals to reduce reliance on China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/japan-rare-earth-minerals-deep-sea-mining-plan/106222712</link><description>Tokyo hopes the plan to mine as much as 16 million tonnes of rare earths will help reduce its reliance on China, but will it work?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">541f25a83d40293d5dbe078ce80a2ee4</guid></item><item><title>Three teenagers arrested following Hampton Park home invasion that left 75-year-old man with injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/vic-hampton-park-home-invasion/106236736</link><description>Victoria Police has arrested three teenagers aged between 13 and 16 after they allegedly broke into a home, wielding machetes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6741687ffb09c5684b2325ab4fed8636</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the flash flooding along the Great Ocean Road</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/vic-what-caused-great-ocean-road-flash-flooding/106235904</link><description>Record-breaking rain fell on popular holiday towns in the space of a mere few hours on Thursday, triggering flash flooding that swept away cars, caravans and tents. Here's what we know about the intense rain system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c16087a39c0bb61cb9412d11ca4639b2</guid></item><item><title>Kimberly Birrell knocked out of Adelaide International semifinal by Canada's Victoria Mboko</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/adelaide-international-kimberly-birrell-victoria-mboko/106237590</link><description>It was a tough ask from the outset for Kimberly Birrell, coming up against the teen sensation Victoria Mboko who has been in excellent form of late.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf9fdf97d6598d8bd1b31f11dcd0d1b4</guid></item><item><title>How sunrises and sunsets are helping young people create social connection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/sunrises-and-sunsets-help-young-people-create-social-connection/106130750</link><description>These young people are using sunrises and sunsets to create connection, build friendships and fight the war against loneliness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">183fbc36518025566622ccac534accc3</guid></item><item><title>Man charged in Pheobe Bishop case has matters mentioned in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/kieren-mittelheuser-faces-court-pheobe-bishop-case/106232896</link><description>Lawyers for Kieren Mittelheuser have applied for a registry committal for charges of accessory after the fact to murder and perverting justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">729da9b08233c4d8167df6ccf33fcdb0</guid></item><item><title>Teen directs rescuers through headphones after 80m fall from Mount Walsh</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/teen-directs-rescuers-through-headphones-after-80m-cliff-fall/106227676</link><description>Jake McCollum's bluetooth headphones allowed him to receive calls through his otherwise unusable phone during the arduous wait for emergency services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fb279b7e881326045794e70d68c2659</guid></item><item><title>Peak Jewish body considers further legal action against Islamic preacher Wisam Haddad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/jewish-body-considers-legal-action-wisam-haddad/106236396</link><description>A video has been referred to the peak body’s lawyers to seek advice about possible contempt proceedings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dddc695b22c0cf2c8c2e91c5d13492b1</guid></item><item><title>Iranian asylum seeker exposed to torture by Australia, UN finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/iranian-asylum-seeker-exposed-to-torture-australian-detention-un/106234112</link><description>The United Nations committee has determined Australia breached its international legal obligations by allegedly exposing an asylum seeker from Iran to torture in immigration detention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b86c16f3f4727c5157ee8d1069e1dd9</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the US and European military presence in Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/what-we-know-us-european-military-presence-greenland/106232762</link><description>Here is what we know about the US military footprint in Greenland, and how the increase of troops from Denmark and its allies stacks up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88e9fb4144428e0b64ed7a02ff593a5e</guid></item><item><title>Top religious leaders call on PM to scrap plan to outlaw promotion of racial hatred</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/top-faith-leaders-call-on-pm-to-delay-hate-laws/106237526</link><description>A broad of coalition of Australia's most influential religious leaders have urged the prime minister to scrap Labor's proposal to outlaw the promotion of racial hatred.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc076ae0092ea49a69b774889127ba93</guid></item><item><title>Social media's impact on Australian teenagers' wellbeing isn't black and white, new study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/new-report-social-media-on-teens-mental-health/106224780</link><description>The findings of a newly released study have challenged one-size-fits-all rules and blanket bans, as the Australian government's social media ban for children under 16 has been in effect for over a month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2ce908ee6431741a4f8cc1ce996fb2e</guid></item><item><title>Police say 10 tennis courts' worth of poppies stolen in recent theft</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/large-scale-poppy-theft-tasmania-police-investigating/106231170</link><description>Investigations are continuing into the theft of a large quantity of poppy capsules from a Tasmanian farm. Police have confirmed the harvested area equates to 10 tennis courts, or 2,500 square metres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e446c9678535b4be64f2f18a079d211e</guid></item><item><title>These epaulette sharks are breaking the rules of biology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/epaulette-sharks-are-breaking-the-rules-of-biology/106229708</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcb0cdfb6fe2c17e2820b055802fb9f3</guid></item><item><title>These 'walking' epaulette sharks can make and lay eggs without spending extra energy, scientists say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/captive-epaulette-sharks-make-lay-eggs-using-no-extra-energy-jcu/106231990</link><description>Known best for their ability to "walk" on the sand and coral where they usually live, new research shows epaulette sharks could also defy assumptions in other ways.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b075420a6a431e7245c6cc42b46824c6</guid></item><item><title>High chance of tropical cyclone forming off WA's Kimberley coast next week, BOM says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/potential-cyclone-forming-off-kimberley-coast-bom/106236930</link><description>A tropical cyclone is highly likely to form off Western Australia's far north coast next week, with the Bureau of Meteorology closely monitoring conditions between the Kimberley and Northern Territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d614f61a1749b94bb9c44875f55a6ce0</guid></item><item><title>Can a Nobel Peace Prize be revoked, refused or given away?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/nobel-peace-prize-cannot-be-revoked-or-transferred/106236160</link><description>While it can be gifted, refused or displayed, the Nobel Peace Prize itself — once awarded — belongs to its original recipient forever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ff027ea6ca739809b26fd87a7103b85</guid></item><item><title>Queenaland Maroons captain Ali Brigginshaw calls time on Origin career to focus on Brisbane Broncos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/ali-brigginshaw-retires-state-of-origin-brisbane-broncos/106238298</link><description>Ali Brigginshaw announces she has played her last State of Origin game for Queensland as she looks to focus on one final NRLW season with Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e0933c27558f92c46db864e2a88c3a5</guid></item><item><title>Amy Bowden's mother calls for SA to introduce penalties for not calling emergency services</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/amy-bowden-mother-wants-penalties-failing-to-call-triple-zero/106238080</link><description>The mother of a woman who died of "mixed drug toxicity" is pushing for South Australia to implement penalties for those who do not call emergency services in a medical emergency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">921aea86a1019a6938f01a195a9cfbec</guid></item><item><title>Missing man's body found at Darwin's East Point after large-scale search</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/body-of-missing-man-found-east-point-reserve/106238420</link><description>NT police say they have recovered the body of a missing 44-year-old man, following a large-scale search-and-rescue operation in a Darwin reserve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15a9ba183cfd2b74b609bc32fc4ccb52</guid></item><item><title>No inquest to be held into deaths of workers killed by concrete slab at Eagle Farm racecourse in 2016</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/no-inquest-eagle-farm-racecourse-deaths-2016/106237948</link><description>The family of the two men killed when a wall crushed them at the racecourse are disappointed there will be no inquiry into the events of the "terrible day".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8daafc46c699b59e676c943f4f13156</guid></item><item><title>Jim Chalmers defends 'professional' Fed boss Jerome Powell in face of Trump attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/jim-chalmers-defends-federal-boss-jerome-powell-as-trump-attacks/106238258</link><description>Treasurer Jim Chalmers defends US central bank boss Jerome Powell as professional and diligent after the Trump administration launched a criminal investigation into the Federal Reserve chair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bb45703942b5dd53badf54783cd96ea</guid></item><item><title>Ruling that left NSW parliament powerless to force witnesses to front inquiries to be challenged</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/nsw-mps-back-challenge-ruling-forcing-witnesses-front-inquiries/106238374</link><description>In December, the president of the legislative council said he would not seek to overturn a finding that laws allowing no-shows to be arrested were invalid, but this week he reversed course.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c7b64009fa2966cb291c0470cff8084</guid></item><item><title>Perth man accused of assaulting Labor figure Tim Picton faces charges over separate alleged attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/tim-picton-alleged-attacker-accused-of-separate-assault-/106184014</link><description>The man accused of assaulting former Labor strategist Tim Picton allegedly knocked another man unconscious two days prior.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31fb9468e7cb51c7e01b3c34f6733c8d</guid></item><item><title>How climate change is making extreme rainfall events like the Great Ocean Road flooding more frequent and intense</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/victoria-floods-climate-change-and-extreme-rainfall/106237516</link><description>When it comes to extreme rainfall, it is hard for climate scientists to say what's natural and what's caused by climate change, but they do know the most extreme events are dropping more rain, more often. This is why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fd2e0d2674eeb2b04eb9157146b56cd</guid></item><item><title>Authorities say Heidelberg sinkhole 'preventable' as works resume on North-East Link tunnel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/authorities-say-heidelberg-sinkhole-preventable-north-east-link/106237930</link><description>The state's road building authority says a planned test should have been aborted given the circumstances, as tunnelling recommences for the North-East Link tunnel project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ff47fabe3f2aa39e48b87d6271ddd0c</guid></item><item><title>Former South Korean president Yoon Suk Yeol sentenced over martial law declaration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/former-south-korean-president-yoon-suk-yeol-sentenced/106229834</link><description>Former South Korean president Yoon Suk Yeol is sentenced to five years in jail over crimes relating to his failed attempt at imposing martial law in the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b60d20cf774eb44beae3719e8d9da91b</guid></item><item><title>Huge European wasp nest found in Albany</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/huge-european-wasp-nest-found-in-albany/106238542</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">973dd9926c8227d4fc3ae503fedffbf5</guid></item><item><title>Huge 40-litre European wasp nest found in Albany suburb</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/european-wasps-found-in-wa/106237180</link><description>An enormous 40-litre nest of European wasps is discovered on the south coast of WA — the last frontier for the invasive species in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ccd67dc177b55a7ae19daf37a86da6c</guid></item><item><title>Police make 15 arrests and seize 12 firearms during investigations into Hobart shootings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/tas-police-arrest-15-during-investigations-into-recent-shootings/106238518</link><description>Tasmania Police says it received "valuable information" from the public in relation to recent shootings in Gagebrook and Bridgewater.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1829e1ef3c1953162eb6c7f4760e942</guid></item><item><title>Indonesian fishing boat intercepted off Queensland coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/indonesian-fishing-boat-intercepted/106238458</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d7650aa621b25c8610b3f7e9345b154</guid></item><item><title>ABF intercepts foreign fishing vessel seen near Cape York Peninsula</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/abf-intercepts-foreign-fishing-vessel-queensland/106238252</link><description>Locals on Queensland's far north tip have shared their account after seeing an Indonesian fishing boat within a stone's throw of the mainland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0622cf43fca5117beadab3891a71300</guid></item><item><title>Construction worker 'seriously injured' by falling excavator bucket at Darwin Civic Centre development site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/darwin-construction-worker-injured-falling-excavator-bucket/106237966</link><description>A Darwin construction worker has been "seriously injured" after an excavator bucket fell and hit him, with paramedics transporting the man to hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4779c5e3f505d0904044a761f18cb4e</guid></item></channel></rss>