<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 19:47:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka defends 'Battle of the Sexes' exhibition, wants to play Nick Kyrgios again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/i-need-revenge-sabalenka-targets-kyrgios-rematch/106193082</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka does not want her "Battle of the Sexes" clash with Nick Kyrgios to be the last and insists exhibitions have a vital role to play in tennis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edeffac013109e9ec2af9346d1b39ff6</guid></item><item><title>WA police searching for snorkeller missing off Ledge Point Beach, north of Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/police-searching-for-snorkeller-missing-off-ledge-point/106193204</link><description>Authorities step up their search for a 32-year-old snorkeller missing since yesterday afternoon in the ocean off Ledge Point Beach, north of Perth, after he disappeared while diving for crayfish.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">375f7873595de23bb39c9b6238003bbd</guid></item><item><title>Nation's largest employer bodies throw support behind royal commission into Bondi Beach terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/business-leaders-call-for-bondi-attack-royal-commission/106193032</link><description>Former Reserve Bank governors and CEOs are among more than 130 business leaders and prominent Australians calling for a Commonwealth royal commission in the wake of the Bondi Beach terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54c0c03c5a894dd1b680cb4a824ce524</guid></item><item><title>Russia says 20 killed in Ukrainian strike in occupied Kherson region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/russia-says-ukrainian-strike-kills-20-in-occupied-region/106193226</link><description>It comes as Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy says Russia is bringing the conflict "into the new year" with a barrage of drone strikes on the country's energy infrastructure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c228ff2ae4409e3f470e601765b251e</guid></item><item><title>Sydney and Melbourne property markets go backwards as national values hit speed bump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/national-house-price-hit-speed-bump-property-market/106185196</link><description>The red-hot Australian housing market is showing the first signs of easing since interest rates started rising in May 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecc800966e5f0b96cd673ff8c7a5685f</guid></item><item><title>Walking with Moai: Unlocking the mysteries of Easter Island stone statues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/rapa-nui-easter-island-moai-creation-and-movement-explained/106077706</link><description>A study using 11,600 aerial drone photos to map a mountainous quarry in 3D reveals more about how the island's famed stone sentinels were created and moved to their final resting places.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b3f8cc1b4e5b43b191888dd05803527</guid></item><item><title>Focus apps claim to improve your productivity. Do they actually work?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/focus-apps-productivity-distraction-smartphone-addiction-timer/106191902</link><description>To understand whether these apps are worth our while, we first need to consider why staying focused is so difficult in the first place.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecc1c656e8f350a1cec6644b16ddaac9</guid></item><item><title>Two MPs, two legal cases and one region left bewildered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/south-east-politicians-in-custody-analysis/106189724</link><description>The lower house of South Australia's parliament has two representatives from the Limestone Coast. Both are now in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9227dd4c4472299937ecffe98493570d</guid></item><item><title>South Australian emergency services kept busy as hot weather causes trees to drop limbs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/hot-weather-causes-trees-to-fall-and-drop-limbs/106187484</link><description>Hot weather has caused stressed trees to drop limbs, damaging property across South Australia and injuring one person so far this summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a75a80b197494567c0c21be1ccf5c757</guid></item><item><title>Major retrospective of ceramic artist Pippin Drysdale opens in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/retrospective-ceramic-artist-pippin-drysdale-agwa/106158010</link><description>The first retrospective of the ceramic artist's work has gone on show in Perth at the state gallery, telling the story of an extraordinary career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cf75ba5ea1935e46c0fbdce0703cf83</guid></item><item><title>Artist Piiij Goodrem used honest self-portraits and therapy to heal from childhood trauma</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/piiij-art-therapy-childhood-trauma/106096230</link><description>The process of creating detailed self-portraits, inspired by tropical landscapes, helped Piiij Goodrem deal with past trauma and addiction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">672bcb420593ffd676f81f31cb65462e</guid></item><item><title>Could modular and prefabricated homes be the key to solving the ACT's housing crisis?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/are-modular-homes-the-key-to-solving-the-acts-housing-crisis/106170130</link><description>Fast to build, eco-friendly and affordable: modular and pre-fabricated homes have been touted as a possible solution to Australia's housing crisis, but manufacturers and suppliers say changes are needed to reduce costs and meet demand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fd79171175902a5b972cccae88eb9af</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja takes aim at 'racial stereotypes' during retirement announcement ahead of fifth Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/usman-khawaja-to-retire-after-scg-ashes-test/106193812</link><description>Australia batter Usman Khawaja takes aim at his critics one last time as he announces his retirement from international cricket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dad1fab02c02e3fc877030f0aa828415</guid></item><item><title>Unique whale behaviour attracts intrigued visitors to regional Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/unique-whale-behaviour-attracts-intrigued-visitors/106135932</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dcec1c05f8131299fa3512b1c166ebc</guid></item><item><title>Unique 'mugging' behaviour attracts intrigued whale watchers to Queensland hotspot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/humpback-whales-mugging-hervey-bay-qld/106126770</link><description>People normally try to avoid getting mugged, but when it comes to being mugged by humpback whales, sightseers are travelling to Queensland's whale-watching capital to witness this special event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3282eaec233651a17432b7f9aa8ca9f0</guid></item><item><title>As Zohran Mamdani becomes New York's mayor, what are his chances of success?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/zohran-mamdani-inaugurated-as-new-york-mayor/106193766</link><description>New York's new mayor, Zohran Mamdani, has vowed not to water down his ambitious agenda during an impassioned inauguration address outside City Hall. But is his vision achievable?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67da1892dc576e4bb3743a4a18ac7b7d</guid></item><item><title>Zohran Mamdani vows to protect people of NYC at swearing-in ceremony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/zohran-mamdani-vows-to-protect-people-of-nyc/106193942</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9378dbf342cbb415bc3f0a88afebf5f</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja did it all his own way and retires a modern day Australian cricket great</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/usman-khawaja-retirement-cricket-career-legacy-analysis/106092620</link><description>Before his debut in 2011, Australia had never seen a cricketer like Usman Khawaja and, thanks to his work on and off the field, he'll be followed by plenty more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c9a76af7db0042009b315a2619a074c</guid></item><item><title>Tennant Creek mother who died in police watch house described as well-respected and bubbly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/nt-tennant-creek-death-in-custody-aboriginal-mother-autopsy/106184290</link><description>A remote outback town is searching for answers about why a “respectful, friendly and bubbly” Aboriginal mother died in the police watch house, more than 24 hours after her Christmas Day arrest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5738a60bc1f6caebad8e443f99a46a4c</guid></item><item><title>Lachie Neale steps down as Brisbane Lions co-captain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/qld-lachie-neale-steps-down-as-brisbane-lions-co-captain/106194176</link><description>The club said the 32-year-old had made the decision following a "challenging personal period".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">786a557007fbe0bc14c28e09b78783eb</guid></item><item><title>China's beef tariffs aren't personal as economy slows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/china-beef-import-tariffs-australian-trade-industry-economy/106192982</link><description>Beijing's new measures are aimed at trying to rein in an Australian surge and manage local growth, rather than a direct target on Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0adbd0ff03eaa4f3b1b25c350d5abca4</guid></item><item><title>Research ties China's smog clean-up to hotter and drier conditions in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/china-smog-cleanup-affects-global-warming-australian-rain-heat/106177394</link><description>As China caps off a historic clean-up of its smog and air pollution, the clearer air is helping temperatures rise to new records. Now, researchers are linking that change to hotter and drier conditions in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a199564d4f1ce691f7476ce33ac37099</guid></item><item><title>Alleged bikie granted bail after 'calculated hit' inside Queanbeyan hair salon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/bikie-stabbing-queanbeyan-hairdresser-granted-bail/106194238</link><description>In just four minutes, two men were stabbed in the chest and customers inside the Queanbeyan hair salon were left shaken.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b647deea177f7adfd50480c79377331</guid></item><item><title>Venus Williams to become oldest ever Australian Open participant after receiving wildcard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/tennis-venus-williams-oldest-australian-open-player-wildcard/106194896</link><description>Venus Williams will play in the main draw of the Australian Open for the first time since 2021, 28 years after she first graced Melbourne Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">383c70fac8ec31cd0081f57a6d081c9d</guid></item><item><title>Man faces court after alleged crime spree, police pursuit in Latrobe Valley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/man-faces-court-after-alleged-crime-spree-in-latrobe-valley/106194974</link><description>A 34-year-old man has been remanded in custody after allegedly going on a multi-day crime spree across Victoria's south-east involving carjackings, burglaries and a police pursuit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1399ad0101654482f076800cadeee6f9</guid></item><item><title>Man who kidnapped boy from Moora home given eight-year prison sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/man-who-kidnapped-boy-from-moora-home-jailed-for-eight-years/106194254</link><description>A man who abducted a boy from his bed in regional WA after sniffing butane and having delusions about aliens is sentenced to eight years in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d838d36694a1ba7bcb5f596722cc3e5</guid></item><item><title>Boddington family watches heritage cottage filled with antiques go up in flames on Christmas Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/boddington-fire-heritage-family-house-burnt-christmas-day/106185508</link><description>Two heritage homes and thousands of hectares of land were lost in a Christmas Day bushfire in Boddington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfc414b6e60e3ef86dd407eb61ea1511</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump gave a wide-ranging interview about his health. Here's what we learned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/donald-trumps-health-key-points-from-wsj-interview/106194812</link><description>US President Donald Trump says he regrets undergoing advanced imagery on his heart and abdomen because of the "ammunition" it handed his critics, but has once more defended his "perfect" health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45795f8f18432352bfd8576c1750a81f</guid></item><item><title>Todd Murphy in line for Ashes return as SCG curator allays fears over pitch's green exterior</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/todd-murphy-sydney-comeback-green-pitch-concerns-scg/106194954</link><description>Todd Murphy could play his first Test match on Australian soil as the curator of the SCG allays fears over the pitch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6afb840ee8e9c9cf26094b2c13f3912c</guid></item><item><title>Maya Joint hit with illness ahead of Australia's United Cup opener against Norway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/tennis-maya-joint-illness-australia-united-cup-vs-norway/106195416</link><description>Australia's teen sensation is forced to lay low, with team captain Lleyton Hewitt hoping it is just a 24-hour thing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">767bcd062b8c2aa011eed6fd7e4382d3</guid></item><item><title>Mother wallaby death sparks animal cruelty investigation in far north Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/wallaby-death-leads-to-animal-cruelty-complaints/106185200</link><description>Wildlife carers have lodged formal complaints with police and environment officials after stumbling across a scene involving a dead mother wallaby tied to a signpost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c90d255c025ebf1e2f29e236fa840a3</guid></item><item><title>China-Taiwan-US triangle held together by assumptions and one dangerous lie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/taiwan-china-united-states-military-triangle-lies/106189394</link><description>The US has no intention of abandoning Taiwan. But it also has no intention of binding itself to an automatic war commitment on a timeline it does not control.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec0387ed2f1a234d6444e54f05dd6c27</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government can expect economic and political pressure in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/2026-labor-government-albanese-inflation-housing-chalmers/106156690</link><description>What are you watching in Australian politics in 2026? That's the question we put to the ABC's political journalists and columnists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1f99661621e9d02561489076f9ba6e3</guid></item><item><title>Are reading goals helpful or performative? How to read more in the new year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/how-to-read-more-in-the-new-year/105977668</link><description>While some people might find goal setting motivating — such as reading X number of books each year or pages each day — there is a risk of turning what is supposed to be a pleasurable activity into a chore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10a698c1ed7e84a78515524c2f5bf576</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, January 3: Steve Waugh secures a last-ball century to complete his perfect day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/today-in-history-steve-waughs-last-ball-century-scg-ashes/106192024</link><description>With one ball remaining on day two of the fifth Ashes Test in 2003, Steve Waugh stared down a century and his own cricketing mortality before securing one of the most famous centuries of his storied career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05d0aba10e39cfec8283ebaa6d085d05</guid></item><item><title>World-first as Australian donates organs after self-administering assisted dying medication</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/australian-donates-organs-after-self-administering-vad/106086648</link><description>An Australian woman is believed to have become the first person in the world to donate organs after self-administering oral voluntary assisted dying medication.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">771245fd34fb60755bbd5d86c319d888</guid></item><item><title>Red and yellow flags can be dangerously confusing. Is it time to change them?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/red-yellow-flags-drowning-rescue-lifeguards-rip/106195120</link><description>Every summer, millions of Australians head to the beach and every year thousands are rescued by lifeguards or surf life savers, and even surfers or other bystanders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">474042795045b3c3e3237f3a864461e6</guid></item><item><title>Anastasia Golubeva set for 2026 Winter Olympics debut with Australia after citizenship change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/citizenship-change-keeps-figure-skaters-olympic-dream-alive/106194338</link><description>Figure skater Anastasia Golubeva becomes an Australian citizen, just six weeks out from the Milano-Cortina Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d0afd2ba4b8d8ddf86d2b3237f2bf1</guid></item><item><title>The moon will loom extra large tonight — but it's not a supermoon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/how-to-see-wolf-moon-2026/106194794</link><description>Stargazers will be treated with a supersized wolf moon for the first weekend of the year. Here's what to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12bba61f673a8ba85ac4295e8b36f0f0</guid></item><item><title>The parts of Myanmar the military junta doesn't want you to see</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/inside-myanmar-during-military-junta-sham-election-voting/106190364</link><description>Myanmar's military is holding its first elections since overthrowing a democratically elected government in 2021. But as it aims to portray a sense of normality, signs of the junta's menacing presence are everywhere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">948d3c6bb8238924022179a27bbdcb98</guid></item><item><title>Flooded outback Queensland graziers to get $2m government package for fodder drops</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/outback-queensland-flood-funding-announced-graziers/106194300</link><description>Floodwaters remain in outback Queensland as graziers start to tally up livestock losses. Major flooding is possible in the north-west, with king tides forecast on the east coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6be062a8ba3d66a5ef9d894cfa376139</guid></item><item><title>FBI says it thwarted ISIS-inspired New Year's Eve attack in North Carolina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/fbi-foils-isis-inspired-plot-north-carolina/106196040</link><description>The US Attorney for the Western District of North Carolina claims the 18-year-old suspect had planned to attack a grocery store and fast food restaurant in his hometown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94007e2a50b07dbc56d071e34aaf0d9f</guid></item><item><title>Mid North Coast brumby program rehomes 160 wild horses across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/brumby-rehoming-program-gives-wild-horses-second-chance/106085286</link><description>About a third of the brumby population on the NSW Mid North Coast has been rehomed through a program designed to give wild horses a second chance as pets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ece383d3daeacd448a3de2d057214f0</guid></item><item><title>Naomi Osaka loses United Cup match to Maria Sakkari ahead of Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/united-cup-naomi-osaka-maria-sakkari-australian-open/106196062</link><description>Just over two weeks from the season-opening major, former world number one Naomi Osaka reveals she is not at full health after contracting a viral illness over the Christmas period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">512763bd96b8fdd1d3013fa3d2190ff2</guid></item><item><title>Tesla loses title of bestselling EV company to BYD as sales drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/tesla-loses-title-bestselling-ev-to-byd/106196066</link><description>Tesla sales have declined for the second consecutive year, with Chinese rival BYD surpassing it as the world's largest electric vehicle maker.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c10f01312156bde84a15adaabb610cff</guid></item><item><title>Police hunt for offenders after shooting in Melbourne's inner north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/fitzroy-shooting-police-crime/106196082</link><description>Police are searching for offenders, who are believed to have driven past in a silver SUV and fired shots at a young man, before fleeing the scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">558108aa6fbd3604a2fedf660c062bb4</guid></item><item><title>Barbecue explosion prompts safety warning after Qld beautician's burns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/mums-bbq-warning-after-explosion-on-christmas-eve/106195412</link><description>Rachel Dear has a serious warning for anyone using a gas barbecue after she suffered significant face and body burns while cooking on Christmas Eve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb1ca2b13267460bbd659d5184771082</guid></item><item><title>Coffee pods generate thousands of tonnes of waste in Australia. Here's what is being done about it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/qld-australia-coffee-pod-waste-upcycled-schemes-recycling/106149492</link><description>Between 10 and 20 per cent of the 3 million coffee pods Australians consume daily are actually recycled. Here's what's being done to change that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e00615d7dff72de8460ca30c668e1baa</guid></item><item><title>Photographs of Men in Love exhibition reveals public glimpses of forbidden love</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/photographs-of-men-in-love-exhibition-same-sex-couples-canberra/106164254</link><description>What started as a chance discovery of an old photo at a Dallas antique store has spawned a collection of more than 4,000 images of male couples, more than 100 of which are now on display in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">342bd9008f4a6040aef96519ae23b8f6</guid></item><item><title>Helen Burnet has defected from the Greens but voters may still be wondering exactly why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/helen-burnet-quits-greens-questions-remain-over-why/106195524</link><description>Helen Burnet fronted the cameras on Friday to announce she was quitting the party she's been a member of for more than 20 years, but it's still not clear exactly why she's made the move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">045c12b602cf0bd78e6fdcfc284e48f1</guid></item><item><title>WA's Pilbara region shares a human and shorebird FIFO population</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/migratory-shorebirds-land-in-the-pilbara-for-summer/106039306</link><description>Dozens of shorebird species flock to northern WA for summer during their global migration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ff35fe466eef14512e81d2afaf6106e</guid></item><item><title>Middle Percy Island is a 'haven' for sailors, displaying scores of memorabilia from bygone days</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/percy-island-attracts-yachties-from-across-world/105385704</link><description>Middle Percy Island is a rare gem where boaties can come ashore and wander through thousands of mementos left by travellers from across the globe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1746a1ce94f0eacb5cef7b4153c7f3b5</guid></item><item><title>Former Darwin councillor's ex-partner speaks out after guilty domestic violence verdict</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/ex-partner-darwin-councillor-speaks-out-after-guilty-dv-verdict/106170776</link><description>Former Darwin councillor Paul Arnold was found guilty of domestic violence after a years-long court battle, with his ex-partner refusing to be scared into silence. She said the case was "stressful and deeply humiliating", but facing her abuser had been empowering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4c243120a1fef30a2f8354e4ef212a0</guid></item><item><title>Storm chaser captures rare red sprites across Kimberley sky</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/red-sprites-storm-chaser-kimberley-sky/106192812</link><description>A storm chaser says he "screamed" when he captured an elusive natural phenomenon, known as red sprites, on video.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f1f2816c594f555f58c60bc969eeff4</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police riot squad to carry long-arm firearms at Sydney Ashes series following Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/nsw-police-riot-squad-carry-long-arm-firearms-sydney-ashes-/106196098</link><description>Officers will carry long-arm firearms as part of a bolstered police presence at the Ashes series in Sydney in the wake of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6877b2907f2f985901c51db094f90f7d</guid></item><item><title>Premium beef producers expect to be the main casualty of China's new 55 per cent tariff</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/wagyu-angus-casualty-of-china-tariffs-on-australian-beef/106194112</link><description>Australian cattle farmers producing wagyu and Angus beef are likely to be among the hardest hit by China's 55 per cent tariff on exports exceeding a 205,000-tonne quota.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">228dfb545460ba76f36dbd3ab6992df6</guid></item><item><title>Two separate echidna puggles unearthed during home renovations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/two-separate-echidna-puggles-unearthed-during-home-renovations/106159590</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bee84e046009ae0bde6da898d0d96438</guid></item><item><title>Wildlife carers warn people to watch out for puggle burrows this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/watch-out-for-puggle-burrows/106123746</link><description>With female echidnas seemingly creating burrows in random places at this time of the year, wildlife carers warn to keep an eye out for what might be disturbed while doing holiday work on your property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b008ff0393e48ce7d75c57dbd80231e6</guid></item><item><title>Local government inspector Tony Brown granted new powers to probe WA councils and 'improve accountability'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/wa-perth-local-government-inspector-powers/106172240</link><description>The new role of Western Australia local government inspector Tony Brown includes the ability to send in monitors — as well as legal and financial experts — to stamp out any early signs of trouble.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">348a4d2e5cc41b88eb40686a673c393e</guid></item><item><title>Driver arrested for allegedly speeding at 209km/h on Southern Expressway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/p-plater-arrested-for-alleged-street-racing-at-209kmh/106196234</link><description>Police say two 19-year-old drivers will face court for street racing along Adelaide's Southern Expressway, with one of the P-platers allegedly detected speeding at 209km/h.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b4af35eb1673cc59d51314fb6ffcc48</guid></item><item><title>Australia coy about Cameron Green's role in final Ashes Test against England at SCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/fifth-ashes-test-australia-england-steve-smith-cameron-green/106196310</link><description>Steve Smith launches an impassioned defence of the out-of-form Cameron Green, but cannot guarantee the all-rounder's place in Australia's XI for the final Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44e672e99bdcb5e120088bfc68bef9ed</guid></item><item><title>Hunt for escaped red-whiskered bulbul that has SA's fruitgrowers worried</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/authorities-hunting-escaped-invasive-bird-threatening-fruit-crop/106192434</link><description>The sighting of a single red-whiskered bulbul in the wild might not seem like a big deal, but this invasive pest could put crops and the environment at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a966eb6406a57993be641fd862019d7</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with hit-and-run death of woman on Darwin's Bagot Road, one week after incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/nt-police-charge-man-hit-and-run-death-indigenous-woman-darwin/106196270</link><description>Police arrest a 61-year-old man after a seven-day investigation involving CCTV, crime scene analysis, forensic examination and witness enquiries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d1b49b76fa056ebc89a2d587c85f317</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan court sentences journalists to life in prison over links to 2023 protests after Imran Khan's arrest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/pakistan-court-sentences-journalists-to-life/106196366</link><description>Eight journalists and social media commentators are sentenced to life imprisonment in Pakistan after being convicted of terrorism-related offences linked to online activity in support of jailed former prime minister Imran Khan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c33f5501c8a0952d3b0934e4af7ac2d</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police investigating woman's death at Goulburn home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/police-investigating-womans-death-in-goulburn/106196478</link><description>NSW Police launch an investigation after an unidentified woman was found dead in a home in Goulburn on Saturday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5adbd3ecf7e382f730e10a80618394a7</guid></item><item><title>Fight breaks out after crash on Monash Freeway in Melbourne's south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/monash-freeway-crash-fight-narre-warren-police/106196610</link><description>Police are investigating an altercation potentially involving edged weapons after a collision on the Monash Freeway in Melbourne's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9465fcb7ffb6741e7ff20ab5071d8f6a</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios prepared to go through Australian Open qualifying if wildcard spot eludes him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/kyrgios-prepared-to-go-through-aus-open-qualifying/106196636</link><description>Nick Kyrgios describes himself as a "chaotic mess, but an entertainer" as he prepares to return in Brisbane and awaits a call on his Australian Open status.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2122f15620e50b8bead13b9bfd9b350</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says US forces have 'captured' Venezuelan leader Nicolas Maduro — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/venezuela-explosions-low-flying-aircraft/106196656</link><description>US President Donald Trump says the US has "captured" Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro, who earlier declared a national emergency and hit out at US "military aggression" after attacks in the capital, Caracas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a64d55167d8d483d5fa33b5e38a803f</guid></item><item><title>Helicopters stream into Caracas, the Venezuelan capital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/helicopters-stream-into-caracas-the-venezuelan-capital-/106196710</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0a863f422aa0c234c6547efcfbcd801</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan residents capture successive explosions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/venezuela-residents-capture-successive-explosions/106196778</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">609617ce9ba4e56884382b45c8d1d20c</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's attack on Venezuela and 'capture' of Nicolás Maduro has been months in the making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-03/united-states-captures-nicolas-maduro-explainer/106196798</link><description>While Mr Maduro remained publicly defiant in the face of US pressure to step down, in private he was taking measures to dodge a potential US strike, and even reportedly negotiating with American officials over a possible managed exit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b8aaea830abe67d8718721c5c3db6e3</guid></item><item><title>Nicolás Maduro was 'captured' by the US military. This is who he is</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/who-is-nicolas-maduro-explained/106196820</link><description>The 63-year-old Venezuelan president was "captured" in a "large-scale strike". Here is what is known about the man set to stand trial on criminal charges in the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cc9c5f7831714d7c7d694a482d152e2</guid></item><item><title>Trump says US 'will run' Venezuela as Maduro arrives in New York after capture during raid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/venezuela-trump-says-maduro-on-way-to-new-york/106197080</link><description>Deposed Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro is now in New York after he was captured in an early-morning US raid on the nation. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be4394dd4dad737718f96cd59d5c48e4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says US will run Venezuela and control oil industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/donald-trump-says-us-will-run-venezuela-and-control-oil-industry/106197224</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2538a57bf8235e7b280ff1c3380375d2</guid></item><item><title>For its 250th birthday, America is being America</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/on-its-250th-birthday-america-is-being-america/106193418</link><description>It is entirely fitting that the US is so splintered on its semiquincentennial. Division, for the lion's share of its history, has been its default.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be15980d4e27f638fbdc28e784e3d4d9</guid></item><item><title>Butter, margarine or nut spreads. Which is best for your home?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/butter-margarine-nut-spreads-which-is-best/106010740</link><description>You might have a personal preference for which spread you use at home, but experts say there are health considerations for which one you use.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffd9f40f3868b38eeed0e32478084049</guid></item><item><title>Australian exporters still grappling with 'the wild west' eight months after 'liberation day'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/australian-brands-still-dealing-with-trump-tariffs-more-in-2026/106194486</link><description>From de minimis to beef tariffs, Aussie exporters are preparing for another "wild" year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9246f57d955ff69454a3be3212a7d4f7</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan's first woman to summit K2 sparks new wave of female climbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/pakistan-women-hikers-summit-k2-sparks-new-wave-female-climbers/106032678</link><description>Pakistani women are hiking some of the world's tallest mountains and glacier trails, claiming a space that has long been out of reach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f79cc4bf811ab7235c60a6f796067699</guid></item><item><title>Blak romance surges as First Nations authors rewrite love stories with 'choc-lit'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/blak-romance-choc-lit-magabala-first-nations-love-stories/106164166</link><description>An anthology of love stories written by First Nations people is in the works with stories of blak love, joy, and connection capitalising on the fastest growing literary genre in the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df9b7659d4d072a526b05734c5f9c4cb</guid></item><item><title>Man in Bangladesh describes aftermath of house being burnt down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/man-in-bangladesh-describes-aftermath/106194158</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0621a32111114172756b4f63a259c44a</guid></item><item><title>Bangladeshi Hindus on edge as Islamic extremists target minority community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/bangladeshi-hindu-minority-fearful-after-lynching-of-worker/106192790</link><description>Four Hindu men have been killed in Muslim-majority Bangladesh in just over two weeks, and several houses have been burned, leaving the minority community traumatised and fearing for their lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1db19eebdb0b3d81ec5cfe1cdfb579f</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says US will run Venezuela for now after Nicolás Maduro's capture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/venezuelan-president-nicolas-maduro-captured-by-us/106197206</link><description>The US will temporarily run Venezuela after American forces captured the country's president and first lady in an extraordinary military strike, US President Donald Trump says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6071f5efeb5d6d77093a6c135f8f37a4</guid></item><item><title>Tourists stranded, dozens of roads closed as rain continues in flooded outback Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/tourists-stranded-dozens-of-roads-closed-by-queensland-flooding/106196556</link><description>Tourists are stranded in towns dotted across north-west Queensland as rain continues to keep major rivers in flood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4063b5ce47cbef605b6e0562bf95ada7</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur unfazed by United Cup loss to Casper Ruud in Australian Open build-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/united-cup-tennis-alex-de-minaur-casper-ruud-australian-open/106197302</link><description>Alex de Minaur is not concerned about his Australian Open preparations, believing he can "flip that switch" after recording his first career defeat to Casper Ruud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0897fbd111d1c554413b28e57ba54b5b</guid></item><item><title>Inside the 'dark, deadly' US mission to capture Nicolás Maduro at his compound in Caracas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/inside-the-dark-deadly-us-mission-to-arrest-maduro-and-wife/106197254</link><description>Fresh details about the operation to detain Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro and his wife on Saturday have been revealed, and even Donald Trump's top military advisor has described the mission as "audacious".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5822eac0bef3ecf460079c5a85ca7948</guid></item><item><title>Man who failed to remove backyard cheese facility told to pay $120,000</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/contempt-of-court-finding-over-backyard-cheesemaking-facility/106189800</link><description>An Adelaide retiree who continually ignored orders to remove an unauthorised backyard cheesemaking facility from his suburban home is ordered to pay more than $120,000 in costs, after being found guilty of contempt of court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89d32b91d3f2e7ca208840f2bd1320dc</guid></item><item><title>Calls for universal vision screening tests for all SA preschool children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/calls-for-universal-preschool-vision-testing-in-sa/106190758</link><description>A group of researchers is calling on the South Australian government to implement a universal vision screening program for all children attending preschools or day care centres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44abe98801d7c95d0cc2201b06217444</guid></item><item><title>Tumbarumba Rodeo celebrates 80 years of bulls, broncos, thrills and spills</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/tumbaumba-rodeo-turns-80/106194110</link><description>As the Tumbarumba Rodeo celebrates its 80th year, the Rial family have held on for the longest ride of them all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b960525b255ab23d980624f3a76c4aeb</guid></item><item><title>How Louis Braille’s musical notation system remains relevant 200 years after its invention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/louis-braille-music-200/106176564</link><description>In the 1820s, Louis Braille devised a raised-dot system of letters, numbers and musical notation. 200 years later, it’s still opening the music world for blind musicians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e97e8f94552d14784e346f2986eed9e1</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested at Sydney airport after alleged sexual assault in Melbourne laneway on New Year's Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/sexual-assault-investigation-melbourne-coors-lane-new-years-day/106197360</link><description>A 22-year-old French man has been arrested at Sydney International Airport following an alleged sexual assault in Melbourne's CBD in the early hours of New Year's Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1e42251cf2ef235b74a4ea4c82ac818</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane man aiming to be fastest person from sea level to Mount Everest summit in memory of late mother</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/world-record-mental-health-oliver-foran-everest/106166224</link><description>Oliver Foran struggled with his mental health after losing his mother to cancer. Now, he is training to set a world record while raising money and awareness for youth mental health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68a58cbf6598c7f23302ee42fb7f336e</guid></item><item><title>Scientists, landowners working on Tasmania's Bruny Island to help forty-spotted pardalote species</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/forty-spotted-pardalote-bruny-island-endangered-species/106176110</link><description>Donning a helmet and a well-equipped harness, Dr Fernanda Alves looks like she is set to take on an extreme sport. Instead, she is climbing trees to check nesting boxes for a tiny and very rare bird.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7065e03d105853f2e0eb6a85285754a5</guid></item><item><title>Former North Melbourne AFL player Phoenix Spicer dies aged 23</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/afl-former-north-melbourne-player-phoenix-spicer-dies/106197350</link><description>Phoenix Spicer, who played 12 AFL matches for North Melbourne, has died at the age of 23.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfa0dfdd5a10b7ce680fca27b175557a</guid></item><item><title>How artificial intelligence is being used across the ACT to provide vital services</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/how-act-government-is-using-ai-across-services/106137618</link><description>Artificial intelligence is a controversial subject, but as the debate rages it is already being used by ACT government departments, doctors and the people running firefighting operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10d58a3640f58092e04e8f0b3594fff5</guid></item><item><title>Top End dams overflow as parks come to life in the wake of Cyclone Fina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/fogg-dam-darwin-river-cyclone-fina-monsoon/106194820</link><description>The Northern Territory's Top End has been transformed into a lush green paradise by a cyclone and a monsoon that have brought an unusually heavy start to the annual wet season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bbc1a06303d5df7cdf15ccf7111d910</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2026: Bad light halts England's charge as Harry Brook and Joe Root dominate spinless Aussie attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/live-updates-ashes-australia-vs-england-fifth-test-day-one/106197464</link><description>The top two men's Test batters in the world make hay against a spinless Australian attack, only to be stopped by the weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d9e95b3c067548eb7455d61911bd1a7</guid></item><item><title>Sports stars call for federal royal commission into antisemitism and Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/sport-stars-call-for-federal-royal-commission/106197406</link><description>Ian Thorpe, Jess Fox and Lleyton Hewitt are among more than 60 Australian sports stars joining public calls for a Commonwealth royal commission into the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfe61c6f50adb040dbfdacd8e9523102</guid></item><item><title>Captured Maduro touches down in New York</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/captured-maduro-touches-down-in-new-york-/106197506</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbdeb06a0ee170385f9595f1fdfb7e36</guid></item><item><title>Collector with 50 pinball machines in his shed hopes to create a playable museum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/western-australia-pinball-collector-greg-sharpe-bally-williams/106190702</link><description>This shed in Western Australia is filled wall-to-wall with collectable pinball machines, all in working order. Greg Sharp hopes to one day share it as a playable pinball museum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">551adce7b764201eb76b53d9fbddfb07</guid></item><item><title>People celebrate Maduro’s capture around the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/people-celebrate-maduro-s-capture-around-the-world-/106197528</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5e56aca1a7518d9b280843b572c2751</guid></item><item><title>Some world leaders view Venezuelan strikes with 'deep concern', others 'salute' US action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/how-world-leaders-reacted-to-venezuelan-strikes/106197592</link><description>The US mission to capture deposed Venezuelan president Nicolás Maduro and his wife prompts celebration and condemnation across the globe. Here's how key world leaders have reacted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">279fcf720691af2b125e7bc3ad5eb256</guid></item><item><title>US makes 'bold' grab for oil as financial markets brace for price change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/us-intervention-in-venezuela-impact-on-oil-prices-unclear/106197522</link><description>Oil futures do not trade until Monday, Australian time, and financial market participants are divided over whether there will be a spike or correction in the price of oil in Asian trade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cddf5973a667bf5403f659045cd625dd</guid></item><item><title>The Venezuela strike sets a new low for the world order — even by Donald Trump's standards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/venezuela-operation-us-blatant-disregard-international-law/106197628</link><description>Even in a world that has grown used to a cavalier attitude to international law from Donald Trump, the move stuns leaders across the globe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51723f26a2ed373c59c19ed134c851e4</guid></item><item><title>Death in custody investigation launched after fatal crash on SA rural highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/highway-fatal-crash-treated-as-death-in-custody/106197538</link><description>Police launch a death in custody investigation, after a 33-year-old man was killed in a crash in an allegedly stolen car that was road-spiked on South Australia's Eyre Highway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e7160a86849d3d52922b1ce5327b915</guid></item><item><title>Evonne Goolagong Cawley's life story immortalised in screen drama</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/evonne-goolagong-cawley-tennis-lila-mcguire/106121294</link><description>Lila McGuire on the pressure and joy of playing former world number one and winner of seven grand slam singles titles, tennis legend Evonne Goolagong Cawley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17b39dbac2a0c60bd0858768f09e02d7</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan diaspora divided over US capturing of leader Maduro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/venezuelan-diaspora-divided-over-us-capturing-of-leader-maduro/106197588</link><description>Venezuelan migrants across Latin America and other parts of the world cheered in the streets, supporting the US mission to capture Venezuela's deposed president, Nicolás Maduro.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bb59c27e88d19c330d4a4cf93d035c4</guid></item><item><title>Convoy believed to carry Maduro arrives at DEA complex</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/convoy-believed-to-carry-maduro-arrives-at-dea-complex/106197822</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbf90a15e8e69976d1581129272c1b9c</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Venezuelan diaspora gathers after US captures president Nicolás Maduro in military strike</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/venezuela-australian-reaction-after-us-military-strike-maduro/106197558</link><description>Australia's small but tight-knit community of Venezuelan-born residents is gathering to discuss the unfolding situation in their home country after the US captured Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af4bf140de0b9a9dd93ed13301415cd0</guid></item><item><title>Deposed Nicolás Maduro inside New York law enforcement offices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/deposed-nicol%C3%A1s-maduro-inside-new-york-law-enforcement-offices/106197952</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d502c57a26e57e60c600e9f5fb4a9de2</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelans race to stock up on essential goods after Maduro's capture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/venezuelans-race-to-stock-up-on-essential-goods/106198102</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e5500561dd2a6cb53683ff2abef77a4</guid></item><item><title>SCG pays tribute to Bondi heroes, weather frustrates and Australia goes spinless — quick hits from day one of fifth Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/ashes-fifth-test-at-scg-day-one-quick-hits/106197510</link><description>Australia opts not to pick a spinner for another Test, breaking a streak of 138 years at the SCG, which rises as one to honour the heroes of the Bondi terror attack. Here are the quick hits from the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb302c1928946d6230d618f585d1ea1b</guid></item><item><title>Weary Australia eyes Ashes finish line at the SCG as England senses opportunity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/ashes-fifth-test-day-one-weary-australia-eyes-ashes-finish-line/106197850</link><description>Only the rain could slow England's progress on day one in Sydney, as a weary Australia reflected its coach's claims the series really ended in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0673d5a9a75261e6fada5da482bd264</guid></item><item><title>Australian cricket great Damien Martyn awakes from induced coma after falling ill with meningitis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/australian-cricket-great-damien-martyn-awakes-from-coma/106198212</link><description>Former Australian Test batsman Damien Martyn is awake and talking after being in an induced coma for several days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c44eb726bb83ef6540bbd5a1ffa2f384</guid></item><item><title>Thanasi Kokkinakis tears up and Nick Kyrgios chills out as Special Ks return at Brisbane International</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/nick-kyrgios-thanasi-kokkinakis-special-ks/106198254</link><description>Thanasi Kokkinakis said he didn't think he'd be able to return to tennis after a 2025 blighted by injury. Instead he's made a winning return alongside doubles partner and all-round showman Nick Kyrgios.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7aef09a3f488ce63cc4a9cf1fddbcb21</guid></item><item><title>Maduro arrives at Manhattan court, Trump doubles down on oil plans for Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/venezuela-maduro-in-custody-blog-january-5/106198380</link><description>Deposed Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro and his wife have been transferred to a New York courthouse as Donald Trump doubles down on oil plans for Venezuela — as it happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dfd5b587b46b480d65b9556a0e4fc6b</guid></item><item><title>Death toll rises in Iran as anti-government protests spread</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/iran-protests-spread-death-toll-rises/106198320</link><description>At least 16 people have been killed in a week of demonstrations fuelled by the rising cost of living.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95d5d3870c71498c6f6b04fccea8017d</guid></item><item><title>Cookbook Club Naarm is bringing strangers together over food</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/cookbook-supper-club-community-events-cooking-books-chef-potluck/106092308</link><description>Each month, strangers and friends meet to share dishes from a chosen cookbook. But Cookbook Club Naarm is more than a foodie feast, it's a reminder of food's power to bring us together.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7003e991adab8bd16875eb0360f89db3</guid></item><item><title>Inflation, tariffs, EVs: What the ABC's business experts are watching in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/economy-markets-predictions-2026-business-experts/106156688</link><description>What are you watching in 2026 when it comes to the economy or markets? That's the question we put to the ABC's experts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8e64e8827c29ee9a51c9b365ad229e5</guid></item><item><title>Repeated brain injuries linked to memory changes in intimate partner violence survivors, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/brain-injury-concussion-strangulation-partner-violence-study/106159980</link><description>An Australian-first study finds evidence of previously undetected, long-term cognitive changes in women more than six months after they experienced repeated concussions and strangulation during intimate partner violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3515faea792fbbea3ef26d94212d5fbf</guid></item><item><title>Value of Australian dollar now dependent on interest rates, commodities prices and geopolitics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/australian-dollar-now-dependent-on-interest-rates-commodities/106186480</link><description>The value of Australia's currency could move significantly up or down depending on the direction of interest rates. But the global economic backdrop will also be crucial in determining its direction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7e2086e93d1eeda3b7369847e469d66</guid></item><item><title>Were the US actions in Venezuela legal under international law?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/were-the-us-actions-in-venezuela-legal-under-international-law/106198134</link><description>International law is created by all states, not just the powerful few. This makes international community reactions to breaches particularly important.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a0e863241ad26e5cd8c8ea505ef6198</guid></item><item><title>National donor conception register would prevent 'potential trauma', advocate says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/national-donor-conception-register-for-key-information-call/106188336</link><description>Hundreds of people have accessed South Australia's Donor Conception Register in its first year, lifting decades of secrecy surrounding anonymous donations — an outcome that has prompted calls from a leading advocate for similar moves at national level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ccef3ff92f6b64b2e7e9c03e5e15da5</guid></item><item><title>Satellite images show damage at Fuerte Tiuna, the site where Maduro was captured</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/satellite-images-fuerte-tiuna-strikes-maduro-capture-venezuela/106197796</link><description>Satellite imagery captures the scale of destruction from US strikes at the Fuerte Tiuna military base, where Venezuelan officials say president Nicolás Maduro was captured.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">617ba7feabcbca745af6da97695d90b2</guid></item><item><title>The benefits of intergenerational friendships in the workplace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/intergenerational-friendships-workplace-tiktok/106170442</link><description>Social media users are showing off their intergenerational work friendships, but experts say the benefits are substantial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b4f4d6761e56838f12af4f8d625b54e</guid></item><item><title>Nicolás Maduro's allies maintain power in Venezuela, rejecting US claims they will 'comply'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/nicolas-maduro-allies-take-power-in-venezuela/106198570</link><description>The Trump administration insists Venezuela's leaders will now comply with American demands after the extraordinary capture of president Nicolás Maduro — but his allies are resisting US pressure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83250884e03b7c92ee18975a7269611d</guid></item><item><title>Daria Kasatkina defeated at Brisbane International as Ajla Tomljanović reaches second round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/brisbane-international-tennis-daria-kasatkina-ajla-tomljanovic/106198664</link><description>Daria Kasatkina admits she held back tears and dealt with severe nerves during an agonising three-set loss at the Brisbane International.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a32d0120141242f52a751aac1eeffec</guid></item><item><title>Emergency departments ill-suited for mental health crises, advocates say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/patient-traumatising-hospital-care-act-crisis/106157462</link><description>A 24-year-old NSW border resident says dismissive treatment in hospitals, long waits for care and limited access to services have pushed her away from support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f1c951190641b270ccdeaceac77ed09</guid></item><item><title>First stock loss figures reported as Western River at Winton reaches major flood level</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/qld-wet-weather-richmond-winton-flood/106197638</link><description>As widespread flooding maintains its grip on north-west Queensland, thousands of livestock are reported missing or dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c62a51b2e3d40a513de6bd79879eb19a</guid></item><item><title>This sacred 'forbidden island' in Japan is World Heritage listed and completely off limits to women</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/okinoshima-island-world-heritage-listed-gender-ban/106017014</link><description>Boasting thousands of years of history and a World Heritage listing, Okinoshima is Japan's very own treasure island. It's also completely off limits to women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6008aa4cf4f81cb4dd85f39230b6299</guid></item><item><title>NT police data shows crime down in Alice Springs, locals worry it will be short-lived</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/alice-springs-crime-rates-down-long-term-solutions/106177896</link><description>After years of negative headlines, crime rates in Alice Springs are showing signs of turning a corner but some locals remain worried the change could be short-lived.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3d99161c25f0c4a1425171ad43ced0f</guid></item><item><title>Australia urged to back spinners after Todd Murphy's omission from fifth Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/ashes-scg-test-australia-critcises-for-leaving-out-spinner/106198718</link><description>Leg spinner Mitchell Swepson wants Australian cricket officials and curators to buck the growing trend of producing pitches that heavily favour seam bowlers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94e68ac134662be379513200ede43cac</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelans march in Caracas to oppose Maduro's capture.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/venezuelans-march-in-caracas-to-oppose-maduro-capture/106198748</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dd0da9fbce5906065ad8e4f58fa4553</guid></item><item><title>Motorcyclist killed in crash that forced closure of lanes on South Eastern Freeway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/motorbike-crash-at-crafers-west-on-south-eastern-freeway/106198698</link><description>A 25-year-old motorcyclist has died in a crash that forced the closure of city-bound lanes on Adelaide's South Eastern Freeway this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">590e21b6ca29b9a31bdbf77803c64112</guid></item><item><title>Rufous scrub-bird DNA project aims to safeguard ancient and elusive songbird</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/dna-project-to-save-rufous-scrub-bird/106191878</link><description>The Rufous scrub-bird is one of the world's oldest surviving species of songbird, but scientists believe fewer than 2,000 of the birds remain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9303e143d26a1ac223b41d18d2f75fda</guid></item><item><title>Higher rate of eviction for community housing residents in WA as decision-making process questioned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/higher-rate-of-eviction-for-community-housing-residents-in-wa/103417084</link><description>Community housing is seen as a way for the government to tackle the housing crisis, but between limited options and court orders, some people are falling through the cracks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f09ccbcce50039859f8104c5fcbe1f78</guid></item><item><title>What is developmental delay and how can you to tell if your child has one?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/how-to-tell-if-your-child-has-a-developmental-delay/105888348</link><description>Developmental delay will be a big part of the new NDIS alternative for some kids. But what does the phrase mean and how can you tell if your child has one?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c55d7c08342830d440475646461211de</guid></item><item><title>Is sustainable forestry certification protecting Australia's bushland?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/sustainable-timber-certification-concerns/105904122</link><description>Questions are being raised about sustainable timber certification in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d5dcc7b9702ebd2eb291f96d40e8434</guid></item><item><title>Country league president reported to AFL integrity unit over alleged 'gender weirdness' comments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/kyneton-womens-fc-report-league-president-to-afl-integrity-unit/106190264</link><description>A country football league president has been reported to the AFL Integrity Unit over alleged comments about a club's "grooming and gender weirdness" after it was involved in blocking the club from entering a neighbouring competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ceb9c73f6adf9f57f90bb1caae08180</guid></item><item><title>Geraldton e-scooter contract with Beam Mobility up for renewal as crash victim urges people not to ride</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/e-scooter-contract-beam-mobility-up-for-renewal-geraldton/106192128</link><description>Geraldton locals like Stuart Wise are calling for a crackdown on e-scooter safety, weeks after a man in his 30s died in an accident in the regional WA city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17b15607b1dc87c6a6cde718d48a1a25</guid></item><item><title>Oil prices fall after US strikes on Venezuela, ASX flat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/asx-markets-business-live-news-jan05-2026/106198892</link><description>Australian shares have ended the session unchanged on Monday, while oil prices fall in a choppy trade following the US strike on Venezuela that sparked concerns about oversupply.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f288e3c976105486c93bd0feca2bfa3</guid></item><item><title>Ditching Sydney for a wheat header, French farmer travels 17,000km to pick up where dad left off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/french-farmer-travel-to-australia-brittany/106192804</link><description>When 22-year-old Tanguy Bodiguel's friends said they were travelling to Australia, he left them in Sydney to work on a farm with sentimental value.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cf0435bf977df35b5865638e1562af7</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2026 live updates: Australia 2-166, Travis Head 91* after Stokes-Labuschagne clash on day two of fifth Test at SCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/ashes-cricket-scg-test-day-two-live-blog/106199006</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne falls two runs short of a Test half-century, nicking off to Ben Stokes immediately after clashing with the England captain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc60eeb2c778ab5b08f78ec8147d9340</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic exits Professional Tennis Players Association ahead of Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/novak-djokovic-exits-professional-tennis-players-association/106199048</link><description>Novak Djokovic is stepping away from the Professional Tennis Players Association citing concerns over transparency and governance within the organisation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">970d55f22cdf9cf67d04dfab8333e33e</guid></item><item><title>This toad busting group is determined to take back Magnetic Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/magnetic-island-cane-toad-busters/106136446</link><description>On a tropical Queensland island, 'toad busters' have decided the cane toad's spread across northern Australia should not be a lost cause.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8dc5263c05317f292acb302d1806c9f</guid></item><item><title>South-East Asian powers offer strong criticism of US operation in Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/asian-powers-express-grave-concern-over-us-venezuela-operation/106198804</link><description>Indonesia, Singapore and Malaysia express "grave concern" over the US capture of Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24e70a3542fee7391f5108367731680e</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Liberal Party deputy leader Sam Groth will exit politics at next election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/sam-groth-victorian-liberal-party-deputy-leader-exit-politics/106199004</link><description>Sam Groth, the deputy leader of the Victorian Liberal Party, has announced he will not contest the upcoming state election in November, saying he made his decision after realising that some recent negative public pressure had come from within his own party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f5b5f8c41cda77210cad523d0a9e51b</guid></item><item><title>Tributes flow for founding father of Australian beef industry, Sir Graham McCamley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/australian-beef-industry-mourns-loss-of-sir-graham-mccamley-93/106198876</link><description>From building one of Queensland's most respected cattle empires and championing the Brahman breed, Sir Graham's lifelong dedication to agriculture and his community was truly remarkable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53678aa9f26c57b78d0c160062c6859c</guid></item><item><title>Critics Choice Awards 2026 winners: One Battle After Another wins best picture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/critics-choice-awards-2026-winners-list/106199058</link><description>Now in their 31st year, the Critics Choice Awards are historically known to be the most accurate predictor of the Academy Award nominations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8952945cea491eff7e8aa4654529ec63</guid></item><item><title>Eels sign Brian Kelly as potential replacement for Zac Lomax ahead of 2026 NRL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/nrl-parramatta-eels-brian-kelly-zac-lomax/106199350</link><description>In the wake of Zac Lomax's sudden departure, Parramatta makes a move in the player market as it looks to lifts its fortunes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac27c637175a2fbeca89c1866fa2c76</guid></item><item><title>Jacob Elordi and Sarah Snook win at Critics Choice Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/critics-choice-awards-2026-key-moments/106199154</link><description>Australian actress Sarah Snook takes out Best Actress in a Limited Series or Movie Made for Television with All Her Fault while Australian Jacob Elordi takes out Best Supporting Actor for Frankenstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8693e491b3fd4de2f6d37b7e51d742e6</guid></item><item><title>Measles alert as Adelaide and Sydney airports among possible exposure sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/measles-case-travelled-from-adelaide-to-sydney-on-qantas-flight/106198812</link><description>SA and NSW health authorities have issued alerts about a potential measles exposure risk, after a person with the disease recently caught a flight from Adelaide to Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">871c233d42ef3773ef479cf4dcf379c7</guid></item><item><title>Trump's Venezuela move assumes his base will support his foreign interventions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/donald-trump-venezuela-foreign-policy-honduras/106199368</link><description>Donald Trump has long defied political gravity but whether his followers in Congress and the MAGA movement will follow him into a new colonialism is a big gamble.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fa61fc0754b3cf4b15eaf2e43ea3549</guid></item><item><title>NSW residents urged to check if they are owed share of $300m in unclaimed cash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/about-300-million-in-unclaimed-money-in-nsw/106199820</link><description>Almost $300 million in refunds, dividends and cheques remain unclaimed by households and businesses across New South Wales, with locals urged to take action to secure the money they are owed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7337b84bfbea19ae477d4850fbbd042f</guid></item><item><title>What's Going on in Venezuela?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/what-s-going-on-in-venezuela-/106199950</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0798e3f8fb2d3bd2b2e21a497df3929e</guid></item><item><title>Joe Root best since Donald Bradman says Darren Lehmann after second Ashes century on Australian soil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/joe-root-second-century-scg-don-bradman/106199570</link><description>Joe Root is hailed as the greatest cricket player since Don Bradman after adding a second century to his tally this Ashes tour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a3694ac0d0eba32578e8d3615060f54</guid></item><item><title>Victoria, SA, NSW brace for 'worst' heatwave since Black Summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/worst-heatwave-conditions-since-black-summer/106197780</link><description>Blisteringly high temperatures are expected throughout Victoria and in parts of South Australia and New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdda092ae934d3725735806ccaf33077</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate burglary at offices of comedy troupe Sooshi Mango</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/sooshi-mango-burglary-crime-melbourne/106199662</link><description>The group posted CCTV footage on social media appearing to show a man breaking into an office in Carlton.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6519ffa9603a05f81a708440735d5eb5</guid></item><item><title>Emergency departments ill-suited for mental health crises, advocates say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/act-emergency-departments-ill-suited-mental-health-crises/106200130</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb03edf77794382a8abaf4029cb90a38</guid></item><item><title>Autopsy unable to determine cause of Tennant Creek woman's death in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/nt-tennant-creek-watch-house-death-in-custody-post-mortem-result/106199844</link><description>Police say the cause of a woman's death in a Northern Territory police watch house last month remains "undetermined" following a post-mortem examination conducted on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1fb0594a4e3a0f4ef5d5114e677138e</guid></item><item><title>All 40 victims of Crans-Montana bar fire identified amid outpouring of grief</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/all-victims-of-swiss-bar-fire-identified-police-say/106200304</link><description>Swiss police say more than half of the 40 people killed after a fire broke out at a bar in the Crans-Montana resort were teenagers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be79554e24e09bfc8a188718c2ecb50d</guid></item><item><title>Crews worked on the fire for more than 2 hours.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/fire-brisbane-wynnum/106199440</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f6eb147221b62b38b506e0458109771</guid></item><item><title>Alert canine saves residents as fire destroys Wynnum home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/qld-wynnum-fire-dog-saves-residents/106199984</link><description>Family escapes house fire 'by the skin of their teeth' thanks to their dog who raised the alarm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d81465da29c08b8f892630edf44e2873</guid></item><item><title>Trump ramps up rhetoric on Colombia, Cuba and Mexico after Venezuela raid.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/rhetoric-trump-venezuela/106200620</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c091f82677be41778140424f59c9d8dc</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave sweeps across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/heatwave-sweeps-across-australia/106200958</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc4d9f91bc5d90b4f57c83903f102b3a</guid></item><item><title>Langi Kal Kal prison escapee threatens farm worker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/prison-escapee-attacks-farm-worker-langi-kal-kal/106199880</link><description>A farm worker says he was threatened by a man who escaped from Langi Kal Kal prison near Ballarat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22a240d35a388433f5b60959e32c27ab</guid></item><item><title>Why did a Venezuelan rally go ahead in Sydney despite protest restrictions?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/nsw-explainer-protest-ban-bondi-as-venezuelans-rally-in-sydney/106199170</link><description>New laws restricting protests were recently passed in NSW, yet close to 300 people took to the streets of Sydney after the US attack on Venezuela.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abd16d859e4adf561fa9fedbb64772ac</guid></item><item><title>Moderate chance of cyclone hitting Far North Queensland coast by the weekend, weather bureau forecasts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/far-north-queensland-cyclone-forecast/106199464</link><description>The chance of a tropical low off the Far North Queensland coast developing into a cyclone is increasing from low to moderate by the weekend, according to the weather bureau.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb93f7f8d3e6c70af69b17d4c25e36b5</guid></item><item><title>Key points to understand US attacks on Venezuela and capture of President Maduro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/what-happened-us-strikes-venezuela-maduro-captured-what-next/106198900</link><description>These are the key points to get up to speed with what we know about the US strikes on Venezuela and the current state of play after its president was ousted and removed from the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8831a0d03d39f3b5a7c9e57fd010b6ca</guid></item><item><title>Alleged driver in fatal Darwin hit-and-run Pairat Junsomran bailed, allowed by court to travel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/nt-fatal-hit-and-run-alleged-offender-bail-bagot-road-darwin/106200298</link><description>A 61-year-old dual national charged over a fatal hit-and-run in Darwin has been granted bail, less than 10 days after the crash which claimed the life of a 27-year-old woman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74a2bbea3e8cba37941ac669bd8be510</guid></item><item><title>Victims withholding information after three Hobart shootings in a week, Tasmania Police says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/hobart-three-shootings-police-victims-withholding-information/106198946</link><description>Three shootings have occurred in northern Hobart in the space of a week, with police saying two appear to be related.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6547af8b9c7d035da4d8d77424d0f4d2</guid></item><item><title>Denmark tells Trump to back off over 'threats' against Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/denmark-rejects-us-trump-threats-greenland/106199700</link><description>The leaders of Denmark and Greenland have urged US President Donald Trump to stop threatening to take over Greenland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90f98d74a11dbe632e6e2a20575310b9</guid></item><item><title>Small aircraft crashes at airport in Adelaide's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/small-aircraft-crashes-at-airport-in-adelaide-s-north/106201012</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09b85a9721ddc253f7442a89b4ba7b0d</guid></item><item><title>The design of Queensland's Olympic stadium has been revealed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/qld-olympic-stadium-victoria-park/106199988</link><description>The new stadium will host the opening and closing ceremonies and athletics at the 2032 Games, before becoming the city’s main stadium with 63,000 seats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc65511cc45cc8274771f4409e073445</guid></item><item><title>Pasta, slow-cooker recipes and tray bakes: Our top 10 recipes from 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/your-favourite-recipes-of-2025/106091718</link><description>Easy weeknight meals were your favourite (again), with tray bakes, soups and noodles amongst the most loved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8de5c8d7977a031014b35aa3f1495f1</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro held in New York prison described as 'hell on earth'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/nicol%C3%A1s-maduro-in-the-new-york-metropolitan-detention-center/106199184</link><description>The facility where detained Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro has been taken is a notorious New York jail that has held a string of high-profile and celebrity criminals, from drug cartel leaders to hip-hop stars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">784a697b58d4fb284175a75608400421</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach gunman Naveed Akram moved to Goulburn Supermax prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/bondi-beach-gunman-naveed-akram-moved-goulburn-supermax-prison/106201450</link><description>The ABC understands Naveed Akram was moved earlier on Monday from Sydney's Long Bay jail hospital where he has been for the past fortnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73d6914d5f15ad2ae4b31a9c0f392f9f</guid></item><item><title>Senior Queensland doctor cleared of allegations after 14-month suspension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/chief-medical-officer-reinstated-mackay-charles-pain/106200692</link><description>Mackay's chief medical officer, Charles Pain, returns to work after an external investigation cleared him of allegations of poor clinical governance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85b480f0b3f7daeb998b973f37ba8781</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne prises farcical wicket, Cam Green's agony continues, Travis Head sparkles — quick hits from day two of SCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/ashes-scg-test-quick-hits-day-two/106199122</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne picks up a farcical wicket, Cam Green can't catch a break and Joe Root enters rare air. Here are the quick hits from the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63d637764db6fed8ea8267c149c9b46d</guid></item><item><title>Energy company ENGIE promised pensioner refund then sent debt collectors after him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/engie-energy-makes-mistake-sends-debt-collectors-after-pensioner/106132388</link><description>Australia's energy prices continue to soar as questions continue to be raised about the actions of providers, including by this pensioner who was overcharged and then had debt collectors chasing him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f33b84b38f7a914084ecd3e5659b2fe6</guid></item><item><title>Travis Head and Joe Root bring batting class to bowlers' Ashes on a fiery second day of SCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/batting-class-prevails-for-head-and-root-ashes-scg-day-two/106200104</link><description>In what has been a bowlers' series, the class of Joe Root and Travis Head again shone on day two in Sydney, where it often took something silly for a wicket to fall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c0d5da305e3e8babfb546559bd6132d</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/gold-and-silver-jump-after-us-attacks-venezuela-oil-down-slightl/106201488</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6baf356d650d49c9ff9bf950dca45c81</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Police employee faces court over alleged antisemitic online posts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/police-service-employee-faces-court-over-alleged-hate-crimes/106201402</link><description>Muamer Nukic, a 50-year-old Queensland Police Service employee and described as a "self-proclaimed anti-Zionist" was granted bail in the Brisbane Magistrate Court on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52a4aaba462836bd8b3c7c152be81a0f</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump claimed Venezuela stole US oil assets but the issue is more complicated than that</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/why-venezuelan-oil-is-not-stolen-from-the-united-states/106200804</link><description>US President Donald Trump has said Venezuela stole United States oil assets. Experts say the truth is much more complex than that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1185033f9bae9e894518bb6079f6eeb6</guid></item><item><title>Former Labor politicians urge Albanese to call federal royal commission into antisemitism and Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/former-labor-politicians-plead-albanese-royal-commission-bondi/106201744</link><description>A group of former Labor MPs, senators and party officials have signed an open letter asking Anthony Albanese to call a national royal commission into the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26a868908b51731a34c2d0c946047074</guid></item><item><title>Manchester United sacks head coach Ruben Amorim after turbulent tenure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/manchester-united-sacks-coach-ruben-amorim/106201814</link><description>It comes less than a day after the club drew one-all with Leeds United and a testy post-match press conference in which Amorim questioned his own role and the club's management.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a2476a5bca8dd0da1f9c213592433da</guid></item><item><title>A Paris court finds 10 people guilty of cyberbullying France's first lady Brigitte Macron</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/10-charged-for-cyberbullying-brigitte-macron/106201796</link><description>Several defendants told the court their comments were intended as humour or satire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5382845bf3ac9a036f487b1f6faa3210</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann launches High Court appeal in latest defamation fight, alleging findings 'compromised'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/bruce-lehrmann-launches-high-court-appeal/106201754</link><description>Former Liberal staffer Bruce Lehrmann takes his appeal to the High Court against the findings that he, on the balance of probabilities, raped Brittany Higgins in 2019.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">446e771832ca4322175a527c2b872641</guid></item><item><title>Ousted Venezuelan leader Nicolás Maduro and wife Cilia Flores plead not guilty in New York court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/venezuelan-leader-nicol%C3%A1s-maduro-appears-in-new-york-court/106201846</link><description>Nicolás Maduro and Cilia Flores, who were captured in Caracas at the weekend, face multiple charges, including narco-terrorism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">893a666a98bd976fe476ea782d0fed9e</guid></item><item><title>How this new Melbourne suburb is dodging baking heat in summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/clyde-tree-canopy-requirement-casey-council/106174988</link><description>Thousands of young trees dot the streets and front gardens of this outer Melbourne suburb as part of a neighbourhood-wide push to create more shade and curb the urban heat island effect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">416a36938699bfbb40f85c53e408d39c</guid></item><item><title>Nancy Kerrigan assault a soap-operatic story that overshadowed the 1994 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/nancy-kerrigan-assault-tonya-harding-1994/106184912</link><description>The gentile and sequined world of figure skating had its dark side exposed in a drama worthy of a soap opera in 1994, as Nancy Kerrigan was the victim of a dastardly plot to eliminate her from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1979bdf82e7b75b4e83dc1710e143ef</guid></item><item><title>How much do you know about the meat pie? Test yourself (or treat yourself)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/dr-karl-how-things-works-pie-quiz/106086912</link><description>From pastry processing to mass-cooking meat — test your knowledge on the humble meat pie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7992118d27286ee078a2f7a57c588df</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's 'bold' oil grab in South America appears to be a major chess move</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/venezuela-oil-donald-trump-power-grab/106200092</link><description>In a world awash with oil, US President Donald Trump's takeover of Venezuela seems to be more about power than production.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c448111ae1ca3e26a21c7187e2bfbb4b</guid></item><item><title>'Most significant' heatwave in six years brings temperatures above 45C</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/australia-heatwave-most-significant-in-six-years/106200088</link><description>The "most significant" heatwave south-eastern Australia has seen in six years is likely to trigger an extreme fire danger alongside searing hot temperatures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62b8cc56863c610fcfcc3d2abaf4eee4</guid></item><item><title>UN chief Antonio Guterres warns of wider instability following US operation in Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/un-security-council-meets-to-discuss-us-attack-on-venezuela/106201850</link><description>The warning by the UN chief comes during an emergency session of the United Nations Security Council, just blocks from where Nicolás Maduro and his wife Cilia Flores are facing a Manhattan judge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4231245359710a0d66c24b6639109fa</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's bioluminescence unrelated to salmon farm nutrients, scientist says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/algal-bloom-concerns-near-tasmanian-salmon-farms/106199152</link><description>Scientists say a bioluminescent algae causes the red tides at the centre of recent environmentalist concerns — but that's not to say the magnificent display is totally harmless to marine life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e53ddd06679985fe547fe80d6ac07c62</guid></item><item><title>What to expect from Reserve Bank and interest rates in 2026 with rate hikes on the table</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/what-to-expect-from-rba-interest-rates-in-2026-hikes-on-table/106200132</link><description>Mortgage borrowers and savers may have used the new year as an excuse to get their financial affairs in order, but things may be set to change within a matter of months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">750d17a1fe3aa50c384088d78725fa3d</guid></item><item><title>Child abuse campaigners want reforms to Centrelink, insurance repayments from compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/child-abuse-survivor-compensation-repayments/106186294</link><description>When survivors of child sexual abuse receive compensation, many may have to repay Centrelink, Medicare and private health insurance amounts relating to their abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">445284820f8256e62fd89879c511bb41</guid></item><item><title>Walk while you work: Are the extra steps using an under-desk treadmill worth the cost?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/is-a-desk-treadmill-worth-the-cost/106195036</link><description>Many people know what it feels like to sit at a computer all day, then sit on the living room couch all night. Would a desk treadmill help?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffcf1a90a47f29dce8bb12e93387795c</guid></item><item><title>Woolwich Marina expansion rejected but locals worry about future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/local-groups-stop-woolwich-marina-expansion-but-fear-isnt-over/106194942</link><description>Local groups that helped save heritage-listed Kelly’s Bush Park from being impacted by a marina expansion proposal are calling on the NSW government to do more to protect the foreshore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ef73f7409172d89acff9defaf0a59bc</guid></item><item><title>ABC News - Trusted Source of Latest News &amp; Headlines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2022-12-13/harley-and-katya-the-price-of-an-olympic-dream/101557348</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee96c51cbc5b98d83ab9002535dfc647</guid></item></channel></rss>