<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 02:26:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dust flies in Ayers Rock Resort $65m writedown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2013-10-24/ayers-rock-resort-writedown-indigenous-land-corporation-reactio/5043254</link><description>The Indigenous Land Corporation (ILC) is making sweeping changes after writing off more than $62 million from the value of its flagship tourism property at Uluru. The Federally-funded corporation paid $317 million for the Ayers Rock Resort in 2010 but its value has now been written down to about $250 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">135bf91d59625f325e4f0891cb1507f1</guid></item><item><title>Review questions Ayers Rock Resort valuation and buy by Indigenous Land Corporation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2013-12-19/review-questions-ayers-rock-resort-valuation-and-buy-by-ilc/5167056</link><description>An advisory group that delivered the highest valuation for central Australia's Ayers Rock Resort in 2010 was paid a fee based on the purchase price.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba9d66f3f913cb1323a523cd5fce74bd</guid></item><item><title>Ayers Rock Resort losing $3 million a month while it waits for tourists to return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2020-06-05/uluru-ayers-rock-resort-hopes-to-see-tourists-back-by-august/12324070</link><description>Ayers Rock Resort says it is losing millions of dollars of month while it waits for tourism to pick back up from the pandemic slumber.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c94689009938315f8cdd3356a5746047</guid></item><item><title>Update your ABC News homepage for more local stories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2020-09-03/update-to-abc-news-homepage/12579988</link><description>We've got an ABC News homepage for you. Adjust your settings for the right mix of local and national news.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">146f1699ce6b1b7420a91b6bb80d0309</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of jobs on horizon after green light from Transgrid for Hydrostor's compressed-air energy storage in Broken Hill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2023-12-08/hundreds-jobs-hyrostor-energy-storage-project-broken-hill-sa/103206346</link><description>While the future of one of Broken Hill's major mines is still uncertain, a green energy storage project to be built in the coming years may provide employment opportunities for some of the displaced workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99ff2c78cd7e9bc30fefaa5a0b934a32</guid></item><item><title>Carnarvon banana growers using freeze-dried facility to save fruit rejected by Australian supermarkets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-02-13/carnarvon-banana-growers-finding-new-way-to-reduce-food-waste/103159688</link><description>Tonnes of West Australian bananas that would end up as waste or mulch are being made into freeze-dried snacks and used to make products like vodka as Carnarvon growers look to reduce wastage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3db5e9ab19176521a9894deddc9a324e</guid></item><item><title>Banana industry turns to robots and AI for 'dangerous' packing-shed task of cutting fruit from stem</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-02-17/robotic-arm-under-development-to-separate-bananas-from-stem/103461494</link><description>It takes effort to get bananas from the farm to the fruit bowl, with growers relying on a significant workforce to pick and pack. Now scientists are working on technology to make it easier and safer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c3b804dbaf7cc16ef3f96ddf51df551</guid></item><item><title>South Australian Liberals elect Vincent Tarzia as new leader to replace David Speirs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-12/sa-liberals-elect-new-leader-david-speirs-resignation/104211328</link><description>South Australia's Liberal Party has elected Vincent Tarzia as its new leader, replacing David Speirs, who announced his resignation last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">517a9d4020d8234214a9b6a3335d10f0</guid></item><item><title>Underground compressed air energy storage facility green-lit at Broken Hill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-02-25/underground-compressed-air-energy-storage-facility-broken-hill/104978122</link><description>An old mine in Broken Hill will be re-purposed by Canadian company Hydrostor as an "innovative" renewable energy storage and generation project tipped to create hundreds of local construction jobs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e888e9a29107b357c3372054e5dbb1f</guid></item><item><title>Betrayal of Trust: Australia's Childcare Crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-03-17/betrayal-of-trust/105063150</link><description>Four Corners is the home of Australian investigative journalism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95b04766effe22c7795f5a0edc6a2e16</guid></item><item><title>Push for seniors' dental scheme grows ahead of federal election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-13/aged-care-dental-scheme-australia-federal-election/105149782</link><description>Imagine living in aged care and not having your teeth or dentures properly cleaned and checked each day. That's a risk faced by elderly Australians, prompting calls for the next federal government to boost oral health training and services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36d312d336a36247fd1c01e78814112b</guid></item><item><title>Australia's growing cohort of tenants fear they will rent forever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-16/australias-growing-tenant-cohort-fear-forever-renting/105127148</link><description>Home ownership rates in Australia have been falling for decades, and with rental vacancies at record lows and prices at historic highs, many fear their dream of owning a home may be out of reach. Some experts say rental caps could help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36f35fe439f533ac9522c679c7e37187</guid></item><item><title>Graduates in 'debt vortex' as HECS front and centre for first time in an election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-16/federal-election-2025-hecs-student-debt-policies/105177248</link><description>New research shows a sharp rise in HECS debts, despite graduate earning power declining, as student loans become a potent election issue for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48707ffafbe02c400b1200e6269fd40e</guid></item><item><title>Next-generation voters call for better engagement ahead of federal election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-18/federal-election-rural-next-generation-voters/105173450</link><description>Young people in Albury say issues that directly affect them and their communities are not being addressed by major parties for the 2025 election campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ae182892b8c9591cd9ec35e6e57fcb9</guid></item><item><title>Tiwi Islanders eager to have their say as remote voting for the federal election begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-22/early-voting-starts-in-remote-communities-tiwi-islands-aec/105201318</link><description>Voters in the small remote community of Pirlangimpi on the Tiwi Islands, north of Darwin, have become some of the first to cast their votes for the federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0c419fe3ae44debe7edf27241c0e5c1</guid></item><item><title>Record gold price sees West Australian mine revived</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-24/record-gold-prices-revive-older-west-australian/105332774</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7bcacad1a085a072ef34952c7f0c55a</guid></item><item><title>Tennant Creek hopes gold mine reopening marks return to 'gold capital'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-30/tennant-creek-nobles-gold-mine-reopens/105356378</link><description>As the first gold bars are poured at the reopened Nobles Nob gold mine in the Northern Territory, locals hope it will bring a return to the region's golden era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34048484d0ac7eede0187920edefe7d7</guid></item><item><title>US demands Australia lifts defence spending by $40b a year 'as soon as possible'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-06-02/us-australia-defence-spend-billions-hegseth-china/105364740</link><description>The United States wants Australia to lift spending on defence to about $100 billion a year, with its Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth warning of a "real and potentially imminent" threat from China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8eff472718611cc99b3ff9fc24f49158</guid></item><item><title>What the Socceroos need against Saudi Arabia to qualify for the World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-06-10/what-do-the-socceroos-need-to-qualify-for-2026-fifa-world-cup/105387428</link><description>The Socceroos are just a solid performance from reaching their sixth FIFA World Cup finals in a row, but must remain focused against Saudi Arabia in Jeddah. Here's everything you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ed479d5b4ca038f6b8dce6874dd5b21</guid></item><item><title>Mat Ryan wanted to freeze time on 100th appearance for Socceroos after penalty save</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-06-11/mat-ryan-100-caps-freeze-time-socceroos-penalty-save/105402378</link><description>The keeper said he felt like he had played his final Socceroos match when he was left out of the starting XI late last year. Now he's celebrated his 100th international with a fine penalty stop as Australia progressed to the FIFA World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4506e8323b27154a8fa2e1d11bf3c807</guid></item><item><title>Heather Ewart reflects on the tough road to Back Roads success</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-07-17/heather-ewart-farewells-back-roads-ten-year-anniversary/105425700</link><description>Heather Ewart was a powerhouse political reporter when she was asked to create a show about regional Australia. A decade later, and with her final season going to air, Ewart admits that getting the idea off the ground was no easy feat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">015b32b8ed1e8c3177e94f59c0a95456</guid></item><item><title>Ausgold acquires 860ha of farmland for Katanning Gold Project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-25/gold-mine-buys-agricultural-land-in-katanning-great-southern/105686334</link><description>Ausgold's deal includes an 860-hectare land acquisition, as well as compensation and relocation of the farming families involved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7df88b33c0d05d732eff8e9db89fc0d</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners sign native title agreement for Agnew gold mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-28/tjiwarl-traditional-owners-sign-native-title-agreement-agnew/105707172</link><description>Tjiwarl Aboriginal Corporation meets with South African miner Gold Fields in Leinster to sign an agreement for one of the WA's oldest gold mines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51ca4ff541773437dbc751aa88f3b5b3</guid></item><item><title>Nestory Irankunda returns to Socceroos squad after 10-month absence as Tony Popovic praises maturity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-29/nestory-irankunda-named-socceroos-squad-vs-new-zealand/105712802</link><description>Socceroos coach Tony Popovic praises Nestory Irankunda's maturity as he names the starlet in his squad for the first time this year ahead of the "Soccer Ashes" against New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84d7728351746df3394e2a263de9b664</guid></item><item><title>Robert Karl Huber sentenced over manslaughter of Lindy Lucena</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/robert-huber-sentenced-lindy-lucena-manslaughter/105752582</link><description>Robert Karl Huber is sentenced to 12 years in prison over the death of his partner Lindy Lucena in Ballina in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f50eb6571753bee833f6c02077e51b44</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth Avenue Bridge upgrade likely to cause commuter chaos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/act-commonwealth-avenue-bridge-shrink-three-lanes-construction/105808342</link><description>Major upgrades addressing the structural safety of the Commonwealth Avenue Bridge will soon begin, leading to two years of significant traffic disruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae43eb5f622240005e280fc21f5eea60</guid></item><item><title>Former A-League footballers Clayton Lewis and Kearyn Baccus sentenced over betting scam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/a-league-betting-clayton-lewis-kearyn-baccus-sentencing/105811400</link><description>Both players were paid $10,000 each to intentionally get themselves yellow cards while playing for Macarthur FC against Sydney FC to influence overseas bets on the game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4d047a9369284c7941aaf5cccc0a654</guid></item><item><title>Southern pygmy perch 'ear bones' provide data to re-establish populations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/fish-ear-bones-could-be-key-to-pygmy-perch-revival/105811482</link><description>Information gleaned from tiny growth rings on "ear bones" of native pygmy perch could be the key to bringing them back from local extinction in the lower Murray.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">649c11322dafbfaa01c2ce68e583e5e7</guid></item><item><title>Betting companies keep millions stolen from investors by 'VIP' gambler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/betting-companies-keep-vip-gamblers-stolen-millions-four-corners/105843526</link><description>Nick and Aimee Mazza's hard-earned cash was gambled away by a man they thought was investing it. Bookmakers encouraged him to keep betting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42e39985dc4f61b535e2da312f2a4c6d</guid></item><item><title>Losing Streak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/losing-streak/105859060</link><description>Four Corners is the home of Australian investigative journalism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ef84904ddd616d8cc62e4f9670ac635</guid></item><item><title>Gold price hits record high, topping $US4,000 an ounce for first time, amid US shutdown and lower interest rates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/gold-price-hits-record-high-topping-4000-an-ounce/105863902</link><description>The price of gold has hit another record and is set to become Australia's second most valuable resource export after iron ore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8a6a55db842730246cc3ca2cf30402a</guid></item><item><title>Calls for national gambling watchdog grow amid NT conflict allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/government-reviews-conflict-allegations-against-nt-gambling-body/105863006</link><description>The NT government is standing by its de-facto regulation of Australia’s $50 billion online gambling industry, despite allegations that it is too closely linked to the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1787670408388b683f9dbffa05bd3b95</guid></item><item><title>Las Vegas licence hearing turns nightmare for boss of Australian pokies giant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/las-vegas-licence-withdrawn-australian-pokies-boss/105878214</link><description>Regulators in the world's most influential gaming jurisdiction have dismissed a licence bid by the boss of Australia's Ainsworth Game Technology, branding him "arrogant", "misleading" and lacking in "emotional intelligence".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c92d4ad80838c1474d9c5146b5c7914</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government's BetStop scheme not working, former gambler says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/betstop-scheme-not-working-former-gambler-says/105878872</link><description>Diehard Richmond fan "Tiger Shaun" says he's watched on in horror as gambling advertising and sponsorships have come to dominate football — and become a constant reminder of the addiction he has struggled with.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6b9cac18f3f5518da8b3cd291770331</guid></item><item><title>More than $6 million of cocaine and methylamphetamine seized during vehicle stop in southern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/highway-patrol-drug-haul-in-hay-nsw-vehicle-stop/105909462</link><description>Highway patrol stopped the black luxury SUV on a major New South Wales highway for a random drug and alcohol test on Friday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0b12cb731bfba08c1331b8020ab344b</guid></item><item><title>Survey finds majority of Victorian renters face problems — but not nearly as many lodge a complaint</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/victorian-renter-confidence-index-survey-launched/105918696</link><description>A survey of 1,000 Victorian renters finds nearly four in five households faced a tenancy issue over a 12-month period — but only half of them escalated the issue by lodging a complaint.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f9dd5af832fd62ecc3f2ad00d140c38</guid></item><item><title>NT politicians call for inquiry into Australia's de facto online gambling regulator</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/nt-parliament-requests-online-gambling-regulator-inquiry/105921322</link><description>More than 40 of Australia's corporate bookmakers are based in the Northern Territory for its low taxes and what critics describe as weak regulation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3b7377d7f8cdec5a4d99f5052c0097c</guid></item><item><title>Mate Stipinovich, Aristides Avlontis, Karl Whitburn jailed for bungled Albany drug smuggling attempt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/drug-smugglers-who-clung-to-esky-off-albany-sentenced/105920248</link><description>Three men forced to cling to an esky to survive in wild seas off Albany as they tried to import hundreds of kilograms of cocaine into Western Australia are described by a judge as "Keystone criminals" at their sentencing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3a907b92905039815d6a864be91a54d</guid></item><item><title>Australia is all in on AUKUS. In Donald Trump's America, it's more complicated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/us-aukus-commitment-welcomed-but-questions-remain/105928396</link><description>In Washington on Monday, Anthony Albanese made something clear once again: Australia is all-in on the trilateral defence pact. Clarifying what US powerbrokers think remains a multi-billion-dollar question.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2097e546d99243d4faca7eb0a1113d6</guid></item><item><title>What we know about 'mind-boggling' NBA rigging and poker fraud cases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/nba-rigging-and-poker-fraud-cases-explained/105928536</link><description>The allegations involve NBA luminaries, multiple New York mafia families, millions in cash and even an x-ray poker table that could read cards face down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">baea5497909229f2d0e05e216133bb50</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle mother calls for tougher laws after toddler run down by e-bike</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/mother-calls-for-tougher-laws-after-toddler-run-down-by-e-bike/105928636</link><description>More than a year after her 21-month-old child was hit by an e-bike, a Newcastle mother is calling for change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bc69cffa7f162ac54d3c32a7e7ea9d5</guid></item><item><title>Walking netball adaptation helping players stay on the court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-26/walking-netball-masters-games-active-inclusive-sport/105934176</link><description>Before they take the court, the Magnolias strap on knee braces and tie bows in their hair. But don't be deceived, they're playing one of the 'most competitive games', and there may be elbows thrown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcba91251592e68fb53952910d872d63</guid></item><item><title>NSW government's drug summit response rejects medicinal cannabis defence for drivers for now</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/nsw-government-drug-summit-response-cannabis/105941584</link><description>The government says it was "investigating" a medical defence for drivers prescribed cannabis but ruled out the use of sniffer dogs and strip searches for suspected drug possession at music festivals in its response to last year's drug summit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a947513c37d9ffbc448fecfb8fed4dd5</guid></item><item><title>The key role a 'lost' reef is playing in South Australia's algal bloom fight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/native-oyster-reefs-restored-algal-bloom-recovery-sa/105943318</link><description>A marine ecologist's discovery two years ago sparked a restoration project and has become a key element in South Australia's response to a devastating algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6da4b9d6a96705189c11b0f39230daf7</guid></item><item><title>Dicky Beach holiday park residents angry after Sunshine Coast Council decision</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/dozens-of-homes-now-worthless-after-council-van-park-decision/105916100</link><description>More than 100 residents face an uncertain future after a Queensland council votes to end permanent residencies at a holiday park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ac50bc59234ac58c8aca59875c1028a</guid></item><item><title>Caravan street parking solution stifled by council red tape, storage owners say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/councils-may-hold-key-to-caravan-street-parking-solution/105943790</link><description>A Queensland council struggling to solve a caravan street parking crisis is hampered by its own planning laws, a storage business says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7d53cb5cb69021542c53ecf6bb5c3ef</guid></item><item><title>Oyster farmers blockade trucks carrying oysters from algal bloom waters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/streaky-bay-oyster-farmers-block-oyster-trucks-sa/105951284</link><description>Oyster farmers have formed a blockade at Haslam in South Australia to prevent oysters from an area affected by the algal bloom being put in the waters around Streaky Bay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97901e580ccfa96c7bd7857d732b6022</guid></item><item><title>Brazil's deadliest ever police operation leaves at least 120 dead after Rio de Janeiro drug raid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/brazil-police-raid-rio-de-janeiro-drugs/105950908</link><description>Brazil's deadliest ever police operation has triggered protests against the use of excessive force and calls for Rio's governor to resign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5e14d55465b115edb8d6ea6d6f4c36b</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos coach Tony Popovic says restoring Australia's football DNA is key to creating World Cup history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/socceroos-coach-tony-popovic-pursues-greatness-fifa-world-cup/105949386</link><description>The Socceroos have historically been seen as plucky underdogs at the FIFA World Cup. Now, Tony Popovic believes those same traits can see his side create history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7050d95216cea24d2baa5d8678bea0bf</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's campaign against Venezuelan drug boats is rooted in past failure and a hatred of Nicolas Maduro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/trump-blowing-up-boats-as-maduro-arms-venezuelans/105947824</link><description>Donald Trump is on a revenge tour during his second stint in the White House and now his gaze has shifted to an enemy who once "humiliated" him — Nicolas Maduro.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">322e4374aa993498dd5dadd4ad39a7a1</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump’s war on drugs targets Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/donald-trump-s-war-on-drugs-targets-venezuela/105953962</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b47b4a43e055be0fb0d9e5917ab5592</guid></item><item><title>The Canberra Liberals need to put their internal feud behind them. It's hard to see how they'll do that</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/canberra-liberals-internal-feud-distracting-from-job-opposition/105959904</link><description>After suspending two backbenchers from her party room this week, Canberra Liberals leader Leanne Castley has been silent. And it's hard to see how staying silent is helping Canberrans build trust in her party and her as the ACT's alternative chief minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6092a469630022aa6e000888ae487a5c</guid></item><item><title>Horse racing replays edited to remove falls and deaths as industry grapples with social licence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/horse-racing-disappearing-video-replay-ethical-concerns/105812252</link><description>For years, the racing industry has been quietly removing falls and deaths from its replays. Now, industry insiders are speaking out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60509cf475521db2072628c3e8b45285</guid></item><item><title>A game for the ages: Nan and teen granddaughter line up together in country netball</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/newstead-netball-game-for-the-ages-nan-and-teen/105944908</link><description>A grandmother and granddaughter played for their regional Victorian netball team, turning a secret plan into a moment of country sport history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95920eb90f08d84fbc57ca7f8a5ec5ad</guid></item><item><title>Fishers and researchers are working together to create a 'transformational' data set</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/fishsoop-to-changes-ocean-knowledge/105946294</link><description>An international program in which researchers collaborate with the fishing industry is generating a dataset that will change global weather forecasting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d0be8dd19db857d8bebdf3c09e48455</guid></item><item><title>Plan to apply commercial council rates for short-stay rentals sparks debate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/mount-gambier-council-short-stay-rates-airbnb-changes/105943950</link><description>A council in South Australia wants to charge short-stay rentals such as Airbnbs at a higher rate, saying they act as businesses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d47a93022c4ac1259f4b1659047e216</guid></item><item><title>Calls for football clubs to divest from pokies with more than $110 million lost to machines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/afl-football-pokies-machines-gambling/105953142</link><description>There are calls for football teams to distance themselves from poker machines after data found more than $110 million was lost at venues owned by football clubs and leagues in the last financial year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdb126202dde835a7f847688b62cc9df</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police, WA Police and AFP charge 18 people in Strike Force Bloomfield drug bust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/nsw-and-wa-police-charge-18-people-as-part-of-major-drug-bust/105969768</link><description>Police charge 18 people in Perth and Sydney and seize 268 kilograms of illicit drugs following a multi-agency investigation into a national crime syndicate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8a93680e5ed3262899b3b094cb1054f</guid></item><item><title>Sorry seems to be the hardest word for ACT Transport Minister Chris Steel after bungled MyWay+ rollout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/sorry-the-hardest-word-for-act-transport-minister-chris-steel/105969026</link><description>Five days after being censured in the ACT's Legislative Assembly for the bungled rollout of the territory's MyWay+ network, Transport Minister Chris Steel has issued a statement to "apologise to anyone impacted by the transition to the new service".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e37c545d0d688068102d25ea466764bd</guid></item><item><title>Family of Australian man accused of cocaine smuggling speak ahead of possible Bali death sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/australian-man-lamar-ahchee-family-speaks-to-abc-news-in-bali/105974682</link><description>The sister of Australian man Lamar Ahchee, who has been on trial on drug charges in Bali, describes the moment she heard the news of his arrest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">271d268e1f515e85a72bb2001ee899e1</guid></item><item><title>High-speed rail business case linking Sydney and Newcastle supported by government assessment body</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/high-speed-rail-sydney-and-newcastle-another-step-closer/105978262</link><description>The business case for high-speed rail between Sydney and Newcastle identifies four initial station locations for a one-hour journey.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c13c1f5942eb64b891c8be688b0154e6</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri says he still has what it takes to win F1 world championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/oscar-piastri-says-he-still-has-what-it-takes-to-win-f1-champ/105982570</link><description>Oscar Piastri has said he is still a serious contender for the Formula 1 world championship despite seeing his lead evaporate over the past five races.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff57cd80f16f081c606c43761fd855eb</guid></item><item><title>Chinese-made electric buses on Australian roads spark cybersecurity concerns after Norway flags issue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/chinese-electric-buses-in-australia-spark-security-concerns/105982738</link><description>The same Chinese company that makes electric buses now under review in Denmark and Norway also has electric buses on Australian roads.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77608d57816d5695bf284b6f9cf56ba8</guid></item><item><title>A letter to Anthony Albanese could allow Labor MPs to speak up on gambling reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/albanese-government-free-vote-gambling-ad-reform-andrew-wilkie/105969714</link><description>Andrew Wilkie has asked the PM to allow a free vote on banning gambling advertising and it appears many Labor MPs would support it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c1fb7933c8c4d48fed937f5e719605f</guid></item><item><title>Albury's Macquarie Textiles celebrated for decades of manufacturing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/alburys-rich-wool-and-textile-history-celebrated-in-exhibition/105958750</link><description>Textile manufacturing took Albury's work to the Opera House, federal parliament, the Olympics and beyond.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e79d3a3fce1ccbf4621429603303d231</guid></item><item><title>Renewable energy 'spilled' as generation outgrows demand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/renewable-energy-spilled-as-generation-outgrows-demand-/105929716</link><description>Mountains of clean power are regularly "wasted" as Australia's energy system evolves. But a large amount of battery storage is waiting in the wings, ready to soak it up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c172fa2bcb9a7c1c64d98273854a3f25</guid></item><item><title>City of Melbourne rejects Mildura's attempt to return 'Yellow Peril' home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/city-of-melbourne-rejects-mildura-vault-heist-attempt/105989078</link><description>City of Melbourne rejects Mildura's attempt to take the city's controversial "Yellow Peril" sculpture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db05a1ca3a875019911c68d8e994aa0f</guid></item><item><title>Spike in dolphin deaths at Huon Aquaculture pens prompts questions from Tasmanian regulator</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/huon-aquaculture-response-to-dolphin-deaths-salmon-pens/105991470</link><description>Tasmanian regulators question major salmon farm operator Huon Aquaculture about the effectiveness of its "predator" nets after a spate of dolphin deaths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d859cad498ca0936341476fc5e0e6629</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian renters wanting a pet just got new protections. Here's how to get approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/tasmanian-government-introduces-pets-in-rentals-legislation/104652212</link><description>Under the updated legislation, landlords now need a "reasonable" rationale to say no to a tenant having pets — and that reasonableness can only be decided by an independent tribunal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07c060cc59daba763377e7155d70b4f3</guid></item><item><title>Northern NSW growers welcome bumper grain harvest as south plagued by drought</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/northern-nsw-bumper-grain-harvest-south-drought/105999124</link><description>Growers at Walgett are grinning from ear to ear as they fill their silos with a bumper grain harvest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af1f7fe681297cd42d47b42f3400c3d1</guid></item><item><title>Growing evidence of secret taxpayer-funded boats for illegal foreign fishers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/fishing-boats-used-to-send-illegal-fishers-home/106005568</link><description>An Australian Border Force vessel has docked in Broome carrying four fishing boats, prompting anger from the fishing industry over a government scheme that gives illegal fishers boats to return home in.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b9163b8790e832a86acbd433652a510</guid></item><item><title>Cynthia Erivo praised for protecting co-star Ariana Grande from invader at Wicked event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/ariana-grande-ambushed-wicked-red-carpet-cynthia-erivo/106009192</link><description>Video shared across social media shows a man jumping over a crowd-control barrier, running towards Grande and putting his arms around the singer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3167ebaae671f22b74722c2b9c8e213</guid></item><item><title>A Great Act of Love by Heather Rose delves into her family's convict history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/heather-rose-new-book-a-great-act-of-love/106005806</link><description>In A Great Act of Love, the award-winning author interweaves a surprising chapter of Tasmanian history with the story of her ancestor who was transported to Van Diemen's Land in the 1800s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf87a42c95961b9dc560d58e6df29f33</guid></item><item><title>The other-worldly ecstasy of the Socceroos' penalty shootout against Uruguay, 20 years on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/socceroos-uruguay-world-cup-qualifier-20-year-anniversary/106010284</link><description>Nostalgia can be an intoxicating force, especially when it comes to the 20-year anniversary of the Socceroos' remarkable win over Uruguay on penalties, which remains an Australian cultural touchpoint.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47245075f2a8785886b932f62bc620e3</guid></item><item><title>Esperance community fights for more change, a decade on from deadly bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/deadly-esperance-fires-10-year-anniversary/106011936</link><description>A decade on from bushfires that claimed four lives, this community says not enough has been done to ensure they are safe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26fef5c10f539bb8ef24c281e054fc28</guid></item><item><title>China's seafood import rules behind a partial closure of Tasmania's rock lobster fishery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/tasmania-rock-lobster-fishery-antibiotic-florfenicol-salmon/106016448</link><description>The Tasmanian government closed two zones within the state's rock lobster fishery just hours after the commercial season opened. The closure is in response to concerns about an antibiotic being used by salmon companies and the rock lobster industry's reputation in overseas markets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b69359e0def6b5ab9dacf255531f62d1</guid></item><item><title>South African man who attended Neo-Nazi rally outside NSW parliament has visa cancelled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/verify-neo-nazi-rally-participant-visa-revoked/106018130</link><description>The federal government has revoked the visa of a man who attended the far-right National Socialist Network protest at NSW's parliament house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b76921ba7f888c119b8ec7bca1ab37b</guid></item><item><title>Queensland racing industry review delayed as government withholds landmark report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/queensland-racing-review-delayed-over-month/106007056</link><description>The report was supposed to be released in mid-October until an industry event was abruptly cancelled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f717b940c87cc4adf0af2cfe264a1f1</guid></item><item><title>Landowner concerned about site rehabilitation as Murray Zircon shuts operations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/murray-zircon-mine-closed-with-promise-to-rehabilitate/105973222</link><description>A mine in South Australia's Murray Mallee is ceasing operations and says it will rehabilitate the site back to its original condition. However, the site's owner says the land will never get back to what it was before mining.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d676c8d6d8249e35ac4a7caeead00ae9</guid></item><item><title>Category two cyclone predicted off NT coast by Thursday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/tropical-low-cyclone-nt-bureau-of-meteorology-/106023036</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology has issued its first forecast track map for a tropical low over the NT, showing the system is expected to strengthen into a category two cyclone by Thursday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a6c322a2a62ea9ae943397610bd552c</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of power poles wrapped in protective mesh ahead of 'what could be a dangerous bushfire summer'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/power-poles-wrapped-fire-resistant-mesh-bushfires/106015438</link><description>A fire-resistant mesh is being used to protect thousands of wooden power poles from bushfires across the NSW Central Coast and Hunter regions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20ee7810140cad6a6c4dbd4849a91ace</guid></item><item><title>'Little prospect of rate relief' following wages data release — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/asx-markets-business-live-news/106025882</link><description>ABS figures show that workers received an average base pay increase of 3.4 per cent over the year to September. Webjet shares soar after a takeover offer from rival Helloworld. Here's a look back on how the business day unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83fdeab36f891d1ab8b747278d6317f7</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos coach Tony Popovic fumes at penalty decision in 3-0 friendly loss to Colombia in New York</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/socceroos-vs-colombia-new-york-live-blog/106026972</link><description>Socceroos coach Tony Popovic laments a "disappointing" penalty decision as the Socceroos fall to a 3-0 loss to Colombia in New York.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7d3fc982270b2839d0e5643620424f0</guid></item><item><title>Through dust and drought, these women are redefining resilience</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/through-dust-and-drought-these-women-are-redefining-resilience/106024268</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15ec73793bc09515a28939cf16fbf8df</guid></item><item><title>FOI data shows Australian mining and manufacturing sectors take months to detect cyber breaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/delays-detecting-data-breaches-australian-mining-manufacturing/105978234</link><description>Australia's mining and manufacturing sectors are taking up to two years to notice and report cyber breaches to authorities, prompting concerns about the data security of industries critical to the nation's economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9e3c9e78e3c97ec12b11b398f2f9b97</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri tipped to fight back in F1 championship at Las Vegas Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/f1-las-vegas-oscar-piastri-mclaren-lando-norris/106030732</link><description>Oscar Piastri is backed to regain form in the final three races of the F1 championship, despite the Australian trailing teammate Lando Norris on the drivers' standings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75407edc2c2f29c4799c37caac473093</guid></item><item><title>Why celebrity scandals can leave us feeling shattered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/why-celebrity-scandals-can-leave-us-feeling-shattered/105991484</link><description>Whether it's controversy around a jeans ad, voting for a political party you disagree with, or criminal allegations, it can feel confronting to learn more about a person you admire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">203139f74d1c4e9da21f147451a6c068</guid></item><item><title>Queensland aquaculture company and CEO fined $300k for illegal barramundi farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/illegal-barramundi-farm-sentencing/106027364</link><description>The company was sentenced to pay the fine, with the chief executive also given a $60,000 penalty as well as payment of court costs for the environmental breach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bf7b3d8844c1a249582da7268be33a7</guid></item><item><title>Future of Liberty Bell Bay smelter in limbo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/future-of-liberty-bell-bay-smelter-in-limbo-/106034132</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e26fa7821d462f9b60f61c4df695892</guid></item><item><title>A helicopter conducts its first night-time water-bombing operation.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/first-night-time-water-bombing-operation/106031276</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e697744f70c5bf595d030845fc52efb9</guid></item><item><title>Boys' netball movement gains pace on Sunshine Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/sunshine-coast-all-boys-netball-competition/105867122</link><description>From regional Queensland to state level, boys' netball is gaining momentum and reshaping the future of the sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6163db43d0ecb3dc1cb9bd8e17a7ebb</guid></item><item><title>Zoe Terakes reclaims queer love in ancient Greek myths in debut short story collection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/zoe-terakes-book-eros-queer-myths-for-lovers/106017590</link><description>Zoe Terakes, star of Wentworth and Ironheart, has added another string to her bow, publishing a collection of short stories inspired by ancient tales — with a queer twist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80300b1df26488820c836bd47909c683</guid></item><item><title>Martu rangers capture rare night parrot in WA's Pilbara region.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/martu-rangers-capture-rare-night-parrot-in-wa-s-pilbara-region/106034066</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b21800156c4a741b9f8c24db2648fa27</guid></item><item><title>F1 Las Vegas Grand Prix: Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris disqualified, Max Verstappen wins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/f1-las-vegas-grand-prix-oscar-piastri-lando-norris-disqualified/105995102</link><description>Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris have both been disqualified from the Las Vegas Grand Prix, in a stunning post-race moment that has blown the battle for the Formula 1 drivers' championship wide open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6fd104ffb99297d627f46331c85d527</guid></item><item><title>Calls to end water extraction from Great Artesian Basin before culturally significant springs are lost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/calls-for-end-to-water-extraction-at-great-artesian-basin/106038490</link><description>Environmentalists are calling for mining giant BHP to end its water extraction from the Great Artesian Basin when a major desalination plant is built in South Australia's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fca6049feefb20e454a9a71cee3b252</guid></item><item><title>What did McLaren do wrong to get Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris disqualified from the Las Vegas F1 Grand Prix?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/what-did-mclaren-do-wrong-at-the-las-vegas-f1-grand-prix/106043812</link><description>McLaren apologises to Norris and Piastri as F1 officials explain why the drivers were disqualified in Las Vegas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2671ab4d067425eab2cc4bd22461f6b1</guid></item><item><title>ElecraNet to explore alternative options for Northern Transmission Project after farmers voice concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/northern-transmission-line-moved-from-south-australia-mid-north/106045600</link><description>ElectraNet are shifting their focus east, after farmers voiced concerns about renewable energy line Northern Transmission Project running through prime cropping country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87bbcecad36ba980df103634b30e7276</guid></item><item><title>Federal government backtracks on reducing default speed limits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/reduction-of-default-speed-limits-not-on-the-cards/106052562</link><description>The truck industry has welcomed a federal government decision to walk away from lowering speeds on unsigned roads, but road safety experts question the move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">778c0df6e1eac2b5554359ccb168fabc</guid></item><item><title>APY Lands community members disappointed after delay into hearing on governance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/apy-lands-governance-hearing-delayed-indefinitely/106049734</link><description>Anangu Pitjantjatjara Yankunytjatjara (APY) Lands community members have been left disappointed by a last-minute decision to halt a hearing that was set to probe governance issues in the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79e0944f7b835eaf79a7ec71fd278eeb</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners travel to Darwin as fight over aquifer reaches NT Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/nt-court-challenge-mataranka-water-allocation-plan-river/106049348</link><description>Dozens of Aboriginal Territorians from remote communities travelled to Darwin where they stand alongside Environment Centre NT in a bid to axe a controversial water allocation plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcfc162e595d6f9121ad6715fd34d9f2</guid></item><item><title>Invasive Species Council blames government for booming rabbit numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/rabbit-boom-invasive-species-council-blames-government/106050286</link><description>Landholders across Australia say rabbit numbers in some areas are at levels never seen before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">668c4b4bff68a95a2912ec002f5026a8</guid></item><item><title>US National Parks to raise fees for millions of international tourists to popular sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/us-national-parks-raise-fees-for-international-tourists/106057350</link><description>Changes set to take effect on January 1 will include annual park passes jumping to $US250 for foreign tourists, while US residents will continue to be charged $US80, according to authorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6544a5e86aab374c3adc52c6f8f28473</guid></item><item><title>London Broncos rugby league hopes buoyed by Brisbane icon Darren Lockyer and players from PNG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/london-broncos-rugby-league-hopes-buoyed-by-brisbane-icon-darren/106054530</link><description>The London Broncos might be the only rugby league club in Britain to have experienced relegation before a season even began — and Darren Lockyer, through the help of PNG Players, is hoping to bring them back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adb18a1d230194d5cd653be6a57035e1</guid></item><item><title>Department of Transport and Main Roads orders shutdown of North Ipswich Free Shop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/tmr-orders-shutdown-of-unauthorised-street-charity/106056444</link><description>Queensland's transport department has threatened to penalise residents who set up street-side charity cupboards without filling in the requisite paperwork.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5f68b265064320596ea9b346d00604d</guid></item><item><title>Varroa mite detected in bee hives at Sellicks Hill and Taratap</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/varroa-mite-detected-at-sellicks-hill-and-taratap/106057922</link><description>Beekeepers are being urged to monitor their hives more frequently after further detections of the deadly bee parasite varroa mite in South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7eb6178921afeda19d18f99d63e45b70</guid></item><item><title>Victoria faces risky summer with bushfire potential fuelled by spring grass growth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/summer-fire-outlook-puts-victoria-at-high-bushfire-risk/105904142</link><description>Dry conditions dogging Victoria put the state at a high risk of bushfires this summer, according to the latest summer fire outlook.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cf73f58347b048623fa0fcf358ee844</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri dismisses helping McLaren teammate Lando Norris win F1 drivers' championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/oscar-piastri-will-not-help-lando-norris-win-f1-title-in-qatar/106076210</link><description>Oscar Piastri says McLaren raised the prospect of the Australian helping his teammate Lando Norris win the Formula 1 world championship, but it was rejected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3ec980521382ffb12e9d33768384b86</guid></item><item><title>US futures markets halted as CME data centre overheats — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-28-november/106074700</link><description>Derivates trading operator CME Group says trading in its markets has been halted due to a cooling issue at data centres. Global financial markets watch futures closely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ae0c62e2e60633eaddc29868f23f37f</guid></item><item><title>Jane Edmanson hangs up her Gardening Australia hat, reflects on labour of love behind show's success</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/jane-edmanson-gardening-australia-retires/106027658</link><description>As Gardening Australia's longest-serving presenter, Jane Edmanson says farewell and shares the secrets behind the success of Australia’s favourite gardening program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">281e322ce0bc8aaface52c810fbad18a</guid></item><item><title>Kyra Cooney-Cross scores stunning long range goal as Matildas down New Zealand 5-0</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/kyra-cooney-cross-goal-matildas-defeat-new-zealand/106074508</link><description>A spectacular long range effort from Kyra Cooney-Cross has helped the Matildas to a dominant 5-0 win over New Zealand in Australia's penultimate game before hosting the Asian Cup in March.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ed492f5f89ed6ab1feddf18b1b73bf8</guid></item><item><title>Wala Kooral-bi juvenile justice facility opens in northern WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/wala-kooral-bi-juvenile-justice-facility-opens-in-northern-wa/106057316</link><description>An on-country youth diversion facility has been built in the state's far north, offering a culturally grounded alternative to traditional youth justice programs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">142d8035e60293b2bfd4ea512b3d855f</guid></item><item><title>Albanese knows the power dynamic between Labor and mining interests has shifted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/anthony-albanese-mining-labor-greens-deal-environment/106045658</link><description>There has been a shift in the power dynamic between Labor and the mining industry. This week's environmental law reform is its embodiment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f47fba9a6d450b1c3228007e52bf0c6</guid></item><item><title>Think you're ready to own a home? Here are the costs that experts want you to consider</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/the-up-front-and-ongoing-costs-of-home-ownership/105984188</link><description>We asked three financial experts about the up-front and ongoing costs of buying a home and for their tips on how to prepare for home ownership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a044e362104441aa527db1d121dcea86</guid></item><item><title>Cricket Australia set to speak with Usman Khawaja after he labelled Perth Ashes Test pitch a 'piece of shit'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/usman-khawaja-pillories-perth-ashes-test-pitch/106081416</link><description>Usman Khawaja may face a sanction for labelling the first Ashes Test surface a "piece of shit", with Cricket Australia understood to be disappointed by the remarks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62c5c47efcba08e3a71df02e352a8f9e</guid></item><item><title>After suffering 'terrifying' postpartum rage, this mother wants others to know they're not alone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/mother-comes-to-terms-with-terrifying-postpartum-rage/106072456</link><description>When Ali Gossage gave birth a second time, she did not experience the constant joys of motherhood. Instead, she was sometimes filled with "terrifying" anger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d749279af4a3906951170031a067264</guid></item><item><title>The spooky First Nations movie you need to see at BIFF</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/it-will-find-you-brisbane-international-film-festival/106074274</link><description>First Nations stories are combined with modern horror scares in this new film from Australian creatives Chris Broadbent and Enzo Tedeschi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b235169fa73d8695e28eb94f33cc4ba4</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri wins Qatar F1 sprint race, qualifies fastest for GP, edging closer to Lando Norris in standings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/oscar-piastri-wins-qatar-sprint-race-pole-position-grand-prix/106082990</link><description>Australian driver Oscar Piastri is doing everything he can to catch McLaren teammate Lando Norris in the world championship race, winning the sprint race and qualifying in pole position for the Qatar Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91fb4a7e45b5fd7c127dde77f8c1f27a</guid></item><item><title>Labor should theoretically be confident ahead of the 2026 Victorian election — but challenges are mounting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/labor-liberal-victorian-state-election/106074182</link><description>On paper, Labor should be confident that it will score an unprecedented fourth term in office when Victorian voters go to the ballot box in a year's time, with the Liberal opposition still scrambling to present as an electable alternative.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3a467f756b8d054f7af57490a3defae</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia flood death toll climbs amid cyclone devastation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/indonesia-flood-death-toll-climbs-amid-cyclone-devastation/106083102</link><description>Torrential rain causes flash floods and landslides in Indonesia, where the toll rises as authorities mount rescue operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a7d38c9d0ca4ec2f45b4cce22c32dae</guid></item><item><title>LNP's Wayde Chiesa promises to get to work after victory in Hinchinbrook by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/lnp-wayde-chiesa-wins-hinchinbrook-by-election/106074692</link><description>The LNP's Wayde Chiesa will be the next representative for the Queensland seat of Hinchinbrook, which had been safely held by Katter's Australian Party since 2017.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">316d56db0aad14eb566c92220ddfecdb</guid></item><item><title>Photographer Lyn Alcock captures wild antics of Dryandra's numbat population over 20 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/dryandra-numbat-antics-photographer/106051162</link><description>Lyn Alcock is known as the 'Numbat whisperer', spending hours every day observing and photographing the tiny, endangered marsupials, recording behaviours that have never been seen before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50f2d4bc8d830154bacd7c73f39c8ce2</guid></item><item><title>Hinchinbrook by-election a tick of approval for LNP government but no crystal ball for outcome of next election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/qld-hinchinbrook-analysis-win-for-lnp-but-no-crystal-ball/106083638</link><description>A week is a long time in politics, let alone three years, and the LNP's success at the next election is by no means assured, writes Jack McKay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa5569c66ea70291d591041c2aae0c67</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Travis Head prepared to play any role in day-night Ashes Test against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/ashes-second-test-australia-england-travis-head/106085110</link><description>Travis Head says he has no qualms if he is shifted back down Australia's batting order following his exploits as an opener in the first Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e36579986c8f33bf873c39e73ac34573</guid></item><item><title>F1 standings: Lando Norris, Max Verstappen, Oscar Piastri set for Abu Dhabi decider after Qatar GP</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/f1-standings-lando-norris-max-verstappen-oscar-piastri/106085058</link><description>Oscar Piastri's hopes of winning the F1 title suffered a hammer blow after McLaren's strategy error in Qatar, but there is still hope. Here's how the Aussie can upset the odds in Abu Dhabi's decider.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a4463704d85f1accca0c659dbe24ccd</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Island's last dog embraced by the remote community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/last-dog-on-christmas-island-shiloh/105722366</link><description>Dogs were banned some years ago to protect the unique wildlife of Christmas Island, but one very special chocolate Labrador remains, and she is shared by the whole community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed4a79fb8808d98d72d90b95f6cfe390</guid></item><item><title>Geraldton bushfire destroys one home as up to 200 firefighters worked to control blaze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/wa-bushfire-emergency-second-day-as-geraldton-homes-threatened/106085396</link><description>Authorities have downgraded their warning levels for bushfires burning in the greater Geraldton area to an 'advice' level after a challenging day for firefighters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d3515fd97db7af71f664858e3914f5e</guid></item><item><title>Pablo Escobar's final mistake and the lonely death of the cocaine king</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/today-in-history-december-2-pablo-escobar-death/105966258</link><description>More than three decades since his death in a rooftop shootout with police, the legacy of cocaine king Pablo Escobar continues to affect Colombia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14d48ef3caf2128f49fc1e97d31fba61</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanians express mix of views ahead of final Macquarie Point stadium vote</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/hobart-stadium-weighing-on-minds-of-community-before-vote/106085678</link><description>By the end of this week, Tasmania will know whether or not Hobart will have a new AFL stadium. Many Tasmanians are still making up their own minds about whether they support it or not.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6296ba9abc412578f7570cc2fbe9b3b</guid></item><item><title>Maps reveal the Ukraine regions Vladimir Putin does not hold, but wants anyway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/trump-concept-for-ukraine-in-maps-as-putin-negotiations-continue/106046750</link><description>Donald Trump is expected to send his special envoy Steven Witkoff to Moscow this week to talk about a revised proposal for peace in Ukraine. There are five regions central to negotiations and Vladimir Putin wants them all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a12224be088e27d1b0d33dcaebf31199</guid></item><item><title>Two men first in SA to be found guilty of charges arising from encrypted devices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/sa-ironside-trials-guilty/106082150</link><description>Two South Australian men are the first in the state to be found guilty after standing trial for charges arising from the major police operation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa71e1612601917501fab0b6b74d6a3d</guid></item><item><title>As teacher shortages loom across Australia these Queensland schools are trialling solutions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/teacher-shortage-nearing-crisis-point-solutions/106026086</link><description>As staff shortages "near crisis point", these Queensland schools are going to extraordinary lengths to put teachers in classrooms — and keep them there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a577430673addb35fb00c86c4dd4f38</guid></item><item><title>South Australian farmers fear future as bird flu recovery causes egg oversupply</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/egg-shortage-becomes-egg-oversupply-bird-flu-recovery-sa/105964496</link><description>The industry was plagued by bird flu 12 months ago, but some producers are now struggling to sell their product due to a faster-than-expected recovery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0349b4f56e5ca56ffe4f70096bf07b8</guid></item><item><title>ASX edges higher, Bitcoin dives, government releases its National AI Plan - as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/asx-markets-business-live-news-dec-2/106089726</link><description>The ASX edged higher, while the federal government released its National AI Plan. Catch up on the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70caa11f82424eaa331f775c02e71740</guid></item><item><title>Red Bull admits fault over 'clearly incorrect' suggestion Kimi Antonelli allowed Lando Norris to overtake him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/red-bull-regret-engineer-call-antonelli-norris-qatar-drama/106090182</link><description>Red Bull retracts suggestions made by its engineer that Mercedes driver Kimi Antonelli deliberately let Lando Norris overtake him at the Qatar Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00502f29db037f266ada98fa8be30d4d</guid></item><item><title>South Coast fishermen charged over alleged deliberate scuttling of trawler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/ulladulla-fishing-boat-allegedly-scuttled-charges-nowra-court/106083924</link><description>Two Ulladulla fishermen have been charged under federal sea-dumping laws over the alleged deliberate sinking of an unseaworthy trawler.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0a5c1a67746fd7f4305f5156800d9bc</guid></item><item><title>Folk Rhythm and Life Festival cancelled at last minute due to permit problems</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/folk-rhythm-life-festival-cancelled-eldorado-wangaratta-permit/106090234</link><description>A festival that has been running for 30 years has been cancelled just days before it was due to begin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10af3cae58b8cfb757e9f098d612a3ad</guid></item><item><title>Elderly woman allegedly assaulted in 'unprovoked and isolated' incident at South Plympton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/adelaide-elderly-woman-seriously-injured-in-alleged-assault/106091210</link><description>Police say members of the public helped the 84-year-old woman after the alleged attack before she was taken to hospital with serious injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4a7a50ac567e2f3e5e3a498ea8aa17e</guid></item><item><title>Spear fisher accused of killing protected blue groper on NSW Central Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/speared-fisher-accused-of-killing-protected-blue-groper/106090448</link><description>Investigations are underway into the death of the near-threatened species on the NSW Central Coast, prompting calls for better awareness about local marine life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abee347f53e8f595e204e3e3b3328f24</guid></item><item><title>Fugitive prisoner who evaded police for months charged after dramatic Alice Springs arrest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/nt-police-arrest-absconded-prisoner-after-alice-springs-escape/106090820</link><description>An absconded prisoner has been charged with 15 offences, including strangulation and making threats to kill, after escaping police custody and evading capture for more than 70 days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b2822ebe8180da093d307d8199c2ad2</guid></item><item><title>Queensland man Brett Daniel Taylor charged with assisted suicides of three people granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/brett-daniel-taylor-bail-assisted-suicide-court/106090558</link><description>A Queensland man charged with assisting the suicides of three people has successfully applied for bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9de1a9d49535ff563cb453ead91630b</guid></item><item><title>England trio Ben Stokes, Mark Wood and Jamie Smith spotted riding e-scooters without helmets in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/ben-stokes-mark-wood-e-scooter-helmet-ashes-brisbane/106093396</link><description>England captain Ben Stokes and several teammates have been spotted in Brisbane riding e-scooters without helmets ahead of the second Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e531e16cc6680cfd8f1ac1f9e02d56a6</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja ruled out of Brisbane Test following back injury, Travis Head set to open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/usman-khawaja-ruled-out-of-second-ashes-test/106093584</link><description>Australia will be without veteran opener Usman Khawaja for the second Ashes Test after the 38-year old was ruled out due to an ongoing back problem.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a1c846f0714bb58803e3567a30b23ba</guid></item><item><title>Review into incident at Tasmania's Ashley Youth Detention Centre of makeshift spit hood on detainee's head tabled in parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/tasmania-custodial-inspector-recommends-ban-on-spit-hoods/106090220</link><description>An incident at a Tasmanian youth detention centre where a detainee had an improvised spit hood put over his head while being transported by a contracted security company, has been criticised for being "entirely incompatible" with human rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2930eeea5ee343dce324f64c2de4ea7f</guid></item><item><title>Six prisoners remain in NT watch houses after report exposes 'inhumane' conditions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/nt-reducing-police-watch-house-reliance-custody-prison-overflow/106091946</link><description>Days after acting Northern Territory Ombudsman Bronwyn Haack raised the alarm about "inhumane" conditions in overcrowded police cells, the government says just six inmates remain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb6a12cde9c3df46f3586a607866826f</guid></item><item><title>Lemon8 and Yope put on notice as social media age ban targets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/lemon8-and-yope-put-on-notice-for-social-media-ban-targets/106093818</link><description>Social media platforms Lemon8 and Yope are put on notice about age limit laws as both apps surge in popularity ahead of a ban for under 16s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73e181c24f76aa7aec06bc066c4de932</guid></item><item><title>Indian government demands Sanchar Saathi app be pre-installed on Apple, Android and Xiaomi mobile phones</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/indian-government-demands-sanchar-saathi-app-installed-on-phones/106094470</link><description>New Delhi wants a government app installed on all of the country's mobile phones, but opposition MPs and privacy advocates have voiced concerns about surveillance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24946ea2cf9e95f66ff4a1ccb172d905</guid></item><item><title>Environment Protection Authority to monitor Ballarat Gold Mine amid air pollution concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/epa-to-install-air-monitoring-around-ballarat-goldmine/106085894</link><description>Ballarat Gold Mine has exceeded national standards for potentially dangerous air pollutants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00ab53f890c0252369ba784309b97b47</guid></item><item><title>Australia's longest-running radio show celebrates 80 years of rural storytelling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/abc-rural-the-country-hour-turns-80/106008860</link><description>Australia's longest-running radio show is celebrating 80 years on air, and while so much has changed in farming and broadcasting, the core of The Country Hour remains the same.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">713100469aff078bfb490ca63c33fd3f</guid></item><item><title>Three Paralympians talk about how disability altered their lives in documentary Changing Track</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/changing-track-idpwd-paralympians/106090210</link><description>Filmmaking siblings Tristan and Timothy Kenyon's documentary Changing Track explores how competing in the Paralympics changes lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43ae5e96f57cf6d122c59b4f78dcb7dd</guid></item><item><title>England cricketing great Robin Smith dies in Perth aged 62</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/england-cricket-great-robin-smith-dies-in-perth/106094634</link><description>The cricket world mourns after the death of English batting great Robin Smith in his Perth home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc56dcf45199549bd187a16fffc8064c</guid></item><item><title>Pete Hegseth defends second US strike on alleged Venezuelan drug boat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/pete-hegseth-defends-follow-up-strike-on-venezuela-boat/106094652</link><description>US Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth defends authorising a follow-up strike on a Venezuelan boat that killed 11 people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">105acb8c8ce95ccb1914f4455bb42adb</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106093212</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fc874191084064899dfd7859568b83d</guid></item><item><title>Sabrina Carpenter slams White House for using her music in ICE video</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/sabrina-carpenter-slams-white-house-donald-trump-for-using-music/106094936</link><description>Two-time Grammy winner Sabrina Carpenter slams the White House for using her song in a social media post about ICE raids, telling the Trump administration to never involve her in its "inhumane agenda".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8f7bdbb2cd0918ab4dc555b58041df2</guid></item><item><title>Victorian government relaxes car parking rules around well-connected residential developments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/allan-government-relaxes-car-parking-rules-homes-transport-links/106095118</link><description>The Victorian government vows to overhaul "outdated" car parking requirements for new residential developments in areas that are well-serviced by public transport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbd853c1855a14f011ecbb83f424873f</guid></item><item><title>Stadium minister Eric Abetz holds press conference with CFMEU</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/eric-abetz-hold-press-conference-with-cfmeu/106095626</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6462c1538a7fa6fc38b2422320a0eb8</guid></item><item><title>Hopes remain for return of eagles to relocated nest at Bundaberg Hospital site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/wedge-tailed-eagle-nest-relocation-bundaberg-hospital/106091190</link><description>A wedge-tailed eagle's nest was moved in an operation costing about $100,000 involving a 60-tonne crane, a specialist arborist and a carefully engineered basket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44f4ee129a4a56a8978a10e15f65edcf</guid></item><item><title>Peter Scammell charged with murder, extradited over 2020 death of nurse Katrina Hawker in Palmerston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/peter-scammell-charged-with-murder-over-katrina-hawker-death/106095606</link><description>A 44-year-old man has been charged with murder over the death of his partner near Darwin, and has been extradited from Victoria ahead of his first appearance in the Darwin Local Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5c7039d078e6825087f1be22888c869</guid></item><item><title>Demersal fishing ban announced for commercial, recreational fishers in Perth and WA amid scarce fish stocks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/perth-wa-strict-fishing-ban-commercial-recreational-fishers/106095814</link><description>Strict bans limiting commercial and recreational fishing in Perth and WA are announced in an effort to save some under-threat fish species from the brink of collapse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e453fcaba88e452b2844efd665762060</guid></item><item><title>Hugh Jackman and Kate Hudson surprise patrons with impromptu performance at Aussie pub in NYC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/hugh-jackman-kate-hudson-old-mates-pub-sweet-caroline/106095716</link><description>Hugh Jackman sung the crowd-pleaser Sweet Caroline and even climbed onto the top of the bar counter for the performance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b533f89ca790e766808a38268893eac8</guid></item><item><title>What time does the Gabba Test start? How to watch the Ashes, and Brisbane weather forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/ashes-2025-what-time-does-the-gabba-test-start/106095876</link><description>The second Ashes Test is upon us and we have fingers crossed it will last more than two days. Here's everything you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5877ff31536d915fc1044634dafee1f7</guid></item><item><title>What happened to Lisa Lynn? The untold story of Greg Lynn's first marriage and his wife's sudden death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/unravel-huntsman-what-happened-to-lisa-lynn/104591040</link><description>Long before Greg Lynn was convicted of murder in Victoria's High Country, his estranged wife died suddenly at home in Mount Macedon. Now, some of those closest to Lisa Lynn are pushing for the coroner to re-examine her death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d05853d821bab6cebb3660faa1636d5</guid></item><item><title>Government considers offloading retiring Tiger helicopters to Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/government-considers-tiger-helicopters-to-ukraine/106097120</link><description>As the United States attempts to broker a peace deal at the Kremlin in Moscow, it is expected a significant funding boost from Canberra to aid Ukraine's war efforts is imminent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d5df644b3bb02e84a4c678130b237d</guid></item><item><title>How to prepare yourself and your child for the social media ban on December 10</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/social-media-ban-pocket-guide-december-10/105938784</link><description>From December 10, young people will lose access to part of their online world. Here's how to support them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">778f718b5f3382e1a2ff7745675b7836</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's local and state governments to pay $650,000 for Foo Fighters concert in Launceston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/tas-to-pay-650000-for-foo-fighters-concert-in-launceston/106096094</link><description>Tasmania's "biggest concert ever" will take place at Launceston's York Park next month when American rock band Foo Fighters play their only Australian show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf968a5fd5a8aa81d76d97a55f862ebd</guid></item><item><title>Man killed, two others injured in northern NSW shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/northern-nsw-shooting-two-hospital-police/106098328</link><description>A man has died and two others injured following a shooting on a property in Murwillumbah in northern NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51ab5f45097fc9549a966da49bd3d843</guid></item><item><title>First community-designed, culture-led home from new outback housing initiative arrives in Tennant Creek</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/tennant-creek-first-wilya-janta-culture-led-homes-arrives/106090624</link><description>A one-of-a-kind home, designed with the input of Tennant Creek families, has rolled up the Stuart Highway from Adelaide on a convoy of trucks. It is part of a new initiative aiming to transform housing in remote First Nations communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1245d00b9a5564e52777b7a81c103d3</guid></item><item><title>Jodie Hill denies involvement in alleged murder of 72-year-old Dimboola man John Hunter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/jodie-hill-dimboola-murder-supreme-court-crime/106097744</link><description>A woman on trial for the alleged murder of 72-year-old Victorian man John Hunter tells the Supreme Court she was present when he was attacked but another person was responsible for his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eef245144a5b7185d3fbcd25811e3cbf</guid></item><item><title>New police investigation into Lisa Lynn’s death stalls over bill for expert report, family says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/new-lisa-lynn-police-investigation-stalls-over-expert-report/106089854</link><description>The family of the late first wife of High Country killer Greg Lynn says a fresh investigation into her death has stalled because police will not pay for an expert report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fa2d52decd1defbb0eb923844e95973</guid></item><item><title>One player's case against the world's biggest crypto casino</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/case-against-the-worlds-biggest-crypto-casino-stake-vip-host/105884760</link><description>Chat logs and gambling data show the tactics used by Australian-run online casino Stake to keep one user hooked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e509f307e4a257bfe74d3a546597ee94</guid></item><item><title>Tens of thousands of cars damaged after hailstorms lash Queensland and parts of New South Wales</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/hail-damage-to-cars-what-to-do/106097274</link><description>Insurers are urging those with damaged cars to make their claims as soon as possible in the aftermath of hailstorms across Queensland and parts of New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebffad31eb3a4275196f679fa6e0faf8</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith says adaptability is Australia's focus heading into the second Ashes Test at the Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/steve-smith-on-adaptability-heading-into-second-ashes-test/106099612</link><description>Steve Smith reveals the mindset Australia is taking into the second Test as the Aussies look to go up 2–0 in the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10898752092de46072fa6e796c3eda38</guid></item><item><title>Risk of 'imminent' RBA rate hike rising, as Australian dollar moves above 66 US cents — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-december-4/106099782</link><description>A leading economist says the "risk" of an "imminent" RBA interest rate hike is "rising", while former treasurer Peter Costello is urging Australia to arrest its fertility downturn.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b017f58b6f90dbd3804789d973fb3d6a</guid></item><item><title>Increasing wait times for mammograms could have 'potentially tragic' consequences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/up-to-nine-month-wait-for-diagnostic-mammograms/106092334</link><description>A Medicare funding freeze and high cost of training new students has left a shortage of workers and blown out wait times of critical diagnostic services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">010130b4e8ae7c75d997cc1a3237e030</guid></item><item><title>Former NT administrator, musician and author Ted Egan dies aged 93</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/ted-egan-former-nt-administrator-musician-dies-aged-93/106100878</link><description>Folk music legend, author and former Northern Territory administrator Ted Egan has died aged 93.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6daba67379b08c7ea64857ac472194c</guid></item><item><title>Descendent emotional to see WWI digger in unmarked grave receive recognition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/students-uncover-legacy-of-lost-world-war-i-veterans/106095386</link><description>South Australian high school students have helped to uncover the legacies of five war veterans who were laid to rest in unmarked graves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bccf814e8044742cf11301d47e6cc4d</guid></item><item><title>Anti-bullying review recommends making kids 'upstanders'. Does it work?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/upstanders-bullying-schools-research-jason-clare/106088358</link><description>Research suggests that actively encouraging students to be 'upstanders' to bullying may even be counterproductive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46c591942c7744cdc3303a13a113f9f0</guid></item><item><title>SA CFS volunteer sentenced for intentionally starting bushfire near Naracoorte</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/cfs-volunteer-sentenced-for-starting-naracoorte-bushfire/105665876</link><description>An 18-year-old who had been a cadet captain in the Country Fire Service admits deliberately lighting a bushfire near Naracoorte, but mental health conditions lower the sentence he might otherwise have been given.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87abb35d9a810672d5e9e1e2e928fefc</guid></item><item><title>Cost of living remains a sore point for voters as political year wraps</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/anthony-albanese-election-coalition-cost-of-living-anika-wells/106087960</link><description>A mammoth year in politics ended with a focus on what is worrying most Australians ahead of Christmas: the cost of living.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3d580f2783d85343577bf467e6eefd8</guid></item><item><title>Woman dies after dog attack in South Australia's upper Spencer Gulf</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/sa-woman-dies-after-dog-attack-in-whyalla/106103542</link><description>South Australian police say a woman has died after a dog attack at Whyalla in South Australia's upper Spencer Gulf region this afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e53a20862d35b0a6d3d300bb875fefa2</guid></item><item><title>Israel to compete at Eurovision Song Contest in 2026, prompting several nations to withdraw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/israel-allowed-to-compete-at-eurovision-2026-prompting-boyott/106104460</link><description>Public broadcasters in Spain, Ireland and the Netherlands say they will not participate in next year's event and more are expected to follow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58b2f0f1f947dfe1f049f7fcb63a55d2</guid></item><item><title>AUKUS will survive Trump, says Australia's top diplomat in London Stephen Smith</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/steven-smith-prepares-to-leave-london-after-three-years/106103968</link><description>The trilateral agreement has come under significant scrutiny, but Australia's top diplomat in London says he believes its future is assured.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87cc7c62361d5c820c9adee8662b5b2e</guid></item><item><title>Community housing provider HousingFirst defends dual rent rises on newly acquired properties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/housing-first-defends-dual-rent-rises-glenloch-properties/106044734</link><description>Elderly residents in Melbourne's south-east say they are in financial distress after two rent increases, which a community housing organisation says are a necessary move to a standard rent-setting model.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a5a283809f77682fb5ea37a5ebb7b00</guid></item><item><title>The best new TV shows of 2025, from The Golden Bachelor to The Studio</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/best-tv-shows-2025-golden-bachelor-the-studio-wayward/106074292</link><description>From a send-up of Hollywood studios to a chilling depiction of violence and masculinity to an age-appropriate reality TV romance, these are our favourite TV shows of 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e2b633a744ea39e8ec6696aeeafa789</guid></item><item><title>Education leaders call on News Corp to cease 'harmful' NAPLAN league tables</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/news-corp-naplan-league-tables-education-leaders-open-letter/106100742</link><description>Forty-one signatories to an open letter say they are "dismayed" and that school rankings cause "harm to our communities".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f660e6e3c573e8ed48a796fd1326d637</guid></item><item><title>A blend of Cool Runnings, Eddie the Eagle: The Filipino curling team on the cusp of an Olympic spot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/phillippines-curling-team-channel-cool-runnings/105880680</link><description>The idea of the Philippines curling team reaching the Winter Olympics has a hint of Cool Runnings about it, while one team member, Alan Frei, has more than a suggestion of Eddie the Eagle. But at the heart of this story is a genuine sporting fairytale that is one step away from becoming an Olympic legend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8897aa2cdb4d9d98c2d32748ef874a0</guid></item><item><title>The cold supermoon will appear in the night sky tonight. Here's how to spot it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/how-to-see-the-cold-supermoon/106101342</link><description>The final supermoon of the year is set to delight stargazers tonight. Here's how to spot it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe06bd21c7eb1cda6c5df6a7292c0667</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: Australia to manufacture multiple-rocket guided missiles at new factory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/federal-politics-live-dec-5/106104506</link><description>Australia will begin manufacturing multiple-rocket guided missiles this month with the opening of a new factory in South Australia. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95ca25021247df75ee5430b1c072b2b2</guid></item><item><title>South Australian golf course wetland is breeding site for locally extinct tiny native olive perchlet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/sa-golf-course-wetland-used-as-breeding-site-for-olive-perchlet/106102092</link><description>Golf courses around the world feature picturesque water ponds as a challenging hazard for players to avoid, but scientists are diving right in. They say golf club wetlands are an ecological safe haven to repopulate threatened native fish.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ee1f1543bd846b93c0d7845f74d1acc</guid></item><item><title>Markets live updates: ChatGPT's owner OpenAI launches in Australia, partners with NextDC, ASX slips</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/asx-markets-business-live-news-dec-5-2025/106104580</link><description>The company that brought AI into household vernacular is launching in Australia today. It comes as other companies like Meta are struggling to make traction in this space. Follow the day's events and insights as they happen with our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97ffbb609f0db052123663cd504a92ec</guid></item><item><title>Compressed air energy storage is coming to Broken Hill, but how does it work?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/compressed-air-energy-storage-explainer/105999452</link><description>Broken Hill will be the location of Australia's first large-scale compressed air energy storage system. What is it and how does it work?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0efc28edd209486ddfa4f2a24046a67e</guid></item><item><title>Pentagon's AUKUS review finds areas to put nuclear submarine pact on 'strongest possible footing'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/aukus-review-pentagon-donald-trump-administration/105588512</link><description>The review has "identified opportunities to put AUKUS on the strongest possible footing", the Pentagon says. But a congressman who has seen the report says it "fully endorses" the pact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b23bce599e6ebbcf46142e953f6505eb</guid></item><item><title>F1 title contender Oscar Piastri non-committal about helping Lando Norris win in Abu Dhabi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/oscar-piastri-and-lando-norris-in-abu-dhabi-grand-prix/106104724</link><description>Oscar Piastri dodges the question of whether he might help Lando Norris lift the world F1 title in Abu Dhabi, saying McLaren has not discussed the issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7501564d8239c082852e90c9916d0fe5</guid></item><item><title>Police officer's claim about search for Lindy Lucena in Ballina tested at watchdog hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/officers-claim-about-search-for-lindy-lucena-tested-by-watchdog/106099230</link><description>A Law Enforcement Conduct Commission is examining why it took police officers nearly an hour to respond to a Triple Zero (000) call about an assault which left Lindy Lucena dead at the hands of her partner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbaff3f6e13e94a6fadefcaba28c5d4b</guid></item><item><title>Housing crisis taking a toll on caravan park owners in WA's South West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/housing-crisis-has-impact-on-caravan-parks/106051650</link><description>The housing crisis is landing at the doorstep of caravan parks and owners like Greg Homer, who says the transition from tourism operator to landlord is taking a toll.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">560e4eeca6970f98d3ab29cb9688aa64</guid></item><item><title>Zak Crawley says Nathan Lyon being dropped for second Ashes Test helped him find rhythm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ashes-2025-zak-crawley-on-nathan-lyon-being-dropped/106104822</link><description>Nathan Lyon speaks during an awkward TV interview as Zak Crawley says the spinner's omission helped the English batter find his rhythm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b8bb53a79743035f3a5a726208ac768</guid></item><item><title>Ed Craven's VIP gamblers club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ed-craven-vip-gamblers-club-stake-messages/106028000</link><description>Leaked messages between an Australian multi-billionaire and his former associate reveal the inner workings of the online casino Stake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3cdd1980153499e59e25072593fa403</guid></item><item><title>Australian red-tipped bananas go viral as social media interest ramps up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/red-tipped-ecoganic-bananas-go-viral-on-social-media/106102526</link><description>Red-tipped bananas are not new to Australian consumers, but they have gone viral on social media this month after an inquisitive post from two bewildered British backpackers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96a1afa6a1c4a4e11aa62494a6c30ebb</guid></item><item><title>Socceroo Aziz Behich excited that World Cup draw could set up rematch with Argentina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/world-cup-socceroos-and-argentina-possible-draw-and-rematch/106104608</link><description>The Socceroos cannot wait to learn who their opponents will be at the upcoming World Cup, especially if it allows them to handle some unfinished business.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">379271a3ecdcd1a5d66aca938f390eb9</guid></item><item><title>US military says it killed four men in strike on suspected drug vessel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/us-military-kill-four-in-suspected-drug-boat-strike/106105538</link><description>The US military says it has killed four men in a strike on a suspected drug vessel in international waters in the Eastern Pacific</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbdd6dd3db4413394fc38b227e838592</guid></item><item><title>Live: Fires, heatwaves strike across Australia with extreme warnings issued</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/heatwaves-fires-live-blog-december-5/106105352</link><description>A broad heatwave is expected to spread across Australia, with short and sharp bursts of heat throughout the southern states. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8394bee0a73b0d19791eaed9f5db0d97</guid></item></channel></rss>