<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 07:38:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Linda Reynolds launches bankruptcy proceedings against Brittany Higgins after defamation win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/brittany-higgins-faces-bankruptcy-proceedings-linda-reynolds/105887676</link><description>Former senator Linda Reynolds files a creditor's petition in the Federal Court against her ex-staffer, Brittany Higgins, as she tries to recover damages awarded to her for defamation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73d83a01246222ea001cb02d5ce0a719</guid></item><item><title>Midnight Oil fans rally to keep Rob Hirst's drum kit 'in public hands' at charity auction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/midnight-oil-fans-secure-rob-hirsts-drum-kit-at-charity-auction/105887566</link><description>Midnight Oil drummer Rob Hirst auctions off the kit, which he has had since 1979, saying he can no longer play it because of his battle with pancreatic cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4b1a250f2c50ae072e79e344e2dc5fa</guid></item><item><title>Plans for national art gallery in Alice Springs scrapped after government rift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/nt-aboriginal-and-torres-strait-islander-art-alice-springs/105887842</link><description>The Northern Territory government scraps controversial plans to build the Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Art Gallery of Australia in Alice Springs after nine years of back and forth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">218dcceb9a72a6805cd42afc69e27584</guid></item><item><title>When to share the news of a pregnancy with your employer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/when-to-share-the-news-of-a-pregnancy-with-your-employer/105865350</link><description>Experts on the rules around when you need to inform your employer if you’re planning to take parental leave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdd7ceffb7b18af44c36f8079e6d9e03</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar's president flees country on French plane amid student protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/madagascar-president-andry-rajoelina-flees-country/105888408</link><description>Andry Rajoelina flees the country amid widespread protests that saw an elite military unit join demonstrators in opposing the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d597776aaaad785146891e7f721ca00</guid></item><item><title>Paul Kelly on the songs that inspire him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/paul-kelly-influences-archie-roach-go-betweens/105840822</link><description>As the 70-year-old songwriter prepares his 30th album, he talks about the music that has driven him creatively.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeb74292394ee123f769e46166b7fd50</guid></item><item><title>Katter's Australian Party MP Nick Dametto resigns from Queensland parliament to run in Townsville mayoral by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/qld-nick-dametto-resigns-parliament-townsville-mayor/105889624</link><description>Katter's Australian Party MP Nick Dametto has formally resigned from state parliament to run for Townsville mayor — forcing a by-election in his north Queensland seat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa2231bc0621c602e2e41f67dbbfc8a8</guid></item><item><title>Monitors reappointed to City of Whittlesea council, with 'wrecking ball' former mayor set to return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/whittlesea-mayor-aidan-mclindon-return-municipal-monitors/105890768</link><description>Municipal monitors will be reappointed to an embattled council in Melbourne's booming outer north following an inquiry probing the lead-up to the suspension of a former mayor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb06b13fda9df4cb6cb453876c867f18</guid></item><item><title>Indie film producers tell SXSW Sydney about how to survive and thrive making horror</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/sxsw-sydney-indie-producers-on-how-to-survive-making-horror-film/105890988</link><description>Horror films can be a great training ground for filmmakers, but there is also a gritty reality, a panel of indie producers tells SXSW Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1c6edf129ce345474e049a6b56c5528</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105891880</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">653774c141b651a45c0a8cb8f098cded</guid></item><item><title>Senior conservative James Paterson cautions Liberal Party against splitting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/james-paterson-urges-liberals-not-to-break-up-farage-teal/105888150</link><description>In a major address to his party, James Paterson says "marginal" voices agitating for the Liberal party to split must be kept on the sidelines, cautioning it would spell "disaster".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b19c93195b4681ddf79b775907477599</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar military says it is seizing power after president flees country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/madagascar-military-takes-control-coup-president-flee/105892454</link><description>The country's parliament voted to impeach President Andry Rajoelina after he fled the country in the face of growing opposition from soldiers and police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55efccf0b4c7a9354d313eee5adbd18d</guid></item><item><title>Victorian councils call on state government to strengthen trial aimed at preventing gambling harm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/gambling-harm-prevention-trial-yourplay-card-criticism/105865050</link><description>Victorian councils taking part in a trial of account-based play at pokies venues say they're disappointed with the state government's handling of the scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7908f4da03b11575b3818fb735f838e</guid></item><item><title>An embarrassing backflip by Chalmers on super or a strategic shift?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/was-chalmers-taught-a-lesson-in-his-fight-over-superannuation/105891400</link><description>After two years of refusing to reshape his superannuation shake-up, the treasurer abandons the idea of taxing unrealised gains while agreeing to index a key tax threshold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81f26bfccf07023bc6ed3051fab482c2</guid></item><item><title>Why does SA have a summer plan for the algal bloom and what's in it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/sa-government-algal-bloom-summer-plan-explained/105888438</link><description>The full details of South Australia's algal bloom summer plan which aims to ensure South Australians can "enjoy their summer" were released yesterday. The plan includes measures to protect the state's coast while supporting businesses and communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17101f197978ee94d6b7eece79d9f8c2</guid></item><item><title>Forensic imaging revealing hidden layers under Sidney Nolan's Ned Kelly paintings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/act-revealing-hidden-layers-of-sidney-nolan-ned-kelly-paintings/105889294</link><description>Hidden figures and inscriptions are being discovered beneath some of Australia's most famous paintings as conservators use infrared technology to reveal details in Sidney Nolan's Ned Kelly series, unseen since the artist's own time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">571022a8dd0d719c04c7924d5d111407</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos coach Kevin Walters pledges no Queensland bias in Ashes series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/nrl-kangaroos-england-australia-ashes-tests/105892660</link><description>Reece Walsh has built a compelling case for selection in the Kangaroos' starting line-up to face England, but coach Kevin Walters says he will not show favouritism towards the Maroons contingent in his squad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbaa2f074a49fcbe600576d71e6b56e2</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's fashion industry fears TasTAFE course cuts will impact creative pathways</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/tasmanian-young-fashion-designers-career-pathways/105887772</link><description>Under planned government cuts to vocational training in Tasmania, young aspiring creatives are worried about a loss of opportunity in their home state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82f5f9f78478f10675a08b7502145bd5</guid></item><item><title>Coroner makes rare public statement as NSW records most Indigenous deaths in custody in a year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/nsw-coroner-confirms-12-first-nations-deaths-in-custody-2025/105890400</link><description>NSW Coroner Teresa O'Sullivan's rare public comment on the "entrenched over-representation" of Indigenous prisoners as the state records the most ever in a single year, is welcomed by the grieving family member of a man who died in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7425c8c84b1cdadda86460fb9f8cc6d</guid></item><item><title>Regional Victorian farmers left high and dry as decent spring rain fails to arrive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/farmers-cutting-crops-for-hay-as-decent-spring-rain-doesnt-come/105884166</link><description>Some Victorian farmers are cutting crops for hay as the drought continues to bite in the nation's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">509574dcbec28aaf0b1eb34f8aa69ab5</guid></item><item><title>Japan makes history as Brazil records 'unacceptable' 3-2 loss in international friendly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/japan-beats-brazil-in-football-international-friendly/105893036</link><description>For the first time in 14 meetings, Japan defeats Brazil 3-2 in their international friendly at a sold-out Tokyo Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6454207cf8d9709c6caca8495b04511c</guid></item><item><title>Queensland health minister knew of hospital failures before going on leave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/queensland-health-minister-knew-about-caboolture-/105890580</link><description>Queensland's health minister has revealed he knew about failures at Caboolture Hospital involving the death of a patient after delays to medical scan results, before he went on holiday when the issue later became public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12969694309920e5fabdb01232ea2a22</guid></item><item><title>England thrashes Latvia 5-0 to qualify for World Cup finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/football-england-thrashes-latvia-to-reach-world-cup-finals/105893278</link><description>Unbeaten in its qualifying matches, England reaches next year's World Cup finals following a dominant 5-0 defeat of Latvia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">776384400073f9c24dc5ed3d14d31475</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of Victorians are graduating as paramedics, but have to go interstate for jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/paramedic-student-glut-no-jobs-ambulance-victoria/105874740</link><description>For regional paramedicine graduates, finding a job, let alone one in your hometown, is a challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87a5961a74a7b4d6e63a1037bd6466b2</guid></item><item><title>Search continues for missing bushwalker Daryl Fong in Tasmania's Mount Field National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/search-for-hiker-missing-in-mt-field-national-park-continues/105893390</link><description>Tasmania Police Inspector Luke Horne says gale force winds and deep snows are slowing search crews on day three but they still hold out hope.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">390b73e5cb58f0ab0c47066c89188622</guid></item><item><title>The US has dropped out of the top 10 most powerful passports — but where does Australia rank?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/united-states-passport-drops-out-of-top-10-most-powerful/105893408</link><description>The US passport has fallen to 12th place, a five-spot decline from its previous ranking, tying with Malaysia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">210460eb5dcbc50a34d606ea70c1a796</guid></item><item><title>Powerhouse misses opportunity to get Melbourne-bound drums of Sydney's Midnight Oil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/sydneys-powerhouse-missed-out-on-midnight-oil-drums-hirst/105894330</link><description>Midnight Oil are Sydney rock royalty, but the drum kit that stuck with the band for more than 40 years is heading to a Melbourne music museum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77d8f6e30d82e4cfddfe3d8643cf4ad8</guid></item><item><title>CCC investigation into former Townsville mayor Troy Thompson finished, but unreleased</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/former-mayor-troy-thompson-ccc-investigation-finished/105894368</link><description>A crime and corruption investigation into former Townsville mayor Troy Thompson has been finished, weeks away from a by-election he is expected to contest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80c6a9e3495196a82025540b243c8512</guid></item><item><title>Conjoined boys born in PNG bound for Australia for medical treatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/png-conjoined-twins-braun-hospital-medical-treatment-sydney/105888942</link><description>The boys, who are only the second known case of conjoined twins born in PNG, are expected to come to Australia for medical treatment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">602984aa1a6e648bd1700a79bdd0ced0</guid></item><item><title>ARLC says NRL players face 10-year ban for joining rebel leagues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/nrl-players-face-10-year-ban-for-joining-rebel-leagues/105894992</link><description>The Australian Rugby League Commission has announced a 10-year ban for any NRL player who agrees to join a football competition it does not recognise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddb37f0928e43c1b5bbf5bd94cff1dfa</guid></item><item><title>When is the F1 US Grand Prix, how can I watch and who is battling for the championship?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/f1-us-grand-prix-what-time-how-to-watch-oscar-piastri/105614112</link><description>Formula 1 returns to the United States, officially marking the final quarter of an epic 2025 championship. Here is what is to come.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53bd31ae325a4d1a91c38ac12e6504cf</guid></item><item><title>Hamas executes 'collaborators and lawbreakers' in graphic scenes in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/abc-news-verify-hamas-executions-gaza-city/105893350</link><description>Masked gunmen have carried out "extrajudicial executions" in the streets of Gaza City as an expert claims the terror group is trying to regain control of the destroyed enclave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">011b7d02b9a4606194657179c44c731f</guid></item><item><title>Hamas fighters execute alleged collaborators in Gaza. ABC NEWS Verify has chosen not to show the executions due to their graphic nature.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/hamas-fighters-execute-alleged-collaborators-in/105893348</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d75241605dfda6cf26081e293c37b7c</guid></item><item><title>Michael J Fox talks about life with Parkinson's disease</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/michael-j-fox-talks-about-death-and-parkinsons-disease/105894044</link><description>The Back to the Future star has been candid about life with the degenerative neurological condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb8da2122b00a39bed22e5f831e89528</guid></item><item><title>Federal government puts states, territories on notice over failure to close the gap for Indigenous people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/closing-the-gap-proposed-penalties/105894194</link><description>The federal Indigenous minister may impose penalties on states and territories that fail to meet critical targets for the National Agreement on Closing the Gap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db05c3e8b8aaf1109e2ab7a09d9a6061</guid></item><item><title>Australia's baby recession deepens, new ABS data says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/australia-s-baby-recession-deepens-new-abs-data-says/105541086</link><description>The baby recession in Australia is deepening as cost of living pressures make the decision for people to have children less of a choice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c8e24e2ff09a356f53956f037c71227</guid></item><item><title>Three Australian men accused of killing Zivan Radmanovic in Bali could face death penalty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/three-australian-men-could-face-death-penalty-bali/105896428</link><description>Indonesian police allege Zivan Radmanovic was killed when two Australian men stormed the villa, shooting him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4bb686a2307e1685b9fddd02d399650</guid></item><item><title>Boat approaches southern right whales off Albany coast in WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/boat-approaches-southern-right-whale-and-calf-wa/105893974</link><description>The latest close encounter with a protected whale species has renewed calls for the public to give the animals space.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d402bafad752b1c94a1343f0154bcac</guid></item><item><title>Residents in WA's north urged to prepare for cyclone season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/bom-retires-cyclone-outlook-for-northern-wa/105894634</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says it will no longer publish a cyclone outlook for WA's north, saying it was less reliable due to a changing climate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53781b9b19159607ee69607086ea9579</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105896606</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5de03d8a271e83312ef111c5e775f4b8</guid></item><item><title>One of four bodies handed over by Hamas does not match any hostage, Israel says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/body-returned-to-israel-not-a-hostage-israel-says/105897000</link><description>The Israeli military says one of four bodies handed over by Hamas on Tuesday night, local time, is not that of an Israeli hostage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f337f67d18c93c55e85db0501d33d7d5</guid></item><item><title>Syria's president Sharaa tells Putin he will respect all past deals with Moscow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/syrian-president-to-honour-past-deals-with-russia/105897210</link><description>Syrian President Ahmed al-Sharaa has told Russian President Vladimir Putin he would honour all past deals struck between his country and Moscow, a pledge suggesting Moscow's two main military bases in Syria are safe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20ceb7fb8dd0ab7c013b89252936bab6</guid></item><item><title>Australia sees opportunity in China-US rare earths dispute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/trump-albanese-xi-critical-minerals-us-china/105884214</link><description>Trump may have expressed "shock", but his administration is clearly not surprised at China's willingness to flex its dominance on rare earths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa98a5f162d3f58f6ff157adeeba8042</guid></item><item><title>Fresh new faces campaigning to make a difference in Melbourne's north as part of youth council</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/hume-council-youth-elections/105895026</link><description>Melbourne's Hume Council will see the city's first-ever democratically elected youth mayor take office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">495c6511513593a8edc13e076cfdb0e4</guid></item><item><title>Singapore, 'so dependent on external demand', braces for tariff hit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/singapore-economy-business-fallout-donald-trump-tariffs/105893038</link><description>Businesses in Singapore — one of the most trade-exposed economies in the world — have been watching the fallout from Donald Trump's 'Liberation Day' tariffs with apprehension.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f30cb84dd7e9868667ba93e4670d3a2</guid></item><item><title>'No understanding': The extreme cost of living crisis affecting Australia’s most remote communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/cost-of-living-crisis-aurukun-australia-remote-communities-/105879078</link><description>Being one of Australia’s most remote and disadvantaged communities, Aurukun’s grocery prices are some of the highest in the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b0e33d99ce449a6673d4b6cc201e7ed</guid></item><item><title>Historic Number 12 Squadron returns as Australia expands anti-submarine capability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/poseidon-12-squadron-defence-air-force-australia-us-china/105895342</link><description>The federal government has re-established the Number 12 Squadron in SA at the same time as Australia's anti-submarine capability is expanding with the arrival of new aircraft.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6176d289d3b4affa946abe70f4a0a0c</guid></item><item><title>US wants to make rare earth deals with Australia but without China involved, expert says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/us-is-open-to-make-rare-earth-deals-with-australia/105895128</link><description>As rare earths re-emerge as a central battleground in the US-China trade war, Australian companies are already striking deals to supply America. A policy expert says talks at the White House next week could secure a national agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93a0c2c00f2f1e07783629d538ec8b4e</guid></item><item><title>Fifty years since the Balibo Five murders, families are still seeking justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/balibo-five-murders-50-years-indonesia-australia-timor-leste/105884316</link><description>On the 50th anniversary of the Balibo Five murders, families are still grieving the loss of their loved ones and remain committed to holding those responsible accountable for their actions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1314ae8328046a527aba9120658d2d1d</guid></item><item><title>Australians are no fans of Donald Trump, but see no alternative to US alliance, according to poll</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/polls-no-alternative-united-states-ally-trump-negative/105895536</link><description>New polling shows most Australians want to stick with the US alliance, despite holding overwhelmingly negative views towards the Trump administration and harbouring deep worries about the erosion of American democracy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b34e4eb2cc25c472ba249c4f880b3e50</guid></item><item><title>Australians Ajla Tomljanović and James Duckworth reach WTA and ATP quarterfinals in Asia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/tennis-alja-tomljanovic-james-duckworth-ningbo-almaty-open/105897556</link><description>Australian duo Ajla Tomljanović and James Duckworth reach the quarterfinals at their respective events in China and Kazakhstan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">336d915e1efab8f376e17988ed3ec4ca</guid></item><item><title>Funeral held for dead Israeli hostage Guy Illouz as two more bodies released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/funeral-for-dead-israeli-hostage-guy-illouz/105892306</link><description>Funerals begin for dead Israelis returned from Gaza in the ceasefire and hostage exchange deal, as the nation receives the remains of two more former captives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8225bf7145b96b2938ea9a624f2675cd</guid></item><item><title>Third day of renewed search for missing 4yo Gus wraps up amid extreme heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/search-for-missing-gus-near-yunta-to-continue/105894686</link><description>More than 100 people, including from SA Police, the Australian Defence Force, and the State Emergency Services, have been walking about 20 kilometres per day in hot conditions during the renewed search, police say. The search concluded about midday on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cc1f1a5678d418814e5b57c1fcb4bc6</guid></item><item><title>Soldier killed in vehicle rollover during army training in north Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/army-soldier-killed-in-vehicle-rollover-while-training/105897572</link><description>The Department of Defence says an Australian soldier has died after a single-vehicle rollover during training at the Australian Army's Townsville Field Training Area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9064921280d2988c8f1986804181b2f4</guid></item><item><title>England saved by rain in Pakistan World Cup match as Australia prepares to face Bangladesh</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/cricket-world-cup-england-pakistan-banadoned-colombo/105897648</link><description>Only a rain downpour against Pakistan prevents England from recording its first defeat of the World Cup, as Australia looks to book its berth in knockout stages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">149a025fb79f05b67378d20a66adf0e4</guid></item><item><title>Cost of 'best practice' on emissions at leaking Darwin gas plant an 'intolerable risk' for Santos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/santos-darwin-lng-emissions-best-practice-intolerable-risk/105819802</link><description>Santos's Darwin gas plant is set for a new lease of life despite a major methane leak. The company told federal officials the risk it could be forced to meet best practice on carbon emissions was "intolerable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4185616f1eb4420fa8e0bb9f51a7a95</guid></item><item><title>Replica of destroyed Juukan Gorge being built five years after Rio Tinto blast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/juukan-gorge-rock-shelter-recreated-models-virtual-reality/105889276</link><description>A full-scale replica of the Juukan Gorge rock shelter, destroyed by mining company Rio Tinto, will be built over the remains of the original in Western Australia's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17d49eeea6ddb3bcb9585027b4d633f3</guid></item><item><title>Prestigious Australian wine labels feeling the pinch as Chinese buy and drink less</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/premium-wine-penfolds-reports-china-sales-slump/105887474</link><description>Cheaper bulk wine has been struggling in the market, but now even prestigious labels like Penfolds are feeling the pinch off the back of changing drinking habits and a reported crackdown on lavish banquets for civil servants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">824a7cb7547f583c912f4b33ffcad31d</guid></item><item><title>R360 hits back at Australian Rugby League Commission's threat of 10-year bans for rebel players</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/arlc-nrl-r360-hits-back-at-ban-threats-for-players/105897732</link><description>The boss of R360 says threats of 10-year bans for NRL players who defect to the rebel competition are predictable, as the code war escalates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a507cb97abb406d1566b15b62aa13750</guid></item><item><title>Country GP crushed by vintage tractor in Denmark issues safety warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/safety-warning-after-country-gp-crushed-by-heritage-tractor/105885980</link><description>What started as a routine day of chores for a country GP and his son became a life-or-death situation after he was crushed by a vintage tractor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc4c053f90131636fe18b998de8dcf1f</guid></item><item><title>Four-time Olympic champion Ariarne Titmus announces retirement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/swimming-ariarne-titmus-announces-retirement/105898036</link><description>Ariarne Titmus draws the curtain on a decorated career, in which she won eight medals across two Olympic Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b20c3d209eb66b297a235d75ac8ea914</guid></item><item><title>Madura Plains sheep station hits the market as wool and lamb prices soar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/historic-madura-plains-for-sale-wa-sheep-station/105894986</link><description>One of Australia's largest sheep stations is listed for sale as wool and lamb prices soar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdf5cb0f5e7c6d4612908253b324ec0b</guid></item><item><title>NSW Supreme Court finds protest law amendments invalid after Palestine Action Group challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/nsw-court-palestine-action-group-protest-law-amendment-challenge/105898160</link><description>The Palestine Action Group has won a NSW Supreme Court challenge against a law that limited protests near places of worship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10a0f52fe7d5082728fa923101f920a5</guid></item><item><title>Which team came out the most ahead in the AFL draft period and does free agency need fixing?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/afl-trade-period-2025-which-team-came-out-the-most-ahead/105897898</link><description>It was one of the more chaotic AFL trade periods on record as picks and players moved all over the place — but who came out ahead the most?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4de5f79b4339bc87a72fedad20788ad</guid></item><item><title>Calls for federal oversight of Indigenous deaths in custody rejected in the NT</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/nt-parliament-rejects-aboriginal-deaths-in-custody-motion/105895810</link><description>Three decades after the landmark Royal Commission into Aboriginal Deaths in Custody, the Northern Territory parliament rejects a motion proposing the federal government establish an independent oversight body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf403f214ebf0a2f051e0cb3ec8f817b</guid></item><item><title>Australia's unemployment rate jumps to 4.5pc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/australia-unemployment-rate-rises-september-2025/105898244</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate jumped to 4.5 per cent in September, up from 4.3 per cent in August.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">944d983f4c3e591e79c311c6deea0d20</guid></item><item><title>Kingston residents rally to save 130yo oak tree from transmission project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/campaign-to-save-algerian-oak-kingston-western-renewables-link/105885046</link><description>Residents are getting creative in their fight to save a "magnificent" 130-year-old Algerian oak tree from being felled for a controversial transmission line project in western Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f54bb8b9ecab1e3d0af3c172dfd77c73</guid></item><item><title>Remains of missing Victorian woman Lucinda Miller discovered in police search</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/lucinda-miller-items-found-neerim-south-gippsland/105895350</link><description>New information from a member of the local community has led police to human remains in bushland in Victoria's east believed to be missing woman Lucinda Miller.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ff902b644302bf25e73309688f89cf5</guid></item><item><title>Ariarne Titmus labelled a 'living legend' after calling time on decorated swimming career</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/swimming-ariarne-titmus-olympics-teammates-rivals-tribute/105899022</link><description>Olympic teammates and rivals pay tribute to the career of Australian swimming great Ariarne Titmus, who has announced her retirement at the age of 25.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcd8f1c3121e47375a837e4ff51132ea</guid></item><item><title>Endangered regent honeyeaters released in Hunter breeding effort</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/critically-endangered-regent-honeyeaters-released-hunter-valley/105897506</link><description>Dozens of regent honeyeaters have been released in woodlands in the NSW Hunter Valley in an effort to boost the critically endangered population.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">383b1b3969cfdfce4abe0f4f51474d27</guid></item><item><title>Hope at last for families as NSW backs inquiry into unsolved murders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/hope-as-nsw-backs-probe-into-unsolved-murders/105898598</link><description>The NSW Parliament has backed an inquiry into decades of unsolved murders and missing persons cases, following a campaign led by Illawarra families.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">967e3ff5e688cbc3cc4d948f1955a838</guid></item><item><title>Curators among 45 full-time jobs to be axed in Art Gallery of NSW cuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/curators-among-45-jobs-to-be-axed-at-art-gallery-of-nsw/105892942</link><description>Leaked documents show curators and conservator jobs will go as 45 full-time roles are cut from the Art Gallery of NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cf617a6570a7217321d8d4482b5215b</guid></item><item><title>Review: After the Hunt has noble ambitions but misses the mark</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/after-the-hunt-julia-roberts-review/105876254</link><description>The ingredients are all here — public scandal, duelling divas and unearthed secrets — but Luca Guadagnino's provocative drama misses the mark.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f67b806ed73e7ac77c9e5486230066b3</guid></item><item><title>Albanese dismisses lobby concerns, Chalmers takes one for the team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/anthony-albanese-jim-chalmers-good-oppositions/105884222</link><description>This week, the PM was not wasting any time on "this" issue, and the treasurer took one for the team as Brett Worthington signs off with his final political wrap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8caaca04017f6e10ef0a87a9a892f94f</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government approves Arrow Energy gas plant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/darling-downs-arrow-energy-gas-plant-approval/105900018</link><description>The Queensland government's recent approval of a major coal seam gas-processing facility three kilometres from a farming family's home has left them feeling "extremely disappointed".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cfb1f65a2244ef0e91ff8d80b92092e</guid></item><item><title>Essendon CEO says Hawthorn AFL trade tactics for Zach Merrett were surprising</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/essendon-ceo-says-hawthorn-afl-trade-tactics-merrett-surprising/105900392</link><description>Essendon chief executive Craig Vozzo says the club was surprised Hawthorn waited until late in the AFL trade period to make an offer for their captain, Zach Merrett.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e96f0a6c62b0d3f1e70f37fd7a66a0b2</guid></item><item><title>Mark Haines inquest hears differing opinions from detectives on teen's mysterious death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/mark-haines-inquest-hears-from-detectives-and-homicide-squad/105887822</link><description>Thirty seven years after his death, police still cannot agree on how 17-year-old Mark Haines came to be found on train tracks near Tamworth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f08356610886575aa5a825b2c6af363e</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian and Jewish communities in Australia watch on with caution over Gaza peace plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/palestinian-jewish-people-australia-react-to-gaza-peace-plan/105896464</link><description>Samer Tarazi is one of thousands with strong ties to the Middle East region, watching from afar to see what the US-led peace plan means for the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">404b4d3c975048899e4387620de98f34</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne improves Ashes Test case with another century for Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/marnus-labuschagne-scores-century-for-queensland-sa/105900926</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne has added to his case for selection in Australia's Test team for the Ashes, making an emphatic case for selection with his fourth century in five innings for Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c8ce13cfc70e71af84960d841aaf47</guid></item><item><title>Diane Keaton's family releases cause of death, urging tributes to homelessness services and animal shelters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/diane-keaton-cause-of-death-released/105898904</link><description>The actor's family says the 79-year-old died of pneumonia, expressing gratitude for the "extraordinary messages of love and support" received following news of her passing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ad4d9062c3fd28201c61a47954bccd0</guid></item><item><title>Release of Virginia Giuffre's memoir renews sex allegations against Prince Andrew</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/virginia-giuffre-book-prince-andrew-allegations-jeffrey-epstein/105898044</link><description>Extracts from Virginia Giuffre's posthumously released memoir have further intensified the recently renewed scrutiny on Prince Andrew.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40e21158edb995f36869ca565b0e2b53</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/thursday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/105900826</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39251dff22abd93c574816fddff415b9</guid></item><item><title>National Gallery will host APY artwork exhibition after paintings cleared of improper interference</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/act-apy-indigenous-art-interference-national-gallery-exhibition/105901272</link><description>The National Gallery will host an exhibition of art from the Aṉangu Pitjantjatjara Yankunytjatjara Lands three years after a video appearing to show a non-Aboriginal assistant helping to paint an artwork led to it being postponed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f256cd75d8dd22a070a0b023a2212e2</guid></item><item><title>Rugby Championship scrapped for 2026 due to Test calendar squeeze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/rugby-championship-scrapped-for-2026-test-season/105901714</link><description>The competition will not be played next year but will appear on the global calendar the following three years, including ahead of the 2027 Rugby World Cup, the organisers say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84c38b2c85ed36bf3a8054c41860989d</guid></item><item><title>Alyssa Healy scores second straight century as Australia qualifies for World Cup semis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/womens-world-cup-australia-beats-bangladesh-for-semifinal-berth/105899700</link><description>Australian captain Alyssa Healy scores her second straight century as her side maintains its unbeaten record at the cricket World Cup with a 10-wicket win over Bangladesh.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa8f9519f2a73e65f2eef48c11a9f988</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says Narendra Modi has pledged that India will stop buying Russian oil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/donald-trump-says-india-will-stop-buying-russian-oil/105901976</link><description>The US president says his Indian counterpart has made the pledge, as pressure continues to mount over the purchases that fund Moscow's war in Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfa3d657832c0a2a078b14f16d2fc9e8</guid></item><item><title>Calls for Australia to follow England's ban on supermarket junk food specials</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/calls-for-australia-to-follow-england-ban-on-junk-food-specials/105807974</link><description>Research finding supermarkets continue to offer discounts and multi-buy deals on junk food more frequently than healthy food prompts calls for Australia to follow England's lead and ban "buy one, get one free" deals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edbe2cd8f08f8c2fc9c6395f9edf30b7</guid></item><item><title>Temperatures across Australia to soar, threatening October records</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/forecast-for-australian-weather-weekend-high-records-october/105901378</link><description>Unseasonable temperatures have lasted along the eastern seaboard for weeks — which has Sydney, and possibly Brisbane, on track to observe their warmest October on record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f4bf36d4491c7073e70092e07ba68cc</guid></item><item><title>'Dangerously low' funding to Tasmanian arts sector creating reputational damage, minister warned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/tasmanian-arts-industry-highly-vulnerable-low-funding-investment/105899498</link><description>"Dangerously low" arts sector funding has rendered the Tasmanian industry "highly vulnerable", with funding stagnant since 2016-17, the state government has conceded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a29de7c4d5bc252c9a785dea93220878</guid></item><item><title>Jim Chalmers and Tony Burke are in a long race for prime position</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/jim-chalmers-tony-burke-leadership/105884226</link><description>There is general agreement in Labor that Jim Chalmers is the government's best communicator. But insiders watching this race know Tony Burke is the master tactician.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93f58dc170f3f37c70cca03a69e3a6f5</guid></item><item><title>From cult web series to cinema: Nirvanna the Band the Show the Movie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/nirvanna-the-band-the-show-the-movie/105898756</link><description>Canada's cult web series heads to the big screen, after creators Matt Johnson and Jay McCarrol were told they could make any movie they liked after their success with BlackBerry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcab9960bf8462cac061bee2cf98745a</guid></item><item><title>Specialist health services shortfall for women in regional WA leave many struggling for support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/women-missing-out-on-specialist-health-services-in-regional-wa/105866424</link><description>Faced with a lack of specialist women's health services, women in regional WA are researching their own conditions and volunteering to raise awareness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a46a1f1f255a795ba616233f2bb18c5</guid></item><item><title>Younger candidates out to bring change in WA local government elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/young-candidates-seek-change-in-wa-local-government-elections/105888820</link><description>In the last local government elections in WA, the average age of candidates running for councils was 53 years old — but these young candidates are keen to lower that figure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">612d6039eb66ee2883e4b90a17276dfe</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government seeks private market interest to develop riverside precinct in South Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/qld-riverfront-precinct-south-brisbane-private-sector/105902488</link><description>The government says construction could begin from March 2027 and has suggested the site could feature over 4,000 homes, as well as "event lawns" and promenades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71e510b6fa92de09ab4aec4b9b044d41</guid></item><item><title>NicheLiving customers continue to find defects</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/nicheliving-customers-continue-to-find-defects/105899574</link><description>Nicheliving customer Kathy Ellis thought her three-year nightmare was finally over in July, only to discover defective plumbing work in her new house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c827db340a1c42daeb836818d1a1c034</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says he will meet with Vladimir Putin 'within two weeks or so'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/donald-trump-says-he-will-meet-with-putin-within-two-weeks-/105902626</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3952d5581444934dd2d638c3febb4800</guid></item><item><title>Starmer criticises police decision to ban fans of Israel's Maccabi Tel Aviv from Aston Villa match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/football-maccabi-tel-aviv-fans-banned-police-aston-villa/105902590</link><description>Fans of Israel's Maccabi Tel Aviv are banned from attending next month's Europa League match against Aston Villa in Birmingham over "public safety concerns".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">effc61153d88fcce13575af2eb2a3f1c</guid></item><item><title>King Charles marks land rights milestone in first visit to London's Australia House</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/king-charles-commemorates-40th-anniversary-of-uluru-handback/105902056</link><description>King Charles marked the major milestone in Aboriginal land rights alongside Uluru-Kata Tjuta's traditional owners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7d5382ea3e29445cd53373bb9eda014</guid></item><item><title>Australian swimming star Ariarne Titmus says she lost 'fire in the belly' before shock retirement call</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/swimming-ariarne-titmus-retirement-press-conference/105902788</link><description>Ariarne Titmus has spoken publicly for the first time after abruptly retiring from professional swimming at just 25, revealing the reasons behind her decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce4208efcf5ba5f558acc40ad5edc802</guid></item><item><title>Defence in talks to support Gaza peace plan but Australia says no request yet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/defence-in-talks-with-us-to-support-gaza-peace-plan/105902742</link><description>Australia's defence force has had discussions with the Unted States to provide support for its Gaza peace plan but the government says no formal request has been made yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd80619b996f35eb17de143a6b7e07dc</guid></item><item><title>How wild bird poo testing in northern Australia is helping keep eggs on the shelves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/bird-flu-poo-testing-in-northern-australia-keeps-eggs-on-shelves/105894598</link><description>Hundreds of kilometres from the nearest supermarket, Indigenous rangers in Australia's remote north are working to keep eggs on your breakfast table.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">126bc279f84d1b05bc9d6ac31fa6b513</guid></item><item><title>Indigiearth founder inspires Indigenous women to chase business dreams</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/indigiearth-award-sharon-winsor-australian-cuisine/105899236</link><description>Sharon Winsor is honoured for her pioneering work in native Australian cuisine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9867852928883c2abad3f488c0d1bf3b</guid></item><item><title>Bears kill record number of people in Japan amid scores of attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/record-number-of-bear-attacks-in-japan/105902770</link><description>At least seven people have been killed by bears in the country since April and many more have been injured as the hungry animals venture into human territory to find food.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41b4b93bb120166534952debb22263e8</guid></item><item><title>US dangled threat of Tomahawks for Ukraine, then Russia called to negotiate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/us-tomahawk-long-range-missiles-supply-ukraine-russia-talks/105884192</link><description>US President Donald Trump threatened to send Tomahawk missiles to Ukraine if Russia did not return to peace talks, but analysts say the long-range weapons are not the game-changer they are made out to be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab37297fc9b45cbc08d59856d14f85f4</guid></item><item><title>'No doubt' Anthony Albanese and Donald Trump will discuss critical minerals: Chalmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/albanese-trump-chalmers-critical-minerals-deal/105903392</link><description>Anthony Albanese will "no doubt" use a meeting with Donald Trump next week to discuss critical minerals, the treasurer says as he dismisses a call for Australia to "decouple" with China over rare earth materials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fe4351ff10e966c7a84c8e260555fa8</guid></item><item><title>Missing man Troy Milne found alive in bushland more than two hours from campsite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/missing-man-found-troy-milne-fire-gippsland/105904026</link><description>A man who was missing in Victoria's east for more than a week is recovering in hospital after being found in bushland when he started a fire to draw attention to his location.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c75d2afbeefc32496c0ab94cbb90f22</guid></item><item><title>Pet-friendly flights are taking off in Australia. Here's what to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/pet-friendly-flights-what-to-know/105903876</link><description>The first pet-friendly commercial flights have taken off in Australia this week. Here's what you need to know about the new service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4379a2d55c184d75fb0dbc167127d3db</guid></item><item><title>Australia Test batter Nic Maddinson reveals testicular cancer diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/australia-test-batter-nic-maddinson-testicular-cancer-diagnosis/105905220</link><description>Former Australia batter Nic Maddinson has revealed he underwent chemotherapy for testicular cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7f603e8cc45b625885d16071d38bc7a</guid></item><item><title>David Pye on bail after being refused anxiety drugs in custody, Nick Martin trial hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/david-pye-trial-told-of-nick-martin-killer-iraq-terror-link-/105903116</link><description>An accused murderer and bikie gang member on trial in WA's Supreme Court amid heightened security is granted bail because he is unable to get access to anti-anxiety medication behind bars, it is revealed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d458f503d4b0f4c89690a3b91078a89e</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's plan to leave his mark on Washington DC by building Paris-style arch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/trump-plans-to-build-paris-style-arc-in-us-capital/105904744</link><description>The arch would stand at the Washington end of Memorial Bridge, which spans the Potomac River from Arlington, Virginia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">602d98d8a4c8909392f7e0e5d59de569</guid></item><item><title>Europe unveils plans for 'drone wall' to shield continent from Russian threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/europe-drone-wall-defence-system-russia-threat-incursions/105893030</link><description>The European Commission unveils plans for its so-called "drone wall", which is part of a range of initiatives to get the continent ready to defend itself by 2030.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15ca3d3f92a6b391e69aeb1231da05cd</guid></item><item><title>Inquest hears of grief, trauma from families of Eugowra locals after record-breaking 2022 flood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/eugowra-inquest-day-five/105902498</link><description>Families speak of loss, trauma on final day of the coronial inquest into the deaths of Les Vugec and Diane Smith.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dcae5aba593220ee08189da0bc90ff1</guid></item><item><title>Video released of moments leading up to strip search that breached Aboriginal woman's human rights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/julianne-williams-strip-search-canberra-jail-video-release-court/105905888</link><description>The ACT Supreme Court has made public confronting video showing the moments leading up to a strip search that violated an Aboriginal woman’s human rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdcb7325932b405b24aab30e15587062</guid></item><item><title>Deepfake image-based abuse happening at least once a week in schools, eSafety data shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/deepfake-image-based-abuse-doubles-across-australia/105905152</link><description>The latest data revealed by Australia's eSafety Commissioner comes just days after reports that digitally altered explicit images of female students from a Sydney high school were shared online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd27dfbd0ff0516ec2e07457a0070394</guid></item><item><title>Grimmer family sets parliamentary privilege deadline for cold case identity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/cheryl-grimmer-brothers-set-deadline-parliamentary-privilege/105904330</link><description>A brother of three-year-old Cheryl Grimmer, who vanished in 1970, has given the man who confessed to her killing a deadline to come forward or be named.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f15982335786071048424d142871b2b9</guid></item><item><title>Strict conditions imposed on future LIV Golf site at North Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/strict-conditions-on-north-adelaide-golf-course-redevelopment/105905844</link><description>South Australia's Aboriginal affairs minister has imposed 31 strict conditions on the government's planned redevelopment of the North Adelaide golf course.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc6d01343d110faca4bb8653ade74cc5</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/friday-finance-with-david-chau/105906178</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6b775f25a05cb343702a02cf5d8de47</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar military leader Michael Randrianirina sworn in as president after coup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/madagascar-new-president-sworn-in-after-military-coup/105906334</link><description>An army colonel who seized power in a military coup has been sworn in as Madagascar's new leader, after a sudden power grab that ousted the president and sent him fleeing from the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96dcc3f3b1832b7f3704ff8662f60934</guid></item><item><title>Russia convicts 15 captured Ukrainian soldiers on terrorism charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/russia-convicts-15-captured-ukrainian-soldiers/105906652</link><description>Fifteen captured Ukrainian soldiers from the Aidar battalion have been sentenced in a Russian court to up to 21 years in a penal colony.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b7ddec1dccff7c0b1c93ead771afa46</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's Trump meeting comes amid global geopolitical circus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/gaza-ceasefire-deal-donald-trump-anthony-albanese-trade-tariff/105884238</link><description>All signs suggest Anthony Albanese will be sticking with Plan A in his meeting with the US president on Tuesday, rather than becoming a prop for the bigger global circus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7369e04e283103228bfcf69dddc12dd2</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew giving up his royal titles and honours after speaking with King Charles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/prince-andrew-to-give-up-royal-titles-and-honours/105907098</link><description>King Charles's brother has come under significant pressure after being linked to the late convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein and his ties to China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b88d507f6b73a3388229f325fd5168e</guid></item><item><title>Video appears to show March for Australia organiser coordinating with Neo-Nazi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/march-for-australia-organiser-coordinates-with-neo-nazi/105902754</link><description>A previously unreported video has emerged appearing to show a key March for Australia organiser coordinating with a Neo-Nazi at the first rally in Sydney in August, ABC NEWS Verify has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc104ef4e2d70260f456bb05e05b9a6c</guid></item><item><title>Administrative Review Tribunal swamped by surging demand, more than 100 members short</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/administrative-review-tribunal-overwhelmed-surging-demand/105893728</link><description>The Administrative Review Tribunal was set up to resolve issues with its predecessor, but has struggled with staffing and long wait times over its first year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fd2f156e95340a969daa8b6003273f1</guid></item><item><title>Education department admits not enough done to stop Dubbo College Delroy aide harming children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/systemic-failure-to-investigate-nsw-dubbo-school-staff/105807290</link><description>The NSW government says it should have taken allegations of wrongdoing by a male school staff member more seriously. That failure left those who reported it so isolated their mental health spiralled and never fully recovered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c22f6955d77c23cb8f7c088405ad508</guid></item><item><title>Benjamin Netanyahu's name prompted boos in Israel but is it a signal he has lost favour?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/benjamin-netanyahu-popularity-in-israel-in-spotlight/105903240</link><description>As the dust settles on the ceasefire and hostage exchange deal, the question arises as to whether the partial resolution could deliver Benjamin Netanyahu a bounce in the polls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3cc3003b8b28e951e730e5aa18bbb1f</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou defends record as pressure builds at Nottingham Forest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/ange-postecoglou-launches-passionate-defence-of-record/105907112</link><description>Amid growing pressure of his poor start at Nottingham Forest, Ange Postecoglou delivers a five-minute defence of his record as a manager.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1863ae28c5532d8ed98a6a975abd634</guid></item><item><title>Fire authorities warn of 'above average' fire season as NSW starts to warm up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/nsw-above-average-fire-season-bushfire-risk-weather/105900120</link><description>Fire authorities warn of above average fire season in NSW despite previous modelling showing a wet summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52eaca3898c563789480ae66f0c7a43f</guid></item><item><title>Brad Battin under pressure as Liberal MPs weigh up second leadership spill in less than 12 months</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/brad-battin-victorian-liberal-leader-analysis/105904104</link><description>The Victorian Liberals could be headed for their third leader in less than 12 months, with MPs internally dissatisfied with the performance of current leader Brad Battin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c7498fe9c9833ab207d978dc7164bb6</guid></item><item><title>Is the transfer of Australia's best young soccer players a good thing?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/soccer-a-league-player-transfers/105893566</link><description>Are A-League soccer fans right to be frustrated when its best young players are sold off, or should they accept it is a 'selling' league?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0e06963459d7a95465fff2d57464f52</guid></item><item><title>As the Australian op shop turns 100, the legacy of Lady Millie Tallis lives on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/lady-millie-tallis-australian-op-shop-100-year-anniversary/105901846</link><description>One hundred years ago, showgirl-turned-philanthropist Millie Tallis spent weeks preparing for a major second-hand goods fundraiser in Melbourne, giving rise to the Australian op shop.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92ea4c4664694717607b7fd6c4bd9662</guid></item><item><title>Protesters clash with police as Bangladesh's political parties agree to pathway for reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/protesters-clash-with-police-in-bangladesh-over-political-reform/105907038</link><description>Tear gas and stun grenades were used to disperse hundreds of protesters who were calling for more provisions for those who helped oust the former government of Sheikh Hasina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">487bc6155e85e21b8f55d26aa4aa70b8</guid></item><item><title>Lack of housing in remote NT community Borroloola forcing families off country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/borroloola-housing-lack-forcing-families-leave-country/105895586</link><description>Remote NT residents are calling on the government to fund new housing in the Gulf community of Borroloola, fearing limited access to appropriate homes has forced families to move off country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df22bcf01f5fa2c70abd461d204c6d03</guid></item><item><title>James Duckworth returns to ATP Tour semifinal four years after his last</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/james-duckworth-atp-tour-astana-open-semi-final/105907190</link><description>Four years since he last reached an ATP tournament semifinal in Kazakhstan, Australian James Duckworth is back in the last four at the Almaty Open</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dceb858841c1c847c349b2a7432508b3</guid></item><item><title>Locals swarm when air freight carrying fresh food arrives on the island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/locals-swarm-when-air-freight-carrying-fresh-food-arrives/105896242</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">874c9e4756d74a99a787d3dd04623436</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Island wants more tourists but luggage is often left behind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/christmas-island-travellers-luggage-regularly-left-behind/105778992</link><description>On Christmas Island, locals are not surprised if tourists' checked baggage does not arrive with them. Fragile supply chains on the remote Indian Ocean island are a part of life in this unique community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf635fd57a7aedc3288c6869b3851e6d</guid></item><item><title>The face of Brisbane is changing — but should thousands of homes be developed in a flood zone?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/visy-montague-road-riverfront-precinct-thousands-of-homes-floods/105904030</link><description>Plans to build a riverfront precinct in a flood-prone area of Brisbane have urban planners and locals wary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d506b00fbc8d45eff04ef30c465454e6</guid></item><item><title>Pakistani soldiers killed by suicide bomb near Afghanistan border</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/suicide-bomb-attack-kills-soldiers-in-pakistan/105906932</link><description>The attack on a military base near the Afghanistan border comes as Taliban and Pakistani officials say a peace deal has been extended.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a43f6b1a97e689f439e7e9bc7a686da6</guid></item><item><title>Western Australia starts harvesting what could be a record-breaking grain crop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/western-australia-harvest-record-grain-crop-expected/105900332</link><description>Farmers in Western Australia have begun harvesting a grain crop that could set a new record. It is a different story on the other side of the Nullabor though.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a84a87f36461e65b587de7b1fd2f66c6</guid></item><item><title>From a Springsteen biopic to a doggy horror: here are the movies out in October</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/october-movie-wrap-what-to-watch/105893300</link><description>From the highly anticipated Bruce Springsteen biopic to a horror movie from the viewpoint of the family pup, here are the films filling up cinemas in October.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f217a9477d3de1211d4744ae2ba19bd8</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne's record-setting AFLW winning streak is clear in the numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/north-melbourne-setting-aflw-standards/105905842</link><description>Having developed the program layer by layer since joining the AFLW in 2019, North Melbourne's disciplined, professional style of footy is forcing the rest of the league to rise to their level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3f69ec228f1094f89b081dd9d305cb5</guid></item><item><title>Cool weather prescribed burn on WA's south coast should be expanded, environmental group says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/call-to-expand-cool-weather-burns-to-protect-the-environment/105896512</link><description>The success of a small, autumn prescribed burn on WA's south coast has prompted calls to replace the regular program to reduce environmental damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">164585befee231bbcfbedee418ccc7bd</guid></item><item><title>Phoebe Litchfield learning from opening partner Alyssa Healy at Women's Cricket World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/phoebe-litchfield-alyssa-healy-womens-cricket-world-cup/105907312</link><description>Alyssa Healy has joined an elite band of women batters with 7,000 international runs, and Australia's captain is giving her brilliant young opening partner something to aim for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a50f38a0dacc4756881494b6edf4d5e</guid></item><item><title>Minister flags compulsory voting in local government elections, 4-year terms amid low voter turnout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/compulsory-voting-flagged-for-wa-local-government-election/105901804</link><description>Voting in council elections could become mandatory in Western Australia if the turnout for this weekend's poll continues to plummet, the local government minister warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90ce7dc5327df5d0b3904814e2638839</guid></item><item><title>Heavy horsemen keep farming traditions alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/heavy-horsemen-keep-farming-traditions-alive/105887988</link><description>Aleks Berzins is farming the land in the same way his grandfather did, using draught horses for jobs now widely done by machines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f47d3bf2b7c8199053c352b6aaf54536</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy says he trusts Trump wants to finish Ukraine war</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/zelenskyy-says-he-trusts-trump-wants-to-finish-ukraine-war/105907350</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a02436a06499efc13375877506c05db</guid></item><item><title>Trump tells Putin and Zelenskyy to ‘stop right now at the battle line’</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/trump-tells-putin-and-zelenskyy-to-stop/105907490</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a042aa321b911d55cae568609cf02a54</guid></item><item><title>Max Verstappen claims sprint pole ahead of Lando Norris and Oscar Piastri at US F1 Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/f1-max-verstappen-lando-norris-oscar-piastri-us-grand-prix/105907488</link><description>Max Verstappen topples McLaren pair Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris to claim pole position for the sprint race at the United States Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0aead0d7f508abc19c76aa70fab17de8</guid></item><item><title>A history of the Israeli settler movement in the Occupied Palestinian Territory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/israeli-settlers-rear-vision/105789284</link><description>Since October 7, tensions have been rising between Palestinians and Israeli settlers in the Occupied Palestinian Territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23198e502573622dd9f58f17a1d48075</guid></item><item><title>Gungahlin United Football Club to fold after losing NPL licence, leaving 2,000 grassroots players club-less</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/gungahlin-united-fc-fold-capital-football-licence-revoke/105907530</link><description>Just last year, the club won the league, and a former president was jailed for stealing $20k. Now they are going to fold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b94409bd3e5cff77f2199cae368e6fbf</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos defeat Crows by 40 points to move closer to winning record as Saints, Dockers and Demons notch victories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/aflw-demons-swans-kangaroos-crows-giants-dockers-blues-saints/105907762</link><description>North Melbourne moves one victory away from equalling the all-time VFL/AFL and AFLW winning record with a 40-point drubbing of Adelaide as St Kilda moves closer to a maiden finals appearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3036c640f5f12f4b89b3526d94476ea</guid></item><item><title>Chinese Communist Party's Central Committee set for major shake-up at plenum meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/xi-inner-circle-major-shakeup-ccp-meeting-beijing/105885472</link><description>A key meeting of the Chinese Communist Party Central Committee is expected to include a major shake-up of President Xi Jinping's inner circle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41655c3a7bf399a2c8c3669a0f55d79b</guid></item><item><title>Collingwood cult hero Mason Cox not offered new contract for 2026 AFL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/mason-cox-leaves-collingwood-magpies/105907852</link><description>Mason Cox, the first American to become an AFL regular, confirms he will not be with the Magpies in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faaa19652e592fb7fd468bdd25c33d4d</guid></item><item><title>Jamie Melham creates Caulfield Cup history after riding Half Yours to victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/caulfield-cup-jamie-melham-makes-history-with-half-yours-win/105907872</link><description>Jamie Melham breaks new ground as the first female jockey to win the Caulfield Cup in its 149-year history, steering favourite Half Yours to victory in the $5 million handicap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">667ff62cf5c5a273ffd2a976a56004c6</guid></item><item><title>Jack Miller eyeing breakthrough MotoGP podium at Australian Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/jack-miller-eyeing-australian-grand-prix-podium/105907966</link><description>Jack Miller qualifies in the front row for Sunday's Australian Grand Prix — the first Aussie to do so since Casey Stoner in 2012.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7268d01cc3711cc55d464d5f7e8f5393</guid></item><item><title>Israel identifies remains of 10th hostage handed over by Hamas as 76-year-old Eliyahu Margalit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/israel-10th-hostage-handback-identified-76yo-eliyahu-margalit/105907884</link><description>Eliyahu Margalit's body was found after two bulldozers ploughed up pits in the earth in the city of Khan Younis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1d5a64c472215dfc37dd3ae22ab51a6</guid></item><item><title>Nottingham Forest sack manager Ange Postecoglou immediately after loss to Chelsea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/ange-postecoglou-sacked-nottingham-forest/105908162</link><description>Nottingham Forest sacked the winless manager moments after their 3-0 defeat by Chelsea on Saturday local time, which left the club 17th in the standings and on the brink of slipping into the relegation zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57c551c6fd2ddff4af0d49de00cd0a77</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese is set to sit down with Donald Trump. What can he learn from other world leaders?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/anthony-albanese-sits-down-with-trump-what-can-he-learn/105894690</link><description>As other world leaders have discovered, a visit to Donald Trump's White House can become an unpredictable, if not uncomfortable, encounter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4b6d1356ae3c998aaee4553a3793db7</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew's decision to give up his titles may have been quietly orchestrated by members of his own family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/is-prince-andrews-decision-enough-to-stem-damage-to-monarchy/105907688</link><description>With the swirl of news around Prince Andrew this week, something had to be done; the question was whether he would do it himself or if his brother would be forced to show him the door.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b77456c907ef9b548850123a9b10fa3e</guid></item><item><title>BOM's first long-range summer forecast shows increased chance of extreme heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/bom-summer-weather-forecast-hot-and-dry-with-high-fire-risk/105899594</link><description>Hot nights coupled with high daytime temperatures could see Australia heading into an extremely hot summer, BOM's first long-range forecast indicates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f141a77feebbff9dd877f9c172a7d949</guid></item><item><title>Native mussel restoration project supported by Victor Harbor community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/mussel-bed-rebuilding-at-encounter-bay-after-algal-bloom/105887684</link><description>Victor Harbor was one of the first areas affected by SA's harmful algal bloom. Now its citizens are funding and supporting research into rebuilding native mussel populations as it looks to the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5482853b2341d466e8d2331ff929036a</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz Kids: Who says trivia is just for grown-ups? It's time to put your thinking cap on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/hard-quiz-kids-weekly-trivia-tom-gleeson/105894882</link><description>Hard Quiz Kids is here again, and we're gifting you a bunch of straightforward questions. Don't embarrass yourself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eae196e3bd245bc87722d2b719e6f741</guid></item><item><title>After Ukraine, Finland hopes it won't be Putin's next target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/inside-finlands-preparations-for-russian-invasion/105859992</link><description>Blasted into the bedrock, deep below the streets of Helsinki, these massive bunkers are currently used for recreation. Their primary function, however, is much more sinister: preparing for a Russian invasion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3896c79d12d96bc2c66108ed2320d926</guid></item><item><title>How Mother Teresa helped Steve Waugh channel his 'power' for children in need</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/steve-waugh-on-meeting-mother-teresa/105671818</link><description>When Steve Waugh retired from cricket, he knew he wanted to use his influence to make a difference. It was meeting Mother Teresa that made him realise his new path.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f532c8e947e73fb6c25eb280850294d</guid></item><item><title>Gellung Warl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/gellung-warl/105887694</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf0fe968e72376f9816a5efb2bcd3919</guid></item><item><title>Nyerna Yoorrook Telkuna</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/nyerna-yoorrook-telkuna/105887680</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93e42589db4490a6e86b296e2255f3d6</guid></item><item><title>Nginma Ngainga Wara</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/nginma-ngainga-wara/105887688</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83c32e5e94f6c2ec9f717181d30f1691</guid></item><item><title>'Gellung Warl' and other Victorian Aboriginal words that are part of Australia's first Treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/victoria-treaty-aboriginal-language-words-gellung-warl/105874164</link><description>Victoria's first Treaty with First Peoples' was debated in state parliament last week. The Treaty introduces some Victorian Aboriginal words you may not have heard before — here's how to say them and what they mean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5888d4d050285e49bfa8b0319e6bfc2c</guid></item><item><title>Julian Assange seeks 20-year jail term for David Morales, the Spaniard who spied on him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/julian-assange-suggested-sentence-for-david-morales/105908048</link><description>His lawyers suggested the jail term for David Morales, accused of discovery and disclosure of secrets, bribery, money laundering and illegal possession of weapons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d09193e99604a479bc0cc7a2da23e6e</guid></item><item><title>Sheffield Shield round two quick hits: Marnus Labuschagne confirms form ahead of Ashes, Scott Boland bullies and spinners offer reminder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/sheffield-shield-summary-marnus-labuschagne/105907142</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne's magical early season form continues with the bat, Scott Boland and a pair of spinners offer a reminder of their skill, while Sam Konstas turns on the flair at round two of the Sheffield Shield.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">054ff0d8e5945ea2d312a9468fd3278e</guid></item><item><title>James Duckworth falls at Almaty Open semi-final stage against Daniil Medvedev</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/james-duckworth-falls-almati-open-semi-final-daniil-medvedev/105908658</link><description>Australian seed-slayer James Duckworth has finally met his match in Almaty, where Daniil Medvedev dug deep to beat him in three sets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0d127a1f537ae19f3d552f01bce600f</guid></item><item><title>Flood mapping is different between councils, but one resident is calling for change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/qld-flood-mapping-local-council-development-ban-petition/105885362</link><description>Ben Parkinson is proud of the five acres he calls home in south-east Queensland, but what is missing is the ability to develop his land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7ccf073b5939120e126c4119a081064</guid></item><item><title>It's been called Canberra's 'forever government' — but ACT Labor's brand is growing tired</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/act-canberra-forever-government-but-labor-brand-growing-tired/105904332</link><description>It's been a year since Canberrans re-elected an ACT Labor government for a seventh consecutive term — but as budget pressures bite, analysts say Labor's stocks are suffering from brand fatigue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ee3cbb31b12feb0dbf9a314f57eeb6d</guid></item><item><title>International chefs share signature flavours as part of Lambassador program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/international-lambassadors-arrive-in-australia-for-lamb-lessons/105903950</link><description>A delegation of international chefs from 11 countries have landed in Australia to gain a deeper understanding of locally produced Australian lamb.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71e07198c67015e99c324d0292653818</guid></item><item><title>US warns of 'imminent' Hamas attack on Palestinians in Gaza in potential ceasefire breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/hamas-hands-over-two-more-israeli-hostages-remains/105908710</link><description>The United States has received "credible reports" indicating an imminent violation by Hamas of the ceasefire with Israel in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b7efb1dc721bfd6d2e091b751007994</guid></item><item><title>De Havilland Vampire Mk35A jet fighter to be restored by Dareton Men's Shed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/dareton-mens-shed-to-restore-vampire-jet/105853774</link><description>A former RAAF jet fighter will be rebuilt by an amateur team of restorers in the second such project for a south-west New South Wales men's shed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc8af33eebe8769b38460bd8a9275ea1</guid></item><item><title>National Disruption Group to be established to crush tobacco black market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/national-distruption-group-tobacco-black-market/105908764</link><description>A new "National Disruption Group" will be convened to stamp out the exploding illicit tobacco market and other "converging" threats, the home affairs minister has announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cc3bdda511d1e9aa7bb583dee35ef1e</guid></item><item><title>Five suspected rat poison cases detected in south-east Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/qld-rat-poisoning-symptoms-reported-to-hospitals/105908798</link><description>Queensland Health is investigating after five people were hospitalised with symptoms of ingesting rat poison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17e5b91d5e833fa2e54a07c383a89f60</guid></item><item><title>Australia's worst peacetime aviation disaster memorialised on 75th anniversary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/york-aviation-disaster/105905138</link><description>A memorial, including a replica of the aircraft and a plaque made out of a stone recovered from the crash site, has been unveiled in York.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70423a2e9f7ce7b6aa9d37cc98a7b545</guid></item><item><title>Committed band of skateboarders trying to preserve Fremantle's best spots</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/fremantle-skateboarding-community-fighting-development/105905606</link><description>WA's bustling port city of Fremantle is changing, and in between a swathe of redevelopment stands a persistent, dedicated and vocal group experiencing some mixed results — the skateboarding community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c906228a8685aa2fbf624bd8d81dc06c</guid></item><item><title>3rd Battalion pays tribute to Lance Corporal Tulsa Rumney who died during training near Townsville</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/lance-corporal-tulsa-rumney-remembered/105908804</link><description>The 3rd Battalion (3RAR) is remembering Lance Corporal Tulsa Rumney who died during training as a passionate and proud Australian who will be forever missed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4dbf33297fc133487e2bd9c51801215</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou's Nottingham Forest stint a classic case of wrong place, wrong time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/ange-postecoglou-nottingham-forest-wrong-team-brian-clough/105908712</link><description>Ange Postecolgou was on a hiding to nothing at Nottingham Forest, his sacking the result of terrible recruitment and a knee-jerk appointment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0adc426b55b3caeb01dc1561cdfadbc</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan and Afghanistan agree to immediate ceasefire after peace talks in Doha</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/pakistan-afghanistan-agree-to-immediate-ceasefire-doha-talks/105908852</link><description>A week of fierce border clashes has seen the worst violence between the two countries since the Taliban seized power in Kabul in 2021.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ae3ed5418e4616f7f9a9cc4b9feaba5</guid></item><item><title>'Green bans' saved Sydney's historic buildings and taught economists a lesson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/green-bans-sydney-1970s-unions-nimby-yimby-milton-friedman/105903850</link><description>The "green bans" in the 1970s saved many of Australia's historic buildings and our cities are richer for them. But a famous economist didn't like them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abdb337970b734f91db4e99387b96c1a</guid></item><item><title>Australian Para Triathlon mixed relay team seal silver at World Triathlon Championship Finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/paratriathlon-relay-seal-silver-at-world-championships/105908976</link><description>Australia's para triathlon mixed relay team sealed a successful week by claiming a sensational silver medal on the final morning of the World Triathlon Championship Finals in Wollongong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9b6a331ee8dec8a3f69255dcf628bf3</guid></item><item><title>Anti-immigration rallies and counter protests held across the country with lower numbers — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/march-for-australia-anti-immigration-counter-protest/105908854</link><description>Demonstrators gathered in cities across the country today, with March for Australia rallies sparking counter protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc46a6a077edb7895f0c0b99d9e04d87</guid></item><item><title>Crowds gather in Sydney for anti-immigration protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/crowds-gather-in-sydney-for-anti-immigration-protests-/105909172</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f87180c33805ea2fb0d2296604d95808</guid></item><item><title>Mollie O'Callaghan crushes 200m short course world record as post-Titmus era begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/mollie-o-callaghan-crushes-200m-short-course-world-record/105909080</link><description>Mollie O'Callghan breaks the women's short course 200m freestyle world record on day two of the World Aquatics Swimming World Cup second leg in Illinois.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6231da4c79de0162d4eb6b705e6680d</guid></item><item><title>Loud bangs heard at Melbourne protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/loud-bangs-heard-at-melbourne-protest/105909204</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae2f1c14709343893f847e83d1c91361</guid></item><item><title>Riot police move in</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/riot-police-move-in/105909206</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2a76d910b0fa478e8718288eb2db969</guid></item><item><title>The Top 100 Books of the 21st century countdown continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/top-100-books-of-the-21st-century-radio-national-live-updates/105900036</link><description>Lessons in Chemistry by Bonnie Garmus has taken the fifth spot in Radio National's Top 100 Books of the 21st Century countdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a93d820be1134030d36a0450e5827bd4</guid></item><item><title>Missing bushwalker Daryl Fong's brother thanks crews as search continues in 'dangerous' conditions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/missing-bushwalker-daryl-fong-search-continues-mount-field/105909192</link><description>Rescue crews have faced challenging conditions in the search for Daryl Fong, who has been missing in Tasmania's Mount Field National Park since last Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79317a802b551f057750daca1b564099</guid></item><item><title>How Claire's decision to be 'one and done' was rocked by divorce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/how-claire-feels-about-being-one-and-done-after-divorce/105870074</link><description>After a traumatic birth, followed by mental and physical health challenges, Claire was "one and done". But divorce made her think twice about her decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c4071ab0f2b41bc5ba8af85bdc44b4</guid></item><item><title>Tiger snake slides over passenger's foot during a drive on NSW far south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/tiger-snake-encounter-passenger-narooma-rescue/105909112</link><description>A passenger in a car has the fright of his life when a tiger snake slithers across his feet during a drive on the NSW far south coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2664ddc2ecf35a9e1c24c1ee8681b6ac</guid></item><item><title>North Adelaide golf course safeguards fall short, some Kaurna community members say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/liv-golf-aboriginal-heritage-reaction/105908982</link><description>As the Malinauskas government proceeds with its $50 million North Adelaide golf course upgrade, some Kaurna elders are grappling with the prospect that the redevelopment could uncover Aboriginal remains.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9101d5e10e56032ae087ac48805699a</guid></item><item><title>Wadeye traditional owners say Yidiyi cultural festival brings community together as 'one family'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/wadeye-nt-yidiyi-festival-2025-brings-community-together/105908796</link><description>Traditional owners of the remote NT Aboriginal community of Wadeye say the community has been brought "together as one family" at this year's Yidiyi cultural festival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d233684dc20b0f2b15cd1d575b533874</guid></item><item><title>Wayne Cheeseman speaks on Melbourne protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/wayne-cheeseman-speaks-on-melbourne-protests/105909574</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ab7ce796eb8aad3dfda4b8de5db0e10</guid></item><item><title>More than $6 million of cocaine and methylamphetamine seized during vehicle stop in southern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/highway-patrol-drug-haul-in-hay-nsw-vehicle-stop/105909462</link><description>Highway patrol stopped the black luxury SUV on a major New South Wales highway for a random drug and alcohol test on Friday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0b12cb731bfba08c1331b8020ab344b</guid></item><item><title>Lions overcome injuries to down Bombers by 38 points</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/aflw-bombers-lions-magpies-tigers-suns-bulldogs/105909452</link><description>Brisbane shrugs off injuries to Bre Koenen and Courtney Hodder to return to the AFLW's top four with a 38-point defeat of Essendon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">220f543ca713782ae1e2a21e7e2fa7c0</guid></item><item><title>Tensions erupt on Melbourne streets as opposing immigration rallies held across Australian capitals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/tensions-flare-melb-march-for-australia-anti-immigration-rallies/105908634</link><description>Two Victoria Police officers were hospitalised after violent clashes, while protesters were also arrested following scuffles in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0df5800a61965c627856a41a42a4d2f1</guid></item><item><title>If we're going cashless, why do we still pay card fees?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/if-we-re-going-cashless-why-do-we-still-pay-card-fees-/105909604</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99d81835be593f4489d729ef0cd5668f</guid></item></channel></rss>