<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 15:59:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Wilcannia Weir project relies on increased federal funding, NSW minister says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/wilcannia-weir-project-funding-issues-rose-jackson/105849134</link><description>After decades of lobbying and design controversy, the New South Wales government says it needs another $30–40 million to proceed with the Wilcannia Weir upgrade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58e66e347555f3ff3da55e931beb4da2</guid></item><item><title>Australian wins with a jaffle at World Porridge Making Championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/melbourne-woman-wins-porridge-making-championship-with-jaffle/105861480</link><description>An oatmeal-filled jaffle made by a Melbourne food stylist and flavoured with Bundaberg Rum and bananas wins over judges in Scotland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">166b409d3c84e96a4aaae8acce2b6d24</guid></item><item><title>SA Police Commissioner Grant Stevens cleared over 1990s firearm incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/sa-police-commissioner-cleared-over-firearms-incident/105862988</link><description>South Australia's corruption watchdog has cleared Police Commissioner Grant Stevens of a discipline breach for accidentally discharging his firearm during a house raid in the early 1990s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11b1d529aef3b13c3907006779d8dc1f</guid></item><item><title>SA childcare centre closed for 90 days amid supervision concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/edge-early-learning-closure-extended-90-days/105862742</link><description>The Education Standards Board has closed Edge Early Learning Centre at Plympton for 90 days following an investigation into reports of "inadequate supervision" of children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecd91d4d6915aff8eca13d17480e9222</guid></item><item><title>Trump is deploying more troops on home soil — here's where things stand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/trump-national-guard-deployments-us/105862330</link><description>US President Donald Trump is ramping up efforts to deploy the National Guard in more cities across the country to combat what he claims is a "war from within". Here's a quick rundown on where Mr Trump has stationed troops — and which cities might be next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81336c34b8947a268eb83228d6116265</guid></item><item><title>Gerard Community Council Aboriginal Corporation pleads guilty to failing to lodge reports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/gerard-community-council-aboriginal-corporation-guilty-riverland/105861718</link><description>The corporation has been fined $2,000 for failing to lodge reports to the Office of the Registrar of Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Corporations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">667cc72e63a68b60053f0faf8d783cbf</guid></item><item><title>Suspects in Bega stabbing death still at large, as police rule out chainsaw injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/bega-murder-investigation-park-death-police/105860516</link><description>Authorities say they are still piecing together who was involved in a "violent altercation" that left a man fatally stabbed and another in hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7db04311e9317f536592263b17a60b7</guid></item><item><title>Australia confident in batting at Women's Cricket World Cup, as Pakistan match approaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/australia-able-to-break-records-with-cricket-world-cup-approach/105862918</link><description>Beth Mooney has predicted Australia's new approach to ODI cricket will pay off in the Women's Cricket World Cup, with a greater desire to take the game on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6676359c94593bc78b44ad4f5348aa3</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast mayor says Qld government hoarding cyclone recovery funds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/gold-coast-mayor-attacks-qld-government-cyclone-funding-delay/105862826</link><description>Gold Coast mayor Tom Tate is calling for the state government to hand over funding allocated to help cover the city's growing disaster recovery bill following Tropical Cyclone Alfred.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b7381e80a01b974d263f402f2cda200</guid></item><item><title>State of WA appeals $2.8 million compensation payment to Dion Barber for abuse in state care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/state-appeals-dion-barber-abuse-compensation-amount/105862254</link><description>The state of WA is appealing a record $2.8 million compensation payment awarded to Dion Barber, who suffered repeated sexual abuse while in state care during the 1980s and 1990s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e41686a64a06dc35c2c557558da4dcb</guid></item><item><title>Australia Kangaroos lose Xavier Coates and Zac Lomax ahead of rugby league Ashes in England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/kangaroos-lose-xavier-coates-zac-lomax-rugby-league-ashes/105863632</link><description>Australia suffers a double blow with Zac Lomax and Xavier Coates ruled out of the overseas tour through injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0d6fe219c5cfcc432c5c99a3e88b226</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105863898</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">250fa4d6f9e87b19ec96acde65af18af</guid></item><item><title>Police tactical operation in Revesby leaves cars with holes, windows smashed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/revesby-condell-park-tactical-arrest-police-fire-shots-at-car/105863486</link><description>A major police operation has taken place in Sydney's south-west after tactical operations officers conducted a "high risk" arrest on a suburban street.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fabe83686895e90c930f9ad9092cc79</guid></item><item><title>Surfer bitten twice by shark chasing seal off Kangaroo Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/shark-attacks-man-seal-uses-as-decoy-kangaroo-island/105863812</link><description>A surfer who was twice bitten by a shark that was reportedly chasing a seal in waters off Kangaroo Island, is recovering well with a coffee, according to his boss.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1b369fa6480a966dd5e0a9d060721c6</guid></item><item><title>Sheffield Shield round one: Victoria and NSW register wins, Tasmania bats for a draw against Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/sheffield-shield-round-one-victoria-and-nsw-register-wins/105863840</link><description>Victoria has upset reigning Sheffield Shield holders South Australia at the Adelaide Oval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d87a196b1e0545296dee75c1390f932</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds looking to change things up in second netball Test against South Africa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/australia-diamonds-south-africa-netball-second-test/105863906</link><description>Australian coach Stacey Marinkovich says she needs to try different combinations ahead of the Test series against New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c866a0db7bc54576ae7d2689ff95490</guid></item><item><title>Robin Williams's daughter begs fans to stop making AI content of her father</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/zelda-williams-calls-out-ai-video-of-late-father-robin-williams/105863964</link><description>The daughter of the late actor Robin Williams has condemned AI-generated content featuring her father's likeness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffd2a5defe194f05995a766f5c162ef7</guid></item><item><title>Scientists win Nobel Prize in Physics for discoveries in quantum mechanics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/scientists-physics-nobel-prize-quantum-mechanics-discovery/105863766</link><description>Three scientists have won the 2025 Nobel Prize in Physics for "the discovery of macroscopic quantum mechanical tunnelling and energy quantisation in an electric circuit".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e33d892453da0aeb26e45b03f8612f75</guid></item><item><title>Emmanuel Macron urged by his first PM to resign in escalating French crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/macron-urged-by-first-pm-to-resign-in-escalating-french-crisis/105864272</link><description>Emmanuel Macron's first prime minister urges the cornered French head of state to resign in a shock call that compounded an escalating political crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a9bdac4b0b2a74c58b74f54d75495b5</guid></item><item><title>Recently-elected German mayor Iris Stalzer in critical condition after being stabbed outside home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/herdecke-mayor-iris-stalzer-stabbed-in-germany-/105864280</link><description>Iris Stalzer, a Social Democrat who was elected mayor of Herdecke in the Ruhr region a week ago, is reportedly suffered life-threatening injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">167b87894c38ff1cccc6dda664d52cc7</guid></item><item><title>Research shows females carry a much higher genetic risk for major depression than males</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/queensland-depression-genetic-link-research-females-males/105864472</link><description>In a study involving about 200,000 people diagnosed with depression, scientists have identified almost twice as many genetic red flags in the DNA of females compared with males.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">992adc88f4efa48c96375158189324b7</guid></item><item><title>AFP Commissioner Krissy Barrett speaks with the ABC.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/afp-commissioner-krissy-barrett-speaks-with-the-abc/105862722</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1cfd1ae4c5fcc542f7f9613a01e3749</guid></item><item><title>New AFP boss warns hate crime laws may need to be strengthened further</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/afp-commissioner-krissy-barrett-national-security-warning/105848960</link><description>In a wide-ranging interview as she begins as AFP commissioner, Krissy Barrett announces a new sub-terror strike force, and flags that newly written hate crime laws may need to be strengthened further.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d0647acfa2b665dfd6ab93b824444e0</guid></item><item><title>Up to 3,000 flood victims' details have been given to ChatGPT. What does that mean for privacy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/can-private-information-uploaded-to-chatgpt-be-found-by-others/105858422</link><description>Data experts say it is hard to know what the implications are for 3,000 flood victims who have had personal information uploaded to the AI platform by a government contractor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b6ff30e1811147304ebcb6a92bbcce4</guid></item><item><title>BlueScope chief demands urgent action on 'broken' gas market to save industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/bluescope-steel-mark-vassella-press-club-speech-on-gas-crisis/105856934</link><description>A future made in Australia? Not if gas prices keep rising, major manufacturers warn as they call for urgent action to secure affordable supply.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc3ec4d318789f0142aff31a9de0f8a9</guid></item><item><title>Anika Wells points to surprise stress test of triple-0 network ahead of bushfire season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/surprise-drill-for-telcos-as-coalition-goes-after-wells/105863244</link><description>The adequacy of Australia's emergency call network will be stress tested with a surprise drill ahead of bushfire season, as the opposition ramps up its assault over the communication minister's handling of last month's fatal triple-0 outage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02ad837597eec81457217abff18e9818</guid></item><item><title>'Everyday living cost' or assistive technology? NDIS participants frustrated with flexibility of rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/participants-frustrated-with-ndis-support-rules/105815444</link><description>A year after a controversial NDIS change, advocates are growing increasingly concerned that "counterintuitive" and "nonsensical" funding decisions are reducing participant independence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">463a7d10821bae40d417e7cbf53a0d7b</guid></item><item><title>Warragul social group helping parents of children with disability find connection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/warragul-social-group-connects-parents-of-kids-with-disability/105812018</link><description>Parents of children with disability can miss out on social support, but a Victorian physiotherapist hopes to change that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62d5225573dfcab728349685dfc6dfeb</guid></item><item><title>Audit finds state government-run aged care facility inappropriately used restraints</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/disability-sa-northgate-restrictive-practices-prompt-outrage/105861214</link><description>A South Australian government aged care home, which looks after 23 people with dementia or complex disabilities, inappropriately used lap belts and other mechanical restraints to stop falls and control residents' behaviour, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfe50e1638f58d32951b2d2bf875d085</guid></item><item><title>Can Donald Trump win the Nobel Peace Prize? Experts say it's unlikely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/can-trump-win-nobel-peace-prize-expert-thoughts/105862126</link><description>US President Donald Trump has made no secret that he wants to win this year's Nobel Peace Prize. Here's why experts say it's unlikely he'll win the prestigious award.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40b81801bd48b020a2cee223d4417f19</guid></item><item><title>Tourism operators seek more funding to mitigate algal bloom impact in SA over summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/tourism-operators-seek-more-incentives-to-mitigate-algal-bloom/105862594</link><description>Tourism, seafood industry and community representatives are calling for greater funding, education and travel incentives ahead of the release of the South Australian government's upcoming Summer Plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9e5b120fcb56d82bd8c6da140631dca</guid></item><item><title>Sheffield Shield round one quick hits: Marnus Labuschagne enjoys timely century while Ashes Test hopefuls struggle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/sheffield-shield-round-one-quick-hits-labuschagne-century/105861198</link><description>The Sheffield Shield is underway, with all eyes on the contenders for Australia's problematic opener spot. Here are five quick hits from the opening round of the season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8af9da9a39c94a9f7e4cb1494d9164a1</guid></item><item><title>R360 players to be banned from international rugby union</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/sport-r360-players-will-be-banned-from-international-rugby-union/105864582</link><description>Rugby union players who sign up for the R360 breakaway franchise league will be ineligible for international selection, national governing bodies have confirmed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d618fd0e8467a243d4f99e91775e42c</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian government stadium report responds to planning commission's criticisms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/stadium-report-released-for-hobart-afl-macquarie-point-stadium/105805830</link><description>The state government response to last month's scathing report from the planning commission says that while "change can be challenging", the "dream of a Tasmanian team representing our state in the AFL and AFLW is now within reach — we cannot turn back".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a5d3dfd9f4b596cda1002d9c43f9ade</guid></item><item><title>Gold price hits record high, topping $US4,000 an ounce for first time, amid US shutdown and lower interest rates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/gold-price-hits-record-high-topping-4000-an-ounce/105863902</link><description>The price of gold has hit another record and is set to become Australia's second most valuable resource export after iron ore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8a6a55db842730246cc3ca2cf30402a</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police intercept alleged 'kill team' near daycare centre in Revesby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/nsw-revesby-police-intercept-kill-team-near-childcare-centre/105864634</link><description>Police say tactical officers foiled an alleged planned hit near a daycare centre in Revesby in Sydney's south-west on Tuesday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6fdc683fd3660f0c048758c5b3a8bd8</guid></item><item><title>US Senate committee questions Trump's Pentagon nominee John Noh over AUKUS review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/trump-pentagon-nominee-john-noh-questioned-on-aukus/105864552</link><description>The AUKUS submarine pact may need "commonsense" action from both Australia and the US to make it more "sustainable", according to Donald Trump's nominee to oversee US defence strategy in the Indo-Pacific.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0d29435ebb41a976009ed6932acad05</guid></item><item><title>Regulator investigating WA fire that burnt 11,000ha and left residents homeless</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/regulator-investigating-january-fire-in-wa-southern-wheatbelt/105830912</link><description>Residents who lost their homes in a blaze that ripped through WA's southern wheatbelt in January may have to wait more than two years to seek compensation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcb6cf350db3b25039b12adb41ae9aac</guid></item><item><title>Saltwater crocodile found with mouth zip-tied shut in Adelaide River, sparking calls for stronger penalties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/saltwater-crocodile-found-with-snout-zip-tied-in-darwin-nt/105848320</link><description>The discovery of a saltwater crocodile with its mouth bound shut by zip ties in a Darwin river has sparked outrage, with animal rights advocates calling for stronger wildlife protections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd6688be17a6ce08037f8d10631587f5</guid></item><item><title>As WA government looks set to bring Serie A game involving AC Milan to Perth, some football fans are not happy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/serie-a-game-perth-ac-milan-como-reaction/105861988</link><description>Italian heavyweights AC Milan look set to play a match, for actual Serie A points, in Perth. What will the state government pay to lure them here, and why are some football supporters unhappy?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ea1d7a00e17cb83abc6238ac91d46f8</guid></item><item><title>Surge in shark-tracking app downloads following fatal Sydney attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/downloads-increase-of-sharksmart-app-after-sydney-fatal-attack/105863682</link><description>There has been a surge in downloads of the SharkSmart app following the fatal attack of a Northern Beaches surfer — in a sign the incident has left some nervous to get back into the water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00d803bb4b6dccf774ca067d2e5c7022</guid></item><item><title>Players concerned over Shanghai heat as Novak Djokovic collapses on court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/players-concerned-over-shanghai-heat-as-novak-djokovic-col/105864786</link><description>Holger Rune says "there is always a limit" as soaring temperatures and humidity in Shanghai and Wuhan tennis events cause player distress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0a40634d1b457b5752fb7f8a643aea7</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, day three recap: Brisbane Lions land Oscar Allen, as Sam Flanders, Judd McVee and Brandon Starcevich find new homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/afl-trade-period-day-3-live-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca/105862940</link><description>Oscar Allen's move to Brisbane is official as West Coast finds out what compensation it will receive for losing its captain. Here's how day three of the AFL trade period panned out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a8dbfcdd651f8cb3552c19a5bbf32ce</guid></item><item><title>Police investigating after body found on road in Newborough, Gippsland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/body-found-gippsland-newborough-moe-police-investigate/105864816</link><description>The discovery was made early this morning. Traffic diversions are in place and specialist detectives are set to investigate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc86701297322da6434c82ca1caa35d2</guid></item><item><title>Australian merino wool future positive after surging price restores grower confidence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/surging-wool-price-restores-grower-confidence-in-aussie-merino/105845730</link><description>Amid a run of price rises at Australian wool auctions, the next generation of growers say global demand and fresh confidence could mark a turning point for the fibre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a54f47d8d99a1127e10b40056ef58297</guid></item><item><title>Taylor Swift wears Adelaide label Paolo Sebastian in The Fate of Ophelia music video</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/taylor-swift-wears-paolo-sebastian-dress/105864738</link><description>Founder and designer Paul Vasileff says he's grateful to have his Adelaide-made couture dress on the world stage with pop superstar Taylor Swift wearing it in the new The Fate of Ophelia music video.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0332df3f421d0e89d81fee932d81f9b</guid></item><item><title>Neighbour of Kotoni Staggs pays tribute to Broncos star after supporting family through husband's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/kotoni-staggs-tribute-after-death-of-david-orange/105864876</link><description>The neighbour of Kotoni Staggs pays tribute to the Broncos star for helping her through a devastating family death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08ab9d0efbc29ab8d98a303c4c86194f</guid></item><item><title>Australians are reading less than ever before. Here's how to read more books</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/how-to-read-more-books-when-reading-rates-are-declining/105857550</link><description>Research shows Australians are reading fewer books than ever before. One writer shares her advice on how to make reading a daily habit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c18e0ca034d56b4b48cf5532a280e3a6</guid></item><item><title>Pam Bondi accused of using justice system to target Donald Trump's opponents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/pam-bondi-accused-of-using-doj-to-target-donald-trump-opponents/105864762</link><description>US Attorney-General Pam Bondi has faced heated questioning from senators over claims she's transforming the justice department into a "shield for the president and his political allies".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e370271e506a39abe7bb883d20d3aff</guid></item><item><title>Arsenal lose 2-1 to Lyon at Women's Champions League as trio of Matildas feature</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/womens-champions-league-arsenal-lose-to-lyon/105865154</link><description>Arsenal goes down 2-1 to Lyon in the Women's Champion League as three Matildas stars make an appearance at Meadow Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6ab5ae4953fe13baa90426dc6bb6897</guid></item><item><title>WA iron ore mining shows no signs of slowing despite price drop concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/rio-tinto-bhp-continue-to-invest-in-pilbara-iron-ore-mining/105862166</link><description>Australia's two biggest iron ore miners continue to expand their operations in WA's Pilbara, despite warnings of waning demand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8309ec60fbd1a3ef21ca4c2344103b7</guid></item><item><title>More families raising children with cystic fibrosis staying in the bush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/outback-life-kids-cystic-fibrosis/105843356</link><description>Two mums in rural Queensland have spoken about why they choose to live more than 1,000 kilometres from the Queensland Children's Hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d919ce008ebdfdac5b3cf84ab09bed02</guid></item><item><title>Single farmers in Western Australia ditch dating apps for something face to face</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/farmers-single-mingle-speed-dating/105843296</link><description>When the dating app radius won't reach the edge of your property, and you're harvesting grain from sun-up til sundown, how do you find a partner?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08d15c91b798615b073d0cf6ec0e8cb3</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of court cases potentially compromised amid Victoria Police investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/victoria-police-audit-sex-offence-cases-potentially-compromised/105864962</link><description>Police have arrested a digital forensics officer and are investigating whether his work compromised hundreds of cases over nearly a decade including sexual offence and child abuse cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a7453570f7b1c6a6ea15dd2c467e2dd</guid></item><item><title>WA's Bibbulmun Track running record broken twice in one week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/record-for-bibbulmun-track-broken-twice-in-a-week/105862894</link><description>Two men have smashed the record for completing one of the world's longest walking tracks in the fastest time, within days of each other.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d30da50c333b34f04755b1e8b4637c1</guid></item><item><title>Glencore refinery sites stay open with taxpayer funds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/glencore-copper-queensland-smelter-refinery-open/105462262</link><description>The last Australian copper smelter processing third-party product will stay open after its owner accepted a support package.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e6c15045f1cc98d2905cdee8a8e6ebc</guid></item><item><title>Last night's harvest moon made for stunning photos. When is the next supermoon?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/harvest-moon-photos-when-is-the-next-supermoon-/105864622</link><description>Stargazers from around the world have captured the luminous glow of October's supermoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b8da86f3072d1f3813b7bd9b88f7e17</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr to play for Matildas for the first time in two years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/sam-kerr-matildas-return-mary-fowler-asian-cup/105864112</link><description>Sam Kerr's two year absence from the Matildas is almost over, she's set to feature in friendlies later this month, while Mary Fowler is recovering well from her own ACL injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">702d31688fd2da622b3e1419726855e7</guid></item><item><title>More than 500 hikers reportedly rescued after being stranded on Mount Everest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/mountain-everest-hikers-rescued-blizzard-tibet/105864778</link><description>Hundreds of trekkers, villagers and support staff have safely reached the Tibetan town of Qudang, according to Chinese state media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33bcbc3a4f3e7c41f2704aebf600f9c7</guid></item><item><title>Geelong Cats fined by AFL over third-party arrangements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/geelong-cats-fined-by-afl-over-third-party-disclosures/105866216</link><description>The AFL fines Geelong $77,500 for failing to disclose third-party agreements with players over a six-year period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f8e13e797e402b65d8ae17b2688c11f</guid></item><item><title>Male humpback whales race in pursuit of female during east coast migration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/male-whales-race-in-pursuit-of-female-in-east-coast-migration/105861060</link><description>A drone photographer captures vision of a tightly packed pod of 11 humpback whales heading south in a race to mate off the NSW mid-north coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eaad686271b69be2d05ad42ad5ebf30b</guid></item><item><title>Male whales race in pursuit of female in east coast migration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/male-whales-race-in-pursuit-of-female-in-east/105866386</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55b8752a7c5fd19bc070efbd5ef98490</guid></item><item><title>Surfer bitten by shark chasing seal off Kangaroo Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/surfer-bitten-by-shark-chasing-seal-off-kangaroo-island/105866450</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28aca7d922cfde7788f5978a622379e1</guid></item><item><title>Dolly Parton's sister speaks out over singer's health concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/dolly-parton-sister-speaks-out-las-vegas-concerts-delayed/105866370</link><description>Dolly Parton's sister has asked fans to pray for the country music singer's health just one week after the star delayed several concerts in Las Vegas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">002181e5b2952a8159dea961b0c5c76d</guid></item><item><title>Man spared jail time by ACT court after he raped and filmed woman without consent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/paul-james-donnelly-spared-jail-rape-woman-met-on-tinder/105866018</link><description>A 38-year-old man has been spared jail time, partly on account of his autism diagnosis, after raping a woman he met online and filming their sexual encounters without consent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d65f8d8e2b2e6eb767bbc69fe77554a4</guid></item><item><title>Optus email mishap left department in dark about triple-0 outage, even after Anika Wells' office told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/optus-email-mishap-left-department-in-dark/105866628</link><description>The telco operator sent two emails about its outage, which understated its extent, to a departmental email address that had been changed a week earlier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">076c258d9594921f83dc78f45a740c8e</guid></item><item><title>Abuse survivor Dion Barber 'mortified' by state's challenge of $2.85m compensation payout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/dion-barber-child-sexual-abuse-compensation-appeal-reaction/105866440</link><description>An appeal against a $2.85 million compensation payout to a man who suffered child sexual abuse while in state care should be abandoned, a prominent Perth lawyer and the state opposition says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">730cc98d181b155b9543fde30e7e2642</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police hold 'significant concerns' about planned pro-Palestinian march to Sydney Opera House</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/police-concerned-with-pro-palestinian-march-sydney-opera-house/105866112</link><description>A senior NSW Police officer has expressed cynicism that a crowd of tens of thousands could be managed in a staggered manner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5c8ad22018d9bafdb39ed42fd7fa602</guid></item><item><title>Ecuadorian protesters filmed throwing rocks in alleged presidential assassination attempt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/ecuador-protesters-alleged-daniel-noboa-assassination-attempt/105866368</link><description>Five people have been detained after hundreds of protesters surrounded the presidential motorcade of Daniel Noboa and began throwing rocks and stones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09226775ccfe0c4292d465c3315aeca2</guid></item><item><title>City of Stirling terminates football club's lease after player's alleged explicit Stephen Hawking costume</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/osborne-park-fc-stephen-hawking-silly-sunday-costume/105866188</link><description>A Perth football club faces deregistration and has been expelled from their club rooms after a player reportedly attended a post-season party dressed as Stephen Hawking, allegedly with explicit images involving himself as a child attached.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9da9996042f9a3ca08b4afec97e1cd7d</guid></item><item><title>Former clinical director Hannah Lake leads Hobart Clinic rescue bid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/hannah-lake-in-hobart-clinic-rescue-bid/105866436</link><description>The former clinical director of the Hobart Clinic, psychiatrist Dr Hannah Lake, is part of a last-minute push for the institution to be given a reprieve before it closes its doors at the end of next week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13ff2d4aa757dfd275b29ddc0ded6164</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne man sentenced over medical cannabis company Cann Group insider trading case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/man-sentenced-over-medical-cannabis-cann-group-insider-trading/105865698</link><description>A Melbourne man found guilty of insider trading during a $20 million capital raise by a medicinal cannabis company has been ordered to pay more than $225,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dc238f9150615779cfae17a7ffe5073</guid></item><item><title>AFLW Carlton star Darcy Vescio says 'punching down' on Mad Monday must end</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/aflw-carlton-darcy-vescio-mad-monday-pride/105867186</link><description>Inaugural Carlton AFLW star Darcy Vescio has urged players to be more conscious of their role-model status when dressing up for end-of-season celebrations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8aa8bc4d3b0c0602e2afe2492234d703</guid></item><item><title>Qantas says 'legal protections in place' as cyber hacking group threatens to release personal data</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/qantas-responds-to-cyber-hacker-threat-to-release-data/105866656</link><description>Qantas says it is continuing to support customers as a hacking group threatens to release personal data from around 40 companies to the dark web.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">579d41470988631592c5369804bffca5</guid></item><item><title>Trade restrictions for Philippines banana imports to be reviewed by federal government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/australian-government-review-banana-imports-from-philippines/105863456</link><description>The federal government will review its quarantine rules after a formal request by the Philippines to import its bananas, but the industry is pushing back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3914bf6a6bd32339f4e721ddf4773ebe</guid></item><item><title>Scramble to protect Kangaroo Island bee colony, one of the world's unique colonies, from varroa mite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/beekeepers-welcome-extra-varroa-biosecurity-for-kangaroo-island/105865160</link><description>A deadly parasite that has laid waste to bee colonies throughout Australia has so far not made it to Kangaroo Island, home to the world's oldest bee sanctuary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6145c18bd3b3f056f510a5b63f60615b</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Collingwood player Shannon Cox jailed for killing women in Brand Hwy car crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/former-afl-player-shannon-cox-sentenced-for-fatal-road-crash/105864080</link><description>Former Collingwood player Shannon Cox, who had meth in his system when his car smashed into a hatchback, killing two elderly women, is jailed for manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db37245d6c5e233b1abdae93f311f4fc</guid></item><item><title>Hobart's Macquarie Point stadium debate weighs 'expert' advice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/hobart-macquarie-point-stadium-debate/105865012</link><description>Tasmania's minister responsible for the proposed $1.13 billion Macquarie Point stadium, Eric Abetz, says there are many "expert" views, but ultimately the government will decide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb634d41fd45254375e1e37438c6811d</guid></item><item><title>Strava is suing Garmin for patent infringement. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/why-is-strava-suing-garmin/105865392</link><description>Fitness app Strava and sports watchmaker Garmin usually go hand-in-hand, but the two fitness tech leaders are now in competition in a US lawsuit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">405e53404a636a1e020301726d45cc2f</guid></item><item><title>Stephen Miller has said Donald Trump has plenary authority but what does that actually mean?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/stephen-miller-donald-trump-plenary-authority/105865430</link><description>A Trump administration official faces criticism after allegedly claiming US President Donald Trump has "plenary authority" while on a live interview with CNN.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7749a6fbb7a76dc4181cbe4a0e3a80c7</guid></item><item><title>Do dishwashers release microplastics when you wash plastic containers and kitchenware?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/do-dishwashers-release-microplastics-wash-plastic-containers/105860862</link><description>If you're worried about microplastics, is it safe to wash plastic containers and other utensils in the dishwasher, given the use of heat and detergents? We asked two experts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fd5611f6ea7fae53cd7f7e02afd0135</guid></item><item><title>Jon Stevens releases new album Shimmer, announces tour on 64th birthday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/jon-stevens-new-album-shimmer-announces-tour-on-64th-birthday/105867096</link><description>From teen idol to rock great, Jon Stevens has fronted legendary bands Noiseworks and INXS. He has chosen his 64th birthday to release a new album and announce a tour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afdcebd18dbb3b1f571e9a4bc92e8758</guid></item><item><title>Three charged with murder and torture of Brisbane man Andrew Burow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/qld-andrew-burow-investigation-three-charged-with-murder/105866608</link><description>Police will allege Andrew Burow endured a three to four-day ordeal which began after meeting with the accused in August.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c2ceca2aab98422918a40ced8c296b3</guid></item><item><title>Former RAAF pilot Robert John Crawford appears in court, charged with murder of wife Frances Crawford</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/queensland-robert-crawford-committed-trial-alleged-murder/105865292</link><description>Robert John Crawford has been charged with murder over the death of his wife at their home in July 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60e067671364f051a50810e58c33d586</guid></item><item><title>City of Melbourne set to vote on security camera overhaul, surveillance powers for staff</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/melbourne-city-council-cctv-security-network-proposed-expansion/105864992</link><description>The City of Melbourne is set to vote on a new plan that would see more privately owned CCTV cameras feeding into the city's security network and staff able to access the footage to investigate local law breaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e651efd7aa333e63fda95c9803c5fcae</guid></item><item><title>Australia's parliament is likely to grow for the first time in 40 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/parliament-increase-fixed-terms-senate-estimates/105865534</link><description>Australia's parliament is likely to get larger as the government canvasses possibilities for expanding the number of MPs and introducing fixed or four-year terms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47e1e744d90a2df3ebb85c40bc9c207c</guid></item><item><title>Algal bloom chief asked about 'disaster' declaration as inquiry told of thousands of marine deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/algal-bloom-parliamentary-inquiry-told-of-marine-death-tolls/105866214</link><description>The SA government has never formally requested that the Commonwealth declare the algal bloom a "national disaster", a senior bureaucrat has told a parliamentary inquiry — despite a state minister "advocating" for such a response three months ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">daf6411ce251563c25ae83ac3c0acbde</guid></item><item><title>Audit reveals widespread public housing electrical issues in wake of three-year-old's tragic death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/mitchell-thomas-inquest-alice-springs-house-fire-audit/105867072</link><description>The death of a three-year-old boy in an Alice Springs house fire has led to an electrical audit of Northern Territory public housing, which uncovered widespread issues affecting hundreds of homes, an inquest has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47454752054229e91ce6cd896977bb0e</guid></item><item><title>Grieving Canberra dog owner warns of deadly blue-green algae but testing shows no increased risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/warning-blue-green-algae-lake-ginninderra-toxic-dog-dead/105865256</link><description>Toxic algae is sometimes detected in Canberra's waterways, where a dog died after swimming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf133c39e7536cf2d8235f23b13118b4</guid></item><item><title>Jordan Spencer jailed for 13 years for setting woman alight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/jordan-spencer-jailed-for-13-years-for-setting-rival-alight/105866418</link><description>A 34-year-old Shepparton woman has been jailed for 13 years after dousing another woman with petrol and setting her on fire during a dispute over an e-scooter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">707885cae62c2b76a53d98bee76345dc</guid></item><item><title>Murder trial begins for man accused of killing and burning David Collisson near Mudgee</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/murder-trial-begins-after-bones-found-near-mudgee/105856394</link><description>David Collisson's remains were found near Mudgee in October 2023. It is believed he was shot dead a month earlier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32b187aeb064d392310444ba7f12356b</guid></item><item><title>With pressure from China to last, more metals facilities could put their hands up for a bailout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/metals-facility-bailout-china-price-pressure/105865170</link><description>The bailout of another metals facility — this time in Queensland — is unlikely to be the last, with pressures on the sector driven by China to keep up for years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">178a81a316c523f3b3497386fb31f5cf</guid></item><item><title>British man jailed in New York over $US99 million fine wine fraud scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/british-man-pleads-guilty-to-wine-fraud/105867228</link><description>The scheme ran from June 2017 to February 2019, and collapsed when interest payments stopped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">304f6da93469258db1ce9b623d7ddcbc</guid></item><item><title>Mates channel MacGyver in rescue of galah trapped in power pole in WA's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/macgyver-style-rescue-of-galah-in-wa-north-goes-viral/105865732</link><description>A lifetime sailor says his experience problem-solving with limited resources helped figure out how to rescue a galah trapped in an 8-metre-tall power pole.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1c6d99ab2227d23bfdd561aeeaec0e4</guid></item><item><title>Callum Cook pleads not guilty to Christmas Day murder of Russell Klein in Millmerran</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/millmerran-christmas-day-murder-trial-begins/105867224</link><description>A barrister for the accused tells a Queensland court Callum Cook acted in self-defence during an incident that left a 55-year-old father dead in his front yard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ce42627a30b0cc2aabc6cb09e5cec60</guid></item><item><title>Labor backbencher calls for action to stop countries onselling Australian gas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/ed-husic-gas-reserve-stop-foreign-onselling/105868522</link><description>Ed Husic calls for stronger action to prevent foreign countries that buy Australian gas from onselling it to other countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42f93ef61706ee720ac19d9c1c2ebe2a</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar's military uses paraglider to bomb festival and anti-junta protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/dozens-killed-in-myanmar-military-strike-on-festival/105868620</link><description>People were gathering for the festival and an anti-junta demonstration when bombs killed at least 20 people and injured dozens more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be1cd3bf5f119b10691e3900edf734f0</guid></item><item><title>Beth Mooney, Alana King save Australia from Women's Cricket World Cup upset loss to Pakistan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/womens-cricket-world-cup-live-australia-pakistan-scores/105865554</link><description>Beth Mooney's century and a classy unbeaten 51 from Alana King saves Australia from a stunning upset loss to Pakistan at the Cricket World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68de1642a2a5924a00441e4e4b57ef52</guid></item><item><title>Latest Financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/latest-financial-news/105868506</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1a868105805417396e4aa5c69b199e6</guid></item><item><title>Trio of scientists awarded Nobel Prize in Chemistry for 'development of metal-organic frameworks'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/nobel-prize-in-chemistry-announced/105868538</link><description>Scientists Susumu Kitagawa, Richard Robson and Omar Yaghi receive the 2025 Nobel Prize in Chemistry "for the development of metal-organic frameworks", the award-giving body announces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f15011661bf2d10170a38ea0db800969</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds put foot down to beat South Africa in 67-40 victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/netball-second-test-australia-diamonds-south-africa/105866192</link><description>Australia flew out of the blocks to take a 2-0 lead in the series and extend their unbeaten record against South Africa to an extraordinary 48 wins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0427a680bc32ada296a05841db9a59e</guid></item><item><title>News Corp executive warns AI firms are asking Australia to 'surrender our stories'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/news-corp-chairman-warns-of-impact-of-ai/105868882</link><description>News Corp Australasia executive chairman Michael Miller issues a call to arms for all media companies to stand together and demand the government rule out any changes to copyright laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c0e3025b7eda15bcc138db9fd43f1e1</guid></item><item><title>Former FBI director James Comey pleads not guilty in Congress case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/fbi-james-comey-pleads-not-guilty/105868956</link><description>The guilty plea follows an extraordinary chain of events that saw Mr Trump publicly implore Attorney General Pam Bondi to take action against Mr Comey and other perceived adversaries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fd328797f1f1abe6fed7f0fe675ae4b</guid></item><item><title>Jonathan Rinderknecht arrested and charged with deliberately lighting Pacific Palisades blaze in Los Angeles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/man-arrested-charged-lighting-los-angeles-pacific-palisades-fire/105869026</link><description>Police arrested and charged Jonathan Rinderknecht over the fire this week, which was the most destructive in Los Angeles's history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92369c05e25867d8eac4db63d06ae393</guid></item><item><title>Can we still trust Australia's sunscreens?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/sunscreen-spf-factor-labelling-tga/105866434</link><description>Summer is just around the corner, and many Australians are confused right now about which sunscreens they can trust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a36a8730c1869e4f7b2ec19d264243d0</guid></item><item><title>Optus wears blame but government needs to explain how it handled early advice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/optus-triple-zero-communications-anika-wells-senate-estimates/105830532</link><description>The government is determined to avoid wearing any blame for Optus' failure but also needs to be transparent about how it handled early advice from the telco.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98d8487976bf0f469413f350d685cb67</guid></item><item><title>Older Australians struggling to find work before hitting the pension age</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/struggle-to-find-work-before-hitting-pension-age/105866550</link><description>In the three years that 65-year-old Kerry Forrest has been applying for positions, she has faced repeated rejection. She thinks it is time employers consider older workers more favourably.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d07133eca0875d7bd02bcb35fe05a6b4</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic icebreaker's costly refuelling saga yet to be resolved</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/icebreakers-costly-refuelling-saga-yet-to-be-resolved/105868524</link><description>Two years after the RSV Nuyina was banned from going under Hobart's Tasman Bridge to refuel, the Australian Antarctic Division has formally ditched the possibility of trying to overturn the decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">252662d22385cd7b44b5dcdb37754300</guid></item><item><title>In voice notes from Gaza, Majeda chronicles her family's displacement and despair</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/the-journey-of-displacement-from-gaza-city/105776430</link><description>The war in Gaza may be ending soon, but those displaced by Israel's bombardment and invasion know their suffering is far from over.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89f402e8df29b0f402e5e387289edcf1</guid></item><item><title>Renewed focus on 'kill cars' as police swarm on hit crew in Sydney's south-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/sydney-underworld-kill-cars-used-in-organised-crime/105867242</link><description>It is a tried and true tactic in the underworld when trying to get away with murder, but police have sought out "kill cars" and they are reaping the rewards from it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1125b8693a60adab9b8ae8ca0de866e</guid></item><item><title>Australia's energy transition in flux amid struggle to build major transmission arteries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/australia-energy-transition-hampered-by-power-lines/105838808</link><description>Touted as a model for the energy transition, a "quick and easy" high-voltage powerline project linking South Australia directly to New South Wales is running dramatically over time and over budget.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3919f7987267766fce355906093f6bda</guid></item><item><title>University wrongly accuses students of using artificial intelligence to cheat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/artificial-intelligence-cheating-australian-catholic-university/105863524</link><description>An Australian university has accused thousands of its students of cheating with artificial intelligence. The problem? Many have done nothing wrong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9aa7eccad194fe36c313cc265ad306a3</guid></item><item><title>Annabel Kennedy eyes F1 Academy after becoming first female to stand on Indian F4 podium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/australian-annabel-kennedy-eyes-f1-academy/105844394</link><description>With success at home and abroad, Annabel Kennedy is part of a growing number of Australian women and girls making their mark in motorsport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adb2eff37cf9c374c8f01f22435bfcf2</guid></item><item><title>Third narco sub found in Solomon Islands, as cocaine and meth trafficking comes to the Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/narco-sub-cocaine-meth-solomon-islands-pacific/105865658</link><description>Cousins Reubenson and Martin Fugui found a 'Made in Colombia' narco sub in Solomon Islands over the weekend — the third such vessel found in the country's waters over the past year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ccb8717f57ba48e14b4a6f2a33a4d8f</guid></item><item><title>Inappropriate use of restraints on Adelaide aged care home residents echoes elements of the Oakden scandal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/sa-northgate-analysis/105867062</link><description>An audit has revealed an Adelaide aged care facility was inappropriately using restraints on patients, raising the question of whether the state government has learned from the Oakden aged care scandal in 2017.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">452cb3f1727311b0bf78ddcf26ff3112</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government urged to take stronger action on conservation as number of threatened species rises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/calls-for-stronger-action-queensland-great-barrier-reef-species/105867412</link><description>The Queensland Conservation Council (QCC) has called out the LNP government for "not taking the environment seriously" with the number of flora and fauna species under threat on the rise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b70dd89997ce7aa2dc6d03f773c448ec</guid></item><item><title>Domain rental report for September quarter shows rent for houses stable across combined capital cities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/domain-rental-report-september-quarter-2025/105868398</link><description>Domain's September quarterly report shows house rents across the country's combined capitals have remained stable for five consecutive quarters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4195ce266d53f9e8b7b3108d8b6860ff</guid></item><item><title>Powerlifting champion aged 82 and ready to represent Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/powerlifting-champion-aged-82-and-ready-to/105868692</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e86a029c85c4645e6a5b1179ad310de</guid></item><item><title>Man who turned to weightlifting for health now headed to powerlifting world championships at 82</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/powerlifting-champion-aged-82-and-ready-to-represent-australia/105868066</link><description>Ravi Sood turned to the gym to help build muscle before a knee replacement. It has changed his life and led him to the World Masters Powerlifting Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37b1b80b2e0569777da0ad8458a97675</guid></item><item><title>Police thought alleged Croydon Park gunman was 'fine' in weeks leading up to shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/family-alleged-croydon-park-shooter-say-police-did-welfare-check/105868196</link><description>A close family member of Artemios Mintzas tells the ABC she asked police to visit his unit three weeks ago, after growing increasingly concerned about his state of mind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cb199ba95aa21735b44bbe20a97b100</guid></item><item><title>Murray Watt nears deal with Coalition to finally overhaul environment laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/watt-coalition-near-deal-epbc-environment-laws/105865472</link><description>Environment Minister Murray Watt will sit down with his Liberal counterpart Angie Bell today, with quiet optimism in both parties that a deal might soon be struck to finally rewrite Australia's "broken" and outdated environment laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">826e7cc6dd7537e0557ff29d46425beb</guid></item><item><title>Infant's death in illegal Robinvale childcare centre among sector's secret failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/nanicha-singchart-childcare-death-among-dozens-of-vic-incidents/105863798</link><description>The death of a 15-week-old baby in an unlicensed home day care in Victoria’s north-west is among more than two dozen disturbing childcare incidents recorded in government documents unearthed by the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c4247f6a5ffdf24ec78c48a9f742fcd</guid></item><item><title>Advocates say First Nations children's commissioner must have power to make change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/snaicc-conference-first-nations-childrens-commissioner/105865612</link><description>Governments have been unable to reduce the rates of First Nations children in out-of-care and youth detention. Advocates say the new children's commissioner needs the power to hold them to account.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8fcc6e4952034663250399e1ab743fd</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Shadow treasurer ejected from QT as Chalmers pokes fun — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/federal-politics-live-blog-october-9/105868056</link><description>Ted O'Brien is ejected from Question Time as Jim Chalmers jokes his counterpart's question wasn't "based on reality".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc43947e1726992ff93fbabd439ddbb4</guid></item><item><title>Family donates $1.7 million to transform dementia care at aged care facility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/family-donation-to-reshape-dementia-care-in-stawell/105865792</link><description>An aged care facility in western Victoria receives an "unprecedented" donation that will allow it to enhance the lives of residents living with dementia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c79206d096282f78f6a33d3d4655ea3f</guid></item><item><title>ASX rises as Wall Street notches fresh records, Fed split on rates — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/asx-markets-business-live-news-oct-9/105869198</link><description>The S&amp;P and Nasdaq close at new highs as Australian stocks follow their upwards trajectory. Look back on the day's financial news and insights from our specialist business reporters on our live blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d8f99193883e6edbd6f8111a8996590</guid></item><item><title>Hereditary fructose intolerance group to raise awareness about often-misdiagnosed condition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/hereditary-fructose-intolerance-support-group/105762986</link><description>A Queensland woman is on a mission to raise awareness about hereditary fructose intolerance, after having to wait until age 45 to understand why so many foods make her sick.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f0f08453e32ae97dac0be23d422ac74</guid></item><item><title>Endometriosis sufferers battling to manage pain as system struggles to cope</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/endometriosis-sufferers-struggle-pain-mental-health/105811172</link><description>Women suffering from the chronic pain associated with endometriosis have called for more government investment into understanding the condition, with an expert warning the mental effects can be just as debilitating as the physical symptoms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efee30effa42b7415297303fa8cdabb8</guid></item><item><title>Manhunt underway after man shot dead, cars set alight in Sydney's Riverstone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/nsw-police-investigating-riverstone-shooting-suman-mokhtarian/105869128</link><description>In the footage obtained by the ABC, several shots could be heard ringing out as a toddler was seen standing in a driveway metres from where Suman Mokhtarian was killed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13b706c07889044861805802890bc7b1</guid></item><item><title>Gisele Pelicot tells rapist appealing guilty verdict to 'take responsibility'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/gisele-pelicot-urges-accused-rapist-to-take-responsibility/105869154</link><description>Gisele Pelicot returns to court to face the only man, out of 51, who appealed against his guilty verdict in a mass rape trial that gained worldwide attention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10f66d3a16b26cbe9b2adbb6626c37b1</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, day four recap: St Kilda causes a stir by aborting Leek Aleer deal after adding Liam Ryan, Max Heath joins Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/afl-trade-period-day-four-live-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca/105868314</link><description>St Kilda officially adds Liam Ryan in a trade with West Coast as the AFL world continues to react to the Saints' stunning decision to pull out of a move for Leek Aleer. Here's how day four of the AFL trade period panned out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61352215a3672db81129ef51e60bb9ea</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur wins 50th tennis match for 2025, reaching Shanghai Masters clash with Daniil Medvedev</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/alex-de-minaur-wins-50th-match-of-2025-at-shanghai-masters/105869206</link><description>Alex de Minaur wins 50 matches in a season for the first time in his career as he reaches the quarterfinals at the Shanghai Masters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f318b33e8803f18a1248bbeb3fc659a</guid></item><item><title>AC Milan star Adrien Rabiot says plan to play Serie A match in Perth is 'truly absurd'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/ac-milan-in-perth-plan-criticised-by-star-player-rabiot/105869346</link><description>AC Milan midfielder Adrien Rabiot hits out at plans to play a game in Perth, earning a rebuke from the Serie A chief executive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b67cb7b2da39989b0184ef8b981ebc78</guid></item><item><title>Measles warning in WA's Pilbara as confirmed cases rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/measles-cases-from-unknown-source-climbing-in-wa/105867168</link><description>Health authorities say they are not able to trace WA's latest measles cases to a source, meaning they cannot tell how far the virus has spread.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e5094457d4a2fdecf3cadb2c8f3f399</guid></item><item><title>Beast of War is the indie shark movie that bit off a lot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/beast-of-war-kiah-roache-turner-mark-coles-smith/105857098</link><description>Mystery Road star Mark Coles Smith and his Beast of War director Kiah Roache-Turner on taking a chomp out of WWII soldiers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c11e53d16ff74618f42da0430ef3787b</guid></item><item><title>Self-taught child drummer makes rock band debut with The Living End</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/child-drummer-plays-with-the-living-end-wanderer-festival/105861302</link><description>It was a dream come true when 12-year-old Noah Pope was pulled from the crowd to perform with The Living End.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">344b9fa1c598bc226869e34d887a6ff5</guid></item><item><title>Trump says Israel Gaza war ceasefire deal is 'very close', Rubio more cautious</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/trump-says-deal-to-end-israel-gaza-war-is-very-close/105869362</link><description>Donald Trump is handed a note from Marco Rubio during White House talks saying: "We're very close to a deal in the Middle East."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee742bc1a3df383a7ab9cff87ff3c6ec</guid></item><item><title>Dolly Parton responds to concerns about her health, says she is not dying</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/dolly-parton-reassures-fans-after-health-concerns/105869280</link><description>Dolly Parton has taken to social media to hose down speculation about her health after a comment from her sister sent fans into a tailspin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9cf814360dff4a14df6f80136217574</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr returns to Champions League in Chelsea's draw with Twente Enschede</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/sam-kerr-returns-to-champions-league-football/105869372</link><description>Australian striker Sam Kerr makes another appearance for Chelsea off the bench, getting 23 minutes of playing time but unable to break a 1-1 deadlock with their Dutch opponent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8be88f2cf245467da33d855cd83d496a</guid></item><item><title>NSW court rules in police's favour over planned Sydney Opera House pro-Palestine march</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/nsw-pro-palestinian-sydney-opera-house-protest-decision/105869474</link><description>The Palestine Action Group had expected 40,000 people to attend the rally on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c236965947507fe92677293c620d060a</guid></item><item><title>Friends believe Mark Sear's disappearance in Kimberley is suspicious</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/missing-man-mark-sear-wa-suspicious-friends-say/105866728</link><description>Friends of Mark Sear, who has been missing in WA's Kimberley for nearly three weeks, say the disappearance should be treated as suspicious.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f514d0e0ff425cf3de9669eb9d84230f</guid></item><item><title>Israel and Hamas agree to first phase of peace plan, Donald Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/israel-hamas-agree-first-phase-peace-plan/105356144</link><description>US President Donald Trump says Israel and the militant group Hamas have accepted the first phase of a peace plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57611618e3e61827cbf9c31d5a43d060</guid></item><item><title>Gaza updates: Israelis and Palestinians celebrate agreement on first phase of peace proposal — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/israel-and-hamas-agree-to-gaza-peace-proposal/105356146</link><description>US President Donald Trump says Israel and the militant group Hamas have signed off on the first phase of a Gaza peace proposal that would see a pause in fighting and the release of at least some hostages and prisoners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e786618afe3994238f153a2d53cf775</guid></item><item><title>Martin Dole named Northern Territory police commissioner after inquiry into recruitment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/martin-dole-named-nt-new-police-commissioner/105869520</link><description>Seven months after the Northern Territory's former police commissioner Michael Murphy was stood down, Acting Police Commissioner Martin Dole has been announced as the next person to take on the position of top cop.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d183443749986f42e62ebfa03c94b839</guid></item><item><title>Argentina-Puerto Rico football friendly moved from Chicago amid immigration crack down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/argentina-puerto-rico-game-moved-over-national-guard-in-chicago/105869564</link><description>An Argentine Football Association executive confirms an upcoming football match against Puerto Rico is moving from Chicago due to the National Guard being called in to quell immigration protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35a5e12e2ec1b8bc2ccbf801832e994b</guid></item><item><title>RFS firefighter seriously injured by falling tree at Coutts Crossing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/firefighter-injured-by-falling-tree-at-coutts-crossing/105869728</link><description>A volunteer firefighter is hospitalised with head and neck injuries after being hit by a falling tree on a fireground on the NSW north coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">654deebe092f5cd200812102adee8fc4</guid></item><item><title>Fertiliser plant uncertainty puts Mount Isa Copper Smelter future in doubt despite bailout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/dyno-nobel-fertiliser-plant-impact-on-mount-isa-copper-smelter/105869194</link><description>Mining giant Glencore's government bailout was touted as its outback smelter's saving grace, but uncertainty about a fertiliser plant it relies on could still see it cease production before 2028.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42624d0211cf45c084e8456b48de4067</guid></item><item><title>Albany's tiny art gallery joins growing global community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/tiny-art-gallery-albany-global-movement/105857528</link><description>A new tiny art gallery on WA's south coast adds to a growing global movement of community verge-side offerings that range from puzzles to seed exchange.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbdc3d5da80b26f3c016522a14117d79</guid></item><item><title>Victorian judge wrong about Erin Patterson's solitary confinement prospects, prosecutors say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/erin-patterson-appeal-prosecutors-jail-mushroom-murder/105869802</link><description>In sentencing the triple-murderer, Justice Christopher Beale found there was a substantial chance she would remain in solitary confinement for years, which prosecutors dispute.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92d90a8049ad76f0295a83e4305c39c2</guid></item><item><title>The draft order to approve Hobart's stadium has been released. So what's in it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/hobart-stadium-draft-order-released/105869502</link><description>Tasmania's parliamentarians have received a draft version of the order they'll vote on to determine the fate of the Macquarie Point Stadium project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e435ec76e14e5d0b3b06f97c8960bb31</guid></item><item><title>Madeleine McCann's mother tells court she is distressed by stalker who claims to be her daughter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/mother-of-missing-maddie-mccann-tells-of-fear-of-alleged-stalker/105869518</link><description>The mother of Madeleine McCann says a woman accused of stalking her for over two years made her feel distressed and "invaded" by approaching her at her house and claiming to be her daughter. Madeleine went missing in 2007, aged three.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f8625e45bd8b707808a0ca9dfc3e675</guid></item><item><title>RSL NSW president Mick Bainbridge and three board members resign in wake of 7.30 investigation into conflicts of interest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/rsl-nsw-president-and-three-board-members-resign/105870106</link><description>The president of RSL NSW Mick Bainbridge has resigned from the board along with three other directors in a shock move just minutes before a scheduled vote on his removal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2c7b2b995905cefb9bd3f5bb68b63f9</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Liberal MP Wendy Lovell makes mass citizenship email mistake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/liberal-mp-makes-mass-citizenship-email-mistake-wendy-lovell/105869436</link><description>A mass email from a Liberal MP wrongly congratulates many people across northern Victoria on becoming new Australian citizens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de9f75949de48bd80fb71bf87aabccb6</guid></item><item><title>Hit-and-run driver Jake Danby's case sparks outrage in NT communities as victim's family calls for jail time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/jake-danby-case-sparks-outrage-victim-family-calls-for-jail-time/105823972</link><description>A fatal hit-and-run case in Darwin has exposed deep disparities in the NT’s justice system, say Aboriginal leaders, as the victim’s family speaks out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aafeaf2228951fb63aed6e6d324353dd</guid></item><item><title>Former ACT attorney-general Gordon Ramsay charged with grooming teen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/act-former-act-attorney-general-gordon-ramsay-in-court-grooming/105869620</link><description>Former ACT attorney-general Gordon Ramsay has faced the ACT Magistrates Court, charged with grooming a teenage boy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7d05b4213863efaf98964e01572dd4b</guid></item><item><title>Cessnock Rifle Club captain charged with manslaughter after pig hunting incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/rifle-club-captain-charged-with-manslaughter-pig-hunt-shooting/105869672</link><description>A 63-year-old rifle club captain has been granted bail after being charged with manslaughter over a shooting incident in the NSW Hunter Valley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">853e43073071b277baf547c22ab7d96d</guid></item><item><title>Israel and Hamas have reached an agreement. What does this mean for the Gaza peace plan?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/israel-and-hamas-gaza-peace-plan-hostage-deal-explainer/105870194</link><description>All of the living Israeli hostages in Gaza could be released as soon as next week under the first phase of a peace plan led by the United States — but the full details are yet to be released. Here is what we know so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8da3d97ca5dce024309cb5991f9e3f7c</guid></item><item><title>UN to slash quarter of peacekeepers in nine operations globally due to lack of funds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/un-slash-peace-keeping-force/105870788</link><description>That would amount to between 13,000 and 14,000 troops and police removed from their nine operations around the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1c7789b92595e9ac432e52bc0b9a5ae</guid></item><item><title>Former RAAF pilot Robert John Crawford to stand trial over alleged murder of wife, Frances Crawford</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/robert-crawford-ipswich-magistrates-committal-hearing/105869272</link><description>Robert John Crawford has pleaded not guilty to the murder of his wife Frances Crawford, who was found dead at the couple's home last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11cd33f6a1d112d9431e984377ced9c0</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins's injury recovery continues ahead of Ashes, Mitchell Starc confident he can perform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/pat-cummins-backed-by-mitchell-starc-in-ashes-tests/105865832</link><description>Australia captain Pat Cummins is in serious doubt for the Ashes and has almost been ruled out of appearing in the first Test as he continues his recovery from a back injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3777906494e600c595b49e6589350fb9</guid></item><item><title>Denmark to ban social media for under 15s, following Australia's world-leading laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/denmark-to-ban-social-media-for-under-15s-following-australia/105870694</link><description>Denmark is planning to ban children under 15 from using social media, following Australia's world-first laws to curb social media use among teenagers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbb9686f20f19c6ff490a40ff33dd199</guid></item><item><title>Gaza emergency doctor evacuated, reunites with husband Dr Mo in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/gaza-dr-mo-nour-reunite-perth-australia/105858548</link><description>Mohammed Mustafa and Nour Dalloul got married while bombs exploded around them. Now their war-torn love, forged in the emergency rooms of a Gazan hospital, has found a home in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7558a8e49bfdc55a3cdbe724d3d74777</guid></item><item><title>Bell Bay Aluminium delivers 'unsettling news' to staff ahead of power deal expiry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/bell-bay-aluminium-delivers-unsettling-news-to-staff-/105869370</link><description>Bell Bay Aluminium has told staff the company faces a "significant risk" after negotiations for a new power deal stalled, jeopardising its future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6a799ca0ee5a9a7a0516228a1102673</guid></item><item><title>How reading romance has helped keep the spark alive for this couple</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/romance-books-a-doorway-into-improved-sexual-intimacy/105734524</link><description>After 10 years of marriage and two kids, Joseph Heath and wife Laura are still in the "honeymoon phase". He says romance novels are a large part of why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e4147b61abe9cc6aa8f9a59e8b43f57</guid></item><item><title>Jane Fonda joins other stars to revive a group that emerged during Hollywood's anti-communist panic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/jane-fonda-free-speech-committee-first-amendment/105869756</link><description>The original group was formed in October 1947 at a time when the US government worried that there were communists in Hollywood who were putting left-wing propaganda into the movies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4aee10a373c8419c317734657120521</guid></item><item><title>Music for the Indiana Jones video game evokes the classic film sound, while still creating a unique experience</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/pete-ward-indiana-jones-video-game-composer/105853838</link><description>The sound world of Indiana Jones is iconic. While in Australia, the video game's audio director shares how he leveraged this to bring the game world to life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cce63c74f54f8437322663561e93c2e</guid></item><item><title>Defence officials grilled over report F-35 fighter jet parts sent from NSW to Israel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/f-35-fighter-jet-parts-israel-exports-australia-supply-chain/105870224</link><description>Department of Defence officials distance themselves from F-35 fighter jet parts allegedly shipped from Australia to Israel, saying the material is the property of Lockheed Martin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a6b5cb31bbe405f6a13c191d793ab4a</guid></item><item><title>Man charged over alleged death threat against Prime Minister Anthony Albanese refused bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/man-accused-of-making-death-threats-anthony-albanese-court/105870888</link><description>A Queensland man accused of threatening to kill the prime minister has been refused bail, with a magistrate describing his alleged threats as "deeply disturbing."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93cb357d791beef63d9cec6b0c0ce97d</guid></item><item><title>Grounded rapid-response fire trucks add to pressure on CFA brigades as summer looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/story-forest-fire-management-vehicles-faults-bushfires/105869610</link><description>Hundreds of rapid-response fire vehicles are off the road ahead of bushfire season, prompting fears local brigades will have to pick up the slack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a51087b6ad2fbd882ff28f13b60c81a</guid></item><item><title>Tony Burke suddenly keen to answer questions about Islamic State relatives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/tony-burke-andrew-hastie-anthony-albanese/105858462</link><description>This week in Canberra, Tony Burke finally answered questions about the return of Islamic State relatives, Senate estimates turned into an episode of Utopia, and Andrew Hastie quit the frontbench.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c1650235972fc3a8c1d9de82b0cc008</guid></item><item><title>Former transport official Ibrahim Helmy tells corruption watchdog he artificially inflated invoices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/nsw-icac-transport-ibrahim-helmy-says-he-received-cash-payments/105871166</link><description>Former NSW transport official Ibrahim Helmy tells the corruption watchdog he artificially inflated invoices for work provided to the government before splitting the profits with contractors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ceb7d19f10b2665dd248454c24378059</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanians urged to prepare for wind gusts of up to 125kph</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/tasmanians-urged-to-make-preparations-for-damaging-wind-gusts/105869730</link><description>Residents on the north and west coast of Tasmania are being warned to secure loose items around their homes ahead of wind gusts of up to 125 kilometres per hour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd3f34d6777160f9f308d5b13e5847cf</guid></item><item><title>Aftermath of shark attack off Kangaroo Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/aftermath-of-shark-attack-off-kangaroo-island/105873704</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb4473318e375dbdf33a5b3cfef189b3</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroo Island visitor details 'extraordinary moment of timing' family came across shark attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/kangaroo-island-shark-attack-witness-extraordinary-moment/105873108</link><description>A man who witnessed the "extraordinary" moment a surfer was bitten by a shark chasing a seal offshore Kangaroo Island has spoken to the ABC after his footage circulated online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d0e5cadb01ecb795fa49f3d163b5f24</guid></item><item><title>Sneak peek at Sydney's new Fish Markets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/sneak-peek-at-sydneys-new-fish-markets./105873112</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13f18b856c1f335fe682e16e1250bce4</guid></item><item><title>First look inside the Sydney Fish Market, with opening date yet to be confirmed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/sydney-fish-market-fist-look/105869460</link><description>The NSW government is expecting construction for the long-awaited Sydney Fish Market development to be completed by next month, but an opening date for the $700 million project is yet to be announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca1a9ee73ddfb5826bb72526f304f43d</guid></item><item><title>Israel and Hamas' first-phase peace plan agreement is monumental but the end of the war is far from certain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/question-marks-on-israel-hamas-peace-agreement-details/105870198</link><description>The announcement that Israel and Hamas have agreed to phase one of a peace deal in Gaza is significant. But despite the celebrations, the end of the war is still far from certain, writes Matthew Doran.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9b24489302e1fcdf06a4b33cf35d476</guid></item><item><title>Netball fights for recognition amid influx of women's sports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/netball-fights-for-recognition-amid-influx-of-womens-sports/105869454</link><description>Netball Australia is taking elite-level netball to regional communities, hoping to showcase the sport's global impact and inspire the next generation of athletes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c29340636422638897d13e7c3376d3f</guid></item><item><title>How drought inspired Goondiwindi's thriving art movement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/goondiwindi-lanescape-sculpture-trail-festival/105867942</link><description>Goondiwindi's Lanescape art collective transforms the Queensland border town into an open-air gallery featuring large steel sculptures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dff5c0bac15384a50569b46b3772841</guid></item><item><title>Mixed feelings among Israelis after news of hostage return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/mixed-feelings-among-israelis-after-the-news-of/105874048</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acca73ee358b7512c5568ad88027636a</guid></item><item><title>Mitch Brown was thrust into the spotlight after coming out. He wants to use it to 'call people in,' not out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/mitch-brown-hate-after-speaking-out-on-queer-issues/105862948</link><description>After coming out, Mitch Brown became an unofficial spokesperson for queer issues in the AFL. While that experience has been overwhelmingly positive, it's also come with an onslaught of hate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e05331597384262a651057a5ba1156ec</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne boosts Ashes hopes with One-Day Cup century for Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/ashes-australia-england-marnus-century-in-one-day-cup/105873938</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne's case for a men's Ashes call-up continues to build after he scored a second century in the space of a week and third of the domestic summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">362174f44227618140154caed43afb5a</guid></item><item><title>Future of pokies boss hangs in balance after US gaming licence troubles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/future-of-pokie-boss-hangs-in-balance-after-us-licence-troubles/105458416</link><description>An Australian pokie machine giant says it is reviewing its chief executive's future after a US gaming regulator spurned his licence application. It comes months after the ABC revealed he was the subject of a corruption investigation in Austria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae656b170969f4c342d640a338150205</guid></item><item><title>Competition watchdog approves Elders' $475m acquisition of agribusiness rival Delta</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/elders-delta-acquisition-approved-by-accc-competition-watchdog/105869652</link><description>The consumer watchdog has given the go-ahead for Elders to acquire its competitor, Delta, but it must sell six Delta stores in WA to improve competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dda21e910c76f2e0fe579ad341f4b7a</guid></item><item><title>Family 'quite nasty' to woman who married step-uncle before his alleged murder, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/zaid-abdus-samad-murder-trial-kuraby-queensland/105869882</link><description>A woman who married her step-uncle under Islamic law — before he was allegedly murdered by her brother at his Brisbane home — has told a court her family accused her of committing incest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7c900bc8030d0b27705c24c0f1221c9</guid></item><item><title>Narrabri Shire down to less than two weeks' supply of water amid PFAS contamination 'crisis'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/narrabri-water-crisis-triggered-by-pfas-contamination/105869576</link><description>Two of Narrabri's three water supplies have been switched off amid claims the state government is "taking too long" to find a solution to a chemical contamination issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">397bff02854b41307c5981ace5ae7868</guid></item><item><title>NT chief minister ignores requests for chauffeur service rules after pizzeria, golf club trips</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/nt-calls-for-government-to-release-guidelines-for-chauffuer/105873100</link><description>The NT chief minister is ignoring requests for information about rules for a taxpayer-funded VIP chauffeur service after claiming trips to a pizzeria and golf club were above board.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a40821454b82d45f955287649119817e</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm grants Nelson Asofa-Solomona immediate release from NRL contract</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/nrl-melbourne-storm-nelson-asofa-solomona-contract-release/105874194</link><description>Melbourne will clear Nelson Asofa-Solomona's salary from its cap after the powerful front-rower was granted a release from the final two years of his deal with the club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b68459e3d2d56c43d3bea81b42409d1</guid></item><item><title>Teenager denied bail after allegedly posting Islamic State propaganda and threatening synagogue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/teenager-denied-bail-alleged-islamic-state-propoganda-extremism/105873474</link><description>A teenager who allegedly posted terrorism propaganda online and made threats to kill has been denied bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49561fb65189712eeea0c418650f7165</guid></item><item><title>Bunbury massage therapist Anthony Brain sex assault trial begins with French nudist colony claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/bunbury-masseuse-anthony-brain-sex-assault-trial-begins/105861108</link><description>Bunbury masseur Anthony Brain told women clients he needed to work on intimate parts of their bodies to relieve tension, but in reality it was for his own pleasure, a Perth court hears as his sexual assault trial gets underway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">160cfd8379cb2de41693229bccb1b6a6</guid></item><item><title>Queensland police investigating death in Hervey Bay suburb of Torquay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/qld-police-investigate-death-hervey-bay/105874560</link><description>Emergency services were called to reports of a disturbance at a Hervey Bay address this afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7288471a90a4d90e38e0dc25142987c</guid></item><item><title>Deloitte caught out using AI in report for federal government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/deloitte-caught-out-using-ai-in-report-for-federal/105874634</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73a40e241a39295c35b76e8f87cb1de6</guid></item><item><title>Questions over Optus's priorities during the triple-0 crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/questions-over-optuss-priorities-during-the-triple/105874638</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a04cae1697cfd7c08bf89286d042e1f1</guid></item><item><title>The first phase of a Gaza peace deal has been agreed upon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/the-first-phase-of-a-gaza-peace-deal-has-been/105874648</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">973bb4b43edd06a3e9acc285af85cd38</guid></item><item><title>Ahmad Hodroj handed five-year jail term for domestic violence manslaughter of Amira Moughnieh</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/ahmad-hodroj-jailed-for-manslaughter-of-amira-moughnieh/105874532</link><description>Amira Moughnieh's estranged husband will be released from prison in 2026 after being sentenced to five years' jail for her manslaughter on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">369b5a131e5016a3f856864e35c1bc94</guid></item><item><title>László Krasznahorkai awarded Nobel Prize in Literature for 'visionary' work that 'reaffirms the power of art'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/l%C3%A1szl%C3%B3-krasznahorkai-nobel-prize-in-literature-2025/105874554</link><description>László Krasznahorkai has been awarded the Nobel Prize in Literature, one of the world's most prestigious writing awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcaabf1e799e51426d25d8a82300fd8f</guid></item><item><title>Top stories from ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/top-stories-from-abc-news/105874824</link><description>Listen to ABC News interviews and commentary and analysis from radio programs like AM, PM and The World Today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">244ea5d94f772ff19486e9b211411ca5</guid></item><item><title>Ruby Hunter, Shellie Morris and Missy Higgins among recipients at Australian Women in Music Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/australian-women-music-awards-winners-2025/105818332</link><description>The Australian Women in Music Awards recognised contributions across the music sector, from artists, to photographers, journalists, filmmakers, and leaders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6a9fa96fc27f3c059d502ac8fe237a0</guid></item><item><title>Europe Commission President Ursula von der Leyen survives no-confidence votes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/ursula-von-der-leyen-no-confidence-vote/105874816</link><description>The European Commission president has faced criticism from the left and right after striking a tariff deal with the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38f9eb683dff13f9b08da77359695e43</guid></item><item><title>China further limits the export of rare earth materials and products</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/china-rare-earth-exports-limited-further/105874886</link><description>The issue has been a key sticking point in the trade war between Beijing and Washington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5225fa84dc406f960ab2eba29fe1bd5</guid></item></channel></rss>