<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 23:38:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Trump receives mixed reaction of boos, cheers at US Open men's final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/trump-receives-mixed-reaction-at-us-open/105747200</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eab70e58b0ce57ef768d67ec4943a0d8</guid></item><item><title>An Ozzy Osbourne tribute, a Mayhem Ball and a Mariah Carey medley delight fans at the 2025 MTV VMAs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/key-moments-from-the-2025-vmas/105746958</link><description>Ariana Grande and Lady Gaga took home the biggest awards at this year's MTV VMAs with several nineties stars honoured for their musical legacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7aac3df4ab0753ac617e05bcf866036a</guid></item><item><title>State ward was groomed and exploited while in the residential care system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/state-ward-was-groomed-while-in-residential-care/105699088</link><description>The New South Wales government put Tayla in the residential care system, where the girl with high needs and multiple diagnoses was pulled into a cycle of sexual abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59b7a9264e06a8b1e616029641689c9d</guid></item><item><title>Rupert Murdoch settles court fight with children over media empire's future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/rupert-murdoch-james-lachlan-news-fox-media-empire/105751262</link><description>The deal ends a bitter Succession-style dispute that had pitted members of the family against each other in court, and means Rupert Murdoch's media outlets are likely to retain their right-wing bent after his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">476275a126ab6e501e0e3157597630fa</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout leads rising generation of Australian stars at World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/australian-athletics-stars-inspired-and-highly-motivated/105749554</link><description>Armed with the largest team ever assembled for a major athletics meet, Australia enters the World Athletics Championships with a sense of excitement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf3b0645d7e3d89f855a7e1f8ba88881</guid></item><item><title>Lachlan Murdoch has secured the legacy of his father's empire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/lachlan-murdoch-rupert-succession-fox-news-corp/105752206</link><description>The deal secures Rupert Murdoch's legacy as the founder of the world's most powerful conservative media empire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48ae0d4e58610e05aa248ea0705abbc5</guid></item><item><title>Extreme heat a rising threat to 2026 World Cup venues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/extreme-heat-a-rising-threat-to-2026-world-cup-venues/105755726</link><description>A new report called Pitches In Peril says by 2050, nearly 90 per cent of North America's host stadiums will require adaptation to extreme heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce0c393dc0e568545262e7a1e7f85c7f</guid></item><item><title>Women's Rugby World Cup players trialling flashing mouthguards to help predict concussions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/women-rugby-world-cup-concussion-flashing-mouthguards/105732190</link><description>The Women's Rugby World Cup, currently being held in England, is trialling a revolutionary approach to concussion management. Players are wearing LED mouthguards which light up when a player sustains a hit that could result in a concussion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cac3259c78755b6836d00648b4bdd3a2</guid></item><item><title>Murdochs resolve succession saga but family's hold on empire is vulnerable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/murdoch-money-trust/105753004</link><description>Rupert Murdoch's family has always been close. But if you really want to trace the extent of filial and sibling affection, you need to follow the money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05772215b7594bca0b62e72680c673b5</guid></item><item><title>Australia on alert to shot-hole borer threat as WA pivots to tree canopy rehabilitation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/shot-hole-borer-tree-threat-australia/105740250</link><description>It's barely the size of a sesame seed, but the shot-hole borer has quickly devastated Western Australia's tree canopy. Experts are warning other states and territories to take action now to avoid a similar fate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aea657a36513f410d730aac2a0066292</guid></item><item><title>How a tiny beetle became one of Australia's biggest biosecurity threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/how-a-tiny-beetle-became-one-of-australias-biggest/105747334</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eafbb5c3d40ad11ab57b695cf0eedc81</guid></item><item><title>Shot hole borer has infected scores of trees in Hyde Park.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/shotholeborer-4/105742092</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">630b371efc0d65a664bffc7dbaf03f5d</guid></item><item><title>WA firearm reforms spark animal welfare, biosecurity concerns amid roadkill management review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/dbca-says-firearms-reforms-put-animal-control-program-at-risk/105755420</link><description>A WA government department says the state’s new firearms laws are causing headaches for a program which responds to reports of injured and suffering animals on the roadside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28e337c77c2a7ba8cccc7d97d10ea479</guid></item><item><title>Pouched Lamprey migration up Margaret River</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/pouched-lamprey-migration-up-margaret-river/105754220</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee05f7f052f6d9f2ba478f1313d6fb67</guid></item><item><title>Megan Phipps wasn't surprised by the poor results in the Women's Health Matters survey. (ABC News: Ian Cutmore)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/megan-phipps-wasnt-surprised-by-the-poor-results/105756252</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">262bc10368976e6aae4f17a80db69eea</guid></item><item><title>Fears for K'gari as researchers compile database of species on Australian islands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/researchers-compile-database-of-kgari-freshwater-species/105754114</link><description>A groundbreaking study has revealed the extraordinarily rich biodiversity of Australia's islands and experts say it shows tighter controls are needed to protect the most diverse island of them all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2efd20d29666ca92bac88f95a0cc2cc</guid></item><item><title>Super Rugby AUS presents new opportunity for rising stars and Wallabies hopefuls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/super-rugby-aus-provides-young-stars-chance-to-show-talent/105752962</link><description>Australian rugby's latest chapter in a third-tier competition kicks off this weekend with high hopes that it can be a platform for future stars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5c0ac30b5043bc8c84ffdde8c293957</guid></item><item><title>Indian actor Navya Nair fined for bringing jasmine flower garland into Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/indian-actor-navya-nair-fined-for-flower-garland-jasmine-gajra/105751236</link><description>The incident involving Navya Nair highlights a common concern facing many visitors to Australia — what can be brought in without the risk of breaching strict biosecurity laws?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91c7cb29dc74f7c2ae2ccae7d09b8a0f</guid></item><item><title>Cats star Bailey Smith confronts a photographer at a Geelong training session.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/cats-star-confronts-photographer-at-geelong/105758708</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a8646dbf1e0a0dad57d492a87b11045</guid></item><item><title>Grand slam champion Lleyton Hewitt suspended for pushing anti-doping official</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/lleyton-hewitt-suspended-pushing-antidoping-official/105759864</link><description>Two-time grand slam champion and Australia's Davis Cup captain Lleyton Hewitt has been suspended for two weeks for pushing an anti-doping official.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fe5b681b1f4d14402fc091095be4e17</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu warns Australia that expanding Woodside's North West Shelf gas project could breach international ruling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/vanuatu-warns-australia-about-expansion-of-woodside-gas-project/105759934</link><description>Australia's move to expand Woodside's North West Shelf gas project has not been welcomed in the Pacific, which is fighting the most dramatic effects of climate change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">112f08872918df84094b125b428478cd</guid></item><item><title>Right-wing activist and Trump ally Charlie Kirk shot dead at Utah university</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/charlie-kirk-shot-utah-university-event/105418226</link><description>Donald Trump confirms Charlie Kirk has been shot dead in front of a crowd of horrified students, with the US president describing the conservative activist as a "tremendous person" and a "very good friend".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ea200333d2037582fb4799f0fc34d4d</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou vows to take Nottingham Forest back to the top of European football</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/ange-postecoglou-nottingham-forest-back-to-rightful-place/105760224</link><description>Nottingham Forest fans have been made a promise by Ange Postecoglou that he'll give his all to help them bring back their glory days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2112a0c82bb2034b916fcef82e37656</guid></item><item><title>Athlete Claudia Hollingsworth prepares for World Championships in Tokyo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/athlete-claudia-hollingsworth-prepares-for-world/105755400</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88fe79472cae00da34c77b3394352050</guid></item><item><title>Murdoch children 'pleased' family trust dispute is 'behind them'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/murdoch-children-pleased-family-trust-dispute-is-behind-them/105760498</link><description>James Murdoch, Elisabeth Murdoch and Prudence MacLeod say they are "pleased" to have reached an agreement to settle litigation over the Murdoch family trust, saying the issue is "now behind them".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5326cb2c5525d09c552e2e1a107a26f</guid></item><item><title>Australian FMX rider Clinton Moore lands 720 trick</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/australian-fmx-rider-clinton-moore-lands-720-trick/105748934</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b750776abb60a888ae4a0a4f4496216</guid></item><item><title>Jess Fox announces she will miss Canoe Slalom World Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/jess-fox-announces-she-will-miss-canoe-slalom/105762586</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5dc18bb88857142cc4820e1ddcca090</guid></item><item><title>What time does the Wallabies vs Argentina rugby Test match kick off? How can I watch it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/wallabies-vs-argentina-how-to-watch-what-time-is-kick-off/105761962</link><description>The Wallabies have made four changes to their starting team for the second Test match against Argentina in the Rugby Championship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9978bacfa028d836c185006d29f6276</guid></item><item><title>How Hawthorn and Gold Coast proceed to the AFL preliminary finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/how-hawthorn-and-gold-coast-get-to-prelim-finals/105762028</link><description>Hawthorn and Gold Coast go into their cut-throat semifinals with reasons for some confidence against the Crows and Lions. Cody Atkinson and Sean Lawson look into the factors driving both teams' September runs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bee6f2e0e1aee53ecd326cca279df14</guid></item><item><title>Researchers have counted superb fairy-wrens at National Botanical Gardens for 40 years — 2025 was 'confronting'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/act-half-historic-superb-fairy-wren-population-die-over-winter/105762554</link><description>The ACT's superb fairy-wren population has declined by 60 per cent since counting began in the 1980s, but this last winter the figures were even worse, new research has revealed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d37f4cd5eeaf2c85c2f6cc5449bb0a6e</guid></item><item><title>Sprint great Usain Bolt says Gout Gout needs the right support and focus to succeed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/it-s-never-just-easy-usain-bolt-message-gout-gout-world-titles/105763446</link><description>Usain Bolt delivers a simple piece of advice to Gout Gout as the Australian teenage sprint sensation prepares for his first world championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bbe4c5df31d0eaa97dba1aeafad326e</guid></item><item><title>How Jamal Fogarty learned to be the hero Canberra needed for its premiership charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/jamal-fogarty-canberra-raiders-nrl-finals-broncos/105763708</link><description>Jamal Fogarty has spent a rugby league lifetime waiting to play on a team like the Raiders. Now with the NRL finals approaching, he's ready for his close-up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37ebbb2fb5d1d3bfd53ea39bbcdce144</guid></item><item><title>Albany residents call for lower speed limits after van strikes pedestrian at crossing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/improved-pedestrian-safety-calls-driver-charged-albany-crash/105763894</link><description>A crash involving a van and an 81-year-old woman in Albany prompts calls for reduced speed limits from locals and road safety advocates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28cafa4834c5ecfdd772b7a30cc30200</guid></item><item><title>Australia to face Belgium in Davis Cup in Sydney with Final 8 spot up for grabs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/nothing-for-granted-aussies-wary-of-belgian-davis-cup-threat/105767498</link><description>Lleyton Hewitt's Australian Davis Cup team is ready for another fierce battle with old foes Belgium as they chase a spot in this year's Final 8 in Italy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25e0a60e31cf0b026f68b6ea2239af89</guid></item><item><title>Mop-top virus found in potatoes bought from retail stores in Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/mop-top-virus-found-in-supermarket-potatoes/105767970</link><description>Biosecurity Tasmania is working to trace the origins of the two potatoes, as potato mop-top virus continues to spread through Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b203465ed9e5237115d518e91f8591f</guid></item><item><title>Matildas to face England Lionesses in October international window</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/matildas-to-face-england-in-october-international-window/105768734</link><description>The Matildas have announced an international friendly against England this October, the first time they will face the European champions since the semifinal of the 2023 FIFA Women's World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dcbfca402515a25dcb9fa30ae7dbe58</guid></item><item><title>Sushila Karki sworn in as Nepal's new prime minister after gen Z protests prompt political change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/sushila-karki-nepals-new-prime-minister-after-gen-z-protests/105769388</link><description>Sushila Karki garnered widespread support from many young Nepalese people who took to the streets in anger over government corruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b14068c37ad26302453e199b0b0960b7</guid></item><item><title>Evidence points to remains found in Vietnam cave being South-East Asia's earliest known homicide victim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/vietnam-remains-earliest-known-homicide-victim-cold-case/105741956</link><description>It was on a sweltering morning in 2018 in a cave in northern Vietnam when Chris Stimpson and his team uncovered what may be the oldest cold case murder in South-East Asia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34f92776d6167c167af22a4b170f6648</guid></item><item><title>When does Gout Gout run in the 200m at the 2025 World Athletics Championships in Tokyo, and other key events</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/when-does-gout-gout-run-at-the-world-athletics-championships/105748430</link><description>The 2025 World Athletics Championships in Tokyo sees Australia's largest-ever team tackle the best athletes on the planet. Here are the key events you won't want to miss.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed7a4e602de605c0371a42019cfce15a</guid></item><item><title>Wallaroos primed for Rugby World Cup quarterfinal against Canada</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/rugby-world-cup-australia-wallaroos-canada/105769754</link><description>Considered underdogs against the world number two, the Wallaroos are urged to be bold in their sudden-death encounter in Bristol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00a664df1e40e5f48d4be15d391193dc</guid></item><item><title>Who is Tyler Robinson, the accused killer of Charlie Kirk?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/tyler-robinson-charlie-kirks-alleged-killer/105769710</link><description>After his father encouraged Tyler Robinson to turn himself in, people close to the 22-year-old provided investigators with crucial insights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeb2177456349534e747aeb65ed554d9</guid></item><item><title>Astronomer Grote Reber's ashes are held in radio telescope locations around the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/pioneering-radio-astronomer-grote-reber-built-first-big-dish/105725764</link><description>Grote Reber helped spark decades of interest in radio astronomy in Tasmania when he decided to call the southern state home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9417f11c5baa5079e22009aea0722381</guid></item><item><title>Rare good news for critically endangered east coast grey nurse sharks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/critically-endangered-grey-nurse-shark-numbers-on-the-rise/105765674</link><description>Scientists say increasing numbers of east coast grey nurse sharks is rare good conservation news for the critically endangered species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10548b61892e77ded2ac12afc8405a87</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne's Royal Children's Hospital cancels children in war discussion citing staff safety</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/royal-childrens-hospital-children-in-war-event-cancelled/105768998</link><description>Melbourne's Royal Children's Hospital says a symposium on the effect of war on children has been cancelled due to safety fears, but some doctors say pressure from a group opposing antisemitism is to blame.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fccbb42b0ca2b5ba0a4d9a7fdb9a9816</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fall to 28-26 defeat against Argentina in The Rugby Championship in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/live-updates-wallabies-vs-argentina-the-rugby-championship/105753320</link><description>The Wallabies have fallen just short of a magical comeback against Argentina, losing 28-26 in a thrilling Rugby Championship Test in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac9963693b81c061d5a7137f7874121c</guid></item><item><title>Erika Kirk makes first public statement after assassination of husband Charlie Kirk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/erika-kirk-pays-tribute-to-late-husband-charlie-kirk/105770008</link><description>Charlie Kirk's widow, Erika, delivers her first public remarks since the fatal shooting of her influencer husband.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a3e797f573f130d4cdaa37fc918652a</guid></item><item><title>Advocates call for action on brain health as AIHW reveals dementia is leading cause of death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/australians-dying-from-dementia-more-than-any-other-cause/105768682</link><description>Advocates warn the number of people with the condition could exceed 1 million without government intervention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b35bf8bb29f6390428b007c4fc10877</guid></item><item><title>Supreme Court gives Queensland hospital permission to terminate 12yo girl's pregnancy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/qld-hospital-gets-court-permission-for-abortion-on-12yo-girl/105770196</link><description>A 12-year-old girl in residential care in Queensland should be allowed to have an abortion, a court rules, after a judge found she was not capable of making the decision herself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86cd5589ba9855a3f68a146a74e238ad</guid></item><item><title>NRLW wrap: Brisbane Broncos thrash the Cowboys 50-4, Gold Coast grab last finals spot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/upton-hat-trick-leads-broncos-to-big-nrlw-win-over-cowboys/105770416</link><description>It's a big day for Queensland sides in the NRLW, as the Broncos — led by skipper Tamika Upton — are far too good for the third-placed Cowboys, while the Titans clinch the last finals spot with a win over Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0af6a0f9bdb8ae75a28c6c7e963ce856</guid></item><item><title>WA Health issues measles warning as two more cases linked to Bali travel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/two-more-measles-cases-in-wa-linked-to-bali-travel/105770492</link><description>West Australians planning to visit South-East Asia are being urged to get vaccinated against measles, with two more cases linked with travel to Bali.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1897bbaf4493022b86af465fcc949ac6</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane far too good for Gold Coast in QClash semifinal, setting up Collingwood prelim date</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/afl-finals-brisbane-lions-gold-coast-suns-live-blog/105768034</link><description>Bouncing back from a resounding loss to Geelong, the Brisbane Lions comfortably dispense of the Gold Coast Suns to advance to the preliminary finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35fd90e486aa2532889961cd9ae474b8</guid></item><item><title>From Formula 1 to creating the 'world's best' croissant, how baking saved Lune founder Kate Reid's life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/cars-to-croissants-kate-reid-and-the-lune-empire/105750472</link><description>Kate Reid's Lune croissants have been called the world's best. But how did a young woman struggling with a near-fatal eating disorder end up perfecting pastry?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d09b350f758690100795053d1425df1</guid></item><item><title>Children missing out on early intervention for language delays due to shortage of speech pathologists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/australias-speech-pathology-therapy-language-delay/105658306</link><description>One in four children starting school now has a speech or language delay. It can hold back their learning, affect their friendships and harm their mental health. Speech therapists are struggling to find ways to support them all, but one school is leading the way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fd8643f474de3cb897a95d95769fb75</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's health chief, RFK Jr, is dividing Republicans on vaccines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/trump-health-chief-rfk-jr-divides-republicans-on-vaccines/105763060</link><description>US Health Secretary Robert F Kennedy Jr's anti-vaccination agenda is gaining ground, but resistance is coming from all sides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">550382bc4a2dad860c2ebd332ba5da22</guid></item><item><title>Trump hits out at Florida's 'tough stance' on vaccines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/trump-hits-out-at-floridas-tough-stance-on-vaccines/105767070</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">411cbb4e0109999f07a638bac1bb9e45</guid></item><item><title>'Bone lady' who helped find Daniel Morcombe still unearthing stories of the dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/life-of-qld-police-forensic-anthropologist-donna-macgregor/105757258</link><description>From the search for Daniel Morcombe to a flaming roadside torso, Queensland's top forensics cop deals with some of the state's worst crimes — when she's not identifying fallen Australians on WWI battlefields.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">756451363a24944c71314b39d4ee9da4</guid></item><item><title>Wallaroos' Rugby World Cup hopes dashed by dominant Canada in 46-5 loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/rugby-world-cup-wallaroos-canada-quarterfinal/105771382</link><description>The Wallaroos miss the chance to reach the Rugby World Cup semifinals, losing heavily 46-5 to Canada in Bristol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eeea51af32489f3175d1f115a728a37</guid></item><item><title>The Pacific won a stunning climate victory at the International Court of Justice. What's next?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/whats-next-after-pacific-icj-climate-victory/105747794</link><description>Pacific Island nations are weighing up how to use a historic international court ruling in their fight to bring about stronger emissions reductions and climate justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4d5352fd2872714b73915e90a078b57</guid></item><item><title>World-famous bee sanctuary on Kangaroo Island under threat from Varroa mite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/world-famous-bee-sanctuary-under-threat-from-parasite/105766650</link><description>Beekeepers on Kangaroo Island are demanding that biosecurity measures be boosted to prevent a deadly parasite from wiping out the island's world-famous bee sanctuary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dc81d0494e04695ce39dafec86cab57</guid></item><item><title>Brick-pit frog recovery another win for green and gold at Sydney Olympics site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/green-and-golden-bell-frogs-thrive-at-sydney-olympics-site/105762124</link><description>Twenty-five years after the Sydney Olympics, an important Homebush planning decision has led to successful conservation efforts for a species born in the green and gold. But a deadly fungus poses a threat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7163e13b015cd649bd1282f9f989c65e</guid></item><item><title>Wombats in Robe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/wombats-in-robe/105762994</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b3220b0971b015745735ee5063bf7e0</guid></item><item><title>The Franklin River rescue was extreme. Here's how medics prepare for the wilderness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/expedition-medicine-frontline-wilderness-rescue-tasmania/105647214</link><description>The Franklin River rescue was an extreme test for the skills of medics. In remote Tasmania, here's how they train for "chaos".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ad6b3276dc3d97f9e83daaf4447dd1e</guid></item><item><title>Outback nurse transforms remote diabetes care with cans, rocks and bush tucker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/collarenebri-hosts-pilot-diabetes-and-holistic-health-program/105600544</link><description>When Rishoniy Caine arrived in a remote NSW community with one general store and no gym, she knew fixing its diabetes problem would need a different approach to what had already failed the locals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">222ba35951a8a4a1e2c0a8f063f85b5b</guid></item><item><title>The federal press gallery is ceding power to the Albanese government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/australias-press-gallery-problem-with-political-coverage/105762464</link><description>The federal press gallery is ceding power to the Albanese government. It needs to take it back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ab87f4785a2cdb321543f771c1d84de</guid></item><item><title>All Blacks forced to re-group after 43-10 loss to Springboks in Rugby Championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/all-blacks-regroup-after-springboks-defeat/105771568</link><description>After a demoralising 43-10 loss to the Springboks on home soil, the All Blacks are looking to rebound against the Wallabies in the upcoming Bledisloe Cup Tests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14cb19776ed7e08739a74354c2afa92e</guid></item><item><title>'World's biggest' hockey game in York fundraises for cancer research</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/eliza-reynolds-hockey-game-cancer-fundraiser/105763156</link><description>More than 370 people participate in a hockey game lasting more than eight hours in honour of a little girl who died from a rare form of cancer earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6940b0964bbe2ae1724b08b2a97f81f</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley reshuffles frontbench in wake of Jacinta Nampijinpa Price saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/coalition-frontbench-reshuffle-melissa-price-claire-chandler/105771468</link><description>West Australian MP Melissa Price will replace Jacinta Nampijinpa Price as the shadow minister for defence industry and personnel, after the outspoken senator was sacked for refusing to back her leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5afabc2037eaede8864df8e5a67e0e3f</guid></item><item><title>How to give your indoor plants a spring clean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/how-to-spring-clean-indoor-plants/105754044</link><description>As gardens, parks and nature strips start showing signs of spring, our indoor plants might need a little help to jump into the new season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7041345f64a52b3d64fb6ac2ef82f3b</guid></item><item><title>Ben Hunt's Golden Point field goal sends Brisbane Broncos into NRL prelims after downing Canberra Raiders in all-time classic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/nrl-live-updates-finals-canberra-raiders-brisbane-broncos/105767630</link><description>Jamal Fogarty scores a try in Golden Point to send the Raiders to a preliminary final only for it to be disallowed before Ben Hunt delivers a dagger field goal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6df4f99fbc4ba21354c9bf49bf40731</guid></item><item><title>FBI director Kash Patel to face congressional hearing amid missteps on Charlie Kirk assassination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/kash-patel-faces-congressional-hearing/105771606</link><description>Kash Patel faces a clear test of whether he can convince the country that the FBI, under his watch, can avoid compounding its mistakes in a time of political violence and deepening distrust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff3edf3e8615beb76880722256515f03</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull cruises to 1,500m final at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-2025-in-tokyo-day-2/105772150</link><description>Jess Hull made light work of a rough semifinal to progress in the women's 1,500, but Linden Hall and Torrie Lewis both fell just short of making the final themselves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3251a6322d104d5e8dec69a8eb3f155</guid></item><item><title>Belgians break Australian hearts in Davis Cup classic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/tennis-de-minaur-australia-belgium-davis-cup-wrap/105772264</link><description>Beligum's Raphael Collignon wore down late stand-in Aleksandar Vukic in the deciding rubber to lead Belgium to the quarter-finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48108db3db36157632582610dcc8f4ed</guid></item><item><title>Reece Walsh grabs the Sun to lead Brisbane to an all-time victory over Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/canberra-raiders-brisbane-broncos-nrl-finals-reece-walsh/105767838</link><description>Brisbane and Canberra went to the great beyond in their golden point finals match and it was Reece Walsh who led the Broncos to the promised land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">863df8dd52133df36ae1790ea450fe7c</guid></item><item><title>The year Australia is due to blow its carbon budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/australia-carbon-budget-2035-emissions-target/105341080</link><description>Unless Australia lifts its ambitions, its "fair share" of carbon emissions will be spent 14 years early. With the government announcing a 2035 climate target this week, there is intense debate on how high the government should aim — and whether it will be enough to help limit global warming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92c26486065559e6e68fc907f4300c31</guid></item><item><title>The higher Australia's 2035 emissions target, the more necessary a carbon tax will be</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/albanese-government-2035-climate-emissions-target/105771566</link><description>Australia's emissions reduction number is, in short, a laugh-or-cry-o-meter, or perhaps more accurately, a tax-o-meter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5aae41b286ff6b7c3400069e180e67f</guid></item><item><title>GIM Trading accused of defrauding millions from ordinary Australian investors with 'low risk' bonds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/gim-trading-alleged-fraud-investors-bonds/105747410</link><description>A Gold Coast musician approached by a man he knew from a local bar went on to front a trading company, later accused of defrauding millions from ordinary Australian investors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef7a680d03253010b78fa5b88e06a4f0</guid></item><item><title>Dads leaving sex education to mums, report finds, with concerns young boys are missing out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/dads-leaving-sex-education-to-mums-boys-missing-out/105761172</link><description>New report finds mothers do more of the sex education at home, raising concerns that young boys are missing out on key information from their dads.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09373ae607cb293f5028b7499dce7b5a</guid></item><item><title>Family violence survivors waiting years for social housing as demand surges in Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/social-public-housing-wait-times-victoria-family-violence/105655044</link><description>As family violence survivor and mother-of-two, Maya was assessed as a high priority for social housing. Eight years later, she's finally moved into a suitable home in outer-suburban Melbourne, with vulnerable Victorians left waiting for years as the social housing waitlist soars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e74302190404e5284428c6e45ccbce8a</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic expeditioners join research project to help astronauts on space missions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/antarctic-expeditioners-join-astronaut-research-project/105767136</link><description>Expeditioners at Australia's Antarctic stations are taking part in a research project to better understand the cognitive and physiological impacts of extended deployments — which can include actual "brain shrinkage".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d57ace742d2dab72c8470091d9eea61</guid></item><item><title>Residents say former Moe Hospital could become public housing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/moe-hospital-newborough-derelict-building-social-housing/105637366</link><description>A retired nurse who worked at Moe Hospital says the closed facility could be used for housing rather than left to further rot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d6259927cc7b3ea15a9fcb2704c8b7c</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr scores 100th goal for Chelsea in long-awaited WSL return from knee injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/sam-kerr-makes-wsl-chelsea-return-from-torn-acl/105772878</link><description>Matildas star Sam Kerr scores her 100th goal for Chelsea just minutes after returning to the pitch for the Blues for her first game since 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bae5f25a567be7986ec4489f569f5f25</guid></item><item><title>Nepalese migrants in Australia turning to parents to help with childcare and culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/canberra-nepalese-community-family-tradition-and-culture/105772020</link><description>For many Nepalese families living in Canberra, the arrival of parents from overseas is both a helping hand with raising children and a connection to their homeland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83d7bb8c245d2e5d11433eda0c9b3fd1</guid></item><item><title>Documents reveal unauthorised sediment releases at Blackwater Coal Mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/blackwater-coal-mine-contamination-sediment/105769922</link><description>A report obtained by lobby group Lock The Gate under right-to-information laws reveal a mine in central Queensland was releasing sediment into environmentally sensitive areas for more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c0e5d78e0e78c7d0e25c51e02aed43f</guid></item><item><title>Traditional custodian readies for 'challenge' over North West Shelf gas project extension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/traditional-custodian-fights-north-west-shelf-approval/105770306</link><description>Environment Minister Murray Watt approved the extension of Australia's biggest gas project last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fff78b1c904abb60057a8fd295536c56</guid></item><item><title>Blind, big-wave surfer Matt Formston inspires students' dance performance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/blind-big-wave-surfer-matt-formston-inspires-students/105758670</link><description>Record-breaking surfer and Paralympic cycling gold medallist Matt Formston's feats are brought to life in a dance performance by students in New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7ece4beed1bdd4fb2bc2ae712f13dea</guid></item><item><title>Specialist GPs to diagnose ADHD in WA amid calls for further easing of restrictions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/wa-gps-soon-start-diagnosing-adhd/105759814</link><description>As a select cohort of WA GPs begins to diagnose ADHD in people older than 10, parents of younger children and some medical professionals have expressed concerns about the scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32f743c6d37c23f14438dac29a9eb199</guid></item><item><title>WA's expanded container deposit scheme to cost wineries, distilleries millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/container-for-change-wa-wine-expansion-hits-small-business/105763914</link><description>Producers in Western Australia's premier wine region say the state government's expanded bottle recycling scheme is set to cost them millions of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16ff8a6ec9140b73f0af3e85a003dec0</guid></item><item><title>Port Hinchinbrook marina remains inaccessible despite dredging project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/port-hinchinbrook-marina-remains-inaccessible-after-dredging/105739106</link><description>Mud and silt continue to choke the channel connecting the controversial development to the Great Barrier Reef, once again putting industry and conservationists at odds over the fix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00377919955e2acc697f9565f436b2a9</guid></item><item><title>Nepal's Gen Z demands reform as country begins new political path</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/nepal-generation-z-anti-corruption-protests-kathmandu/105773042</link><description>Protesters in Nepal say their Gen Z-led movement was not just about removing one leader, but about reforming the system to ensure accountability and protect Nepal’s future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">836ee3f4801e6cf8e546d51627e6e4b8</guid></item><item><title>Australian rules football and SANFL administrator Max Basheer dies aged 98</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/sanfl-administrator-max-basheer-dies-aged-98/105773500</link><description>Max Basheer — the football administrator who oversaw the creation of the Adelaide Crows and the purpose-built stadium Football Park — has died aged 98.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">594325c3e747906c91d2cd8c90983d6f</guid></item><item><title>AFL State of Origin will return, with Western Australia-Victoria clash confirmed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/afl-announces-state-of-origin-return-with-wa-vic-clash-confirmed/105773392</link><description>AFL chief executive Andrew Dillon confirms Western Australia will play Victoria in Perth next February in the first State of Origin match since 1999.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d22aa23c3e429a537fcaf8a6093051d</guid></item><item><title>Indian cricketers refuse to shake hands with Pakistani counterparts at Asia Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/indian-cricketers-refuse-to-shake-hands-with-pakistanis-asia-cup/105773820</link><description>Indian captain Suryakumar Yadav refuses to shake hands after his side's seven-wicket win over Pakistan at the Asia Cup in the latest controversial episode between the two rivals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e14fcc55b27a2d660ff4a5b3250b9de6</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Roosters confirm ACL injury for Tarryn Aiken on eve of NRLW finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/sydney-roosters-confirm-tarryn-aiken-acl-injury-nrlw/105773930</link><description>Tarryn Aiken will miss the Sydney Roosters' NRLW finals campaign, with scans confirming a knee injury that will require a knee reconstruction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">880a495525ca619936ce2de16f4379d3</guid></item><item><title>Starving wallabies at The Briars spark urgent Mornington Peninsula Shire council meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/the-briars-mornington-peninsula-wallaby-overpopulation-council/105773468</link><description>A study prompted by the deaths of wallabies at a beloved wildlife reserve south of Melbourne finds the population has grown five times larger than what The Briars sanctuary can sustain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">424a62aaec22ec8d6b644d8c878fed7b</guid></item><item><title>SA to roll out ChatGPT-style AI app in all high schools as tech experts urge caution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/education-chat-gpt-style-ai-app-to-roll-out-to-sa-high-schools/105772944</link><description>A ChatGPT-style app to be rolled out at all South Australian high schools next term has been welcomed by tech experts, who are also warning its use should be carefully managed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd8111de02cfad378cd6bbaeb5b75896</guid></item><item><title>2025 Emmys key moments: From Hacks star Hannah Einbinder's acceptance speech to chants for Stephen Colbert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/emmys-2025-key-moments-from-hannah-einbinder-to-stephen-colbert/105773412</link><description>From a rallying political cry from Hacks star Hannah Einbinder to standing ovations for Stephen Colbert, here are your Emmys 2025 key moments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5949a0290fa0abaf999a6b633f1291cd</guid></item><item><title>How much fish is in tinned tuna, and how to shop for your needs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/packaged-foods-content-supermarkets/105707244</link><description>When you're at the supermarket, do you wonder how much much tuna you're getting in a can? A series of popular social media has been comparing how much food there is in some packaged items.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c07e1af76a9ce085f39b2e2924bc18d</guid></item><item><title>How is Australia affected by climate change? The National Climate Risk Assessment models the future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/national-climate-risk-assessment-and-why-it-matters-explained/105773936</link><description>For the first time, the government has modelled the threats from climate change on Australia's future. What's the point of a document like this, and can it help us avoid the worst-case scenarios?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ad84229da5de3e8a79b28e4eacc8cab</guid></item><item><title>Cricket Tasmania seeking ways to make proposed Macquarie Point stadium 'compatible' for matches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/cricket-tasmania-support-macquarie-point-afl-stadium/105774588</link><description>After initial concerns that the roof design of the proposed Hobart AFL stadium at Macquarie Point would hinder cricket matches, sporting authorities have thrown their support behind the build, saying "we will find a way".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52fc9b1b49c5b01644f528cf1efb60b0</guid></item><item><title>Defence dilemma facing Anthony Albanese as he heads to New York</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/the-defence-dilemma-facing-albanese-as-he-heads-to-new-york/105775954</link><description>Amid uncertainty over whether the prime minister will secure his first one-on-one meeting with Donald Trump, the political test is whether his recent defence commitments will be seen as a genuine step-up on capability or a sidestep from American calls to spend more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30bac552ea1477bb6ea09d9f427e1a77</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle Knights announce Justin Holbrook as new NRL head coach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/-newcastle-knights-justin-holbrook-nrl-head-coach/105776208</link><description>Sydney Roosters assistant coach Justin Holbrook has been named the new head coach of the Newcastle Knights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1dd4d58f20f4f23adda8178a9bef8c9</guid></item><item><title>Shadow minister Andrew Hastie says he will be 'without a job' if Liberals don't abandon net zero</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/andrew-hastie-flags-resignation-or-sacking-over-liberal-net-zero/105776432</link><description>Liberal frontbencher Andrew Hastie indicates he will quit or be dumped from the shadow cabinet if the Coalition does not abandon the target of achieving net zero greenhouse gas emissions by 2050.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d65a81fca15feb36d2a53c3d3bdd85a3</guid></item><item><title>Whispering Jack: The John Farnham Musical to premiere in Sydney Theatre Company's 2026 season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/whispering-jack-john-farnham-musical-sydney-theatre-company-2026/105766868</link><description>Whispering Jack: The John Farnham Musical is one of 13 plays coming to Sydney Theatre Company next year, alongside shows starring David Wenham and Miranda Otto.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ade2dd75f87979058d05fced4a9318</guid></item><item><title>NRL announces preliminary finals dates, Melbourne Storm on Friday, Brisbane Broncos play Sunday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/nrl-preliminary-finals-dates-melbourne-brisbane/105776416</link><description>The NRL has shaken up its preliminary finals weekend, electing to host one of its grand final qualifiers on a Sunday for the first time in 18 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29c35159922bc6cf9a11532627c3c244</guid></item><item><title>All the latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/all-the-latest-financial-news/105776480</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f073c7f7020949078deb2eb0c7a85c</guid></item><item><title>Final rules for social media ban revealed, with no legally enforceable effectiveness standard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/social-media-ban-final-rules-announced/105776730</link><description>While substantial fines would apply to social media platforms that make no effort to ban under-16s, they would not need to test the age of every user.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bf25735e4356b3846b028a3101595a6</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste students protest government plan to buy new cars for parliamentarians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/timor-leste-protesters-demand-repeal-of-plan-to-buy-cars-for-mps/105776898</link><description>About 1,000 students hit the streets of the capital to rally against the plan, before police clashed with some protesters who reportedly threw rocks and damaged properties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ce414e161409b0fcdd72ce826062fbc</guid></item><item><title>US and China agree to TikTok 'framework' ownership agreement at trade talks in Spain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/us-and-china-agree-to-framework-for-tiktok-sale/105776964</link><description>US Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent says the framework would see the platform switch to US ownership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5792446bfea9843c09b316ffd472ee8e</guid></item><item><title>Australia-PNG defence treaty will require countries to 'act' if either one is attacked</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/australia-and-png-defence-treaty-could-oblige-military-action/105776214</link><description>Australia and Papua New Guinea will be legally obliged to defend each other from a military attack on either territory under a landmark defence treaty, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a01cbea51a11c9d04e1bcff45aa8aa5</guid></item><item><title>DNA at crime scene matches Charlie Kirk murder suspect, FBI says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/charlie-kirk-crime-scene-dna-matches-murder-suspect/105777360</link><description>Tyler Robinson, 22, was arrested last week over the death of conservative influencer Charlie Kirk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7cf3e37a6ee22b7ae5bb477725734fa</guid></item><item><title>Lawyers urge Australians to ensure valid will in place as house prices rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/lawyers-urge-australians-to-ensure-valid-will-in-place/105767604</link><description>Lawyers urge Australians to ensure they leave behind a valid will to avoid legal disputes as surging house prices and superannuation balances increase the size of inheritances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a89e25f073724834a4daf823bb8d4cd</guid></item><item><title>Fewer Aussies would need NDIS if government boosted mental health support, expert says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/psychosocial-disability-mental-health-ndis/105773308</link><description>As the Albanese government seeks to rein in the cost of the NDIS, a former Australian of the Year says money could be saved with this one shift.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5bca27cbb4ae9aab43ea5684315161e</guid></item><item><title>Climate Risk Assessment's 'high risk' warning for 1 million Australian homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/climate-risk-assessment-million-homes-insurance-gdp-costs/105774418</link><description>One in 10 homes could be effectively uninsurable by 2050, while lost labour productivity to extreme weather could wipe $211 billion in household wealth, the Climate Risk Assessment warns, with tourism, trade, and property values forecasted to take a dive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">801dfb5f2bac8394e795c9893975dce2</guid></item><item><title>ANZ commits bank errors in its favour. Is there any other kind?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/anz-slammed-for-bank-errors-in-its-favour/105775702</link><description>ASIC has lived by that aphorism in its decision to strike a settlement deal with ANZ over a raft of wrongdoing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eab85143099e30eb989aba207539b011</guid></item><item><title>How Melbourne mosquitoes are being used to fight dengue fever and save lives in Laos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/melbourne-mosquitoes-fight-dengue-fever-laos-save-the-children/105773926</link><description>They are the deadliest animals in the world, and millions of them are being sent from Australia to the Laos capital Vientiane in a bid to save lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a24e6c7c32402fe5603b887c428f2552</guid></item><item><title>Pathological Demand Avoidance, a little-known profile of autism affecting kids and adults</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/pathological-demand-avoidance-awareness-of-autism-subtype/105772066</link><description>A surge of professional and personal interest in Pathological Demand Avoidance (PDA), an autism subtype — which in children can affect everything from cleaning teeth to attending school — has led to Australia's first-ever PDA conference, to be held in Perth in November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21dc9dcc25ab99ec13266f4d172f1692</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull believes in world championship 1,500m glory against serial winner Faith Kipyegon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/jess-hull-believes-in-world-championship-1500m-victory/105772376</link><description>Australia's Jess Hull has self-belief, despite facing an uphill task to beat three-time world and Olympic champion Faith Kipyegon over 1,500m at the World Athletics Championships in Tokyo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">101bafefa4e4f1f51f1ac514223465df</guid></item><item><title>WWII-era bombs are killing and injuring thousands in PNG. Now trainees will learn how to remove them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/png-world-war-2-unexploded-ordnance-removal/105774308</link><description>Trainees in Papua New Guinea will learn to remove unexploded ordnance, as fading memories of World War II expose more people to the conflict's dangerous legacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8bf240cd5378047327fc404a9e7f897</guid></item><item><title>Victorian childcare worker denies abusing toddlers, says he is appealing ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/victorian-childcare-worker-denies-abuse-appeals-ban/105702584</link><description>A Goodstart worker who allegedly abused toddlers at a Ballarat centre speaks out for the first time and says he is appealing after being banned from working with children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77e6b47d221359d2363dbff039a62a30</guid></item><item><title>Western Sydney is set to dramatically heat up, this is how communities are preparing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/western-sydney-plans-to-address-climate-change-warming/105775030</link><description>A "shocking" warning that heatwave deaths could skyrocket brings the issue of urban heat back into sharp focus, particularly in the city's west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8587e0ed7880e781adeb84da2b9f99da</guid></item><item><title>Will it happen? Crunch time imminent for Tasmania's proposed Macquarie Point stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/macquarie-point-stadium-planning-decision/105759040</link><description>It's not the be all and end all — but the impending delivery of the Tasmanian Planning Commission's final report is a major moment for the Macquarie Point stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b39f129ad1988ebe3b71971d4e7bb065</guid></item><item><title>Residents encouraged to attract native bees amid varroa mite spread</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/backyard-owners-encouraged-to-attract-native-bees-gardening/105767140</link><description>A pollination ecologist says it is important people play their part in preserving native bees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2de85a81cf81cdc683c925dfd059c30</guid></item><item><title>Tia-Clair Toomey-Orr's eighth CrossFit Games title confirms her GOAT status</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/tia-clair-toomey-on-motherhood-and-becoming-the-crossfit-goat/105774312</link><description>Tia-Clair Toomey-Orr has been considered the CrossFit GOAT for some time, and she is not slowing down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b1bf3278129b6f1f5eae0776b29f16f</guid></item><item><title>Jacinta Nampijinpa Price and Kerrynne Liddle a 'unity ticket' on Indigenous affairs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/kerrynne-liddle-backs-jacinta-nampijinpa-price/105776102</link><description>Kerrynne Liddle speaks for the first time since Jacinta Nampijinpa Price was dumped from the frontbench, saying the pair are "on a unity ticket" when it comes to Indigenous affairs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">baf6de4a9c0796b996abab3ba46e1810</guid></item><item><title>Fears parts of Queensland will have to 'retreat' amid predicted sea level rise and increased severe weather events</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/climate-report-national-climate-risk-assessment-queensland/105775976</link><description>The warning comes amid a national report finding up to 185,000 residential buildings in Queensland could be in "very high-risk areas" if climate change is not addressed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c13eb12a1db1234d6f66dae28d2620c</guid></item><item><title>Spanish prime minister calls for Israel to be banned from sport after La Vuelta a España finale called off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/vuelta-a-espana-final-stage-cancelled-pro-palestinian-protests/105777508</link><description>Pro-Palestinian protests sparked by the inclusion of an Israeli team in La Vuelta a España prompt the cancellation of the last stage of the race, with Spain's prime minister calling for Israel to be treated like Russia by sporting organisations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac0ef3fdcf72c0008f752df151d4c3f8</guid></item><item><title>The hidden impact of injuries costing AFL clubs millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/the-hidden-costs-of-injuries-costing-afl-clubs-millions/105777624</link><description>New research highlights the financial impact of injuries in the AFL, with one club losing $13 millions over six seasons, nearly 17 per cent of its total player salaries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1df9a60d5e14380c28dd088a5cbf203a</guid></item><item><title>Rex Airlines apologises after wheelchair-using passenger stranded for six hours at Perth Airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/rex-passenger-issues-albany-perth-wheelchair-user-/105774708</link><description>Albany woman Debby Butler says she had to ask strangers to help her to the bathroom after Rex delayed her flight home from Perth Airport and left her without a wheelchair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbfe858ddf70fc0694fbe80e02bdc22a</guid></item><item><title>Nikki Webster sings with her children for 25th anniversary of Sydney Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/nikki-webster-sings-with-her-children-for-25th/105778014</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c83bf0274f16a9fa314e120145c3d8f</guid></item><item><title>Cathy Freeman and Ian Thorpe among Stadium Australia's first hall of fame inductees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/cathy-freeman-ian-thorpe-stadium-australia-hall-of-fame/105777908</link><description>The first golden group of inductees were honoured at an event that threw back to the Sydney 2000 games with Nikki Webster reproducing her iconic opening ceremony performance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdef62442b745f1023ee6848ed55f9e3</guid></item><item><title>Vantara wildlife facility cleared of wrongdoing by court-ordered probe in India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/vantara-wildlife-facility-cleared-of-wrongdoing-by-indian-probe/105777330</link><description>Conservationists had raised concerns about Vantara but investigators say the issues raised are "devoid of merit".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ae8a80b362270975ef42f54dcbd8c5</guid></item><item><title>Lisa Reihana's exhibition, Voyager, recasts history through an Indigenous lens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/lisa-reihana-ngununggula-exhibition-voyager-indigenous-maori/105760474</link><description>The internationally renowned Maori artist's technically complex, visually mesmerising exhibition spans nearly a decade of artwork.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ed46a76298102094bcf604b8536fb9b</guid></item><item><title>How to determine if your kid is well enough for child care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/the-advice-around-sending-a-sick-kid-to-child-care/105734762</link><description>Work demands and a lack of village mean keeping a child at home from care every time they have a sniffle can be a dilemma for many parents. So when it it OK to send them?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3431c0d66326982196374e9a6c348b5f</guid></item><item><title>Family comes first for Queensland newsreader Rob Brough after months off-air</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/newsreader-rob-broughs-family-battle/105775464</link><description>The long-time nightly newsreader says it was an "instant choice" to leave work as his daughter faced a battle with cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23d10f83e00ccce3717d0f0a569d4a1c</guid></item><item><title>Craig McLachlan withdraws from Cluedo stage show following backlash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/craig-mclachlan-withdraws-cluedo-the-play/105779280</link><description>Less than a week ago, Craig McLachlan was announced to play Colonel Mustard in the forthcoming national tour, making his return to the theatre after The Rocky Horror Show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2abe05c441b509ea22995eb926f87711</guid></item><item><title>Planning commission rejects bid to turn Redbank Power Station into bioenergy hub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/planning-commission-rejects-redbank-power-station-biofuel-plan/105777592</link><description>The Independent Planning Commission of NSW knocks back plans to restart Redbank Power Station in the Hunter Valley, fuelling it with biomass instead of coal tailings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">149bdcd14f72ed4787e50322861090cb</guid></item><item><title>Australia Diamonds announce netball squads for Test series against New Zealand, South Africa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/australia-diamonds-announce-test-netball-squads-new-zealand-sa/105779230</link><description>Goal-shooter Lucy Austin is a shock selection in the Australian netball squad to face South Africa, winning a place after initially being included as an "invitee" to their training camp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f84722b6abee542504171a8343b1b82</guid></item><item><title>Central Queensland included in fire ant biosecurity zones</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/fire-ant-biosecurity-zones-introduced-in-central-queensland/105777728</link><description>New restrictions in place on moving materials into five central Queensland sites to reduce the spread of the invasive species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f62a27c6d9e79b642f55fa3dab985fb8</guid></item><item><title>Victoria delays Gippsland offshore wind auction, stalling developers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/victoria-offshore-wind-auction-delay/105778708</link><description>The Victorian government pushes back its timeline for new offshore wind farms in the state's east in a blow to developers looking to move their projects to the next stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80c982b89a58ea8f9bc5c06f098af297</guid></item><item><title>Aaron Chen talks comedy, faith, and moving to New York</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/aaron-chen-take-5-comedy-interview-music-tonight-fisk/105773602</link><description>How Aaron Chen went from being booted out of Sydney pubs to winning Logies and chasing global stardom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd43f88c371be470e8b83b1b925f650a</guid></item><item><title>Does washing your fruit and veggies remove chemicals?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/best-way-to-wash-fresh-produce-fruits-veggies-remove-chemcials-/105773664</link><description>This is what experts have to say about washing fruit and veggies, with removing chemicals and reducing the amount we consume in mind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57b4d4864180c3c11eed8be0eca03f20</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump files defamation and libel lawsuit against The New York Times, claiming 'massive economic damage to his brand value'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/trump-files-us15-billion-lawsuit-against-new-york-times/105779782</link><description>In a lengthy post on his social media platform, the US president accused The New York Times of lying about him, his family and his business.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">025394af4103f19c4c76069f86680f4b</guid></item><item><title>Concurrent disasters will overwhelm responders, stress ADF, risk report warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/defence-forces-disaster-response-climate-risk-assessment/105778304</link><description>A dedicated disaster recovery force is needed, or else responders and defence forces could be "overwhelmed" by multiple concurrent natural disasters, the National Climate Risk Assessment warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79a82e7988ce64cb47e2aea9d939b300</guid></item><item><title>Breastfeeding Gold Coast mum says she was asked to leave Virgin Australia lounge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/virgin-australia-apologises-mother-pumping-breast-milk/105779738</link><description>Mother-of-two Elise Turner says she was asked to leave the Virgin Australia business lounge after refusing to go to a bathroom to pump breast milk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a5d01ae6ec3bc3224e376127e761ff5</guid></item><item><title>How Isabelle Kelly shook off getting her 'teeth pushed back' to return for Roosters' NRLW finals charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/isabelle-kelly-injury-jaw-teeth-roosters-nrlw-finals/105780582</link><description>Isabelle Kelly was meant to rest up for a few weeks after suffering an oral fracture that nearly cost her several teeth but the Roosters skipper missed just one match and has now returned to lead the club's premiership charge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">062a7201f7cd32cadeb54c8069a61337</guid></item><item><title>China has a 'chokehold' on the rare earth supply chain. Could Australia offer an alternative?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/china-rare-earths-monopoly-australia-alternative-supplier/105748058</link><description>Rare earths are critical for manufacturing everything from electric vehicles to wind turbines and defence equipment, and with China's dominance over the supply chain, they have also become inextricably enmeshed in geopolitics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7e66c6df15c930bf8fa103970dac05b</guid></item><item><title>Israeli military launches ground offensive to occupy Gaza City</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/idf-launches-military-offensive-to-occupy-gaza/105777948</link><description>The Israel Defense Forces says its expanded operation in Gaza City "to destroy Hamas's military infrastructure" has begun, with residents warned to move south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80bfd937165cc59a068b4d0ad85e2045</guid></item><item><title>Israel is committing genocide in Gaza, major United Nations report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/israel-committing-genocide-in-gaza-un-report-says/105780230</link><description>Israel has committed and is continuing to commit genocide in Gaza, according to the "most authoritative assessment" to date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e547fcd275b42fb12bbaa7d9028fd7aa</guid></item><item><title>James O'Connor still hopeful of playing Bledisloe Cup for Wallabies against All Blacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/james-oconnor-still-hopeful-of-playing-bledisloe-cup/105780738</link><description>James O'Connor has flown to England with his Test future still up in the air, but the Wallabies playmaker has not given up on playing in his first Bledisloe Cup match in five years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fe6060cfa537dad8e49fa78e8c41f63</guid></item><item><title>A UN report says Israel is committing genocide. Experts hope it spurs Australia to act</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/un-report-on-israel-genocide-msg-to-nations-including-australia/105777232</link><description>What ultimately determines whether the UN's report joins the list of other shocking but overlooked inquiries is whether this latest finding moves any governments, including Australia's, to take further action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">121775c05df3d7bd0ed0b0d63cee2c23</guid></item><item><title>Approval of $453 million battery project angers Kiewa Valley residents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/victorian-premier-approves-kiewa-valley-battery-project/105779392</link><description>The state government approves the development of a $453 million energy storage system by a Chinese company in the state's north-east, angering nearby residents who say their concerns have been ignored.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0714747da477ffd0c9e429861e28643d</guid></item><item><title>China accuses Philippines of 'illegal' intrusion at its new nature reserve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/china-accuses-philippines-of-illegal-intrusion-at-new-reserve/105781038</link><description>China's coastguard has accused Philippine ships of illegally entering China's territorial waters at a shoal that is internationally recognised as within the Philippines' exclusive economic zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d22fae2218c2b953ce31ac500d27401e</guid></item><item><title>NRL finals week two team lists: Canterbury Bulldogs pick new halves combination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/nrl-finals-week-two-team-lists-bulldogs-panthers-raiders-sharks/105781098</link><description>Winger Jacob Kiraz has revealed he is happy to keep playing with painkilling injections as a patched-up Canterbury turn to a barely tested halves combination of Lachlan Galvin and Toby Sexton to save their NRL season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e00963cd95ccbc1a7f4dac1f88d12452</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105781402</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e2b5a3b30f5fdf1b8c8739f00047ca8</guid></item><item><title>Man 'choked to death' on ribbons and food in Adelaide nursing home, inquest told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/sa-inquest-hears-nursing-home-resident-choked-on-ribbons/105697736</link><description>A nursing home resident known to wander and ingest foreign objects died after choking on ribbons at a facility in Adelaide’s north, an inquest has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95ba5d590939d36f5248d85d89547a6f</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull wins 1,500m bronze, Peter Bol crashes out at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-jess-hull/105778240</link><description>Jess Hull claims bronze in the women's 1,500m at the World Athletics Championships, after Peter Bol was eliminated from the 800m in the heats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7250f2b7b3eaaed7b8f51092ef3fc818</guid></item><item><title>Is the Opposition in crisis over climate change policy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/is-the-opposition-in-crisis-over-climate-change/105781502</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e90e0f2ed4edff762cfcb406a5eae813</guid></item><item><title>Broadcaster Alan Jones hit with nine new indecent assault charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/alan-jones-new-indecent-assault-charges/105781256</link><description>Court records confirm the new charges were formally laid against veteran broadcaster Alan Jones on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b603c10b6c32f66440446167e3e24ee3</guid></item><item><title>Robert Redford, Hollywood idol of the 1970s and Oscar-winning director and actor, has died aged 89</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/actor-and-activist-robert-redford-dies-aged-89/105781564</link><description>Redford died "at his home in Sundance in the mountains of Utah" surrounded by family, his publicist announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f08a88e14f2b784115f4aa8b363f1ecc</guid></item><item><title>Nepal's protests estimated to have caused hundreds of millions of dollars in damage as families farewell those killed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/nepal-gen-z-protests-cause-millions-of-dollars-in-damage/105781578</link><description>As clean-up efforts continue and an interim government finds its feet, families have said farewell to loved ones killed in last week's violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1064109a46dbf7b37962228d9f172092</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump takes aim at ABC journalist as he suggests he'll meet Albanese 'very soon'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/donald-trump-john-lyons-exchange-before-anthony-albanese-meeting/105781624</link><description>Donald Trump takes aim at the ABC's Americas editor during an extraordinary exchange at the White House, as the president suggests he will meet Prime Minister Anthony Albanese "very soon".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">156db315a11501aa8fbeaf35550e4091</guid></item><item><title>New York judge dismisses state terrorism charges against Luigi Mangione</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/judge-dismisses-terrorism-charges-against-luigi-mangione/105781696</link><description>The 27-year-old Ivy League graduate still faces New York state second-degree murder charges and a federal death penalty prosecution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdb179c60ca3cc9f40d0ef6ea086656d</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste protesters vow to continue rallying until plan to buy MPs 65 cars is overturned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/timor-leste-protests-over-mp-car-plan-grow/105781726</link><description>The protests nearly doubled in size on Tuesday as people continued to vent their frustrations at a plan to buy MPs 65 new SUVs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">feeb6a6ab4a2322ebf2709358b8c2353</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk shooting suspect Tyler Robinson charged with murder as prosecutors seek death penalty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/alleged-charlie-kirk-shooter-tyler-robinson-charged/105781872</link><description>Utah prosecutors say they will seek the death penalty for the 22-year-old alleged shooter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87bd66a147b9d8ff76e79fdd79e8ff76</guid></item><item><title>Australians too dependent on government, says Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/australians-too-dependent-on-government-says-sussan-ley/105781276</link><description>In her first major economic speech, the opposition leader hits out at universal subsidies and says "dependency" has affected Australia's "national character".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">651c319b8e005af88f9f36c064e26d9e</guid></item><item><title>Britain is hoping it has a secret weapon to charm Donald Trump this week: 'all his favourite things'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/donald-trump-heads-to-uk-for-second-state-visit/105764556</link><description>The US president has been given something no other world leader has ever received: a second state visit invitation from Buckingham Palace. But assessing the trip's success means looking beneath the pomp and pageantry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">816968e21bc208bd8ed8cd9ca5863c1d</guid></item><item><title>Botox, fillers among the cosmetic injectables targeted in medical regulator's new rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/cosmetic-injectables-rules-botox-fillers/105778596</link><description>New rules have come into place aimed at better protecting patients from unsafe cosmetic procedures. Here's what it mean for your next appointment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f034dc98c168b046f196741357b091bf</guid></item><item><title>Threat of stagflation bears down on world's largest economy as Federal Reserve decision looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/threat-of-stagflation-bears-down-on-world-s-largest-economy/105781264</link><description>The world's largest central bank is less than 24 hours from announcing one of the most anticipated interest rate decisions of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">317d2acf44c6b55d5cef638469f7338f</guid></item><item><title>What time does Gout Gout run at the World Athletics Championships? How to watch Gout Gout's 200m heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/when-does-gout-gout-run-200m-at-world-athletics-championships/105775006</link><description>Gout Gout will make his senior World Athletics Championships debut at the Tokyo National Stadium on Wednesday night. Here's how to watch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d64ce570ae00cb2a79c594c389ec4b0</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of childcare workers blacklisted but parents kept in the dark</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/childcare-workers-blacklisted/105774698</link><description>About 400 educators were issued prohibition orders banning them from early education or care in the past five years, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">969481d17339daff15088beab11c2217</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump chastised ABC journalist John Lyons over questions about his business dealings.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/trump-tells-off-australian-reporter/105781964</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4126cdea12b1cfee4255c1102333a08</guid></item><item><title>The Federal Home Guarantee Scheme is expanding, but just how many will be able to afford to buy in?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/home-loan-guarantee-scheme-cost-first-home-buyers/105772918</link><description>The expansion of the scheme, which allows first home buyers to purchase a property with as little as a 5 per cent deposit, has some warning it will also inflate the market. Here's what you'll need to be earning to get a foot in the door.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4fd4e5c6040f2d8b9de5c0800458317</guid></item><item><title>Unpaid mandatory work experience a 'significant barrier' for some NSW law students</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/plt-unpaid-placements-nsw-law-students-a-financial-difficulty/105774700</link><description>During her unpaid placement at a not-for-profit community legal centre in Sydney, Dani struggled to make ends meet. She is among some law students whose entry into the profession is fraught with financial difficulty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a77e2484c201c3b6a1ff99c5e168d5c6</guid></item><item><title>Fingal Post Office saved from closure after local farmers confirmed as new operators</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/fingal-post-office-in-tasmania-saved-by-local-pig-farmers/105779962</link><description>A rural Tasmanian community has fought to keep its post office open, fearing losing the important service could lead to their hometown disappearing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08e347abc9bfa22abeb9447ad06020ab</guid></item><item><title>SA's ongoing harmful algal bloom labelled 'cultural emergency' by First Nations groups</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/sa-algal-bloom-cultural-emergency/105631230</link><description>First Nations South Australians say the harmful algal bloom impacting the state's coastline is a cultural emergency, as it continues to devastate beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ed15cf74630a813b331beecfe638cdf</guid></item><item><title>Fire threatens koala habitat at Gold Coast's Burleigh Headland national park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/fire-threatens-koala-habitat-at-burleigh-headland/105781982</link><description>Police are investigating how a suspicious fire started in the popular tourist spot overnight, burning through around 75 per cent of the grass under the boulder clusters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a9ef095f199bc494bedacf6b3ab64f2</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians fear they have no place to flee as Israel's army pushes deeper into Gaza city</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/israel-push-deeper-gaza-city-palestinians-fear-no-place-to-flee/105781870</link><description>Israeli troops encircle Gaza City as the UN chief slams the offensive as "systematic destruction", with thousands of Palestinians unable or unwilling to flee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d201c662cb235506a4e3a65fa23e2158</guid></item><item><title>Children are being 'poisoned' by high lead levels as state government agency is accused of report cover-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/broken-hill-lead-poisoning-cover-up-mudgee-silver-mine-fears/105775230</link><description>A state government body sat on a report into lead dust that was "poisoning" children for nearly four years and tried to keep its release quiet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c539d0a8e324dc8143836fe465192aec</guid></item><item><title>Griffith locals push for new health district to meet needs of their community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/griffith-locals-push-for-new-health-district/105729862</link><description>Residents and medical professionals in south-western NSW are pushing to establish a new local health district in Griffith, arguing current services are not good enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">811a2f3a903585b4dace7ad758f6a3f0</guid></item><item><title>ABC reporter reflects on heated exchange with Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/abc-reporter-reflects-on-heated-exchange-with-trump/105782066</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d66c9b484df7f246f7468910b081bdfa</guid></item><item><title>Cashrewards's abrupt closure leaves shoppers many unanswered questions. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/cashrewards-abrupt-shutdown-stuns-many-australians/105765936</link><description>Two and a half million Australians have signed up for this cashback app, which leaves them wondering what's next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74d5aaf89ebaad05dd5c26265b442d23</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: Australia, PNG defence treaty fails at final hurdle, leaders sign communique instead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/federal-politics-live-september-17/105781024#live-blog-post-224383</link><description>A major defence treaty between Australia and Papua New Guinea has failed to get over the line today, with the countries resorting to signing a communique in lieu of the actual document. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">519de852a1de903d74903c1208102e67</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: Australia, PNG defence treaty fails at final hurdle, leaders sign communique instead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/federal-politics-live-september-17/105781024</link><description>A major defence treaty between Australia and Papua New Guinea has failed to get over the line today, with the countries resorting to signing a communique in lieu of the actual document. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43721cebab6002970109bf4316e512ac</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: Australia, PNG defence treaty fails at final hurdle, leaders sign communique instead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/federal-politics-live-september-17/105781024#live-blog-post-224372</link><description>A major defence treaty between Australia and Papua New Guinea has failed to get over the line today, with the countries resorting to signing a communique in lieu of the actual document. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07a905f0319e858a7c107e25321d88c3</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: Australia, PNG defence treaty fails at final hurdle, leaders sign communique instead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/federal-politics-live-september-17/105781024#live-blog-post-224386</link><description>A major defence treaty between Australia and Papua New Guinea has failed to get over the line today, with the countries resorting to signing a communique in lieu of the actual document. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0703c6f19c1180e9fe941513093deb8</guid></item><item><title>New doco Signorinella: Little Miss celebrates the Italian women who shaped modern Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/signorinella-little-miss-documentary-italian-film-festival/105774428</link><description>Signorinella: Little Miss, the new documentary from the filmmakers behind Lygon St — Si Parla Italiano, celebrates the tenacity of Italian Australian women in business and beyond.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dc3ea23b27aab754a73fa0319a25aee</guid></item><item><title>NT DPP considering appeal of 'callous' fatal hit-run driver's home detention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/nt-appeal-call-in-shocking-aboriginal-hit-and-run-death/105780750</link><description>The Northern Territory's Director of Public Prosecutions is considering whether to appeal a decision to allow a young fatal hit-and-run driver who bragged to his friends afterwards to avoid jail time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb939e2ec24d851b13e88e0a5a420eb3</guid></item><item><title>Starving wallabies on the Mornington Peninsula have been spared from euthanasia after council motion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/vic-briars-wallabies-council-decision/105781992</link><description>A council on Victoria's Mornington Peninsula has voted to relocate starving wallabies from The Briars wildlife sanctuary, rather than destroy them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02ef3566afd789e1a2e2de6749141251</guid></item><item><title>Sam Konstas scores Australia A century in four-day game in India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/sam-konstas-scores-australia-a-century-against-india-a/105782060</link><description>Sam Konstas's push for an Ashes spot continues as he clatters a century in an extended session for Australia A in Lucknow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cec1e71dd86b61ad4d12f75e6292662</guid></item><item><title>WA Police officers subject to restraining orders desk-bound under gun reforms, union says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/wa-police-taken-off-beat-under-gun-reforms/105743700</link><description>New firearms laws meaning WA Police officers can't carry a gun if they're subject to a restraining order are leaving them desk-bound, their union warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9778f00d409cd20aa6f59b898e30bc37</guid></item><item><title>Animal advocates want WA to 'get on board' with phasing out greyhound racing amid welfare concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/wa-greyhound-racing-parliamentary-inquiry/105781496</link><description>Animal advocates call on the WA government to follow the lead of other jurisdictions and phase out greyhound racing, as a state parliamentary inquiry examines the sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d151b0111cbdf98135b0a72304ccd15</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull completes second act at World Athletics Championships as quest for gold continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/jess-hull-world-1500m-bronze-medal-wants-gold/105781748</link><description>Jess Hull claimed Australia's best result in a 1,500m at the world championships with a bronze medal, but she wants to make it gold next time around.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b678c9c3d3bc90e24f522348f78b840</guid></item><item><title>Markets live: ASX to fall, Wall Street slips from record highs ahead of Fed rate cut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/asx-markets-business-live-news/105782190</link><description>The Australian share market is likely to fall in morning trade ahead of the latest ABS inflation data, while the Nasdaq rises above 17,000 points for the first time. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acd1d6f1424bebf9031a3c2efe25f550</guid></item><item><title>Investigation underway after man dies following stabbing on Gwydir Highway near Grafton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/man-dies-after-stabbing-on-gwydir-highway-near-grafton/105782226</link><description>A 35-year-old man has died after he was stabbed overnight in what police believe was a targeted attack on the Gwydir Highway in Grafton.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9be9ee2105f9780cac11dba00ca665f6</guid></item><item><title>Two men to face court over $14 million cocaine bust in Melbourne's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/cocaine-bust-in-kalkallo-melbourne/105782246</link><description>Two men will face court after police found $14 million worth of cocaine in a vehicle in Melbourne's north. It's alleged the men were transporting the cocaine for an illegal drug syndicate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a60437be42c502a08eb499ce95492b9f</guid></item><item><title>BHP alliance to sack 750 workers, blaming Qld government mining royalties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/bhp-alliance-to-sack-750-workers-qld-mining-royalties-saraji/105782302</link><description>One of Queensland's biggest coal miners will cut about 750 jobs across its operations, blaming the impact of high royalties imposed by the state government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b896656142195d5941582f9cbb0f9982</guid></item><item><title>South Australia's feral deer culling program targets eradication amid plague warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/sa-deer-eradication-program-aerial-culling-reduces-population/105763068</link><description>South Australia has ramped up its feral deer aerial culling program as drought-affected farmers battle the pest on their properties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62ba923682e9f4c1c2fea7cd969ab7fd</guid></item><item><title>Australia and PNG fail to clinch defence agreement, resorting to communique</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/australia-png-fail-defence-agreement-communique/105782424</link><description>A major defence treaty between Australia and Papua New Guinea has failed to get over the line today, with the countries resorting to signing a communique in lieu of the actual document.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d5916f8d88a6bb049ef9ef389165d8e</guid></item><item><title>Rainbow bee-eaters prevented from nesting on Qld festival site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/rainbow-bee-eaters-prevented-from-nesting-at-agnes-water-site/105773530</link><description>Conservationists say one of the country's largest colonies of a protected native bird is under threat at a two-day festival site.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c2f01e7162df177f029c3df3ed57e39</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Roosters, Brisbane Broncos NRLW favourites, Andrew Abdo banking on finals surprise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/roosters-broncos-nrlw-dominance-ahead-of-finals/105782346</link><description>As the NRLW finals kick off with the Roosters and Broncos miles ahead of the competition, chief executive Andrew Abdo is hoping the unpredictability of sudden-death finals will generate some surprises.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86b0bb2a5b175f5f803d5ee41052ecb1</guid></item></channel></rss>