<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:43:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Best books out in November, featuring Margaret Atwood's memoir and The Mushroom Tapes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/best-books-november-margaret-atwood-memoir-mushroom-tapes/106018540</link><description>Wondering what to read next? This month's best books include a novel that brings to life Britain's only named wind and a new book by the author of The Handmaid's Tale.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9716753e1b04846ee97e8f09ff9b42a</guid></item><item><title>England captain Ben Stokes dismisses 'arrogant' label amid criticism of Ashes Test loss to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/ashes-cricket-england-australia-ben-stokes-arrogant-label/106082046</link><description>Captain Ben Stokes responds to England's critics in the wake of the defeat to Australia in the first Test, maintaining his squad will not step back from its aggressive approach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cadb1c10356060c35802d310ab0fa02f</guid></item><item><title>Why Barbados became a republic and cut ties with the British monarchy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/barbados-history-republic-commonwealth-monarchy/105958372</link><description>With countries like Australia still debating whether or not the time has come to become a republic, what prompted tiny Barbados with its population of less than 300,000, to take the leap?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e2cc0f86de1e08744b5c83a12201fa7</guid></item><item><title>The spooky First Nations movie you need to see at BIFF</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/it-will-find-you-brisbane-international-film-festival/106074274</link><description>First Nations stories are combined with modern horror scares in this new film from Australian creatives Chris Broadbent and Enzo Tedeschi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b235169fa73d8695e28eb94f33cc4ba4</guid></item><item><title>Sterile flies rain down on Kangaroo Island as battle to wipe out sheep blowfly gets serious</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/kangaroo-island-sterile-blowfly-eradication-program/106056134</link><description>Researchers on Kangaroo Island have been breeding and releasing millions of sterile Australian sheep blowflies in an attempt to eradicate the pest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">233b4fa9b04b33e056e44ce318137bca</guid></item><item><title>British playwright and Oscar winner Tom Stoppard dies at 88</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/british-playwright-tom-stoppard-dies-at-88/106083072</link><description>Stoppard was often hailed as the greatest British playwright of his generation, with multiple awards for his work on stage and screen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98af289ac7e02d33ea03fab0ce5d0ac4</guid></item><item><title>Sydney FC great Alex Brosque fumes over alleged handball in Wanderers' 1-0 ALM win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/a-league-men-sydney-fc-wanderers-alleged-handball/106083524</link><description>Sydney FC's four-match winning streak comes to a crashing halt, but its 1-0 loss to Western Sydney has sparked debate about what constitutes a handball.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de18334568fcf4b8e3c548d6262734b1</guid></item><item><title>LNP's Wayde Chiesa promises to get to work after victory in Hinchinbrook by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/lnp-wayde-chiesa-wins-hinchinbrook-by-election/106074692</link><description>The LNP's Wayde Chiesa will be the next representative for the Queensland seat of Hinchinbrook, which had been safely held by Katter's Australian Party since 2017.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">316d56db0aad14eb566c92220ddfecdb</guid></item><item><title>Em Rusciano on finding balance in life after her ADHD and autism diagnoses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/em-rusciano-autism-adhd-perimenopause-work-life-unwind-with/106074920</link><description>As a writer, singer, comedian, podcaster, author and single mum, Em Rusciano has become accustomed to navigating a chaotic life. The self-described "maximalist power queen" shares how she unwinds and how her approach to life has changed since going through perimenopause and being diagnosed with ADHD and autism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54a0940ddb38aa0802a5f057eb56cae2</guid></item><item><title>Photographer Lyn Alcock captures wild antics of Dryandra's numbat population over 20 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/dryandra-numbat-antics-photographer/106051162</link><description>Lyn Alcock is known as the 'Numbat whisperer', spending hours every day observing and photographing the tiny, endangered marsupials, recording behaviours that have never been seen before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50f2d4bc8d830154bacd7c73f39c8ce2</guid></item><item><title>Spain's David Puig wins Australian PGA Championship by two strokes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/australian-pga-championship-david-puig-wins/106084240</link><description>David Puig joins legendary countryman Seve Ballesteros as an Australian PGA champion after emerging from a congested field at Royal Queensland Golf Club in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">812b93393c051ab8c1803cbf9df390f6</guid></item><item><title>Homes under threat as bushfire bears down on properties in Geraldton suburbs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-30/waggrakine-moresby-fire-threatens-homes-greater-geraldton/106084318</link><description>Lives and homes are again under threat from a bushfire burning in Western Australia's Midwest, with a fresh emergency warning issued in Geraldton's outer suburbs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5208f0ff12f02163d98015c2210bd05</guid></item><item><title>England's Ashes demolition job of Australia in Brisbane's first ever cricket Test match at the Ekka</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/ashes-test-brisbane-debut-1928-ekka/105922054</link><description>Australia's Ashes domination in Brisbane is almost total, with England winless at the Gabba since 1986. It wasn't always like this though, with the first visit to Brisbane resulting in the heaviest defeat in cricket history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab43081c32b914f98f525f1dcad3283b</guid></item><item><title>Queensland to have brief break from heat and storms, with more forecast by weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/queensland-weather-heat-storms-reprieve-forecast/106083672</link><description>After a soaking November, this week could deliver a very brief reprieve from the storms and scorching heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3473f1682b68eb0a13e64623d647611d</guid></item><item><title>Hinchinbrook by-election a tick of approval for LNP government but no crystal ball for outcome of next election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/qld-hinchinbrook-analysis-win-for-lnp-but-no-crystal-ball/106083638</link><description>A week is a long time in politics, let alone three years, and the LNP's success at the next election is by no means assured, writes Jack McKay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa5569c66ea70291d591041c2aae0c67</guid></item><item><title>The Macquarie Point stadium decision is due this week — here's how it could play out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/decision-week-for-hobart-afl-stadium-macquarie-point-arrives/106083308</link><description>The long-running debate over whether an AFL stadium should be built on Hobart's waterfront is reaching an end, as the parliamentary vote takes place this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a9c6bb32e5fb7b1c9f738f20dc9a98a</guid></item><item><title>Opticomm customers across Australia losing free-to-air television and facing internet outages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/opticomm-free-to-air-television-internet-outages/106018424</link><description>About 50,000 Australians are set to lose access to free-to-air television using their existing technology. And the troubles do not end there, with many customers also reporting regular and prolonged internet outages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">933c51c03c903bfd60d6f5b3b5bbdbbe</guid></item><item><title>Geraldton bushfire destroys one home as up to 200 firefighters worked to control blaze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/wa-bushfire-emergency-second-day-as-geraldton-homes-threatened/106085396</link><description>Authorities have downgraded their warning levels for bushfires burning in the greater Geraldton area to an 'advice' level after a challenging day for firefighters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d3515fd97db7af71f664858e3914f5e</guid></item><item><title>Ngangkaṟi share traditional healing in new edition of book that went global</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/traditional-healers-of-central-australia-ngangka%E1%B9%9Fi-book/106044308</link><description>The Ngangkaṟi in Central Australia use traditional healing techniques to draw out illness with their hands. A new edition of their book aims to share this knowledge Western health workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da3cdb0b168f3c536805a673e3da2c38</guid></item><item><title>Popular and easy summer desserts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/popular-easy-summer-desserts-for-christmas/105694904</link><description>Summer desserts are for sharing and we have 10 options for end-of-year gatherings and Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3366cdd05c515593818911cf9afece2f</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr edges closer to injury return in final Matildas friendly vs New Zealand before Asian Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/sam-kerr-in-the-mix-for-matildas-return-new-zealand/106088840</link><description>Matildas captain Sam Kerr is running out of chances to make her long-awaited return from a knee injury, as the Australian team faces New Zealand's Football Ferns in their last scheduled match before next year's Asian Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">400ff4b4f8245af06660fd82ad475744</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanians express mix of views ahead of final Macquarie Point stadium vote</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/hobart-stadium-weighing-on-minds-of-community-before-vote/106085678</link><description>By the end of this week, Tasmania will know whether or not Hobart will have a new AFL stadium. Many Tasmanians are still making up their own minds about whether they support it or not.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6296ba9abc412578f7570cc2fbe9b3b</guid></item><item><title>The numbers and narrative behind Australia's staggering pink ball success</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/ashes-australia-england-pink-ball-test-numbers/106085716</link><description>Day-night Test cricket provides Australia with one of the most potent home advantages in the history of the sport. Ten years into its existence, these are the numbers behind the format, its best performers and the ways England could spring an upset in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffa771d00a61b6e9f3aadf2b0fa603c9</guid></item><item><title>As teacher shortages loom across Australia these Queensland schools are trialling solutions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/teacher-shortage-nearing-crisis-point-solutions/106026086</link><description>As staff shortages "near crisis point", these Queensland schools are going to extraordinary lengths to put teachers in classrooms — and keep them there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a577430673addb35fb00c86c4dd4f38</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Lethlean undecided on whether to challenge Jacinta Allan in Bendigo East</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/nationals-election-2026-tilt-bendigo-east-premier-jacinta-allan/106058372</link><description>Nationals favourite Andrew Lethlean is tight-lipped on whether he will challenge Premier Jacinta Allan in Bendigo East next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">721000b60bd831162f40f3b72df076fe</guid></item><item><title>Filmmaker breaks decades of silence over Yolŋu clan leader's alleged murder by police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/nt-officer-witnessed-fellow-police-murder-yolngu-clan-leader/105987868</link><description>Acclaimed filmmaker George Gittoes has revealed a former NT police officer told him he witnessed his colleagues taking a Yolŋu clan leader out to shoot him and dump his body in Darwin Harbour in 1934.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">500aeaa5e5493474fdfb9c4d9e62fe5d</guid></item><item><title>Geraldton resident Nick Morgan grateful for support after losing home in bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/geraldton-bushfires-nick-morgan-lost-home-in-blaze/106088720</link><description>A home owner who lost his house and his cat to a bushfire in Geraldton, in WA's Mid West, says "karma" is looking for anyone who may have deliberately lit the blazes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9494d02854696251499de8271a43c661</guid></item><item><title>South Australian farmers fear future as bird flu recovery causes egg oversupply</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/egg-shortage-becomes-egg-oversupply-bird-flu-recovery-sa/105964496</link><description>The industry was plagued by bird flu 12 months ago, but some producers are now struggling to sell their product due to a faster-than-expected recovery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0349b4f56e5ca56ffe4f70096bf07b8</guid></item><item><title>Princess Aiko's popularity sparks calls to ditch male-only succession law in Japan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/japan-princess-aiko-calls-to-change-monarch-succession-law/106089708</link><description>Historically, Japan has had numerous women monarchs. But current laws prevent the emperor's daughter from succeeding him — and politicians, including the prime minister, support the status quo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a7cf5b898879cec1db4ebac35f7bc73</guid></item><item><title>Submarine tour, roof protest and shark encounter feature in our top WA photos for November</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/wa-photo-wrap-november/106079370</link><description>Our photographers cast their eyes towards WA's exploding rabbit population, a surfer's near-miss with a suspected great white shark, and a school program helping parents bond with their children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f974edd6698d9f6bfc9bf46521e5ae93</guid></item><item><title>Western Bulldogs former number one AFLW pick Kristie-Lee Weston-Turner wants to join North Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/bulldogs-top-aflw-draft-pick-wants-to-join-kangaroos/106090324</link><description>The Kangaroos' domination of the AFLW is set to be given another boost, with a former number one draft pick confirming she wants to head to North.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bede87c0bbc97c907b16f1cc846785fe</guid></item><item><title>Farmer killed fighting West River bushfire near Ravensthorpe on WA's south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/farmer-killed-fighting-bushfire-in-southern-wa-ravensthorpe/106089112</link><description>A man is killed while trying to establish a firebreak to help tackle a blaze near Ravensthorpe along WA's south coast, with the premier describing his death as "devastating".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f62a47050e206d1a04b1aabb0ce35cf</guid></item><item><title>Right to repair reforms to be expanded to farm machinery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/right-to-repair-reforms-to-be-expanded-to-farm-machinery/106089888</link><description>After years of depending on dealership networks for essential repairs, farmers will have the right to fix their own equipment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e7f1a7001f78874dfc5eb6a2f95a15b</guid></item><item><title>Beekeepers warn of food price increases amid varroa mite battle in South Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/varroa-mite-impact-bees-increase-food-costs-supermarket-sa/106090336</link><description>Beekeepers say the escalating cost of pollinating crops will be passed onto consumers as the industry battles a devastating bee killer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d8e8e6eedfb1484bd8b7f1f8335eb8a</guid></item><item><title>My daughter has two mums. I'm her other mother</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/what-it-is-like-being-the-other-mum/105977574</link><description>Even though I am Evie's favourite — I am, after all, the fun mum — I can't shake the feeling that when it comes to serious mothering, I'm the spare. Her back-up mum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1546fe4cb3da574ab3d824be96796e2</guid></item><item><title>England trio Ben Stokes, Mark Wood and Jamie Smith spotted riding e-scooters without helmets in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/ben-stokes-mark-wood-e-scooter-helmet-ashes-brisbane/106093396</link><description>England captain Ben Stokes and several teammates have been spotted in Brisbane riding e-scooters without helmets ahead of the second Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e531e16cc6680cfd8f1ac1f9e02d56a6</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja ruled out of Brisbane Test following back injury, Travis Head set to open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/usman-khawaja-ruled-out-of-second-ashes-test/106093584</link><description>Australia will be without veteran opener Usman Khawaja for the second Ashes Test after the 38-year old was ruled out due to an ongoing back problem.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a1c846f0714bb58803e3567a30b23ba</guid></item><item><title>Ravensthorpe deputy shire president Mark Mudie killed in West River fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/mark-mudie-identified-as-farmer-killed-in-ravensthorpe-fire/106093572</link><description>A farmer who died trying to stop a "treacherous" fire from destroying his family's property in WA's south is identified as the local town's deputy shire president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dfdce37dfe29ffa7c1ef121ff7ef626</guid></item><item><title>ACT legislates commitment for public servants to uphold 'Closing the Gap principle' in Australian first</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/act-public-servant-closing-gap-indigenous-legislate-commitment/106091888</link><description>Senior ACT public servants will soon be required to demonstrate their work towards ending the inequality experienced by First Nations people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af7a065344a40a39d176be504d2ce31d</guid></item><item><title>WA Electoral Commissioner Robert Kennedy resigns months after problem-plagued state election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-02/wa-electoral-commissioner-robert-kennedy-commissioner-resigns/106089050</link><description>Robert Kennedy tends his resignation as WA electoral commissioner, nine months after a state election that was plagued by issues including long wait-times to vote, and polling booths running out of ballot papers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5a23699dbf53954a7f09c02f3f4b243</guid></item><item><title>End to war in Ukraine 'no closer' after US-Russia talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/vladimir-putin-claims-troops-have-claimed-pokrovsk/106094222</link><description>The Kremlin says a resolution to the war in Ukraine is "no closer" after a meeting between Russian President Vladimir Putin and two of Donald Trump's most powerful envoys.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca379091cc2018c9a36a685965f31c18</guid></item><item><title>MPs to probe Crown Estate property portfolio after Mountbatten-Windsor lease revelations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/uk-mps-launch-iry-into-royal-family-living-arrangements/106094472</link><description>MPs in the United Kingdom will investigate the Crown Estate, after revelations Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor — Queen Elizabeth II's second son — had not paid rent for two decades sparked outrage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed1f0ba27870114eb8ee59c7195642e</guid></item><item><title>Today in history, December 3: Bhopal gas leak kills thousands in world's worst industrial accident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/today-in-history-december-3-bhopal-gas-leak/106093592</link><description>It started with a cloud of gas in the dead of night, silently submerging the city in a toxic soup. By morning on December 3, 1984, an Indian city awoke to a nightmare.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4280e0510d23f178779fc6ecddfd143</guid></item><item><title>Australia's day-night Ashes Test against England comes months after a demolition of West Indies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/australias-last-pink-ball-test-vs-west-indies-before-ashes-gabba/106086436</link><description>The last time Australia played a Test with the pink ball, the brilliance of Mitchell Starc and Scott Boland turned the game into a farce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5dd20d696153407c25f5f8e1f653c6d</guid></item><item><title>Environment Protection Authority to monitor Ballarat Gold Mine amid air pollution concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/epa-to-install-air-monitoring-around-ballarat-goldmine/106085894</link><description>Ballarat Gold Mine has exceeded national standards for potentially dangerous air pollutants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00ab53f890c0252369ba784309b97b47</guid></item><item><title>Proton therapy cancer unit debacle leads to $US32 million lawsuit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/proton-therapy-cancer-unit-debacle-leads-to-lawsuit/106086490</link><description>Seven years ago, cancer patients forced to travel overseas for proton therapy were promised an Australian-based service — but the project collapsed last year and is now at the centre of a multi-million-dollar lawsuit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4379600a0cb036bfe0cb2477eb40c199</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police response to Lindy Lucena's fatal bashing to be probed by watchdog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/nsw-police-lindy-lucena-death-response-lecc/106089740</link><description>The independent body in charge of overseeing NSW Police misconduct allegations will today probe the response to Lindy Lucena's fatal bashing in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">468b73bc326c3abbe5f7504306182bdf</guid></item><item><title>Backpackers and PALM scheme workers scrambling for jobs after Dicky Bill shutdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/dicky-bill-salad-farm-palm-backpacker-workers-job-cuts-fallout/105904136</link><description>Backpackers and PALM workers in Victoria and Queensland are looking for new jobs following the shock shutdown of Dicky Bill Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf4eb77536db2f9d0a984bd48d36f40f</guid></item><item><title>WA Police Arson Squad pinpoint ignition point of Geraldton bushfire that destroyed home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/police-ramp-up-investigation-into-cause-of-geraldton-bushfire/106091594</link><description>Police offer up a $25,000 reward as they try to determine the cause of a blaze that tore through 160 hectares of land, left two homes uninhabitable and completely destroyed another in Geraldton.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1b96b9911ad77f33d43269bf9e5431f</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr praised in Matildas return as Australia beats New Zealand 2-0</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/matildas-vs-new-zealand-sam-kerr-enjoys-strong-return/106094810</link><description>Sam Kerr makes her long-awaited return to the Matildas on home soil as Australia downs New Zealand 2-0.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dedce6582c53151e0b3481c017949b9</guid></item><item><title>Sabrina Carpenter slams White House for using her music in ICE video</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/sabrina-carpenter-slams-white-house-donald-trump-for-using-music/106094936</link><description>Two-time Grammy winner Sabrina Carpenter slams the White House for using her song in a social media post about ICE raids, telling the Trump administration to never involve her in its "inhumane agenda".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8f7bdbb2cd0918ab4dc555b58041df2</guid></item><item><title>Hopes remain for return of eagles to relocated nest at Bundaberg Hospital site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/wedge-tailed-eagle-nest-relocation-bundaberg-hospital/106091190</link><description>A wedge-tailed eagle's nest was moved in an operation costing about $100,000 involving a 60-tonne crane, a specialist arborist and a carefully engineered basket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44f4ee129a4a56a8978a10e15f65edcf</guid></item><item><title>Peter Scammell charged with murder, extradited over 2020 death of nurse Katrina Hawker in Palmerston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/peter-scammell-charged-with-murder-over-katrina-hawker-death/106095606</link><description>A 44-year-old man has been charged with murder over the death of his partner near Darwin, and has been extradited from Victoria ahead of his first appearance in the Darwin Local Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5c7039d078e6825087f1be22888c869</guid></item><item><title>Crystal Fabergé egg shatters record, fetching $46m at auction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/crystal-faberg%C3%A9-egg-crafted-for-russian-royalty-shatters-record/106095312</link><description>The Winter Egg is made from finely carved rock crystal, covered in a delicate snowflake motif wrought in platinum with 4,500 tiny diamonds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa8c9f575b3950461f5671df857d7dd8</guid></item><item><title>Council says warnings ignored about tree removal in Central West Orana REZ</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/renewable-tree-destruction-council-criticism/106091996</link><description>The NSW government is being accused of wilfully ignoring warnings about the destruction of hundreds of native trees as part of a renewables project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c96e7e487df6855f57961c9b19f8335</guid></item><item><title>Hugh Jackman and Kate Hudson surprise patrons with impromptu performance at Aussie pub in NYC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/hugh-jackman-kate-hudson-old-mates-pub-sweet-caroline/106095716</link><description>Hugh Jackman sung the crowd-pleaser Sweet Caroline and even climbed onto the top of the bar counter for the performance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b533f89ca790e766808a38268893eac8</guid></item><item><title>What time does the Gabba Test start? How to watch the Ashes, and Brisbane weather forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/ashes-2025-what-time-does-the-gabba-test-start/106095876</link><description>The second Ashes Test is upon us and we have fingers crossed it will last more than two days. Here's everything you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5877ff31536d915fc1044634dafee1f7</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins eyeing early return from injury in Gabba Test with Josh Inglis poised for Ashes debut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/josh-inglis-pat-cummins-ashes-brisbane-gabba/106096640</link><description>Australian skipper Pat Cummins is pushing for an early return from injury in the second Test in Brisbane while Josh Inglis will be making his Ashes debut.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17fed6f87907ecb612b4497bead483e4</guid></item><item><title>What happened to Lisa Lynn? The untold story of Greg Lynn's first marriage and his wife's sudden death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/unravel-huntsman-what-happened-to-lisa-lynn/104591040</link><description>Long before Greg Lynn was convicted of murder in Victoria's High Country, his estranged wife died suddenly at home in Mount Macedon. Now, some of those closest to Lisa Lynn are pushing for the coroner to re-examine her death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d05853d821bab6cebb3660faa1636d5</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann loses appeal against failed rape defamation case as lawyer hints at High Court challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/bruce-lehrmann-loses-appeal-of-finding-raped-brittany-higgins/106096496</link><description>Bruce Lehrmann has lost his appeal against a Federal Court ruling that found on the balance of probabilities he raped his then-colleague Brittany Higgins in 2019.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57e5db8864dc3cc122fbb3a1a6649b13</guid></item><item><title>Michael and Susan Dell donate nearly $10 billion to 'Trump accounts' for children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/michael-susan-dell-donate-billions-for-trump-accounts/106096100</link><description>Tech billionaires Michael and Susan Dell have pledged $US6.25 billion ($9.5 billion) to new investment accounts for children, known as "Trump accounts". Here's how the donation will work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19c6ff0ac176fa53ecaa5d9c7090a492</guid></item><item><title>Is it better to sleep naked or wear pyjamas in summer?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/is-it-better-to-sleep-naked-or-wear-pyjamas/106022700</link><description>What you wear to bed can affect the quality of your sleep. And if that's nothing at all, there are a few things to consider.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d379ee8e077de4c450e19dbddaa8427</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's local and state governments to pay $650,000 for Foo Fighters concert in Launceston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/tas-to-pay-650000-for-foo-fighters-concert-in-launceston/106096094</link><description>Tasmania's "biggest concert ever" will take place at Launceston's York Park next month when American rock band Foo Fighters play their only Australian show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf968a5fd5a8aa81d76d97a55f862ebd</guid></item><item><title>First community-designed, culture-led home from new outback housing initiative arrives in Tennant Creek</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/tennant-creek-first-wilya-janta-culture-led-homes-arrives/106090624</link><description>A one-of-a-kind home, designed with the input of Tennant Creek families, has rolled up the Stuart Highway from Adelaide on a convoy of trucks. It is part of a new initiative aiming to transform housing in remote First Nations communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1245d00b9a5564e52777b7a81c103d3</guid></item><item><title>Footballer sacked, youth worker charged after 'last-minute' intel leads to drug drop police sting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/footballer-youth-worker-drug-bust/106097862</link><description>A regional Victorian footballer and youth worker are facing drug trafficking charges after being caught with a package allegedly containing illegal drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38e52f4cb62113f362aec8387ad7abe5</guid></item><item><title>EU's former diplomat Federica Mogherini charged in 'fraud and corruption' probe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/eu-ex-top-diplomat-charged-in-fraud-and-corruption-probe/106099332</link><description>European prosecutors are investigating suspicions of fraud related to an EU-funded training scheme for junior diplomats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe2677ea1ef8a2a94c50f327b533b3e3</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Barnes: The story behind Working Class Man and his American dream</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/jimmy-barnes-working-class-man-interview-40-years/106088240</link><description>Cold Chisel was over. America beckoned. And Jimmy Barnes was terrified. This is the story of the album that made him, and the song that saved him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6b683513940f3ea59d642826a0e9d3f</guid></item><item><title>Spotify Wrapped 2025: Bad Bunny takes global top artist spot for fourth time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/spotify-wrapped-2025-bad-bunny-takes-top-spot-wiggles-australia/106098954</link><description>Spotify Wrapped is back for 2025, with Bad Bunny taking the top spot for global artist for a fourth time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">486a29b95aff8226e12fcecbb0acc59a</guid></item><item><title>Here is what we know about the Russia–Ukraine war peace negotiations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/russia-ukraine-war-peace-process-explainer/106099444</link><description>After a flurry of meetings, Russia's war in Ukraine continues. So where is the peace process at?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fabbc5ddcf3b15095a8b38c8f4e310c9</guid></item><item><title>NSW council votes to stop flying Indigenous flags and enforce permissions for Welcome to Country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/aboriginal-torres-strait-islander-flags-federation-council/106090716</link><description>A mayor in southern NSW says removing the Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander flags from council meeting chambers will "promote civic neutrality".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26969c1b10c251548facab2ddd0db10b</guid></item><item><title>Australia's teen social media ban has unofficially begun. Here's what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/when-is-the-teen-social-media-ban-what-apps-are-banned/106086152</link><description>December 4 marked the unofficial start of the teen social media ban. Here's everything you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92055cd8f8b6664d761c0582f88b1c76</guid></item><item><title>New images of Jeffrey Epstein's island released as Ghislaine Maxwell flags bid for freedom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/new-images-of-jeffrey-epsteins-house-released-by-us-democrats/106099494</link><description>Democrats say the newly released images provide a "harrowing look" into Jeffrey Epstein's world, as the late sex offender's jailed accomplice, Ghislaine Maxwell, informs a court she is planning to challenge her imprisonment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bead4755722543864d2ef9ed0c63a927</guid></item><item><title>Superstar Twiggy on the documentary of her storied life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/twiggy-interview-sadie-frost-documentary/106085568</link><description>For the first time, the much-loved English model, actress and singer tells her own story in a new documentary by Sadie Frost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69ede7f405562c37563819191cd8818e</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast beaches eroded by Cyclone Alfred all open in time for summer holidays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/gold-coast-beaches-reopen-after-cyclone-alfred/106097888</link><description>Severe erosion caused by Cyclone Alfred forced the closure of several beaches in March. Now, extra lifeguards are being recruited as they anticipate a busy summer period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edb25a2af80d5486baec7f99c79a78d6</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith says adaptability is Australia's focus heading into the second Ashes Test at the Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/steve-smith-on-adaptability-heading-into-second-ashes-test/106099612</link><description>Steve Smith reveals the mindset Australia is taking into the second Test as the Aussies look to go up 2–0 in the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10898752092de46072fa6e796c3eda38</guid></item><item><title>Homegrown trainee Darrenia Carr helps fill recruitment gap in Tennant Creek art centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/barkly-regional-arts-training-filling-recruitment-gap-locally/106086734</link><description>An apprenticeship program in a remote Northern Territory town is helping businesses find skilled workers by connecting homegrown teens to local employment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10c61922907728d9fe670f60ee92389d</guid></item><item><title>Aged home care package changes set off cash conflict between providers and suppliers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/home-care-package-kickbacks-row-between-providers-suppliers/106095962</link><description>Care providers are trying to strongarm cash from suppliers of equipment, including wheelchairs, a month after the federal government reformed home care packages for senior Australians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e55de2b95201e71f552d7c77f3667f03</guid></item><item><title>Fourth person arrested over Elizabeth shopping centre stabbing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/fourth-person-arrested-over-adelaide-shopping-centre-stabbing/106099642</link><description>The Elizabeth City Centre shopping centre was placed in lockdown with shoppers evacuated on Friday afternoon after an alleged fight that left two males with "critical" and "life-threatening" injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04ddca072ad4913507344368ab7a9e28</guid></item><item><title>EU proposes using frozen Russian assets as repatriation loans for Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/eu-proposes-using-frozen-russian-assets-to-fund-ukraine/106099644</link><description>Belgium is pushing back on a European proposal to use frozen Russian assets to help financially support Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f98f0c5dfb0cd5838b63eb26c196931</guid></item><item><title>Risk of 'imminent' RBA rate hike rising, as Australian dollar moves above 66 US cents — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-december-4/106099782</link><description>A leading economist says the "risk" of an "imminent" RBA interest rate hike is "rising", while former treasurer Peter Costello is urging Australia to arrest its fertility downturn.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b017f58b6f90dbd3804789d973fb3d6a</guid></item><item><title>Increasing wait times for mammograms could have 'potentially tragic' consequences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/up-to-nine-month-wait-for-diagnostic-mammograms/106092334</link><description>A Medicare funding freeze and high cost of training new students has left a shortage of workers and blown out wait times of critical diagnostic services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">010130b4e8ae7c75d997cc1a3237e030</guid></item><item><title>Remote community in WA's Pilbara saves $400k of food after truck breaks down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/remote-community-rescues-400k-food-delivery/106090818</link><description>A mammoth effort by community members saves $400,000 worth of food for the Punmu remote community, but the incident reignites the debate about the condition of WA's most remote roads.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">249659075efb94f6e6dac94931adddd3</guid></item><item><title>Pentagon watchdog finds Hegseth's use of Signal posed risk to US personnel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/hegseths-use-of-signal-posed-risk-to-us-personnel/106099946</link><description>A report by the Pentagon watchdog concludes US Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth violated Pentagon policy by using his personal device for official business and recommends better training for all Pentagon officials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cacc57158d03e604c4499ae6ed5e899</guid></item><item><title>Alleged childcare paedophile Joshua Dale Brown hit with more than 80 additional charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/police-more-charges-alleged-childcare-paedophile-joshua-brown/106100140</link><description>Detectives have issued an additional 83 charges against Joshua Dale Brown, a former childcare worker who was charged with more than 70 offences earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e7aa0842c1dc25269edefc994152801</guid></item><item><title>Opal mining to continue on land cut out from new Qld national park, formerly Vergemont Station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/opal-miners-continue-operations-vergemont-station-national-park/106095772</link><description>The Queensland government's purchase of Vergemont Station last year led to months of uncertainty for miners with tenures inside the former cattle station, which is larger than the Australian Capital Territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44d9c36f105074c8a972c2e3b68b1439</guid></item><item><title>Man who allegedly lied about theft of Arnie the dog facing additional charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/arnie-dog-owner-new-charges/106100342</link><description>A man who allegedly misled police over the theft of his vehicle and family pet has been charged with driving offences and obstructing police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a731900e7c083ed6bf6260ace6742a68</guid></item><item><title>Former NT administrator, musician and author Ted Egan dies aged 93</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/ted-egan-former-nt-administrator-musician-dies-aged-93/106100878</link><description>Folk music legend, author and former Northern Territory administrator Ted Egan has died aged 93.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6daba67379b08c7ea64857ac472194c</guid></item><item><title>Steve Cropper, legendary guitarist for Booker T and the MG's, dies aged 84</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/steve-cropper-dies-aged-84/106100460</link><description>Steve Cropper, was best known as the guitarist for Booker T and the MG's, but also co-wrote the classics Green Onions, and In the Midnight Hour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">950d40493d57fa69fd217c90cce415a2</guid></item><item><title>Beer box musician, land rights champion and NT administrator Ted Egan's 'big and generous life'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/remembering-ted-egan-nt-musician-activist-bureaucrat/103438310</link><description>A former Government House occupant and a prolific author and historian, Ted Egan will also be remembered as the man who reinvented the beer box as a musical instrument.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc82942f2340d9245f3388bff950f0b5</guid></item><item><title>SA CFS volunteer sentenced for intentionally starting bushfire near Naracoorte</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/cfs-volunteer-sentenced-for-starting-naracoorte-bushfire/105665876</link><description>An 18-year-old who had been a cadet captain in the Country Fire Service admits deliberately lighting a bushfire near Naracoorte, but mental health conditions lower the sentence he might otherwise have been given.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87abb35d9a810672d5e9e1e2e928fefc</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025 updates: Australia vs England, Joe Root scores century, Mitchell Starc takes six wickets on day one of the second Test in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/ashes-second-test-live-gabba-day-one-australia-vs-england/106100550</link><description>Joe Root scores the first Ashes century of his career on Australian soil, as Mitchell Starc's 6-71 enlivens a thrilling day of Test cricket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15fdeb226de9240e8ee39f29f9f09c88</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian emergency bushfire warning issued for Dolphin Sands, fires at Glenlusk and Levendale downgraded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/emergency-bushfire-warning-for-glenlusk/106101700</link><description>A shack has burnt down in a bushfire in Dolphin Sands on Tasmania's east coast, where a bushfire emergency warning has been issued.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c6572be766632ad3ee22261f3e21e19</guid></item><item><title>E-rideables inquiry calls for wide-ranging changes to WA laws, including tougher penalties against riders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/e-rideables-inquiry-calls-for-wide-ranging-changes-to-wa-laws/106099232</link><description>The WA government is urged to toughen penalties for e-rideable offences and punish retailers who help people modify e-rideables to break the rules, after an inquiry sparked by the death of a Perth father.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">501c1793b4a5caea68b256a6101c51c3</guid></item><item><title>Father of the baby bonus Peter Costello wants falling fertility rate 'back on the agenda'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/peter-costello-urges-government-to-consider-new-baby-bonus/106101512</link><description>With Australia's fertility rate at a new low and concerns about its economic impact on the future, the former treasurer behind the early 2000s baby boom says all options should be on the table to encourage more children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e14be90dc741e2d5d9a3588325c7fb1</guid></item><item><title>Rory McIlroy starts slowly at Australian Open but proves he is the headline act</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/australian-open-golf-round-one-rory-mcilroy-scott-lee/106098186</link><description>Rory McIlroy knows there is room for improvement after his first round at the Australian Open, as the five-time major champion brings spectators flocking to Royal Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fce8aecabd14cc961e8a1a242049c816</guid></item><item><title>Gangster Mejid Hamzy's enemies and 'torture plot' revealed as alleged gangland assassins found not guilty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/mejid-hamzy-murder-trial-verdict/105760778</link><description>Mejid Hamzy's murder sparked Sydney's deadliest gangland war in a generation. For two years what led to his demise has been a secret.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6385b4327704482e20fa6723c3865d76</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian minister censured for withdrawing footy club funding after it attended opposition's media event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/tasmanian-minister-censured-for-withdrawing-footy-club-funding/106102352</link><description>Tasmanian parliamentarians have censured a minister for breaking his word to a local football club after it attended an election campaign media event with the opposition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a50f89df04db440581624e46b075fed5</guid></item><item><title>Jewish leaders attend Adass Israel Synagogue for anniversary of firebombing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/adass-israel-synagogue-firebombing-anniversary/106103130</link><description>Leaders of international Jewish communities have walked through the debris of an Melbourne synagogue a year after it was firebombed as two accused men faced court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bbf6e2a5cc3e407b6c40f01abce177d</guid></item><item><title>Woman dies after dog attack in South Australia's upper Spencer Gulf</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/sa-woman-dies-after-dog-attack-in-whyalla/106103542</link><description>South Australian police say a woman has died after a dog attack at Whyalla in South Australia's upper Spencer Gulf region this afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e53a20862d35b0a6d3d300bb875fefa2</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Nathan Lyon's axing leaves Australia struggling on docile Gabba pitch in second Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/nathan-lyon-axing-second-ashes-test-gabba/106103444</link><description>Australia leaves Nathan Lyon out of its XI for the second Ashes Test at the Gabba, marking an almost 14-year first.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a047be68f52e82cf4da3a71a299e58f</guid></item><item><title>Root notches century despite stunning run-out, non-Starc seamers struggle without Lyon — five quick hits from Ashes second Test day one</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/ashes-second-test-day-one-quick-hits-joe-root-run-out/106101422</link><description>Joe Root overcomes a horror mix-up to notch a long-awaited first Test century in Australia, while Australia's seamers largely struggle without the dropped Nathan Lyon. Here are the quick hits from the first day of the pink-ball Ashes Test in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a24f895f2e6e991ca803f11ce6c93550</guid></item><item><title>Hobart stadium at Macquarie Point gets final approval in parliament's upper house</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/tas-parliament-vote-approves-afl-stadium-for-tasmania/106103886</link><description>A $1.13 billion stadium on the edge of the Hobart CBD has been approved by Tasmania's upper house, satisfying a key condition for the state's AFL licence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c881f50449274ddd97789fe9d382154b</guid></item><item><title>Putin bears 'moral responsibility' for 2018 poisoning of UK woman, inquiry finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/uk-inquiry-findings-woman-2018-novichok-poisoning/106103644</link><description>A UK public inquiry concludes that Russian President Vladimir Putin "must have" ordered the Novichok nerve agent attack on Russian double agent Sergei Skripal in 2018.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ef9cac28206ecd99b86c43edee379e1</guid></item><item><title>Value of private health insurance 'eroding' as doctors urge reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/private-health-insurance-eroding-as-doctors-urge-reform/106095198</link><description>A new report from Australia's peak doctors' body says private health insurance is increasingly failing to deliver value to the roughly 15 million Australians who hold a policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">506ed9de17cafac299e52fb7051726a7</guid></item><item><title>What does Vladimir Putin want from his state visit to India and his meeting with Narendra Modi?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/what-does-vladimir-putin-want-from-state-visit-to-india/106104162</link><description>The Russian leader's first state visit to India in nearly four years is expected to focus heavily on trade amid a backdrop of international sanctions and Donald Trump's tariff policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2dcd3e4e81b1de6f9a515dc5b6adfa8</guid></item><item><title>Israel to compete at Eurovision Song Contest in 2026, prompting several nations to withdraw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/israel-allowed-to-compete-at-eurovision-2026-prompting-boyott/106104460</link><description>Public broadcasters in Spain, Ireland and the Netherlands say they will not participate in next year's event and more are expected to follow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58b2f0f1f947dfe1f049f7fcb63a55d2</guid></item><item><title>The best new TV shows of 2025, from The Golden Bachelor to The Studio</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/best-tv-shows-2025-golden-bachelor-the-studio-wayward/106074292</link><description>From a send-up of Hollywood studios to a chilling depiction of violence and masculinity to an age-appropriate reality TV romance, these are our favourite TV shows of 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e2b633a744ea39e8ec6696aeeafa789</guid></item><item><title>Search engines will soon have to blur porn image results in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/search-engines-will-soon-have-to-blur-porn-image-results/106103600</link><description>Pornographic image results will be blurred and searches for self-harm information will redirect to mental health supports under new Australian online safety codes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d02383c63601660295ab094f6471369</guid></item><item><title>Industrial relations are risky business for the Liberals after WorkChoices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/liberals-industrial-relations-workchoices-unions-labor-workers/106088082</link><description>The Liberals argue Labor's industrial relations concessions to the unions are a "handbrake on productivity" but this area has been tricky for the Coalition since John Howard's disastrous overreach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ec8241dae12cdb6d8eb1b9f8047c34a</guid></item><item><title>Pentagon watchdog releases report on Pete Hegseth's use of Signal app</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/pentagon-inspector-general-releases-pete-hegseth-signal-report/106104450</link><description>The 84-page report finds US Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth violated policy and could have put American troops at risk when he used the Signal app to discuss military strikes in Yemen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b81f7be2d1c07cc10f66b20e47460a7e</guid></item><item><title>The Ashes are kickstarted at last by Mitchell Starc and Joe Root, but Australia's underbelly is tested</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ashes-gabba-day-one-mitchell-starc-joe-root-australia-england/106102778</link><description>A day of tough, fluctuating Test cricket kickstarts the Ashes series at last as Mitchell Starc and Joe Root carry their sides despite concerns about what lies beneath.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">226df8ba60b1cb43029c91d0a941d28d</guid></item><item><title>Manhunt underway in Adelaide for man in cuffs and hospital gown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/police-search-for-man-who-escaped-custody-at-adelaide-hospital/106104514</link><description>Police are looking for a man who escaped custody in a medical gown and handcuffs in Adelaide's western suburbs, and are warning the public not to approach him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2aafddb8873f46e1e153d0e8546074d9</guid></item><item><title>Alex Carey channels AFL pedigree for classic Ashes catch despite Marnus Labuschagne's tackle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/alex-carey-catch-marnus-labuschagne-tackles-ashes-test/106103934</link><description>Alex Carey's phenomenal catch late on day one at the Gabba would have been special all on its own, but it was made even more impressive after he had to "out-body" his own teammate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bc8c0c6309a235dfb1ac59547cac646</guid></item><item><title>ChatGPT's owner OpenAI launches in Australia, partners with NextDC, ASX closes slightly higher — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/asx-markets-business-live-news-dec-5-2025/106104580</link><description>The company that brought AI into household vernacular launched in Australia today. It comes as other companies like Meta are struggling to make traction in this space.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97ffbb609f0db052123663cd504a92ec</guid></item><item><title>Local consortium races to rescue Sanjeev Gupta's Tahmoor mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/local-australian-bid-to-take-over-gupta-tahmoor-mine/106101390</link><description>A local consortium is rushing to put forward a bid for the mothballed Tahmoor coal mine, saying it wants the site reopened quickly to protect hundreds of jobs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ce422c06fcba8101b36e09ceeebfef2</guid></item><item><title>Pentagon's AUKUS review finds areas to put nuclear submarine pact on 'strongest possible footing'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/aukus-review-pentagon-donald-trump-administration/105588512</link><description>The review has "identified opportunities to put AUKUS on the strongest possible footing", the Pentagon says. But a congressman who has seen the report says it "fully endorses" the pact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b23bce599e6ebbcf46142e953f6505eb</guid></item><item><title>Diners and commercial fishers to feel impact of WA demersal fishing ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/demersal-fishing-ban-impacts-food-security/106100994</link><description>New fishing rules come into effect in Western Australia next month, significantly reducing the amount of local fish available in the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cae795942ae953d26eb78b05cc38240</guid></item><item><title>Zak Crawley says Nathan Lyon being dropped for second Ashes Test helped him find rhythm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ashes-2025-zak-crawley-on-nathan-lyon-being-dropped/106104822</link><description>Nathan Lyon speaks during an awkward TV interview as Zak Crawley says the spinner's omission helped the English batter find his rhythm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b8bb53a79743035f3a5a726208ac768</guid></item><item><title>Dozens of property damaged in Dolphin Sands bushfire on Tasmania's east coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/bushfire-dolphin-sands-tasmania-december-2025/106104816</link><description>There has been damage to at least 19 homes and shacks and 15 outbuildings at Dolphin Sands, on Tasmania's east coast, firefighters say, with residents told it is not yet safe to return.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7018dcf6e1fc46582fd14533b113bf14</guid></item><item><title>Country Hour reporters join listeners to celebrate 80 years of broadcasting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/country-hour-reporters-celebrate-80-years/106100556</link><description>Outside broadcasts highlight how the Country Hour connects with the daily life of rural Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd8300d14f1560b08c0a000ab75472dd</guid></item><item><title>Police on scene at Gregory Hills shopping centre after shots fired at man outside gym</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/gregory-hills-shooting-world-gym-police/106105080</link><description>Police swam on a shopping centre in south-western Sydney after a man narrowly avoided injury after being shot at.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">002f2252717f793570a5b82a7a052a78</guid></item><item><title>Fires, heatwaves strike across Australia with emergency warnings issued — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/heatwaves-fires-live-blog-december-5/106105352</link><description>A broad heatwave is expected to spread across Australia, with short and sharp bursts of heat throughout the southern states.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8394bee0a73b0d19791eaed9f5db0d97</guid></item><item><title>The queen of New Years Eve Casey Donovan sings This Is Me</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/the-queen-of-new-years-eve-casey-donovan-sings-this-is-me/106105632</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcf96ae53b875516a2c7a967dc73deb4</guid></item><item><title>Police say targeted search for alleged killer Dezi Freeman focused on finding his body</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/dezi-freeman-alleged-police-killer-search-victoria/106105844</link><description>Victoria Police says a targeted search has focused on locating evidence or the body of fugitive Dezi Freeman, four months after he allegedly fatally shot two police officers in Porepunkah, in north-east Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f0a9a0e7171f62c56e9dd1af0b1ccac</guid></item><item><title>All five members of 90s British boy band FIVE are back on tour after 25 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/all-five-members-of-90s-british-boy-band-/106104714</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f48d62d059c34e462424b61a1fc84b9c</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberal leader Vincent Tarzia steps down from leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/sa-opposition-leader-vincent-tarzia-steps-down/106106170</link><description>South Australian Liberal leader Vincent Tarzia will step down from the leadership, just three months out from the next state election. He told a press conference he made the decision on Friday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dc8becab9dacb49fbc7be525b654f96</guid></item><item><title>Homicide investigation launched after man killed in 'targeted attack' at Slacks Creek in Logan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/qld-man-dies-after-targeted-attack-shooting-slacks-creek-logan/106105316</link><description>Police say the 41-year-old man was transported to hospital in a life-threatening condition and was declared dead on arrival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b75a3cdba21b182c4d649367eb4c08a3</guid></item><item><title>Family lose holiday home on Tasmania's east coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/shack-burns-down-at-dolphin-sands/106106584</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3cc12f6bf2ae6e87004a5755378d72b</guid></item><item><title>Ayers Rock Resort to be sold to American-owned tourism company</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ayers-rock-resort-being-sold-ilsc-to-us-company-journey-beyond/105867822</link><description>A deal for the sale of operations at Ayers Rock Resort, near Uluru, and the Mossman Gorge Cultural Centre, in Far North Queensland, is one step closer after the Indigenous Land and Sea Corporation reached an agreement with Journey Beyond, an Australian-based "experiential tourism" company owned by an American private equity firm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6ef1a0f06a4be580e3676b070b7bf86</guid></item><item><title>Victorian government defers increases to controversial emergency services levy in budget update</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/budget-update-victorian-government-jaclyn-symes-emergency-levy/106105012</link><description>The Victorian government has backed down on key parts of an unpopular tax used to fund the state's emergency services as part of its budget update.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a670b1f6d27efba52dc3ec8d3455fb1</guid></item><item><title>Will a controversial water plan lead to 'bad years' for Roper River barramundi?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/nt-roper-river-fish-barramundi-sawfish-bad-years/106096762</link><description>Documents obtained under Freedom of Information laws have revealed planned water extraction from the aquifer that feeds the Northern Territory's Roper River could lead to "bad years" for its fish populations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d7bb7831b65908d859d05539c687390</guid></item><item><title>Hot air spreading across the country.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/hot-air-spreading-across-the-country-/106107736</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ca8f455d8b3f69e9fad34fd4a337e08</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025 updates: Australia leads wasteful England by 44 runs on day two at the Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ashes-live-second-test-australia-vs-england-at-the-gabba/106105310</link><description>Will Jacks took a sensational catch, but England dropped five other chances as Australia builds a first innings lead on day two of the second Test Ashes Test at the Gabba.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e9db51099b8654b3d2221d2afdcbfc5</guid></item><item><title>Israel's continued participation in Eurovision the latest in a string of contentious moments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/israel-eurovision-participation-latest-contentious-moments/106105888</link><description>Eurovision strives to put pop before politics, but it has repeatedly become embroiled in world events, particularly relating to Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9071735fa8336d50847413c7c5e2c13b</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested after alleged hit and run in Melbourne's east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/man-arrested-alleged-hit-and-run-mooroolbark/106104626</link><description>A man has handed himself into police after a 28-year-old Lilydale man died following an alleged fatal hit and run in Mooroolbark on Friday morning</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5696eaa421c4aa4f66160a459042eb0a</guid></item><item><title>Chevron invests $3b to continue development of the Gorgon gas project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/chevron-to-continue-development-of-the-gorgon-gas-project/106105984</link><description>The works will connect gas fields in the Greater Gorgon Area to existing infrastructure on Barrow Island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6605d42224c13ea286e827760abcd918</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's greyhound ban passes parliament's lower house — here's what happens now</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/greyhound-racing-legislation-passes-house-of-representatives/106090430</link><description>Legislation that lays out the phased approach to ending greyhound racing in Tasmania has passed the state's lower house and will be debated in the upper house next week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8578c44093e5303dbcaeb836bf538099</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106109020</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8322d7a43d0a8d690dd3f63ac6a19b7</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Usman Khawaja's Test future questioned as Travis Head, Jake Weatherald open at Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/usman-khawaja-test-future-ashes-travis-head-jake-weatherald/106107710</link><description>After another slashing partnership between openers Travis Head and Jake Weatherald, the future of Usman Khawaja in the Test arena appears to be getting murkier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d23b20fc5430b142af6fa84641c3d79a</guid></item><item><title>Rory McIlroy nervously avoids Australian Open cut as Min Woo Lee lights up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/australian-open-mcilroy-avoids-cut-lee-scott-impress/106104592</link><description>Much to the relief of tournament organisers and his legion of fans, Rory McIlroy survives to fight another day at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">924b88f663c80d133e8ff23959c91d46</guid></item><item><title>Cary-Hiroyuki Tagawa, actor who performed in Mortal Kombat, has died at 75</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/cary-hiroyuki-tagawa-died-at-75/106109270</link><description>Tagawa died surrounded by his family in Santa Barbara from complications due to a stroke, according to his manager Margie Weiner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f2505d88563bec72acd402c8981f1fa</guid></item><item><title>Gocs cameo leaves Smith starstruck, England mourns dropped catches, Weatherald winks — five quick hits from Ashes second Test day two</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/ashes-second-test-day-two-gocs-smith-archer-head/106107888</link><description>Steve Smith is starstruck by a surprise cameo, England rues a slew of drops and Jake Weatherald announces his arrival with a wink. Here are the quick hits from the second day of the pink-ball Ashes Test in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fca052ae07b72821a3591793d738cec2</guid></item><item><title>Jacob Elordi, Nicole Kidman, Alison Brie among the 2026 AACTA nominees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/aacta-nominations-2026-jacob-elordi-nicole-kidman/106101160</link><description>Apple Cider Vinegar, a partly fictionalised retelling of accused wellness scammer Belle Gibson's public fall from grace, leads this year's AACTA nominations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95d35035fb82bef329f01389c5ded03f</guid></item><item><title>EU hits Elon Musk's X with $210 million fine for breaching bloc's social media law</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/eu-fines-x-120m-euros-for-breaching-online-content-rules/106109626</link><description>European Union regulators say the breaches of the bloc's digital regulations could leave users exposed to scams and manipulation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5d067a74e0c45efa3f59dd28fad3866</guid></item><item><title>WA Police charge children over Geraldton bushfire that destroyed home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/geraldton-bushfire-police-lay-charges/106109634</link><description>WA Police allege young boys were responsible for lighting a fire in Geraldton last weekend that later reignited and destroyed a home in an outer suburb of the Mid West city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26a6ef4372cdf369a5ed6f71699e208d</guid></item><item><title>Netflix wins deal to buy Warner Bros's film and TV studio and streaming service for $108bn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/netflix-buys-warner-film-and-television-unit/106109630</link><description>The merger will see beloved shows and movies such as The Big Bang Theory, Game of Thrones and The Wizard of Oz join Netflix’s portfolio.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">981ddc6ccc5d007d5023ffd52e9e62d2</guid></item><item><title>Russian manpower challenges Ukraine's technological edge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/russia-ukraine-drones-europe-warfare-technology-weapons/106088044</link><description>When it comes to weaponry, Russia has strength in manpower despite Ukraine's early technological edge while Europe's arms production efforts are running into infrastructure hurdles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1265c860b9aa0cca74479ed0aaf2a6e</guid></item><item><title>Porridge back on the menu as budget pressures grow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/budget-pressures-anika-wells-peter-costello-porridge-senate/106088014</link><description>How does a treasurer tell households the government will no longer continue a $300 energy rebate when it's happy to blow $100,000 on three flights?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9275c262e4575f63a63a407e008ac21</guid></item><item><title>ABC 50/50 quiz: Every question is an even chance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/abc-50-50-quiz-dec-6/106101584</link><description>Every question has only two options: one is right and the other is wrong. You have an even chance of guessing correctly each time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e134f877402d0b2f74af88f6783ca27b</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 6: The day scientists found evidence of water on Mars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/today-in-history-december-6-water-on-mars/106096326</link><description>Scientists said at the time that the flow of water would have filled multiple swimming pools.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">054766de87b60e22cc18569655b05e35</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos to face Paraguay and host country US in 2026 FIFA Men's World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/fifa-world-cup-draw-socceroos-group-stage/106109780</link><description>Australia is set to face the US, Paraguay and a European play-off winner in the initial group stage of next year's FIFA World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cdf0eeb358bb53e53703647d968cc06</guid></item><item><title>Severe heatwave forecast for NSW, with Sydney's west set to reach temperatures in the low 40s</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/severe-heatwave-brings-temperatures-in-40s-to-sydney/106105586</link><description>The first heatwave of the summer will reach its peak across New South Wales today, with temperatures above 40 degrees Celsius likely to span from Western Australia's north-west all the way to Parramatta.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22433392b671827b1270cc100c86190d</guid></item><item><title>Lebanon says it's trying to disarm Hezbollah but fears sparking internal conflict</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/hezbollah-refuses-to-disarm-as-israel-bombs-lebanon/106105328</link><description>Lebanon's government says it is trying to disarm militant group Hezbollah, but there are fears of sparking an internal conflict.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08ff3200b8808497c7b511f7adb8cdda</guid></item><item><title>Senator who backs social media ban says she was a victim of a catfishing attempt in high school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/youngest-senator-reveals-she-was-catfished-online/106107346</link><description>As the social media ban for teens looms, the parliament's most recent senator reveals she knows firsthand the dangers that can confront young people online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36f20c5139f55ad3d007ff21ef249880</guid></item><item><title>Australia delights in a familiar Ashes tale of English woe to take control at the Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/australia-delights-in-a-familar-tale-of-english-woe-at-the-gabba/106109124</link><description>Australia took control of the second Ashes Test at the Gabba on a day that carried plenty of the hallmarks of failed English tours of yesteryear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19c15eaa8e29f069a6d5569366cc2322</guid></item><item><title>Winter athletes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/winter-athletes/106108908</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b59a8867955a0214d05017fcca2dc266</guid></item><item><title>Vladimir Putin offers India 'uninterrupted' fuel supplies at summit in New Delhi with Narendra Modi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/vladimir-putin-offers-india-uninterrupted-fuel-supplies/106109824</link><description>The offer is made at a summit in New Delhi, where new deals on energy, agriculture and labour have also been announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b238a3fa21ca446dc7aa3c074f7c98b</guid></item><item><title>Under deadline, Donald Trump is remaking the White House in his own image</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/donald-trump-is-remaking-the-white-house-in-his-own-image/105552330</link><description>The US president has spent much of his first year back in office changing the historic building he fought to reclaim in a bid to cement his legacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f4b9ceff316e49e4842fbae903137c2</guid></item><item><title>Jai Opetaia vs Hüseyin Cinkara, IBF and the Ring world cruiserweight, how to watch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/jai-opetaia-husseyn-cinkara-cruiserweight-how-to-watch/106107668</link><description>Jai Opetaia may feel that fighting Hüseyin Cinkara is beneath him as he continues to hunt for a unification fight. But he cannot afford any lapses against a powerful puncher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23ef174dc6cc95e7c1e06f1c4e4082d3</guid></item><item><title>It's been a tumultuous time for SA's Liberals — they now need to find another new leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/sa-liberal-party-new-leader-analysis/106108800</link><description>SA Liberal leader Vincent Tarzia has stepped down. Pressure had been mounting in the lead-up to the 2026 state election, and predictions for the Liberal Party's chances are not looking promising.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">712c9410084cf6a74ba0ca3ce24a92a2</guid></item><item><title>BNPB supply drop to remote village in North Sumatra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/bnpb-supply-drop-to-remote-village-in-north-sumatra/106109106</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9079a40c3d67c71d43b9ed7cf3e8e733</guid></item><item><title>Drone vision shows devastation across North Sumatra after landslides and floods.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/drone-vision-of-north-sumatra-after-landslides-and-floods/106108910</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dde3efaae63772ae898bb52cbac35cb1</guid></item><item><title>Efforts turn to helping survivors and recovering the dead after devastating floods in Indonesia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/indonesia-sumatra-floods-landslides-weather-recovery-efforts/106097076</link><description>Landslides across Sumatra in Indonesia have cut off roads and destroyed homes, creating several pockets of isolated villages where a helicopter is the only way in.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a73b3e2b1904da69e708162f515043ac</guid></item><item><title>Sexism, harassment and inflexibility drive women out of winemaking, survey reveals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/sexism-harassment-driving-women-out-of-winemaking/106092352</link><description>Among the main factors contributing to women leaving Australia's wine industry were sexism, discrimination, and a lack of flexibility, a nationwide study has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">094e243fb1468c4e673b13fdb1a2a964</guid></item><item><title>Australian Christmas in full bloom as flora and fauna burst with colour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/christmas-flora-and-fauna/106105702</link><description>As the summer heat settles in, flora and fauna associated with Christmas in Australia can be spotted throughout the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f8a1842054bfafbb5f4f2081770f575</guid></item><item><title>State Theatre's new name speaks to the philanthropy predicament in the arts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/arts-funding-philanthropy-melbourne-state-theatre-ian-potter/106088052</link><description>No sensible organisation can now afford to turn down money or its requirements. So, cash-strapped institutions find themselves between a rock and a hard place with a big name painted on it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d39e9f43068b001c6ce3e2e947fdcc11</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane community radio station 4ZZZ celebrates 50 years against all odds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/4zzz-brisbane-radio-station-50-years/106101658</link><description>Brisbane community radio station 4ZZZ has withstood political, social and financial pressure for 50 years and it's still thriving as a loud and proud beacon of counterculture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1532fda67974c3d08f8e86892a5ce3e2</guid></item><item><title>Young people urged to join stem cell donor roll with full matches hard to come by</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/stem-cell-donor-campaign-rowan-tong-law/106086354</link><description>Rowan Tong-Law, 18, was diagnosed with acute myeloid leukaemia last year and has been searching for a full stem cell donor match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7619250c0c8fe5a61dbd35854893da66</guid></item><item><title>English teenager Tommy Lamb closing in on 100-day, 21-country overland journey to Adelaide's Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/tommy-lamb-ashes-trip-to-adelaide-manchester/106109176</link><description>Tommy Lamb is taking the long way from Manchester to Adelaide for the third Ashes Test and the 18-year is closing in on a 100-day odyssey that must be seen to be believed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fef5110c9f56da13b3f39f394c0576b0</guid></item><item><title>BOM says 'threshold' for fire weather warning wasn't met ahead of Tasmanian bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/bom-warnings-ahead-of-bushfires-across-tasmania/106105962</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says the initial forecasts did not meet the threshold to trigger fire weather warnings ahead of Thursday when 30 blazes burnt across Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c246f885887b104140d861380f48ad7</guid></item><item><title>Coronial inquest investigates Terry Airey's death at Sunshine Coast University Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/coronial-inquest-investigates-terry-airey-death/106090278</link><description>A Queensland hospital has increased staffing and revamped its radiology protocols and systems following an 87-year-old's death from organ failure after routine surgery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bbe0dfc8c2f6c068198bdae68e0b6d1</guid></item><item><title>Life on the APY Lands where family, country and culture are protected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/apy-lands-culture-lifestyle-protected-but-calls-for-houses-jobs/105999584</link><description>The stark beauty of Australia's protected APY Lands is alive with ancient songlines and culture. But Elders see a need for change to secure the future of today's children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">353653a4d89cd1c2c5636c30029525d0</guid></item><item><title>Notorious child murderer Bevan Spencer von Einem dies in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/murderer-bevan-von-einem-dies-while-serving-life-sentence/106052480</link><description>Convicted killer Bevan Spencer von Einem — who police have linked to "The Family" — has died while serving a life sentence for the sexually motivated abduction and murder of Richard Kelvin in 1983.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f21bf483c5402b57f6074aec904c7897</guid></item><item><title>How this wheelchair basketball Paralympian is helping rewrite the NT's para-sports story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/paralympian-returns-to-wheelchair-basketball-after-25-years/106104752</link><description>When Mellissa Dunn was starting her wheelchair basketball career in Darwin in the 1990s, she felt she had to do everything on her own. Three decades later, the silver-medallist Paralympian says the support now being offered to the next generation of para-athletes is "life-changing".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67d4cc3ac7addcd02e57876f18b5af5a</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri misses first practice at Abu Dhabi Grand Prix, finishes 11th in second session behind Lando Norris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/piastri-struggles-as-norris-leads-abu-dhabi-f1-practice/106109968</link><description>Lando Norris makes the best start of the title contenders in practice at the Abu Dhabi Grand Prix as Oscar Piastri endures a disappointing day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b2daef87913249292dfa8fdb35ccd6e</guid></item><item><title>Frank Gehry, world-renowned architect who designed the Guggenheim Museum Bilbao, dies aged 96</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/frank-gehry-guggenheim-bilbao-dies-aged-96/106109892</link><description>Gehry's most memorable creations were either celebrated as works of genius or reviled as self-indulgent messes — but either way, people were looking, as he liked to say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecfb4aee4144b1097d9f9d29ef26c3fc</guid></item><item><title>Blue whale swimming off Busselton Jetty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/blue-whale-swimming-off-busselton-jetty/106105306</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d10be79b81cc7f5bcfab5c804d73069</guid></item><item><title>Blue whales off Dunsborough</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/cow-and-calf-blue-whale/106106620</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2679d706e21deadabffe76fdbb7dce0</guid></item><item><title>Heatwaves spread across Australia, with emergency warnings issued — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/heatwaves-fire-live-blog-december-6/106109210</link><description>There are several fires in New South Wales as the state battles incoming lightning, forecast for Saturday evening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">638fa1ea058fd88ace4d0dbfe0bf54ce</guid></item><item><title>The National Indigenous Art Triennial in Canberra reflects on legacy, rebirth and renewal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/national-indigenous-art-triennial-after-the-rain-tony-albert/106105020</link><description>Indigenous artists from across Australia, including Alair Pambegan and Grace Kemarre Robinya, feature as part of the National Indigenous Art Triennial in Canberra: After the Rain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">298d22642d30f831c89ee4391ea7cd3c</guid></item><item><title>Up to 16 homes lost in Bulahdelah and Koolewong fires in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/strong-winds-intense-heat-thunderstorms-nsw/106109226</link><description>More than 1,500 firefighters with 300 vehicles were deployed by the RFS across eastern and central NSW amid extreme heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97594e0790a4e0dbae88468a24108d86</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate hikes increasingly likely in 2026 but a major event would produce the opposite result</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/interest-rates-2026/106106712</link><description>Inflation is a problem as 2025 comes to a close and it's set to remain that way. Without a swift rise in productivity or a financial markets meltdown, borrowers are facing several interest rate hikes next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d746d4688a4127389fb3a4b35770ed4</guid></item><item><title>Princess Kate celebrates community work at Christmas service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/princess-kate-celebrates-community-work-at-christmas-servive/106110208</link><description>Heir to the throne, Prince William, was due to deliver a reading before 1,600 guests along with actors Kate Winslet, Chiwetel Ejiofor and Joe Locke, as well as actor and comedian Babatunde Aléshé.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f492efc72b407e5a589182f56473bc91</guid></item><item><title>Woman found dead after three days outside NSW south coast police station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/dead-woman-found-after-three-days-in-nsw-police-station-car-park/106109896</link><description>A critical incident has been declared after a 48-year-old woman's body was found inside a car at a police station car park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcc7ebca49cf528a119c2068018cbe58</guid></item><item><title>An RFS Chinook flies above the Bulahdelah fire on the Mid North Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/rfs-chinook-flies-above-the-bulahdelah-fire/106110314</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dad630d4115bb5b48c742b0992b7287e</guid></item><item><title>Controversial genetically modified mosquito release paused after backlash in Qld</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/controversial-gm-friendly-mosquito-release-paused-csiro-oxitec/106108190</link><description>An organisation that planned to sell "friendly" mosquitoes to reduce the spread of diseases like dengue withdraws its licence application after backlash from scientists and health experts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99c152b0ac25af67c26215182860c9d9</guid></item><item><title>Malaysian football in chaos after FIFA suspends national players from Argentina, Spain and Brazil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/player-naturalisation-scandal-rocks-malaysian-football/106095646</link><description>A football players' union says seven South American and European members of the Malaysian national team suspended over allegedly forged documents are "victims".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4856b0aaec28e11010c2f73e3c63280</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos far from a World Cup 'group of death' against United States, Paraguay and a European qualifier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/socceroos-world-cup-draw-analysis/106110310</link><description>Nothing can be guaranteed in a World Cup, but the Socceroos' draw alongside the United States, Paraguay and a European qualifier gives a solid shot at advancing, with the Australians avoiding most of the big names.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49c5d81bdd2e928aa1bc4fde8d7d5a0b</guid></item><item><title>2025 US National Security Strategy warns Europe faces 'civilisational erasure', does not mention AUKUS</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/trump-warns-europe-faces-civilisational-erasure/106109888</link><description>The Trump administration releases a document saying its goal is to "help Europe correct its current trajectory", adding that it faces "civilisational erasure" due in part to "mass migration".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">031ccdcf7ac49d6c2a4eaf559d9d572f</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025 live updates: Australia building lead over England on day three of second Test at Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/ashes-second-test-live-gabba-day-three-australia-vs-england/106110146</link><description>Scott Boland breaks through after Australia takes a monster 177-run lead into the second innings of the pink ball Test in Brisbane. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d64b4e80361f254db5f9a88be54a499e</guid></item><item><title>Rory McIlroy's Australian Open tilt hindered by discarded banana skin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/australian-open-golf-rory-mcilroy-banana-skin-third-round/106109898</link><description>Inclement weather is not the only challenge Rory McIlroy faced on his way to shooting a three-under-par 68 in the third round of the Australian Open at Royal Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d596c2f754d69973f2ccca4bc0300f50</guid></item><item><title>The gold toilet, the bags of cash and the corruption still stalking Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/latest-corruption-allegations-a-headache-for-zelenskyy/106048496</link><description>Ukraine has a history of corruption issues, but the latest allegations include close confidants of the president and many people want answers from Volodymyr Zelenskyy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">150e0fc94af50740baa09c3494745ca2</guid></item><item><title>At least six houses lost in a fire burning on the Central Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/at-least-six-houses-lost-in-a-fire-burning-on-the-central-coast/106110668</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef38bf9361cae92b1ff587e1d85833e2</guid></item><item><title>Man dies after being trapped under machinery at Fosterville gold mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/man-dies-trapped-under-machiner-fosterville-gold-mine-bendigo/106110510</link><description>An investigation is underway following the death of a 53-year-old man who was trapped under machinery at a gold mine in Central Victoria on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a47abef26d175764503596b08c0f9e50</guid></item><item><title>Critics choice nominations 2026: Sinners scores 17 nods, One Battle After Another earns 14</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/critics-choice-awards-nominations-sinner/106110372</link><description>The gothic vampire period drama Sinners has topped the Critics' Choice Movie Awards, securing 17 nods, followed by One Battle After Another with 14.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a30900a46808c056c75a85fb6601196e</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government to pump $200 million into racing facilities under long-awaited industry plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/qld-government-racing-report-independent-review/106110228</link><description>The Next Lap plan will establish a $200 million infrastructure fund, streamline governance, and maintain taxation levels, and comes about two months after an independent review into the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">546690db480bac34e24c47bb307f1dbf</guid></item><item><title>Escapee back in custody after running from Adelaide hospital, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/escapee-who-prompted-manhunt-back-in-custody-police-say/106110628</link><description>A 36-year-old who prompted a manhunt after allegedly escaping custody at Adelaide's Queen Elizabeth Hospital on Thursday night has been re-arrested and will face court on Monday, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfe9431ed7e5eb9fa6f90cfa81d97c38</guid></item><item><title>Geraldton community raises funds and thanks responders as juveniles charged with alleged arson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/juveniles-charged-with-alleged-arson-following-geraldton-fires/106110454</link><description>While police say the investigation is over, the local community is still trying to move forward from the devastation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4122eb9d5167b06fe6f887df21b32420</guid></item><item><title>Live updates: Jai Opetaia vs Hüseyin Cinkara, cruiserweight world title fight, Jason Moloney claims victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/live-updates-jai-opetaia-vs-huseyin-cinkara-boxing/106109620</link><description>Jai Opetaia defends his IBF and The Ring cruiserweight world titles against Hüseyin Cinkara in a stacked card of boxing on the Gold Coast. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">945a3204a0f94369d635a361f6e6d44f</guid></item><item><title>Teen seriously injured in e-bike crash in Claremont after e-rideables inquiry called for widespread changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/teen-seriously-injured-in-ebike-crash-in-claremont/106110818</link><description>A 14-year-old boy suffers serious injuries in an e-bike crash in Perth's western suburbs, just two days after a parliamentary inquiry into WA's e-rideable laws made 33 recommendations in a bid to make the devices safer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beba62eb0654ea9ca6f7cebcd2e680cf</guid></item></channel></rss>