<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 11:46:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Friends pay tribute to Canadian Piper James after her death at K'gari beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/kgari-beach-death-piper-james-friends-pay-tribute/106256026</link><description>Friends of 19-year-old Canadian woman Piper James pay tribute to a woman who loved adventure and nature.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9391837a6355875001ab3cdb3c15b312</guid></item><item><title>Vietnamese gen Zs reclaim forebears' exploitative history of garment outwork</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/vietnamese-gen-zs-reclaim-exploitative-history-garment-outwork/106231528</link><description>Jennifer Kiều Anh Doan's boutique's focus on independent Vietnamese fashioners is subverting her forebears' experience as exploited garment "outworkers".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43eb499c2808541e3f23edb5653dfc39</guid></item><item><title>Perth financial advisor Anthony Paul Torre jailed for taking more than $1 million from clients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/anthony-paul-torre-jailed-stealing-fraud-1million-from-clients/106255256</link><description>Victims of a Perth financial adviser jailed for misappropriating more than a million dollars from investors say his six-year jail term is not enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d61027d39caaea38c6adc2658d7601e</guid></item><item><title>Forbes man Lawrence Wilfred Norris intends to plead not guilty to historical child sex offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/lawrence-norris-intends-to-plead-not-guilty-child-sex-offences/104852292</link><description>A NSW court hears the former vice-president of a local show society intends to plead not guilty to dozens of historical child sexual assault charges if he is found fit to stand trial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f13bb702d228f8cf1e73d4fef38f24e</guid></item><item><title>Australia's anti-slavery commissioner asks Tony Burke for visa reform after inquest into Jerwin Royupa's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/jerwin-royupa-inquest-training-visa-program-risk-exploitation/106256652</link><description>Australia's anti-slavery commissioner has written to Home Affairs Minister Tony Burke asking for reform on the 407 training visa, following the inquest into the death of Jerwin Royupa.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78c2b89799ced9a7c99a9e0c8149bf9c</guid></item><item><title>Geraldton man found floating off coast after WA police discover empty boat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/missing-boatie-in-geraldton-kenneth-robinson/106258882</link><description>Geraldton police find 61-year-old Kenneth Robinson in the water near Chapman Bay after they discovered his boat unoccupied this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46c8bbc7a43c4a84b2beb0c04bace03d</guid></item><item><title>Two women and man killed in shooting in NSW town, gunman at large</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/lake-cargelligo-shooting-central-west-nsw-police-operation/106258896</link><description>Three people have been shot dead in the Central West town of Lake Cargelligo, with the gunman still at large.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ac8b0eb3a5d60e126006e896390812a</guid></item><item><title>St Vincent's Hospital charged over 2024 death of Makalie Watts-Owen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/melbourne-st-vincents-hospital-worksafe-makalie-watts-owen/106258858</link><description>Makalie Watts-Owen died by suicide while admitted to St Vincent's Hospital's mental health unit, a month before her 24th birthday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">481fed42fae5b1f13529ac9d555f0b95</guid></item><item><title>City of Perth probe lays bare workplace 'crisis', erosion of trust between Mayor and CEO</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/city-of-perth-workplace-behaviour-probe-/106250502</link><description>The City of Perth has rapidly descended into a workplace of psychological harm, according to a secret report obtained by the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64fc50ebb57a43747397b8920642f9ac</guid></item><item><title>From Bone Temple to Oscar hopefuls, here are January's best movies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/what-to-watch-in-cinemas-january/106233164</link><description>Multiple Oscar hopefuls are finally hitting Australian shores this month, as well as the return of zombie franchise 28 Years Later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2272f4f6ef3115ef6805bda843c70c9</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106258766</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e59c5ef1942298829e1214a0c64fd5dc</guid></item><item><title>First LNG cargo from Santos Barossa gas project bound from Darwin to Japan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/nt-first-cargo-lng-santos-barossa-gas-leaves-darwin-for-japan/106258638</link><description>After a series of delays, Santos announces the first gas from its $5.6 billion Barossa project will be shipped from Darwin bound for Japan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd8bba37d4f040d1881712e836830e01</guid></item><item><title>Maddison Inglis wins epic Australian Open second-round match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/australian-open-maddison-inglis-wins-second-round-melbourne/106258820</link><description>With a 10-point tiebreaker to decide her Australian Open fate, Maddison Inglis knew there was only one avenue to victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7da89e4d1adfe1038099cca78fbd4468</guid></item><item><title>Albanese apologies for Bondi Beach terror deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/albanese-apologies-for-bondi-beach-terror-deaths/106259358</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94b82df021fca2826d2b7b9e1c9e2f51</guid></item><item><title>Naomi Osaka apologises for 'disrespectful' post-match comments aimed at Sorana Cirstea after tense Australian Open exchange</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/tennis-naomi-osaka-apologises-sorana-cirstea-aus-open-exchange/106259566</link><description>Naomi Osaka walks back her aggressive retort to a tense handshake between her and second-round opponent Sorana Cirstea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09581ba0cb5ce587403760bbfce3cced</guid></item><item><title>Oscars 2026: Sinners break record with nominations, Jacob Elordi and Rose Byrne receive nods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/oscar-nominations-2026-academy-awards-sinners-jacob-elordi/106259128</link><description>Vampire film Sinners broke the Academy Award record for nominations with 16, while Rose Byrne was recognised for If I had Legs I'd Kick You and Jacob Elordi got a nod for his role in Frankenstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48c475fdedf71590ecb11f7edcbff1a8</guid></item><item><title>Climate change increased the chance of intense Australian heatwave fivefold, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/climate-change-increased-australian-heatwave-january-study/106253192</link><description>A study by World Weather Attribution has analysed temperatures during the intense early January heatwave. It found that what was once a rare event is now happening far more often.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c1638010033b66e55d7fe8893d1a603</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: A political break-up, a fashionable entrance and Macron's aviators</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/weekly-news-quiz-january-23/106258548</link><description>Another week, another quiz. Are you ready to test yourself?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54cbf4b01ab6495cdb58b22385dc9242</guid></item><item><title>The Nationals split shows the foundations of right-wing politics are shifting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/liberals-nationals-split-coalition-right/106257774</link><description>It is impossible to view this week’s events without the broader context of the relationship between the Liberals and the Nationals, how the electoral map is changing and what that means for right-wing politics in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e5d77a30c76d5a35cb630af005cbb89</guid></item><item><title>Questioning your relationship in the new year? You're not alone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/why-the-new-year-exposes-relationship-problems-/106224924</link><description>The fresh start of a new year causes us to reassess many parts of our lives, including relationships. Knowing whether it's time to call it quits or give things more time requires reflection — and support — as our experts explain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a8679e8fb180c317100f0812cb15f67</guid></item><item><title>Australia names second-largest Winter Olympic team in history for 2026 Milan-Cortina Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australia-names-athletes-for-2026-winter-olympics-milan-cortina/106257140</link><description>From five teenagers making their Winter Olympics debut to five-time Olympian and gold medal hopeful Scott James, Australia has named its second-largest team in history for the Milan-Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9364382cbf12d3eab2d2239d3c30bf50</guid></item><item><title>Anger and confusion after Australian courier Sendle collapses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-courier-tech-sendle-collapses/106237380</link><description>The Australian company's customers feel like they have been "ghosted", while investors and shareholders are angry and confused about what happens next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75d4d8cc352fa82cac285f1a0bcac529</guid></item><item><title>Seven-day heatwave to engulf south-east states, raising bushfire danger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/seven-day-heatwave-for-south-east-australian-states/106258360</link><description>South-east states are predicted to bake through a prolonged severe heatwave from Saturday onwards, which has the potential to break all-time temperature records and fuel another round of dangerous bushfires.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e206661f047d7153c78444b4bf38fcc</guid></item><item><title>Fiji police allegedly seize $780m cocaine shipment in drug operation targeting Pacific Ocean 'narco sub'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/fiji-vatia-alleged-cocaine-bust/106252766</link><description>Fijian chiefs reported suspicious activity along their stretch of coastline to law enforcement agencies — which then swooped on an alleged $780 million drug operation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7b65c9bfdd418c9e913eeb19db1490c</guid></item><item><title>Daylesford op shop may permanently close after donation causes bed bug infestation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/daylesford-op-shop-closed-after-bed-bug-donation/106257322</link><description>The future of a Victorian op shop is in doubt after a worker opened a bag containing the stuff of nightmares, leading to the destruction of stock and hefty cleaning bills that may prove to be a deadly financial blow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92343d5a6b3a6f9e91a7d081f2faf352</guid></item><item><title>Gunman wanted over triple shooting could be difficult to find, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/police-search-for-lake-cargelligo-gunman-after-three-shot-dead/106260214</link><description>Police have warned residents in villages neighbouring Lake Cargelligo to remain vigilant after three people were shot dead in a domestic violence attack on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6237034df4c10ee4887c72324b79c0b</guid></item><item><title>David Speirs not entitled to public campaign funding, electoral commission says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/david-speirs-not-entitled-to-campaign-funding-commission-says/106252588</link><description>Former opposition leader David Speirs would "not fulfil the nomination requirements" if he applied to be a candidate at the upcoming state election, the state's electoral commission says, raising significant doubts about his chances of a political comeback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b51d1258f01f889f9ffa8d09f9b01925</guid></item><item><title>Solid start to AI camera trial with rock fisher rescue at one of NSW's deadliest locations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/ai-camera-rescue-rock-fisher-kiama-blowhole/106252572</link><description>Surf Life Saving NSW says the successful rescue of a rock fisher at Kiama Blowhole using two AI-enabled surveillance cameras proves the technology works.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e967a1d1c2cfc39de99b807ffaa9f852</guid></item><item><title>triple j's Hottest 100 of 2025 — when it happens, how to listen and more</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/triple-j-hottest-100-of-2025-date-start-finish-time/106255830</link><description>Australia's favourite music poll is back for another year — here's when it happens and how to listen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1040e2c0baec6105e30c997bf6a0c8f8</guid></item><item><title>Former childcare worker sentenced to community service after pleading guilty to assaulting five-year-old</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/qld-childcare-abuse-court-beenleigh/106257348</link><description>A former Queensland childcare worker who dunked a child in a "muddy" puddle, causing him to hit a toy and injure his face, has been sentenced to 100 hours of community service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19283855a6e721356bc514d5d85a2141</guid></item><item><title>Wawrinka's post-match recovery beer and an 'elite coffee snob' — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-open-2026-quick-hits/106256482</link><description>Madison Keys praises Melbourne coffee, Stan Wawrinka says he deserves a beer and Nick Kyrgios back to racquet throwing ways. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdb19a2b8f7adeb672b77b643c9797c4</guid></item><item><title>Homeschool 'drop-off' groups are booming but some say they are unregulated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/homeschool-drop-off-groups-australia-regulation/106192824</link><description>Education experts say homeschooling's exploding popularity has sparked a growing market of "drop-off" groups.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0ca7121cc29813c44dbfbed385a671b</guid></item><item><title>DNA found in an ancient Colombian skeleton may hold answers to origin of syphilis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/ancient-dna-in-colombian-skeleton-syphilis-finding/106257238</link><description>A previously unknown strain of syphilis bacteria has been discovered in human remains in Colombia, dating back 5,500 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">761f4136bcbedf14e3f88cb864e27b50</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios and Thanasi Kokkinakis lose first round Australian Open men's doubles clash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/special-k-nick-kyrgios-thanasi-kokkinakis-aus-open/106260326</link><description>After playing like "shadows of our former selves", Nick Kyrgios and Thanasi Kokkinakis are out of the Australian Open men's doubles and into an uncertain future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c0855d44f970a7bd97e76435b181e56</guid></item><item><title>ASX slightly up, Aussie dollar hits 15-month high — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/asx-markets-business-live-news-jan23-2026/106260382</link><description>The Australian share market has finished slightly higher after a rally on Wall Street, as investors showed signs of relief a day after US President Donald Trump dropped tariff threats against eight European countries. Look back on our Friday business blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40932dc245b230489389510db47af34d</guid></item><item><title>Woman sentenced for illegal use of pepper spray as NT government looks to make laws permanent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/darwin-woman-sentenced-over-illegal-use-of-oc-spray-nt/106255114</link><description>A Darwin woman is handed a community corrections order for attacking someone with OC spray in a nightclub fight just weeks after the Northern Territory government announced a 12-month trial of the product.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3932d3b6bca7945308a5322d8d1504e</guid></item><item><title>How cool rooms and cold storage work to keep fruit fresh year-round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/cool-rooms-keep-apples-fresh-year-round/106244706</link><description>Apples only grow for three months of the year — but thanks to an ancient technique, that doesn't stop us grabbing one from the grocery store year round.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18d4e3c1e52e7cd899af23bc7bc1ad00</guid></item><item><title>Defiant Sussan Ley downplays Nationals' split, vows to remain leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/defiant-sussan-ley-vows-to-remain-leader/106260460</link><description>The Liberal leader did not speak about the Nationals' decision to terminate the Coalition on yesterday's National Day of Mourning, but on Friday insisted her focus was on the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a7f9d5a8b73b778d178181d0ad4f49c</guid></item><item><title>Japan's demand for Australian table grapes drives export growth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-table-grapes-export-to-japan-demand-rises/106237572</link><description>A rise in demand is making it feasible for some Australian grapes to be on sale in South-East Asia within 48 hours of being dispatched.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7648010b07efe81af52be5bcd7df448c</guid></item><item><title>Canberra woman to face court after allegedly assaulting airline crew member on flight to Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/act-woman-to-face-court-after-alleged-assault-airline-crew/106260556</link><description>Police say the 52-year-old woman "forcibly grabbed the arm and head" of a crew member, causing them minor injuries, as the plane was preparing to take off from Canberra on December 13.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8d313f02dd8a6264c1556516aafe4d5</guid></item><item><title>Oscar nominations 2026: All the snubs, successes and surprises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/oscar-nominations-2026-snubs-successes-surprises/106260530</link><description>Hybrid horror Sinners came up as the big winner in the 98th Academy Award nominations, with Aussie actors also eyeing up gold, and Wicked: For Good wiped off the map.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d761bb2879eaa9851b2172d6c644d374</guid></item><item><title>De Minaur powers through with straight-sets win over Tiafoe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-open-2026-live-sabalenka-alcaraz-de-minaur-osaka/106260854</link><description>Alex de Minaur defeats American Frances Tiafoe in straight sets on Rod Laver Arena after Yulia Putintseva mocks Turkish fans after knocking out qualifier Zeynep Sönmez.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a04cafe18c649afd498aa7f1f3f47fbb</guid></item><item><title>Taylor Fritz pays tribute to 40-year-old Stan Wawrinka ahead of Australian Open match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-open-stan-wawrinka-taylor-fritz-third-round/106261080</link><description>It was meant as a compliment, rather than a show of disrespect, when Taylor Fritz answered a question about Australian Open rival Stan Wawrinka's age.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c2e005d319489a9f8a0eccc72657f11</guid></item><item><title>1,000 cakes and eight complaints: Brisbane picnic event under investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/qld-cake-swap-food-safety/106254312</link><description>An investigation has been launched into a viral Brisbane 'cake swap' event after attendees raised concerns over food safety and hygiene, with cakes reportedly left uncovered in hot weather for hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1e5dc3e8811ac8635e15909c20516d4</guid></item><item><title>ICE officers detain five-year-old Minnesota boy as he arrives home from preschool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/ice-officers-detain-5-year-old-minnesota-boy/106260888</link><description>School officials and the family's lawyer say the boy and his father were taken to a detention facility in Texas, making the boy the fourth student from Minneapolis detained by immigration officers in recent weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f1e66129057f445bb42e4ec7cae6d7</guid></item><item><title>Man allegedly doused Gungahlin Police Station foyer in petrol and lit fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/man-arrested-for-lighting-fire-in-canberra-police-station-foyer/106261084</link><description>Police allege the man entered the station with a jerry can, poured petrol onto the floor and lit it on fire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f76650c41aafda93d65436a756e99021</guid></item><item><title>Illegal dumping creates eyesore and hard work at Sunshine Coast op shops</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/sunshine-coast-op-shops-frustrated-with-illegal-dumping/106247800</link><description>Volunteers say they are tired of "lazy" residents dumping their unwanted goods outside op shops to avoid paying tip fees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">871279b041aa2167b88a4b69d8849176</guid></item><item><title>Lanlan Yang admits to breach of bail after Rolls-Royce crash in Sydney's east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/nsw-lanlan-yang-court-rolls-royce-crash/106261518</link><description>The 23-year-old has sparked curiosity and intrigue among Chinese Australians due to her apparent wealth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b43c3604703b1dd2574a016e52f8ee24</guid></item><item><title>Paris Hilton brings sex tape story to Washington for AI deepfake porn fight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/paris-hilton-returns-to-washington-for-deepfake-porn-fight/106260660</link><description>The party girl turned anti-abuse advocate throws her glamorous celebrity heft behind a push to tackle deepfake pornography.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be3bdab756405b29eee8fe4b96735764</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone warning extended as tropical low edges closer to Kimberley coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/tropical-low-cyclone-kimberley-coast-weekend/106257742</link><description>A tropical cyclone warning has been issued for residents along the far north WA coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40b1ded951323489c7af96436cdb5857</guid></item><item><title>Interstate police reviewing use of force in Kumanjayi White's death in custody in Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/kumanjayi-white-case-update-death-in-custody/106261098</link><description>After resisting calls for an arms-length investigation, NT police are "facilitating" prosecutors' request for an independent review of the arresting officers' use of force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b04ff3a2a2c57cfe96d3912780dbf7f4</guid></item><item><title>US and China sign off on TikTok agreement to avoid ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/us-and-china-sign-off-on-tiktok-agreement-to-avoid-ban/105946464</link><description>Social media giant TikTok reaches a deal for a new joint venture in the United States to avoid being banned for American users. The platform's Beijing-based parent company, ByteDance, will retain a 19.9 per cent stake in the company.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98db492f98dbae94336107116f99f2ec</guid></item><item><title>What Bernard Fanning and Ben Lee's Hottest 100 topping hits tell us about them in 2005</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/ben-lee-bernard-fanning-2005-tea-sympathy-precocious-awake-sleep/106254430</link><description>In 2005, Bernard Fanning and Ben Lee were very different men with very similar struggles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4104fb0576195f6d49333b282b330b1c</guid></item><item><title>Queensland brothers charged by Australian Federal Police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/queensland-brothers-charged-by-australian-federal-police/106260960</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbe8574470d5b56affd5bb91706d698d</guid></item><item><title>Queensland brothers charged with child abuse material offences after US tip-off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/ashley-and-kaden-millard-gladstone-charged-child-abuse-offences/106260552</link><description>Australian Federal Police investigators allege the men accessed child abuse material on social media platforms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b379ecc2a299291d7b0566fdc26d53e</guid></item><item><title>Letter sent to Lakemba Mosque threatening violence on Australia Day investigated by police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/nsw-australia-day-mosque-threat-police-investigation/106260802</link><description>The note, seen by the ABC, incited violence against several groups, including Middle Eastern communities, Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islanders and a number of political figures from Labor, the Greens and "socialists" were also singled out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40a93d7c9c85c5131545560539c3e2e1</guid></item><item><title>Who is the Neo-Nazi who was booed at Hobart's March for Australia rally?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/who-is-neo-nazi-nsn-member-at-hobart-march-for-australia/106243774</link><description>With the organisers of March for Australia rallies saying they "are in no way concerned by the presence" of members of the National Socialist Network, the ABC can confirm a Tasmanian man whose words were too extreme for many in the Hobart crowd is believed to be a leader within the state's Neo-Nazi movement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dd9e1cf44e49a7d888aa48587dc3692</guid></item><item><title>Labor identity Tim Picton remembered at Perth Stadium memorial service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/tim-picton-memorial-service/106255116</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is among political figures and business leaders who travel across the country to pay their respects to Mr Picton.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5d7055f3334cbd3e08a1546f091c39f</guid></item><item><title>Federal Court finds extended Victoria Police stop-and-search declaration was unlawful and invalid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/federal-court-police-designated-area-designation-unlawful/106262240</link><description>The Federal Court has found a Victoria Police move to give officers greater powers in Melbourne's CBD for six months was invalid and unlawful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff906739ce6790b737ba6a47ae4879b9</guid></item><item><title>How to attract native wildlife and birds to your garden</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/how-to-attract-native-wildlife-and-birds-to-your-garden/106042150</link><description>There are simple things we can all do to encourage more native wildlife to our gardens, backyards, balconies and shared spaces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a86ce4b9695adc5a6d1286749a33f7cf</guid></item><item><title>Video of bull shark washed up on Brisbane River bank sparks debate over AI technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/qld-bull-shark-brisbane-river-ai-speculation/106261868</link><description>A video posted to social media of a bull shark washed up in the Brisbane River went viral and prompted speculation that it was AI-generated, but experts say it appears to be legitimate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79cee32b8f5ede448241764cbe5b102e</guid></item><item><title>Former Broome pub manager jailed for six years over rape of staff member</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/broome-pub-manager-stewart-burchell-sentenced/106037710</link><description>Stewart Patrick Burchell is jailed for six years, found guilty by jury trial of raping a staff member and indecently assaulting several others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfd31eca85588a6872ef20bdd2788feb</guid></item><item><title>Sam Welsford wins Tour Down Under stage three, fears for riders with 42C temperatures Saturday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/sam-welsford-wins-tour-down-under-stage-three/106261424</link><description>Sam Welsford claimed a brilliant Tour Down Under stage victory, the seventh of his career, as experts fear for riders ahead of 40-degree Celsius temperatures predicted for Saturday's fourth stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38187f744e5d2eca7d5d7ad509f0a094</guid></item><item><title>Lake Cargelligo residents in shock after three people shot dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/lake-cargelligo-urged-indoors-a-neighbours-recall-gunshots/106260708</link><description>Residents of a remote NSW town of just 1,500 residents have expressed shock at a deadly shooting spree where three people were shot dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d8d66d4d35e438eccff0c1e13a7f7fa</guid></item><item><title>UK government says new passport rules designed with national security in mind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/uk-government-says-new-passport-rules-improve-national-security/106263628</link><description>The requirement for dual British citizens to have a valid UK passport while entering the country would help prevent the arrival of people who present a threat, Australia's British High Commission says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43f832a9617243fb7df73acd79487d61</guid></item><item><title>Friday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/friday-finance-with-david-chau-230126/106263986</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34ec08ab02b049799d6e47323e23bab7</guid></item><item><title>Yulia Putintseva taunts Zeynep Sönmez's Australian Open supporters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-open-yulia-putintseva-zeynep-sonmez-crowd/106263414</link><description>Kazakhstan's Yulia Putintseva happily plays the role of villain following her three-set win over Zeynep Sönmez at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97bc78ebf825d2b6a958edc49355cb10</guid></item><item><title>To Lam wins second term to rule Vietnam through 2030</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/vietnam-to-lam-reelected-second-term-rule-2030/106263924</link><description>Vietnam's leader To Lam has been re-appointed as head of the ruling Communist Party for the next five years, and pledges to turbocharge growth in the export-reliant nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9955cc5f187fbcce22b63cc8db6f3dcd</guid></item><item><title>Lawyers call for Australian investigation into Israeli President Isaac Herzog amid genocide allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/calls-to-probe-israeli-president-isaac-herzog-australia-visit/106263374</link><description>The Australian Centre for International Justice has formally requested a police investigation into Israel's president for alleged incitement to genocide. He is expected to visit to Australia next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79c6b12747235201bc8fcc9a866d9ce4</guid></item><item><title>West Coast Eagles player Tyler Brockman charged with assault after Geraldton fracas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/afl-tyler-brockman-charged-over-geraldton-fight/106264146</link><description>West Coast Eagles player Tyler Brockman is charged with causing grievous bodily harm following an incident in Geraldton in late December.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ec2577e804e9db4e400b95d5de33a53</guid></item><item><title>Fire threat means Tour Down Under stage four loses iconic Willunga Hill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/tour-down-under-loses-willunga-hill-fire-threat/106264208</link><description>Tomorrow's fourth stage of the Tour Down Under has been shortened due to local bushfire threats and forecast temperatures in excess of 40 degrees Celsius.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dab1bf69dcea4fc7cf309f12ab43d0ee</guid></item><item><title>Jake Fenner sentenced to three years in prison over father's death in Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/jake-fenner-sentenced-for-death-of-father-nt-supreme-court/106252140</link><description>Jake Fenner, 32, has been handed a partially suspended sentence for causing the death of his father at their Moil home in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab2c8bc6fdb3610ca213e6d4be73e833</guid></item><item><title>Drowning most likely cause of death of Canadian backpacker Piper James on K'gari, coroner says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/canadian-teen-piper-james-likely-died-from-drowning-on-kgari/106256020</link><description>A preliminary report from the Coroners Court of Queensland finds that while Piper James was bitten by dingoes before she died on K'gari, drowning is the most likely cause of death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12168408beb719f457f5902194785958</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith delivers again as Sixers down Hurricanes to cruise into BBL decider</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/steve-smith-fires-sydney-sixers-into-bbl-final/106264300</link><description>Steve Smith top scores for the fifth time in as many innings as the Sixers down the Hurricanes to book a place in Sunday's BBL decider in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e348c53fcfa7f88f916aeae4be93ff8</guid></item><item><title>Hottest 100 quiz: How well do you remember past countdowns?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/hottest-100-history-quiz-triple-j/106237066</link><description>While you wait to hear who is number one this year, test your memory of past Hottest 100 countdowns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">355a47b8d47ae7693d3035362c3c91a4</guid></item><item><title>As Russia's war intensifies Europe is exploring military and economic independence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/davos-donald-trump-zelenskyy-russia-war-technology/106252046</link><description>As the world's elite gathered in Davos, European leaders confronted a reality in which they might need to defend themselves, and potentially against, the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">777407f3d912131f903aabe2a0e5650c</guid></item><item><title>From ultimatum to implosion: How the Coalition went its separate ways</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/how-the-coalition-split-played-out/106263654</link><description>Dissecting the implosion of the Coalition and figuring out what comes next has become a full-time vocation for the newly emancipated Liberals and Nationals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f29b55a2c0c1f764650c346e4ccff7cd</guid></item><item><title>Prince Harry takes on the Daily Mail in High Court privacy showdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/prince-harry-duke-sussex-daily-mail-court-case-principle-anger/106261250</link><description>The Duke of Sussex takes on the publisher he believes poisoned his childhood, his marriage, and his peace of mind in a legal battle driven by anger as well as principle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0734b45ec2433eaff1d6c9115bfcbc11</guid></item><item><title>Search for Julian Ingram enters third day following Lake Cargelligo shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/lake-cargelligo-search-resumes-for-gunman-julian-ingram/106262074</link><description>A gunman accused of killing three people and seriously injuring another in New South Wales' Central West may be receiving help to evade authorities, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be92b25778e6ce54592c9759ee196224</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Luana forms into category one system off Kimberley coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/tropical-cyclone-luana-forms-off-kimberley-coast/106257746</link><description>Residents in WA's West Kimberley are being warned to prepare for days of wild weather, with a tropical cyclone forming up off the region's coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25fb2f9c9cb6af9ec15007da7b412fc9</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur driven to prove doubters wrong as Australian Open campaign continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/australian-open-tennis-alex-de-minaur-frances-tiafoe/106264260</link><description>Alex de Minaur is back in familiar territory, on the cusp of the Australian Open quarterfinals, but he is adamant he can make a deeper run at Melbourne Park than his previous appearances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f65a72004cb1c174e578be2ecb878b9b</guid></item><item><title>Australia smash Sri Lanka by nine wickets to stay unbeaten at Under-19s Cricket World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/australia-u19s-result-will-byron-sri-lanka/106264830</link><description>Australia have continued their dominant run through the Under-19s Cricket World Cup with Will Byrom's 5-14 leading the way in a nine-wicket win over Sri Lanka in their final group match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d9de7093079101b37bad476ef784e63</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur's wedding confession and Yulia Putintseva plays the villain — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/australian-open-2026-day-six-quick-hits-putintseva/106261160</link><description>Alex de Minaur has some thoughts on his upcoming wedding with Katie Boulter, while Yulia Putintseva plays the villain on day six. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89847952f8857b2a9bac637c4dd83daa</guid></item><item><title>Australian Neo-Nazis use symbols that may evade hate speech laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/verify-neo-nazi-symbols-explainer/106258068</link><description>Viking symbols and a Norwegian jacket have now become synonymous with Australia's Neo-Nazi groups, but what do they mean?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f2701670a0fb89f719abd3c6cfdc0f4</guid></item><item><title>Track temperatures as heatwave sweeps across continent over Australia Day weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/temperatures-heatwave-tracker-australia-day/106263796</link><description>Use our tracker to keep an eye on temperatures as a heatwave moves across much of the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d78fc3dc49dc4e45663bc0aa841072a</guid></item><item><title>Inside Minnesota, Reverend Ashley Horan is helping people steer clear of ICE agents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/leading-the-fight-against-ice-in-minnesota/106248564</link><description>Reverend Ashley Horan lives one block from where Renee Good was shot and killed and by ICE agents. She and her neighbours have been tracking ICE's movements around Minneapolis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e946a892ab913ccf34bcadc83d433d0f</guid></item><item><title>Worst crown-of-thorns starfish outbreak in decades emerging on Great Barrier Reef</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/crown-of-thorns-starfish-outbreak-great-barrier-reef/106252468</link><description>Scientists are rushing to contain an emerging outbreak of coral-eating crown-of-thorns starfish on the Great Barrier Reef, warning it could be one of the worst in 60 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd5b86f1137da7bacc6ec43d7b35523a</guid></item><item><title>SA heatwave leads to total fire bans, catastrophic conditions and Tour Down Under changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/sa-heatwave-saturday-total-fire-bans-catastrophic-conditions/106262450</link><description>South Australia's hottest weather in six years creates dangerous bushfire conditions, which the head of the Country Fire Service says are "as serious as it gets".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3c13d73d888acbf298fb2981f3b0728</guid></item><item><title>Triggering a heatwave takes more than just temperature — as Australia braces for another</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/what-makes-heatwave-in-australia-explained/105893650</link><description>Yet another major heatwave is sweeping across south-eastern Australia. But what actually triggers the warning? Spoiler alert: hitting 40C is not enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30b4e1477044b893bcbb4f31df0a73b8</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave and fire warnings across south-east Australia as tropical cyclone hits WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/heatwave-south-east-australia-tropical-cyclone-wa/106261940</link><description>Parts of south-east Australia are enduring severe heatwaves with fire warnings in place over the long weekend, as the Bureau of Meteorology issues a tropical cyclone warning for Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29b281821a69a1c26a74706b3f280a03</guid></item><item><title>Majority of NSW beaches shut amid shark attacks to reopen for Australia Day long weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/nsw-beaches-to-reopen-for-australia-day-after-shark-attacks/106261374</link><description>Heatwave conditions and Australia Day long weekend activities are expected to draw crowds back to the water after a dangerous 48 hours on the New South Wales coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b26028194206b86204ce55f677e9d46</guid></item><item><title>Ross River Virus cases quadruple in South Australia in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/ross-river-virus-cases-quadruple-in-south-australia-in-2025/106206394</link><description>There were more than four times the number of Ross River Virus cases in South Australia in 2025 compared to 2024, prompting a new public health awareness campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">700c70d9ba7d34701e727a4888e57afe</guid></item><item><title>How a tank of zebrafish helped two children born with a rare genetic variant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/zebrafish-research-helps-children-with-rare-genetic-variants/106243868</link><description>With a tank of zebrafish, Queensland researcher Jean Giacomotto was able to test a never-before seen genetic variant affecting two babies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4739baaea5242ec7f686f3813e4bb7e1</guid></item><item><title>Future of Canberra's Black Mountain Tower in limbo as Ngunnawal cultural site plans stall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/black-mountain-tower-indigenous-cultural-site-stalled/106263224</link><description>Custodians say they have been excluded from talks between Telstra and the ACT government about plans to develop the iconic tower into a Ngunnawal cultural site.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0308dda5f51e68e7f5117a2dda31603a</guid></item><item><title>Gen Z led the revolution in Bangladesh — can they win the election?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/bangladesh-election-gen-z-revolution-will-they-win/106204040</link><description>After toppling Sheikh Hasina, Bangladesh's newest political party faces its first election next month, testing a newly formed alliance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69dbde527d8d7c5e03110e8208a21381</guid></item><item><title>Range Tennis Club in Toowoomba grows from 12 members to 600 in six years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/range-tennis-club-toowoomba-membership-boom/106254320</link><description>A regional sports club bucks the national trend of declining membership in community sporting groups, serving up a love for the game of tennis that crosses generations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e57db77e02fd9afa2036fca629034c0</guid></item><item><title>Quick and easy pasta with a zesty, no-cook salsa sauce - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/summer-pasta-with-no-cook-salsa-sauce/106254654</link><description>Salsa is not just for tacos. It's the perfect summer pasta sauce and makes the most of juicy summer tomatoes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1362255da12c15379673ce7cc421c41</guid></item><item><title>Chalamet getting fresh for an Oscar, or is his campaign a bit (ping) pongy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/marty-supreme-review-timothee-chalamet/106254190</link><description>Director Josh Safdie's debut solo film has been garnering accolades left and right but isn't quite lead actor Timothée Chalamet's finest work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d8ce71feb87facc97229d5e74b415d7</guid></item><item><title>Play to start earlier at Australian Open as Melbourne braces for a heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/heatwave-australian-open-explainer/106261014</link><description>Play will start earlier on Saturday, with temperatures in Melbourne set to reach 40 degrees Celsius.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fffa174362da9d8d3d2f45a84643da37</guid></item><item><title>Aussie Inglis progresses as Osaka announces shock late withdrawal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/australian-open-2026-live-sinner-djokovic-osaka-inglis/106264358</link><description>Naomi Osaka withdraws from her match against Maddison Inglis shortly before it was due to be played, putting the Australian into the fourth round.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b366d250003b9ec32168a906e200075</guid></item><item><title>Griffith City Council decides flannelette shirts are appropriate business attire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/flannel-shirt-deemed-appropriate-council-meeting-attire/106167948</link><description>Flannelette shirts might not be acceptable in every office, but after a lengthy discussion councillors in one NSW town will be allowed to wear them to meetings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12d9243e708a2d9a043686fbc7b2a38c</guid></item><item><title>FBI releases video of former Olympic snowboarder Ryan Wedding's arrest.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/former-canadian-olympic-snowboarder-ryan-wedding-arrested-by-fbi/106265004</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">437ad517148a36324b6a0188aad66c32</guid></item><item><title>David Connolly's appointment as NT administrator sees a cultural rift widen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/david-connolly-nt-administrator-appointment-cultural-rift-widens/106263574</link><description>The man picked for one of the Northern Territory's most lucrative jobs — which comes with a manor overlooking Darwin Harbour — has drawn controversy before even walking through the gates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a09173cee118657952ceab3bb7d5423</guid></item><item><title>WA government hopes new Perth Film Studios can become epicentre of Australia's screen industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/perth-film-studios-government-and-industry-hopes-for-success/106259442</link><description>Perth's new film studio is almost ready to receive its first production. There’s just one problem – no one has signed up yet. Is that a sign of things to come from a facility the government has sunk millions into?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39e220c614ab3816b31923e158ff07f5</guid></item><item><title>Olivia Dean takes out the #1 spot on the triple j Hottest 100 of 2025 — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/triple-j-hottest-100-2025-live-updates/106256428</link><description>After millions of votes from Australia and around the world, British artist Olivia Dean has topped the triple j Hottest 100 of 2025 with her song, Man I Need.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b1235c93fa1b3b0beabeb92cc471b08</guid></item><item><title>John Williamson takes his final bow at the Tamworth Country Music Festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/john-williamson-last-tamworth-country-music-festival-performance/106260430</link><description>Aussie music legend John Williamson will take the Tamworth Country Music Festival stage for the last time as he steps into retirement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76021075858529b46df379e68b918807</guid></item><item><title>Plume of smoke rises after house fire in Portsea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/plume-of-smoke-rises-after-house-fire-in-portsea/106265082</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">986a243dc4e8c093491f74249d552489</guid></item><item><title>Scientists fear 30pc of critically endangered western ground parrot's habitat lost in bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/endangered-parrot-habitat-destroyed-by-fire/106253522</link><description>Experts estimate 11,000 hectares of core habitat for the critically endangered parrot has been lost to a recent fire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f62310fe6ae66e2033707fb8f3cb0a3f</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos receive major boost as Jackson Irvine returns from injury for St Pauli</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/jackson-irvine-returns-for-st-pauli/106265074</link><description>In welcome news for Socceroos boss Tony Popovic, key Australian midfielder Jackson Irvine has made an early return from injury for St Pauli in the Bundesliga.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">853c1fc9f4dd19feb631e0ba0d3226d2</guid></item><item><title>Inside the program getting more First Nations people into fire and rescue squads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/getting-more-first-nations-people-into-fire-and-rescue/106174194</link><description>For First Nations recruits the path to firefighting is demanding, competitive and often deeply personal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f19bb0c87e87116c9a2998740d63e11c</guid></item><item><title>Fortescue breaks ground on Pilbara's first wind farm in move to decarbonise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/fortescue-begins-construction-on-pilbaras-first-wind-farm/106245178</link><description>A mining company in Western Australia's Pilbara region is one step closer to decarbonising its iron ore production after starting construction on the region's first wind farm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5760d1f6700c62fb3199b3a3d87dbc2f</guid></item><item><title>The Limestone Coast's Little Blue Lake drawing visitors over summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/visitors-flock-to-little-blue-lake-mount-gambier/106206022</link><description>While its younger brother gets much of the shine, the Little Blue Lake is a unique and ancient spectacle in SA's south east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">913f2c4f8d1e642033ae9741fed05184</guid></item><item><title>A generation of activists like Grace Oo are taking up arms against Myanmar's military</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/taking-up-arms-against-myanmar-military/106252216</link><description>As Myanmar's military junta seeks international legitimacy through elections, its brutal repression of the pro-democracy movement is radicalising a new generation of activists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72a427ab5a1dcc938b3234c3d5fc1407</guid></item><item><title>Indra Brown wins X-Games silver on debut ahead of 2026 Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/indra-brown-wins-x-games-silver-superpipe/106265186</link><description>Indra Brown continued her extraordinary form heading into the 2026 Winter Olympics with a silver medal at the X-Games in Aspen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd6223839c26a92699538cad467c82b5</guid></item><item><title>US looks to South Korea to take 'primary responsibility' in monitoring Kim Jong Un and North Korea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/pentagon-north-korea-kim-jong-un-threat-usa-looks-to-south-korea/106265180</link><description>The United States says it intends to play a "more limited" role in deterring nuclear-powered North Korea, shifting the burden of responsibility onto South Korea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d75a773c638178ae047d145130dba1fa</guid></item><item><title>Nico Antic, 12yo boy attacked by shark at Sydney beach, dies in hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/sydney-12yo-shark-attack-victim-nico-antic-dies-in-hospital/106249554</link><description>Nico Antic, the 12-year-old boy who suffered serious leg injuries after being bitten by a shark in Sydney's east has died in hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">474853b08513b0a0e52bb924383d3a16</guid></item><item><title>Jay Vine loses teammates to crashes, Ethan Vernon wins truncated Tour Down Under stage four</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/tour-down-under-stage-four-jay-vine-ethan-vernon/106265046</link><description>Jay Vine loses two teammates on a blistering fourth stage of the Tour Down Under, but retains his overall lead as Ethan Vernon claimed the stage victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a194054d69ff81ec8a8aa2ef3e21fb1</guid></item><item><title>Piper James 'felt so free' on K'gari beach where her body was found</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/piper-james-family-plan-to-return-her-home-to-canada/106265238</link><description>Piper James loved to start her days on K'gari by swimming alone at sunrise. Now her family is planning her final journey home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af4e580ae0cd3a17f831c15dc351d070</guid></item><item><title>Seven dead, 82 missing in Indonesia landslide, agency says, with search and rescue efforts ramped up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/indonesia-landslide-west-bandung-west-java-province/106265558</link><description>The landslide was reported in the West Bandung region of Indonesia's West Java province, according to the nation's agency spokesperson Abdul Muhari.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83eec2673f3c329c50e7714442880bbe</guid></item><item><title>Corpse flower Smellanie at Adelaide Botanic Garden is blooming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/adelaide-botanic-garden-corpse-flower-is-blooming/106265134</link><description>Cheese, fermented cabbage, roadkill – these are how some people have described the smell emitting from a corpse flower that has finally bloomed at the Adelaide Botanic Garden.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63d8e365c23135287ab9f84703b095af</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open matches suspended due to extreme heat at Melbourne Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/australian-open-tennis-extreme-heat-play-suspended-melbourne/106265530</link><description>Extreme heat protocols kick into gear at Melbourne Park, as the stifling weather conditions wreak havoc with the Australian Open tournament's schedule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e3c348c3155bcfa535fe5ebb441d66a</guid></item><item><title>Reports of power outage in parts of Derby as Tropical Cyclone Luana continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/tropical-cyclone-luana-landfall-kimberley/106265140</link><description>Tropical Cyclone Luana edges closer to the Kimberley town of Derby as a category one system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15e65308b1282b1903c0a762c6831687</guid></item><item><title>Jannik Sinner admits he got lucky after surviving Australian Open scare against Eliot Spizzirri</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/australian-open-jannik-sinner-eliot-spizzirri-extreme-heat-rules/106265666</link><description>Had the Australian Open's extreme heat protocols not taken effect, Janik Sinner wonders if he would still be in the tournament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c7186386f575c662a856857fb38637a</guid></item><item><title>Hottest 100 of 2025 - featuring Playlunch, Olivia Dean, Tame Impala and RAYE</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/triple-j-hottest-100-top-ten/106265932</link><description>It's that time again, triple j has counted down the year's Hottest 100 songs as voted by the public, celebrating all the incredible music that soundtracked our lives in 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdc1d7983a23a4037df77daa00502580</guid></item><item><title>Travel-weary Sydney Sixers aim to turn tables on Perth Scorchers in BBL decider</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/sport-bbl-final-preview/106265930</link><description>After a taxing, cross-continental travel journey to Sunday's BBL decider, the Sydney Sixers are set for one final push against the all-conquering Scorchers at Perth Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54b24a18247b60ff4917de5291fb9523</guid></item><item><title>Naomi Osaka withdaws from Australian Open as Maddison Inglis reaches fourth round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/australian-open-naomi-osaka-pulls-out-maddison-inglis/106265922</link><description>Naomi Osaka pulls the pin on her Australian Open campaign, handing Maddison Inglis her first appearance in the fourth round at a major.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fb7807b2427603f13b3317ad60da70f</guid></item><item><title>US-brokered peace talks end without deal as Russia continues Ukraine attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/russia-attacks-ukraine-amid-peace-talks-with-united-states/106266046</link><description>Russian attacks on Ukraine have killed at least one person and wounded 31, as negotiators from both countries and the US met for a second day of peace talks. The meetings ended without a deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aaa528e12dd3aacdb1cad8a2cc6919ce</guid></item><item><title>Golden Guitar success for Kasey Chambers and Shane Nicholson with The Divorce Song</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/golden-guitar-award-winners-2026-tamworth-country-music-festival/106265498</link><description>Kasey Chambers wins three Golden Guitars in Tamworth, including Single and Song of the Year for a track she penned with her ex-husband Shane Nicholson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38596e03b2ac284a1d0fbebfa8f9c827</guid></item><item><title>After a horror week of shark attacks, how do we sift facts from fear?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/horror-week-shark-bites-attack-nsw-facts-fears-risk/106260980</link><description>As a devoted ocean swimmer, I've learned to accept the risk of exploring an ocean that is not my natural habitat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">375df3f5296337c1503d72c1ff87ef64</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, January 25: How Nirvana saved the first Big Day Out in 1992</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/first-big-out-sydney-nirvana-violent-femmes-ken-west-podcast/106250404</link><description>How the first Big Day Out in 1992 turned a risky idea into a landmark moment in Australian music history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7592856fccfe81735e675eb6afd24a6c</guid></item><item><title>Nine self-harm hospitalisations in 12 months after new NT youth justice centre opened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/nt-youth-detention-foi-self-harm-sexual-assault-vandalism/106180656</link><description>Nine youths ended up in hospital after self-harming at Darwin's new $130 million detention centre in the 12 months after it opened, documents released to the ABC under Freedom of Information laws have revealed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1507602bcbebeefc7c1248b80539fa27</guid></item><item><title>From truth-telling to closing the gap, First Nations leaders outline their priorities in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/truth-telling-closing-the-gap-indigenous-affairs-agenda-2026/106260862</link><description>Ahead of the national debate around Indigenous rights and recognition this January 26, the ABC has spoken to First Nations leaders about what they think are the top priorities for Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c23e331bbf8ea07539a3839ef19cbf4</guid></item><item><title>Liberals wait on Hastie-Taylor decision before challenging Sussan Ley's leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/liberals-hastie-taylor-likely-challengers-sussan-ley-leadership/106265762</link><description>Liberal leadership aspirants Andrew Hastie and Angus Taylor are being urged to "sort out" which of them will challenge Sussan Ley for the party's top job before a spill is called.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38227caeb5c6b1e6f7f67ca03bde848a</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic shows his love-hate relationship with Australian tennis fans is like no other</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/novak-djokovic-relationship-aus-open-fans-analysis/106266018</link><description>Novak Djokovic shows once again that his relationship with Australian tennis fans is as complicated as it gets, turning a routine win into a full-blown drama.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0eb61ac860fa8a8e4d8546a429594486</guid></item><item><title>Stan Wawrinka says goodbye with a beer as Jannik Sinner is saved by the sun — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/australian-open-day-seven-quick-hits/106264454</link><description>Stan Wawrinka bowed out from the Australian Open with a tear in his eye and a beer in his hand, while a grumpy Novak Djokovic set an incredible new benchmark. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29c23ec47dd1cef86a3e862e9a472167</guid></item><item><title>Former state care kid calls for fundamental change to fix 'broken' residential care system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/state-care-children-say-system-is-broken-south-australia/106090498</link><description>Residential care is often a last resort for society's most vulnerable children, but being raised by a "system" can leave both physical and emotional scars. It's why those who have gone through it are asking for their voices to be included to reform it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f11503bf6b8a54ccd1a7e5d6836ec3d2</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Will this be the week you nail it? Nah, probably not</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/105682622</link><description>I applaud your repeated attempts to do well at this quiz. Will your desperation pay off?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89fec54edfa9225fdb7d508e1fcc26f6</guid></item><item><title>Australia warned recovering Chinese tourism market may cool in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/tourism-chinese-travel-to-australia-may-cool-in-2026/106253542</link><description>Chinese visitor numbers have increased but are still below pre-pandemic levels, with economists warning ongoing economic uncertainty in China could dampen long-haul travel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ec5f9e3768658cee9097b8de01f520b</guid></item><item><title>Australia Day event Aus Lights on the River cancelled in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/adelaide-australia-day-community-event-cancelled/106265304</link><description>An annual Australia Day event in the Adelaide CBD has been cancelled ahead of potentially the hottest day in six years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeb35a757efe5d8eba2b29ea078269e0</guid></item><item><title>Sydney volunteers break barriers to music, sports events for disability community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/people-with-disability-find-connection-at-gig-buddies-sydney/106237060</link><description>For some, going to a music gig or sporting event alone can be daunting, but a Sydney volunteer program is empowering people with a disability to get out of their comfort zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39bdd1743bb1b0f4d8ecef293ff9d7de</guid></item><item><title>Out-of-control bushfire in Victoria's Otways grows as state faces record temperatures on Tuesday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/victorian-otways-fire-threatens-communities-heatwave/106265690</link><description>An out-of-control bushfire has threatened communities in Victoria's Otways, as heatwave conditions continue in some parts of the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29cf4c2db076445131cac9cd5f11c931</guid></item><item><title>New residents purchase real estate in Barcaldine, attracted by affordable prices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/buying-real-estate-barcaldine-western-queensland/106258330</link><description>From retirees to first home buyers, people are making the most of affordable housing in this outback town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4c2b2111eba794338928c407d7f3966</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Tropical Cyclone Luana downgraded to tropical low after impacting Dampier Peninsula</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/tropical-cyclone-luana-brings-destructive-winds/106265736</link><description>Ex-Tropical Cyclone Luana is downgraded to a tropical low as it continues inland after crossing the northern WA coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cc55225bb75a2d4f30a63e20c1c02af</guid></item><item><title>Mother shares tribute to 15-year-old Max trapped under Mount Maunganui landslide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/nz-landslide-victims-unlikely-to-survive-police-say/106265934</link><description>After two days of holding out hope despite all the odds, the local police superintendent had the heart-wrenching job of announcing that no-one trapped by the landslide at Mount Maunganui could have survived.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16cc801b4de5cb7aa92580629fad34c1</guid></item><item><title>Former Japanese PM Shinzo Abe's killer motivated by 'disgust' at links to Unification Church</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/shinzo-abe-killer-tetsuya-yamagami/106254108</link><description>The man who killed former Japanese prime minister Shinzo Abe thought it was his life's mission to destroy a controversial church.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9f13f005150aef71c839b8510ff63fd</guid></item><item><title>Young victim-survivors say 'shameful' Victorian family violence response causes harm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/young-victim-survivors-family-violence-response-harm-teenagers/106257876</link><description>Young Victorian victim-survivors of family violence say the state government must prioritise their needs so they can leave violent homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a01b6ece4864ecd91957bfd13c47304</guid></item><item><title>Police chief calls for calm after man killed during Minneapolis immigration crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/police-chief-calls-for-calm-after-minneapolis-shooting/106266626</link><description>This is the second fatal shooting involving federal agents this month during a surge in immigration enforcement in the northern US city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31a370c081a2fce290f3572269e98084</guid></item><item><title>Rod Laver’s father built him a backyard tennis court 80 years ago. Now locals are battling to save it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/rod-laver-arena-rockhampton-tennis-courts/106261184</link><description>Like Donald Bradman’s tank stand, the backyard tennis court of Rod Laver’s youth has survived against the odds, but it is yet to be heritage listed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">425a1b86dfad8a1d856e4d776e79ef2e</guid></item><item><title>Meet the change makers nominated to be 2026 Australian of the Year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/meet-the-2026-nominees-for-australian-of-the-year/106245932</link><description>Life-saving underwater amputations, decades of healthcare in refugee camps and fundraising campaigns for Australia's first astronaut – these are just a few of the achievements of the 2026 crop of Australian of the Year nominees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc91c4a8b52d7529cfec5ba10505bf9c</guid></item><item><title>Searching for Celine: How YouTube filmmaker Rob Parsons helped the search for missing tourist Celine Cremer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/filmmaker-rob-parsons-celine-cremer-search/106242088</link><description>Rob Parsons amassed a following on YouTube for his videos of remote gold panning and mineral fossicking. Now, his attention is on the search for missing Belgian tourist Celine Cremer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">521a8c9e5bde3fa9d8b039d08914de68</guid></item><item><title>Moment federal officers shoot man dead in Minneapolis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/moment-federal-officers-shoot-man-dead-in-minneapolis/106266718</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ce9ba5844ff5050cc1492e691204936</guid></item><item><title>Kondoli Dreaming brings Ramindjeri and Ngarrindjeri knowledge to firefighting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/kondoli-dreaming-ramindjeri-ngarrindjeri-firefighting/106219126</link><description>A new fire response vehicle in South Australia's Fleurieu Peninsula has been named after a Dreaming story about a powerful whale man that explores the creation of fire, paying homage to tens of thousands of years of local fire management knowledge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1656ac7a8e7fb47c7bac7e67f6c125a0</guid></item><item><title>Iranian protesters chant for a 'revolution' after years of economic chaos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/iranians-chant-for-a-revolution-amid-economic-chaos-corruption/106262220</link><description>Decades of economic mismanagement and government corruption have widened wealth gaps in Iran, leaving ordinary Iranians calling for a revolution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44fd911d05e4d5c5c0c324b5c4c5510c</guid></item><item><title>How moving overseas changed my shopping habits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/shopping-habits-fashion-moving-overseas/105996352</link><description>Amid all the adventure and growth, I've noticed a surprisingly quiet shift I didn't expect: my relationship with shopping.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">246193d66753b2f67119b594a2a8704e</guid></item><item><title>People involved in Runt movie grappling with how to feel after author Craig Silvey charged</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/york-told-to-stay-positive-after-author-craig-silvey-charged/106256812</link><description>As one of Australia's most renowned authors faces child exploitation material charges, the town where one of his children's books was turned into a motion picture is grappling with the news.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cda3d8a5cb21aaa32a1fe451153b02da</guid></item><item><title>PM says Trump's insult to troops 'not acceptable', as he names Greg Moriarty next ambassador to the US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/greg-moriarty-us-ambassador-rudd/106266786</link><description>Defence department boss Greg Moriarty is named the next ambassador to the United States, as Prime Minister Anthony Albanese criticises the US president's claim that allied troops did not serve on the front lines of Afghanistan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55e8297fd9a084b4a7a18aecf5e07fec</guid></item><item><title>Protests erupt after second deadly shooting by federal agents in Minneapolis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/protests-erupt-after-second-deadly-shooting-by-federal-agents/106266850</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad38aa90c8ea23cba501e99ce6b11ab2</guid></item><item><title>Australia's most popular baby names from 2025 revealed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/what-were-the-top-baby-names-in-australia-2025/106254306</link><description>Abbey wanted a traditional, feminine name for her newborn daughter that would convey strength. Unwittingly, she chose one of the most popular baby names in Australia from 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cfe9454f77a8acac0f46bb2716ef08a</guid></item><item><title>Bangladesh officially withdraws from T20 World Cup as Scotland wins last-minute call-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/scotland-replaces-bangladesh-at-t20-world-cup/106266812</link><description>After weeks of uncertainty, Bangladesh officially withdraws from next month's T20 World Cup due to security concerns, with Scotland called in for the tournament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">189c2faf107b43cfcc1cfdbb76f2c8a7</guid></item><item><title>Live: De Minaur demolishes Bublik to storm into quarterfinal date with Alcaraz</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/australian-open-live-blog-day-eight-results-updates/106266662</link><description>Alex de Minaur obliterates Alexander Bublik in straight sets on Rod Laver Arena, after superstars Aryna Sabalenka and Carlos Alcaraz progressed through to the last eight of the Australian Open. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c3cbe72f16d8fda6572d88173ef6672</guid></item><item><title>Why easing demand for illegal cigarettes will be a win-win situation for WA government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/illegal-cigarette-demand-challenge-for-wa-government/106259170</link><description>Much has been made of how the WA government is trying to stop the supply of illegal cigarettes, but its more difficult challenge is what can be done to ease demand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4455e7789896347bde7302557b8254ff</guid></item><item><title>Prince Harry takes the Daily Mail to the High Court, but some say the result will be a judgement on him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/prince-harry-daily-mail-court-case-begins/106262650</link><description>This week, Prince Harry traded the sunny West Coast for London to give evidence in a "super claim" against the publishers of the Daily Mail and the Mail on Sunday, Associated Newspapers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d87d7e5f971463f94815e6f8aee664c</guid></item><item><title>British dual citizen shares concerns about middleman websites overcharging for passport renewals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/british-passport-fallout-overcharging-middleman/106253650</link><description>As many British-Australian dual nationals grapple with new entry requirements, experts warn of exploitative and middleman websites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97e43718b529a76c13b69c77406b3330</guid></item><item><title>Health warning issued as Melbourne blanketed in smoke from Otways fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/melbourne-blanketed-in-smoke-as-bushfires-burn-in-otways/106266832</link><description>A health warning was issued to Melbourne residents as the city was covered in smoke from a bushfire burning in the Otways, in Victoria's south-west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0db367855914aaa45c945e0cb361fc1</guid></item><item><title>Chinese military's top general investigated for 'suspected serious violations of discipline' as purge targets officials</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/china-military-investigation-zhang-youxia/106266914</link><description>Rumours of a probe swirled last week after military officials Zhang Youxia and Liu Zhenli appeared to miss a meeting chaired by Xi Jinping.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">075ca0d4ae3f70b3ad9a48ecfa4e825a</guid></item><item><title>Sharn Davidson is living with Tourette syndrome and uses dinosaurs to educate others about differences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/sharn-davidson-tourette-syndrome-dinosaur-roar/105083252</link><description>Sharn has two dinosaurs inside her — one is called Kevin and the other Terry. Here's how she handles it when they roar unexpectedly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26a520c7ef67da8b2820dcfa0758bc48</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump praises UK troops as 'brave' warriors after widespread condemnation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/donald-trump-praises-uk-troops-as-brave-warriors/106266908</link><description>The US President has praised British soldiers, after remarks he made earlier this week about NATO troops in Afghanistan were described as "insulting and appalling" by the UK's Prime Minister Keir Starmer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b3bfe0fe5b80ccb5fab58a7fdb9e6a1</guid></item><item><title>Queensland family trades cattle breeding for steak searing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/queensland-family-trades-cattle-breeding-for-steak-searing/106176382</link><description>A Queensland family is trading decades of purebred cattle breeding for life in the kitchen, selling off 20 years of stud work to focus on a new paddock-to-plate restaurant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62a203869abe7b45e4ae4900c04b308c</guid></item><item><title>Police confirm possible sighting of Julian Ingram in Mount Hope after Lake Cargelligo shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/julian-ingram-possible-sighting-at-mt-hope/106266998</link><description>A large-scale search is underway in the Mount Hope district after a possible sighting of the alleged triple murderer overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ccfd0fa14b664d8eddeabb588e0be60</guid></item><item><title>US snowstorm triggers thousands of flight cancellations and power outages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/us-winter-storm-power-outages-thousands-of-flight-cancellations/106267082</link><description>A monster snowstorm is moving across the US, cancelling thousands of flights, knocking out power and snarling major roadways with ice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49bd6af08f652cf14dd4efe6af6657fc</guid></item><item><title>Snow blankets cities as a winter storm hits parts of the US.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/snow-blankets-cities-as-winter-storm-hits-parts-of-us/106267276</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec67ee046cac9dc84cedbee9df846608</guid></item><item><title>Troy Cassar-Daley sings his song at Windradyne's grave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/troy-cassar-daley-windradyne/106258104</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87041a9e9b3fe8a50dc316a44b7ba79e</guid></item><item><title>Country star Troy Cassar-Daley sings home the song of First Nations warrior Windradyne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/windradyne-troy-cassar-daley/106254264</link><description>Country music star Troy Cassar-Daley didn't know anything about First Nations warrior Windradyne. But once he learned more, he was determined to sing his story home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e019e958d71a0cb97a3166892cc5fcb</guid></item><item><title>Self-harm and sexual assaults recorded in first year of new NT youth detention centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/holtze-youth-justice-foi-self-harm-sexual-assault-darwin/106265928</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45c549cfb54e7042d9b24f1a4a52d39b</guid></item><item><title>K'gari dingoes involved in death of Canadian backpacker Piper James euthanased</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/dingoes-involved-in-k-gari-backpacker-death-euthanised/106267322</link><description>Queensland government officials euthanase six dingoes involved in the death of a Canadian backpacker on K'gari, with more to be put down in the coming days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bfa49a34602f1d4686b9473f49d9482</guid></item><item><title>Trump’s geopolitics undermines AI focus at World Economic Forum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/trump-s-geopolitics-undermines-ai-focus-at-world-economic-forum-/106267360</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edded62c7bc80e01e99e3d7e672c6f4d</guid></item><item><title>Last-ditch push to land hospital and NDIS funding deal, as states fight back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/national-cabinet-hospital-ndis-funding-deal/106267184</link><description>The Commonwealth will try to force a deal on hospital funding at a National Cabinet meeting this week, after months of stalled negotiations with angry state leaders, who say the federal government is not contributing its fair share.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e26818d1805e43aae7af031c7316554</guid></item><item><title>What makes a house a home? Kevin McCloud and Tim Ross might have the answer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/kevin-mccloud-tim-ross-grand-designs-architecture/106157748</link><description>What makes a house a home? Grand Designs' Kevin McCloud and design enthusiast Tim Ross say it's as simple as a building that "puts you in contact with other people".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1aa166f0de3c8c1241627ef7085a8f0</guid></item><item><title>American rock climber Alex Honnold reaches top of Taipei 101 skyscraper without ropes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/alex-honnold-climbs-taipei-101-without-ropes/106267428</link><description>It took Alex Honnold about 90 minutes to reach the top of the 508-metre-tall building.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61152ce9f24dd4a9695fb849ebe2fafd</guid></item><item><title>New era dawns in Australian cricket as Big Bash generation steps up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/next-generation-players-new-era-australian-cricket/106265608</link><description>While Australian punters and pundits alike have been wringing their hands over an aging national cricket squad, the next generation has been quietly getting to work, proving they are ready to fill the shoes of retiring stars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dcd7bde6122f635acf8eab9ebf5ff13</guid></item><item><title>Bull shark tagging and extra drones for NSW beaches following attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/sydney-bull-shark-tagging-program-and-extra-drones-nsw-beaches/106266896</link><description>NSW coast and Sydney Harbour beachgoers can expect to see more drones in the sky after a $4.2 million investment into the state's shark management program in the wake of four shark attacks, including one fatal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">240ff0417da03ec80d9714660ffe00bd</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open favourite Aryna Sabalenka's simple approach to being world number one</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/australian-open-aryna-sabalenka-wins-fourth-round/106267374</link><description>As another Australian Open title beckons, Aryna Sabalenka reveals why she has not changed since topping the world rankings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23b5005766c8500ce2314a50d9cd23d5</guid></item><item><title>Scotty James wins fifth-straight X-Games superpipe gold ahead of Milano Cortina Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/scotty-james-wins-x-games-gold/106267420</link><description>Scotty James has matched snowboard legend Shaun White by claiming his eighth superpipe gold medal at the X-Games Aspen 2026, making him a sure favourite for Olympic gold in Milano Cortina next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ebcd8f21f4b4607fa1cf0da6c09d841</guid></item><item><title>Singer Dave Grohl speaks to the crowd about the Beaconsfield Mine rescue. Supplied: Alicia Kitchener</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/dave-grohl-speaks-about-beaconsfield/106267576</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93bf68e0fc4a9b64f8635c89097db5fd</guid></item><item><title>Foo Fighters and Beaconsfield trapped miner reunite at Launceston concert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/foo-fighters-concert-launceston/106267426</link><description>Foo Fighters frontman Dave Grohl says it was a "profound moment" when a pair of miners requested the rock band's music to lift their spirits while trapped underground in 2006.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78956d31425276f2bc52f431584836d6</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroo takes out Tour Down Under peloton, Jay Vine claims overall victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/kangaroo-crashes-into-tour-down-under-peloton-as-jay-vine-wins/106267096</link><description>Jay Vine was taken out by a pair of kangaroos and lost yet another teammate to injury, but was still able to hang on and claim a second career Tour Down Under victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b78e63a5ece1034f2c7fe54cfd3e8da</guid></item><item><title>A second person has been shot dead by federal agents in Minneapolis. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/explainer-here-s-what-we-know-about-the-minneapolis-shooting/106267266</link><description>The death of 37-year-old US citizen Alex Pretti has prompted a fierce political debate and further protests in an already tense city. This is what we know about the situation so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fb0f6f0f4a69d84a400ec03d5050a7e</guid></item><item><title>Police at Mount Hope after possible sighting of Julian Ingram</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/police-at-mount-hope-after-possible-sighting-of-julian-ingram/106267806</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">528eb11903cb6d5353149cbf4ce74d45</guid></item><item><title>Police seize illicit tobacco products in WA's south-west.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/police-seize-illicit-tobacco-products-in-wa-south-west-/106267450</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b916a97ee76d6a6a40d8ba9e69815546</guid></item><item><title>Tens of thousands of cigarettes and vapes seized in illicit tobacco crackdown in South West WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/illicit-tobacco-crackdown-in-southwest-wa/106267262</link><description>Tens of thousands of cigarettes and vapes, and almost $90,000 cash, has been seized during a week-long crackdown on illicit tobacco in WA's South West.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21c66596d26ba93c8b1fdeb004174b8c</guid></item><item><title>Sydney man, 70, charged after allegedly sending threatening letter to Lakemba Mosque</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/man-70-charged-alleged-threatening-letter-lakemba-mosque/106266730</link><description>Police seized more than 100 letters, stamps, notepads and several electronic devices after a raid on the 70-year-old's Belmore home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ade4ebeb7617c0b4f298b715ae3965ce</guid></item><item><title>Police search for missing 12-year-old boy at Venus Bay in Victoria's east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/missing-12yo-boy-venus-bay-victoria-gippsland-coast-search/106267850</link><description>Police and the community have mounted a search for 12-year-old Danny, who was last seen swimming at a beach in Venus Bay on Sunday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a0462944dd56b6809f5d577cf656dd9</guid></item><item><title>Live: Scorchers on cusp of glory as Sixers roll over in BBL final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/bbl-final-sixers-vs-scorchers-live-updates/106265840</link><description>Steve Smith and the Sydney Sixers are dismissed for a meek 132, with David Payne leading an inspired Scorchers bowling performance in the BBL final. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">431537a3be89a430c517f56d8dbe45e6</guid></item><item><title>Space industry trailblazer named Australian of the Year 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/australian-of-the-year-awards-2026/106267536</link><description>Katherine Bennell-Pegg has been named 2026 Australian of the Year for making history as the first Australian to qualify as an astronaut under the nation's space program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5ae7678f581697b07ccbb5311d87c21</guid></item><item><title>Sole survivor of Lake Cargelligo shooting opens up on the moment violence erupted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/lake-cargelligo-shooting-survivor-kaleb-macqueen-speaks/106265692</link><description>Nineteen-year-old Kaleb Macqueen was working on his car in the quiet NSW outback town of Lake Cargelligo last Thursday when violence erupted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe99dfe1797ad4944b4d36c256b7d244</guid></item><item><title>2026 Local Hero Frank Mitchell accepts honour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/2026-local-hero-frank-mitchell-accepts-honour-/106267998</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa57d4b1175e95962f9620cee559b61a</guid></item><item><title>2026 Young Australian of the Year Nedd Brockmann accepts honour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/2026-young-australian-of-the-year-nedd-brockmann-accepts-honour/106268010</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db6fb635da0ba04c2c373f033be90c19</guid></item><item><title>2026 Senior Australian of the Year Henry Brodaty AO accepts honour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/2026-senior-australian-of-the-year-henry-brodaty-ao/106268026</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">696e3cc0358e17ca7705eabe62682807</guid></item><item><title>2026 Australian of the Year Katherine Bennell-Pegg accepts honour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/2026-australian-of-the-year-katherine-bennell-pegg/106268050</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2c530bbcdd7eb8b34b1e73121e4acb7</guid></item><item><title>Australia Day Honours List 2026: Meet some of the people inspiring the nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/2026-australia-day-honours-list/106258634</link><description>From champion athletes to those working to help our most vulnerable, the 2026 Australia Day Honours List showcases the very best of the nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53711307a01f4f50a4d1a89d08fb4c85</guid></item></channel></rss>