<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 09:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Australian cow market at record high as US demand hits 'scary times'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/us-cattle-prices-soar-increasing-demand-for-aussie-beef/105776020</link><description>Australian cow prices are at record highs, but are still way below the United States where beef demand is going "crazy".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56f2d0555cc98f7f69e717a8162ea988</guid></item><item><title>Son, 28, charged with murder after allegedly assaulting parents on Father's Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/man-charged-with-murder-after-alleged-coffs-harbour-assault/105788172</link><description>A 28-year-old Coffs Harbour man has been charged with murder and attempted murder after allegedly assaulting his parents and starting a house fire on Father's Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe632a8da922ef75e0d1e5b6cb68d663</guid></item><item><title>Authorities urge parents to check Little Ones Nappy Pants for khapra beetle larvae</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nappy-pants-still-unaccounted-for-khapra-beetle-larvae-found/105787812</link><description>Hundreds of cartons of nappy pants remain unaccounted for after one of the biggest threats to Australia's grain industry, khapra beetle larvae, was found in the imported products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45cfd2bf95d89861ab6dc3f7a688868c</guid></item><item><title>Cats coach Chris Scott regrets run-in with AFL staffer after qualifying final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/geelong-cats-chris-scott-afl-staff-qualifying-final/105789664</link><description>Geelong coach Chris Scott says long-held frustration with the AFL was behind his regrettable post-qualifying final win outburst at a junior league employee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64f8afe41599735121373a93d14d1aff</guid></item><item><title>The Albanese government has learned from the last major climate commitment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/2035-target-energy-debate-power-prices/105787072</link><description>The government is keenly aware that the cost of the transition is a sensitive issue, which is why the prime minister was flanked not just by his climate minister but also his treasurer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb04f44e27c2583896465cd35dce2ecb</guid></item><item><title>Bindi Magic art exhibition opens in Alice Springs as organisation celebrates 25 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/bindi-magic-art-exhibition-opens-in-alice-springs/105789908</link><description>For 25 years Bindi Mwerre Anthurre Artists has been helping people with a disability to communicate through creativity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac6f9add20cd12006d1f874f0c4e4ec</guid></item><item><title>Police lay murder charge after woman's alleged domestic violence death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/man-charged-with-murder-after-alleged-dv-death-palmerston-nt/105790976</link><description>Northern Territory police have charged a 32-year-old man with the murder of his 31-year-old partner, who died hours after she was found unresponsive in the front yard of a Palmerston home earlier this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ef129cc6970d350f41596426a01f694</guid></item><item><title>Independent advice spells out mammoth task ahead for government to reach 2035 target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/the-task-ahead-to-reach-2035-emissions-target/105789538</link><description>Getting to even the bottom end of the government's 62 to 70 per cent emissions reduction target by 2035 will require drastic increases to solar and wind power capacity, electric vehicle take-up and an extension of the safeguard mechanism, according to the Climate Change Authority.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">112c61869ecf0e96b28c94212500d843</guid></item><item><title>After deadly floods in Bali, its people want answers. Many are blaming overtourism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/bali-overtourism-blamed-in-wake-of-deadly-floods/105785674</link><description>Unexpected and deadly flooding rocked Bali last week at a scale many had never experienced before. In the wake of this disaster, the search for answers has begun.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">744d51865bef7cb34f9b946d580e8498</guid></item><item><title>First Guardian, Shield superannuation disasters expose deep flaws in Australia's $4.3 trillion retirement system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/first-guardian-shield-collapse-asic-and-superannuation-flaws/105783328</link><description>The failed First Guardian and Shield schemes have cost about 12,000 Australians more than $1 billion in retirement savings and exposed deep flaws in how Australia's $4.3 trillion superannuation sector is regulated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b80687a0c984dcbca73fbbe0b5a3dbb7</guid></item><item><title>Riverina family grapples with daughter's devastating childhood dementia diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/riverina-family-grapples-with-childhood-dementia-diagnosis-/105789234</link><description>Rachel Anderson says she knew something was not right when her daughter Hannah began struggling to remember things she had just done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30cd776df827d075049497355a0ec58f</guid></item><item><title>Mount Isa waits for '11th-hour' decision on financial support for copper smelter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/mount-isa-copper-smelter-glencore-negotiations/105787756</link><description>Copper production is on the chopping block in outback Queensland, with mining giant Glencore about to decide on its future. What is the cost of losing a legacy industry?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6389a1b1230c562f480fd57d5cbe967b</guid></item><item><title>Miranda Tapsell and Gwilym Lee show it 'takes a village' to raise a child in Top End Bub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/top-end-bub-miranda-tapsell-gwilym-lee/105775286</link><description>Miranda Tapsell and Gwilym Lee return to their characters from the hit movie, Top End Wedding, to take on parenthood in the TV series, Top End Bub.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6b3a94883d6882b00c7e6f5904787b6</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Albanese seizes on Ley's climate slip up — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/federal-politics-live-sept-19/105790890</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has seized on remarks made by Opposition Leader Sussan Ley about Australia's climate targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d8c53f5355ddd10031e0a3f823e1972</guid></item><item><title>AFL finals fever takes hold as fans line up to buy tickets offline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/fans-line-up-for-afl-grand-final-tickets/105783152</link><description>AFL fans fed up with the online ticketing system have opted to line up in person days in advance to secure their finals tickets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae67e6d9e7b54c457bfa6e91a30fd4f7</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout misses out on 200m final at World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/gout-gout-misses-out-on-200m-final-at-world-athletics-/105792462</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44814bf4d05e24efb9a86e9874126c57</guid></item><item><title>Young members bring new life to the Rural Fire Service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/rural-fire-service-brigades-seek-new-members/105778996</link><description>Nearly a quarter of all western NSW Rural Fire Service volunteers are older than 70, but some younger recruits are urging others to follow in their footsteps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a9645dec99c6b79501e9b7ecffcd0c1</guid></item><item><title>Rabbits cause 'devastating' damage to Junee cemetery in southern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/rabbits-cause-devastating-damage-to-junee-cemetery-southern-nsw/105792784</link><description>The Junee Shire Council says it is battling a rabbit problem, which forced a recent closure of the town's main cemetery for a week, including on Father's Day, for a baiting program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6e24632645222977003b4a6af3561fc</guid></item><item><title>RONA. weaves together country, colonialism and club music on new EP It's All Here</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/rona-its-all-here-ep-bush-beats-country-colonialism-club-music/105758094</link><description>This Kaytetye producer has a fresh take on the space race that draws from First Nations knowledge and culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f63cbfd798f6826103c82f171f571494</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann likely to face four-day hearing in Tasmania over motor vehicle stealing charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/bruce-lehrmann-likely-to-face-four-day-hearing/105794304</link><description>Former Liberal staffer Bruce Lehrmann appears in the Hobart Magistrates Court after pleading not guilty to one count of motor vehicle stealing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">680bec6e2ce2b4d53ae9b27667c53e23</guid></item><item><title>China urges Papua New Guinea not to exclude other countries after it signed 'Pukpuk' communique with Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/china-warns-papua-new-guinea-against-bilateral-deal-australia/105794018</link><description>China has urged Papua New Guinea not to sign any deal that might exclude or restrict third parties from cooperating with the Pacific nation, as Australia scrambles to clinch a landmark defence treaty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad04d0391ea73681a5f0351d55692b32</guid></item><item><title>Hakyung Lee, mother accused of killing children, had a 'disease of the mind', defence expert tells court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/hakyung-lee-suitcase-murders-auckland-new-zealand/105781562</link><description>Hakyung Lee has been charged with murdering her children and has pleaded not guilty by reason of insanity after leaving their bodies in an Auckland storage facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">690cb00a0c2ca94e57c34909bfc58001</guid></item><item><title>Sharks vow not to taunt Raiders in sudden-death NRL semifinal as minor premiers look to bounce back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/nrl-cronulla-sharks-canberra-raiders-semi-final/105795410</link><description>Cronulla suggests it will not niggle Canberra in Saturday night's semifinal, despite the Brisbane Broncos successfully getting under the Raiders' skin in their thrilling one-point win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de811a022c87a3d1a6baef74c8c54ce6</guid></item><item><title>How to build a flourishing garden in a courtyard or smaller space</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/how-to-create-a-garden-with-not-much-space-or-sun/105763316</link><description>Living in a smaller space doesn't mean you can't have a lush garden. Here's how to rejuvenate your garden with some easy tips.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10fca8a72dcf1eb2dd616158042c2c3b</guid></item><item><title>Patrick Dangerfield stars to send Geelong into the AFL grand final as concussion rules Tom Stewart out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/afl-preliminary-final-geelong-vs-hawthorn-live-blog/105779366</link><description>Geelong utility Tom Stewart will miss the AFL grand final, but coach Chris Scott feels his Cats are in a great position to win the premiership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dd33f956ae78d4a6741605fb30417b7</guid></item><item><title>All the latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/all-the-latest-financial-news/105796416</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6301e2bdeedf208ea5d5c5a791f35a27</guid></item><item><title>Optus CEO apologises to customers impacted by major network outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/optus-ceo-apologises-to-customers-impacted-by/105796546</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76fd1e56e640c3fcc4ec93132683da1d</guid></item><item><title>Optus CEO confirms three deaths during network outage affecting emergency calls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/optus-ceo-confirms-three-deaths-during-network/105796530</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2616d41c37b08dbe3f6b1464bddea5b</guid></item><item><title>A secret lived in plain sight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/a-secret-lived-in-plain-sight/105708692</link><description>Alliyah is reckoning with a decade of grooming and abuse at the hands of a trusted teacher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e77cd7303996f6436a98d30e0bbc14ed</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the Optus outage which disrupted triple-zero calls, linked to three deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/what-we-know-about-optus-network-outage/105796618</link><description>It's been two days since three people died after a devastating Optus outage caused hundreds of emergency calls to fail, but information about the incident remains scarce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81d841cfe097dc82a144e78eb4423953</guid></item><item><title>Israel faces pressure over Gaza ahead of General Assembly as United Nations confronts its own identity crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/united-nations-general-assembly-israel-trump-climate/105778680</link><description>The UN's role in areas beyond diplomacy, such as in humanitarian aid and refugees, cultural heritage, health, and climate, are all under assault from savage budget cuts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">375fa7d383a147731e52173b0d2956ad</guid></item><item><title>Collingwood and Brisbane meet again, two years on from classic 2023 grand final, for tantalising rematch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/afl-preliminary-final-collingwood-brisbane-preview/105793028</link><description>The 2023 grand final will go down as one of the best deciders in AFL history, and though the stakes are only marginally lower two years on, the numbers suggest Collingwood and Brisbane's 2025 preliminary final could be another classic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ec81c3cb39b858091335eeff1f3c10e</guid></item><item><title>Federal government's agriculture emissions reductions 'ambitious' but 'achievable'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/agriculture-industry-responds-toemissions-reduction-expectations/105792968</link><description>A professor of carbon farming says the agriculture industry will "naturally" contribute to a 28 per cent emissions reduction projected by 2050, but is unlikely to hit its own net-zero targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be4c701559d4d36210ea847a9fa9b087</guid></item><item><title>Pink Floyd's album and ode to Syd Barrett Wish You Were Here turns 50</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/pink-floyd-wish-you-were-here-turns-50/105782374</link><description>Pink Floyd looked to the past to find a way forward after the massive success of Dark Side Of The Moon in 1973. The result was Wish You Were Here, released 50 years ago this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78a552157b44e92ce3d5f5773e471f3d</guid></item><item><title>Storm damage sees shark net installation delay at Sydney's Shark Beach in Nielsen Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/shark-net-installation-delay-at-sydney-shark-beach-neilsen-park/105794772</link><description>Shark Beach in Sydney's east is seasonally netted with an enclosure to protect swimmers from sharks during Sydney's warmer months — but for the upcoming school holidays, it is unlikely the nets will be installed in time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fb506200ed1eacf664848d3c53c5964</guid></item><item><title>Remote NSW council holds election after 12 years in administration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/central-darling-shire-council-election-nsw-votes-after-12-years/105757794</link><description>The 700 voters living in the remote Central Darling Shire Council area of New South Wales will finally head to the polls to vote again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2af8d61243c1a142aa5a6b000bb6dea5</guid></item><item><title>Chelsea FC Women's star Sam Kerr presented with special football to mark 100 goals for club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/like-a-new-person-sam-kerr-all-smiles-after-comeback-goal/105797260</link><description>Sam Kerr is honoured with a special football to mark her 100 goals for Chelsea — and she can't stop smiling since the landmark strike.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52628ebbe474caa569cc4274ed7dde0b</guid></item><item><title>Victor Caulfield moved to Florence in his 70s and became an artists' model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/victor-caulfield-moved-to-florence-and-became-an-artists-model/105762988</link><description>Victor Caulfield packed up his Australian home and moved to Italy, where he fell into the art scene as an accidental model.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf11c6e1cc2bef7d1c59c017a7b1915d</guid></item><item><title>One-tray honey chicken wings are an easy family dinner - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/one-tray-sticky-chicken-wings/105658174</link><description>It’s easy to make these irresistibly sticky wings that will have you licking your fingers and reaching for more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b49e38fcb0cc57c3220c789ba5301301</guid></item><item><title>'America is not happy': ABC under fire for pulling Jimmy Kimmel Live!</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/complaints-about-kimmel-axing-meant-for-us-abc-sent-to-australia/105793428</link><description>The ABC has received hundreds of complaints about US talk show Jimmy Kimmel Live! being pulled off air and threats to boycott sponsors ... but that's the problem when two broadcasters from different countries share a name!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">058463060dc5663ada42854e5496b80c</guid></item><item><title>Turtling tracking in Broome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/turtling-tracking-in-broome/105794988</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10cb5e530edb2253e9361a5ada40925c</guid></item><item><title>World-first turtle tracking reveals secrets of flatback turtles in WA's Roebuck Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/world-first-tracking-of-flatback-turtles-in-roebuck-bay-broome/105794534</link><description>GPS tracking, motion sensors and video cameras reveal where flatback turtles in Broome's Roebuck Bay feed and travel, contributing to a richer understanding of the vulnerable species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6abd49307f41fd71e6160fa5f1479b4d</guid></item><item><title>UN says there's evidence organised crime scam centres are moving from South-East Asia into new frontier of the Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/organised-crime-scam-centres-move-into-pacific-united-nations/105775972</link><description>As scam centres run by organised crime find it harder to operate in South-East Asia, evidence emerges of them moving into the Pacific and setting up lucrative operations estimated to net billions each year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb89464594316563fc34dc56a716880e</guid></item><item><title>From Jennifer Lopez to K-pop, meet the Australian backing artists helping superstars shine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/jlo-kpop-paul-kelly-backing-artists/105765732</link><description>Backup dancers and backing singers spend years perfecting their craft. But who are these artists and how does it feel performing in the shadows of superstars?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0b91ab8cfee821d0f58d79f05cf3da5</guid></item><item><title>Minister slams 'extremist' candidates nominating for WA council elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/wa-minister-condemns-extremist-council-candidates/105739550</link><description>Local Government Minister Hannah Beazely condemns the emergence of "extremist" candidates nominating for the state's forthcoming council elections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bcdc6a1da26fcdf49227a137e3eb1f7</guid></item><item><title>Crowds flock to Toowoomba Carnival of Flowers despite wet weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/toowoomba-carnival-of-flowers-draws-crowds-despite-weather/105794286</link><description>Cold and damp conditions have not been enough to keep people away from Toowoomba's annual floral extravaganza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0670d318c12fc7fd9d19e3d22856487c</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane defeats Collingwood by 29 points to advance to third-straight AFL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/afl-preliminary-final-collingwood-brisbane-live-blog/105795084</link><description>A training session on Saturday morning featuring speed work adds to Lachie Neale's optimism about returning for Brisbane in the AFL grand final after the Lions beat the Magpies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">118ad3d44ffed50378b8e6071fbd05cf</guid></item><item><title>NRL finals updates: Cronulla Sharks defeat Canberra Raiders 32-12 in semifinal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/nrl-finals-live-updates-canberra-raiders-cronulla-sharks/105780662</link><description>An out-of-place nose doesn't hurt Joe Tapine as much as Canberra's NRL finals exit, but he hopes the pain of defeat will drive them to greater things next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2af84c91f7e4b5942651511648ab086f</guid></item><item><title>What is 'Solastalgia' and how are climate-affected communities tackling it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/climate-change-anxiety-first-nations-communities-respond/105793766</link><description>If you're overwhelmed by emissions targets, climate change and environmental collapse, start small and look to First Nations practices to help your wellbeing and the world around you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bff8375209835a394c77e6936900b17</guid></item><item><title>Antinatalists say human suffering, and climate change, makes having children unethical. Are they right?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/antinatalism-child-free-climate-change-human-suffering-baby/105695328</link><description>Elon Musk believes the collapsing birth rate is humanity's biggest danger. But antinatalists argue having kids is little more than a procreational Ponzi scheme, and the risks are real.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28999cb939ddfbe63b4a8339d72f435e</guid></item><item><title>Asia's protests grew from social media where misinformation also spread</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/nepal-indonesia-gen-z-social-media-misinformation/105779038</link><description>These movements may be separated by time, distance and language, but they were all born on social media, led by a new generation of activists fed up with the old systems of corruption and nepotism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">553dda439e393b87eb7b6bc4eff754a9</guid></item><item><title>What makes China confident enough to ban microchips made by US firm Nvidia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/what-makes-china-confident-to-ban-nvdia-microchips/105795486</link><description>Beijing's decision this week to ban Chinese companies from using microchips made by US firm Nvidia indicates the country is increasingly confident about replacing them with domestically produced chips, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c451e4e0710bc1516100c22ae7e23289</guid></item><item><title>Pirate attacks and sea robberies surge in key South-East Asian shipping lane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/piracy-sea-robberies-rise-malacca-strait-asia/105736740</link><description>Piracy and sea robberies are increasing in the strategic straits of Malacca and Singapore, which could have implications for Australian imports and exports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2b3b37fb5cc2fee69c406b2aa0ccdc5</guid></item><item><title>Scrubs is getting a reboot just in time for the hospital procedural revival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/scrubs-reboot-the-pitt-cheat-sheet/105793612</link><description>In a sea of hospital-based TV, long-running sitcoms Scrubs is often highlighted as one of the most realistic options. Now the reboot has been confirmed, and off the back of The Pitt’s big Emmy wins, we look back at the beloved show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f7cc2efbfa7b3a4841ebb5cb0fb4b85</guid></item><item><title>Street artist Rone's new 90-metre mural a visual love letter to Geelong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/tyrone-rone-wright-new-mural-captures-geelong-faces/105762354</link><description>The faces of 14 people will be immortalised in an enormous mural on the side of a new building in Geelong by locally born, globally renowned artist Rone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28ac13e735d6c51ed4a4df9593e87271</guid></item><item><title>Tough times in Wagga Wagga as young tennis stars chase grand slam dreams</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/wagga-wagga-young-tennis-stars-chase-grand-slam-dreams/105782764</link><description>Cara Korhonen played on Rod Laver Arena when she was 10 years of age and is putting her blood, sweat and tears into setting foot on there again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f95f37d9c572b37b64f39f73603da74</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberals' star candidate in spotlight after AI algal bloom 'admin error'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/ai-liv-golf-algal-bloom-comments-put-frank-pangallo-in-spotlight/105787864</link><description>When Frank Pangallo announced he was joining the Liberal party, he vowed to put the blowtorch on a first-term government riding high in the polls. But barely four weeks later, the blowtorch is firmly on Pangallo instead, writes Leah MacLennan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bd3524d93d528173e52862abfbcd325</guid></item><item><title>Inside Ninga Mia, a forgotten community in the shadow of Kalgoorlie the city of gold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/ninga-mia-kalgoorlie-mining-aboriginal-reserve-homelessness-gold/105774862</link><description>There's an eerie silence in Ninga Mia, a once thriving community on the edge of Kalgoorlie. The Aboriginal reserve is a microcosm of the cycle of displacement endured by many First Nations people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eafa5daeccecbae05c7c9ef093e72c5</guid></item><item><title>Cockchafer worm wreaking havoc on West Australian grain crops</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/cockchafer-pest-costing-wa-grain-farmers-thousands/105783068</link><description>Growers and scientists have teamed up in a bid to combat the rapidly increasing population of the voracious pest, which is devastating crops in WA's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a33788626f5c22861ceddd417b44c658</guid></item><item><title>Government has not set 2035 renewables target, downplays 90 per cent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/government-yet-to-set-2035-renewables-target/105798906</link><description>In New York for the UN summit, Energy Minister Chris Bowen declines to offer a renewable energy target for 2035 after the Climate Change Authority projected more than 90 per cent would be needed to hit its recommended emissions target.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4880a6213f11733719ca49464957e58</guid></item><item><title>Symbio Wildlife Park emu chicks being raised by hens after father walks out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/symbio-wildlife-park-abandoned-emus-raised-by-chickens/105795380</link><description>Birds of a different feather are flocking together at a wildlife park in New South Wales, where the chickens have been given the responsibility of being foster parents to a pair of abandoned emu chicks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6846407eac281053e23e77b5a99c248</guid></item><item><title>Crocodiles on the move in northern Australia as breeding season arrives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/crocodiles-on-the-move-breeding-season-arrives-north-australia/105766898</link><description>It's crocodile breeding season and at one central Queensland farm, the drama is on par with a reality television dating show as keepers try to work out the best pairings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab50329a1039618670babc23784c4980</guid></item><item><title>Optus outage 'unlikely' to have caused baby's death, police say, but impact spreads to NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/baby-death-unlikely-caused-by-optus-outage-police-say/105798926</link><description>Optus reveals that in addition to customers in South Australia, Western Australia and the Northern Territory, two people in New South Wales were unable to connect to emergency services during the 13-hour outage last Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88c597d073f490d4418d712b6d14a44a</guid></item><item><title>Life on Aboriginal reserve remembered by Carnarvon traditional owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/aboriginal-reserve-memories-carnarvon-traditional-owners/105510728</link><description>In 1975, an anthropologist wrote his thesis on Carnarvon's rich Aboriginal reserve. Decades later, traditional owners revisit the work to contribute to "big truth-telling" documentary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecf8bb607751e84f71648e4dfa5cd44a</guid></item><item><title>Australian-born singer drops out of Russian-hosted Intervision song contest after 'political pressure'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australian-born-singer-drops-out-of-russian-hosted-song-contest/105799020</link><description>Vassy dropped out of the contest at the last minute after coming under what Russian organisers said was "unprecedented political pressure from the government of Australia".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6f53824a2ed40b9ae66bd7ebdb25e1a</guid></item><item><title>How Brisbane, Hawthorn, Geelong and Collingwood stay on top of the AFL world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/afl-analysis-geelong-brisbane-collingwood-hawthorn/105797710</link><description>The 21st century has been dominated by four AFL clubs — Geelong, Hawthorn, Collingwood and Brisbane — but there's no single secret to their success.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0de8258f95182f2d73692053694b3fa</guid></item><item><title>Penola High School's agriculture program revives community and enrolments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/penola-high-school-ag-program-revives-falling-enrolments/105787042</link><description>Cory O'Connor's three-week teaching placement turned around his hometown high school. Now he's receiving an award for the agriculture program he started there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">800678cadea15a18ec482186c893d046</guid></item><item><title>How to clean out your wardrobe as the seasons change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/how-to-spring-clean-wardobe-clean-out/105780140</link><description>It's the kind of task that can seem overwhelming, but the change of season is the perfect opportunity to review what's in your wardrobe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf9c7f0a36323b3457588962f5d0b0b0</guid></item><item><title>Optus CEO confirms further customer report calls, service outage at NSW-SA border.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/optus-ceo-confirms-further-customer-report-calls,/105799496</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99f2ad74ac543864780c38476c5a3384</guid></item><item><title>Penrith's win over Canterbury was a reminder there is no team like them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/panthers-bulldogs-nrl-finals-cleary-galvin-too/105799368</link><description>Canterbury is a team built in Penrith's image, but the Panthers served Canterbury a stark reminder that there can be only one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43391fdd3b75eadfd140d1ee7f293931</guid></item><item><title>Australia formally recognises state of Palestine as Anthony Albanese arrives in US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australia-formally-recognises-state-of-palestine/105799238</link><description>The historic decision foreshadowed last month has now become a reality, as Australia moves with Canada and the United Kingdom to join the growing list of countries to recognise Palestinian sovereignty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f7f36cbe6b5b1fbaaf3e78efd2951a2</guid></item><item><title>Can recognising the state of Palestine achieve a two-state solution as Israel continues bombing Gaza?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australia-recognises-state-of-palestine-two-state-solution/105799276</link><description>While the Israel Defense Forces bomb Gaza and bulldoze the West Bank for settlements, moves to recognise Palestine in pursuit of a two-state solution may appear like something of a sick joke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfa3467335da07f9ce07cf8e87421ac9</guid></item><item><title>Is artificial intelligence overhyped or is AI the 'fourth industrial revolution'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/is-ai-the-fourth-industrial-revolution/105790912</link><description>It's estimated 30,000 people are working in the AI industry in Australia, and fanfare is growing with start-ups tapping into billions of dollars of venture capital. Yet there are concerns about hype and a lack of regulation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26daac2bce5f986abcbf545a3ec82df2</guid></item><item><title>Brownlow Medal 2025 — when is it, how to watch and who are the favourites for AFL's best-and-fairest award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-medal-2025-explainer-how-to-watch-who-might-win/105799236</link><description>The AFL's big night is here, as the league's best and fairest player is honoured with the Brownlow Medal. Here is everything you need to know about the big event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a533b478e86cba0a5d23c3da7fd118e4</guid></item><item><title>The government says its 2035 climate targets are achievable but mathematics suggests a different story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/climate-target-2035-2050-carbon-emissions-global-warming/105799080</link><description>The problem with an emissions reduction target is that its mere existence implies it is achievable and that if we do achieve it, we will be fine. The truth is more complex.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55dd3a3450e5da05cd2e7e786ef836f8</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Kopp's teacher Paul Grealy groomed her at 15. As an adult, she held him to account</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/sarah-kopps-teacher-paul-grealy-groomed-her-from-15/105775958</link><description>Sarah Kopp's life was up-ended when a charismatic teacher twice her age started grooming her. Then they married and had children. When she sought justice 20 years on, she faced an impossible choice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">329e0e5fdb603a2e16d3f7e31513666e</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump calls Charlie Kirk a 'martyr' at memorial service, widow Erika Kirk forgives alleged assassin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/thousand-gather-charlie-kirk-memorial-service-donald-trump/105800038</link><description>US President Donald Trump says Charlie Kirk was a "martyr to American freedom", while his widow says she forgives his alleged assassin during a memorial to the right-wing activist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a195c5eaab3b46f9f8c92705e3433bbb</guid></item><item><title>Australia has been free of endemic measles since 2014. Could that change?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/measles-cases-on-the-rise-australia-explainer/105799284</link><description>So far this year, there have been 121 measles notifications across Australia — the highest number since 2019, when there were 284 notifications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cebd25abdddc63773dde66358f7395f</guid></item><item><title>Storm-damaged turbine at NSW Central West wind farm raises safety concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/storm-damaged-turbine-at-nsw-central-west-wind-farm-concerns/105782400</link><description>After a wind turbine blade snapped in half during a storm, the NSW National Party has called for a safety audit into the renewable technology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">020cbe7c7b785e21c8f3c2fd850c4be9</guid></item><item><title>Short-term stays are swallowing up housing stock in these WA coastal havens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/wa-coastal-towns-for-rent/105628728</link><description>With one of the nation's highest proportions of Airbnbs, some of WA's most popular tourist towns face a dilemma. Tourism is their biggest breadwinner — but with a housing crisis in full swing, short-term stays are pushing more and more locals away.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42e3387b3cda80c2ffd9d9842d5c1c42</guid></item><item><title>Worker dies after being struck by forklift in Sydney's east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/sydney-man-dies-in-matraville-work-site-forklift-incident/105800506</link><description>The 57-year-old man was at a worksite in Sydney's east when he was seriously injured by a forklift.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3a2752abe4ded520b3c92b7cbfdbd1d</guid></item><item><title>This program could be the blueprint for helping kids fleeing domestic violence stay off the streets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/homeless-kids-domestic-violence-solution-politics/105793902</link><description>Every night, thousands of Australian kids are homeless without an adult to look after them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e17c22bd4e0bdb7ea0d6cd380a87fbf</guid></item><item><title>World leaders are meeting at the UN General Assembly this week. Here are four things to watch for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/united-nations-general-assembly-what-to-watch-for-in-new-york/105800440</link><description>World leaders are arriving in New York for the UN General Assembly — and for the first time, Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is among them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">761958b8abcd8c47c96a8d78d674b211</guid></item><item><title>Optus triple-0 outage investigation underway as minister warns of 'consequences'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/optus-investigation-triple-0-outage/105800556</link><description>The Australian Media and Communications Authority begins its investigation into the Optus triple-0 outage that has been linked to multiple deaths in South Australia and Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64e8d943c326b70c38e9b095d514da19</guid></item><item><title>Optus customer details failed triple-0 call after mother was trapped by mobility scooter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/sa-optus-victim-speaks-out/105800730</link><description>A former triple-0 operator has detailed the distressing moment she could not reach emergency services when her mother became trapped under her mobility scooter during the company's 13-hour outage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17fcf874f0c650c193d3577e9ebbb23e</guid></item><item><title>Australians can't trust the triple-0 network after 13-hour Optus outage results in deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/optus-triple-0-failure-analysis/105800592</link><description>The Optus failure is shocking and no doubt a massive fine and other sanctions could be on the way, but experts say it raises further questions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2edd7465f8b9851c69c1b7efadb1f5f1</guid></item><item><title>Easy and healthy dinner recipes for spring</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/easy-healthy-recipes-for-spring-dinners/105660408</link><description>If you're looking for light dinner ideas as the weather warms up, we have plenty of easy options. Think veggie-filled frittatas and beef taco bowls with a few healthy swaps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c28e2a7be5345c5402fc685acca89162</guid></item><item><title>West Swan's Pow Street residents demand water pipes be replaced after 'massive' leaks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/west-swan-residents-tire-of-ongoing-water-main-leaks/105802606</link><description>Residents of a street in the Perth's outskirts say they are desperate after six water main bursts in the past 20 years, but the Water Corp says the pipes are only 52 years old and well within their life span.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">659c10fa7f2b80ca122f698fa1a8926e</guid></item><item><title>Vital shipping route plagued by pirates and sea robbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/vital-shipping-route-plagued-by-pirates-and-sea/105802894</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51ae5c28dd52b64419536143c6ef1f57</guid></item><item><title>Geelong star Max Holmes admits missing 2022 grand final hurt relationship with coach Chris Scott</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/i-was-pissed-with-scotty-cats-star-holmes-eyes-afl-flag/105802834</link><description>Geelong speedster Max Holmes is desperate to put his previous grand-final week anger and heartbreak behind him as the Cats eye AFL premiership glory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd1f4bd169de77ac34368207d9141381</guid></item><item><title>Super Netball's Sunshine Coast Lightning enters new Global Sports Fund Management Group ownership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/super-netball-sunshine-coast-lightning-new-ownership/105801344</link><description>Almost a decade after being co-founded by the Melbourne Storm and University of the Sunshine Coast, Super Netball's Lightning is entering a new era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">725e5769d7aa41a90979ec4d3e47f5bd</guid></item><item><title>Alexander O'Sachy faces Brisbane court charged with manslaughter of Angela Godwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/manslaughter-sentencing-domestic-violence-upper-mount-gravatt/105802410</link><description>The court heard the 47-year-old had a criminal history spanning more than 20 years for more than 50 offences, including the unlawful wounding of a former partner in 2008.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b4cf8d12fdea5712adde0cc2c477aae</guid></item><item><title>Brownlow Medal 2025: All the best fashion looks from AFL's night of nights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-red-carpet-wrap/105802436</link><description>Just after the fashion from this evening's Brownlow Medal? We've got you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8922390581e8430e878c1aa384dd8e2d</guid></item><item><title>Matt Rowell wins 2025 Brownlow Medal as Gold Coast star beats out Nick Daicos and Bailey Smith</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-medal-2025-live-blog-daicos-smith-dawson-rowell/105798968</link><description>Matt Rowell becomes the second Gold Coast player to win the prestigious AFL award, as a questionable voting call regarding Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera leaves the room stunned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08247d0fedaa413c59c8aea7818c6570</guid></item><item><title>Latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/latest-financial-news/105804002</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a2a0a2b0118f619ddf3cb8e2061e8e4</guid></item><item><title>Ley writes to Republicans vowing to revoke Palestine recognition ahead of Albanese's UN address</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/albanese-un-palestine-address-ley-republican-letter/105803078</link><description>In an unorthodox move, Opposition Leader Sussan Ley writes to a group of Republicans reassuring the Coalition would withdraw recognition of Palestine, ahead of a major United Nations address to be delivered by the prime minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98f3481476a06e3c9782e1032f1893d8</guid></item><item><title>Moldovan authorities arrest 74 people over alleged Russia-backed election plot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/moldova-election-arrests-russia-backed-plot/105804776</link><description>The widespread raids came ahead of the country's parliamentary elections on Sunday, expected to determine whether the country will pursue closer ties with the European Union.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a647be00ecfc0d387fa0b9a153bf4406</guid></item><item><title>The kids growing up in 'the most dangerous place in the world to be a child'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/children-living-in-gaza/105789464</link><description>There are a million children living in Gaza through the war between Israel and Hamas. Foreign Correspondent follows one young family trying to survive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17536ed0e05730b47651936db408187f</guid></item><item><title>Artificial intelligence to dominate Australia's future economy, but who will reap the benefits?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/australias-future-economy-will-be-dominated-by-ai/105802364</link><description>From robots to supercomputers, artificial intelligence is set to become an integral part of the Australian economy, with tens of billions in benefits to be gained … but for whom?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12e16358f1d06001f22c8315b12c996c</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar junta revoking citizenship of actors, singers and other celebrities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/myanmar-celebrities-left-stateless-after-criticising-junta/105787574</link><description>Myanmar's military junta is using citizenship as a weapon, targeting political opponents, activists and even celebrities who speak out against the regime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df5568a6e89118d9a0c2db08ec61854c</guid></item><item><title>Three Australians lay dead as investors of Optus's parent company Singtel were buying up its shares</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/three-australians-lay-dead-investors-buy-up-shares/105803922</link><description>The actions by Optus management in the hours following a series of failed attempts by its customers to call triple-0 raises questions about the telco's fitness to operate in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24e9f1bc9c2b8e3b2e1bdab5ae2ccb23</guid></item><item><title>Meeting between Anthony Albanese and Donald Trump unlikely ahead of UN address</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/meeting-unlikely-between-albanese-and-trump/105804978</link><description>The US president's itinerary for his 24-hour visit to New York makes no mention of Anthony Albanese, all but confirming a one-on-one will not be happening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9178055a02eb3b7f78d5f3fc4d772a8c</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: 'No doubt' Trump and Albanese will meet soon, acting PM says — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/federal-politics-live-sept-23/105803300</link><description>Richard Marles says he has no doubt the prime minister and US president will meet soon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2770399e32c9257f91ff03c40ec31e7</guid></item><item><title>Calls for long-term plan to address Tasmania's 'concerning' school attendance level</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/tasmania-school-attendance-level-concerns/105770010</link><description>Australia's school attendance levels have dropped since the pandemic but education experts are particularly concerned about Tasmania — a state with an already notoriously low literacy rate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81f75b3e7bbb3bc0d144997482f5d7c9</guid></item><item><title>The public hospital patients who ended up paying abortion clinics for miscarriage care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/qld-mater-miscarriage-care-catholic-hospital-abortion/105781022</link><description>Brisbane women have told the ABC they paid an abortion clinic for their chosen miscarriage care rather than getting it at their large public hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34accc25ffd487a2e3cb32cdcd8a582d</guid></item><item><title>Moment Matt Rowell announced as 2025 Brownlow medallist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/moment-matt-rowell-announced-as-2025-brownlow-medallist/105805032</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4336530cc59f3c10ad2c74d7b058cebe</guid></item><item><title>Matt Rowell delivers Brownlow Medal acceptance speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/matt-rowell-delivers-brownlow-medal-acceptance-speech/105805042</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2002bf4ac5caada0dc95c1432e61966</guid></item><item><title>Doctors concerned easily accessible illegal cigarettes are causing smoking rates to increase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/act-easy-access-to-illegal-cigarettes-seeing-high-smoking-rates/105803450</link><description>Doctors say smoking rates are at levels they haven't seen in a decade due to easy access to illegal cigarettes that are a "quarter of the price" of legal cigarettes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">150ad4af75b20ef2e67ba79a215e5c20</guid></item><item><title>Man Ray and Max Dupain's photography on display together for the first time in new Heide exhibition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/man-ray-max-dupain-photography-exhibition-heide-melbourne/105790024</link><description>Surrealist photographer Man Ray revolutionised 20th-century visual culture. In Australia, a local photographer was exploring similar territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">318bfee371103375fcc23430352eccfd</guid></item><item><title>Dash camera mandate for WA driving instructors considered as part of regulation review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/wa-government-consider-driving-instructor-camera-mandate/105790618</link><description>The WA government is considering mandating the use of dash cameras for driving instructors, in a bid to better protect vulnerable student drivers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a8f037624e70614c35efe8b66ab697d</guid></item><item><title>Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera being robbed overshadowed Matt Rowell's Brownlow Medal win, and could change the voting process forever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/afl-matt-rowell-nasiah-moment-brownlow-medal-voting-analysis/105804320</link><description>It is not often that the AFL's night of nights gets hijacked by a moment not involving the winner of the Brownlow Medal. This is exactly what took place when Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera was seemingly robbed in broad daylight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dfdde5b406fc68132f52c264d89b4c9</guid></item><item><title>Experts say paracetamol safe for pregnancy, no proof for autism link made by Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/trump-administration-links-autism-to-paracetamol-tga-says-safe/105803566</link><description>Australia's medicines regulator says paracetamol remains safe to use during pregnancy despite Donald Trump's administration linking its use to an increased risk of autism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9575c0f36522e77b42eccc5329990b40</guid></item><item><title>Paddleboarder gets too close to whales to film them, gets nudged away</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/paddleboarder-gets-too-close-to-whales-to-film-them/105801626</link><description>Drone footage shows a paddleboarder getting too close to film a southern right whale mother and calf, and being nudged away by the whale, off Point Ann.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccd42678f7b40484099efe1f5126dddd</guid></item><item><title>Devonport City Council approves memorial for victims of Hillcrest jumping castle tragedy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/devonport-council-hillcrest-memorial-approval-coles-beach/105804118</link><description>A proposed memorial at Coles Beach for the child victims of the Hillcrest jumping castle tragedy has been unanimously approved by the Devonport City Council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a5663271771429de2aa53e25b1c0e8e</guid></item><item><title>Women band together to create community for rural mums feeling lonely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/women-create-community-for-rural-mums-suffering-from-loneliness/105803024</link><description>After raising biological and foster children on a farm 60 kilometres from the nearest major town, Tracey Angwin says being part of a community is essential for rural mums.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da92ce9d728ad981483651f9d4c38527</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese joins nine world leaders recognising Palestinian statehood at historic UN summit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/anthony-albanese-united-nations-palestinian-statehood-conference/105804994</link><description>Australia's position has been matched by the UK, Canada, France, Andorra, Belgium, Luxembourg, Malta, Monaco and Portugal. But it is attracting fresh criticism from the White House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17600ad15d70de99a64a9c7966a2716a</guid></item><item><title>Deeming rates have increased after a five-year freeze. Here's how that could impact pension payments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/deeming-rate-freeze-ends-impact-on-pension-payments/105798966</link><description>The changes impact people on Centrelink payments who earn an income from financial assets, but pensioners are the biggest group to be affected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2a6081a58d1e888118022ad40f5fcfd</guid></item><item><title>As a doctor I'm choosing self-care over resilience</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/doctor-choosing-self-care-over-resilience/105728568</link><description>As a doctor who advocates for self-care, it took me a surprisingly long time to look after myself. Now I'm trying to be a good example for my patients and other doctors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96d1bd7d0cdf02ba7b181e19ec630701</guid></item><item><title>Childcare boss unsure if bonuses were docked over rise in safety breaches, inquiry told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/nsw-childcare-inquiry-ceo-questioned-over-bonuses/105805562</link><description>The CEO of Affinity Education Group appears at a state parliamentary inquiry into the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3ece1d8ebaeed33106cbc2f0f9066d1</guid></item><item><title>Experts say it is safe to use paracetamol during pregnancy and Trump's autism declaration is 'baseless'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/taking-paracetamol-during-pregnancy-does-not-cause-autism/105806092</link><description>Donald Trump's advice that pregnant women should limit the use of paracetamol in pregnancy has been criticised as "baseless". So what does it mean for you?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81c81571674ce6c676915af2ca81de9b</guid></item><item><title>Hakyung Lee found guilty over deaths of children found in Auckland storage unit suitcases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/nz-suitcase-verdict-hakyung-lee-trial/105658224</link><description>Hakyung Lee admitted to giving her two children an overdose of prescription medicine before changing her name and leaving New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76f153f712f5238ae870dbe2b49d9150</guid></item><item><title>Workers 'chuck a sickie' for holiday won in Sunshine Coast tourism campaign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/sunshine-coast-chuck-a-sickie-tourism-campaign/105724034</link><description>Marketing researchers hail the controversy of the "Sunshine sickie" tourism campaign as clever in encouraging people to book a beach holiday to combat burnout.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b69d871421c4f9b7db6e0a841c7cf588</guid></item><item><title>ICC prosecutors charge Phillipines' former leader Duterte with crimes against humanity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/icc-prosecutors-charge-duterte-3-counts-crimes-against-humanity/105806448</link><description>Former president of the Philippines, Rodrigo Duterte, is accused of being involved in the murder of dozens of people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">186fbab29d9070e10f640592f7123774</guid></item><item><title>ASIC accuses RACQ of misleading customers over insurance renewal notices in Federal Court action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/racq-insurance-premiums-regulator-action/105805622</link><description>The corporate watchdog alleges RACQ knowingly misled over 500,000 customers in insurance renewal notices since 2019.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f51ab0965ff2e6958953913e6360ca6b</guid></item><item><title>Father charged with manslaughter of seven-month-old son during camping trip in Queensland granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/qld-jaye-lee-walton-granted-bail-manslaughter-baby-son/105806058</link><description>Jaye Lee Walton, 42, has been charged with the manslaughter of his seven-month-old son Reef Hunter Walton in July.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1c7d659fa35821d1c36f548378d9a1f</guid></item><item><title>Northern Territory CLP government is reviewing sentencing laws. But will it change anything?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/jake-danby-hit-and-run-nt-sentencing-act-changing-clp-government/105801232</link><description>The case of hit-and-run driver Jake Danby has brought renewed focus to the NT's legal system and the problems it faces. But will changing sentencing laws help?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">181ee879b9bbed91231a5952dddf97e9</guid></item><item><title>Kevin Bacon on the importance of music, philanthropy and acting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/kevin-bacon-take-5-actor-music-philanthropy-interview/105793360</link><description>He's a prolific fixture on our screens who's famously six degrees from almost anyone. But Kevin Bacon is also a passionate musician and philanthropist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45104e05b24001759cca6f2985a81b97</guid></item><item><title>Why many Palestinians are underwhelmed by countries like Australia only now recognising statehood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/palestinians-react-to-statehood-recognition-australia-un/105805514</link><description>Australia joined nine other nations in formally recognising Palestinian statehood at the UN this week. But Palestinians have mixed feelings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57a8a3d3134b09135ecae50caa8ec2a8</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu plans to sign police deal with China while Nakamal pact with Australia is left hanging</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/china-vanuatu-police-agreement-equipment-training/105806934</link><description>Vanuatu declares it will sign a new policing agreement with China as the landmark Nakamal pact between Australia and the Pacific Island nation hangs in the balance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e015a5946bffafc3e5c33cd1d8fa895e</guid></item><item><title>Sean 'Diddy' Combs's lawyers pitch shorter prison term, therapy ahead of sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/sean-diddy-combs-lawyers-try-to-impose-14-month-sentence/105807480</link><description>The disgraced hip-hop mogul is expected to be sentenced on October 3.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a3eba260c2608ab5712fd146ba5a4b4</guid></item><item><title>Former AFLW player claims she was spat at as ex-players targeted at local leagues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/former-aflw-player-alleges-she-was-spat-at-local-grand-final/105807282</link><description>Former AFLW player claims she was spat at during her community grand final as ex-players are being targeted at local leagues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d6a2eaa36a8640a26a9d3c7ca905b54</guid></item><item><title>Unproven autism claims like Donald Trump's risk undoing decades of progress</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/trump-unproven-autism-claims-risk-undoing-decades-of-progress/105807344</link><description>The Trump administration's rhetoric only adds to the noise around autism and will make it harder for the community to feel understood and accepted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00fa47bf5ec49c44ed4dd1852e1689f4</guid></item><item><title>Sale of Australia's biggest sheep station at Rawlinna finally gets WA government approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/sale-of-australias-largest-sheep-station-at-rawlinna-station/105807106</link><description>The WA government has finally signed off on the sale of Australia's largest sheep station almost seven months after UK-based Consolidated Pastoral Company announced plans to buy Rawlinna Station.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">453798f3baadfee94d513f7ea0e7efc3</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie's spray at 'muppet', 'coward' Liberal colleagues after post bemoaning loss of Aussie car making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/andrew-hastie-car-making-coward-muppet-liberals/105808280</link><description>Senior Liberal Andrew Hastie has taken aim at colleagues who questioned a social media post where he bemoaned the loss of Australian car making, calling them "nameless cowards" and "muppets".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa8f233e21c3cb087597a2e4648810dd</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105809052</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2291dde89e5f6f2e800c553bd2118818</guid></item><item><title>Two teenagers sentenced to detention over attacks on Perth men lured via Grindr app</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/teenagers-detention-grindr-attacks-men-perth/105807670</link><description>Two "lawless" and "cruel" teenage boys who used social media to lure gay men to isolated locations in Perth before attacking them will remain in detention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04ac3ca89cb5b2ff893be3071e8400f4</guid></item><item><title>Denmark links drones at Copenhagen airport to hybrid attacks across Europe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/denmark-investigates-drone-activity-at-copenhagen-airport/105809166</link><description>Denmark links incident involving drones over its main airport to a series of recent suspected Russian drone incursions and other hybrid attacks across Europe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebee7e7802e9046c39907e2c6a3957b7</guid></item><item><title>Super Typhoon Ragasa lashes Taiwan, with at least 14 dead and 129 missing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/super-typhoon-ragasa-taiwan-dead-missing/105809264</link><description>The most powerful storm so far in 2025 is now heading towards the Chinese mainland, prompting widespread disruption and warnings of sea surges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e86c797982ae3107e7d7d8203132df06</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump uses United Nations speech to lay out the US's complaints with the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/united-nations-general-assembly-donald-trump-speech/105809190</link><description>Donald Trump uses a speech at the UN to criticise US allies' moves to recognise Palestine and chastise the international community over a range of other American grievances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">251d1ac533cc88fd01a9540772aff365</guid></item><item><title>Russia systematically torturing Ukrainian civilians, UN says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/russia-systematically-torturing-ukrainian-civilians-un-says/105809316</link><description>The report is based on detailed interviews with 215 former detainees captured since Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b3ec3854b230344943aa0ea9a1c50f</guid></item><item><title>Incoming triple-0 reforms may not have helped prevent Optus failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/triple-0-reforms-may-not-have-helped-optus-failure/105807524</link><description>The federal government has yet to pass legislation to empower a new coordinator for the emergency services line, but experts say tougher conditions are needed on the telco itself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">196d665b157a51d6ce3440ca5be81bfc</guid></item><item><title>Record number of calls to poisons hotlines for children ingesting melatonin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/melatonin-poisons-hotline-kidshealth/105802406</link><description>The ABC has analysed data from poisons hotlines across the country, revealing almost 1,500 calls were made about children taking melatonin last year, a dramatic rise on previous figures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6379f1180fb83dd59536f7b7017c4f87</guid></item><item><title>Could artificial intelligence and a universal basic income eliminate 'meaningless jobs'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/will-we-need-a-universal-basic-income-to-deal-with-ai-job-losses/105747954</link><description>COVID showed just how "fragile" our economic security is. As artificial intelligence potentially takes jobs from humans, a universal basic income might be a solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5953e2ae7f84df41d0ff5021a284652b</guid></item><item><title>Ryan Routh faces life in prison after guilty verdict in Donald Trump assassination attempt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ryan-routh-guilty-of-donald-trump-assassination-attempt/105809490</link><description>A man accused of trying to assassinate Donald Trump at his Florida golf course last year has been found guilty on all charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0214a8b817cf4108f24678a4dba1f80a</guid></item><item><title>Australians are moving to Tasmania to escape climate change, but the island state is not immune</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/australians-moving-to-tasmania-to-escape-climate-change/105785996</link><description>Jack and Anna swapped the humidity of Queensland for chilly days in Tasmania, but is Tasmania really the climate refuge many think it is?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0ff7fbad477aed99626b4746b82c14c</guid></item><item><title>Holbrook Landcare wins Bob Hawke award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/holbrook-landcare-wins-bob-hawke-award/105806834</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebdc5b27d20f0774f792387b024bec7b</guid></item><item><title>Holbrook Landcare Network wins 2025 Bob Hawke Award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/holbrook-landcare-network-wins-2025-bob-hawke-award/105803040</link><description>A landcare network at "the forefront of technology" has won the 2025 Bob Hawke Award for its innovative approach to sustainable farming practices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">704bd35d01dd4bdc8154c105eb49b76a</guid></item><item><title>Canola crop invaders seeking social media selfies told to stay off farms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/canola-crop-invaders-told-to-stop-trespassing-for-selfies/105802230</link><description>Selfie hunters seeking the perfect social media photo among flowering canola are putting their safety and growers' livelihoods at risk, farmers say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c76b7d5ced248e1d7be9cfa5c171c969</guid></item><item><title>How climate change impacted the 2025 snow season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/climate-change-impacted-2025-snow-season/105808698</link><description>The general sentiment is Australia's ski resorts are coming to the end of a bumper snow season — but is this evaluation accurate, or just positive spin after the dismal 2023 and 2024 seasons?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d83586cda83a6d18a50afafa5ab2f844</guid></item><item><title>NT government open to subdividing purpose-built State Square Art Gallery in Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nt-government-open-to-state-square-art-gallery-subdivide-darwin/105807672</link><description>A leading figure in Australia's art world has criticised the Northern Territory government for considering splitting up the lease for a building designed as a major new art gallery, describing the plan as "pure madness".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cea270549341f3bb40e1fafe548161cf</guid></item><item><title>Video record of violence and racism at Purnim Bears, Noorat country football grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/violence-racism-of-80s-country-victoria-football-grand-final/105741080</link><description>The Purnim Bears were supposed to be the feel-good story of country football — a team uniting black and white communities. But their 1987 grand final was so violent it ended with their expulsion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">231bb9fc7a4848fb3114f306c75ce3e0</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine can win back all territory lost to Russia, Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ukraine-can-win-back-all-territory-lost-to-russia-trump-says/105809578</link><description>The US president criticised Russia on the sidelines of the UN General Assembly, saying it had been fighting "aimlessly" in a war that a "real military power" would have won in less than a week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51fff57c3ffcb071ce802513857b4a30</guid></item><item><title>ASX falls ahead of inflation data, Optus to investigate triple-0 failure — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/asx-markets-business-live-news/105809708</link><description>Optus launches an independent review of last week's triple-0 failure, with chief executive Stephen Rue saying human error meant processes weren't followed during the outage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e7944a8068d04ed1894186577c1f7dc</guid></item><item><title>Purnim Bears and Noorat in the 1987 Grand Final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/lowres-hits-compile-purnim-bears/105809790</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">374e9b7e43683512d21efa87c2aa761e</guid></item><item><title>Queensland speed skydiver Natisha Dingle shows off her impressive skills.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/speed-skydiver-natisha-dingle-shows-off-her-impressive-skills/105807064</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c809122700c1bf91a2b261a16e110608</guid></item><item><title>Australian speed skydiver hangs on to title of fastest woman in the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/natisha-dingle-wins-fai-world-cup-speed-skydiving-title/105805486</link><description>Jumping out of planes and freefalling at nearly 500 kilometres per hour is "addictive" for Queensland woman Natisha Dingle, who has just set a new Oceania speed record in the sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6dae41d360c4eeda58220eedaf6442a</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's meeting with Trump matters for AUKUS and the role of the US in the Asia-Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/anthony-albanese-donald-trump-meeting/105801298</link><description>Trump clearly disagrees with Albanese on Palestine and the reality of climate change, but it's not on the scale of the beef he has with other countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1daf71c6599467c19439c0e23875de0e</guid></item><item><title>Warragul man knocks back dream job after NDIS funding for van rejected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ndis-rejects-van-man-needs-to-drive-to-dream-job/105762830</link><description>Josh Evans, who uses a wheelchair, had to turn down a job with the Bureau of Meteorology because he was unable to get NDIS funding for a vehicle to drive himself to work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21c25c4b57843d7697e914107db94243</guid></item><item><title>Trump claims paracetamol link to autism. Five experts explain what's wrong with that statement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/what-the-experts-are-saying-about-paracetamol-use-lead-to-autism/105806230</link><description>Some leading Australian experts in medicine, autism research and obstetrics say the US president's claims are "a misreading of science," or at worst, "a misuse". Here's why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bffee58bd319bdb466db1eb8559f629b</guid></item><item><title>Why the legacy of the 2023 NRL grand final hangs over the Broncos and Panthers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/panthers-broncos-nrl-preliminary-final-grand-final-cleary/105809026</link><description>On Sunday, the Broncos and Panthers will face off in the finals for the first time since the 2023 grand final, but the memory of that night still hangs over both sides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad8624f8c74a64751af52bbcd1e11c56</guid></item><item><title>Sandy Brondello axed by WNBA side New York Liberty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/sandy-brondello-axed-by-wnba-side-new-york-liberty/105810534</link><description>Australian basketball coach Sandy Brondello is let go by the New York Liberty after a disappointing first-round exit from the WNBA play-offs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a4504d3bbba4c100278133bdd4d6055</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann seeks funding to pay for legal representation over raids at his home in 2024</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/bruce-lehrmann-seeks-funds-for-legal-representation-over-raids/105809920</link><description>Former Liberal staffer Bruce Lehrmann launches Federal Court action seeking funding for legal representation at a National Anti-Corruption Commission hearing after raids on his home in June last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">749a230c4ad7fe395ea22940c47b8259</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fullback Andrew Kellaway ruled out of first Bledisloe Cup Test match against All Blacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/wallabies-andrew-kellaway-ruled-out-bledisloe-cup-all-blacks/105810670</link><description>Wallabies fullback Andrew Kellaway will miss Saturday's Bledisloe Cup Test match against the All Blacks in Auckland, ruled out with a calf strain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11b979e7ef790b13cc2880a8a193f4dd</guid></item><item><title>Canberra golf course redevelopments providing both much-needed housing and financial lifelines for struggling clubs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/golf-course-redevelopments-providing-housing-financial-lifelines/105799100</link><description>With the ACT government pushing for greater urban density, golf courses in inner Canberra suburbs are becoming attractive sites for redevelopment to provide much-needed housing and a way for struggling clubs to bolster their budgets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b488a99ab4311911d8fa6f87e596dc4c</guid></item><item><title>Optus parent company Singtel apologises for triple-0 outage linked to multiple deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/optus-singtel-apologises-for-triple-0-outage/105810296</link><description>Optus's parent company says it will "ensure a thorough investigation of this incident to prevent any future recurrence".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4603051f8c7a42c9b44e671ff971d0d</guid></item><item><title>Man behind iconic ABC TV programs, Graham White, dies aged 93</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/graham-white-abc-tv-and-radio-pioneer-dies-at-93/105806806</link><description>Graham White was a pioneer of Australian radio and television and played a key role in the creation of numerous television series, including A Big Country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54c9a84115c56f73f0923751c300a0e1</guid></item><item><title>When is the 2025 AFL grand final? Here's what time it starts and where to watch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/when-is-the-afl-grand-final-time-where-to-watch-explained/105809976</link><description>Wondering what time the AFL grand final starts and how you can watch it live? We've got you covered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b35be59cc10e4e0032348864c66bd1c7</guid></item><item><title>Despite past controversy, NSW Police commissioner Mal Lanyon has a strong backing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nsw-police-commissioner-mal-lanyon-premier-chris-minns-analysis/105810774</link><description>For newly-announced Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon, Wednesday morning would have been both one of his proudest moments, and his most uncomfortable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed72f9bcc7ce20d2d722b8b43d539719</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel returns, addressing Charlie Kirk and 'un-American' axing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/jimmy-kimmel-returns-thanking-supporters-speaks-to-free-speech/105808410</link><description>Despite the late-night host's return, several US ABC affiliates did not air the episode, excluding an estimated one-quarter of American households.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac8b78a8e557c0d2a91d42ed04e2eed</guid></item><item><title>Family suspects foul play in Noosa man Byron Dumschat's death in a Bali villa pool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/family-suspects-foul-play-in-bali-death-noosa-man-byron-dumschat/105809846</link><description>An Australian family is asking why Indonesian police allowed three Australian witnesses to return home without being interviewed after their 23-year-old son died on the Indonesian holiday resort island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4e8e32abe23c1a44f62c5e3f023e2a2</guid></item><item><title>How #RedundancyDiaries are busting the stigma of being let go</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/busting-the-stigma-on-redundancy-by-sharing-online/105751880</link><description>Camille says being made redundant was hard, so she began sharing her experiences on TikTok hoping to help others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69e9a0930ebbcb9805519c817968e9ee</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's changed stance on Ukraine could be a challenge for Vladimir Putin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/donald-trump-ukraine-nato-comments-a-challenge-to-vladimir-putin/105810170</link><description>If Donald Trump actually means what he has just said — that NATO countries have a right to shoot down any Russian jets in their airspace — the US president may be contracting out a serious counteroffensive against Russian aggression to NATO countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c624737442bcb04137b18db123e6997</guid></item><item><title>Report recommends gondola access to Jenolan Caves near the Blue Mountains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/report-recommends-gondola-access-to-jenolan-caves/105809918</link><description>A report recommends building a gondola to the tune of $44 million to bypass catastrophic road failures that have long plagued the Jenolan Caves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27aa154744525803a917b0b5069cde36</guid></item><item><title>Elon Musk's father, Errol Musk, accused of abusing five of his children over three decades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/errol-musk-elon-father-abuse-allegations/105810162</link><description>Multiple police reports, social workers and family members uncover the allegations against 79-year-old Errol Musk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b128f012c363aa69849c2a916828663b</guid></item><item><title>Mount Isa man charged with more than 70 child sex offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/mount-isa-man-charged-child-sex-offences/105811958</link><description>Police charge a 40-year-old man in Mount Isa and allege the offences occurred over 25 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f170f1084a78ce506347bb313d68dd8b</guid></item><item><title>Why did the UN escalator stop after Donald and Melania Trump stepped on it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/donald-melania-trump-escalator-teleprompter-un-marcon-call/105810256</link><description>Footage of the US president and his wife's reactions to the mishap was shared widely on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87fdb12fe7af401b7964018acf19bc5f</guid></item><item><title>Escalator stops operating as Donald and Melania Trump step on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/escalator-stops-operating-as-donald-and-melania-trump-step-on/105811110</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5b98bfb1abe65dbbbc5d0927519eed6</guid></item><item><title>Doctor who lost daughter to brain cancer receives grant in race to clinical trials</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/doctor-receives-grant-to-continue-brain-cancer-research/105810368</link><description>A professor who lost his daughter to brain cancer in 2018 is hopeful the research to find a cure in children is just five years away from clinical trials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc0272343034af8958b1ec9f51c4c20f</guid></item><item><title>Optus admits procedural failure before outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/optus-admits-procedural%C2%A0failure-before-outage%C2%A0/105811978</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b84c417046bbfc3acea16532e90a47cf</guid></item><item><title>What Hollywood gets wrong about music teachers on screen and how this impacts Australian teachers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/hollywood-portrayals-music-teachers-impact-australians/105803248</link><description>On-screen portrayals of music teachers like School Of Rock are full of cliches. Researchers say this might be stopping more Australians from taking up the profession.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9038906989bc595b89e85f5f95a323fd</guid></item><item><title>Optus to pay $100m fine, as crisis engulfing Australia's second biggest telco continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/optus-fined-100-million-for-sales-misconduct/105810174</link><description>In enforcing the fine today, the Federal Court's Justice Patrick O'Sullivan described the company's conduct as "extremely serious" and "appalling".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5b8ef086dc95c25b9efd2536b1850d6</guid></item><item><title>Tesla's self-driving technology is available in Australia, but road rules differ nationwide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/tesla-self-driving-technology-rules-differ-around-australia/105808104</link><description>Owners of late model Teslas can now access the company's self-driving technology. But the rules for how drivers can use it differ around the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">191d278dfe60ecd4ddb9b581b2e3730f</guid></item><item><title>AFL boss hints at Brownlow voting shake-up after Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/afl-boss-hits-at-brownlow-voting-shake-up-after-controversy/105812086</link><description>Voting for the Brownlow Medal has been a hot topic again in the wake of Monday night's count, with the AFL open to letting umpires have access to statistics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5d9c582b445942c6c11e6f1591db872</guid></item><item><title>Concerns Launceston City Council could give away Birchalls CBD site it bought for $8.8m</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/launceston-council-developer-plans-for-birchalls-building/105809796</link><description>Launceston City Council bought the historic Birchalls building for $8.8 million five years ago. A ratepayer association says it has learnt of a proposal to give it away "for nothing".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57bb6bb59e636d4105fd48c27dcdbaca</guid></item><item><title>Kindergarten cleaner who allegedly filmed children in bathroom faces more charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/kindergarten-cleaner-who-secretly-filmed-children-in-toilet/105811222</link><description>Prosecutors have flagged more potential charges for the Victorian kindergarten cleaner accused of secretly filming children in a bathroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a0e03375009bb4e55aea4b0a8b01d7e</guid></item><item><title>Electric vehicle-to-grid trial in Exmouth generates promising results for state power distributor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/electric-vehicle-to-grid-v2g-trial-in-exmouth-promising/105811868</link><description>State distributor Horizon Power says a trial of bi-directional charging with electric vehicles to both supplement the grid and take up excess power, known as V2G, has proved a success.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c657879091e2ce95be5b33b932b29f12</guid></item><item><title>Hockeyroos legend Katrina Powell quits as coach after two Olympic campaigns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/hockeyroos-legend-katrina-powell-quits-as-coach/105812958</link><description>Hockeyroos great Katrina Powell has quit as coach of Australia's women's team after rebuilding a criticised culture in the elite program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3362fa20010b71b5d18e66dc93b4c83</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel's tearful return to television</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/jimmy-kimmels-tearful-return-to-television/105813120</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a81db5d10a960eaeac1fd927151b17ae</guid></item><item><title>Christopher John Sullivan sentenced for stabbing partner Pauline Mountford in Gooseberry Hill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/christopher-john-sullivan-domestic-violence-sentencing/105812460</link><description>A 74-year-old man who slashed his partner's throat in their Perth Hills home is sentenced to 10 years in jail over the near-fatal attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b34ba7512fda4d4c878ff84234b915f6</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's gripe-filled United Nations speech unsurprising, Foreign Minister Penny Wong says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/penny-wong-responds-to-donald-trump-un-speech-albanese-meeting/105809070</link><description>Foreign Minister Penny Wong says the speech US President Donald Trump delivered at the UN is simply more of the same from him and "consistent" with his views and actions since being elected for a second term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d44f8f03841ac14753961232f5608cf4</guid></item><item><title>Former A-League footballers Clayton Lewis and Kearyn Baccus sentenced over betting scam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/a-league-betting-clayton-lewis-kearyn-baccus-sentencing/105811400</link><description>Both players were paid $10,000 each to intentionally get themselves yellow cards while playing for Macarthur FC against Sydney FC to influence overseas bets on the game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4d047a9369284c7941aaf5cccc0a654</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast posts record tourism spend as mayor warns of public transport 'time bomb'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/record-gold-coast-tourism-spend-prompts-public-transport-warning/105811046</link><description>International tourists are spending more than ever on the Gold Coast, but mayor Tom Tate says the city faces a public transport "time bomb" that could ruin its reputation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c6df1c0bdc0bbebd9425d3678241991</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of Australians fighting 'cruel' battle for COVID vaccine injury compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/fight-for-compensation-for-covid-19-vaccination-injuries/105808630</link><description>Thousands of Australians who were injured by COVID vaccines say they are facing a 'cruel and complex' system to get compensation from the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc0182bdb4d37c0f24454edad8263808</guid></item><item><title>Productivity Commission to review state and territory GST deal, including $60b WA windfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/australia-gst-review-under-review-wa-gst-deal/105813372</link><description>Western Australia's GST deal, expected to cost the Commonwealth $60 billion by 2029, will form part of a review by the Australian Productivity Commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b22ae8ce5ff8afaa0d867d88f15dc4f0</guid></item><item><title>Australian War Memorial updates Ben Roberts-Smith display to mention recent High Court rejection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/war-memorial-updates-ben-roberts-smith-exhibit-again/105813004</link><description>The war memorial's revised display now mentions Ben Roberts-Smith's failed bid to the High Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9edc3cc4a1fb29debf8f915faecacf6</guid></item><item><title>Former police officer Stephen Michael Calcutt pleads guilty to filming teenagers in shower and up skirt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/former-police-officer-pleads-guilty-filming-teenager/105812714</link><description>The former sergeant also filmed up another teenager's skirt and had a number of cartoons depicting children in sexual situations on a hard drive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d016f9d7ccabbb8651e7cb9fc607919e</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Lions trust Lachie Neale to make right call ahead of AFL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/brisbane-lions-lachie-neale-right-afl-grand-final-call/105813604</link><description>All eyes are on Lachie Neale's bid to make a remarkable grand final return from injury, and his teammates will back him to make the right call.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b33183c69e679601c3ad83c2c662b7b</guid></item><item><title>Uber ordered to pay lost wages in 'landmark' unfair deactivation case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/uber-unfair-deactivation-case/105812068</link><description>The Fair Work Commission has ordered Uber to repay lost wages to a driver it deemed was unfairly deactivated from the rideshare platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f3574450e42cae819f14881001f5399</guid></item><item><title>Murder trial hears final arguments from trio accused of 2022 stabbing death of David Jenkins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/trial-of-men-accused-of-david-jenkins-murder-final-arguments/105805736</link><description>The trial of two brothers and another man accused of the stabbing murder of a man in Tasmania's north in 2022 hears there is "no serious dispute" that Luke Shaw "was the person who killed" David Jenkins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">621a1d67e3bb519003eb4e577b718a6e</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105813848</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbeee129e3122b06287a24ba6aa752ed</guid></item></channel></rss>