<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:59:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Calls to ban machetes as elderly Territorians terrorised in their own homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/stateline-nt-calls-ban-machetes-as-elderly-territorians-hurt/105855298</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50227819e4fb3d1211eb8ade2e674398</guid></item><item><title>Outback businesses raise concerns about Services Australia's Centrepay reforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/outback-wa-retailers-worried-about-centrepay-reforms/105844344</link><description>Business owners worry major changes to a buy now, pay later system used by about 500,000 social security recipients will cause a raft of issues when it begins next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df02be8a6f258116a4f810bdcb01fba1</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, day one: Essendon firm on Zach Merrett as Carlton set to play hardball with Charlie Curnow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/afl-trade-period-day-one-live-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca/105853514</link><description>Essendon once again firmly states that captain Zach Merrett will not leave the Bombers as all 18 clubs begin the wheeling and dealing on the first day of the AFL's trade period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf92b2ca3ab4ca2c9aa8406b4938bc0c</guid></item><item><title>Mount Everest rescue underway after snowstorm traps hundreds of trekkers in Tibet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/mount-everest-rescue-hundreds-of-trekkers-escape-snowstorm/105855262</link><description>Local villagers and rescue teams help hikers stranded on Mount Everest after a snowstorm pummels the Himalayas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b076459219cbd10758599c14f0f0a0cb</guid></item><item><title>Search underway for 76-year-old Tasmanian man missing near Hollybank</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/76yo-man-missing-hollybank-tasmania/105855372</link><description>The man has not been seen since he was searching for his car in dense bushland in northern Tasmania on Sunday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">081b7df7b801abe0b02a61dcdb6ab3a3</guid></item><item><title>The chicken and egg dilemma fuelling house prices – 6 October 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/the-chicken-and-egg-dilemma-fuelling-house-prices-/105856110</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af996de1ea6ee0eff39713353a3ab126</guid></item><item><title>Defiant Ange Postecoglou says he will fight back as Nottingham Forest lose again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/ange-postecoglou-defiant-after-another-loss/105856146</link><description>Ange Postecoglou fires up in a post-match press conference after Nottingham Forest lose to Newcastle United 2-0.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">628a8faa39f11e61f1e59c5dc3df9228</guid></item><item><title>Clients of Melbourne builder MJ Harris Group lose life savings as company goes bust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/melbourne-builder-mike-harris-under-investigation/105849496</link><description>More than a dozen customers of MJ Harris Group have told the ABC they have been left significantly out of pocket after the company went into liquidation this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46d68729bac68ea68b04eb0537f41503</guid></item><item><title>Judge blocks Trump from deploying National Guard troops to Oregon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/judge-blocks-donald-trump-from-deploying-national-guard-oregon/105855384</link><description>A federal judge temporarily blocks Donald Trump from deploying Californian National Guard troops to Portland, after earlier blocking the US President from mobilising local troops in Oregon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcc61c937e41ec58121335fd63529179</guid></item><item><title>Reece Walsh's NRL grand final heroics with Broncos rewarded with Kangaroos call-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/nrl-kangaroos-squad-ashes-reece-walsh-broncos-grand-final/105856380</link><description>Recognition of Reece Walsh's breathtaking performance in the NRL grand final continues, with the Brisbane Broncos hero set to make his Test debut for Australia later this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8158c6162030b6da5ff5baca267e3263</guid></item><item><title>What is task paralysis and how do you overcome it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/what-is-task-paralysis-and-how-to-overcome-it/105816676</link><description>Experts say feeling stuck or frozen when trying to start or complete a task can be the body's response to overwhelm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">148760b52f8431484adce2b1a2fde63d</guid></item><item><title>Broncos great Ali Brigginshaw to co-captain Jillaroos after NRLW grand final victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/nrlw-australia-jillaroos-brisbane-broncos-ali-brigginshaw/105856578</link><description>Ali Brigginshaw is named as a Jillaroos co-captain after helping steer the Brisbane Broncos to their fourth NRLW premiership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf319e012e91eeee866e7fc0a592b128</guid></item><item><title>As the AFLW begins to even out, North Melbourne remains untouchable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/north-melbourne-aflw-untouchable-as-comp-evens-out/105856458</link><description>North Melbourne claims its 20th win in a row as it looks to go undefeated for another season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4eb6269951bcaae08f99f7462a32cef</guid></item><item><title>Broncos star Pat Carrigan says a wooden spoon from 2020 helped motivate him for the grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/pat-carrigan-on-wooden-spoon-motivating-2025-nrl-grand-final-win/105856516</link><description>Fans left wooden spoons on Brisbane's training ground in 2020 — it was a move that helped motivate Pat Carrigan to greatness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3da51a345783afff5c94b8cb122d1f73</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand pays $5.3 million to Samoa after sinking navy ship Manawanui on pristine reef</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/new-zealand-pays-compensation-samoa-manawanui-spill/105856488</link><description>The New Zealand government says it has done "the right thing" in offering a $5.3 million compensation payout to the Samoan government after its navy sunk a ship on a pristine reef off the Pacific island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99f964ebb4c46ee11f26209f97fd7525</guid></item><item><title>How much are NRL and NRLW premiership rings worth? What do they look like?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/how-much-nrl-nrlw-premiership-rings-worth-what-do-the-look-like/105856106</link><description>The men's rings are valued at $15,000, while the women's rings have a price tag of $10,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63575b695f4173281ef2a75ac53c102b</guid></item><item><title>Why Kangaroos coach Kevin Walters is looking to the past ahead of Ashes series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/kangaroo-squad-ashes-kevin-walters-reece-walsh/105857268</link><description>New Kangaroos coach Kevin Walters was part of an era where the green and gold jersey was the highest honour rugby league could offer and ahead of the return of the Ashes it's a legacy he's desperate to pass down to his players.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58a50a4f00610fe11bdd54dcdff1814e</guid></item><item><title>Roosters forward Aliyah Nasio sent to judiciary over NRLW grand final brawl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/nrlw-grand-final-aliyah-nasio-roosters-judiciary/105857520</link><description>Sydney Roosters forward Aliyah Nasio is facing a ban for throwing a punch in the brawl at the conclusion of the NRLW grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d859f0db5c7d1d85425a636873ed3736</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne hands Ashes selectors reminder with Sheffield Shield century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/marnus-labuschagne-sheffield-shield-scores/105857408</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne has hit his first century in red ball cricket for over a year just one month out from the first Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a176bd65e86e8cee22777c8998188414</guid></item><item><title>Dead hikers yet to be identified as locals warn of High Country danger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/mount-bogong-hiker-deaths-warning/105856534</link><description>Locals in Victoria's High Country are warning visitors about the unpredictable conditions in the alpine region, after the bodies of two women were discovered near Falls Creek.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18a153de7905cf24421857133c950682</guid></item><item><title>Homeschool registrations are rising and policy needs to catch up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/australians-homeschooling-registrations-growth-queensland/105857486</link><description>Primary school homeschooling registrations in Queensland grew by 110 per cent from 2021 to 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2da6ac568e30445c88402c2dd8b19cc</guid></item><item><title>Australia and Papua New Guinea sign landmark alliance vowing to defend each other in conflict</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/australia-png-sign-defence-treaty-of-mutual-alliance/105858244</link><description>PNG and Australia formally sign a landmark new defence treaty, elevating the bilateral relationship between the two countries to an alliance and agreeing to "act to meet the common danger" if the other is attacked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">614af408f76065f8117ef33a6b854264</guid></item><item><title>Broncos shares surge 40 per cent after Grand Final win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/broncos-shares-surge-40-after-grand-final-win/105858608</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb9f530fa3b53960f57deb774eadfed4</guid></item><item><title>York family honours late son with tractor museum to fund cancer research</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/oliver-crane-tractor-museum-raises-money-for-cancer-research/105848104</link><description>Oliver Crane was diagnosed with bone cancer and died at age 17. This week, his family opened a vintage tractor museum in his memory to help raise money for cancer research.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13789f2997dab8a6f7214155c926b1c1</guid></item><item><title>Timothy Hunt convicted of murdering Tony Rowe after month-long Supreme Court trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/nt-darwin-man-timothy-hunt-convicted-murder-tony-rowe/105842404</link><description>Darwin man Timothy Hunt has been convicted of murdering Tony Rowe, whose remains were found on the city's outskirts in May 2023, one year after he was reported missing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bca0b60fc6589bb7b45b48088fbc19a5</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle Yowies' dual glory in 2025 Koori Knockout rugby league finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/yowies-win-2025-koori-knockout-rugby-league-competitions/105857270</link><description>Yowies playmaker Kyle Laybutt kicks a mammoth field goal to seal victory in the men's final, while the Yowies women keep a clean sheet in their grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d04374ba9775987a358b27b3e554bf57</guid></item><item><title>England's 2003 Rugby World Cup winner Lewis Moody reveals MND diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/england-rugby-world-cup-winner-lewis-moodey-mnd-diagnosis/105859128</link><description>Lewis Moody, a former England rugby captain who helped his side win the 2003 World Cup, has been diagnosed with Motor Neurone Disease.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0125bfc995e3b0a490581c1e722fb8f3</guid></item><item><title>Whakaari eruption inquest hears from frustrated families calling for answers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/whakaari-white-island-inquest-families-want-answers/105859164</link><description>A close family member of a tour guide who died in the Whakaari White Island eruption in 2019 has given an emotional statement as the inquest into the tragedy continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f4b4fa1270dc88d6b858f6039ee3eb6</guid></item><item><title>Greta Thunberg deported as Australian flotilla activists detained by Israel allege physical abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/australian-flotilla-activists-allege-israeli-authorities-abuse/105858942</link><description>Climate campaigner Greta Thunberg and more than 100 activists from the Gaza aid flotilla have been deported to Greece and Slovakia, Israel says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b714cb3ea153979a61059537e52b1de6</guid></item><item><title>Papua New Guinea may sit out potential conflict between Australia and China despite Pukpuk defence treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/png-may-sit-out-australia-china-conflict-despite-defence-pct/105859432</link><description>Papua New Guinea Prime Minister James Marape says there is a "high possibility" the country would not enter a conflict involving Australia and China, despite having signed a mutual defence treaty with its southern neighbour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59feb7c5420f2241d7bceb57053d4049</guid></item><item><title>Monday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105859530</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">506757f396e017cb4299581c67727f19</guid></item><item><title>Losing Streak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/losing-streak/105859060</link><description>Four Corners is the home of Australian investigative journalism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ef84904ddd616d8cc62e4f9670ac635</guid></item><item><title>Perth Royal Show attendance slumps to eight-year low</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/perth-royal-show-attendance-slumps-to-10-year-low/105857262</link><description>Attendance at this year's Perth Royal Show has hit an eight-year low, as organisers blame "heavy downpours" amid complaints from vendors about a lack of support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4db393861a1dcdbd2e0e82e56471da9</guid></item><item><title>English author Jilly Cooper, writer of The Rutshire Chronicles, dies at age 88</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/author-jilly-cooper-dies-at-age-88/105859754</link><description>The author was best known for The Rutshire Chronicles, including the novel Rivals, which was recently adapted into a Disney+ series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e8674f08b263feb4ef22338f75cf54a</guid></item><item><title>Trio of scientists win Nobel Prize in Medicine for 'discoveries concerning peripheral immune tolerance'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/scientists-win-nobel-prize-medicine-for-immune-system-work/105859742</link><description>The Nobel Prize for Medicine has been given to three scientists for discovering how our immune systems protect us from microbes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9af5df2f41780faee103603c8684e8f8</guid></item><item><title>At least 63 people killed in Indonesia school collapse disaster in Java</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/indonesia-school-collapse-kills-at-least-63-people/105859952</link><description>The number of people killed in the disaster could still rise, with some half a dozen children still unaccounted for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb0eaac458f1bcf709a21c7c72610701</guid></item><item><title>TasTAFE to remove subsidy for lab training, design, media and courses that 'don't align with jobs market'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/tastafe-course-fee-subsidies-cut-tasmania-government/105858120</link><description>Tasmanian TAFE graduates worry as some locally taught courses that helped them forge a career may disappear as the cost to study them increases dramatically.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4047a4692b67df396d06e8970f44855e</guid></item><item><title>Two years since Gaza war began, some Israelis feel 'reckoning' is coming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/israel-gaza-war-impacts-on-society-after-two-years/105856702</link><description>After two years of war, a fractured but defiant Israel is struggling to assert itself at home and abroad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80339c0e16865d228ed71373da828c3b</guid></item><item><title>New data shows Australia's extreme weather losses among highest in world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/ica-finds-australia-extreme-weather-loss-among-highest-in-world/105831772</link><description>Amid more extreme weather events, parametric insurance — described as a bet on the weather —is on the rise. It is now being touted as a possible solution for Australians, who have some of the highest insurance losses in the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9275227f9aab52ca7138cba5646e848b</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley cites trans offender case in argument for minimum jail terms for child exploitation crimes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/coalition-minimum-sentencing-child-abuse-trans-debate-maloney/105858528</link><description>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley raises the case of a trans child abuser as she seeks to pressure the Albanese government to create mandatory minimum jail terms for child exploitation offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55234471d2b5596a81b4a31577fdb22d</guid></item><item><title>Telcos face Canberra grilling as Triple Zero Custodian legislation is set to be introduced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/telcos-meet-anika-wells-as-triple-zero-custodian-enshrined/105859926</link><description>New legislation will be introduced to enshrine the powers of the Triple Zero Custodian into law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbd4f5a5b9e0d8c6adaec44f1d1c4ed5</guid></item><item><title>Sole survivor of Bochara fatal crash was behind the wheel, coroner rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/bochara-crash-coroners-report-four-dead/105857490</link><description>A coroner determines that the sole survivor of a crash that killed four people at Bochara was behind the wheel during the incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a161f6794eb7803f4c4104e51e7211a9</guid></item><item><title>What the future holds for Sydney's former psychiatric hospital sites with storied pasts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/future-for-sydney-former-psychiatric-hospital-sites-callan-park/105829904</link><description>The challenge of transforming a major piece of Sydney's public space from a former mental health hospital to an "iconic urban parkland" is a delicate dance for the state government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82ae7a0e643192e5b9a78433c9d0443f</guid></item><item><title>Expert cautions people using AI as search for missing boy in SA outback scaled back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/gus-missing-boy-facebook-ai-misinformation/105856594</link><description>Users have reported Facebook's AI search has shown incorrect information about four-year-old Gus who remains missing in SA's outback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f85f82b8a98c3c714a1862384b881823</guid></item><item><title>Victorian couple sues Barwon Health over delayed diagnosis of rare 'flesh-eating disease' necrotising fasciitis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/barwon-health-sued-after-victorian-man-loses-left-eye-infection/105858504</link><description>A young father who lost his eye after contracting a rare infection is suing the hospital that treated him, alleging it ignored his requests to investigate his condition properly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4cdc819daa534b4f6bc329ec4854437</guid></item><item><title>Songbird heard for first time since 1890s in WA park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/noisy-scrub-birds-return-to-west-cape-howe-national-park/105856064</link><description>The song of the noisy scrub-bird is being heard in WA's West Cape Howe National Park again, bringing joy to bird enthusiasts everywhere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f07fbc8949558b0b0002a157cdb1da49</guid></item><item><title>Bulk-billing rates remain low as GPs spend longer with patients, survey finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/bulk-billing-low-as-gps-spend-longer-with-patients-racgp/105856332</link><description>An industry survey finds GPs are managing conditions typically handled by specialists due to high costs and only 12 per cent can afford to bulk-bill all patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c55f5a7f1ee185ba2bc0949994701619</guid></item><item><title>Singapore PM Lawrence Wong signals 'shared interests' with Australia and desire to expand military ties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/singapore-wants-to-expand-its-military-ties-with-australia/105856094</link><description>Singapore wants to expand its military ties with Australia, including through a greater Australian troop presence in the island state as part of an upgraded trade and defence relationship, according to Prime Minister Lawrence Wong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2d4433b0af1b549d254f001a101dc03</guid></item><item><title>Drought conditions forcing kangaroo mobs to descend on farms, consuming scarce resources</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/drought-kangaroo-populations-impacting-farmers-eating-pastures/105833458</link><description>Farmers are calling for a cull of kangaroos, which they say are being forced onto farmland by drought and dry conditions and consuming what little feed and water they have.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">253309d270a15dbf6688f4cc91faa6e9</guid></item><item><title>Darwin ship lift project cost blowout rivalling Snowy 2.0, economist says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/nt-taxpayers-billion-dollar-ship-lift-pearling-giant-paspaley/105856034</link><description>It’s taken 10 years, blown out by hundreds of millions of dollars, and is still nowhere near becoming operational. Now there are calls for the Darwin ship lift project to be scrapped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c825f0a31c74d4890b2904a10fbbc5ed</guid></item><item><title>Wildlife photographer Rob Blakers pleads guilty to trespassing on Robbins Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/rob-blakers-pleads-guilty-to-trespassing-charges-robbins-island/105858916</link><description>Wildlife photographer Rob Blakers pleads guilty to trespassing after admitting he camped beyond the boundary line whilst visiting privately owned Robbins Island to observe migratory birds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac32173c8f90d3e50097440e350afff4</guid></item><item><title>Daria Kasatkina ends 2025 tennis season early, citing burnout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/daria-kasatkina-taking-a-break-from-tennis-burnout/105860646</link><description>Daria Kasatkina ends her 2025 WTA season early, citing the hectic schedule and a high-stress year after switching nationalities to Australia from Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad2aa1068b4f5295b51933f2a1be3daa</guid></item><item><title>Bayer announces Roundup alternative with rollout of new weedkiller in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/bayer-announces-plans-for-australian-rollout-of-new-weed-killer/105847166</link><description>We've been spraying it on our farms, gardens and roadsides for 50 years, but the world's most used weedkiller is starting to run out of steam.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a610bff358c01395fe7953663db9dcea</guid></item><item><title>Janine Vaughan's family call for billboard to be uncovered ahead of Bathurst 1000</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/janine-vaughan-bathurst-1000-missing-persons-billboard-dispute/105844096</link><description>With more than 200,000 people expected to attend this weekend's Bathurst 1000, the family of Janine Vaughan wants a billboard raising awareness about her disappearance uncovered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0aeca646295fae09d7914bc026223f18</guid></item><item><title>New WA program aims to improve access to childcare for children with disabilities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/childcare-children-with-disability-pilot-program-trial-perth/105854018</link><description>An Australian-first pilot program gets underway in WA in the hope of not only giving the parents of children with complex needs a break, but helping them navigate the maze of different support systems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a8e1b30ed0de1380c55df9e7d995ea6</guid></item><item><title>Woman claiming to be Madeleine McCann on trial charged with stalking parents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/woman-claiming-to-be-madeleine-mccann-stalked-parents-uk-court/105860736</link><description>A 24-year-old woman who claims to be Madeleine McCann is on trial charged with stalking the missing child's parents over the past three years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd2c2d66d238b7d5f1bffa72b34f0719</guid></item><item><title>Search for missing man Peter Willoughby, 76, continues in Tasmanian bushland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/peter-willoughby-missing-man-search-continues/105860682</link><description>Mounted crews and drones are now involved in the search for Peter Willoughby, 76, who became disoriented and walked off into dense bushland near Launceston, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a17b0142996e28b88764fff7accc799</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, day two updates: Rival clubs reportedly interested in luring Nick Daicos away from Collingwood, Carlton secure Liam Reidy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/afl-trade-period-day-two-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca-daicos/105859160</link><description>The reported attempts to lure Nick Daicos away from Collingwood have headlined the second day of the AFL trade period. Look back at how all the day's trade news unfolded in our blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f32b16fe2d281e076b88df5a731c49f0</guid></item><item><title>Kati Thanda-Lake Eyre has reached its peak and is beginning to evaporate, local pilot says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/kati-thanda-lake-eyre-fills-up-south-australia/105856956</link><description>The floodwaters that have created an expansive inland oasis on the usually arid salt beds of Kati Thanda-Lake Eyre have reached a peak, and are beginning to evaporate, a local pilot says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">027c65d1be7d0e6bf6878186f247cce2</guid></item><item><title>With an all-Blak writing team, Erica Glynn brought Mystery Road: Origin's enigmatic detective Jay Swan to life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/mystery-road-first-nations-writing-room-erica-glynn/105803594</link><description>With the help of Mystery Road: Origin's steely detective Jay Swan, an all-Indigenous writing team tackles one of Australia's biggest issues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">937ea5a8466e8813c9dd7a63ef17711b</guid></item><item><title>'Deeply wrong' pro-Hamas graffiti condemned as Australian Jewish community marks October 7</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/october-7-commemorations-marred-by-antisemitic-graffiti/105860494</link><description>Political leaders have condemned the painting of a pro-Hamas slogan on a Melbourne billboard as Australia's Jewish community commemorates the October 7 terrorist attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9d834509cddd326a16a998d7c66b8c0</guid></item><item><title>Singaporean PM on tariffs, defence and Optus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/singaporean-pm-on-tariffs,-defence-and-optus/105861116</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b53a622ac0e8f7bedc60bc2eee37c1b</guid></item><item><title>Ord Valley's northern food bowl 'pipe dream' struggles amid changing climate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/northern-food-bowl-dream-struggles-amid-climate-change/105847668</link><description>Farmers are close to abandoning the dream of a food bowl in northern Australia, as one expert warns the region is nearing its "thermal limits" for cropping and cattle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de905ee900f69caf5bfbca7617e3ef61</guid></item><item><title>AC Milan to host Serie A match in Perth in what UEFA says is a 'regrettable' situation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/ac-milan-to-play-in-perth-as-uefa-says-it-is-regrettable/105861238</link><description>AC Milan will host a Serie A match in Perth next year, as UEFA's hand appears to have been forced to allow the game to go ahead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a50cc225d0e7505d28aab63baed1c536</guid></item><item><title>Local WA governments frustrated with rate of cat law reforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/native-animals-die-local-government-cat-laws-thrown-out/105794048</link><description>Concerned carers in WA say roaming pet cats will kill thousands of native animals while the state government debates changes to cat laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02d9d8ce7ef28bfe0486e2bc87ca5913</guid></item><item><title>Health Research Institute survey reveals midlife loneliness on the rise in Canberra as financial pressures bite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/midlife-loneliness-rises-canberra-as-cost-of-living-bites/105860924</link><description>Loneliness is rising fastest among Canberrans in their 30s and 40s, with new research showing this cohort is now more likely than younger people to report feeling lonely in the ACT.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83eeafbb42717e968cdb2e2b02a165f9</guid></item><item><title>Neighbours fans rush to Melbourne op shops after TV soap props donated to charities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/neighbours-fans-rush-to-find-props-donated-to-melbourne-op-shops/105858078</link><description>Neighbours fans rush to Melbourne op shops after 40 years of props, furniture and Ramsay Street relics were donated to charities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca86ba85c4354b9297414068cc619a44</guid></item><item><title>'Significant' aerial search for four-year-old Gus conducted over the weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/significant-aerial-search-for-missing-boy-gus-police-say/105861608</link><description>Police say they have conducted a "significant" aerial search of a property in South Australia's mid-north, where a four-year-old boy went missing 10 days ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8e4d5f34f117b094e212c99cd94e8e6</guid></item><item><title>Western Sydney University says emails claiming 'revoked' degrees are 'fraudulent'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/nsw-western-sydney-university-data-breach-emails-degrees-revoked/105861146</link><description>Western Sydney University has apologised to current and former students who received emails claiming their degrees have been "revoked", saying the messages are "not legitimate".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e559d4282002d101af53617c09cf33e</guid></item><item><title>NT government to refer parents for income management if child repeatedly skips school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/nt-government-school-truancy-plan-backlash-education/105856318</link><description>Parents in the NT who frequently fail to send their children to school, without a valid reason, may have their income managed by the Commonwealth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12aae044282aa406d31b3ff38d42c37d</guid></item><item><title>In Trent Dalton's new book Gravity Let Me Go, the bestselling author interrogates himself</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/trent-dalton-new-book-gravity-let-me-go-boy-swallows-universe/105806326</link><description>In Gravity Let Me Go, a struggling crime journalist lands the scoop of a lifetime, to the detriment of his loved ones. That's something Trent Dalton understands intimately.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec2f3217c1674a6b89bedc7b6a6f7815</guid></item><item><title>Kimberley bushfire season sees flames burn area double the size of Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/kimberley-bushfires-millions-burnt-hectares/105835854</link><description>This year's northern bushfire season has been dubbed "one of the toughest on record", with blazes having burnt through about 2.7 million hectares of land in WA's Kimberley region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5ea9e4fb95931d39c8997044e1ccfd2</guid></item><item><title>Former transport official Ibrahim Helmy fronts ICAC over kickbacks investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/nsw-icac-ibrahim-helmy-cupboard-transport-police/105861674</link><description>Ibrahim Helmy, who vanished before an inquiry into transport kickbacks, watched the first day of the Independent Commission Against Corruption public hearings via live stream.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10ff784b1f7132e0f3328c0ab3a9a20a</guid></item><item><title>Fresh and fragrant strawberry and cinnamon torte - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/alison-alexander-s-strawberry-and-cinnamon-torte/105849766</link><description>Sweet strawberries pair with a subtle cinnamon spice in this irresistible torte.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f19db1f54abf4889c55a5e00aedebdc8</guid></item><item><title>Artemios Mintzas faces court for the first time on charges over Croydon Park shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/croydon-park-shooting-artemios-mintzas-faces-court/105861858</link><description>The 60-year-old accused of shooting at over a dozen random members of the public in suburban Sydney has faced a magistrate after two lawyers got into an argument over who was representing him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8931b090491cc613a8ed6675842b7d99</guid></item><item><title>Body recovered during search for missing 15-year-old swimmer in Tamworth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/body-found-in-search-for-swimmer-peel-river-tamworth/105860868</link><description>A multi-agency search of the Peel River began on Monday night after police were told the teen had entered the water and failed to resurface.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d85bd2ee7e6ecffb36d40da7111de352</guid></item><item><title>Rescuers pull children from the rubble of Indonesian boarding school collapse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/efforts-to-rescue-indonesian-students-buried-under-school/105857382</link><description>Rescue teams worked around the clock through narrow gaps in the rubble of Sidoarjo's Al Khoziny Islamic Boarding School while risking further collapse to reach anyone still alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90d52525da9c6640b908a582ebebfacd</guid></item><item><title>Falling over a leading cause of hospitalisation, Injury Matters report highlights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/high-rates-of-falls-for-older-people-injury-matters-report/105859552</link><description>Data shows one in three people aged over 65 will have a fall every year. But a Perth not-for-profit wants to send a message that falls are not an inevitable part of ageing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f07c5568557ea0a0e0da1f83a197f2d4</guid></item><item><title>ABC Sport cricket coverage announced for the Ashes 2025/26 as Australia hosts England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/abc-sport-cricket-coverage-25-26-announced/105862028</link><description>Darren Lehmann and Glenn McGrath will join a first-class line-up of cricket talent for ABC Sport's coverage of the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df2427801c044d12182a1c9b4b33fc27</guid></item><item><title>Planning can help save you money this festive season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/preparing-financially-for-christmas-and-holidays/105795388</link><description>Australians estimate Christmas costs them about $800 a year, on average, but planning ahead can reduce the financial burden.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">158e6acd232ffd0c3bea1632ef3d82e3</guid></item><item><title>What the Health of the Nation report tells us about GP doctors by numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/health-of-the-nation-gp-report-by-numbers/105861118</link><description>These five charts give us a glimpse into what the current state of general practice looks like in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fab4fda08cc0d73f7ca73f5c43a01ec1</guid></item><item><title>Canberra boy who pleaded guilty to possessing violent extremist material driven by 'teenage bravado', court finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/teen-with-violent-extremist-material-driven-by-bravado-court/105861716</link><description>The 17-year-old was arrested when police found a large number of videos and messages on his phone and laptop depicting violent extremist acts, many of which were highly disturbing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97674a71ae8be1823d0f5fcfc2611dbe</guid></item><item><title>South Australia declared free from brown rugose fruit virus after more than a year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/south-australia-tomato-virus-free-brown-rugose/105861964</link><description>More than a year since South Australia's $230 million tomato and capsicum sector was plunged into turmoil by the first discovery of the tomato brown rugose fruit virus in Australia, the state has been declared free of the exotic disease.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f9a128f54240cc9f99a036c7afaba14</guid></item><item><title>Hikers feared being buried by snow as blizzard hit Mount Everest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/everest-rescue-how-it-happened/105861220</link><description>Hundreds of hikers are still trapped at an elevation of more than 4,900 metres as rescuers work to clear deep snow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c0bd394cd0abfdd67297249dd45789f</guid></item><item><title>Jarvis Cocker on his wild wedding, Glastonbury, and Pulp's first album in 24 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/pulp-jarvis-cocker-love-songs-glastonbury-more-take-5-zan-rowe/105836540</link><description>Love was "always problematic" for Jarvis Cocker, who fronts Britpop icons Pulp. But after decades of cynical songs on the subject, he's beginning to change his tune on romance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40c3575aacc74b1ddbee13cf6e2dbb39</guid></item><item><title>Wilcannia Weir project relies on increased federal funding, NSW minister says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/wilcannia-weir-project-funding-issues-rose-jackson/105849134</link><description>After decades of lobbying and design controversy, the New South Wales government says it needs another $30–40 million to proceed with the Wilcannia Weir upgrade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58e66e347555f3ff3da55e931beb4da2</guid></item><item><title>Australian wins with a jaffle at World Porridge Making Championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/melbourne-woman-wins-porridge-making-championship-with-jaffle/105861480</link><description>An oatmeal-filled jaffle made by a Melbourne food stylist and flavoured with Bundaberg Rum and bananas wins over judges in Scotland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">166b409d3c84e96a4aaae8acce2b6d24</guid></item><item><title>Search continues for 76yo man missing in Tasmanian bushland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/search-continues-for-76yo-man-missing-in-tasmanian/105862878</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e89673e6391ef9a599f8ed24c488ca1</guid></item><item><title>Peabody and Anglo American enter arbitration over $5.7 billion Queensland mines sale</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/peabody-anglo-american-arbitration-begins-on-moranbah-north-mine/105862190</link><description>Peabody Energy demands Anglo American return its $113.6 million deposit more than a month after the collapse of a deal to buy five mine sites in Queensland's Bowen Basin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61cd4fc8b7a1d2d53449d7b2401c9588</guid></item><item><title>Nationals Senator Bridget McKenzie demands government action over allegations of hundreds of sexual assaults by driving instructors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/bridget-mckenzie-driving-instructor-assaults-catherine-king/105861268</link><description>Frustrated by what she sees as inaction over a 7.30 investigation into alleged sexual assaults made by driving instructors, Nationals Senator Bridget McKenzie demands action from the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a10a5a9f37c5e7ad97e2577c0ef1a54</guid></item><item><title>Man who allegedly performed Nazi salute at Brisbane rally likely to plead guilty, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/qld-man-charged-nazi-salute-caboolture-court/105862006</link><description>Matthew Daniel Whiteway was charged by Queensland Police over allegedly giving a Nazi salute in Brisbane in September.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d7b7cb16fdaa708751bb008cd1d778a</guid></item><item><title>Trump is deploying more troops on home soil — here's where things stand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/trump-national-guard-deployments-us/105862330</link><description>US President Donald Trump is ramping up efforts to deploy the National Guard in more cities across the country to combat what he claims is a "war from within". Here's a quick rundown on where Mr Trump has stationed troops — and which cities might be next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81336c34b8947a268eb83228d6116265</guid></item><item><title>Gerard Community Council Aboriginal Corporation pleads guilty to failing to lodge reports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/gerard-community-council-aboriginal-corporation-guilty-riverland/105861718</link><description>The corporation has been fined $2,000 for failing to lodge reports to the Office of the Registrar of Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Corporations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">667cc72e63a68b60053f0faf8d783cbf</guid></item><item><title>Za'id Abdus Samad pleads not guilty to murdering uncle outside Kuraby home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/qld-kuraby-muder-trial-plea-not-guilty-zaid-abdus-samad/105862744</link><description>Restaurant owner and father-of-four Abdul Basith Mohammed was found dead outside his home in 2017 after going to investigate a power outage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e49e8a375f84eefab8eb3f241b893d37</guid></item><item><title>Australia confident in batting at Women's Cricket World Cup, as Pakistan match approaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/australia-able-to-break-records-with-cricket-world-cup-approach/105862918</link><description>Beth Mooney has predicted Australia's new approach to ODI cricket will pay off in the Women's Cricket World Cup, with a greater desire to take the game on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6676359c94593bc78b44ad4f5348aa3</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast mayor says Qld government hoarding cyclone recovery funds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/gold-coast-mayor-attacks-qld-government-cyclone-funding-delay/105862826</link><description>Gold Coast mayor Tom Tate is calling for the state government to hand over funding allocated to help cover the city's growing disaster recovery bill following Tropical Cyclone Alfred.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b7381e80a01b974d263f402f2cda200</guid></item><item><title>State of WA appeals $2.8 million compensation payment to Dion Barber for abuse in state care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/state-appeals-dion-barber-abuse-compensation-amount/105862254</link><description>The state of WA is appealing a record $2.8 million compensation payment awarded to Dion Barber, who suffered repeated sexual abuse while in state care during the 1980s and 1990s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e41686a64a06dc35c2c557558da4dcb</guid></item><item><title>Australia Kangaroos lose Xavier Coates and Zac Lomax ahead of rugby league Ashes in England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/kangaroos-lose-xavier-coates-zac-lomax-rugby-league-ashes/105863632</link><description>Australia suffers a double blow with Zac Lomax and Xavier Coates ruled out of the overseas tour through injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0d6fe219c5cfcc432c5c99a3e88b226</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105863898</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">250fa4d6f9e87b19ec96acde65af18af</guid></item><item><title>Motorists capture moment armed police make an arrest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/motorists-capture-moment-armed-police-make-an/105863872</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84c3a62e6f0a293aa619852839f622a9</guid></item><item><title>Surfer bitten twice by shark chasing seal off Kangaroo Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/shark-attacks-man-seal-uses-as-decoy-kangaroo-island/105863812</link><description>A surfer who was twice bitten by a shark that was reportedly chasing a seal in waters off Kangaroo Island, is recovering well with a coffee, according to his boss.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1b369fa6480a966dd5e0a9d060721c6</guid></item><item><title>Sheffield Shield round one: Victoria and NSW register wins, Tasmania bats for a draw against Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/sheffield-shield-round-one-victoria-and-nsw-register-wins/105863840</link><description>Victoria has upset reigning Sheffield Shield holders South Australia at the Adelaide Oval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d87a196b1e0545296dee75c1390f932</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds looking to change things up in second netball Test against South Africa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/australia-diamonds-south-africa-netball-second-test/105863906</link><description>Australian coach Stacey Marinkovich says she needs to try different combinations ahead of the Test series against New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c866a0db7bc54576ae7d2689ff95490</guid></item><item><title>Second inquest into homicide of three tourists shot dead Mount Isa in 1978 begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/qld-spear-creek-murder-cold-case-second-inquest-begins/105863768</link><description>Gordon Twaddle, Karen Edwards, and Tim Thomson were killed almost 50 years ago. A second inquest into their deaths hopes to deliver answers for their loved ones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b77536cbcd65a613c86d384c392f6b7b</guid></item><item><title>Robin Williams's daughter begs fans to stop making AI content of her father</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/zelda-williams-calls-out-ai-video-of-late-father-robin-williams/105863964</link><description>The daughter of the late actor Robin Williams has condemned AI-generated content featuring her father's likeness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffd2a5defe194f05995a766f5c162ef7</guid></item><item><title>Scientists win Nobel Prize in Physics for discoveries in quantum mechanics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/scientists-physics-nobel-prize-quantum-mechanics-discovery/105863766</link><description>Three scientists have won the 2025 Nobel Prize in Physics for "the discovery of macroscopic quantum mechanical tunnelling and energy quantisation in an electric circuit".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e33d892453da0aeb26e45b03f8612f75</guid></item><item><title>Emmanuel Macron urged by his first PM to resign in escalating French crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/macron-urged-by-first-pm-to-resign-in-escalating-french-crisis/105864272</link><description>Emmanuel Macron's first prime minister urges the cornered French head of state to resign in a shock call that compounded an escalating political crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a9bdac4b0b2a74c58b74f54d75495b5</guid></item><item><title>Recently-elected German mayor Iris Stalzer in critical condition after being stabbed outside home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/herdecke-mayor-iris-stalzer-stabbed-in-germany-/105864280</link><description>Iris Stalzer, a Social Democrat who was elected mayor of Herdecke in the Ruhr region a week ago, is reportedly suffered life-threatening injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">167b87894c38ff1cccc6dda664d52cc7</guid></item><item><title>Research shows females carry a much higher genetic risk for major depression than males</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/queensland-depression-genetic-link-research-females-males/105864472</link><description>In a study involving about 200,000 people diagnosed with depression, scientists have identified almost twice as many genetic red flags in the DNA of females compared with males.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">992adc88f4efa48c96375158189324b7</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian draft bill would give TASCAT power to dismiss local councillors for 'serious misconduct'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/draft-bill-for-standards-governance-tasmanian-councils/105862822</link><description>Tasmanian councillors could be removed from their democratically elected positions under changes proposed to local government legislation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c0807241755728977d48f66e8742305</guid></item><item><title>New AFP boss warns hate crime laws may need to be strengthened further</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/afp-commissioner-krissy-barrett-national-security-warning/105848960</link><description>In a wide-ranging interview as she begins as AFP commissioner, Krissy Barrett announces a new sub-terror strike force, and flags that newly written hate crime laws may need to be strengthened further.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d0647acfa2b665dfd6ab93b824444e0</guid></item><item><title>Class actions accuse two top Australian universities of misleading and deceptive conduct</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/university-course-accreditation-class-action/105820008</link><description>Students have been left with HECS debts and careers that are "non-existent" after completing degrees that were not accredited. Class actions have been launched against two Australian universities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edfa047f5e9910e62181a6c28b09499a</guid></item><item><title>Up to 3,000 flood victims' details have been given to ChatGPT. What does that mean for privacy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/can-private-information-uploaded-to-chatgpt-be-found-by-others/105858422</link><description>Data experts say it is hard to know what the implications are for 3,000 flood victims who have had personal information uploaded to the AI platform by a government contractor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b6ff30e1811147304ebcb6a92bbcce4</guid></item><item><title>BlueScope chief demands urgent action on 'broken' gas market to save industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/bluescope-steel-mark-vassella-press-club-speech-on-gas-crisis/105856934</link><description>A future made in Australia? Not if gas prices keep rising, major manufacturers warn as they call for urgent action to secure affordable supply.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc3ec4d318789f0142aff31a9de0f8a9</guid></item><item><title>Anika Wells points to surprise stress test of triple-0 network ahead of bushfire season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/surprise-drill-for-telcos-as-coalition-goes-after-wells/105863244</link><description>The adequacy of Australia's emergency call network will be stress tested with a surprise drill ahead of bushfire season, as the opposition ramps up its assault over the communication minister's handling of last month's fatal triple-0 outage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02ad837597eec81457217abff18e9818</guid></item><item><title>'Everyday living cost' or assistive technology? NDIS participants frustrated with flexibility of rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/participants-frustrated-with-ndis-support-rules/105815444</link><description>A year after a controversial NDIS change, advocates are growing increasingly concerned that "counterintuitive" and "nonsensical" funding decisions are reducing participant independence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">463a7d10821bae40d417e7cbf53a0d7b</guid></item><item><title>Warragul social group helping parents of children with disability find connection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/warragul-social-group-connects-parents-of-kids-with-disability/105812018</link><description>Parents of children with disability can miss out on social support, but a Victorian physiotherapist hopes to change that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62d5225573dfcab728349685dfc6dfeb</guid></item><item><title>Audit finds state government-run aged care facility inappropriately used restraints</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/disability-sa-northgate-restrictive-practices-prompt-outrage/105861214</link><description>A South Australian government aged care home, which looks after 23 people with dementia or complex disabilities, inappropriately used lap belts and other mechanical restraints to stop falls and control residents' behaviour, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfe50e1638f58d32951b2d2bf875d085</guid></item><item><title>Tourism operators seek more funding to mitigate algal bloom impact in SA over summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/tourism-operators-seek-more-incentives-to-mitigate-algal-bloom/105862594</link><description>Tourism, seafood industry and community representatives are calling for greater funding, education and travel incentives ahead of the release of the South Australian government's upcoming Summer Plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9e5b120fcb56d82bd8c6da140631dca</guid></item><item><title>Sheffield Shield round one quick hits: Marnus Labuschagne enjoys timely century while Ashes Test hopefuls struggle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/sheffield-shield-round-one-quick-hits-labuschagne-century/105861198</link><description>The Sheffield Shield is underway, with all eyes on the contenders for Australia's problematic opener spot. Here are five quick hits from the opening round of the season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8af9da9a39c94a9f7e4cb1494d9164a1</guid></item><item><title>R360 players to be banned from international rugby union</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/sport-r360-players-will-be-banned-from-international-rugby-union/105864582</link><description>Rugby union players who sign up for the R360 breakaway franchise league will be ineligible for international selection, national governing bodies have confirmed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d618fd0e8467a243d4f99e91775e42c</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian government stadium report responds to planning commission's criticisms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/stadium-report-released-for-hobart-afl-macquarie-point-stadium/105805830</link><description>The state government response to last month's scathing report from the planning commission says that while "change can be challenging", the "dream of a Tasmanian team representing our state in the AFL and AFLW is now within reach — we cannot turn back".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a5d3dfd9f4b596cda1002d9c43f9ade</guid></item><item><title>Born as the first bombs fell, two-year-old Mohammad has known nothing but war</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/gazan-mother-on-raising-baby-born-on-october-7-2023/105860988</link><description>Children in Gaza are experiencing grief, loss, displacement, and starvation. For some, this is all they know or remember.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef3406ceb77c3c45afce642ee93bbe8f</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Citizenship granted to two children of women returned from Syria, Home Affairs confirms — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/federal-politics-live-october-8/105863462</link><description>Home Affairs has confirmed it processed "citizenship by descent" applications for two children who fled Syria last month after being stranded overseas for years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c87ee4438c48cb1e98eac7eacbebadf3</guid></item><item><title>LeBron James 'retirement' teaser that blew out ticket prices for Lakers games ends up being an ad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/lebron-james-retirement-teaser-ended-up-being-an-ad/105864630</link><description>LeBron James's "retirement teaser" — which blew out ticket prices for the LA Lakers' final home game of the regular season — ends up being an advertisement for cognac.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2f17c6426a56a6bbcf42f626c89acad</guid></item><item><title>Trump says US will 'do everything possible' to prevent war if Hamas agrees to peace deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/us-to-do-everything-possible-to-prevent-war-if-hamas-agree-peace/105864574</link><description>Donald Trump insists the United States will "do everything possible" to prevent Israel restarting the war in Gaza, in the event Hamas agrees to a peace deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4db7bc575e49f43f55fdf7f7fef99972</guid></item><item><title>Gold price hits record high, topping $US4,000 an ounce for first time, amid US shutdown and lower interest rates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/gold-price-hits-record-high-topping-4000-an-ounce/105863902</link><description>The price of gold has hit another record and is set to become Australia's second most valuable resource export after iron ore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8a6a55db842730246cc3ca2cf30402a</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police intercept alleged 'kill team' near daycare centre in Revesby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/nsw-revesby-police-intercept-kill-team-near-childcare-centre/105864634</link><description>Police say tactical officers foiled an alleged planned hit near a daycare centre in Revesby in Sydney's south-west on Tuesday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6fdc683fd3660f0c048758c5b3a8bd8</guid></item><item><title>Sunshine Coast Council deploys security guards amid rising violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/rising-violence-sunshine-coast-council-workers/105863164</link><description>A Queensland council is ramping up efforts to protect staff following an alarming rise in verbal and physical abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee73448f5d81c0ca87118eafcf8c8b93</guid></item><item><title>US Senate committee questions Trump's Pentagon nominee John Noh over AUKUS review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/trump-pentagon-nominee-john-noh-questioned-on-aukus/105864552</link><description>The AUKUS submarine pact may need "commonsense" action from both Australia and the US to make it more "sustainable", according to Donald Trump's nominee to oversee US defence strategy in the Indo-Pacific.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0d29435ebb41a976009ed6932acad05</guid></item><item><title>Regulator investigating WA fire that burnt 11,000ha and left residents homeless</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/regulator-investigating-january-fire-in-wa-southern-wheatbelt/105830912</link><description>Residents who lost their homes in a blaze that ripped through WA's southern wheatbelt in January may have to wait more than two years to seek compensation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcb6cf350db3b25039b12adb41ae9aac</guid></item><item><title>Saltwater crocodile found with mouth zip-tied shut in Adelaide River, sparking calls for stronger penalties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/saltwater-crocodile-found-with-snout-zip-tied-in-darwin-nt/105848320</link><description>The discovery of a saltwater crocodile with its mouth bound shut by zip ties in a Darwin river has sparked outrage, with animal rights advocates calling for stronger wildlife protections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd6688be17a6ce08037f8d10631587f5</guid></item><item><title>A juvenile wild saltwater crocodile was found with its mouth zip-tied. The river tour guides who spotted the crocodile were able to remove the restrai</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/a-juvenile-wild-saltwater-crocodile-was-found-with/105863530</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eff0d0e9e297fe2ef59b9e970584478e</guid></item><item><title>As WA government looks set to bring Serie A game involving AC Milan to Perth, some football fans are not happy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/serie-a-game-perth-ac-milan-como-reaction/105861988</link><description>Italian heavyweights AC Milan look set to play a match, for actual Serie A points, in Perth. What will the state government pay to lure them here, and why are some football supporters unhappy?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ea1d7a00e17cb83abc6238ac91d46f8</guid></item><item><title>Australian dollar jumps to 10-month high against yen, ASX slips as gold price hits new record — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/asx-markets-business-live-news-october-8/105864736</link><description>The ASX 200 closes slightly down, as gold maintains record highs. The Australian dollar surges against the Japanese yen on speculation that its central bank will delay lifting interest rates. Look back on all the day's business and finance news.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">471479ca258fb1f4149bb57c197138cf</guid></item><item><title>Surge in shark-tracking app downloads following fatal Sydney attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/downloads-increase-of-sharksmart-app-after-sydney-fatal-attack/105863682</link><description>There has been a surge in downloads of the SharkSmart app following the fatal attack of a Northern Beaches surfer — in a sign the incident has left some nervous to get back into the water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00d803bb4b6dccf774ca067d2e5c7022</guid></item><item><title>Players concerned over Shanghai heat as Novak Djokovic collapses on court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/players-concerned-over-shanghai-heat-as-novak-djokovic-col/105864786</link><description>Holger Rune says "there is always a limit" as soaring temperatures and humidity in Shanghai and Wuhan tennis events cause player distress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0a40634d1b457b5752fb7f8a643aea7</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, day three recap: Sam Flanders, Judd McVee and Brandon Starcevich find new homes as Brisbane makes Oscar Allen bid official</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/afl-trade-period-day-3-live-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca/105862940</link><description>Oscar Allen's move to Brisbane is almost official as West Coast finds out what compensation it would receive for losing its captain. Here's how day three of the AFL trade period panned out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a8dbfcdd651f8cb3552c19a5bbf32ce</guid></item><item><title>Australian merino wool future positive after surging price restores grower confidence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/surging-wool-price-restores-grower-confidence-in-aussie-merino/105845730</link><description>Amid a run of price rises at Australian wool auctions, the next generation of growers say global demand and fresh confidence could mark a turning point for the fibre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a54f47d8d99a1127e10b40056ef58297</guid></item><item><title>Taylor Swift wears Adelaide label Paolo Sebastian in The Fate of Ophelia music video</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/taylor-swift-wears-paolo-sebastian-dress/105864738</link><description>Founder and designer Paul Vasileff says he's grateful to have his Adelaide-made couture dress on the world stage with pop superstar Taylor Swift wearing it in the new The Fate of Ophelia music video.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0332df3f421d0e89d81fee932d81f9b</guid></item><item><title>Neighbour of Kotoni Staggs pays tribute to Broncos star after supporting family through husband's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/kotoni-staggs-tribute-after-death-of-david-orange/105864876</link><description>The neighbour of Kotoni Staggs pays tribute to the Broncos star for helping her through a devastating family death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08ab9d0efbc29ab8d98a303c4c86194f</guid></item><item><title>Taylor Swift ‘bejewelled’ in dress made by Aussie fashion designer in new music video</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/taylor-swift-%E2%80%98bejewelled%E2%80%99-in-dress-made-by-aussie/105865144</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d95cdfaa7bdbf66dc030da1825868fc</guid></item><item><title>Australians are reading less than ever before. Here's how to read more books</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/how-to-read-more-books-when-reading-rates-are-declining/105857550</link><description>Research shows Australians are reading fewer books than ever before. One writer shares her advice on how to make reading a daily habit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c18e0ca034d56b4b48cf5532a280e3a6</guid></item><item><title>Democrats and Republicans clash in fiery Senate hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/democrats-and-republicans-clash-in-fiery-senate-hearing/105864968</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ae4e0cc55ce2777fef10111a22e0a2b</guid></item><item><title>Pam Bondi accused of using justice system to target Donald Trump's opponents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/pam-bondi-accused-of-using-doj-to-target-donald-trump-opponents/105864762</link><description>US Attorney-General Pam Bondi has faced heated questioning from senators over claims she's transforming the justice department into a "shield for the president and his political allies".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e370271e506a39abe7bb883d20d3aff</guid></item><item><title>Arsenal lose 2-1 to Lyon at Women's Champions League as trio of Matildas feature</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/womens-champions-league-arsenal-lose-to-lyon/105865154</link><description>Arsenal goes down 2-1 to Lyon in the Women's Champion League as three Matildas stars make an appearance at Meadow Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6ab5ae4953fe13baa90426dc6bb6897</guid></item><item><title>WA iron ore mining shows no signs of slowing despite price drop concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/rio-tinto-bhp-continue-to-invest-in-pilbara-iron-ore-mining/105862166</link><description>Australia's two biggest iron ore miners continue to expand their operations in WA's Pilbara, despite warnings of waning demand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8309ec60fbd1a3ef21ca4c2344103b7</guid></item><item><title>More families raising children with cystic fibrosis staying in the bush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/outback-life-kids-cystic-fibrosis/105843356</link><description>Two mums in rural Queensland have spoken about why they choose to live more than 1,000 kilometres from the Queensland Children's Hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d919ce008ebdfdac5b3cf84ab09bed02</guid></item><item><title>Single farmers in Western Australia ditch dating apps for something face to face</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/farmers-single-mingle-speed-dating/105843296</link><description>When the dating app radius won't reach the edge of your property, and you're harvesting grain from sun-up til sundown, how do you find a partner?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08d15c91b798615b073d0cf6ec0e8cb3</guid></item><item><title>Rental prices have risen almost 44 per cent in five years, Cotality review finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/rental-prices-surge-almost-44-per-cent-review-finds/105865000</link><description>Median rental prices have risen to more than $700 per week for the first time, according to Cotality's Quarterly Rental Review.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29d81fd4c37ded2df4e0378f9ccc7865</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of court cases potentially compromised amid Victoria Police investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/victoria-police-audit-sex-offence-cases-potentially-compromised/105864962</link><description>Police have arrested a digital forensics officer and are investigating whether his work compromised hundreds of cases over nearly a decade including sexual offence and child abuse cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a7453570f7b1c6a6ea15dd2c467e2dd</guid></item><item><title>Brewer stages beer boycott over Kangaroo Island ferry's 'ridiculous' fares</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/kangaroo-island-brewer-boycotts-sealink-ferry-over-fare-prices/105861274</link><description>A Kangaroo Island brewer says he will no longer supply beer to the island's ferry service, amid a growing outcry over the high cost of fares to the popular international tourism destination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcb960892ba1f087a10e899519db01f7</guid></item><item><title>WA's Bibbulmun Track running record broken twice in one week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/record-for-bibbulmun-track-broken-twice-in-a-week/105862894</link><description>Two men have smashed the record for completing one of the world's longest walking tracks in the fastest time, within days of each other.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d30da50c333b34f04755b1e8b4637c1</guid></item><item><title>Minjee Lee eyes top spot in golf's end-of-season rankings race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/minjee-lee-eyeing-spot-in-end-of-season-rankings/105865746</link><description>Australian superstar Minjee Lee is in line for several big awards as the 2025 golf season enters the home stretch in Asia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af9e3678d24738b12753f9ea22f29150</guid></item><item><title>Glencore refinery sites stay open with taxpayer funds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/glencore-copper-queensland-smelter-refinery-open/105462262</link><description>The last Australian copper smelter processing third-party product will stay open after its owner accepted a support package.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e6c15045f1cc98d2905cdee8a8e6ebc</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill nurse to represent Australia at Ironman World Championship — Women</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/ironwoman-world-championship-hawaii-australian-competitor/105845064</link><description>Broken Hill nurse Bella Kolinac, 23, will represent Australia at the Ironman World Championship — Women in Kona, Hawaii.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">416c1cb578ddc87acd2524cb02022036</guid></item><item><title>Last night's harvest moon made for stunning photos. When is the next supermoon?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/harvest-moon-photos-when-is-the-next-supermoon-/105864622</link><description>Stargazers from around the world have captured the luminous glow of October's supermoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b8da86f3072d1f3813b7bd9b88f7e17</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr to play for Matildas for the first time in two years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/sam-kerr-matildas-return-mary-fowler-asian-cup/105864112</link><description>Sam Kerr's two year absence from the Matildas is almost over, she's set to feature in friendlies later this month, while Mary Fowler is recovering well from her own ACL injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">702d31688fd2da622b3e1419726855e7</guid></item><item><title>Australian Gaza flotilla member criticises federal government after being detained by Israel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/australian-gaza-flotilla-member-speaks-after-israel-detention/105865294</link><description>An Australian activist accuses the federal government of not providing enough support after she and other members of a flotilla were detained by Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e6cb356fc9972b5f202a03bc478fbf2</guid></item><item><title>More than 500 hikers reportedly rescued after being stranded on Mount Everest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/mountain-everest-hikers-rescued-blizzard-tibet/105864778</link><description>Hundreds of trekkers, villagers and support staff have safely reached the Tibetan town of Qudang, according to Chinese state media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33bcbc3a4f3e7c41f2704aebf600f9c7</guid></item><item><title>Geelong Cats fined by AFL over third-party arrangements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/geelong-cats-fined-by-afl-over-third-party-disclosures/105866216</link><description>The AFL fines Geelong $77,500 for failing to disclose third-party agreements with players over a six-year period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f8e13e797e402b65d8ae17b2688c11f</guid></item><item><title>Mark Latham's outburst outside court, as ex-partner pleads not guilty to intimate image charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/nsw-mark-latham-tirade-nathalie-matthews-court-avo-image-charges/105865566</link><description>Independent MP Mark Latham has spoken out against former partner Nathalie Matthews during an ongoing legal battle, on the same day she pleaded not guilty to intimate image charges in a separate matter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf2f2151bb71ae21a37273934715da1d</guid></item><item><title>Witness vision of attack on Ecuadorian president's motorcade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/witness-vision-of-attack-on-ecuadorian-presidents/105866518</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34ba2729b35f86d455373476cb63a54d</guid></item><item><title>Male whales race in pursuit of female in east coast migration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/male-whales-race-in-pursuit-of-female-in-east/105866386</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55b8752a7c5fd19bc070efbd5ef98490</guid></item><item><title>Male humpback whales race in pursuit of female during east coast migration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/male-whales-race-in-pursuit-of-female-in-east-coast-migration/105861060</link><description>A drone photographer captures vision of a tightly packed pod of 11 humpback whales heading south in a race to mate off the NSW mid-north coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eaad686271b69be2d05ad42ad5ebf30b</guid></item><item><title>Surfer bitten by shark chasing seal off Kangaroo Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/surfer-bitten-by-shark-chasing-seal-off-kangaroo-island/105866450</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28aca7d922cfde7788f5978a622379e1</guid></item><item><title>Dolly Parton's sister speaks out over singer's health concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/dolly-parton-sister-speaks-out-las-vegas-concerts-delayed/105866370</link><description>Dolly Parton's sister has asked fans to pray for the country music singer's health just one week after the star delayed several concerts in Las Vegas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">002181e5b2952a8159dea961b0c5c76d</guid></item><item><title>Man spared jail time by ACT court after he raped and filmed woman without consent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/paul-james-donnelly-spared-jail-rape-woman-met-on-tinder/105866018</link><description>A 38-year-old man has been spared jail time, partly on account of his autism diagnosis, after raping a woman he met online and filming their sexual encounters without consent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d65f8d8e2b2e6eb767bbc69fe77554a4</guid></item><item><title>Optus email mishap left department in dark about triple-0 outage, even after Anika Wells' office told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/optus-email-mishap-left-department-in-dark/105866628</link><description>The telco operator sent two emails about its outage, which understated its extent, to a departmental email address that had been changed a week earlier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">076c258d9594921f83dc78f45a740c8e</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police hold 'significant concerns' about planned pro-Palestinian march to Sydney Opera House</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/police-concerned-with-pro-palestinian-march-sydney-opera-house/105866112</link><description>A senior NSW Police officer has expressed cynicism that a crowd of tens of thousands could be managed in a staggered manner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5c8ad22018d9bafdb39ed42fd7fa602</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of flights disrupted as US government shutdown enters its second week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/explainer-us-flights-airports-impacted-by-shutdown/105865276</link><description>The US government shutdown is entering its second week and the impacts are starting to play out, with thousands of flights disrupted across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">268c0ad0353cf6c209dfe6bd29e4cc18</guid></item><item><title>Ecuadorian protesters filmed throwing rocks in alleged presidential assassination attempt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/ecuador-protesters-alleged-daniel-noboa-assassination-attempt/105866368</link><description>Five people have been detained after hundreds of protesters surrounded the presidential motorcade of Daniel Noboa and began throwing rocks and stones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09226775ccfe0c4292d465c3315aeca2</guid></item><item><title>Buddhist monk Naotunne Vijitha pleads not guilty to historical child sexual assault charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/buddhist-monk-naotunne-vijitha-child-sexual-assault-trial/105866012</link><description>The head monk of a Buddhist temple, Naotunne Vijitha, has denied sexually assaulting six girls at the temple in Melbourne's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af3045df086f309de589d36c7b842fb3</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police release aerial video of arrest in Revesby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/nsw-police-release-aerial-video-of-arrest-in-revesby/105866564</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b53b57016c07eaaad6b5edb6b9b97e52</guid></item><item><title>Childcare director Amanda Vassel fined for employing convicted child sex offender husband</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/qld-amanda-vassel-fined-employing-child-sex-offender-husband/105865702</link><description>Amanda Louise Vassel was sacked from her job at the south-east Queensland childcare centre after the matter came to light.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2d23f2888ca6e24e22d451843509a96</guid></item><item><title>Alexander O'Sachy sentenced to 11 years in prison for stabbing Angela Godwin to death at their Brisbane home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/alexander-o-sachy-sentenced-to-prison-stabbing-death-of-partner/105866720</link><description>The Supreme Court in Brisbane heard Alexander O'Sachy tried to clean up evidence of his crime before calling emergency services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edb99f4db6f1d7359246c564251989b1</guid></item><item><title>City of Stirling terminates football club's lease after player's alleged explicit Stephen Hawking costume</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/osborne-park-fc-stephen-hawking-silly-sunday-costume/105866188</link><description>A Perth football club faces deregistration and has been expelled from their club rooms after a player reportedly attended a post-season party dressed as Stephen Hawking, allegedly with explicit images of himself as a child attached.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9da9996042f9a3ca08b4afec97e1cd7d</guid></item><item><title>Deported Gaza flotilla activist slams Australian government for lack of support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/deported-gaza-flotilla-activist-slams-australian/105867176</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24b160130e63ffcdf19bd2c5addbb15b</guid></item><item><title>Former clinical director Hannah Lake leads Hobart Clinic rescue bid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/hannah-lake-in-hobart-clinic-rescue-bid/105866436</link><description>The former clinical director of the Hobart Clinic, psychiatrist Dr Hannah Lake, is part of a last-minute push for the institution to be given a reprieve before it closes its doors at the end of next week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13ff2d4aa757dfd275b29ddc0ded6164</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne man sentenced over medical cannabis company Cann Group insider trading case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/man-sentenced-over-medical-cannabis-cann-group-insider-trading/105865698</link><description>A Melbourne man found guilty of insider trading during a $20 million capital raise by a medicinal cannabis company has been ordered to pay more than $225,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dc238f9150615779cfae17a7ffe5073</guid></item><item><title>AFLW Carlton star Darcy Vescio says 'punching down' on Mad Monday must end</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/aflw-carlton-darcy-vescio-mad-monday-pride/105867186</link><description>Inaugural Carlton AFLW star Darcy Vescio has urged players to be more conscious of their role-model status when dressing up for end-of-season celebrations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8aa8bc4d3b0c0602e2afe2492234d703</guid></item><item><title>Qantas says 'legal protections in place' as cyber hacking group threatens to release personal data</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/qantas-responds-to-cyber-hacker-threat-to-release-data/105866656</link><description>Qantas says it is continuing to support customers as a hacking group threatens to release personal data from around 40 companies to the dark web.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">579d41470988631592c5369804bffca5</guid></item><item><title>Trade restrictions for Philippines banana imports to be reviewed by federal government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/australian-government-review-banana-imports-from-philippines/105863456</link><description>The federal government will review its quarantine rules after a formal request by the Philippines to import its bananas, but the industry is pushing back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3914bf6a6bd32339f4e721ddf4773ebe</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Highway diverted in North Queensland as thick smoke threatens visibility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/bruce-highway-diverted-north-queensland-bloomsbury/105867400</link><description>Queensland Police have diverted traffic off the Bruce Highway south of Proserpine in North Queensland, as fire crews battle a blaze burning close to the road.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e48ede4ef31fd49347a4bacb64ad443f</guid></item><item><title>Scramble to protect Kangaroo Island bee colony, one of the world's purest colonies, from varroa mite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/beekeepers-welcome-extra-varroa-biosecurity-for-kangaroo-island/105865160</link><description>A deadly parasite that has laid waste to bee colonies throughout Australia has so far not made it to Kangaroo Island, home to the world's oldest bee sanctuary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6145c18bd3b3f056f510a5b63f60615b</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Collingwood player Shannon Cox jailed for killing women in Brand Hwy car crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/former-afl-player-shannon-cox-sentenced-for-fatal-road-crash/105864080</link><description>Former Collingwood player Shannon Cox, who had meth is his system when his car smashed into a hatchback, killing two elderly women, is jailed for manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db37245d6c5e233b1abdae93f311f4fc</guid></item><item><title>Hobart's Macquarie Point stadium debate weighs 'expert' advice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/hobart-macquarie-point-stadium-debate/105865012</link><description>Tasmania's minister responsible for the proposed $1.13 billion Macquarie Point stadium, Eric Abetz, says there are many "expert" views, but ultimately the government will decide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb634d41fd45254375e1e37438c6811d</guid></item><item><title>Strava is suing Garmin for patent infringement. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/why-is-strava-suing-garmin/105865392</link><description>Fitness app Strava and sports watchmaker Garmin usually go hand-in-hand, but the two fitness tech leaders are now in competition in a US lawsuit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">405e53404a636a1e020301726d45cc2f</guid></item><item><title>Stephen Miller has said Donald Trump has plenary authority but what does that actually mean?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/stephen-miller-donald-trump-plenary-authority/105865430</link><description>A Trump administration official faces criticism after allegedly claiming US President Donald Trump has "plenary authority" while on a live interview with CNN.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7749a6fbb7a76dc4181cbe4a0e3a80c7</guid></item><item><title>Do dishwashers release microplastics when you wash plastic containers and kitchenware?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/do-dishwashers-release-microplastics-wash-plastic-containers/105860862</link><description>If you're worried about microplastics, is it safe to wash plastic containers and other utensils in the dishwasher, given the use of heat and detergents? We asked two experts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fd5611f6ea7fae53cd7f7e02afd0135</guid></item><item><title>Jon Stevens releases new album Shimmer, announces tour on 64th birthday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/jon-stevens-new-album-shimmer-announces-tour-on-64th-birthday/105867096</link><description>From teen idol to rock great, Jon Stevens has fronted legendary bands Noiseworks and INXS. He has chosen his 64th birthday to release a new album and announce a tour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afdcebd18dbb3b1f571e9a4bc92e8758</guid></item><item><title>Three charged with murder and torture of Brisbane man Andrew Burow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/qld-andrew-burow-investigation-three-charged-with-murder/105866608</link><description>Police will allege Andrew Burow endured a three to four-day ordeal which began after meeting with the accused in August.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c2ceca2aab98422918a40ced8c296b3</guid></item><item><title>Former RAAF pilot Robert John Crawford appears in court, charged with murder of wife Frances Crawford</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/queensland-robert-crawford-committed-trial-alleged-murder/105865292</link><description>Robert John Crawford has been charged with murder over the death of his wife at their home in July 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60e067671364f051a50810e58c33d586</guid></item><item><title>Rex flight evacuated after engine catches fire at Adelaide Airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/rex-fire-causes-flight-evacuation-in-adelaide/105867132</link><description>Passengers have praised the actions of the pilot and cabin crew after a Rex aircraft was evacuated at Adelaide Airport this morning following a fire emergency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc7b37479368d0184c579278aeba62cf</guid></item><item><title>City of Melbourne set to vote on security camera overhaul, surveillance powers for staff</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/melbourne-city-council-cctv-security-network-proposed-expansion/105864992</link><description>The City of Melbourne is set to vote on a new plan that would see more privately owned CCTV cameras feeding into the city's security network and staff able to access the footage to investigate local law breaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e651efd7aa333e63fda95c9803c5fcae</guid></item><item><title>Australia's parliament is likely to grow for the first time in 40 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/parliament-increase-fixed-terms-senate-estimates/105865534</link><description>Australia's parliament is likely to get larger as the government canvasses possibilities for expanding the number of MPs and introducing fixed or four-year terms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47e1e744d90a2df3ebb85c40bc9c207c</guid></item><item><title>Algal bloom chief asked about 'disaster' declaration as inquiry told of thousands of marine deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/algal-bloom-parliamentary-inquiry-told-of-marine-death-tolls/105866214</link><description>The SA government has never formally requested that the Commonwealth declare the algal bloom a "national disaster", a senior bureaucrat has told a parliamentary inquiry — despite a state minister "advocating" for such a response three months ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">daf6411ce251563c25ae83ac3c0acbde</guid></item><item><title>Audit reveals widespread public housing electrical issues in wake of three-year-old's tragic death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/mitchell-thomas-inquest-alice-springs-house-fire-audit/105867072</link><description>The death of a three-year-old boy in an Alice Springs house fire has led to an electrical audit of Northern Territory public housing, which uncovered widespread issues affecting hundreds of homes, an inquest has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47454752054229e91ce6cd896977bb0e</guid></item><item><title>Grieving Canberra dog owner warns of deadly blue-green algae but testing shows no increased risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/warning-blue-green-algae-lake-ginninderra-toxic-dog-dead/105865256</link><description>Toxic algae is sometimes detected in Canberra's waterways, where a dog died after swimming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf133c39e7536cf2d8235f23b13118b4</guid></item><item><title>Jordan Spencer jailed for 13 years for setting woman alight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/jordan-spencer-jailed-for-13-years-for-setting-rival-alight/105866418</link><description>A 34-year-old Shepparton woman has been jailed for 13 years after dousing another woman with petrol and setting her on fire during a dispute over an e-scooter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">707885cae62c2b76a53d98bee76345dc</guid></item></channel></rss>