<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 07:45:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>What to do if your mortgage payments haven't gone down despite an RBA rate cut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/how-to-lower-mortgage-repayments-after-rba-interest-rate-cut/105844258</link><description>You might assume home loan repayments will automatically reduce when an interest rate cut is passed on, but this isn’t always the case. Here's how to check.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9321ceed8438c8f5233f33dc1bbcc97</guid></item><item><title>Here's how Labor's revised super proposal would work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/labor-super-tax-changes-explained/105885434</link><description>Every prominent criticism of the tax has been addressed, with the result that it will apply to fewer people and raise less money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e8eac54b40c708087b8083935640a86</guid></item><item><title>Major review of medical scans at Caboolture Hospital to include 3,500 more patients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/caboolture-hospital-medical-scan-review-broadened/105884950</link><description>Thousands more patients have been caught up in a bungle involving medical scans not being reviewed by doctors at a major south-east Queensland hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8bef54c1a408a99f99190c88af1abba</guid></item><item><title>Jesse Southwell signs with Broncos amid fears of lopsided NRLW competition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/nrlw-jesse-southwell-signs-with-broncos-after-leaving-knights/105885604</link><description>NSW State of Origin halfback Jesse Southwell's two-year deal with the Brisbane Broncos may add to the debate about the NRLW's competitiveness since it expanded to 12 teams.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abe905c2182f063b37016dc4e7f38ab5</guid></item><item><title>Lidia Thorpe's 'burn down Parliament House' remark faces AFP probe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/afp-investigating-lidia-thorpe-burn-down-parliament-house/105885602</link><description>The Australian Federal Police has issued a rare statement confirming it is investigating whether independent senator Lidia Thorpe broke any laws by saying she was prepared to "burn down Parliament House" in support of Palestinians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2fccb71564f1bd7edfc068317149745</guid></item><item><title>Former teacher Rodney Neville Watkins guilty of sexually abusing boys in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/teacher-rodney-neville-watkins-sex-abuse-trial-verdict/105874798</link><description>A former teacher is found guilty of sexually abusing primary school-aged boys in Perth, and one on Rottnest Island, in the 1970s in 1980s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">699b38068724bae2768d7a3807fbfbae</guid></item><item><title>Hamas releases all remaining Israeli hostages in Gaza, IDF confirms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/hamas-releases-all-remaining-israeli-hostages-in-gaza/105885332</link><description>Israel says Hamas has handed over all 20 living hostages in the first phase of the Israel-Gaza ceasefire agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1da4a5a9ff5c0b24b017021965f0b640</guid></item><item><title>Dolphin calf rescued after spending weeks tangled in fishing line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/dolphin-calf-rescued-from-fishing-line-at-forster/105884112</link><description>Marine rescuers issue an urgent plea for people to responsibly dispose of fishing gear after freeing a dolphin calf from a fishing line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90d0d7d157b2b4ce3c86f1c7a19eb88c</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Diamonds mindful they need to lift against New Zealand's Silver Ferns in Constellation Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/constellation-cup-australia-new-zealand-diamonds-silver-ferns/105885876</link><description>Despite the comfortable series win over South Africa, Australia is mindful it will need to step up a gear in the Constellation Cup against New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5fb5d579d17d83c75a2e69cee809c80</guid></item><item><title>Tatiana Dokhotaru told triple-0 her ex-partner was 'trying to kill' her before alleged murder, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/danny-zayat-trial-for-alleged-murder-tatiana-dokhotaru-liverpool/105885166</link><description>Danny Zayat has pleaded not guilty over the alleged murder of his former partner Tatiana Dokhotaru on May 26, 2023, in a high-rise complex in Sydney's south-west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97587d3d724a31ef37090e00aaebbacd</guid></item><item><title>Woodside North West Shelf gas project extension challenged in Federal Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/federal-court-appeals-over-woodside-north-west-shelf-extension/105884752</link><description>Two separate appeals are launched in the Federal Court in a bid to overturn Environment Minister Murray Watt's approval of Woodside's gas hub extension on the North West Shelf.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">342bee27bf9dff6d11dddd935c41d8df</guid></item><item><title>SA Premier says algal bloom is not 'toxic', despite word appearing in official government advice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/algal-bloom-not-toxic-sa-premier-says/105884118</link><description>South Australia's Premier has questioned the use of the word "toxic" to describe the state's ongoing algal bloom, despite the word being used in government advice and by scientists researching it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0743c8445b475273de4ae2bd594c0830</guid></item><item><title>John Torney's mother gives evidence in his manslaughter committal hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/john-torney-committal-hearing-emma-bates/105883888</link><description>John Torney's committal hearing begins as his mother tells the court she was the one who called police to check on the woman before her body was found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27f97cc7b1bc58b7979769f5ce683c9f</guid></item><item><title>Who's in and who's out in Sussan Ley's new shadow cabinet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/shadow-cabinet-reshuffle-federal-politics-ley-hastie-duniam/105886202</link><description>The changes follow two high-profile departures from shadow cabinet within a month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04f8fd366d0a2f3ed19841529ba4629a</guid></item><item><title>Inside Victoria's escalating crime wave, where a car is reported stolen to insurers every 44 minutes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/victoria-carjacking-rises-as-families-left-on-edge/105885482</link><description>A rise in car theft and carjackings in this state has also seen parents left terrorised as cars are taken with their children inside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1d8b1d3339f8fa66e6e20ad33fdcab3</guid></item><item><title>New testimony seeks to shed light on mysterious death of Mark Haines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/mark-haines-inquest-returns-for-fifth-week-of-hearings/105134566</link><description>An inquest has heard evidence contradicting the story told by a driver whose crashed car was found near the body of Mark Anthony Haines almost four decades ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0254cc5f1992da32e9ae401f0ebbfed7</guid></item><item><title>Frustration mounts among Qantas customers as personal data released on dark web</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/frustration-mounts-among-qantas-customers-over-data-breach/105885312</link><description>The airline's customers voice their concerns and disappointment after cybercriminals release their personal data on the dark web.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b231e8012746670f061284735b7d6e0</guid></item><item><title>Victoria is in the grip of a car theft crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/victoria-is-in-the-grip-of-a-car-theft-crisis/105886626</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c8d1572c5790bacdcf9f046246b9f89</guid></item><item><title>Government overhauls its proposed superannuation changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/government-overhauls-its-proposed-superannuation/105886646</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7832422b564ea7c9e914c9d44a5a76f6</guid></item><item><title>Queensland council loses $2 million in alleged international fraud incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/queensland-council-alleged-victim-international-fraud/105886682</link><description>Noosa Council alleges it was targeted by "international criminal gangs" in December last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a81b0adf1072bdc643391700c8d3dc7</guid></item><item><title>Released Israeli hostages wave at crowds as they arrive at hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/released-israeli-hostages-arrive-at-hospital/105886776</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">818105ab787786e2c78fa5d4f2be0c23</guid></item><item><title>Israeli hostages reunite with their loved ones</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/israeli-hostages-reunite-with-their-loved-ones/105886836</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02d664b5e02fdd144286753ad07b004f</guid></item><item><title>Jared Kushner's ties to the Middle East go far beyond diplomacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/jared-kushner-diplomacy-investment-middle-east-real-estate/105862606</link><description>The US president's son-in-law had little diplomatic or successful investment management experience before helping to broker the Gaza ceasefire deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e80b125b4a710b1ae8957f6fa131ce2c</guid></item><item><title>Corporate watchdog slams superannuation funds on 'customer service', communications with retirees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/corporate-watchdog-asic-slams-super-funds-customer-service/105885474</link><description>ASIC's review of 12 super funds collectively responsible for more $1.2 trillion in member assets finds they are failing in customer service and communications, and may not be giving members information to make informed retirement decisions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">780cd3ed2fb645b79ac84aec52bde554</guid></item><item><title>'We have won': Trump hails ceasefire deal in address to Knesset</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/we-have-won-trump-hails-ceasefire-deal-in-knesset-speech/105887354</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4d4881a538f91f6662d1801c4e424ad</guid></item><item><title>Trump heralds 'new beginning' for Middle East</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/trump-heralds-in-new-beginning-for-middle-east/105887360</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abcba0de3ca7736d6aaa21008fbb6016</guid></item><item><title>England provides the blueprint for 2029 Women's Rugby World Cup in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/rugby-world-cup-women-england-wallaroos/105874404</link><description>The recently concluded Women's Rugby World Cup in England took the game to new heights. But, as Alicia Lucas writes, Australia needs to take big strides to ensure its hosting of the tournament in 2029 continues to raise the bar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b19337aaae0b20b96cc6cd07fe6cffb7</guid></item><item><title>US and Arab countries sign deal throwing support behind Gaza ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/israel-gaza-ceasefire-us-trump-deal-arab-countries/105887224</link><description>The deal comes as one group representing hostages accuses Hamas of breaching aspects of the ceasefire agreement, with the remains of 24 hostages yet to be returned to Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ec5c2bc5161b8e45516c12dc73fa2f2</guid></item><item><title>Modelling shows gas project emissions will cause hundreds of heat-related deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/fossil-fuel-climate-impact-study-models-heatwave-deaths/105870098</link><description>Fossil fuel companies and governments argue it's not possible to link climate impacts to specific projects, but Australian researchers have done the numbers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2d5647990e49e0294d580166c094c07</guid></item><item><title>Emotional reunions during hostage-prisoner exchange between Israel, Hamas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/emotional-reunions-during-hostage-prisoner-exchange/105887370</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd24f63c836bfe278cba517857117ed8</guid></item><item><title>Why Santos is behind your soaring electricity and mortgage costs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/why-santos-is-behind-your-soaring-electricity-and-mortgage-costs/105885202</link><description>It was a primary force behind Australia’s inflationary surge, it’s forced businesses either to the wall or to shift offshore, undermined national industry policy and resulted in the loss of countless thousands of jobs. And it all hinged on one disastrous decision in an Adelaide boardroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">103585cee22276b5b682cf9cc4c3ec88</guid></item><item><title>Outback golf tournament brings together 150 players to support Royal Flying Doctor Service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/north-moolooloo-station-golf-classic-rfds-fundraiser/105885132</link><description>There are no manicured greens in sight, but this golf tournament brings more than 150 players to an outback sheep station to raise funds for the Royal Flying Doctor Service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba5593cb8043d656cd820fd84f44f406</guid></item><item><title>Advocates call for better measure of poverty, saying Australia's approach falls short</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/calls-to-measure-how-many-australians-live-in-poverty/105862926</link><description>We get detailed measurements of population, participation and productivity. Advocates want to add a fourth "p" — poverty — so we can understand our economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09b9c5ac7057df2484a85462c70d727f</guid></item><item><title>Hamas returns some bodies of hostages to Israel as Trump hails peace — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/israel-gaza-hamas-ceasefire-october-14/105886534</link><description>Israel's military says Hamas has returned the bodies of four hostages from Gaza, with the remains of 24 others yet to be returned — as it happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83968a4078992a41c9ee341aa9aa93a8</guid></item><item><title>The political theatre of Donald Trump's Middle East trip masks glaring questions about the peace plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/donald-trump-motivations-for-gaza-peace-deal-crucial-for-future/105884836</link><description>Donald Trump's unconventional and often haphazard approach to diplomacy means there are countless questions about what has driven him to date, and what might determine whether he stays engaged in the Middle East peace process in the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d711918a0f392be9269eff374938c3b</guid></item><item><title>Youth crime rates in the bush still high as leaders look for solutions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/inquiry-searches-for-solutions-to-regional-youth-crime/105839372</link><description>Official figures show youth crime is decreasing across NSW, but that does not ring true in some rural communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">123913d2e8ea9f90bf4ab88828346b14</guid></item><item><title>Cape Verde qualifies for 2026 FIFA World Cup in United States, Canada and Mexico</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/cape-verde-qualifies-for-2026-fifa-world-cup/105887380</link><description>Cape Verde will play in the men's FIFA World Cup for the first time after beating Eswatini 3-0 to win its group in African qualifying for the 2026 showpiece.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a68c49530029934617e84ae8ecd3b5f</guid></item><item><title>Convoy carrying hostage bodies return to Israel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/convoy-carrying-hostage-bodies-return-to-israel/105887450</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34235d76fbbef52e55e47c303b184317</guid></item><item><title>After 738 days, Israelis share mixed emotions as hostages are released from Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/israelis-shared-mixed-emotions-in-hostage-square/105887218</link><description>Israelis gather to watch a historic day unfold as hostages held for two years are finally set free.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf68b9df5ada430b879c7ac27176cd9a</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Chalmers, Keating spoke 'half a dozen times' ahead of super U-turn — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/federal-politics-live-blog-oct-14/105886082</link><description>Treasurer Jim Chalmers confirms he spoke with former prime minister Paul Keating last week ahead of the government's U-turn on superannuation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3c45ced41e4a31dd0fefa6b1b2aacf3</guid></item><item><title>Roblox wants exemption from social media ban despite evidence of predators targeting children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/social-media-ban-roblox-predators-access-online-gaming-platform/105884322</link><description>Experts warn Roblox has a predator problem, amid reports Australian children are being exposed to a range of disturbing experiences on the platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f02d3f9a9d7f28e496b39c07746ced7</guid></item><item><title>NT government accused of 'turning a blind eye' to gas company's alleged environmental breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/alleged-environmental-law-breach-nt-beetaloo-basin-gas-company/105854186</link><description>A gas company operating in the Northern Territory has been accused of breaching environmental laws by an NT government department, which decided against prosecution in favour of a formal letter encouraging "behaviour change".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c52c0271aad0cf9daffab8391d37b37</guid></item><item><title>How to help kids prepare for music exams and competitions and manage performance anxiety</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/music-exam-competition-manage-performance-anxiety/105873254</link><description>Music exams and competitions aren't easy, but our experts have some tips to make the process as stress-free as possible, including managing performance anxiety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ce54e25b952b97ee1ce5b2b5c2b6f1c</guid></item><item><title>Chalmers wielded the axe on his super tax, but the PM's fingerprints were obvious</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/chalmers-retreat-on-super-tax-had-prime-minister-behind-it/105886080</link><description>The treasurer has never been afraid to venture beyond his prime minister with his tax reform ambitions, but on superannuation, he has been pulled into line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4152bdb0b9ceed06054c180a355d7942</guid></item><item><title>Fresh doubts over plans to boost Perth's tree canopy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/fresh-doubts-over-plan-for-perth-tree-canopy/105886692</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eeff764a51281b1a24aecd32b078248f</guid></item><item><title>Six NRL players named in England rugby league Ashes sqaud, Man of Steel winner not selected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/six-nrl-players-named-in-england-rugby-league-ashes-sqaud/105887552</link><description>Six NRL players are in the England rugby league squad for the upcoming Ashes series against Australia, but there's no room for the most consistent player of the Super League season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78de8086dd1c502899a17e878f7658b2</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, day seven recap: Zach Merrett, Charlie Curnow and Christian Petracca waiting for deals, Brayden Fiorini goes to Bombers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/afl-trade-period-day-seven-live-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca/105886172</link><description>The big three of Zach Merrett, Charlie Curnow and Christian Petracca remain in limbo with one day left in the trade period, with Brayden Fiorini going from Gold Coast to Essendon the main move of the day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a857679f1703f600b143ca6bda2e17c5</guid></item><item><title>Generator trial to address mobile phone tower outages during WA emergencies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/mobile-phone-power-outages-during-emergencies-generator-trial-wa/105835910</link><description>Rural communities battling power cuts to mobile towers during natural disasters are being offered a temporary solution with a trial of community-operated generators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4ff5e0410778619fa307c454be94887</guid></item><item><title>Alexei Popyrin defeated in ATP Tour Stockholm Open by American Sebastian Korda</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/alexei-popyrin-defeated-in-atp-tour-stockholm-open/105887672</link><description>Alexei Popyrin's ATP Tour return has ended with defeat as Australia's second-highest-ranked men's player returns following a back injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">886c345c6250bdf03fcbbc00174f57fb</guid></item><item><title>Linda Reynolds launches bankruptcy proceedings against Brittany Higgins after defamation win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/brittany-higgins-faces-bankruptcy-proceedings-linda-reynolds/105887676</link><description>Former senator Linda Reynolds files a creditor's petition in the Federal Court against her ex-staffer, Brittany Higgins, as she tries to recover damages awarded to her for defamation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73d83a01246222ea001cb02d5ce0a719</guid></item><item><title>Midnight Oil fans rally to keep Rob Hirst's drum kit 'in public hands' at charity auction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/midnight-oil-fans-secure-rob-hirsts-drum-kit-at-charity-auction/105887566</link><description>Midnight Oil drummer Rob Hirst auctions off the kit, which he has had since 1979, saying he can no longer play it because of his battle with pancreatic cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4b1a250f2c50ae072e79e344e2dc5fa</guid></item><item><title>Plans for national art gallery in Alice Springs scrapped after government rift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/nt-aboriginal-and-torres-strait-islander-art-alice-springs/105887842</link><description>The Northern Territory government scraps controversial plans to build the Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Art Gallery of Australia in Alice Springs after nine years of back and forth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">218dcceb9a72a6805cd42afc69e27584</guid></item><item><title>Tougher jail sentences needed to address record crime in Victoria, police union says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/victoria-police-union-tougher-entences-amid-record-crime/105885870</link><description>The Police Association welcomes the Victorian chief commissioner's new strategy to get more officers on the streets, but says tougher sentences the only effective solution to crime crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff15f598398e5ebea840ccf5adf8f929</guid></item><item><title>Endangered powerful owl among 'sound bath' of bird calls captured by recordings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/powerful-owls-recorded-for-bird-sound-bath/105884696</link><description>Powerful owls prey on possums, and even koalas, but local bird watchers are excited by the discovery of new pairs in South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aff96e27d81dfb12e8372bce926a4ef6</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after alleged carjackings, dramatic pursuit in Melbourne CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/melbourne-cbd-man-arrested-alleged-carjacking-pursuit/105887978</link><description>Police say the gun a man pointed at people in Melbourne on Tuesday was a fake firearm. They have charged him with multiple offences following an alleged carjacking spree through the city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb56ed39fee7ce84638882ce3d7e784b</guid></item><item><title>When to share the news of a pregnancy with your employer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/when-to-share-the-news-of-a-pregnancy-with-your-employer/105865350</link><description>Experts on the rules around when you need to inform your employer if you’re planning to take parental leave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdd7ceffb7b18af44c36f8079e6d9e03</guid></item><item><title>Australia call up Josh Philippe and Matt Kuhnemann for ODI against India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/australia-call-up-josh-philippe-and-matt-kuhnemann/105888558</link><description>Josh Philippe is set to play his first ODI for Australia in four years, after Josh Inglis failed to recover from his calf strain in time for the series opener against India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8aab5eb6aeaedbaf7d2b9dcae9ce4d44</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Liberals to scrap statewide Treaty if elected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/victoria-liberal-opposition-first-peoples-treaty-scrapped/105888108</link><description>The Victorian Liberals will scrap the state's proposed Treaty agreement with First Peoples' if elected. The opposition had previously withdrawn support for the proposed agreement, which is set to be debated in Parliament today and is expected to pass with the support of Labor and the Greens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9edab1601aa5d33e9c3320c6b3914639</guid></item><item><title>Dave Hughes back in hospital with lung issues six weeks after AFL Legends match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/dave-hughes-hospital-again-afl-legends-game/105888798</link><description>Comedian Dave Hughes has returned to hospital, six weeks after suffering five broken ribs and a punctured lung in the AFL's Legends game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93a8308251a6c7103b1ea07bf46519bf</guid></item><item><title>Governments announce full details of $102.5m algal bloom summer plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/sa-summer-plan-announced-state-algal-bloom/105887504</link><description>Large scale reef restoration, new real-time water monitoring and a $1 million trial of "AI-powered submersible cytobots" are part of a $102.5 million government algal bloom program to ensure "South Australians can enjoy their summer".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c633c7e72d90c62a5362f4c5d30fb14d</guid></item><item><title>The Hobart Clinic offered government funding lifeline to stay open for six months</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/hobart-clinic-offered-funding-lifeline-government/105871126</link><description>A southern Tasmanian private mental health clinic will remain open for at least six months after securing $2 million in government funding while it explores a new business model.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35cc0c7b5d6ca1be32aa4ab4247addc4</guid></item><item><title>Woman dies in house fire at Bellingen, west of Coffs Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/coffs-house-fire-death-police/105887620</link><description>A 78-year-old woman escapes a blaze on the NSW Mid North Coast, but the body of another woman — believed to be her daughter who lived with disability — is later found inside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c263f9380650c4b74a704c9e2cd778e</guid></item><item><title>Children under 16 will soon be banned from social media — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/under-16s-social-media-ban-explored-in-digital-dilemma-blog/105884486</link><description>From December, children under 16 will be blocked from accessing social media. Take a look back at our live coverage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87501dff82daeea05a09dc513bd643ab</guid></item><item><title>Mount Buffalo National Park reopens as search for alleged gunman Dezi Freeman continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/mount-buffalo-national-park-partially-reopens-freeman-search/105888550</link><description>Victoria Police says its search for alleged gunman Dezi Freeman will continue as the Mount Buffalo National Park partially reopens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0df5fd73ab4cb55f61d65dbab1ec7cb6</guid></item><item><title>Homicide detectives investigate discovery of man's body in Armidale</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/homicide-detectives-investigate-suspicious-death-in-armidale/105888230</link><description>Police are eager to speak to a second man who was taken to hospital, after the body of a man believed to be in his 70s was found at a home on the NSW northern tablelands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bb60e25f7c21b566ee4cbadd58042fe</guid></item><item><title>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese's mobile phone number made available online</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/anthony-albanese-mobile-phone-number-available-online/105889284</link><description>Sussan Ley and other prominent Australians are among those whose details have also been made available on a US-based website.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8575617fd69a49f6fd196271d2ecccdb</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Antarctic icebreaker RSV Nuyina 'makes contact with ocean floor' near remote Heard Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/icebreaker-nuyina-scrapes-ocean-floor-near-heard-island/105888904</link><description>Antarctic icebreaker RSV Nuyina has headed to deeper waters off remote Heard Island in the Southern Ocean while assessments are undertaken to see if the hull has suffered any damage after scraping the ocean floor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebfe574522a440336bd83f4b4bd7906e</guid></item><item><title>Paul Kelly on the songs that inspire him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/paul-kelly-influences-archie-roach-go-betweens/105840822</link><description>As the 70-year-old songwriter prepares his 30th album, he talks about the music that has driven him creatively.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeb74292394ee123f769e46166b7fd50</guid></item><item><title>Former Collingwood coach Nathan Buckley to join Geelong as assistant coach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/nathan-buckley-moves-back-into-coaching-with-surprise-cats-role/105889810</link><description>Nathan Buckley takes a surprise assistant coaching job as the Collingwood legend awaits on a likely offer to lead Tasmania's inaugural AFL team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fd3d52a338ea52e945304cb458dc004</guid></item><item><title>Australia hosts hottest place on Earth, but here's why it's not a heatwave yet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/australia-hosts-hottest-place-on-earth/105888248</link><description>Parts of Pilbara and Kimberley surpassed 40 degrees Celsius yesterday but meteorologists say the temperatures will not trigger a heatwave warning yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d5466674485d37a8a2a5d373d647f80</guid></item><item><title>Almost 130 people dead or missing in Mexico floods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/dozens-dead-after-torrential-rains-lash-mexico/105889300</link><description>The death toll from flooding in Mexico's central region has risen to 64, with another 65 people missing, according to the Mexican government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8015efd23b16e6fafd30e13d802aae13</guid></item><item><title>Nikita Tszyu recovering after suffering 'minor injuries' following a car accident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/nikita-tszyu-recovering-after-car-accident/105890074</link><description>Nikita Tszyu was involved in a car accident last weekend, putting a possible grudge match fight against Michael Zerafa at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca27801adbd0c4b78e8ad6edbc13d224</guid></item><item><title>Noosa mayor says fraudsters used AI imitation in $2.3m council scam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/noosa-council-scam-mayor-blames-ai-imitation/105887962</link><description>The mayor of a small council that lost nearly $2 million in a "sophisticated" scam says international fraudsters were able to "imitate personalities" using AI.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ad393b46f5cfb4651924cd453233651</guid></item><item><title>Eugowra flood inquest hears evidence of a 'day of hell'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/eugowra-flood-inquest-day-two-hears-of-inland-tsunami/105887756</link><description>A Eugowra resident tells an inquest into deadly flooding how she put her six-day-old granddaughter in a roof cavity after a wave of water hit the Central West town, killing two people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d6a5ec2b5dd8ff9a04b9d8f7c7f8998</guid></item><item><title>WA Police investigating after man fatally injured in Hocking in Perth's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/wa-police-investigating-after-man-injured-in-hocking/105889242</link><description>A man is in custody and homicide detectives are investigating following the death of a man in Perth's northern suburbs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">841b94009ba276cbc8a8f1eed7a0f878</guid></item><item><title>Used car dealer Alexander Hallett fined $25,000 for winding back car odometers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/alexander-hallett-used-car-sales-odometer-fraud/105889740</link><description>Alexander Thomas Hallett pleaded guilty to winding back a total of 648,000 kilometres on the odometers of seven vehicles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94c33e5687ddd173e64734786537d735</guid></item><item><title>Bridget Archer announces funding for Hobart Clinic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/bridget-archer-announces-funding-for-hobart-clinic/105890098</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb1b30d865a9a239f2642a4dd843222b</guid></item><item><title>Roblox 'taken to task' but may not be included in social media ban, says eSafety commissioner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/esafety-commissioner-social-media-ban-roblox/105889222</link><description>Australia's eSafety commissioner says her team has "taken Roblox to task" over its risk of exposing children to harm but warned the online gaming platform may not be included in the upcoming social media ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db4b3f6eea6b606948efa08757097591</guid></item><item><title>Suggestion AFLW being used as a 'trial run' for new rules causes frustration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/frustration-as-aflw-used-as-trial-run-for-new-rules-for-afl-mens/105889756</link><description>Collingwood's Tarni White says it feels as though the women's competition is being used as a trial run for new rules before they are implemented into the men's league.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22b2ee856b6c7691dbc3cfbefcc9b672</guid></item><item><title>Inquest continues into death of energy worker mauled by dogs at Logan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/kane-minion-dog-attack-meter-reader-inquest/105889012</link><description>After meter reader Kane Minion was fatally mauled by dogs at a Queensland property, the Coroners Court hears details about the electricity provider's work procedures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01182291988c671db501930a1e01bf14</guid></item><item><title>Victory in Socceroos' friendly against United States could ease World Cup draw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/socceroos-friendly-against-us-could-impact-world-cup-draw/105890480</link><description>The Socceroos' friendly against the United States is a positive step in their World Cup preparation, while a positive result could also influence their tournament draw.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">818fc0fb7ab727bff2ff2f14d8091448</guid></item><item><title>Parts of Coffs Coast Wildlife Sanctuary evacuated due to 'highly venomous' sea snake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/coffs-coast-wildlife-sanctaury-evacuated-due-to-sea-snake/105888174</link><description>Visitors to a northern New South Wales wildlife sanctuary were forced to evacuate after a woman brought in a rescued sea snake, one of the world's deadliest reptiles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf19e8dfb92ca49756f2b5a4a596a77f</guid></item><item><title>John Torney's brother tells court he knew 'how violent' accused could be</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/john-torney-emma-bates-negligent-manslaughter-witnesses-cobram/105888568</link><description>The brother of a man accused of negligent manslaughter has told a Victorian court that he knew how violent his brother could be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a3cf30b506b640dc3f99cde8cfa328e</guid></item><item><title>As illicit tobacco sales rise into the billions, economist Arthur Laffer puts blame on high tobacco taxation rate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/illegal-tobacco-sales-billions-arthur-laffer-critiques-australia/105873994</link><description>Internal tobacco industry data estimates the illicit tobacco market now makes up 64 per cent of all tobacco consumed in Australia and 82 per cent of the total nicotine consumed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d4469b8b84f45d625bbb2ec0086b843</guid></item><item><title>Police officer had 'high likelihood of PTSD' at time of death, inquest told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/inquest-into-death-of-sa-police-officer-benjamin-warren/105887870</link><description>A coronial inquest will explore whether the 2022 death of SA Police Senior Constable Benjamin Edward Warren could have been prevented if his mental health issues had been identified.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd13e8e347a708108fd3eddb6aa8ea74</guid></item><item><title>Indie film producers tell SXSW Sydney about how to survive and thrive making horror</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/sxsw-sydney-indie-producers-on-how-to-survive-making-horror-film/105890988</link><description>Horror films can be a great training ground for filmmakers, but there is also a gritty reality, a panel of indie producers tells SXSW Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1c6edf129ce345474e049a6b56c5528</guid></item><item><title>Body-worn camera shows Tatiana Dokhotaru's ex-partner wailing at crime scene</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/danny-zayat-alleged-trial-murder-trial-camera-evidence/105890906</link><description>The jury on Tuesday was played several police body-worn camera videos of a wailing Danny Zayat with officers at the scene when police found his ex-partner's body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">029ab8b3ccd887a64682f88b949b1341</guid></item><item><title>WA's flu season exceeds 30,000 cases as authorities blame low vaccination rates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/wa-flu-season-worst-ever-poor-vaccination-rates/105891252</link><description>Western Australia records its worst flu season on record, with more than 30,000 influenza cases reported this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f1f2484096733debed58e21c7b6682</guid></item><item><title>Abducted by Hamas, Noa never lost hope she would see her 'soulmate' again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/noa-argamani-avinatan-or-hamas-hostages-freed/105890692</link><description>Noa and Avinatan's abduction from a music festival became an enduring illustration of the horrors endured by Israelis on October 7. Now safely in each other's arms, a chapter has closed on a harrowing two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e795ebb238cdbebca7f0fd0bfe11d9d4</guid></item><item><title>Truck driver to face trial over fatal 2024 Bulli Pass crash in Thirroul</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/truck-driver-mosa-vaimalu-thirroul-crash-bulli-pass/105891118</link><description>Mosa Vaimalu has pleaded not guilty to charges of dangerous driving over the crash that left one man dead and two people seriously injured.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0401d99c8fd303913beabe8d29ea20d</guid></item><item><title>Concerns teenagers in regional West Australia face further isolation as social media ban looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/regional-teens-left-lonely/105888190</link><description>Advocates are concerned rural and remote children will experience compounding challenges with the looming social media ban for people under 16.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1170b18fc2aa14fb4b4494d3cfed0a2f</guid></item><item><title>Correspondent Eric Tlozek in Ramallah when 80 Palestinian prisoners were released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/correspondent-eric-tlozek-in-ramallah-when-80/105890214</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87ffa977c5e6ad6bbabc2ef68f45a988</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian prisoners reunite with loved ones in Gaza and West Bank, many alleging mistreatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/freed-prisoners-detainees-reunited-in-gaza-and-west-bank/105885078</link><description>Nearly 2,000 Palestinians who were imprisoned in Israel have been reunited with their families as part of an exchange for hostages held by Hamas in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac15bd7ffe224e45bb90bb8c1ae75550</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105891880</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">653774c141b651a45c0a8cb8f098cded</guid></item><item><title>Senior conservative James Paterson cautions Liberal Party against splitting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/james-paterson-urges-liberals-not-to-break-up-farage-teal/105888150</link><description>In a major address to his party, James Paterson says "marginal" voices agitating for the Liberal party to split must be kept on the sidelines, cautioning it would spell "disaster".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b19c93195b4681ddf79b775907477599</guid></item><item><title>Allegedly armed man who sparked hours-long lockdown of Brisbane City Botanic Gardens in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/queensland-police-lockdown-brisbane-botanic-gardens/105890698</link><description>The Brisbane City Botanic Gardens shuts down for three hours as police respond to reports of a man allegedly wielding a weapon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">998c22d5709a1a7dcf5c01a200df488e</guid></item><item><title>ACT Director of Public Prosecutions says she may have to turn away some cases if funding not increased</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/act-top-prosecutor-concerned-cases-may-be-dropped/105889058</link><description>The ACT Director of Public Prosecutions says her office does not have enough funding to deal with an increasing annual case load of more than 23,000 charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">847e8e82d9373bc775e40e74105a64c0</guid></item><item><title>Man once accused of murder of three tourists in Mount Isa in 1978 gives evidence at inquest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/qld-cold-case-trial-mount-isa-178-bruce-preston/105888178</link><description>Bruce Preston was once accused of killing three tourists in Mount Isa in 1978, but the prosecution was later dropped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e198e1fb969f369c602495130d92610</guid></item><item><title>South Sydney Rabbitohs player Tyrone Munro charged with domestic violence offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/rabbitohs-player-tyrone-munro-charged-domestic-violence-offences/105891952</link><description>New South Wales Police launched an investigation on Monday after a woman reported she had been assaulted by her partner near Homebush in April 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42571ab1bfc50d6fa43bac1c5791bffe</guid></item><item><title>Five takeaways from the ABC's Your Say: The Digital Dilemma forum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/abc-your-say-the-digital-dilemma-key-takeaways/105890184</link><description>An emotional plea to the country, concerns about privacy and how Australia's social media ban will actually work. These are the key takeaways from the ABC's Your Say: The Digital Dilemma forum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de6e80e7d191490fa6fdf7119bf8ab6e</guid></item><item><title>Bangladesh garment factory fire kills 16, toll may rise, official says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/bangladesh-factory-fire-kills-at-least-sixteen-people/105892400</link><description>At least 16 people have died after a fire broke out in a garment factory and a nearby chemical warehouse in Bangladesh.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8a2de734e13c2a9c78c22f302808120</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar military says it is seizing power after president flees country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/madagascar-military-takes-control-coup-president-flee/105892454</link><description>The country's parliament voted to impeach President Andry Rajoelina after he fled the country in the face of growing opposition from soldiers and police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55efccf0b4c7a9354d313eee5adbd18d</guid></item><item><title>Victorian councils call on state government to strengthen trial aimed at preventing gambling harm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/gambling-harm-prevention-trial-yourplay-card-criticism/105865050</link><description>Victorian councils taking part in a trial of account-based play at pokies venues say they're disappointed with the state government's handling of the scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7908f4da03b11575b3818fb735f838e</guid></item><item><title>An embarrassing backflip by Chalmers on super or a strategic shift?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/was-chalmers-taught-a-lesson-in-his-fight-over-superannuation/105891400</link><description>After two years of refusing to reshape his superannuation shake-up, the treasurer abandons the idea of taxing unrealised gains while agreeing to index a key tax threshold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81f26bfccf07023bc6ed3051fab482c2</guid></item><item><title>LNP government criticised over new 'jobs for mates' appointment of party powerbroker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/lnp-government-faces-new-jobs-for-mates-controversy/105885154</link><description>Queensland's Crisafulli government is embroiled in a new "jobs for mates" claim after it appointed a Liberal National Party powerbroker to oversee the state's lead agency for disaster recovery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c4a2974cdf74d5e986c5d44d0d027b3</guid></item><item><title>Petrol prices vary across Australia, but discrepancies of 50cpl are prompting calls for an investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/petrol-prices-vastly-different-regional-areas-to-capital-cities/105834588</link><description>Industry experts say there is no excuse for wild variations in fuel prices across Australia, as calls grow for an independent investigation into the disparity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08519c15836f9f4cf74aa4c6d7c3e5c8</guid></item><item><title>Why does SA have a summer plan for the algal bloom and what's in it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/sa-government-algal-bloom-summer-plan-explained/105888438</link><description>The full details of South Australia's algal bloom summer plan which aims to ensure South Australians can "enjoy their summer" were released yesterday. The plan includes measures to protect the state's coast while supporting businesses and communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17101f197978ee94d6b7eece79d9f8c2</guid></item><item><title>Hamas releases more remains of hostages as video of executions in Gaza emerges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/donald-trump-warns-hamas-it-could-be-disarmed-violently/105892558</link><description>US President Donald Trump warns Hamas it must disarm or be forced to as the militant group hands over the remains of four more hostages to Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f7a4b0bab8c00ab36055828f418364a</guid></item><item><title>Military stages coup in Madagascar, overthrows president</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/military-stages-coup-in-madagascar/105892654</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4926bb338c0372aca240ba20363172f5</guid></item><item><title>Should Donald Trump be thanked for the Gaza ceasefire and hostage releases?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/donald-trump-should-not-be-thanked-for-the-gaza-ceasefire/105887220</link><description>Instead of thanking the US president, perhaps people should be asking: why are the hostages only coming home now?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c31148dce22a547e7a3c0c77101654a2</guid></item><item><title>Illegal fishing is awash in the Timor and Arafura seas. Discarded 'ghost nets' kill wildlife and destroy Australia's pristine coastline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/ghost-nets-illegal-fishing-ruining-australias-coastline/105866280</link><description>Illegal fishing is ravaging the world's oceans of fish and shellfish but it is what is left behind that is creating a mess for governments worldwide and of Australia's most remote beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">901328bed07a1a655e86383c38104df6</guid></item><item><title>Why has support for One Nation surged since the federal election, and will it last?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/why-is-one-nation-surging-in-the-polls/105891732</link><description>Polling has support for One Nation somewhere between 10 and 14 per cent, much higher than during the federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c43c33890df5288dbdfac2f8600cb8e7</guid></item><item><title>Shadow drone war against European NATO countries blamed by many on Russia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/russias-shadow-drone-war-against-europe-nato-explained/105867182</link><description>Peaceful European NATO nations that support Ukraine are repeatedly being targeted by mysterious drone incursions, and experts say dozens in the past month appear to have links to Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39efadfabfc28494bc51c4860815a47c</guid></item><item><title>Trump threatens violent measures if Hamas does not disarm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/trump-threatens-violent-measures-if-hamas-does-not-disarm/105892680</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">893785d971380f5a919cf0d340fc3f22</guid></item><item><title>Major study finds tooth decay in Queensland children has declined since water fluoridation expanded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/qld-fluoride-water-tooth-decay-study-rates-plummet/105888306</link><description>The findings are released as more Queensland councils opt out of water fluoridation and amid rising rates of misinformation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dd17fcb3a19584bd9c12acde3b2b3a0</guid></item><item><title>US Supreme Court upholds $2.1b ruling against conspiracy theorist Alex Jones</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/alex-jones-appeal-supreme-court-appeal-rejected/105892560</link><description>The Infowars host claims the 2012 Sandy Hook Elementary School shooting, which claimed the lives of 20 first year students, was a hoax.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d36f678c43614f4fcd24363c0fa5c10</guid></item><item><title>Forensic imaging revealing hidden layers under Sidney Nolan's Ned Kelly paintings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/act-revealing-hidden-layers-of-sidney-nolan-ned-kelly-paintings/105889294</link><description>Hidden figures and inscriptions are being discovered beneath some of Australia's most famous paintings as conservators use infrared technology to reveal details in Sidney Nolan's Ned Kelly series, unseen since the artist's own time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">571022a8dd0d719c04c7924d5d111407</guid></item><item><title>NSW chef Stephen Flelli vanished, leaving his debt-riddled companies behind. It wasn't the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/stephen-flelli-chef-warning-investors-staff-landlords-speak-out/105836000</link><description>After vanishing without a trace, this restaurateur reappeared a year later spruiking a shiny new investment opportunity. But there's just one problem.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd653f3d2b6b9ecdf277cd8e16596699</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos coach Kevin Walters pledges no Queensland bias in Ashes series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/nrl-kangaroos-england-australia-ashes-tests/105892660</link><description>Reece Walsh has built a compelling case for selection in the Kangaroos' starting line-up to face England, but coach Kevin Walters says he will not show favouritism towards the Maroons contingent in his squad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbaa2f074a49fcbe600576d71e6b56e2</guid></item><item><title>Nurse-led clinics allow Riverina GP practices to see more patients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/nurse-led-clinics-allow-riverina-gp-practices-see-more-patients/105833890</link><description>Nurses working at a medical centre in southern NSW are stepping onto the frontline of patient care to ease the burden on GPs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e37d85759053a23f650d0fc53f91c14f</guid></item><item><title>Red Cross convoy retrieves hostage bodies from Hamas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/red-cross-convoy-retrieves-hostage-bodies-from-hamas/105892776</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5117bad241d39447d052c4efcd09811d</guid></item><item><title>Roosters NRLW second-rower Aliyah Nasio banned for four matches after grand-final brawl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/nrlw-judiciary-sydney-roosters-aliyah-nasio-grand-final/105892698</link><description>The NRLW judiciary adds more pain to the Sydney Roosters' grand-final loss to the Brisbane Broncos, with forward Aliyah Nasio banned for four matches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df735a7a0032952d95db73388709cca1</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's fashion industry fears TasTAFE course cuts will impact creative pathways</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/tasmanian-young-fashion-designers-career-pathways/105887772</link><description>Under planned government cuts to vocational training in Tasmania, young aspiring creatives are worried about a loss of opportunity in their home state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82f5f9f78478f10675a08b7502145bd5</guid></item><item><title>Grammy-winning R&amp;B singer D'Angelo dies of cancer aged 51</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/grammy-winning-singer-dangelo-dies-aged-51/105892638</link><description>The Untitled (How Does It Feel) singer died after a long struggle with cancer, his family said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b3f3f79c82f23a9810f81db1f015302</guid></item><item><title>Regional developers cash in on the global gaming industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/regional-gaming-business-growth-pilbara-red-dog-studios/105790186</link><description>Better known for its gas and iron ore, the Pilbara hopes to add gaming to its list of local exports as internet access and technology improve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7464b0f15ce63829b17d4f0b08d239f8</guid></item><item><title>Dying mother loses life insurance after failing to declare UTI tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/dying-mother-loses-life-insurance-after-failing-to/105891944</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3a16fd23e92a2762fe66d3e28645c0c</guid></item><item><title>Failure to declare tests after urinary tract infection sees cancer patient's insurance voided</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/terminally-ill-woman-life-insurance-voided-over-paperwork/105872718</link><description>A terminal cancer patient is told her failure to declare a UTI has voided her insurance policies, leaving her struggling to pay her mortgage and care for her children in her final days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fdc30419a0a448c3301e9d5575cd819</guid></item><item><title>Safety liner under US military fuel tanks in Darwin still failing, weeks after NT government approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/nt-us-military-fuel-tanks-darwin-harbour-leaking-crowley/105888200</link><description>Groundwater is leaking through the safety liner under some of the fuel facility's 11 tanks, which were constructed unlawfully on Darwin Harbour without a building permit. It comes after the NT government approved the tanks for operation in September.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">627e6a3587a4a307ebe07cdecd0b2c9b</guid></item><item><title>Instagram to limit teens to PG-13 content, Meta says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/meta-says-instagram-to-limit-teens-to-pg-13-content/105892760</link><description>Teenagers on Instagram will be restricted to seeing PG-13 content by default and won't be able to change their settings without a parent's permission, Meta has announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e0832f9867ba2782c0e2be955113b10</guid></item><item><title>Coroner makes rare public statement as NSW records most Indigenous deaths in custody in a year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/nsw-coroner-confirms-12-first-nations-deaths-in-custody-2025/105890400</link><description>NSW Coroner Teresa O'Sullivan's rare public comment on the "entrenched over-representation" of Indigenous prisoners as the state records the most ever in a single year, is welcomed by the grieving family member of a man who died in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7425c8c84b1cdadda86460fb9f8cc6d</guid></item><item><title>LGBTQIA+ groups 'horrified' by NT leader's comments about not detaining transgender women in female prisons</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/nt-chief-minister-transgender-women-in-female-prisons-custody/105886668</link><description>The Northern Territory government has doubled down on its stance against detaining transgender women in female prisons, as a local LGBTQIA+ group says it is "horrified" by the comments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5c6096bc97eb511af2af935de227290</guid></item><item><title>RBA chief economist's inflation warning dims interest rate cut expectations, ASX rallies — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/asx-markets-business-live-news-october-15/105892830</link><description>The Reserve Bank's Sarah Hunter says underlying inflation was likely stronger than the RBA had anticipated last quarter, striking another blow to expectations of further interest rate cuts. The ASX has closed up 1 per cent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d280262bd5700ee2ba3a9bc44cc87c4f</guid></item><item><title>Victorian volunteer firefighter numbers grow despite levy angst</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/volunteer-firefighters-increase-despite-esvf-levy-angst/105877566</link><description>Despite resentment and anger from some farmers, the CFA says it's well prepared to deal with an elevated fire risk this spring and summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e9b673b6d8c693c6eb0c7c2ee51716d</guid></item><item><title>Stuart Broad says Australian cricket team at its 'weakest' ahead of Ashes series against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/ashes-australia-england-cricket-stuart-broad-pat-cummins/105892848</link><description>Stuart Broad lights the fuse ahead of the men's Ashes series, saying England has its best chance of winning in Australia since the 2010/11 series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">435e9edd78dfe8ebfb14be2d8d2c80ed</guid></item><item><title>Copper Coast Council threatens ratepayer with legal action over 'offensive' comment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/copper-coast-parking-defamation-letter-social-media-threat-sa/105848794</link><description>Parking on South Australia's Copper Coast is a hot-button issue with one resident saying he is "prepared to go to court" over comments made about council staff, which have been labelled "offensive" and "threatening".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf21f8b95585b50043f00d8bc90b7266</guid></item><item><title>Power outage knocks out Victoria's triple-0 dispatch software for several hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/software-failure-power-outage-affects-victoria-triple-0-response/105892758</link><description>Victoria's triple-0 dispatch software fails due to a power outage, forcing operators to take notes with pen and paper.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29d074bfc5b78adf04bcc060ad451cc5</guid></item><item><title>Prosthetics clients of Jack McDonald question what legal rights they have for compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/clients-of-artificial-eye-maker-jack-mcdonald-want-refund/105888342</link><description>A prosthetics provider has left Australians thousands of dollars out of pocket, some having to cope with ill-fitting or wrong-coloured fingers and eyes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58fd38cac408e72900a888d7ae781834</guid></item><item><title>Driver Joash Alec Green jailed for seven years over manslaughter of cousin in Pilbara highway crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/joash-alec-green-sentenced-seven-years-prison-manslaughter-crash/105891706</link><description>A Kimberley man is sentenced over the unlawful killing of his cousin in a road crash while attempting to overtake and under the influence of alcohol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48a8afc5adc682d4a6da817803c68855</guid></item><item><title>Herald Sun defends reporting as court battle approaches with Liberal MP Sam Groth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/herald-sun-defends-sam-brittany-groth-defamation-lawsuit/105891364</link><description>The Herald Sun newspaper has defended its reporting about deputy leader of the Victorian Liberal Party Sam Groth and his wife as it prepares for a defamation lawsuit in the Federal Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de3cff4a79dae9f15bc556f295a7249c</guid></item><item><title>Regional Victorian farmers left high and dry as decent spring rain fails to arrive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/farmers-cutting-crops-for-hay-as-decent-spring-rain-doesnt-come/105884166</link><description>Some Victorian farmers are cutting crops for hay as the drought continues to bite in the nation's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">509574dcbec28aaf0b1eb34f8aa69ab5</guid></item><item><title>Illawarrra Academy of Sport holds open testing day for aspiring young athletes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/illawarrra-academy-of-sport-pen-testing-day-young-athletes/105878204</link><description>Young athletes wanting to be the next Emma McKeon or Jessica Hull have been put through high-performance testing to see if they have what it takes to be a professional.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15a018213f26351372e484eeb90ad629</guid></item><item><title>Japan makes history as Brazil records 'unacceptable' 3-2 loss in international friendly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/japan-beats-brazil-in-football-international-friendly/105893036</link><description>For the first time in 14 meetings, Japan defeats Brazil 3-2 in their international friendly at a sold-out Tokyo Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6454207cf8d9709c6caca8495b04511c</guid></item><item><title>Queensland health minister knew of hospital failures before going on leave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/queensland-health-minister-knew-about-caboolture-/105890580</link><description>Queensland's health minister has revealed he knew about failures at Caboolture Hospital involving the death of a patient after delays to medical scan results, before he went on holiday when the issue later became public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12969694309920e5fabdb01232ea2a22</guid></item><item><title>James Paterson will support Sussan Ley to lead the Liberal Party to the next election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/james-paterson-will-support-sussan-ley-to-lead-the/105893246</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16f90292d0d949689afb6c7ac1440426</guid></item><item><title>WA's Coolgardie council avoids suspension, with residents expressing frustration and relief over the saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/coolgardie-to-dig-itself-out-of-debt/105881252</link><description>Coolgardie Shire leaders hope to rebuild trust among ratepayers after the local government minister announced the WA state government would not suspend the council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77b218585453033539c537af21793f7f</guid></item><item><title>Woman, two children, confirmed dead in Gladstone house fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/multiple-people-dead-in-gladstone-house-fire/105893160</link><description>Police are still investigating the cause of a fatal house fire in Gladstone this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f4ba9844f871e5977a1ab359883373e</guid></item><item><title>England thrashes Latvia 5-0 to qualify for World Cup finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/football-england-thrashes-latvia-to-reach-world-cup-finals/105893278</link><description>Unbeaten in its qualifying matches, England reaches next year's World Cup finals following a dominant 5-0 defeat of Latvia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">776384400073f9c24dc5ed3d14d31475</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of Victorians are graduating as paramedics, but have to go interstate for jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/paramedic-student-glut-no-jobs-ambulance-victoria/105874740</link><description>For regional paramedicine graduates, finding a job, let alone one in your hometown, is a challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87a5961a74a7b4d6e63a1037bd6466b2</guid></item><item><title>Police charge man with murder over death in Hocking in Perth's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/man-charged-with-murder-over-death-in-hocking-perth/105893274</link><description>Police charge a 27-year-old man with murder over the death of a 58-year-old man who suffered significant stab wounds during an altercation at a home in Hocking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4bde74dec6b433b1fe8bf69b21e7cc4</guid></item><item><title>Alleged South-East Asian scammers targeted by US over huge investment swindle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/uk-us-sanction-south-east-asian-scam-bitcoin-investment-fraud/105892984</link><description>A Chinese national accused of being the mastermind behind one of the largest ever investment frauds has been charged in the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">645ec84b8a9fe2306fed3726877c32a9</guid></item><item><title>Gaps in cyberbullying reporting leave parents feeling lost, struggling to find answers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/cyberbullying-reporting-gaps-leave-parents-children-helpless/105864800</link><description>Parents and carers are frustrated by what they say is a lack of support when trying to report several Instagram accounts targeting children under the age of 17 over the school holidays.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86168b6389493c5ee569ccfbc8f2dbdb</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Health issues public health alert as person dies after ingesting rare nitazene</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/second-death-queensland-novel-nitazene-health-alert/105893200</link><description>A second person has died this month after ingesting a synthetic opioid in Queensland, raising concerns about the safety of thousands of teenagers during Schoolies celebrations in coming weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3e5416e73a0037aeae6e9e25a384a6b</guid></item><item><title>Randa Abdel-Fattah reveals how the Israel-Gaza war shaped her new book Discipline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/randa-abdel-fattah-palestinian-author-new-book-discipline/105865540</link><description>Randa Abdel-Fattah explores the experience of Palestinian Australians in Discipline, her first book for adults.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5256627cfb3d5e9fd11c695daf718ec</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos lose 2-1 to USA in international friendly, ending Tony Popovic's unbeaten start</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/live-updates-usa-socceroos-international-friendly-fifa-world-cup/105884330</link><description>The Socceroos suffer defeat for the first time under Tony Popovic, falling to a 2-1 defeat against the USA in Colorado.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ce54438a6647fef94dd054d64e53f08</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump posts video of US strikes on alleged drug trafficking boat off coast of Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/donald-trump-posts-video-of-us-strikes-on-alleged/105893326</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7821ad1026d9a5f2396b0de54e5b73f6</guid></item><item><title>US strike on alleged drug boat off Venezuela kills six, Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/us-strike-on-alleged-drug-boat-off-venezuela-kills-six/105893308</link><description>It is the fifth deadly strike in the Caribbean amid the Trump administration's crackdown on alleged drug traffickers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c1e71f90039f55cf158db7a0c7d28d9</guid></item><item><title>Wildlife Photographer of the Year 2025 winners list: Spiders, frogs and fungi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/wildlife-photographer-of-the-year-2025/105890182</link><description>An Australian photographer who took a unique shot of a skeletoniser caterpillar is among the winners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad80355b3634f5b9a21420c66946ea25</guid></item><item><title>Julia Roberts and Ayo Edebiri on their new movie After the Hunt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/julia-roberts-and-ayo-edebiri-on-their-new-movie/105893714</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70d6f8d91ae2cc3bb885a9dd2325c900</guid></item><item><title>Auditor-general report shows SA government's $285m hydrogen spend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/sa-ag-report-finds-hydrogen-office-spent-285-million/105893332</link><description>South Australia's Office for Hydrogen Power spent more than $280 million before the state government scrapped the agency amid the failure of its Whyalla hydrogen project, an auditor-general report tabled in parliament has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bb07972104be98d6553c0b621ebc06c</guid></item><item><title>'It feels like we're kids again': Joel Madden on Good Charlotte reunion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/it-feels-like-were-kids-again:-joel-madden-on-good/105893752</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0ac40a093f8cdb26262d3d84c7a34f5</guid></item><item><title>High Court upholds minister's decision to block visa for American commentator Candace Owens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/high-court-upholds-ministers-block-visa-candace-owens/105893248</link><description>The High Court has backed a decision by the government to refuse a temporary visa to American commentator Candace Owens Farmer, who had planned a speaking tour to Australia in 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0984dec3317f1241c1ccbc4191b533f</guid></item><item><title>Federal government urged to deny visa to rapist and beach volleyballer Steven van de Velde</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/convicted-rapist-selected-to-compete-in-beach-volleyball-event/105892968</link><description>South Australia's Attorney-General has written to the federal government urging it to block the entry into Australia of convicted Dutch child rapist Steven van de Velde, who is seeking to compete at the upcoming Beach Volleyball World Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9057781e7c346dd58cd9950ecfa8003</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, deadline day live updates: Zach Merrett, Charlie Curnow and Christian Petracca among big names on the move</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/afl-trade-period-day-live-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca/105893932</link><description>Deadline day of the AFL trade period has arrived, with clubs racing the clock to complete deals today. Does Zach Merrett get to Hawthorn, or Charlie Curnow to Sydney? Find out live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1880fba71c2089a10a592d3d6c29bd87</guid></item><item><title>Rockhampton man charged after allegedly stabbing two men at sports club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/man-charged-after-alleged-frenchville-sports-club-stabbings/105893310</link><description>Police allege a 21-year-old man stabbed two men at a Rockhampton sports club and threatened another man in unprovoked attacks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f2bd9d1641e7a8a163dd0a29d84b977</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann ordered into mediation over funds for lawyers he hired following anti-corruption raids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/bruce-lehrmann-ordered-mediation-corruption-hearings/105893180</link><description>The Federal Court orders mediation for former Liberal staffer Bruce Lehrmann over funding he says he was offered to pay for his lawyers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a10b939bfab1a262a1ba0e39f2e99d7</guid></item><item><title>The US has dropped out of the top 10 most powerful passports — but where does Australia rank?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/united-states-passport-drops-out-of-top-10-most-powerful/105893408</link><description>The US passport has fallen to 12th place, a five-spot decline from its previous ranking, tying with Malaysia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">210460eb5dcbc50a34d606ea70c1a796</guid></item><item><title>Police officer drew gun on dog after fatal mauling of meter reader Kane Minion, inquest hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/meter-reader-kane-minion-fatal-dog-attack-inquest-gold-coast/105894180</link><description>The inquest into the death of Kane Minion hears that investigators feared for their safety when visiting the property where the 2022 attack occurred.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3ddcce5175d70483d48675d0fa352e2</guid></item><item><title>Man sentenced over manslaughter of Darcy Schafer-Turner, found in cabinet in NSW creek</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/nsw-zachary-fraser-sentenced-darcy-schafer-turner-manslaughter/105893696</link><description>The court heard Darcy Schafer-Turner was "unconditionally loved by his family" as his school friend was sentenced to six-and-a-half years imprisonment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e17e8fb5345362802a6ec6e524477eea</guid></item><item><title>Powerhouse misses opportunity to get Melbourne-bound drums of Sydney's Midnight Oil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/sydneys-powerhouse-missed-out-on-midnight-oil-drums-hirst/105894330</link><description>Midnight Oil are Sydney rock royalty, but the drum kit that stuck with the band for more than 40 years is heading to a Melbourne music museum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77d8f6e30d82e4cfddfe3d8643cf4ad8</guid></item><item><title>Brian Barnes pleads not guilty to murder of Quambatook woman Merril Kelly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/brian-barnes-pleads-not-guilty-to-murder-of-merril-kelly/105893414</link><description>Brian Barnes, 67, is accused of the murder of Merril Kelly, 70, whose body was found by firefighters after a grassfire near a cemetery in the small Victorian town in January.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">302d93e21b263bcca74cdd9b98ab2287</guid></item><item><title>CCC investigation into former Townsville mayor Troy Thompson finished, but unreleased</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/former-mayor-troy-thompson-ccc-investigation-finished/105894368</link><description>A crime and corruption investigation into former Townsville mayor Troy Thompson has been finished, weeks away from a by-election he is expected to contest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80c6a9e3495196a82025540b243c8512</guid></item><item><title>Mother of 11yo girl says sexual offender Shegu Bobb caused trauma to whole family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/act-shegu-bobb-mother-11yo-victim-says-family-traumatised/105894708</link><description>The mother of an 11-year-old girl who was the victim of a Canberra man's sexual offences says his actions have had a lasting impact on her entire family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dc348b1801209be8159885fd820a468</guid></item><item><title>Conjoined boys born in PNG bound for Australia for medical treatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/png-conjoined-twins-braun-hospital-medical-treatment-sydney/105888942</link><description>The boys, who are only the second known case of conjoined twins born in PNG, are expected to come to Australia for medical treatment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">602984aa1a6e648bd1700a79bdd0ced0</guid></item><item><title>Australian seamer Megan Schutt looks to delay retirement until 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/full-trophy-cabinet-part-of-schutt-s-cricket-retirement-dream/105894742</link><description>Megan Schutt had once planned to walk away after the ODI Women's World Cup, but the veteran seamer is now considering playing into 2026 for Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f84bc367da9d0232000fcadc14ce9b90</guid></item><item><title>Bus crashes into home on Sydney's Northern Beaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/bus-crashes-into-home-on-sydneys-northern-beaches/105893550</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26a29271ed07609636d96e62edf4300f</guid></item><item><title>ARLC says NRL players face 10-year ban for joining rebel leagues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/nrl-players-face-10-year-ban-for-joining-rebel-leagues/105894992</link><description>The Australian Rugby League Commission has announced a 10-year ban for any NRL player who agrees to join a football competition it does not recognise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddb37f0928e43c1b5bbf5bd94cff1dfa</guid></item><item><title>When is the F1 US Grand Prix, how can I watch and who is battling for the championship?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/f1-us-grand-prix-what-time-how-to-watch-oscar-piastri/105614112</link><description>Formula 1 returns to the United States, officially marking the final quarter of an epic 2025 championship. Here is what is to come.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53bd31ae325a4d1a91c38ac12e6504cf</guid></item><item><title>Hamas fighters execute alleged collaborators in Gaza. ABC NEWS Verify has chosen not to show the executions due to their graphic nature.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/hamas-fighters-execute-alleged-collaborators-in/105893348</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d75241605dfda6cf26081e293c37b7c</guid></item><item><title>Hamas executes 'collaborators and lawbreakers' in graphic scenes in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/abc-news-verify-hamas-executions-gaza-city/105893350</link><description>Masked gunmen have carried out "extrajudicial executions" in the streets of Gaza City as an expert claims the terror group is trying to regain control of the destroyed enclave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">011b7d02b9a4606194657179c44c731f</guid></item><item><title>Electrician denies 'witness contamination' in Alice Springs house fire inquest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/alice-springs-electrician-mitchell-thomas-house-fire-inquest/105888096</link><description>A witness at an inquest into the death of Alice Springs boy Mitchell Thomas has denied doctoring an electrical report in the wake of a fatal house fire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d68cec56ba0393c282748fd46f7a889</guid></item><item><title>Six children charged with murder over alleged stabbing at Shellharbour train station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/police-charge-teenagers-with-murder-over-jack-westren-death/105894962</link><description>A total of six children and an adult have been charged with murder after 25-year-old Jack Westren was allegedly stabbed to death at Shellharbour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecf6ba84ae516290d64da62e8c63aa78</guid></item><item><title>Michael J Fox talks about life with Parkinson's disease</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/michael-j-fox-talks-about-death-and-parkinsons-disease/105894044</link><description>The Back to the Future star has been candid about life with the degenerative neurological condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb8da2122b00a39bed22e5f831e89528</guid></item><item><title>How long does it take to acclimatise to a new place when the weather is very different?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/how-to-adjust-different-climates/105887794</link><description>Do our bodies actually acclimatise when moving from one climate to another and can we do anything to smooth the transition?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7b51651bfb1e6f2f7657bf344b2ebee</guid></item><item><title>Police charge two men after raids on alleged safe houses used by South-East Asian drug gang</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/police-seize-drugs-in-raids-on-south-east-asian-drug-gang/105895348</link><description>Investigators are probing links between a haul of drugs seized on Tuesday and the South-East Asian gang allegedly behind a failed hit in Western Sydney last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b2dd9d3f7b882327d1b570132b6d61c</guid></item><item><title>SES critical of weather bureau, Eugowra flood inquest told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/eugowra-coronial-inquest-told-of-ses-tension/105893086</link><description>The third day of an inquest into two deaths during the 2022 Eugowra flood hears of concerns raised within the SES about the accuracy of weather bureau warnings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba050b5f18ce69c303a9e8769c5bf7fb</guid></item><item><title>Federal government puts states, territories on notice over failure to close the gap for Indigenous people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/closing-the-gap-proposed-penalties/105894194</link><description>The federal Indigenous minister may impose penalties on states and territories that fail to meet critical targets for the National Agreement on Closing the Gap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db05c3e8b8aaf1109e2ab7a09d9a6061</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says Time magazine cover of himself may be 'worst' in history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/donald-trump-reacts-to-time-magazine-cover/105895214</link><description>Donald Trump made the comments in reference to Time magazine's upcoming November cover story, detailing how his administration "sealed the Gaza ceasefire deal".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76e60a710086e2ae8db0e801f7bc30d1</guid></item><item><title>Australia's baby recession deepens, new ABS data says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/australia-s-baby-recession-deepens-new-abs-data-says/105541086</link><description>The baby recession in Australia is deepening as cost of living pressures make the decision for people to have children less of a choice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c8e24e2ff09a356f53956f037c71227</guid></item><item><title>Magistrate issues arrest warrant after teen refuses to attend court over alleged murders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/arrest-warrant-teen-refused-court-melbourne-murders/105894642</link><description>A teenager in youth custody over the murders of Dau Akueng and Chol Achiek is forcibly arrested by police after he repeatedly refused to attend court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bd5acafab7d1eda9c384d53816d696c</guid></item><item><title>NSW bowler Sean Abbott subbed out of Sheffield Shield game after splitting webbing on hand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/abbott-splits-webbing-on-hand-in-latest-australian-bowling-blow/105895908</link><description>Sean Abbott becomes the latest Test hopeful to suffer an injury, ruled out of NSW's Sheffield Shield match after splitting the webbing on his bowling hand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63204e72e5ad62a8ea02127575bba291</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's troubled Spirit of Tasmania IV ship unable to berth at Point Henry in Geelong, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/spirit-of-tasmania-iv-unable-to-berth-at-geelong/105883912</link><description>The ABC understands that a recent safety assessment found the interim berth would need two additional bollards for the ship to dock there, at a cost of $2 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2bd343e3e6466ec49ab1d8be4a52f79</guid></item><item><title>Victims share trauma at inquiry into stamp duty concession reassessment scheme likened to Robodebt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/act-stamp-duty-concession-scheme-inquiry-robodebt/105894632</link><description>Eighteen months after Canberran Cathy Weeden and her kids purchased a home and left temporary accommodation, she received out-of-the-blue correspondence that she owed $50,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb8ff916f6185052e848dad5135a251b</guid></item><item><title>Mother stands trial accused of 'criminally negligent conduct' which resulted in daughter's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/mother-jenni-wilmott-manslaughter-and-criminal-neglect-trial/105894292</link><description>A mother should be held criminally responsible for the death of her 15-year-old daughter, who she allegedly subjected to physical and emotional abuse for a period of five years, a court has heard. Warning: This story includes references to child abuse and self-harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b548a1668d79ca4e5a8322f03015590e</guid></item><item><title>David Pye faces murder trial accused of organising Nick Martin assassination at Kwinana Motorplex</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/david-pye-murder-trial-nick-martin-kwinana-motorplex-killing/105889968</link><description>The man accused of organising the assassination of former Rebels boss Nick Martin believed the bikie had also arranged to have him killed, a Perth court hears.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad56fba6941aeb6e543564f19ae2ea7a</guid></item><item><title>UK social media star 'Big John' Fisher being deported from Australia over visa issues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/british-social-media-star-big-john-fisher-deported-australia/105895746</link><description>British social media star 'Big John' says he is being deported from Australia after apparently failing to comply with visa requirements.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0244074323bf2f66e7b3bda53db7e750</guid></item><item><title>Family of Albanvale murder victim Kylie Sheahan confront her killer Roland Griffiths in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/prosecutors-life-sentence-roland-griffiths-albanvale-fire/105894710</link><description>A lawyer calls for Roland Griffiths to face a life sentence for the murder of his wife, who he doused in petrol and set on fire in Melbourne's north-west in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40b0b528fca67e230df3b96abe480fe1</guid></item><item><title>Byron touches down in Brisbane on Wednesday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/byron-touches-down-in-brisbane-on-wednesday/105896176</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c58c803f5a103b9dbb442daa59df3506</guid></item><item><title>Queensland teenager Byron Waller completes attempt to become youngest supported pilot to fly around world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/qld-world-teenage-pilot-byron-waller-youngest-to-circumnavigate/105893122</link><description>Queensland teenager Byron Waller spent 240 hours flying about 45,000 kilometres around the world before returning to Brisbane to make history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">622cb99cbe4c492a7b9ab9ef7311055c</guid></item><item><title>Byron was greeted by family at Brisbane Airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/byron-was-greeted-by-family-at-brisbane-airport/105896190</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d95d25afbdde159c858d42142656fd0</guid></item><item><title>Three Australian men accused of killing Zivan Radmanovic in Bali could face the death penalty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/three-australian-men-could-face-death-penalty-bali/105896428</link><description>Indonesian police allege Zivan Radmanovic was killed when two Australian men stormed the villa, shooting him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4bb686a2307e1685b9fddd02d399650</guid></item></channel></rss>