<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:59:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Granite Island's little penguin population climbs despite SA's algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/granite-island-penguin-population-climbs-despite-algal-threat/105920654</link><description>The small, fragile colony of surviving little penguins on South Australia's Granite Island records a "significant increase" in numbers amid the state's harmful algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92e580c7cc58e51567df7100b014ca56</guid></item><item><title>Former Prince Andrew set to be stripped of military rank by UK government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-to-be-stripped-of-uk-military-title/105963786</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten Windsor will be stripped of his last remaining military position as part of King Charles's decision to remove him from public life, according to the UK defence minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">186ca1d62c6cac740505a135890fa206</guid></item><item><title>Aftermath of mass stabbing on UK train</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/aftermath-of-mass-stabbing-on-uk-train/105963734</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8861ca23e346f8bceb631f4c77b0edc4</guid></item><item><title>Legal Services Board of Victoria warns lawyers about AI in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/legal-services-board-of-victoria-warns-lawyers-about-ai-in-court/105916628</link><description>The use of artificial intelligence to prepare court documents raises questions in the legal profession about its use and misuse in the industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11322fbec4ebb8c0fb7d75a1fd9addf2</guid></item><item><title>Funding health is one of the biggest challenges facing Tasmania, as Eric Abetz prepares to hand down his first budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/health-funding-budget-challenges-tasmania-eric-abetz/105962530</link><description>A peak health body is worried Tasmania's public health system won't receive enough support in Thursday's state budget to address ballooning demand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">023af7486079fa987a12ff634173e47c</guid></item><item><title>How hitchhiking 'suckerfish' reveal humpback whales' 'web of life'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/hitchhiking-suckerfish-reveal-humpback-whales-web-of-life/105950862</link><description>Suckerfish, the ocean's ultimate hitchhikers, cling to humpback whales for thousands of kilometres and reveal surprising insights into life on the whale highway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4897fceb3d1bc8314797d0f765a3d7b2</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Kimberly Birrell loses Chennai Open final but earns sportsmanship award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/tennis-kimberly-birrell-loses-chennai-open-final/105963952</link><description>Gold Coast tennis star Kimberly Birrell loses in the Chennai Open final but claims a sportsmanship award for touching moment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b050174d333d3fad08b33509268b994</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr and Ellie Carpenter score for Chelsea as manager praises impact of Matildas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/wsl-sam-kerr-scores-for-chelsea-as-ellie-carpenter-stars/105964142</link><description>Matildas Sam Kerr and Ellie Carpenter both score for Chelsea in an impressive performance from the Australian stars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b399797570ec89c343ac07e8138e3b3b</guid></item><item><title>Maternal health forum reveals gaps in NT system, families choosing to move interstate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/our-birth-our-voice-maternal-health-forum-mother-maternity/105962312</link><description>Women who have had traumatic birth experiences at Royal Darwin Hospital have gathered to share their stories and call for urgent action from the territory and federal governments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0c7f28022601c339568e89af3235be4</guid></item><item><title>Rescues on Bluff Knoll increase fourfold in one year as visitor numbers rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/bluff-knoll-hiker-rescues-increase-stirling-range/105957436</link><description>About 50,000 people climb Bluff Knoll in WA's Stirling Range each year, and emergency services say they are being called to more rescues as hikers underestimate the challenging track.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32734c6f058d18bc10fa2dc7af9d7dda</guid></item><item><title>NRL and RLPA to investigate Eli Katoa handling after Tonga star suffered 'seizure activity' during New Zealand Test match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/eli-katoa-undergoes-surgery-after-head-knocks/105964618</link><description>The Storm say Eli Katoa had surgery after suffering "seizure activity" following multiple head knocks in the Tonga and New Zealand clash, and the league and players' association are set to investigate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e73e2e6676e0caeba54a4615e22b408a</guid></item><item><title>Charges laid after 'trail of destruction' and rock thrown at firefighters in regional SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/arrests-over-fire-and-trespass-in-riverland-and-murray-bridge/105964118</link><description>Three arrests have been made in two separate incidents in regional South Australia, one in which a man allegedly lit a fire before throwing a rock at firefighters and another involving a car being discovered in flames after allegedly leaving a "trail of destruction" on a property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">799a6ca9d677c3487e26d5efc182022a</guid></item><item><title>Father of Molly Ticehurst frustrated by court delays in murder case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/daniel-billings-molly-ticehurst-court-delays/105074740</link><description>The father of murdered childcare worker Molly Ticehurst breaks down while expressing his frustration at the delays in the case against her alleged killer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d85f678d019d66080538c67931898225</guid></item><item><title>Mental health reform needed to stop children ending up in prison, doctors say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/experts-raise-alarm-over-nt-prison-mental-health-crisis/105964576</link><description>As incarceration rates continue to soar in the Northern Territory, experts say mental health reform in the justice system is crucial for improving community safety in the long term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c0cf2e9fb892f39645d934494cf0e9</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne hoping for chance to face undefeated North Melbourne in AFLW finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/melbourne-want-to-play-north-melbourne-aflw-2025-finals/105963086</link><description>North Melbourne may be undefeated for the second home and away season in a row, but a star Melbourne player says the short AFLW season means they haven't proven themselves against everyone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">593daee658710b712d3b31a8d7333c87</guid></item><item><title>Dark Mofo sees drop in interstate visitors despite return of full program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/dark-mofo-announces-2026-dates-interstate-visitor-numbers-drop/105964376</link><description>Tasmania's provocative midwinter festival Dark Mofo will return in 2026, as this year's festival reports fewer interstate visitors as "budgets are tightening" across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7592eeb31970369291e1fd1d07958fa</guid></item><item><title>Bathurst childcare worker sentenced over head injury to four-year-old</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/bathurst-childcare-worker-sentencing/105956356</link><description>The Bathurst childcare worker is said to have used "considerable force" on the child, resulting in his head needing medical adhesive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">881b637a3380f570bc2a0ebc764e3c1e</guid></item><item><title>Review of mass salmon mortalities in Tasmania points to litany of failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/tasmanian-government-salmon-mortality-report/105964772</link><description>The state's environment watchdog has released a debrief of lessons and reflections from a mass salmon mortality event in which dead fish washed up on Tasmanian beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9ca2922a14f04ffa535ac0a9c93a414</guid></item><item><title>Alleged manslaughter victim resorted to eating from school bins, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/jenni-gaye-wilmott-criminal-neglect-manslaughter-trial/105964930</link><description>A girl who died, allegedly as a result of criminal neglect by her mother, had resorted to eating food out of bins at her school, a court has heard. Warning: This story includes references to child abuse and self-harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bbef5bcd61372c610efe3388118962d</guid></item><item><title>Jennifer Mui Len Chin avoids jail after stabbing daughter's boyfriend in her home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/jennifer-mui-len-chin-sentenced-for-stabbing-daughter-boyfriend/105729024</link><description>A Perth mother who stabbed her daughter's teenage boyfriend when she found him semi-naked in the family home avoids a prison sentence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">063cff8edce9a9e7ff9e75fd7461ce4f</guid></item><item><title>Brief of evidence in Pheobe Bishop murder case reissued due to server crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/pheobe-bishop-murder-accused-case-delayed-due-to-server-crash/105965760</link><description>Thousands of pages of evidence had to be reissued to defence team after it was lost in server crash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a663bff41ea244b253ec402335426338</guid></item><item><title>Your rights when it comes to breastfeeding and expressing at work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/your-rights-when-it-comes-to-breastfeeding-at-work/105885406</link><description>There are many ways to combine breastfeeding and paid work, for example expressing milk, breastfeeding during breaks, or working from home. Knowing your rights can help you feel more confident when negotiating what that looks like.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9bc5be5b34fd60252cd240bea55393e</guid></item><item><title>Ash Barty urges Australians to be patient with tennis young guns Emerson Jones and Maya Joint</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/tennis-ash-barty-emerson-ones-maya-joint-patience-fans/105965970</link><description>Australia's last women's singles grand slam champ is encouraged by the new crop of kids coming through, but has urged fans to remain patient with their progress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5473442a6386a6e6963a8c2fdd24ada1</guid></item><item><title>Former SA opposition leader David Speirs shares ideas for algal bloom recovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/david-speirs-writes-document-about-algal-bloom-recovery/105964388</link><description>Former South Australian opposition leader David Speirs says he will make a decision about his political future in the coming weeks as he launches his own plans for the algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">152096256b48251dcf5b836c9f15dcc9</guid></item><item><title>Outspoken Mexican mayor known for anti-crime stance killed during Day of the Dead festivities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/carlos-alberto-manzo-rodriguez-killed-during-festivities/105965498</link><description>In recent months Mayor Carlos Alberto Manzo Rodríguez had publicly appealed to the Mexican president for help to combat cartel violence and organised crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71067bc9dcf0697e95fb21e2c73e17c8</guid></item><item><title>Mid North Coast blueberry farmer counts losses after severe storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/blueberry-farmer-counts-losses-after-severe-nsw-storm/105964770</link><description>Stephen Thandi says a storm tore through his northern New South Wales blueberry farm "like a freight train" at the weekend, causing at least at least $300,000 worth of damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bc95aea2afdbdba268996de3d3870d9</guid></item><item><title>Labor pledged to ban nuclear weapons in opposition. In government it got a reality check</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/labor-retreats-from-nuclear-weapons-ban-pledge-four-corners/105959312</link><description>Anthony Albanese and Richard Marles once pledged Labor would sign a treaty to ban nuclear weapons. Why have they walked this back in government?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7b97f5dfd33f372d2e20a376341948d</guid></item><item><title>US judge ends Justin Baldoni lawsuit against Blake Lively for missing court deadline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/justin-baldoni-loses-lawsuit-against-blake-lively/105964392</link><description>The actor's lawsuit against his co-star Blake Lively ends after he missed a court deadline on October 17 to file an amended complaint.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d67cfbc085cd2577ee4a2e2aab8e657</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast Mayor Tom Tate calls for urgent e-transport law changes after deaths of two children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/e-bikes-gold-coast-mayor-legislation-police-parents-safety/105965460</link><description>Following the deaths of a 15-year-old and an eight-year-old in the space of less than two days, Gold Coast Mayor Tom Tate calls for urgent change to Queensland laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08a8c9380f4da24917de076c43271ed4</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate Sydney developer's brother's alleged kidnapping, claim $1 million ransom paid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/nsw-george-ayoub-belfield-kidnapping-ransom-charlie-developer/105964220</link><description>George Ayoub was allegedly taken and shoved into the back of a car while he was walking outside his Belfield home about 5am on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aafe92c1f3295450c142351348b3509c</guid></item><item><title>Hinchinbrook by-election a 'test' for Queensland LNP government as writs issued</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/hinchinbrook-by-election-test-for-lnp-government-as-writs-issued/105964322</link><description>One year after sweeping to power, Queensland's LNP government will face voters at the Hinchinbrook by-election, with the poll seen as a test for the premier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffb39a2372f3dd7130e26a17dfd9fb82</guid></item><item><title>Liberals shifting towards dumping net zero, despite moderate faction fears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/liberals-shifting-towards-dumping-net-zero-2050/105966032</link><description>The centre of debate inside the Liberals appears to be shifting towards dumping net zero, as a tumultuous debate unfolds following the Nationals' decision to formally abandon the 2050 target.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b9fc63959d7c9500d200678644eb8a2</guid></item><item><title>Trial begins for man charged with murder over alleged hit and run at Browns Plains in Logan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/browns-plains-alleged-hit-and-run-murder-trial-begins/105966476</link><description>Umar Al Enizi is charged with the murder of Troy Vandenberg in September 2021. The jury heard both men were "total strangers" who had been involved in an altercation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54aed34dbd3e42cbf6fa00df287384bc</guid></item><item><title>Teenager avoids conviction over 'racist' attack on security guard at Bendigo Marketplace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/teen-avoids-conviction-over-bendigo-marketplace-attack/105965024</link><description>A teenager involved in the violent attack on a security guard that forced a country Victorian shopping centre into lockdown avoids jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5957c3cafab69872dcfc6853254978cd</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says UK royals suffered 'terrible thing' with pressure over Jeffrey Epstein scandal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/trump-says-uk-royals-suffered-with-pressure-over-epstein-scandal/105966134</link><description>Donald Trump says he felt badly for the British royal family after King Charles stripped his brother Andrew Mountbatten Windsor of his title as prince amid mounting pressure over his ties to convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d370207082665fc3845970254d9582a</guid></item><item><title>Suspected meteor spotted in afternoon sky across Victoria's Gippsland region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/suspected-meteor-gippsland-sonic-boom-afternoon-sky/105964144</link><description>Victorians living in the state's Gippsland region say they saw a streak of light whizzing through the Sunday afternoon sky and heard a sonic boom, with many wondering if they saw space junk or a meteor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e9bed216b9650f760b92074d851e252</guid></item><item><title>Chinese ship spies on Australia, Philippines and the US in South China Sea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/chinese-ship-spies-on-australia-philippines-us-naval-exercise/105966362</link><description>A sophisticated Chinese spy ship monitors Australian, Philippines, United States and New Zealand naval forces as they conduct another round of joint exercises in the South China Sea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f50ebe538b32fabcc174dd6fada42689</guid></item><item><title>The key takeaways from Anthony Albanese's time at ASEAN and APEC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/anthony-albanese-apec-asean-summits-key-moments/105966626</link><description>While Australia's relationship with China has improved, there is still growing unease about Beijing's military power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b3fc8fafd7b0d2699a5af5b3187d993</guid></item><item><title>Angel Seafood halts oyster relocation amid protesters' algal bloom fears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/angel-seafood-halts-oyster-relocation-after-blockade-algal-bloom/105966998</link><description>A blockade at a boat ramp to prevent oysters from entering an open fishing bay, over fears of spreading the algal bloom, leads to the destruction of nearly $70,000 worth of oysters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">312ff1f17c13dc66e91576d81bf0bbca</guid></item><item><title>O'Neil welcomes housing progress despite price surge, while Bragg says no to 'NIMBYs'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/oneil-welcomes-housing-progress-liberal-vows-to-ditch-nimby/105967310</link><description>As the government comes under pressure for rising house prices in the first month of its expanded home deposit guarantee, Clare O'Neil welcomes signs of progress on supply.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d615c45d8cbcf9247facb7fb761d60f1</guid></item><item><title>Erin Patterson lodges appeal request in attempt to fight mushroom murder convictions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/erin-patterson-mushroom-murder-appeal/105964152</link><description>The triple-murderer lodges documents in Victoria's Court of Appeal requesting an appeal against her convictions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bae0972bcb7f8344aef07b88621b35c3</guid></item><item><title>Suspected meteor lights up Gippsland afternoon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/suspected-meteor-lights-up-gippsland-afternoon-/105967540</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4750d5c5b5812e12c639053b39fa1700</guid></item><item><title>Sale of WA's Yeeda Pastoral Company near Broome completed, NT abattoir tipped to reopen in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/kimberley-yeeda-pastoral-company-sells-nt-abattoir-may-reopen/105966118</link><description>The sale of Yeeda Pastoral Company, including the Kimberley Meat Company, to TLP4 Australian Holdings is now complete.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a69121df3b6fe37235154873f254a5f</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man avoids jail sentence over part in violent home invasion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/act-canberra-man-avoids-jail-sentence-over-violent-home-invasion/105966702</link><description>Xiantao Shang went to an apartment seeking a woman who owed him money. When told she was not there, he and an accomplice forced their way in and assaulted the couple inside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7512d8ad9e3641601dd71f1628c2ea2d</guid></item><item><title>Students with disability isolated, unsupported in ACT public schools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/act-students-disability-isolated-unsupported-public-schools/105967090</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">066a3e3391a8532274683bb8634d750f</guid></item><item><title>UK train stabbing suspect also charged over incident at London Tube station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/uk-police-charge-train-stabbing-suspect/105967688</link><description>Police are investigating possible links between a man accused of a mass stabbing on an English train and a series of other incidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc5e2ce2990bdfc1fec9afb2bb8ce6e6</guid></item><item><title>Corrections officers placed spit hood on Wayne Hunt, stripped him naked after seizure, coroner hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/wayne-hunt-inquest-darwin-correctional-centre-death-seizure/105964646</link><description>A 56-year-old man was stripped naked, handcuffed and made to wear a spit hood after suffering a seizure inside prison, a coronial inquest into his death has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfbe155202a32163de63ee8ef7180e19</guid></item><item><title>Man who shot poodle in Central Coast caravan park robbery sentenced to eight years in prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/man-who-shot-poodle-during-robbery-sentenced-8-years-jail/105951672</link><description>A man who shot a dog in the face during a robbery on the Central Coast of New South Wales has been sentenced to eight years in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6d5c661df1e9fa1fd08a0c0a69f1702</guid></item><item><title>Leader of Spain's Valencia region, Carlos Mazon, resigns over handling of last year's deadly floods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/valencia-leader-resigns-carlos-mazon-floods/105967614</link><description>The flash floods hit Spain's south-eastern regions on October 29, 2024, killing 229 people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bd3f12afe54d38edb7d533adc71d155</guid></item><item><title>Papua New Guinea conjoined twins should not be separated due to risk of death, hospital says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/hospital-updates-on-png-conjoined-twin-boys-/105967644</link><description>Conjoined twins are extraordinarily rare, accounting for fewer than every two in 100,000 births.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1c1ad8df2bfb45a76ee9dd9be681d6e</guid></item><item><title>New environment laws could help or harm nature depending on the minister</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/new-environment-laws-could-help-or-hinder-nature/105963168</link><description>Ambiguous language in draft national environment laws means acting on scientific facts or not will come down to ministerial discretion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0cbae9dcf0cea368a4b70a16ecae783</guid></item><item><title>Housing supply lags behind demand in St Helens on Tasmania's east coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/east-coast-tasmania-housing-lagging-behind-demand/105964304</link><description>For some residents of Tasmania's east coast, it is either leave the region or risk being homeless as they grapple with a scarcity of long-term rentals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30812efe5a2ba88f57b4ddd9aaabfa90</guid></item><item><title>Zohran Mamdani could be New York's next mayor. His path has been part Barack Obama, part Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/zohran-mamdani-path-to-new-york-mayors-office/105964234</link><description>Donald Trump has thrust the Democrats into the political wilderness but an uprising in the gritty streets of New York may be their future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34789b1586bd2ae6daa2e43cf220aae7</guid></item><item><title>How the arrest of an Israeli military lawyer has again shone light on shocking abuse of Palestinians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/israeli-military-lawyer-arrest-highlights-abuse-of-palestinians/105963704</link><description>Israel's top military lawyer is behind bars after leaking a video of shocking alleged abuse of a Palestinian man in a military jail. This is why the case has shaken politics and the military to the core.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ab6000e91e6db9b77356e98786585e7</guid></item><item><title>Climate change increasingly contributing to home insurance premium hikes, IAG warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/climate-change-plays-role-in-growing-home-insurance-iag-warns/105964560</link><description>A report from IAG and a scientific research centre finds escalating risk from severe weather events in south-east Queensland, New South Wales, and south-west Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc5a7b3e321500b2fbb76b021f6ed0c9</guid></item><item><title>Why Michele Bullock is relieved she is keeping rates on hold as markets continue to shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/why-michele-bullock-is-relieved-to-keep-rates-on-hold/105964738</link><description>Last week the RBA governor issued a blunt warning on the state of financial markets and as markets continue to shift from traditional valuation methods, plenty of cool heads are getting nervous.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9a61068ea39d826f7ec51ea2440d1a6</guid></item><item><title>Young Syrian refugees overcome life challenges to take on year 12 exams</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/syrian-refugees-take-on-year-12-exams/105964670</link><description>After escaping the Syrian civil war as a young boy, Mazen Al Jahed is one of thousands of South Australian students preparing for their year 12 exams.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5db893bf512b3a7ab7f6679e8ef79951</guid></item><item><title>Coalition to meet after Nationals lead charge to dump net zero</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/coalition-to-meet-after-nationals-lead-charge-to-dump-net-zero/105967106</link><description>The Coalition will gather this morning at a joint party room session as the issue of whether to keep or ditch its net zero commitment roils within the party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d6f3fc05b930ee9ac43289c33475ab2</guid></item><item><title>Mouse numbers on the rise, farmers told to be on alert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/mouse-numbers-on-the-rise-farmers-told-to-be-on-alert/105947934</link><description>The CSIRO is urging farmers to reduce opportunities for mice breeding this harvest season as the threat of a pest population boom looms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f996202fa6c43072b3d6d75cc3acde32</guid></item><item><title>Feral pigs devour 99 out of every 100 lambs on this Central West NSW farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/feral-pigs-eating-lambs/105835106</link><description>Neville Mattick says feral pigs are eating the lambs on his farm in the NSW Central West, with fewer than one in 100 surviving this season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f40a48ccdeac51885e04ccba65d4bce0</guid></item><item><title>The World Egg and Sperm Bank's proposed 'reward' scheme for IVF companies raises concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/the-world-egg-and-sperm-bank-proposed-ivf-reward-scheme/105966160</link><description>In an email seen by the ABC, a US-based egg bank told IVF clinics it was introducing its new "Client Success Reward Program in Australia".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cdc281283d90afe3e918cbb4234c0f6</guid></item><item><title>Inadequate funding, outdated class sizes among challenges for children with disability in ACT public schools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/challenges-for-children-with-disability-in-act-public-schools/105935316</link><description>Liam used to dread walking through the school gates. Now, he can't wait to learn — but it took leaving a system that made him feel ignored to get there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f465e029800c9f844ff4186493f69b0</guid></item><item><title>Sydney mum recounts 'panic' at discovering day care wrongly gave son to another person</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/mum-recounts-first-steps-bangor-gave-son-to-another-person/105961026</link><description>Sophie Tilley says she arrived at her son's child care to be told an "older man in shorts" had already collected him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">306a0a18fcf15f99d2fcee7d320efaba</guid></item><item><title>Dedicated radio station launched to help kids in custody get back on track</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/futures-radio-youth-justice-centre-giving-hope/105942784</link><description>A dedicated radio station launches at a Western Sydney juvenile justice facility, helping troubled teens share their stories and rewrite their futures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fbfe5924061846525fbf5312fdacf46</guid></item><item><title>Judge rejects plea deal for funeral home owners accused of dumping bodies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/us-funeral-home-owners-accused-of-dumping-bodies/105968376</link><description>A US judge rejects a plea deal granting shorter jail sentences to funeral home owners accused of stashing nearly 190 decaying bodies in a bug-infested building.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c52b1209f0a0e9629d92613a26454d</guid></item><item><title>Stolen Generations survivors overlooked in aged care reform, advocates say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/aged-care-reforms-overlook-stolen-generations-elders/105966520</link><description>"Discriminatory" changes to means testing in aged care could leave Stolen Generations survivors having to pay high fees for basic everyday services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53ce69cebb8ca0c66941344be41502c6</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne enjoying best form in six years ahead of Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/ashes-cricket-marnus-labuschagne-australia-england-century/105968514</link><description>With the first men's Ashes Test starting in just over two weeks, Marnus Labuschagne reminds selectors of his ability with the bat after hitting another century for Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30ca1a99e99ce16e94904186272c0847</guid></item><item><title>Diane Ladd, three-time Oscar nominee, dies aged 89</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/diane-ladd-dies-aged-89-in-california/105968616</link><description>Diane Ladd, a three-time Academy Award nominee whose roles ranged from the brash waitress in Alice Doesn't Live Here Anymore to the protective mother in Wild at Heart, has died at 89.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85c73f3b8a392f6d186619f546226fc1</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Forrest's plan to alter sacred Ashburton River under fresh legal scrutiny</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/andrew-forrest-traditional-owners-in-sat-ashburton-river-plan/105966594</link><description>Mining billionaire Andrew Forrest's controversial plan to alter the natural river system on his large outback WA cattle station is under renewed legal scrutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">859de5c1125f5edc596b8a6f0861cdf3</guid></item><item><title>WA avocado growers eye record crop as export negotiations with China continue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/wa-avocado-growers-expect-record-crop-push-for-exports/105965972</link><description>WA growers say they are on track to "smash" the record season they enjoyed two years ago, but the volume of production means it is crucial to increase exports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8fa7a577913294e4b28aeffbd73b125</guid></item><item><title>China extends visa-free entry for 45 countries, including Australia, to end of 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/china-extends-visa-freee-policy-to-2026-australia-included/105968854</link><description>The extension, which is until the end of 2026, covers 32 European countries as well as Australia, New Zealand, Japan, South Korea and several nations in South America and the Gulf region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">374c0d903b43e0a657c68be58342bb67</guid></item><item><title>Darwin, Hobart and Canberra all set to have no queer bars or clubs by the end of 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/queer-spaces-disappearing-australian-nightlife/105958852</link><description>For the LGBTQIA+ community, queer pubs and clubs can be an oasis. But in some capital cities they are vanishing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3c82764a87e572720db22b75bb4169d</guid></item><item><title>Severe storms lash south-east Queensland for third day running</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/storms-smash-south-east-qld-three-days-running/105968692</link><description>Severe storms have again rolled through southern Queensland, smashing parts of the state still recovering from weekend weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de67b2c9412eeaec85fdc81a0b8e6285</guid></item><item><title>Larissa Behrendt's Boyer Lecture argues justice and imagination are an investment in democracy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/larissa-behrendt-boyer-lecture-justice-democracy/105965580</link><description>I want to reflect on what I have come to see, through my own experience, as both the illuminating strengths and the shadowed weaknesses of the Australian legal system and its role in our democracy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc27e73207c5aaced764f41b4f120e22</guid></item><item><title>Eli Katoa's 'scary' NRL concussion draws condemnation from ex-player Shaun Johnson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/eli-katoa-shaun-johnson-reaction-scary-incident/105969198</link><description>Former NRL star Shaun Johnson has called for heads to roll after the "scary" incidents that saw Eliesa Katoa requiring oxygen pitchside after suffering three head knocks in Tonga's clash with New Zealand at Eden Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9ca895cf75164e6b99eec2a7e0cdc12</guid></item><item><title>Lone survivor of Air India crash tells UK media 'God took all my happiness'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/air-india-crash-survivor-speaks-to-uk-media/105969152</link><description>A passenger who walked from a Boeing 787-8 Dreamliner crash that killed his brother soon after take-off tells UK media of the mental and physical anguish he has endured since.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">873f350d2b1f538b339d78ed222c43cd</guid></item><item><title>Mount Gambier woman charged over damage to city's Cast in Blue sculpture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/mount-gambier-blue-blob-googly-eyes-vandalism-charge-court/105964692</link><description>A 19-year-old woman appears in court via telephone accused of damaging Mount Gambier's Cast in Blue sculpture, which has drawn criticism for its cost and appearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75b2be6a928e56949cb39dd8e9136db8</guid></item><item><title>How dirty are public toilet seats?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/how-dirty-are-public-toilet-seats/105894996</link><description>Public toilets are a "microbial soup" and there are things you should be doing to protect yourself — including not taking out your mobile phone and never hovering over the seat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">872963b29783bf2f551ddef61ab797c2</guid></item><item><title>Brett Lee says England must play both Jofra Archer and Mark Wood in Perth to win the Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/cricket-brett-lee-archer-wood-selection-perth-ashes-test/105970054</link><description>England is urged to play both Jofra Archer and Mark Wood to begin the Ashes in Perth despite durability concerns with both quicks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7aacfb41dd54e3d710232781a603a19d</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police, WA Police and AFP charge 18 people in Strike Force Bloomfield drug bust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/nsw-and-wa-police-charge-18-people-as-part-of-major-drug-bust/105969768</link><description>Police charge 18 people in Perth and Sydney and seize 268 kilograms of illicit drugs following a multi-agency investigation into a national crime syndicate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8a93680e5ed3262899b3b094cb1054f</guid></item><item><title>RBA keeps rates on hold in November at 3.6pc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/rba-keeps-rates-steady-in-november-2025/105969614</link><description>The Reserve Bank has kept interest rates on hold at 3.6pc after hotter-than-expected inflation in the September quarter squashed hopes of a rate cut.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97ed90e4cedb9eed7629cabb0eb6e8e2</guid></item><item><title>BHP offloads 3,700 hectares of land at Mt Arthur coal mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/bhp-mount-arthur-offloads-3700-hectares/105968394</link><description>BHP will transfer 3,700 hectares of land at the Mt Arthur coal mine to a neighbouring mining company looking to expand its operations, raising questions about its promise to close the mine by 2030.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78cec06fe6eda70ab0b88d877b06c682</guid></item><item><title>RBA forecasts suggest more cost-of-living pain and risk of no more interest rate cuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/rba-interest-rates-statement-on-monetary-policy-analysis/105969494</link><description>Will 3.6 per cent be as low as the Reserve Bank's cash rate gets? A majority of economists now believe so.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a49ecbfed42d168ca6196d7a4b67cac</guid></item><item><title>Some Australian states are set to get a free electricity period every day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/solar-sharer-free-energy-three-hours-outlier-states/105968998</link><description>The federal government says its new Solar Sharer scheme will also benefit Australians who aren't able to access it, but some experts are hesitant to agree.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ed74aea8c7ca1a5ed89fd3d67d343fa</guid></item><item><title>Half Yours wins $10 million Melbourne Cup at Flemington, beating Goodie Two Shoes and Middle Earth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/melbourne-cup-wrap-half-yours-wins-at-flemington/105969044</link><description>Half Yours wins the 165th edition of the Melbourne Cup at Flemington, with jockey Jamie Melham making history as the first female jockey to win both the Melbourne and Caulfield Cups.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4146c0a445122ebed8d609b3f62efabd</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley almost certain to face challenge next year, detractors say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/sussan-ley-almost-certain-to-be-challenged/105970786</link><description>While conservatives are waiting for the net zero issue to be resolved, those who support Andrew Hastie or Angus Taylor for the leadership say her leadership will likely be threatened after the summer break.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f28a7dd365e917dcf51154d1b2cbdd1d</guid></item><item><title>Sorry seems to be the hardest word for ACT Transport Minister Chris Steel after bungled MyWay+ rollout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/sorry-the-hardest-word-for-act-transport-minister-chris-steel/105969026</link><description>Five days after being censured in the ACT's Legislative Assembly for the bungled rollout of the territory's MyWay+ network, Transport Minister Chris Steel has issued a statement to "apologise to anyone impacted by the transition to the new service".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e37c545d0d688068102d25ea466764bd</guid></item><item><title>Hektoria Glacier in Antarctica shrinks at fastest rate recorded in modern history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/hektoria-glacier-antarctica-retreats-fastest-pace-recorded/105968782</link><description>Antarctic scientists have documented the fastest retreat of a glacier in modern history, after it lost eight kilometres of ice in just two months, according to a new report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d7a7558133afee244b380a294b75313</guid></item><item><title>Streaming services to be made to produce Australian content</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/streaming-services-to-be-made-to-produce-australian-content/105970910</link><description>The federal government puts laws requiring streaming services to produce Australian content back on the table after a hiatus following the US election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcc02221f7eedf3c50ecac05c253f945</guid></item><item><title>Multi-generational housing could be a solution to housing shortage, NSW inquiry hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/nsw-housing-crisis-rural-land-zoning-secondary-dwelling-reforms/105970220</link><description>Communal living was once common in regional Australia. Now an investigation is underway into whether it could help ease the housing crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bb1fb4a807d14b85440e9bfac0f885c</guid></item><item><title>Woman convicted of starving ballerina daughter denied bail ahead of appeal hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/ballerina-starvation-trial-mother-denied-bail-appeal/105971136</link><description>A Perth mother jailed for starving her only child to the point of severe malnutrition is denied bail after arguing she should be released because she had not been given a fair trial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ade1bcda1fbf909d0978e59c72c5258</guid></item><item><title>Mother had 'callous disregard' for deteriorating health of dying six-year-old daughter, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/crystal-hanley-criminal-neglect-daugther-charlie-death/105968420</link><description>A court has heard harrowing accounts from emergency services and the siblings of a young girl who died after her mother criminally neglected her. Warning: Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander readers are advised this article contains the first name and image of a person who has died. Readers are also advised this story contains content which may be distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62bd92f2d569de80172b7c7dcef2adb5</guid></item><item><title>Fugitives could be stripped of welfare payments, but critics say it denies 'natural justice'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/fears-fugitive-welfare-cut-off-will-capture-innocent-people/105971100</link><description>Fugitives wanted for some of the most serious crimes and sexual offences could soon be stripped of their welfare payments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad32719dd40599eb4ea863faadf6c79a</guid></item><item><title>Jillaroos boosted by return of Tamika Upton for Pacific Championships final against New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/rugby-league-jillaroos-tamika-upton-return-pacific-champs-final/105971642</link><description>Australia's hopes of claiming the Pacific Championships are handed a major boost with star fullback Tamika Upton ruled fit to play after recovering from a calf injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ce3694d85d94b2ec998942b37dc9e9a</guid></item><item><title>Jamie Melham joins Michelle Payne in rare club after overcoming challenges to reach pinnacle of career</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/horse-racing-jamie-melham-melbourne-cup-journey-analysis/105971088</link><description>Jamie Melham overcomes numerous challenges to reach the pinnacle of her racing career, joining Michelle Payne in the rarest of rare clubs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e2f5f6d120790aecd81a0f86f7cfd7f</guid></item><item><title>Osborne Park Football Club suspended for two years after Stephen Hawking costume controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/osborne-park-football-club-suspended-two-years-perth-league/105971762</link><description>A suburban Perth football club is suspended from its league for two years after a "severe breach" of integrity standards, following an end-of-season costume stunt that left City of Stirling workers distressed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fd1c7d382d9d859b21e11ff03d7cc49</guid></item><item><title>PNG hospital says anyone prepared to take on conjoined twins 'must be willing to take on' the risks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/png-conjoined-twin-boys-parents-ask-doctors-to-explore-options/105969288</link><description>The mother of a rare set of conjoined twins is begging doctors to explore other options after a Papua New Guinea hospital recommended against sending the infants overseas for surgery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d657803cebee8550f4a21eafec07ffad</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105970726</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cf27a37749ce0ed2d1ba30ff7252e80</guid></item><item><title>Will Zohran Mamdani be the next mayor of New York?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/will-zohran-mamdani-be-the-next-mayor-of-new-york-/105971584</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a00bfcc3e0c0b0f84a4eddf8b642047</guid></item><item><title>New vaccine gives fresh hope to save the koalas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/new-vaccine-gives-fresh-hope-to-save-the-koalas/105971598</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9142881ef1d5d357ab9ce70d1cb69a72</guid></item><item><title>At least three nations 'willing to kill' on Australian soil, spy chief says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/asio-chief-warns-three-nations-willing-to-kill-in-australia/105971692</link><description>The nation's top spy uses a major speech to warn there is a "realistic possibility" a foreign government will try to assassinate a dissident on Australian soil, saying ASIO believes "at least three" nations are willing and capable of carrying out such a plot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">640b6baaec87f19cdca711e0f84ab10e</guid></item><item><title>Queensland medical professionals to take industrial action as negotiations with state government stall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/qld-united-workers-union-health-workers-industrial-action/105972044</link><description>About 2,000 radiographers, pharmacists and radiation therapists will take industrial action from Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b402c0ecef21867ce09397bed50a27aa</guid></item><item><title>Buckingham Palace to stage largest-ever display of Queen Elizabeth II's fashions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/largest-ever-display-of-queen-elizabeth-ii-fashions/105972016</link><description>The showcase will feature around 200 garments, including her wedding and coronation dresses, alongside never-before-seen items.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04a47650b925d8f836375647ee9eb62b</guid></item><item><title>Reddit and Kick added to child social media ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/reddit-and-kick-added-to-child-social-media-ban/105971750</link><description>Reddit and Kick will be included in the world-first social media ban for children under 16, which begins next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1d270418671127d74fc448c316aa89b</guid></item><item><title>Former US vice-president Dick Cheney dies aged 84</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/dick-cheney-former-us-vice-president-dies/105972142</link><description>Dick Cheney, considered to be one of the most powerful vice-presidents in US history, has died at age 84, his family has said in a statement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f0c289b54150dc3a8e54d06e0e33bf</guid></item><item><title>Choice hands Commonwealth Bank Shonky Award for fourth time, also calling out Temu, HCF and energy retailers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/choice-shonky-award-commbank-temu-hcf/105964682</link><description>Five companies have been handed the infamous annual award by consumer group Choice, in a bid to name and shame "dodgy products, services and companies".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">395087cc45a22cfda5a7e1e359f26f5f</guid></item><item><title>ASIC shone a light on private lending and did not like what it saw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/asic-deep-dive-into-the-hazy-world-of-private-lending/105965776</link><description>The corporate regulator is threatening Australia's nascent private lending industry with tighter regulation if it does not see a significant lift in standards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1c877b2ee59f887d73b8608bf4dbc63</guid></item><item><title>Norway's sovereign wealth fund to vote against Elon Musk's $1.5t Tesla pay deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/musk-1-trillion-pay-packet-rejected-by-major-shareholder/105972264</link><description>Norway's sovereign wealth fund says it will vote against ratifying Tesla chief executive Elon Musk's proposed compensation package, which is potentially worth $US1 trillion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cdf0ff85b34768849610700b43d33fa</guid></item><item><title>David Beckham receives knighthood from King Charles at Windsor, with wife to be known as Lady Beckham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/david-beckham-receives-knighthood/105972298</link><description>World-famous footballer David Beckham is handed the honour, for services to sport and charity, at a ceremony at Windsor Castle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74efafab9422e6724ca17f6569405651</guid></item><item><title>Five people sentenced to death in China for their role in Myanmar scam centres</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/myanmar-scam-factory-death-penalty-in-china/105972292</link><description>A Shenzhen court has sentenced five people to death for their involvement in a violent criminal gang with fraud operations in Myanmar, Chinese state media says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe3501bf310ef97982468b513af36bca</guid></item><item><title>Zohran Mamdani favourite to become New York mayor as polls close in US elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/new-yorkers-head-to-the-polls-mamdani/105972344</link><description>Zohran Mamdani, who looks set to become the Big Apple's first Muslim mayor, has declared that it is "time for a new day in our politics" as voters headed to the polls in America's largest city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">888fcf543615e64b28ecf28585e00c6c</guid></item><item><title>Some homebuyers feel left behind one month into Australian government's 5pc deposit scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/homebuyer-anxiety-over-five-per-cent-home-deposit-scheme/105956296</link><description>The federal government's expanded 5 per cent deposit scheme is intended to be a leg-up into the housing market but some first home buyers struggling to secure a loan or a deposit are worried they will be left behind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1d75d21b47acce84e60ae881238163c</guid></item><item><title>Marinus Link project payouts cheered by some Tasmanian farmers, but others refuse to budge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/landowners-compensation-to-host-marinus-transmission-lines/105969056</link><description>The fate of the contentious Marinus Link project lies in the hands of hundreds of Tasmanian landowners, some of whom are welcoming the financial compensation. For others, it's a different story.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0375c1b94325d40ff0cbe22e3132d300</guid></item><item><title>What can Australia learn from Norway's approach to taxing resources?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/lessons-for-australia-from-norways-tax-on-resources/105939048</link><description>Norway struck oil in the 1960s. Now, almost a quarter of its national budget is funded through its sovereign wealth fund. How does Australia compare with taxing its resources?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c82fa15bc0ba3c38978449986d8905ad</guid></item><item><title>US Federal Reserve pumps cash into Wall Street as banking system shows signs of stress</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/us-fed-pumps-billions-into-economy-to-avert-credit-crunch/105970180</link><description>Analysts say recent Wall Street activity shows pockets of global money markets are coming under strain. It has got some people worried the world could be heading towards another global credit crunch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c41e7ad4a49feaf61dda8a2c61d228b</guid></item><item><title>Administrators called in for Tahmoor coal owner amid $29m in unpaid royalties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/tamoor-coal-owner-enters-voluntary-administration/105970422</link><description>The future of a NSW coal mine remains unclear after its holding company entered administration, with the mine owing more than $100 million in outstanding debt, including almost $30 million in unpaid royalties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dc3ea5c0e82deb93cf7cf9563554309</guid></item><item><title>Does intermittent fasting dull your mental edge? We crunched the data for the best advice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/intermittent-fasting-mental-performance-research/105970476</link><description>Intermittent fasting can have health benefits, but does being hungry affect our cognitive abilities? Here's what all the evidence tells us.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b79d77e8e5083c608a92039765518c74</guid></item><item><title>November's 'beaver' full moon will be the closest supermoon of the year. Here's how to see it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/november-supermoon-beaver-full-moon/105969072</link><description>The difference from other full moons won't be all that noticeable to the naked eye, but you can enhance the viewing experience if you pick the right time and vantage point.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bab3dc4ef250ead0cd4756b6ec191cd</guid></item><item><title>Using her legs to shoot, Indian star Sheetal Devi is breaking boundaries in para archery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/indian-star-sheetal-devi-breaking-boundaries-in-para-archery/105931584</link><description>Growing up in Jammu and Kashmir to a humble farmer family, Devi's father says she found her own way to do everything — including learning to shoot a bow with astonishing precision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca077391489fda7ff5dc2cd12c6f1747</guid></item><item><title>Workplace culture reviewed at Toowoomba Hospital amid maternity leadership turnover</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/toowoomba-hospital-workplace-culture-review-maternity-concerns/105965506</link><description>Thousands of babies are born at the Toowoomba Base Hospital each year, but some women say they are scared to give birth there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b2e79adfa9003ccfd3e3a85b025d55</guid></item><item><title>Judge awards $500,000 to Joanna Scott in Ben Aulich-founded companies share dispute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/federal-court-joanna-scott-compensation-share-dispute/105971892</link><description>The Federal Court has found a Canberra woman was unfairly stripped of the value of her shares in two companies founded by former lawyer Ben Aulich, awarding her $500,000 in compensation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c5bde13edb3b0ea97324eaf9647dc96</guid></item><item><title>Residents warned to be aware of 'disaster chasers' after severe storms. Here's what to look out for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/qld-warning-for-people-impacted-by-storms-disaster-chasers/105970790</link><description>After being smashed by giant hail, south-east Queensland residents are being warned to be aware.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a52108c0a415a64a3024d5dfba1cffb</guid></item><item><title>Documents reveal Bureau of Meteorology's new website could cost $78m — or as much as $150m</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/true-cost-of-bureau-of-meteorology-new-website/105948508</link><description>Tender documents and sources show the Bureau of Meteorology's new website may have cost between $78m and $150m — much higher than initially reported.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7041e67cdf3a5add3f12bb1f0d49a9cc</guid></item><item><title>Western Sydney hospital report finds 'avoidable' errors in lead up to Deaf man's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/western-sydney-hospital-admits-errors-deaf-man-death/105969074</link><description>Bruce Drabsch's daughter Melinda Dagger, who was travelling to hospital to be with her ailing father, was phoned by a doctor and asked to inform her mother her husband of more than six decades had died, because no Auslan interpreter was provided.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b21237108b80b0debc2a50538b2cb874</guid></item><item><title>NRL to crack down on poaching contracted stars in wake of Lachlan Galvin saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/nrl-launches-new-anti-tampering-rules-in-wake-of-galvin-saga/105972520</link><description>NRL clubs are set to be put on notice and told they can no longer publicly declare interest in a player at a rival team unless the target is off contract.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1f8ce2e6e4238a45e37ee2da215f34a</guid></item><item><title>Typhoon Kalmaegi leaves dozens dead in flooding rains and intense winds in Philippines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/typhoon-kalamaegi-leaves-dozens-dead-in-floods-and-winds/105972498</link><description>More than 50 people are dead and hundreds of thousands displaced after rains from Typhoon Kalmaegi flooded the central Philippines, sweeping away trucks and shipping containers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ec4eb2ce5ff5a78e63e738a3ca8aaa0</guid></item><item><title>Race Around the World: ABC on the hunt for fearless content creators for global adventure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/race-around-the-world-2026-abc-how-to-apply/105941288</link><description>Cult '90s show Race Around the World is back, and we're on the hunt for fearless storytellers! Got a passport, an epic sense of adventure and an eye for a story? We want to hear from you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f80bbeaff371c0005e109bb45167aaa1</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Question Time erupts as treasurer accuses Ted O'Brien of 'egregious lies' — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/federal-politics-live-blog-nov-5/105971464</link><description>Jim Chalmers accuses Ted O'Brien of spreading "egregious lies" about government spending, leading to protests from the opposition. Take a look back at the day's coverage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78157b6e3b56ff4b146a0f2531b2d83b</guid></item><item><title>CSIRO koala population estimates triple, but conservationists cast doubt on figures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/csiro-koala-monitoring-population-estimate-triples/105958844</link><description>Koala advocates and logging supporters have seized on the release of data showing koala population estimates tripled in the past three years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c2275f4a2bbf56302eb72d9521503cb</guid></item><item><title>ASX turns red as Japan's market, Wall St futures tumble, Bitcoin plunges below $US100k</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/105972654</link><description>Australian stocks turn negative as the Nikkei follows the steep tech-inspired sell-off on Wall Street overnight, and a slump in Bitcoin to below $US100,000 for the first time since June.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eeaa9689c88ad2c3d28f4647a4b9ae9c</guid></item><item><title>Key Queensland inland highways left without EV chargers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/inland-highways-left-without-ev-chargers/105950356</link><description>The Queensland government says schemes to help grow its electric charger network have been "fully contracted" with "no additional funding committed", leaving it to towns, roadhouses and accommodation providers to fill the gap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b56f386070c9f02dad04599f79cd50ab</guid></item><item><title>Karenia cristata species source of toxins in SA's algal bloom, scientists believe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/south-australian-algal-bloom-source-identification/105968904</link><description>Scientists believe they have identified the species responsible for the toxins in South Australia's marine algal bloom that has killed millions of aquatic animals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">290c55cec4033bb9e0d95d0dd09f8377</guid></item><item><title>Liz Heggaton lobbies federal parliament for better prostate treatment after husband's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/widow-takes-fight-for-awareness-of-prostate-cancer-to-canberra/105947410</link><description>Liz Heggaton has become an "accidental advocate" for prostate cancer after her husband Craig took his own life while receiving treatment for the disease.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f87ad562de25f3e888ead140d6427e7</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios to face Aryna Sabalenka in Battle of the Sexes exhibition in Dubai</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/kyrgios-to-face-sabalenka-in-dubai-exhibition/105972676</link><description>Nick Kyrgios and Aryna Sabalenka are to star in the latest man-vs-woman tennis match, with Kyrgios following several notable Australians in doing so.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1599946063764dd30e9cd2dee209bbb4</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley defends process to reach position on net zero</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/sussan-ley-defends-process-to-reach-position-on-net-zero/105972746</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">794e73f5dc31c5c0c87bc66b25d0a22b</guid></item><item><title>Thunderstorms, hail, damaging winds mark WA weather forecast for much of the week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/severe-weather-warning-for-wa-with-thunderstorms-damaging-winds/105971670</link><description>A severe weather system is expected to bring thunderstorms, damaging winds and hail to much of Western Australia this week — with 50mm of rain or more possible for some areas through Thursday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a86567a88b312d0246b0f30c41788cb</guid></item><item><title>GrainCorp class action settlement fails with dispute set to head back to court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/graincorp-numurkah-class-action-pollution-settlement-fails/105969088</link><description>A class action stemming from a long-standing dispute over alleged noise and odour pollution from a GrainCorp factory in Victoria will head back to court after the parties failed to agree on a settlement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89032351edc8881f6a530948097f5f55</guid></item><item><title>‘Deeply scar and hurt people’: Women and girls turning away from community sport due to racism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/racism-turning-women-and-girls-away-from-community-sport/105966058</link><description>A new study reveals women and girls are being turned away from community sport by racist behaviours including appearance-based name-calling and a lack of understanding of diverse cultures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fa7a391bfb82a77139c75cb2e824ce3</guid></item><item><title>Police charge husband with murder over the 1991 death of Whittlesea woman Melinda Freeman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/vic-man-charged-over-melinda-freeman-death/105972814</link><description>Police say 63-year-old Craig Freeman has been charged with murder over the death of Whittlesea woman Melinda Freeman in 1991.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">218ad57b382f24fbf0960c21713ebbdd</guid></item><item><title>Robert Taylor, ex-lead guitarist of NZ rock band Dragon, dies aged 74</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/robert-taylor-lead-guitarist-of-dragon-dies/105972792</link><description>Robert Taylor, the former lead guitarist of the New Zealand band behind hits like April Sun in Cuba and Are you old Enough?, has died aged 74.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55396787ee92895e52a061349eadc616</guid></item><item><title>Synergy lodges applications for 'divisive' wind farm on WA's south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/scott-river-wind-farm-divides-community/105967602</link><description>A proposed 20-turbine wind farm at Scott River in WA's South West reaches a development milestone with developers and power provider Synergy lodging formal applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5751ae247bc4d76af5cb9707f8a08d13</guid></item><item><title>Helen Garner wins Baillie Gifford Prize for collected diaries, How to End a Story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/helen-garner-diaries-baillie-gifford-prize-how-to-end-a-story/105942040</link><description>After being featured in Dua Lipa's book club and the SATC spin-off, Helen Garner has won the Baillie Gifford Prize for non-fiction for her collected diaries, How to End a Story.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc9ca65daad3bb3dd0b24fafb4b31c93</guid></item><item><title>Bell Bay Aluminium and Hydro Tasmania 'buy time' with short-term power deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/bell-bay-aluminium-one-year-in-principle-power-agreement/105972712</link><description>Bell Bay Aluminium and Hydro Tasmania reach an in-principle power agreement, after the smelter last month told staff the company's future in northern Tasmania was at "significant risk".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4298c97de9ac427f425a17e120620b39</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley confronts leadership coup speculation head-on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/ley-confronts-leadership-coup-speculation-head-on/105972636</link><description>The opposition leader has sought to hose down speculation she will soon be toppled, saying she is "completely confident" she will still be in the job at the end of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27dd7b404e344f1c584ef230d5c292ca</guid></item><item><title>Dawesville man accused of grooming, sexually assaulting girls faces 59 charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/dawesville-man-accused-of-grooming-sexually-assaulting-girls/105973002</link><description>WA Police charge a 34-year-old man with dozens more child sex abuse charges, including sexually assaulting girls he groomed online, after an initial investigation earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9307ff31ea9c97b85fa9a2c44b67661f</guid></item><item><title>Mount Gambier's Valley Lake welcomes 200 disc golfers for The Eruption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/disc-golf-valley-lake-mount-gambier-sport-eruption-tournament/105964336</link><description>A volcanic eruption 6,000 years ago created the Valley Lake and the conditions for one of Australia's most popular disc golf courses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">302a464d63d812076e45b6d801ad9ec4</guid></item><item><title>Older Australians face long wait to be assessed for aged care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/older-australians-face-long-wait-for-aged-care-assessments/105971968</link><description>Families and insiders say the system to assess people for aged care is in crisis, with 116,000 people on the waiting list. Once approved, they join the queue to get a home care package, which stands at more than 120,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0de5763dd459968f4d5932df674f951f</guid></item><item><title>Little penguins re-establish breeding grounds on NSW far south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/little-penguins-eden-breeding-twofold-bay/105963874</link><description>A re-establishing little penguin colony, once locally extinct, is finding its feet on the NSW far south coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e10f957ed611f695bf39b4cf259a0a5a</guid></item><item><title>Max Dowman, 15-year-old Arsenal winger, becomes Champions League's youngest player</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/max-dowman-arsenal-champions-league-youngest-player/105973312</link><description>At 15 years and 308 days old, Arsenal winger Max Dowman comes on as a sub against Slavia Prague to become the youngest player in Champions League history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d4ce5fd11cc2e2739eb8714e11ffba4</guid></item><item><title>Huge plume of smoke seen after plane crash at Louisville International Airport in Kentucky</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/large-plume-of-smoke-rises-after-plane-crash/105973144</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b738e5f30c1d0200849a197ed8d79fb</guid></item><item><title>At least seven dead after UPS cargo plane crashes during take-off at Louisville airport in Kentucky</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/ups-cargo-plane-crashes-near-louisville-airport-in-kentucky/105973170</link><description>A UPS cargo plane with three people on board crashes after exploding during take-off from Louisville International Airport in the US state of Kentucky.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86ea08ad2cb3cd67fcf4d9aa9d61bb64</guid></item><item><title>Australia names its squad for the first Ashes Test in Perth, Jake Weatherald potential opener</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/live-ashes-first-test-squad-announcement/105973038</link><description>Australia has named its squad for the first Ashes Test, but is no closer to knowing who will open the batting in Perth on November 21.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0d0c619f43c5212413b9ae025f1ea53</guid></item><item><title>Mel C from the Spice Girls talks about living in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/mel-c-from-the-spice-girls-talks-about-living-in-australia/105968924</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a162283a54c754009788142885508497</guid></item><item><title>Jacinda Ardern on her never-before-seen moments in new documentary Prime Minister</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/jacinda-ardern-on-her-never-before-seen-moments/105972672</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41cd6b4e24d11c534876e563c48ab82a</guid></item><item><title>Murchison shires, residents complain about water quality despite significant upgrades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/murchison-shires-residents-call-for-water-infrastructure-upgrade/105966434</link><description>Stinging eyes, dead plants and a "white" film over appliances are among water complaints in Western Australia's Murchison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">016fd112348bb6fa7d37a1ebf49e6143</guid></item><item><title>Ballina shipwreck mystery close to being solved by analysis of single piece of wood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/shipwreck-mystery-close-to-being-solved-maritime-history/105969238</link><description>The identity of a shipwreck that was exposed in northern New South Wales by Cyclone Alfred has been narrowed down to just 13 vessels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6775e15d7d59b516970a94ace342837</guid></item><item><title>Man rescued near Mount Buller after being caught in unexpected November snow dump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/mt-buller-rescue-snow-dump-hikers/105972882</link><description>Police say that a 20-year-old man who was caught in a blizzard near Mount Buller overnight has been safely rescued.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cefd2142c50ec9161672bd272387b36b</guid></item><item><title>Behind the News presenter Jack Evans designs T-shirts to share Indigenous language on screen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/behind-the-news-indigenous-language-t-shirts/105953066</link><description>Every week ABC Behind the News presenter Jack Evans designs a T-shirt featuring a word from his mob's language and shares it with the show's audience.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7ab1434c160dd6d0b882200d6674082</guid></item><item><title>Race discrimination commissioner questions AFL's commitment to fighting racism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/race-discrimination-commissioner-questions-afls-commitment/105956870</link><description>Australia's race discrimination commissioner says the AFL is falling far short of its responsibility to combat "horrific racism" aimed at its players.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cbaad57fc32fce7ce02fb245ee9f682</guid></item><item><title>Father and son die after being stung by swarm of 'murder hornets' during Laos holiday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/father-and-son-killed-by-murder-hornets-during-holiday-laos/105973530</link><description>An American teacher and his teenage son die after being stung more than 100 times by a swarm of hornets while climbing down a tree after zip-lining at a resort in Laos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f91785963588c4bc0b4b9dc7a491425</guid></item><item><title>Bureau of Meteorology wave buoy in SA offline again despite nine-month repair</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/bureau-of-meteorology-wave-buoy-in-sa-offline-again/105971410</link><description>Despite a new "specialist mooring" part that took nearly a year to import and install, the Cape du Couedic wave buoy is offline again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea42eb950667781326303b07e17db109</guid></item><item><title>NYC election result delivers democratic socialist candidate Zohran Mamdani stunning win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/nyc-election-results-set-to-deliver-win-for-zohran-mamdani/105968288</link><description>New Yorkers shake the United States's political establishment and deliver 34-year-old democratic socialist Zohran Mamdani a stunning victory in the city's contentious mayoral election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffed6d1ff9cd680875f37d08206f16a6</guid></item><item><title>Woman seriously injured after car ploughs into Launceston CBD food court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/mortys-launceston-food-court-car-crash/105974210</link><description>Tasmania Police says a woman has been seriously injured after a car crashed into a food court in Launceston's CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2c0da38e17576740aa0249b2f1af54b</guid></item><item><title>Two men charged with murder over gangland assassination of John Versace in Condell Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/john-versace-two-men-charged-with-murder/105974366</link><description>The pair have been charged after the cleanskin tradie was killed outside his family home in May.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78c1f52631bfbfbe386183900863725a</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten Windsor is a prince no more but will this be enough to quell public anger?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-prince-title-stripped-public-anger/105965636</link><description>King Charles III's move to strip Andrew of all his titles and boot him out of his sprawling Windsor Park palace was a defining moment, but some say the former prince is getting off too lightly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c0b30443866aeacde4468e4b329d221</guid></item><item><title>Man's misdiagnosis with cancer after pathology error 'linked with his death', coroner finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/sa-pathology-error-leads-to-cancer-misdiagnosis-coroner-finds/105974340</link><description>The consequences of a contaminated biopsy sample, which led to a man being wrongly diagnosed with lung cancer and having part of his lung unnecessarily removed, were "profound", a coroner has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9661527d7a456e3279840a2fcf36925</guid></item><item><title>Experts share tiny home warning as interest from young people soars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/are-tiny-homes-the-solution-to-the-housing-crisis/105971646</link><description>Public interest in tiny homes has skyrocketed in recent years, but experts warn they come with their own problems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a6a8b535f9eee8a3528beda0ca121e3</guid></item><item><title>Former NRL star Trent Merrin charged with $140,000 crypto theft</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/trent-merrin-arrested-over-crypto-theft/105973884</link><description>Former NRL star Trent Merrin is arrested in the Illawarra, accused of stealing $140,000 in cryptocurrency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f39c5f0d9ca5b3479b340b2cd87dea8</guid></item><item><title>AFLW rising talent Sophie McKay comes from a famous football family. Yet she almost didn't play</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/sophie-mckay-carlton-blues-aflw-eve-of-finals/105969480</link><description>Despite coming from a family with a strong pedigree for football, one of the AFLW's best new talents almost gave it up. Now, she is enjoying putting on a show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">927031e16b31748a06901aafcabd936e</guid></item><item><title>Former Zimbabwe cricket captain Sean Williams reveals 'drug addiction' during probe over mystery withdrawal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/cricket-sean-williams-drug-addiction-zimbabwe-career-over/105974698</link><description>Sean Williams's cricket career with Zimbabwe comes to an end as a probe into his withdrawal from a T20 World Cup qualification tournament reveals his battle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f80e3000838b09f8e430be4cd2d897aa</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberals to phase out stamp duty by 2041 if they win next election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/sa-liberals-promise-to-phase-out-stamp-duty-if-elected/105973000</link><description>South Australia's Liberal party says it will phase out stamp duty by 2041, if elected in March, but the premier has labelled the promise as "one of the most reckless, dangerous policy announcements" he has ever seen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c32ca0ea078f458026a425837d63df2</guid></item><item><title>Local screen industry welcomes proposed Australian content obligation for streaming services</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/local-content-quotas-streaming-services-industry-response/105974654</link><description>On Tuesday, Arts Minister Tony Burke proposed a requirement for 10 per cent of streaming services' local expenditure to be spent on Australian film and TV. Here's what the industry thinks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2774843308e682b9de6dc892da81a1e</guid></item><item><title>Coalition housing spokesman says first home buyer house prices should fall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/bragg-housing-prices-first-home-buyers-fall/105974600</link><description>Taking a position he acknowledges his colleagues may not always want to admit, the Coalition's housing spokesman says prices for "entry-level" properties need to come down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de130e155bef690054826aef5fed6239</guid></item><item><title>Workers at Sydney's Concord Hospital critically injured when hit by car during coffee break</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/concord-hospital-crash-two-seriously-injured-sydney/105974296</link><description>NSW Ambulance paramedics treated a 47-year-old man and a 24-year-old woman, who are Concord Hospital employees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">859a9f71992e8204ded6a84d48854a6f</guid></item><item><title>Viking Cruises cancels second Newcastle visit amid Rising Tide protest safety fears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/rising-tide-climate-change-protest-cruise-liner-cancellation/105972852</link><description>A Hunter Valley businessman is demanding recompense after the cancellation of a second cruise liner's visit to Newcastle amid safety fears sparked by a planned climate change protest on the harbour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5d0a9c04e8bbb7def78c1307845511b</guid></item><item><title>Josh Giddey joins Michael Jordan in rare club after helping Chicago Bulls erase 24-point deficit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/basketball-josh-giddey-triple-double-chicago-bulls-comeback-win/105975132</link><description>Australia's Josh Giddey becomes the first Bulls player to record back-to-back triple doubles since Michael Jordan in 1989 as the Bulls continue their fast start to the NBA season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">157fcac9fea3df475d620b3627728a2d</guid></item><item><title>Moving to the outback gave me courage to do things I never dreamed of</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/moving-to-the-outback-gave-me-courage/105952130</link><description>Being in the middle of nowhere, you learn what really matters. You find yourself experiencing things with unbridled passion, without shame or second-guessing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bcd8762ccdfc9d3d756e2c0f2ff17cd</guid></item><item><title>Seven people arrested in counter-terrorism sting in regional Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/police-arrest-seven-people-in-qld-counter-terrorism-operation/105974254</link><description>Seven people have been arrested in a months-long counter-terrorism sting in regional Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd2105f0e1587785961253281032fb8f</guid></item><item><title>National Gallery of Australia anticipates rolling closures for repairs as it flags funding gaps</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/david-pocock-concerned-national-gallery-nga-leaking/105973662</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese's 2023 promise to fix a "building with buckets to collect leaks" remains unfulfilled, according to the National Gallery of Australia's annual report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eefeed72542fa85bceba3bf142639057</guid></item><item><title>Mayor-elect of New York City Zohran Mamdani targets Donald Trump in victory speech.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/zohran-mamdani-takes-aim-trump/105975390</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb9e8d820f013a96e1ae09f54b00a98c</guid></item><item><title>Bundaberg council takes roadside produce seller to court twice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/bundaberg-council-takes-roadside-produce-seller-to-court-twice/105974120</link><description>Raymond Aitkin has been selling seasonal fruit by the side of the road for more than 20 years, but he has found himself before the court twice this year and claims the council is singling him out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">561144eac511440df4e875071ed0c951</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Police crackdown on e-mobility devices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/queensland-police-e-mobility-evices/105975504</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebb26355111c271c41ad6ff015ac7c78</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government urged to use existing laws to 'crack down', impound illegal e-motorbikes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/queensland-government-crack-down-urged-on-illegal-e-motorbikes/105972704</link><description>Some advocacy bodies say the government has all the laws it needs to manage the e-motorbike "crisis" on its streets. It just needs to enforce them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91af0ced2621e9e3724159de491cb907</guid></item><item><title>Zohran Mamdani's win in New York City will send a message to Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/new-york-mayor-zohran-mamdani-donald-trump-and-democrats/105973460</link><description>After using a Trump-style tactic in his campaign, Zohran Mamdani probably now has the US president's begrudging respect — as well as his attention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f47c35effdd3a7250244702bc28abfd8</guid></item><item><title>Wallaroo Mines Primary School principal stood down as education department investigates allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/wallaroo-mines-primary-school-principal-stood-down/105974324</link><description>South Australia's Department for Education confirms the principal of a regional primary school has been stood down pending an investigation into allegations made by students' parents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa8d8f9cfd76c5ba18818d0baee5ba43</guid></item><item><title>US 2025 election winners: Virginia and New Jersey get new governors, Proposition 50 passes in California</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/us-2025-election-winners-governors-mayors-ballot-measures/105975214</link><description>Millions of Americans have flocked to polling booths around the US, casting their votes for governors, mayors and ballot measures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">689d23ed2a36fc25c1198318e2cda549</guid></item><item><title>Nearly 8 million hectares burnt during Northern Territory's hottest October on record</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/eight-million-hectares-burnt-during-record-hot-october-nt/105975262</link><description>Last month nearly 8 million hectares were burnt in the Northern Territory, an area bigger than the entire state of Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab9112ca30b6ed547b7c19fc1f795222</guid></item><item><title>Twice proves there is an audience thirsty for K-pop in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/twice-sydney-k-pop-concert-attracts-excited-fans/105975422</link><description>Next stop Melbourne for multinational K-pop group Twice after Sydney concerts are lapped up by excited fans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">719039fdc9dbad1f64054f2ced27b6c3</guid></item><item><title>Parents call for action after Isla Metcalfe's death outside Rouse Hill Public School</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/rouse-hill-school-parents-call-for-action-girls-death/105975566</link><description>Parents of students at a Sydney school where a five-year-old girl was hit by a car and killed last week have demanded action to prevent another tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4965a2929369af52c1bdfe1018f59a8</guid></item><item><title>Which social media platforms will be forced to ban Australian users under the age of 16?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/what-social-media-apps-are-getting-banned-in-australia/105973258</link><description>Nine platform are included in Australia's world-first social media ban for under 16s next month, however the regulator warns that list could grow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5de49dc79553ac4107728ec451d10bd</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand coach Stacey Jones calls for greater scrutiny of warm-ups as NRL continues probe into Eliesa Katoa incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/rugby-league-stacey-jones-eliesa-katoa-warm-ups-scrutiny/105976068</link><description>New Zealand coach Stacey Jones says his thoughts are with Eliesa Katoa as he prepares his side to take on Samoa in the final of the Pacific Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1c60b917a6b66b573f077d0cf70324c</guid></item><item><title>Logan City Council commissions independent review into flood map modelling after receiving thousands of complaints</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/qld-logan-city-council-flood-modelling-independent-review/105974734</link><description>A south-east Queensland council has commissioned an independent review of its flood zone mapping modelling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6af7b2511dd5d2498d6e6027b7afb5d</guid></item><item><title>Iran, Russia, and India have silenced their critics overseas. Could they do the same here?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/countries-capable-willing-assassination-australian-soil/105975018</link><description>Spy chief Mike Burgess will not name the countries capable and willing to assassinate their dissidents on Australian soil, but these are some possibilities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8251c9ddd3e64cbb7e2bff0fd2977ee</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate vandalism of telecommunications tower as Optus outage hits NSW Hunter region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/vandalism-causes-optus-outage-in-hunter/105975986</link><description>Customers have been warned that calls to triple-0 may be impacted by an Optus outage in the NSW Hunter region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad2a04b7f77f8fcf827e850da44b4c99</guid></item><item><title>Convicted mushroom murderer Erin Patterson outlines her reasons to appeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/erin-patterson-mushroom-murderer-appeals-conviction/105975896</link><description>Triple-murderer Erin Patterson is fighting to have her conviction quashed, claiming there was a "substantial miscarriage of justice" during her trial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e76f0eb39a86c9cfe816e7b6d2a57764</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105975122</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e91d0465be4ab338c89eeb1fe81826c2</guid></item><item><title>Perth Football League's suspension of Osborne Park FC a 'line in the sand' moment, says league boss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/perth-football-league-osborne-park-ban-line-in-sand/105975548</link><description>The boss of the Perth Football League urges clubs to treat the suspension of Osborne Park FC over an end-of-season costume stunt as a "line in the sand moment" for their culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d14c5720caea0299a7ea4e19c1fa4a2c</guid></item><item><title>One in 10 homes bought using first home buyers guarantee in October</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/one-in-10-homes-bought-using-government-incentive-in-october/105976010</link><description>About one in 10 homes sold last month were bought by Australians using Labor's expanded 5 per cent deposit scheme to enter the market for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">105390b5913544e9cb6aac68340591e5</guid></item><item><title>Danielle North leaves Ambulance Victoria executive role after parliamentary inquiry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/victoria-ambulance-danielle-north-covid-funerals/105974020</link><description>Executive director Danielle North has departed Ambulance Victoria, after the service said she may have misled a parliamentary committee about her knowledge of gatherings during COVID lockdowns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85051c441df0330f241c97cf81bf1f76</guid></item><item><title>China lifts some tariffs on US farm goods but soybeans remain costly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/china-suspends-us-tariffs/105976254</link><description>China has ended retaliatory tariffs on a range of US agricultural products but will maintain 10 per cent tariffs on all US goods in response to President Donald Trump's "Liberation Day" duties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d957204129d4de0b35cb10e301561d2</guid></item></channel></rss>