<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 03:34:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Easy homemade granola that will last you weeks - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/easy-chunky-granola-with-nuts-and-seeds/105442842</link><description>When it comes to batch cooking, don't forget breakfast. This granola can make mornings easier and will last weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a385d3e380c821e791d0def365c56e1</guid></item><item><title>Nancy Guthrie may have been abducted in a 41-minute window, authorities say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/nancy-guthrie-potentially-abducted-in-41-minute-window/106313064</link><description>Nancy Guthrie was last seen alive when a relative dropped her outside her Tucson home after a family games night. The 84-year-old grandmother has now been missing for a week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa5ac9bb51cacf8178ae332625490dbc</guid></item><item><title>What is the AIN at the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics? Why Russian and Belarusian athletes are allowed to compete in Italy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/russia-belars-winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-ain/106306898</link><description>The Winter Olympics of Milano Cortina 2026 is another where Russian and Belarusian athletes will be largely absent, although there are a handful competing as individual neutral athletes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b156810fb69debab515ba1c4d4cfceb</guid></item><item><title>A 2026 Winter Olympics opening ceremony message of harmony and peace, rammed into a world of division</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/winter-olympics-2026-opening-ceremony-chilly-global-outlook/106316092</link><description>As the Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics Opening ceremony pleads a message of peace, the world outside the Olympic bubble burns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55c5f67fe73425a4675fe57a1c27a807</guid></item><item><title>Why 13yo Austin Appelbee's story of survival resonated so strongly across the globe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/austin-appelbee-quindalup-rescue-global-phenomenon/106306482</link><description>The remarkable story of Austin Appelbee's marathon swim for help went around the world, so why did it spark such an emotional reaction?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df0506ffba50ac7075d62dfa75270cd6</guid></item><item><title>The Mark of Cain lead singer on a lifetime masking the truth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/the-mark-of-cain-lead-singer-josie-scott-transgender/106315830</link><description>The lead singer of legendary Adelaide rockers The Mark of Cain this week announced she was transgender, but it comes after nearly 60 years of hiding the truth from everyone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f38fc9591c45b6185b51090540bed25</guid></item><item><title>Pregnant women in WA's Kimberley face big distances to hospital and high rates of heart condition, diabetes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/pregnant-women-kimberley-high-rates-heart-condition-and-diabetes/105995596</link><description>Pregnant women in WA's Kimberley experience high rates of preventable health conditions, hours of travel to receive basic care and limited support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a989455c0a62c3be3f08588519da209</guid></item><item><title>The moment turtle Terry was released from Sydney Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/the-moment-turtle-terry-was-released-from-sydney-harbour/106317662</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49c7dbf6c3e6b92b9cc8ad7b4bef2adc</guid></item><item><title>Why Wests Tigers hopeful Pat Herbert jumped off an excavator and into an NRL pre-season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/pat-herbert-nrl-wests-tigers-train-and-trial/106317620</link><description>After three years away from first grade, Pat Herbert was ready to get on with the rest of his life but a call from Wests Tigers got him off the job site and into an NRL pre-season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">916a7b8e20ff292d6a9e4fe1704fad62</guid></item><item><title>Daly River to hit major flood level on Sunday night, damage to homes expected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/nt-daly-river-major-flood-update-damage-evacuation/106317688</link><description>Almost 300 people from Daly River have been evacuated to Darwin, with just a handful of residents staying behind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40c7391489924e4c95d3971aa7147bfc</guid></item><item><title>If you could learn your baby's genetic disease risk at birth, would you?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/map-genome-dna-genetic-disease-newborn-screen/106305482</link><description>From rare cancers caught early to dementia foretold decades in advance, newborn genomic testing raises an unsettling question: Just because we can know, should we?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10b515034a68a9bbb421fb5da7cbb002</guid></item><item><title>Xavier Rudd on visiting Echuca, playing solo, and the spiritual being that follows him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/xavier-rudd-riverboats-tour-live-shows-solo/106299686</link><description>Xavier Rudd performs solo these days, but he carries a spirit with him wherever he goes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">524cef1858a02519f4777fc1222fcba8</guid></item><item><title>How Super Bowl half-time moments became flashpoints from the 'wardrobe malfunction' to caged kids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/super-bowl-half-time-show-janet-jackson-justin-timberlake/106307184</link><description>For a show that lasts roughly 13 minutes, the Super Bowl half-time performance has fuelled decades of conversation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5ff29a641957847844fbaf70655c0c1</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania looks at allowing public hospital midwives to help with homebirths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/tasmania-looks-at-homebirth-model/105899984</link><description>The Tasmanian government is developing a public homebirth model that would allow midwives working in the public system to support women to labour from their homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b288cd9590708ea54ac6e8efd974f327</guid></item><item><title>Coalition reunited after last-minute deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/deal-done-to-bring-coalition-back-together/102760848</link><description>The Liberals and Nationals have reached a breakthrough deal to reunite the Coalition after 11th-hour talks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03d631d89d350d9986b7badfae6006de</guid></item><item><title>Heat and fires expose ancestral remains in Victoria's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/heat-fires-expose-ancestral-remains-in-victorian-mallee/106304308</link><description>Ancestral remains that could be thousands of years old have been uncovered by erosion, dust storms and bushfires in Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49ce14146e6918e7cee89f1e59175fb2</guid></item><item><title>Before opening Meg's Bookshop in 1991, the Arnolds were told kids 'didn't read' in Port Pirie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/meg-s-bookshop-port-pirie-closes-after-35-years-south-australia/106277430</link><description>In one of Australia's most disadvantaged regions, more known for its lead than its literature, a couple wanted to open a book store but were told children didn't read books there. They did it anyway, and it went on to become a "world class" institution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">488cbf932021fe26386b52895acbaa59</guid></item><item><title>Valentino Guseli missed out on a bonus 2026 Winter Olympics medal, but won something even more important</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/valentino-guseli-2026-winter-olympics-big-air-snowboard/106318724</link><description>It was 18 months ago that Valentino Guseli blew out his ACL attempting a backside 1800 at the Beijing big air. At the Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics snowboard big air final, he put that ghost to rest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6cb85fcb30e9b60ce1daa388c5f7d61</guid></item><item><title>3 Doors Down frontman Brad Arnold dies after stage four cancer battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/3-doors-down-frontman-brad-arnold-dies/106318798</link><description>Brad Arnold, a founder and the lead singer of American rock band 3 Doors Down, dies nine months after revealing he had kidney cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cbbceb57b53ce8d7ad340e98b862894</guid></item><item><title>Savannah Guthrie indicates she will pay ransom for return of her mother in video message to apparent kidnappers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/savannah-guthrie-video-says-will-pay-ransom-for-kidnapped-mother/106318892</link><description>In a video posted to Instagram, the host of NBC's Today Show appears to directly address her mother's kidnappers, telling them she and her siblings have "received your message, and we understand".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">273da0c318b4f3898a711c2fb0f22645</guid></item><item><title>Equine photography in demand in Australian performance horse industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/equine-photography-in-demand-in-performance-horse-industry/106298426</link><description>From leaf blowers to dance moves, photographers use every trick they can think of to get the perfect shot for the biggest performance-horse sale in the southern hemisphere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22805fcce898863bfe3fedf070b53d08</guid></item><item><title>Payne Haas quits Brisbane to sign three-year deal with South Sydney Rabbitohs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/payne-haas-signs-with-south-sydney-for-2027/106319316</link><description>South Sydney have pulled off one of the biggest recruitment moves in NRL history after signing Brisbane enforcer Payne Haas to a three-year contract from 2027.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4006492fb182ade2ddeeb67451c5ec53</guid></item><item><title>Police recover pilot's body from croc-infested marsh after Normanton plane crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/police-recover-pilot-body-normanton-plane-crash/106319446</link><description>Police officers armed with rifles guarded their colleagues while they recovered the man's body from the crash site in difficult terrain near Normanton, in the Gulf of Carpentaria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6bcdff91b2f00027265cf151c25bc13</guid></item><item><title>Daly River flooding expected to reach 14m peak on Monday, as first damage to homes reported</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/nt-daly-river-flooding-homes-damaged-ahead-of-monday-peak/106318936</link><description>Several homes in the remote community of Daly River have sustained minor flood damage, as waters continue to rise ahead of an expected 14m peak level on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe93bd355478f5142fa25e391a32a338</guid></item><item><title>Coalition's rushed reunification does not solve their respective branding problems</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/coalition-reunification-liberals-nationals-sussan-ley/106304664</link><description>The Coalition has reunited, but the new agreement does not address underlying party tensions nor the surging fragmentation of the right.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4015c0b9e86f13b0cbf1a5cc8413b8c5</guid></item><item><title>Japan PM Sanae Takaichi leads coalition to landslide election victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/japan-election-sanae-takaichi-landslide-victory/106320228</link><description>Sanae Takaichi's Liberal Democratic Party and its coalition partner are expected to hold upwards of two-thirds of the seats in Japan's lower house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fb71b428c5bbf7507c7f3ce7b77658c</guid></item><item><title>Thailand PM Anutin Charnvirakul confident of forming government after election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/thailand-election-result-anutin-results/106320270</link><description>South-East Asia's second-largest economy went to the polls on Sunday in a tight race between conservatives aligned with the military and the monarchy, and progressive elements represented by the reform-driven People's Party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea445c2de3e44242cdf9e5b0f4e49cf0</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Diamonds smash Jamaica again to seal three-game series in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/all-too-easy-for-the-diamonds-in-sealing-series-win-over-jamaica/106320414</link><description>Kate Moloney celebrates her 50-game milestone in style as the Australian Diamonds post a 32-goal victory over an understrength Jamaica in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17c58aaad7fd1ed71acafd10afe3d217</guid></item><item><title>Green turtle released from Taronga Zoo's wildlife hospital after horror injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/green-turtle-released-taronga-zoo-after-fishing-line-injury/106317556</link><description>After surviving one of the worst fishing line injuries vet Rebecca Robey had ever seen, Terry the turtle has been set free.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b197fd3fc2005d27d37f85e98809f573</guid></item><item><title>Bullying surges in ACT public schools as parents, teachers speak out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/bullying-reports-rise-in-act-public-schools/106269450</link><description>Reports of bullying in ACT public schools have risen sharply in four years. Parents and teachers say children are paying the price, and the system is not coping.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7cda36cd7ac7cd9196735a6516e4323</guid></item><item><title>Explain the Internet: Why Wuthering Heights is one of the year's most controversial adaptations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/wuthering-heights-controversy-emerald-fennell-jacob-elordi/106305404</link><description>Days away from the release of Emerald Fennell's highly anticipated adaptation of Emily Brontë's classic novel, critics and fans alike are still fighting about text fidelity in the comments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51691c38c09e7e812fe2f8ae70e9ae0d</guid></item><item><title>Deua River Valley and Cobargo still rebuilding six years after Black Summer bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/cobargo-deua-river-still-rebuilding-after-black-summer-bushfires/106273804</link><description>Residents who lived through the 2019-20 bushfires on the NSW South Coast say this summer's fires triggered traumatic memories, and highlighted the recovery and resilience projects that remain unfinished.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75a6395d574e8ce915a53455bd5abe17</guid></item><item><title>Liberals despair at prospect of 'non-existence' and weigh leadership change after catastrophic Newspoll</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/liberals-despair-after-disastrous-poll-weigh-sussan-ley-spill/106320642</link><description>Sussan Ley could face a challenge to her leadership from Angus Taylor this week after a disastrous opinion poll showed the Coalition parties falling further behind One Nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d6794b583bc82ebb66b82a29f4dee89</guid></item><item><title>Aussie stars as Seahawks use ferocious defence to claim Super Bowl win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/super-bowl-lx-live-blog-seahawks-vs-patriots-bad-bunny/106320762</link><description>The Seattle Seahawks overawe the New England Patriots in Super Bowl LX as punter Michael Dickson becomes the second ever Australian NFL champion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fad6557763c143875756ac2daf86b7c</guid></item><item><title>Backyard pods won't fix the housing crisis but they signal a shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/backyard-pods-wont-fix-the-housing-crisis/106314472</link><description>Australia's biggest hardware retailer has started selling tiny homes. Are backyard pods the answer to a national housing crisis?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dd2b8a3992ec554b10d8b236bba7c64</guid></item><item><title>Search ends for 'very loved' Gold Coast fisherman Ash Haigh after almost five days lost at sea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/search-ends-loved-gold-coast-fisherman-ash-haigh/106321162</link><description>Queensland Police has suspended the cross-border search for missing Gold Coast fisherman Ash Haigh after an extensive air and sea operation found no signs of life, with his sister describing him as a "very loved" family man.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b728597ddaf78153709b4ea9a825a3a8</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Lindsey Vonn hailed as 'idol' by downhill rivals after Milano Cortina crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/winter-olympics-rivals-pay-credit-to-lindsey-vonn/106320254</link><description>Lindsey Vonn's 2026 Winter Olympic Games ended in disaster, but her teammates and rivals have heaped praise on the three-time Olympic medallist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d1e30943c1086fc7cce481c2af84273</guid></item><item><title>Jon Kudelka, Walkley-winning Tasmanian cartoonist, dies from brain cancer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/jon-kudelka-tasmanian-cartoonist-dies/106321714</link><description>Award-winning Tasmanian cartoonist Jon Kudelka dies after being diagnosed with brain cancer in 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b64794da6dd1ff79a97006ebfd7d1f1b</guid></item><item><title>Rain brings relief and road closures after record heatwave in South Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/rain-brings-relief-and-road-closures-in-outback-sa/106321082</link><description>High rainfall in north-eastern South Australia brings some relief for pastoralists after record-breaking heat, with a reprieve expected for metropolitan Adelaide this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8abb8433aa6e8a46aaa308bd29d9653</guid></item><item><title>Five simple, tasty vegetarian recipes that are perfect for meat-free Mondays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/five-simple-tasty-vegetarian-recipes-for-meat-free-monday/106309846</link><description>Looking to add some more vegetarian dishes to your weekly rotation? We have you covered with these five recipes that are perfect for meat-free Mondays.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8ccc6ae83e7b914cda93001f414be5d</guid></item><item><title>Family rallies to save pets left behind in Daly River flood evacuation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/family-creates-makeshift-animal-shelter-daly-river-flooding-nt/106319036</link><description>When hundreds of people evacuated the Daly River community due to flooding, most had to leave their pets behind. But a nearby family swung into action to help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a64bdce8d15fa7b49eb8035ac084d64d</guid></item><item><title>Daly River expected to surpass major flood level before reaching peak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/nt-daly-river-expected-to-reach-major-flood-level-today/106320860</link><description>Flooding at the Daly River community is expected to surpass the major flood level late Monday, with a peak of 14.1 metres expected by Tuesday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee956724ec301301f81352410e8d51f8</guid></item><item><title>'Massive' Indonesian ghost barge washes up on tiny Torres Strait island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/mystery-indonesian-ghost-barge-washed-up-in-torres-strait/106323116</link><description>The barge drifted into Australian waters from Indonesia after breaking from its moorings during bad weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08b39ef063e5e2f00075ab3cf9dbea37</guid></item><item><title>Coalition reunited again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/coalition-reunited-again/106323374</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62e222383403c789b07fc80e8fe99a11</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Tropical Cyclone Mitchell expected to batter the Gascoyne region as it moves inland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/tropical-cyclone-mitchell-has-crossed-the-wa-north-west-coast/106322566</link><description>The system is expected to bring strong winds and heavy rain as it moves inland through the Gascoyne region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16fcc5ddef3af39a7f8a479648d4aaa0</guid></item><item><title>What happens when a medal is shared at the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/2026-winter-olympics-shared-silver-alpine-mens-team-combined/106324230</link><description>In the men's team combined Alpine skiing event at the 2026 Winter Olympics, the Swiss and Austrian teams tied for silver. So what happens to the bronze medal? And when there was a tie for bronze in the men's ski jumping, was there a spare bronze?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23ca44a0a4bf6ec3bbf545f329db23e6</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian cartoonist Jon Kudelka and the art of cutting through political spin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/jon-kudelka-tasmanian-cartoonist-illustrator-obituary/106322196</link><description>Hailed as an artist who "knew the power of comedy in holding truth to power", Jon Kudelka once described himself as "like a monkey with an automatic rifle".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57fe9e141789e47e0247d8471e7bb6b6</guid></item><item><title>Roblox on notice after 'disturbing' reports of child grooming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/government-puts-roblox-on-notice-reports-of-child-grooming/100020788</link><description>The government puts popular social gaming site Roblox on notice following media reports of children being approached and groomed by predators on the platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17bbfe956fe95675bddb65bf1b70eaed</guid></item><item><title>St Kilda star Max King injured again, Port ruckman Ivan Soldo out for season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/st-kilda-star-max-king-injured-again-port-ruckman-season-over/106324794</link><description>Max King has suffered another injury, further frustrating the St Kilda key forward's bid for an AFL return.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43a7cb7b674656d6ef9e220abeeb6274</guid></item><item><title>Cheryl Grimmer's family fights for new charges against suspect</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/cheryl-grimmer-nsw-parliament-debate-jeremy-buckingham/106321818</link><description>NSW Parliament will again debate the 1970 disappearance of toddler Cheryl Grimmer, following claims her family's pleas for fresh charges against a suspect who confessed to murdering her when he was a teenager have been ignored.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a621721b38ed6d61fcdd406868faa2a</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan reverses cricket T20 World Cup boycott and will face India in Sri Lanka</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/pakistan-reverses-world-cup-boycott-to-face-india-t20-world-cup/106324864</link><description>Pakistan has ‍agreed to play India ​in the ⁠T20 World Cup match scheduled to take ‌place in Colombo this ‍Sunday, February 15.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d7762f897f18cee09e2bbfe5253973e</guid></item><item><title>Native title holders take appeal over one of Australia's largest groundwater licences to High Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nt-high-court-singleton-station-aboriginal-groundwater-rights/106322626</link><description>The cultural value of water will be front and centre in the High Court in Canberra today as a group of native title holders from Central Australia fight to assert cultural rights over an aquifer under their lands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d334f651d8d34fed9db2b05f2f04adba</guid></item><item><title>Margot Robbie and Jacob Elordi sizzle, but Wuthering Heights isn't quite the full Brontë</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/wuthering-heights-movie-review-emerald-fennell-jacob-elordi/106321718</link><description>The two Queensland "bogans" put on a show, but Emerald Fennell's Wuthering Heights is more wish fulfilment than a meaningful adaptation of the classic novel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41b2ef0ef990ef2113fe88e9541e3117</guid></item><item><title>States urged to sign National Water Agreement even though users unaware what's in final version</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/waters-users-in-dark-on-water-policy-ready-for-signing/106314610</link><description>As the country's state governments and territories consider signing a new national water policy that seeks to address climate change and elevate First Nations knowledge, the agricultural industry fears it has been overlooked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f8c01ea5477b908bab868e3c766d92b</guid></item><item><title>Turtles discovered in Dumaresq Dam could be dumped pets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/turtles-discovered-in-dumaresq-dam-could-be-dumped-pets/106304016</link><description>The unexpected discovery of four turtle species in a dam near Armidale has left researchers wondering if people have been dumping unwanted pets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3644822f63b6c74afb1a388ba0882f6d</guid></item><item><title>Savannah Guthrie makes latest video plea as missing mother's ransom deadline nears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/savannah-guthrie-makes-new-video-plea-over-missing-mother/106325066</link><description>US TV host Savannah Guthrie says her family is at its "hour of desperation" in the search for their kidnapped mother, but makes no mention of a possible ransom in a new video.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d7b80629fdda5092a47af99f45d7a10</guid></item><item><title>Catherine O'Hara's cause of death revealed as pulmonary embolism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/catherine-ohara-cause-of-death-announced/106324996</link><description>Award-winning actress Catherine O'Hara died from a pulmonary embolism, according to her death certificate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0db2f6d1caf958e134132f56ca8ef189</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Milano Cortina organisers looking into broken medals after at least four incidents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/winter-olympics-medals-breaking-breezy-johnson-alysa-liu/106325112</link><description>Records are meant to be broken at the Olympics, but in the Milano Cortina Games, it is the medals being dismantled, and organisers are giving it "maximum attention".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da0eeb85cc783bf52dfeec17d907e78e</guid></item><item><title>Licensed program to kill native animals 'weak' and 'outdated' inquiry told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/licences-to-harm-native-animals-inquiry/106320826</link><description>Animal welfare groups are calling for a major overhaul into the system that allows native animals to be killed in NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93d7971e8816215b902c8e022b64e384</guid></item><item><title>Exploitation claims have been levelled against cruise ship company Carnival. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/carnival-cruise-exploitation-claims-what-we-know/106325788</link><description>A major cruise ship has been investigated by the maritime safety regulator for claims around poor working conditions. A spokesperson for The Carnival Cruise Line says it has "nothing to hide" and welcomes AMSA's oversight. Here's what we know so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fb766396c9c7d4da6c405ce6634ae51</guid></item><item><title>At school, I was my brother's protector. But I needed more support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/support-i-wish-i-had-at-school-while-caring-for-my-brother/106279156</link><description>I was my brother's protector at school, but the education system could have done more to support us both.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8737a14dea75637ab0e525bab21121a9</guid></item><item><title>Global Athlete accuses IOC of 'kowtowing' to Russia by including AIN athletes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/russian-winter-olympic-athletes-milan-cortina/106327282</link><description>Advocacy group Global Athlete has accused the IOC of enabling Russia by allowing 13 Russian and seven Belarusian athletes to compete at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c9a39c00f74fc512b507557d2b1ac8f</guid></item><item><title>Tahmoor Coal placed into administration as court hears creditor winding-up bid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/tahmoor-coal-mine-placed-into-voluntary-administration/106326534</link><description>Tahmoor Coal has been placed into voluntary administration just as the Supreme Court was set to hear a creditor's winding-up application.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">953d7d3b73b007feb1525c6e38b10dea</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government appoints tenderers for new oil and gas exploration in Taroom Trough</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/oil-gas-exploration-queensland-taroom-trough/106325922</link><description>The Queensland government approves new oil and gas exploration in a region they believe could become Australia's first new major oil province in 50 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ce99f23603aeb7aa96f732ac4f261b6</guid></item><item><title>Raymond Reddington murder trial hears Sharon Fulton seemed scared in hours before 1986 disappearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/sharon-fulton-murder-trial-raymond-reddington-woman-was-scared/106327376</link><description>A close friend of a woman allegedly murdered by her husband in Perth 40 years ago tells a Perth court she seemed frightened in the hours before her disappearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78ffe88ad62d326c893e3ac20446550a</guid></item><item><title>Cam Bolton fractures neck as training falls rule two Aussies out of Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/winter-olympics-2026-live-milano-cortina-moguls-ice-hockey/106326694</link><description>Australia's Cam Bolton and Misaki Vaughan are ruled out of the Games after training falls, while reigning Olympic gold medallist Jakara Anthony advances to the women's moguls final at the Milano Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf10d0c49b40e45eace54bd9ee12cefa</guid></item><item><title>Liberals plot resignations to pave way for leadership challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/liberals-plot-mass-resignation-to-force-leadership-spill-/106328762</link><description>Liberals are bracing for a wave of frontbench resignations as soon as Wednesday to pave the way for Angus Taylor to mount a leadership challenge against Sussan Ley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68227eb101c335608129c57bdf313d7f</guid></item><item><title>WA police investigate possible tobacco wars link to fire at Kelmscott store</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/fire-alleged-linked-to-illicit-tobacco-under-investigation/106325512</link><description>WA Police Commissioner Col Blanch confirms officers from Taskforce Maverick, which investigates crime linked to the illicit tobacco and vape trade, are involved with the investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c193a813072c7da9378b52e50d8e27c3</guid></item><item><title>Celine Cremer search in Arthur River finds more bones and missing backpacker's car key</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/car-key-teeth-found-search-celine-cremer-tasmania/106323260</link><description>Tasmania Police say a car key found in the Arthur River has been "formally verified" as belonging to missing backpacker Celine Cremer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f44f7b3c1d64c6fe98c04e84cabd033d</guid></item><item><title>Waterfalls on Uluru, Daly River flooding peaks as rain soaks Central Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nt-weather-rainfall-uluru-daly-river-flooding/106326436</link><description>Heavy rain in Central Australia has sent water cascading down the face of Uluru and filled the usually parched Todd River, while cutting off a number of remote communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">154698806a27d58e8b258474e05ea7dd</guid></item><item><title>The Epstein files are shaking Britain, but Donald Trump could still have 3 million reasons to worry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/epstein-files-shake-uk-but-white-house-could-still-be-worried/106324788</link><description>Donald Trump's enemies made no secret of their hopes the documents would contain something explosive enough to bring the president down, but right now the Epstein spotlight is on Britain's politicians and palaces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd62bb34a29f437c14df3ee1992e6c76</guid></item><item><title>Jakara Anthony picture perfect, Matt Graham with room to improve at 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games moguls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/jakara-anthony-matt-graham-pressure-moguls-qualifiers/106324214</link><description>Jakara Anthony will do anything aside from thinking about moguls skiing after qualifying number one for Wednesday's 2026 Winter Olympics final, taking to Lego, a puzzle and Grey's Anatomy instead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c5b1f5d3da4862fb201d76474dc2318</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberals face wipeout not seen since state bank election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/sa-liberals-face-wipeout-not-seen-since-state-bank-election/106325582</link><description>Labor faced a humiliating election loss following the state bank collapse in the early 90s. Now, recent polling shows a collapse of another kind could be brewing for the Liberal Party with One Nation hot on its heels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d37b7dfeb9d62359f82edf2221b3e29</guid></item><item><title>How to reduce loneliness while working remotely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/how-to-reduce-loneliness-while-working-remotely/106286338</link><description>Working remotely can be a lonely experience. Here's what you can do about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07ee38b05fb1af72edee6be374ac35ed</guid></item><item><title>Surgeon Kelvin Kong's life growing up Chinese and Indigenous in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/kelvin-kong-s-growing-up-chinese-and-indigenous-australia/106326388</link><description>Australia's first identified First Nations surgeon, Dr Kelvin Kong spoke about his Malaysian Chinese heritage during the annual Wang Gungwu lecture at Parliament House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3366e9b48200b228bb48ce12f315720</guid></item><item><title>FBI footage appears to show suspect in search for Nancy Guthrie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/fbi-footage-appears-to-show-suspect-in-search-for-nancy-guthrie/106329454</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b672dab476a4d5af8f2417bc7c354cc</guid></item><item><title>Citizen scientists work on 100-million-year-old ichthyosaur fossil in Winton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/ichthyosaur-winton-australian-age-of-dinosaurs-fossil/106310754</link><description>Participants from across Australia and the world travelled to outback Queensland to clean up the near-complete ichthyosaur fossil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af8a6ea34ab1f32371b167c057d77dd9</guid></item><item><title>Images of alleged tobacco wars kingpin Kazem Hamad released in Iraq</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/images-of-kazem-hamad-released-by-afp/106329460</link><description>Hamad was deported from Australia in 2023 and has been a key person of interest relating to firebombings at Victorian tobacco shops and businesses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e824b5d9e2cfb1c10502ba2cb1ccb7d</guid></item><item><title>Trump told police chief 'everyone' knew about Epstein, FBI document says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/trump-commerce-chief-claims-no-relationship-with-epstein/106329468</link><description>Donald Trump allegedly told police in 2006 that people in New York knew about Epstein, a newly uncovered FBI interview shows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3c205dcd4860dd580cc592880560660</guid></item><item><title>Volunteers say neglect by state's wildlife department caused bushfires on WA's south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/fitzgerald-river-bushfire-dbca-mismanagement/106321810</link><description>Farmers and volunteer firefighters say decades of neglect by WA's Department of Biodiversity, Conservation and Attractions is at the heart of fires that ripped through more than 200,000 hectares of state-managed land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40f45582a4045e521119758ac54edc75</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Stunning cheating admission overshadows medal win as Naumov brings tears with tribute — quick hits from day four</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/sport-quick-hits-winter-olympics-day-four-cheating-nauov-tribute/106329142</link><description>A Norwegian's first-ever medal is overshadowed by a stunning admission to reporters as Maxim Naumov pays tribute to his parents in the most beautiful way. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4ddae6dcef41de86448ed66a84d4881</guid></item><item><title>Western quoll joey born in outback NSW likely to be first in a century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/western-quoll-thrive-outback-nsw-after-taronga-program/106304882</link><description>Once thought to be extinct in NSW, the small, spotted, and highly photogenic western quoll is making a hard-fought comeback to the wild.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1127d8b0dfa1ad403186fda2e24d1f68</guid></item><item><title>High Court finds Catholic Church liable for priest's sexual abuse but halves compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/high-court-catholic-church-liable-priest-sexual-abuse/106329926</link><description>A man who suffered sexual abuse at the hands of a priest in the 1960s has won his High Court battle over liability, but had his compensation nearly halved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">115a801497fb65d312764e99856603d5</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 5, Wednesday, February 11</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide/106325628</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4808821c5d5c5ad794f816a30958d89</guid></item><item><title>Missing man Corey Chugg separated from friend while collecting firewood, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/search-for-missing-man-corey-chugg-in-tasmania/106328680</link><description>A 32-year-old man missing in Tasmania's north was collecting firewood with a friend when the pair became separated on Sunday, police have said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e1ef0edf011bcec194b5dfaf7f996fe</guid></item><item><title>Police say there was 'serious, imminent risk' of child kidnapping in Perth by Jason William Forbes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/baldivis-child-kidnapper-jason-william-forbes-update/106327906</link><description>WA Police say "something terrible" could have happened if there was a delay in intercepting a Baldivis man who planned to abduct and sexually abuse a child in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9cb2e1663474710cf734cdb38d48828</guid></item><item><title>Doongmabulla Springs decision leaves Qld government to weigh appeal or face trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/doongmabulla-springs-qld-government-appeal-or-face-trial/106305714</link><description>Wangan and Jagalingou peoples await the state government's next move after a win in their fight to have alleged damage to a sacred site near a mine in Central Queensland investigated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">409498e1a5333e429fc6fc92646dec77</guid></item><item><title>Dinosaur dig on Victoria's Bass Coast uncovers more than 60 bones and fossils</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/dinosaur-dig-at-inverloch-finds-bones-and-fossils/105904132</link><description>A collection of more than 60 dinosaur bones and fossils are unearthed from rocks at the site of a fossil dig in Victoria's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d67f1ab883871846b55d6387f0f8bd4a</guid></item><item><title>Perth brothers Nezir and Enver Ibrahimovic avoid jail for assault at Scarborough bar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/bouncers-avoid-jail-scarborough-bar-assault/106331266</link><description>Two brothers working as bouncers when they assaulted a man at a Scarborough bar avoid jail after a magistrate recognised the trauma they suffered in the Bosnian war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78455998eac3b4222b694f47d3f06d7a</guid></item><item><title>Former Carlton legend Peter Dean hospitalised after serious assault in Albury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/former-carlton-legend-suffers-serious-assault-in-albury/106331586</link><description>Former AFL player Peter Dean is recovering in hospital after he sustained serious head and facial injuries in an alleged assault at Albury on the New South Wales Victorian border.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4ceb1d2b4738f0666d773a5bf7a2435</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Tropical Cyclone Mitchell brings damage and rain to farmers in WA's south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/strong-winds-wreak-havoc-on-farm-properties-wheatbelt-region/106329960</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says a weather system influenced by ex-Tropical Cyclone Mitchell delivered storms to the Great Southern and central Wheatbelt this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe2f4307942ad8b54d9b5037e79ee1e6</guid></item><item><title>US politician Ro Khanna reveals names of six 'powerful men' scrubbed from Epstein files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/ro-khanna-reveals-names-redacted-from-epstein-files/106331712</link><description>US politician Ro Khanna has publicly named six men whose identities were scrubbed from the Epstein files, including the former boss of Victoria's Secret, who the FBI suspected was a co-conspirator of the sex offender's crimes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5436a5f0bc8f114fceefe16bdeef79e9</guid></item><item><title>Supersized fatberg clogging Sydney sewer blamed for mysterious debris balls on beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/supersized-fatberg-clogging-sydney-sewer-debris-balls/106309658</link><description>The debris balls that have washed up on NSW beaches in recent years are likely to continue as Sydney Water admits a massive fatberg it cannot reach is clogging sewers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e47536114404d9c787ba564b5b869472</guid></item><item><title>Mum of motorcyclist fatally hit by car tells court of 'immeasurable' devastation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/victim-impact-statement-after-motorcyclist-killed-in-crash/106331510</link><description>A grieving mother whose 21-year-old son died after he was struck by a car while riding his motorcycle south of Adelaide tells a court of her devastation and issues a plea to drivers to "check, double check and check again" for bikes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd9c850d55ea31fc30c7fe349201dec0</guid></item><item><title>Ex-student tells court alleged abuse by Matriculation College teacher led to theft and 'warped' relationships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/hobart-matriculation-college-former-student-gives-evidence-rape/106332498</link><description>A woman suing her former teacher has told a court that the alleged abuse impacted her future relationships and "warped" her professional boundaries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa634835bf36571a04b2a810f331b12b</guid></item><item><title>Austin Appelbee's Triple Zero call to save family swept out to sea at Geographe Bay released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/austin-appelbee-triple-zero-call-released/106333174</link><description>Police release the recording of the Triple Zero call made by 13-year-old Austin Appelbee after his marathon 4 kilometre swim through rough seas to save his family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">080bb848fb9e646a03ddfb0802a198e8</guid></item><item><title>Kane Dallow sentenced to two years in prison on fraud and other charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/tasmanian-man-kane-dallow-jailed-for-28-offences/106227598</link><description>A Tasmanian man who impersonated the Launceston Magistrates Court has been convicted on 28 crimes relating to fraud, forgery and perverting justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a46ce2b2cf467d06b9f88e5ba53d770b</guid></item><item><title>Chinese flotilla sailed to edge of Australia's waters, ADF chief reveals at Senate estimates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/chinese-flotilla-edge-australian-exclusive-economic-zone/106333020</link><description>Under questioning in Senate estimates, the chief of the Australian Defence Force reveals that a Chinese flotilla sailed within seven nautical miles of Australia's 200 nautical mile exclusive economic zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54162e69e9611e52a37af7ad332cce70</guid></item><item><title>Surveillance devices captured accused talking about alleged murder of Geoffrey McLean, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/court-hears-evidence-over-alleged-murder-of-geoffrey-mclean/106333170</link><description>An SA Supreme Court trial hears listening devices captured alleged murderer Mark Murphy admitting to his role in killing Geoffrey McLean in 2022. Warning: This story contains details that some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dee7af032cb8fec1ac1248900b766e93</guid></item><item><title>Olympic great impressed by Aussies as James and Guseli reach halfpipe final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/winter-olympics-2026-live-jakara-anthony-scotty-james/106329908</link><description>Australian Scotty James starts his quest for a third Olympic medal, qualifying in first place with a phenomenal run in snowboard halfpipe qualifying at the Milano Cortina Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bde28b9ffb03fa5cbe8c29b66aac219b</guid></item><item><title>Is there going to be a Liberal leadership showdown?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/is-there-going-to-be-a-liberal-leader-showdown-/106333560</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffda194d6e76caf03cdfdc9957c0d5c4</guid></item><item><title>Britney Spears sells rights to music catalogue in reported $281m deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/britney-sells-rights-music-catalogue-primary-wave/106333696</link><description>Spears is the latest music star to sell the rights to their work, a decade after the release of her ninth and last studio album.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46d37ff06c7881b67f6362f876d81145</guid></item><item><title>Jakara Anthony misses medals at 2026 Winter Olympic Games in Milano Cortina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/jakara-anthony-2026-winter-olympics-moguls-final-wilson/106333690</link><description>The Australian spectators in Livigno are stunned as defending champion Jakara Anthony crashes out of contention in the women's moguls final at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a060f999a428f2c8f193deb043d835a1</guid></item><item><title>The identities linked to corruption at the CFMEU, according to Queensland's Commission of Inquiry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/cfmeu-inquiry-report-corruption/106333306</link><description>Members of bikie gangs, convicted murderers and violent criminals are among more than 25 people who allegedly benefited from or are linked to corrupt behaviour at the CFMEU, according to a report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79526cb09b14525015408b39b1c1b5b4</guid></item><item><title>Crack found in new $786m Bridgewater Bridge, RTI documents reveal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/concrete-cracks-in-bridgewater-bridge-rti-documents-reveal/106326476</link><description>Days before the official opening, the Tasmanian government's largest-ever infrastructure project hit a hurdle, with a large crack picked up in one of the Bridgewater Bridge's piers detected and fixed, documents show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dedb596ad7690da3fa77fd190349acb0</guid></item><item><title>Kath &amp; Kim is back on ABC iview. Test your Fountain Lakes fan credentials with our quiz. It's noice, it's different, it's _____</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/kath-and-kim-quiz/106286470</link><description>It's an Aussie classic, but do you know who delivered these iconic lines in Kath &amp; Kim? Put down your cardonnay and footy franks and show us what you've got.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b67dba22afc919812a6491878f676fa7</guid></item><item><title>Australia's toxic legacy at Wilkes Station in Antarctica</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/wilkes-station-in-antarctica-a-toxic-legacy/106281888</link><description>The ABC has been given rare access to an abandoned Australian base in Antarctica that continues to pose a threat to the environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86fbd4ded36d272a381c32bb0d71bd55</guid></item><item><title>Australia Diamonds defeat Jamaica 80-33 in third netball Test to claim 3-0 series win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/australia-diamonds-defeat-jamaica-80-33-in-third-test/106333890</link><description>Coach Stacey Marinkovich believes a refreshed Diamonds squad has found its "identity" ahead of attempting to become the first Australian netball team to defend Commonwealth Games gold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">572f0f2c0fcd545047cd50c575ce4950</guid></item><item><title>Animal abuse charge takes one year as RSPCA prosecutions in Queensland drastically decline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/queensland-rspca-drop-in-prosecutions-animal-cruelty/106277220</link><description>A man has been charged with animal cruelty a year after neighbours first made a complaint to the RSPCA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cd8515cd059d1ed39c4f1b8f6e3e75d</guid></item><item><title>Baker Boy talks new album Djandjay, Riverboats festival and family legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/baker-boy-djandjay-album-riverboats-festival-racism-fresh-prince/106321578</link><description>The Yolŋu artist known as the Fresh Prince of Arnhem Land is the king of feel-good bilingual bangers. But heavy is the crown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a7e4fe54da381b9b3169df148ff7976</guid></item><item><title>Canada school shooter 18-year-old Jesse Van Rootselaar acted alone, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/canadian-shooter-identified-in-school-attack/106333992</link><description>Police identify the person who carried out a school massacre in a remote Canadian community as an 18-year-old woman with mental health issues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3aa7b080fb4f452119e946dd95e8524</guid></item><item><title>Women reveal alleged assaults near Daylesford after solo hiker raises alarm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/women-reveal-alleged-assaults-after-solo-hiker-safety-concerns/106321554</link><description>A woman's solo hike through regional Victoria took a disturbing turn near Daylesford, raising questions about safety and police responses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f26aa974b43557ea835742330da7382</guid></item><item><title>Pam Bondi grilled over Epstein files as survivors express fury over redactions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/pam-bondi-faces-congress-questions-over-epstein-files/106329688</link><description>US Attorney-General Pam Bondi faces furious questions over the censorship of names in the Epstein files at a heated hearing before a committee of Congress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f6370664d2895327e9152794883f228</guid></item><item><title>Darwin traditional owners feel 'bulldozed' by ambitious solar farm company's approach to consultation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/darwin-traditional-owners-bulldozed-solar-farm-legal-case/106325986</link><description>A renewable energy company planning to build a solar farm near Darwin is seeking a court ruling that no native title claim exists at the proposed site.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3568f961affbc4c6c592ec5ca4aea80</guid></item><item><title>How Perth paedophile Jason William Forbes hid in plain sight in suburban Baldivis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/jason-william-forbes-paedophile-hid-in-plain-sight-in-balidivis/106332628</link><description>"A regular sort of bloke" is how one of Jason Forbes's neighbours described the 39-year-old electrician — but behind the walls of his unassuming home in Perth's suburbs, he was hiding a dark secret.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dd2b32c45fd3aa306f9b3c95567d560</guid></item><item><title>Future of Port Hedland's West End uncertain after buyback scheme ends</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/port-hedland-buyback-ends-leaving-uncertain-future/106050394</link><description>As Port Hedland's controversial dust buyback scheme winds up, Pilbara Ports quietly walks away from major plans to build a training facility and accommodation, with development plans for the area still uncertain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3587d18364662f59c0d70ef1c4dbc441</guid></item><item><title>Authorities warn Alice Springs flash flooding threat isn't over, more Central Australian rain predicted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/nt-alice-springs-flooding-wet-weather-emergency-rain/106334186</link><description>Authorities are warning Alice Springs could face further flooding overnight, with forecasts of more wet weather posing a threat to slowly receding water levels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f0111c3d67d09aaf04530f675a2283b</guid></item><item><title>FBI combs desert terrain for clues in Nancy Guthrie's disappearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/fbi-search-for-nancy-guthrie-continues-suspect-released/106334272</link><description>The man detained for questioning in the investigation into the disappearance of a US TV show host's mother has been released and the search continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98abca4b75add9ecbb225412ab313ec8</guid></item><item><title>Greens call for parliamentary inquiry into paedophile former Tasmanian police officer Paul Reynolds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/tasmanian-greens-paul-reynolds-parliamentary-inquiry-call/106332474</link><description>The Greens will push for Tasmania's parliament to scrutinise how police handled child abuse allegations against former officer Paul Reynolds, and why it was decided to give him a full police funeral.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f7f501ebb062cec9e3826f249c2421e</guid></item><item><title>Public DNA databases lead to arrest over historical NSW sexual assault cases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/dna-technology-leads-to-arrest-nsw-sexual-assault-cold-cases/106334110</link><description>A 77-year-old man is arrested in connection with a string of alleged sexual assaults in NSW dating back to the 1990s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">957f7d3970b9923c7d95cd14199fbfad</guid></item><item><title>Albemarle's lithium refinery in WA's South West placed on care and maintenance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/albemarle-kemerton-lithium-refinery-shut-down/106334822</link><description>A multi-billion-dollar lithium refinery in WA's South West has been shut down, affecting about 275 workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5062fb4ce50ee697f9ff892aa55a778c</guid></item><item><title>Scotty James and Valentino Guseli raise their level at 'unbelievable' snowboard halfpipe qualifier at Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/scotty-james-valentino-guseli-snowboard-halfpipe-qualification/106333268</link><description>Scotty James is the man to beat in the snowboard halfpipe at the 2026 Winter Olympics, but a stunning qualifying competition proves that the final is going to be on another level entirely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84595f7c496f7dbad48fe23b81679130</guid></item><item><title>UK police to decide on Andrew Mounbatten-Windsor Epstein trade document investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-police-epstein-files-investigation/106334742</link><description>British police say they are "making progress as quickly as possible" on whether to launch a full investigation into allegations that Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor shared confidential trade documents with late financier and sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70f896e77bb48c2fb240d5bc44cccee3</guid></item><item><title>Three arrested by CFMEU corruption taskforce as premier insists she took appropriate action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/three-arrested-taskforce-hawk-cfmeu-corruption-investigation/106334256</link><description>The arrests were made hours before Premier Jacinta Allan faced reporters over separate allegations detailed in a new report that $15 billion in taxpayer dollars had made its way into the hands of criminals who had infiltrated the union.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc02ad89e79207293943a68d6da5adee</guid></item><item><title>Video shows Guildford shooting victim pleading for help from neighbours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/guilford-shooting-video-shows-victim-plea-for-help/106335532</link><description>Vision shows the moment a bleeding man shot in Sydney's south-west overnight begs for help in a neighbour's back yard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b41f498015908cf46ca9f5559c3f42e2</guid></item><item><title>5,000 cannabis plants seized on rural NSW property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/5-000-cannabis-plants-seized-on-rural-nsw-property/106334568</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51853416fd6d3685a6d065d7635bcf34</guid></item><item><title>Four people charged after alleged discovery of thousands of cannabis plants in NSW Riverina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/alleged-cannabis-plant-seizure-nsw-riverina-property/106334240</link><description>Police allege the four people charged were cultivating a large-scale cannabis farm in the Riverina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc722b2f2ad68bab10683a6dbc9f2acf</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 6</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-matt-graham/106330602</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e7755738441e4486f4c3fbb99fe3561</guid></item><item><title>Reo Te Whetu Marama Marsh pleads guilty to murdering Mary Benedito on Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/marybenedito-murder-former-partner-pleads-guilty-southport/106335664</link><description>The 25-year-old mother was found unresponsive in a Southport apartment in 2021 and later died of her injuries in hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41675660826075c3b3cef1da1d9a7876</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian man Corey Chugg found alive four days after going missing in bushland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/corey-chugg-found-after-being-missing-for-four-days/106336412</link><description>The 32-year-old man went into a bushland with a friend to collect firewood on Sunday. Police say he has been found alive at the bottom of a steep incline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5572cc953ef79133e4c891baf00fb4d7</guid></item><item><title>Electronic monitoring bill strengthening bail laws passes Qld parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/electronic-monitoring-bill-passes-qld-parliament/106335736</link><description>Magistrates will now be able to order children as young as 10 to wear electronic monitoring devices as a bail condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d62157adacf18c5a2ad5fd577c7e2ed0</guid></item><item><title>Camels dying from dehydration descend on APY Lands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/apy-lands-feral-camels-dying-drought-sa/106321572</link><description>Large mobs of camels wreak havoc in remote Indigenous communities as they desperately search for water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c807cb91079deb6ab0c14e1cb642ee2</guid></item><item><title>James Van Der Beek was synonymous with his character. How he embraced it with humour will be his legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/james-van-der-beek-dawsons-creek-character-legacy/106335718</link><description>James Van Der Beek's death prompts wide-ranging tributes from co-stars and friends who have praised his kindness and humour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a76d007b4e1dd749503740e00c13fea9</guid></item><item><title>RBA governor accused by senator of 'gaslighting' Australians on economy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/rba-governor-accused-of-gaslighting-australians-on-economy/106335332</link><description>Reserve Bank governor Michele Bullock fires back at Nationals senator Matt Canavan after he accused her of "gaslighting" Australians over the state of the Australian economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3d3abbc8ab57a6e74180c9d88ef4dae</guid></item><item><title>Man faces Mackay court accused of buying boat for drug smuggling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/man-accused-buying-boat-facilitate-import-illegal-drugs/106336250</link><description>Police allege the owner of a recently set up fishing company purchased a vessel with illicit funds to facilitate the importation of illegal drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a0b73226052d169923a9a7b5bfd9b8e</guid></item><item><title>Support firms for Angus Taylor to win Liberal leadership, though Ley expected to achieve 'good result'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/angus-taylor-liberal-leadership-support-firms/106334120</link><description>Support is firming for Angus Taylor to topple Opposition Leader Sussan Ley, though her supporters still expect her to achieve a "good result".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ec143f5904383374cfda9bd081918e1</guid></item><item><title>Chocolate recipes to share some love with the people in your life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/valentines-day-recipes-love-chocolate/106325802</link><description>Whether you are into Valentine's Day or not, these chocolate recipes are perfect for sharing some love.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4882faeefbbf9e3310ba059823c6008</guid></item><item><title>The often-dry Todd River is flowing rapidly after rain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/todd-river-in-alice-springs-is-flowing-rapidly/106337626</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7382a9fe969d54d1b921651d6d31b0dd</guid></item><item><title>NT coroner hands down findings into death of infamous murderer Martin Leach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/nt-coroner-findings-into-death-of-murderer-rapist-martin-leach/106333540</link><description>An inquest into the 2024 death of double murderer Martin Leach raises questions about whether prisoners have a right to end-of-life care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1343d6662df13df32315e87290cc3466</guid></item><item><title>Liberals' leadership machinations dominate the political week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/liberals-leadership-spill-angus-taylor-sussan-ley/106325872</link><description>The Liberals have spent the week embroiled in leadership woes as the party braces for a spill on Friday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">874320a6b150dbbf66b077e9b0f5d9b5</guid></item><item><title>Ballarat man pleads guilty to taking almost 200 'upskirt' images in public places</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/ballarat-man-derek-grima-pleads-guilty-to-upskirting-offences/106337058</link><description>A court hears a man took "upskirting" images of unwitting women and girls in shopping centres and his workplace, in Melbourne, Geelong and Ballarat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33712309d1614f6803be7f6621987692</guid></item><item><title>New video shows violent arrest of Australian filmmaker James Ricketson at Sydney's anti-Herzog protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/video-shows-arrest-filmmaker-james-ricketson-sydney-protest/106337470</link><description>New video obtained by ABC NEWS Verify shows in vivid detail the arrest of a 76-year-old man, who was later released without charge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e8b85f342914cc4a1db8e8f827b072c</guid></item><item><title>Barbeques Galore enters receivership as debt burns into bottom line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/barbeques-galore-enters-receivership/106337962</link><description>Barbeques Galore has plunged into receivership, leaving question marks for nearly 100 stores that employ about 500 staff.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69523934e505732dbc33d0c34030742d</guid></item><item><title>Cars submerged, trees torn down, roads inundated: Alice Springs flooding in pictures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/nt-alice-springs-flooding-in-pictures-floodwaters-damage/106336102</link><description>Overnight thunderstorms left Central Australian rivers inundated on Thursday, with rapidly rising floodwaters submerging cars, ripping up trees and leaving multiple people stranded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e025807245504400521b8ef8f7040fd1</guid></item><item><title>Teen bounces back from nasty crash to snatch gold from American great</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/winter-olympics-2026-live-milano-cortina-matt-graham/106338490</link><description>Two-time Winter Olympic champion Chloe Kim is pipped for first place by 17-year-old Gaon Choi late in the women's snowboard halfpipe final at the Milano Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24d8b89831532879a46a1f89cff67b37</guid></item><item><title>Father finds family's bones in rubble of Gaza house destroyed in air strikes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/gaza-father-searches-for-family-bones-in-house-rubble/106335798</link><description>Mahmoud Hammad believes he has found his family's remains in the rubble of his house, which was destroyed more than two years ago in air strikes, killing his pregnant wife and their five children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c72e878a5950523e5fef0914825cd59a</guid></item><item><title>Man charged over alleged sexual assault of girl on Adelaide bus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/man-charged-after-allegedly-sexually-assaulting-girl-on-bus/106338508</link><description>A 33-year-old man is expected to face an Adelaide court on Friday, after a teenage girl was allegedly sexually assaulted on a public bus earlier this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5e0089a8bf7fb0272825e6ee0e3c89c</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor to challenge for Liberal leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/angus-taylor-to-challenge-for-liberal-leadership/106337940</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">868bbbd6de942f7fd80a9a7d018a148b</guid></item><item><title>IOC disqualifies Ukrainian skeleton racer Vladyslav Heraskevych over helmet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/olympics-ukrainian-vladyslav-heraskevych-disqualified-helmet/106338586</link><description>Vladyslav Heraskevych is disqualified over his customised helmet featuring the faces of Ukrainian athletes and coaches killed in the Russia-Ukraine war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fccc878b54f516f48ad6edf96316efba</guid></item><item><title>Muslim men had permission to pray before officers removed them from Sydney protest, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/muslim-men-had-permission-to-pray-at-sydney-protest/106338734</link><description>A group of Muslim men had already received police permission to worship during a Sydney protest before they were disrupted mid-prayer by officers, NSW Police Force confirms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96634ee0fdc26c6f60ce7edf1fb81c08</guid></item><item><title>Cooper Woods welcomed to the Winter Olympic 'gold medal club' by Alisa Camplin-Warner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/cooper-woods-gold-medal-club-alisa-camplin/106338996</link><description>Only seven Australian athletes have ever felt the weight of a Winter Olympic gold medal being hung around their necks. And one of the first, Alisa Camplin-Warner, was thrilled to welcome the most recent, Cooper Woods, to the club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00bcbc79601b776b4d7b20f266d65169</guid></item><item><title>What living in a multigenerational home with one of your parents is really like</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/multigenerational-home-grand-designs-transformations-reality/106331396</link><description>Kay and her daughter, Cat, moved back in together a year ago — along with Cat's husband and their three kids. This is the reality of what it's like living with three generations under one roof.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3af29ad48f8e5edb33eee4096469d8b3</guid></item><item><title>Liberal Party poised to dump first female federal leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/liberal-party-poised-to-dump-first-female-leader/106338452</link><description>The Liberal Party is poised to dump its first federal female leader, with Sussan Ley's supporters acknowledging her rival, Angus Taylor, is in the "ascendancy".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6149b17b767527046bc7170e8b43226a</guid></item><item><title>3,100 aged care patients stranded in hospitals as states again press Commonwealth for action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/aged-care-hospital-funding-bed-block/106336820</link><description>With the ink still wet on a new hospital deal, state and territory health ministers will today use a meeting with their federal counterpart to call for urgent action on stranded patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db2af93a0e38f039ffeb1e1ccf5f3042</guid></item><item><title>Men face drug cultivation charges after $10 million cannabis bust in Victoria's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/men-face-commercial-drug-cultivation-charges-after-cannabis-bust/106338128</link><description>Police allege a drug bust in Victoria's north-west has uncovered 10 large grow houses cultivating $10 million worth of illegal cannabis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7d9fee7539b4a4ea68bd8031cfeac2b</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: A leadership spill, a ghost barge and mysterious balls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/weekly-news-quiz-february-13/106336680</link><description>Have you been paying attention to the headlines this week? Test yourself here.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8661fd8f3afb21c5f2bd8d2ebafdb227</guid></item><item><title>Cooper Woods, Australia's unexpected Winter Olympic champion, finds his purpose</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/cooper-woods-australias-unexpected-champion-winter-olympics/106339106</link><description>Cooper Woods came into the 2026 Winter Olympic Games ranked 22nd in the World Cup rankings in moguls. But in finding his purpose, he roared to a glorious gold medal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ca54a379cdb065db55986946103d8e3</guid></item><item><title>How the Liberals' first female leader found herself here</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/sussan-ley-liberals-leadership-spill/106325896</link><description>Sussan Ley has had much less than a year to try to prove herself. So how did the Liberals' first female leader find herself on the canvas so quickly and dramatically?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a78c7472c31dc86785a72568b3e7375</guid></item><item><title>ASX boss to depart as another controversy unfolds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/asx-boss-to-depart-as-another-controversy-unfolds/106336322</link><description>A decade of technology failures, unplanned outages, management upheaval, irate investors and the torching of hundreds of millions of dollars has left the ASX's reputation in shreds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d1cb6399c00e87f8a119dacdf9976aa</guid></item><item><title>Epstein victims stand up during House Judiciary Committee hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/epstein-victims-stand-up-during-house-judiciary-committee/106336132</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9715195d155fadad84500e2798d0720</guid></item><item><title>Epstein survivor says release of files was 're-traumatising' and falls short of transparency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/epstein-survivor-says-release-of-files-retraumatising/106317616</link><description>Lisa Phillips says the publication of the "Epstein" files was meant to deliver long-promised transparency but has instead exposed victims, deepened trauma and continued to shield powerful men.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">702d35e388b86c7214a684bca057a62f</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor is the new leader of the Liberal Party. Who is he?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/who-is-liberal-party-leader-hopeful-angus-taylor/105268090</link><description>After months of speculation, Liberals hope Angus Taylor can bring the Liberals back from what many in the party fear is the edge of obscurity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da8415b8432271ddc8217b42ad3a877c</guid></item><item><title>Economist Bruce Preston appointed to RBA Board</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/economist-bruce-preston-appointed-to-rba-board/106337708</link><description>The economics professor is the second academic economist added to the board since a review recommended boosting its expertise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c0edb3495c53e1eb1dd6f353acd5bef</guid></item><item><title>More than 100 Stolen Generations survivors gather for apology anniversary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/largest-gathering-of-stolen-generations-survivors-for-apology/106322950</link><description>More than 100 Stolen Generations survivors have gathered in Canberra for the apology anniversary. The government is pledging new money to help them heal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c81bef72da28cb61fb66cddb9bf13666</guid></item><item><title>Marine biologists fight to save endangered seagrass species in Sydney Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/science-key-to-saving-endangered-seagrass-population/106337120</link><description>A centuries-old nautical technique is being redesigned within a small Sydney cove in a bid to save a tiny remnant population of a dying species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c23125b58cdf591c3340528784e5fcd</guid></item><item><title>Intense rainfall risk for south-east Queensland as weather system drenches Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/intense-rainfall-south-east-qld-wet-condtions-queensland/106331410</link><description>South-east Queensland is being told to brace for an intense soaking from today with up to 150 millimetres to fall in some coastal areas and rainfall all weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">554feef4458ed64818b6a117e26a1463</guid></item><item><title>The 'farm-fluencers' taking agriculture online to bridge the rural divide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/farmer-influencers-sharing-rural-lives-online-content-creators/106326048</link><description>Farmers and agricultural workers are taking to social media to educate a new audience while building a community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed4626a80b6a8b07114590acfaf1a595</guid></item><item><title>Queensland police given greater powers to pursue animal abusers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/queensland-police-given-greater-powers-to-pursue-animal-abusers/106338042</link><description>Queensland police will be able to pursue animal abusers without seeking permission from a government department after regulation change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f16d1b253b7407790bb6843d7ac0cd0f</guid></item><item><title>Cost-of-living crisis sees more young women neglecting health and basic needs, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/young-women-cost-of-living-crisis-basic-needs/106300314</link><description>A study from Deakin University has found many young women admit skipping meals or forgoing medical attention to save money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5cd45054bcabb5c8fa618e72defa4a5</guid></item><item><title>Openly gay men in elite sport are rare, leaving women to lead the way for queer inclusion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/queer-lgbtiqa-inclusion-womens-sport-anneli-maley-wnbl-pride-cup/106149906</link><description>While high profile instances of homophobia in elite men's sport continue, leading female athletes are hoping to help create more inclusive spaces for all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70321d6613ab8607cbaea120ca706e88</guid></item><item><title>Four charged after $10 million cannabis crop busted in Victoria's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/four-charged-after-10-million-cannabis-crop-busted-/106339512</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b696f2667e1fc6727a09310d1c0869ee</guid></item><item><title>Live: Sussan Ley to quit politics after losing spill, setting up by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/federal-politics-live-blog-liberal-spill/106339480</link><description>Sussan Ley announces she will quit the parliament after losing her leadership to Angus Taylor, setting up a by-election in her seat. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e54c956be73e4b8996ca621b91910220</guid></item><item><title>Kim Jong Un set to pick daughter Kim Ju Ae to lead North Korea, South Korean intelligence says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/kim-jong-un-to-pick-kim-ju-ae-as-next-leader-south-korea-says/106339110</link><description>South Korea's spy agency says that Kim Jong Un is set to choose his daughter as his heir, extending his family's rule into a fourth generation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37569486a4575609470e58b928b30b7e</guid></item><item><title>Max Verstappen critical of new Formula 1 cars as preseason testing continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/max-verstappen-critical-of-new-formula-1-cars/106339508</link><description>Four-time Formula 1 world champion Max Verstappen says the 2026 cars are "not so fun", claiming the increasing energy management demands on drivers are "just not Formula 1".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">950bfbf36871e9c9d62401075e1fd446</guid></item><item><title>NT Australian of the Year Felix Ho volunteers thousands of hours to the community each year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/nt-australian-of-year-dr-felix-ho-thousands-of-volunteer-hours/106329556</link><description>Finding time to volunteer can be a stretch for most people, but for Darwin doctor Felix Ho, who volunteers thousands of hours every year, it's his "full-time hobby".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b99c4561a769bc93eea33549024a298</guid></item><item><title>Thai raid finds Cambodian scam centre had personal details of 300 Australians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/australians-targeted-by-cambodian-scam-compound/106335866</link><description>Australia's National Anti-Scam Centre says documents seized in a raid on a Cambodian scam compound contained the phone numbers, names and addresses of 300 Australians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08f7a75e42a1578ec6ae98632dc8210b</guid></item><item><title>From new life to grief, Ella Macens's music for the Melbourne Symphony Orchestra is rooted in love</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/music-by-australian-ella-macens-premiered-by-melbourne-symphony/106323262</link><description>After experiencing the Bondi terror attack in December, this composer's new music grew to encompass love's power to heal us from hate and harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bbfdad77654f3b7445bd689a1085326</guid></item><item><title>The key factor that will define your NRL team's chances in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/2026-nrl-season-preview-key-stats/106334724</link><description>With the preseason challenge well underway and the season-opening matches in Las Vegas on the horizon, find out the key numbers that will make or break your team's NRL chances for 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdbd63c61f95bb7099a8f344adfd200e</guid></item><item><title>Raymond Reddington blamed wife Sharon Fulton's disappearance on serial killers David and Catherine Birnie, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/raymond-reddington-blamed-serial-killer-birnies-for-missing-wife/106336720</link><description>Notorious Perth serial killers David and Catherine Birnie could not be ruled out as suspects in the alleged murder of a woman who vanished the same year they killed four young women, the detective who arrested them says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2bbe9165743f94c76dde41edb99743d</guid></item><item><title>Trump repeals power to fight climate change, axes vehicle emissions rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/trump-revokes-basis-of-us-climate-regulation-ends-vehicle-emissi/106339598</link><description>President Donald Trump's administration has revoked a scientific determination that has been the central basis for US action to fight climate change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14587c3b8bd37c5943c0d33c136fd2f9</guid></item><item><title>Keen to declutter this year? Here’s how to start</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/simple-ways-to-start-decluttering-at-home/106300708</link><description>Experts say you don’t need to pull out the entire contents of a cupboard, beginning with one bag is best.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a8e041b72c037976f8eb5cb64a4f2a3</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Breezy Johnson gets engaged at the Games, Snoop Dogg shows plenty of support — quick hits from day six</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/sport-winter-olympics-quick-hits-day-six/106339098</link><description>Breezy Johnson's pain of crashing was washed away by the euphoria of love, while Snoop Dogg showed his support with a magnificent snow jacket. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59bf59903ae0317ba477a60054f1e33f</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor becomes Liberal leader after defeating Sussan Ley 34–17</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/angus-taylor-becomes-liberal-leader/106339798</link><description>Sussan Ley, the first female leader of the Liberal Party, is set to quit politics after losing a leadership vote today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fa7d372d6cff076b3d6fe902ba524d0</guid></item><item><title>Former Tottenham manager Ange Postecoglou says Spurs 'not a big club' in wake of Thomas Frank sacking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/former-tottenham-manager-ange-postecoglou-on-club-issues/106339490</link><description>Tottenham Hotspur are "not a big club" because of their policy in the transfer market, former manager Ange Postecoglou has said in the wake of the London club's sacking of head coach Thomas Frank on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ce56a4955c12cf141f86e6540834b3a</guid></item><item><title>Future uncertain for 150-year-old mansion on SA's Limestone Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/struan-house-future-uncertain-amid-research-centre-rebuild/106323358</link><description>Since a government department moved out, the historic Struan House has sat empty, with no set plans for its future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6c247ec0e3848af955a61e405c1cfba</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 medal tally: Cooper Woods puts Australia ahead of Canada and China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-medal-tally/106339814</link><description>Cooper Woods's moguls gold puts Australia ahead of powerhouses Canada and China on the official Winter Olympics medal tally, despite having fewer medals overall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7c36716af86ea21ffeeaac5f7b3ef61</guid></item><item><title>Norway's former PM, Thorbjoern Jagland, accused of aggravated corruption over Epstein links</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/norway-former-prime-minister-ties-with-jeffrey-epstein/106339852</link><description>The files indicate that Thorbjoern Jagland and Jeffrey Epstein's assistants made detailed plans in 2014 for the politician to visit the American in Palm Beach, Florida.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3b70dba55d4ba770182042e51ba2176</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Australian snowboard cross riders struggle after Cam Bolton's injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/winter-olympics-snowboard-cross-emotional-toll-cam-bolton/106338726</link><description>Cam Bolton's broken neck hangs heavily over the Australian snowboard cross team, with his late replacement Jimmy Johnstone vowing his appearance was "all for him".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">108a118275afba78a9d56fcdc5b77bdd</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs woman survives 12-hour flood ordeal on Todd River</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/alice-springs-todd-river-flood-rescue/106338710</link><description>When her mum was swept into the flooding Todd River this week, Alice Springs woman Latarne Wayne went in after her.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a0d92e3f4e0d139f91767b2f3eb420c</guid></item><item><title>Law Enforcement Conduct Commission announces investigation into police actions during Sydney protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/lecc-investigates-town-hall-protest-response/106340598</link><description>The Law Enforcement Conduct Commission on Friday said it would investigate the police response to the demonstration at Town Hall on Monday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19f86deb588b5858f9b56b0f2e73a2bb</guid></item><item><title>It took 80 years for a woman to become Liberal leader, and 9 months to ditch her</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/sussan-ley-s-time-as-liberal-leader/106045934</link><description>Sussan Ley vowed to be a different opposition leader, one who consulted widely and listened to her broad church. But it left many wondering what, if anything, she stood for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05d0ee7f0ef658ce063e5a98c8024ae7</guid></item><item><title>Alexander Repin sentenced over murder of Rex Upton in Lismore in 2023</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/alexander-repin-sentence-for-murder-of-rex-upton-in-lismore/106333078</link><description>Alexander Repin had been out of jail for four days when he consumed alcohol and drugs, then murdered an 89-year-old man in Lismore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ceb2ecf386262e6e04d6055c5dac1ba4</guid></item><item><title>FBI raises reward to $US100,000 in suspected abduction of Savannah Guthrie's mother</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/fbi-raises-reward-releases-new-images-for-nancy-guthrie/106340336</link><description>The FBI increases its reward and releases new images as part of its investigation into the suspected abduction of US television host Savannah Guthrie's mother, Nancy, from her southern Arizona home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5acb6c395de1e1de01a4284c80b5a013</guid></item><item><title>Ley leaves Taylor an immediate electoral test with Farrer by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/farrer-byelection-sussan-ley-angus-taylor/106341236</link><description>Within two hours of being elected Liberal leader, Angus Taylor has already been delivered his first big electoral test, and it has come from the woman he deposed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a9957d8828440921d19f5f6180a2356</guid></item><item><title>Adolescence writer Jack Thorne on his new TV adaptation of castaway novel Lord of the Flies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/lord-of-the-flies-tv-show-jack-thorne-adolescence/106295874</link><description>After winning an Emmy for writing Adolescence, Jack Thorne's latest project, a TV adaptation of Lord of the Flies, also sits at the intersection of vulnerability, masculinity and violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd85640874e64ee279c21abb06ec290e</guid></item><item><title>Katie Holmes pays tribute to Dawson's Creek co-star James Van Der Beek in handwritten letter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/katie-holmes-pays-tribute-to-james-van-der-beek/106340686</link><description>In a handwritten letter posted to social media, actor Katie Holmes has paid tribute to her Dawson's Creek co-star James Van Der Beek, who has died. He was 48.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a28511573104b49c927e99586c21dea6</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 7</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-scotty-james/106334738</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e106df780eab1c0c626be93f3649ca6</guid></item><item><title>AFL Origin 2026: Are footy fans still keen on interstate football?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/afl-origin-2026-history-of-interstate-football-state-of-origin/106341464</link><description>After a break of more than a quarter of a century, a battle between two proud football states is returning in Perth for the AFL Origin 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ac0aaab0d5f3f7f1e75b164d08b3c0e</guid></item><item><title>What to know about the Year of the Horse and Lunar New Year celebrations in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/how-lunar-new-year-of-the-horse-is-celebrated-in-australia/106295942</link><description>The Year of the Horse is here and 2026 is a rare "Red Horse" year. Find out what it means, which zodiac animal you are, and how Lunar New Year is celebrated across Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3a175856e4652c5d58d63f6eaaa7e9b</guid></item><item><title>Christopher Mark Jordan, accused of murdering Shyanne-Lee Tatnell, expected to stand trial in September</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/christopher-mark-jordan-shyanne-lee-tatnell-murder-trial/106341902</link><description>A man who has pleaded not guilty to murdering a 14-year-old girl could stand trial as early as September, the Supreme Court in Launceston has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c23cd702f5245c6f78b30b18f7dcff6e</guid></item></channel></rss>