<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 08:09:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Extreme heat returning for south-east Queensland before weekend showers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/queensland-weather-heat-showers/106319132</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology is forecasting "locally severe heatwave conditions" from Tuesday, culminating in a maximum of 35 degrees in Brisbane on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b30ddf4d4ab44e838d7d574f7e1be3ec</guid></item><item><title>Deua River Valley and Cobargo still rebuilding six years after Black Summer bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/cobargo-deua-river-still-rebuilding-after-black-summer-bushfires/106273804</link><description>Residents who lived through the 2019-20 bushfires on the NSW South Coast say this summer's fires triggered traumatic memories, and highlighted the recovery and resilience projects that remain unfinished.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75a6395d574e8ce915a53455bd5abe17</guid></item><item><title>The aftermath of the 2019 Cobargo bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/the-aftermath-of-the-2019-cobargo-bushfire/106294344</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22e913e7b6f7929c3a7fe100eb5b6339</guid></item><item><title>Court appoints statutory trustee to sell rundown Rockhampton Plaza Hotel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/federal-court-orders-sale-of-rockhampton-plaza-hotel/106308402</link><description>After years of complaints from local authorities, a judge has ordered the sale of the property which sits surrounded by temporary fencing, with smashed windows and timber boards nailed across its seven-storey façade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99c69af1176e9dd66374681c276f4de9</guid></item><item><title>Kimberley cotton hits record high in first season with new processing gin in Kununurra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/kimberley-growers-wrap-up-first-season-processing-cotton-locally/106303718</link><description>From farm to fabric, West Australian cotton growers are finally able to grow, process and export record amounts of cotton locally.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">463c2f3636108857669737fceede0d6c</guid></item><item><title>'Punitive' bail law amendments have increased and First Nations people are affected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/bail-law-amendments-resulting-in-more-first-nation-remands/106315210</link><description>A study has found increasing "punitive" bail law amendments are negatively affecting First Nations people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bebd2244ed8d3de1cb17c7226d169513</guid></item><item><title>Backyard pods won't fix the housing crisis but they signal a shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/backyard-pods-wont-fix-the-housing-crisis/106314472</link><description>Australia's biggest hardware retailer has started selling tiny homes. Are backyard pods the answer to a national housing crisis?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dd2b8a3992ec554b10d8b236bba7c64</guid></item><item><title>William and Kate 'deeply concerned' about Epstein files as Andrew faces fresh scrutiny</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/prince-william-kate-epstein-deeply-concerned-statement/106323984</link><description>The Prince and Princess of Wales say their thoughts remain focused on the victims of the late sex offender Jeffrey Epstein, in their first statement on the issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d612c2a641317f685b27655f77ed980a</guid></item><item><title>Queensland health minister orders review of Toowoomba Hospital maternity unit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/toowoomba-hospital-maternity-unit-audit/106323798</link><description>Announcement comes after a woman reveals her support person was prevented from entering the birth suite while she was in labour by Toowoomba Hospital security.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99b063ed21a492a5f313bd8e1046e624</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Tropical Cyclone Mitchell expected to batter the Gascoyne region as it moves inland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/tropical-cyclone-mitchell-has-crossed-the-wa-north-west-coast/106322566</link><description>The system is expected to bring strong winds and heavy rain as it moves inland through the Gascoyne region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16fcc5ddef3af39a7f8a479648d4aaa0</guid></item><item><title>Roblox on notice after 'disturbing' reports of child grooming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/government-puts-roblox-on-notice-reports-of-child-grooming/100020788</link><description>The government puts popular social gaming site Roblox on notice following media reports of children being approached and groomed by predators on the platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17bbfe956fe95675bddb65bf1b70eaed</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan reverses cricket T20 World Cup boycott and will face India in Sri Lanka</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/pakistan-reverses-world-cup-boycott-to-face-india-t20-world-cup/106324864</link><description>Pakistan has ‍agreed to play India ​in the ⁠T20 World Cup match scheduled to take ‌place in Colombo this ‍Sunday, February 15.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d7762f897f18cee09e2bbfe5253973e</guid></item><item><title>Former ATSIC head Geoff Clark was jailed but his community says legal issues persist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/framlingham-aboriginal-trust-shares-court-fallout-geoff-clark/106305592</link><description>Former ATSIC leader Geoff Clark was jailed in 2024, yet some members of his community say legal issues linger on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec0abba8310f5f8dfa22011b1c737b70</guid></item><item><title>Native title holders take appeal over one of Australia's largest groundwater licences to High Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nt-high-court-singleton-station-aboriginal-groundwater-rights/106322626</link><description>The cultural value of water will be front and centre in the High Court in Canberra today as a group of native title holders from Central Australia fight to assert cultural rights over an aquifer under their lands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d334f651d8d34fed9db2b05f2f04adba</guid></item><item><title>McLaren unveils livery for MCL40 ahead of 2026 F1 season, Piastri and Norris excited about new challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/mclaren-unveil-livery-for-mcl40-ahead-of-2026-f1-season/106324952</link><description>McLaren has unveiled its livery for the 2026 Formula 1 championship season, retaining the design that helped it win championships in the previous two seasons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c712cf8881dedcdae7919ab9fe84ee12</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach terrorist Sajid Akram voiced support for Islamic State in 2019, former ASIO agent says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/sajid-akram-voiced-support-for-islamic-state-in-2019-ex-spy-says/106321482</link><description>Bondi Beach terrorist Sajid Akram voiced support for the Islamic State group (IS) in 2019 and expressed admiration for a leading Al Qaeda propagandist, according to accounts from two men who moved in the same extremist circles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20f66d766145bf26694aec7669da86aa</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth asks to meet Roblox following reports of child grooming. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/commonwealth-roblox-reports-of-child-grooming/106323242</link><description>Roblox has been called to an urgent meeting with the federal government in the wake of reports that children are being groomed by predators and exposed to sexually explicit material on the popular online gaming platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8186dce135dbe17f29c38ae0b2e5a4fb</guid></item><item><title>Huon Aquaculture confirms antibiotic use in salmon hatchery on River Derwent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/huon-aquaculture-confirms-antibiotic-use-river-derwent-hatchery/106326652</link><description>There are calls for the public to be made aware of antibiotic use in Tasmania's freshwater hatcheries after Huon Aquaculture recently used oxytetracycline to treat diseased salmon without informing downstream users.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d273d5a7b3627b72a6e5120520d92c4a</guid></item><item><title>Protesters were punched, pushed, and arrested but were NSW Police actions excessive?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/verify-police-use-of-force-town-hall-protest/106328358</link><description>What is reasonable? It's a question being asked by some after footage of clashes in Sydney's CBD, during a rally against Israeli President Isaac Herzog's visit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc032833c827cf116d697c6b10faca22</guid></item><item><title>Food ministers move closer to mandating Health Star Ratings on packaged food</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/move-to-mandate-health-star-ratings-on-food-and-drink/106231700</link><description>The nation's food ministers will this week take a crucial step towards mandating the Health Star Rating scheme on packaged food products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d49aa89b821cfcbaa27037bef0288134</guid></item><item><title>How to reduce loneliness while working remotely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/how-to-reduce-loneliness-while-working-remotely/106286338</link><description>Working remotely can be a lonely experience. Here's what you can do about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07ee38b05fb1af72edee6be374ac35ed</guid></item><item><title>Cricket umpire numbers rise since COVID, but regions still in 'dire' need</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/victorian-cricket-umpires-referee-shortage/106313892</link><description>Cricket umpire numbers increase significantly in Victoria, but some regions remain in desperate need.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c25e208a1280b6ca42f95914eb0b617</guid></item><item><title>Limestone Coast hospital's staff shortage in spotlight after former administrator's fall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/limestone-coast-hospital-staff-shortage/106318896</link><description>David Walshaw spent 20 years looking after the Limestone Coast's hospitals, but a fall made him realise the system was failing patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63b01408b05a077885b47352dd28bbdc</guid></item><item><title>Surgeon Kelvin Kong's life growing up Chinese and Indigenous in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/kelvin-kong-s-growing-up-chinese-and-indigenous-australia/106326388</link><description>Australia's first identified First Nations surgeon, Dr Kelvin Kong spoke about his Malaysian Chinese heritage during the annual Wang Gungwu lecture at Parliament House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3366e9b48200b228bb48ce12f315720</guid></item><item><title>Volunteers say neglect by state's wildlife department caused bushfires on WA's south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/fitzgerald-river-bushfire-dbca-mismanagement/106321810</link><description>Farmers and volunteer firefighters say decades of neglect by WA's Department of Biodiversity, Conservation and Attractions is at the heart of fires that ripped through more than 200,000 hectares of state-managed land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40f45582a4045e521119758ac54edc75</guid></item><item><title>Hand-built high country bridges lost to fires, taking decades of history with them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/historical-high-country-rail-trail-bridges-destroyed-by-fire/106312604</link><description>Volunteers are weighing the future of the High Country Rail Trail after the loss of 12 historic trestle bridges — and decades of work — to bushfires.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84b358786d6ad808955ee6269134044f</guid></item><item><title>Race against bulldozers to save ancient grass trees in WA's South West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/race-to-save-grass-trees-south-west-wa/106323778</link><description>Some of WA's oldest grass trees are being rescued from land clearing and development amid a population and property boom, preserving a unique part of the South West's natural heritage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c035d16240b39fbe758a3a7788f5176</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos striker Mo Toure scores hat-trick on starting debut in English Championship for Norwich</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/socceroos-striker-mohamed-toure-hat-trick-debut-norwich/106330220</link><description>Mohamed Toure moved to England recently on a $5 million deal and it is already looking like a great decision for the 21-year-old forward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ecfd2aa16103898748a1ab83e8c75e7</guid></item><item><title>Formula 1 2026: New engines and no DRS headline major changes in grand prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/formula-1-2026-new-engines-regulations-sprint-races/106325942</link><description>New engines, new regulations and an 11-team grid are just some of the changes in Formula 1 this season. Get up to speed with what is new in F1 ahead of the Australian Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fce942eea4fa4616a149450aa1c7158</guid></item><item><title>Doongmabulla Springs decision leaves Qld government to weigh appeal or face trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/doongmabulla-springs-qld-government-appeal-or-face-trial/106305714</link><description>Wangan and Jagalingou peoples await the state government's next move after a win in their fight to have alleged damage to a sacred site near a mine in Central Queensland investigated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">409498e1a5333e429fc6fc92646dec77</guid></item><item><title>New video sheds light on beginning of altercation between police officers and Town Hall protester</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/-white-shirt-man-town-hall-protests-punched-new-video/106332094</link><description>A new video filmed by a bystander and shared with ABC NEWS Verify shows the full minute before two police officers began punching a protester, shedding light on the beginning of the altercation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4fecc044fc46d6003450c9200ac8eba</guid></item><item><title>Bondi: Path to Terror</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/bondi-path-to-terror-four-corners/106332752</link><description>Four Corners is the home of Australian investigative journalism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3e3ec0c11f67bf60a856adfabe308d3</guid></item><item><title>Australian fans miss out on World Cup tickets as prices skyrocket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/world-cup-ticket-prices-aussie-fans-miss-out/106332736</link><description>A host of Australian fans will be denied the chance to watch the Socceroos World Cup campaign amid accusations of price gouging by FIFA as tickets to the tournament soar to astronomical prices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cb80105f0eeb0984e8c6d7afad7d449</guid></item><item><title>Australia cruises to victory over Ireland in T20 World Cup opener</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/cricket-t20-world-cup-australia-ireland-blog-scores-stats/106330266</link><description>Australia beats Ireland by 67 runs to win its first game at the T20 World Cup, after captain Mitch Marsh was a late out due to testicular bleeding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f10653e8e126254d5fa9b92b8b0d7bf</guid></item><item><title>Channel Nine says Warren Tredrea has now paid costs over long-running legal battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/channel-nine-says-warren-tredrea-has-paid-legal-costs/106333410</link><description>Channel Nine has confirmed it has received legal costs from former AFL player and sports presenter Warren Tredrea, who was ordered to pay $149,000 to his ex-employer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f2d55f17d07ae474e5568f1f5fecbde</guid></item><item><title>Australia Diamonds defeat Jamaica 80-33 in third netball Test to claim 3-0 series win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/australia-diamonds-defeat-jamaica-80-33-in-third-test/106333890</link><description>Coach Stacey Marinkovich believes a refreshed Diamonds squad has found its "identity" ahead of attempting to become the first Australian netball team to defend Commonwealth Games gold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">572f0f2c0fcd545047cd50c575ce4950</guid></item><item><title>Shoalhaven Council loses control over leadership appointments after Andrew Constance hire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/andrew-constance-shoalhaven-council-preformance-improvement/106329850</link><description>The NSW government is set to take control of senior leadership recruitment at Shoalhaven City Council, amid probity concerns regarding the hiring of former Liberal minister Andrew Constance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bdaa91ffe7f73c9cc7024178f88a0bc</guid></item><item><title>Lando Norris quickest on day one of F1 preseason test, Oscar Piastri drives well and Max Verstappen impresses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/f1-preseason-test-bahrain-norris-piastri-verstappen/106333906</link><description>McLaren's Formula 1 world champion Lando Norris was fastest on the first day of preseason testing in Bahrain, but Max Verstappen and Red Bull caught the attention with pace and plenty of laps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba0e6f82ba0e8d4236049cdf992c4cb9</guid></item><item><title>Baker Boy talks new album Djandjay, Riverboats festival and family legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/baker-boy-djandjay-album-riverboats-festival-racism-fresh-prince/106321578</link><description>The Yolŋu artist known as the Fresh Prince of Arnhem Land is the king of feel-good bilingual bangers. But heavy is the crown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a7e4fe54da381b9b3169df148ff7976</guid></item><item><title>Darwin traditional owners feel 'bulldozed' by ambitious solar farm company's approach to consultation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/darwin-traditional-owners-bulldozed-solar-farm-legal-case/106325986</link><description>A renewable energy company planning to build a solar farm near Darwin is seeking a court ruling that no native title claim exists at the proposed site.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3568f961affbc4c6c592ec5ca4aea80</guid></item><item><title>Queenslanders fight to keep public pools as facilities age</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/queenslanders-fight-to-keep-public-pools-open/106327368</link><description>A Queensland mum transforms her backyard to make sure children do not miss out on learning to swim, as hundreds of public pools nationwide reach the end of their lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a516a9cd54434684c204e53cbcc4f74</guid></item><item><title>Declining birth rates in southern right whales alarm researchers in new study</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/climate-change-driving-down-southern-right-whale-calving-numbers/106332214</link><description>New research on the birth rates of southern right whales – once touted as a global conservation success story – has revealed an alarming decline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5d80284251a8c0cd3713b5fe505730a</guid></item><item><title>UK police to decide on Andrew Mounbatten-Windsor Epstein trade document investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-police-epstein-files-investigation/106334742</link><description>British police say they are "making progress as quickly as possible" on whether to launch a full investigation into allegations that Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor shared confidential trade documents with late financier and sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70f896e77bb48c2fb240d5bc44cccee3</guid></item><item><title>Chocolate recipes to share some love with the people in your life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/valentines-day-recipes-love-chocolate/106325802</link><description>Whether you are into Valentine's Day or not, these chocolate recipes are perfect for sharing some love.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4882faeefbbf9e3310ba059823c6008</guid></item><item><title>New video shows violent arrest of Australian filmmaker James Ricketson at Sydney's anti-Herzog protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/video-shows-arrest-filmmaker-james-ricketson-sydney-protest/106337470</link><description>New video obtained by ABC NEWS Verify shows in vivid detail the arrest of a 76-year-old man, who was later released without charge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e8b85f342914cc4a1db8e8f827b072c</guid></item><item><title>Toowoomba Hospital maternity unit to implement recommendations for workplace culture overhaul</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/toowoomba-hospital-maternity-unit-workplace-culture-findings/106338238</link><description>Staff at the Toowoomba Hospital maternity unit will be implementing recommended changes to their workplace culture following an independent review.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fffb7e8031442fc89790d85b110ac64c</guid></item><item><title>Children prescribed puberty blockers without proper assessment at Cairns health service, review finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/qld-puberty-blockers-cairns-health-service/106336756</link><description>The review of the Cairns paediatric gender health service found that children as young as 12 were given puberty blockers inconsistently and without formal consent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">239aa031616658a4122734a07b49c2df</guid></item><item><title>Nightcliff by-election set for March 7, Greens and Labor announce candidates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/nt-nightcliff-byelection-candidates-greens-labor-kat-mcnamara/106335938</link><description>The Greens and Labor have announced their candidates for the Nightcliff by-election, set for March 7, after the resignation of Greens MLA Kat McNamara earlier this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bb26b69187d156e3509e605e9c38389</guid></item><item><title>Italy wins first T20 Cricket World Cup match as Australian-born players shine in 10-wicket win over Nepal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/italy-wins-first-t20-cricket-world-cup-match/106339406</link><description>Sydney-born brothers Justin and Anthony Mosca have guided T20 World Cup debutants Italy to their first win in the tournament, as their unbeaten half-centuries secured a dominant 10-wicket victory over Nepal on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3c6d0fe17105b65b0990f4c481c3845</guid></item><item><title>Max Verstappen critical of new Formula 1 cars as preseason testing continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/max-verstappen-critical-of-new-formula-1-cars/106339508</link><description>Four-time Formula 1 world champion Max Verstappen says the 2026 cars are "not so fun", claiming the increasing energy management demands on drivers are "just not Formula 1".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">950bfbf36871e9c9d62401075e1fd446</guid></item><item><title>Why do some regional councils charge for car parking in country towns, while others don't?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/paid-parking-council-in-victoria-parking-meters-fines-cost/106314960</link><description>Parking meters have been ripped out in some country towns, while in others, motorists are still being slugged, and retailers are feeling the pinch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bee258382b42dba9b9634ad0cdab2b36</guid></item><item><title>Keen to declutter this year? Here's how to start</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/simple-ways-to-start-decluttering-at-home/106300708</link><description>Experts say you don't need to pull out the entire contents of a cupboard, beginning with one bag is best.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a8e041b72c037976f8eb5cb64a4f2a3</guid></item><item><title>Former Tottenham manager Ange Postecoglou says Spurs 'not a big club' in wake of Thomas Frank sacking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/former-tottenham-manager-ange-postecoglou-on-club-issues/106339490</link><description>Tottenham Hotspur are "not a big club" because of their policy in the transfer market, former manager Ange Postecoglou has said in the wake of the London club's sacking of head coach Thomas Frank on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ce56a4955c12cf141f86e6540834b3a</guid></item><item><title>Family push for Sunshine Coast neurosurgery unit after shock brain cancer diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/family-push-for-neurosurgery-sunshine-coast-hospital/106321492</link><description>Despite living in one of Queensland's most populated areas, Sunshine Coast residents are still travelling to Brisbane to access life-saving neurosurgery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca9ad85102b860a2aa548084e02b8a5a</guid></item><item><title>Albany Woollen Mills' 101 years celebrated via shared love of blankets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/albany-woollen-mill-in-albany-celebrates-101-years/106322356</link><description>Established in 1925, Western Australia's first and only woollen mill transformed raw wool into fabric and blankets, becoming a cornerstone of Albany's industry before closing in 2002.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebfd4b3313c5a634d2a8d4ee911573eb</guid></item><item><title>Record-breaking heatwave leaves some flower farmers without Valentine's Day blooms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/flower-farmers-heatwave-victoria-losses-valentines-day/106329998</link><description>A record heatwave has destroyed a Mallee flower farm's Valentine's Day blooms, leaving its owner devastated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7db6c60336395b1e9aea3e528a183bc7</guid></item><item><title>Bald Archy satirical art prize highlights political victories, a murder trial and protest movements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/bald-archy-prize-reveals-politics-crime-and-bob-irwin/106340644</link><description>From the trial of Erin Patterson to the landslide election victory, 2025 is pilloried in this year's satirical art prize, the Bald Archy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e360d2786aee3a4fd31acfa42d11981</guid></item><item><title>Maugean skate's endangered status not changing, Environment Minister Murray Watt says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/maugean-skate-endangered-listing-not-changing-murray-watt-says/106342278</link><description>Environment Minister Murray Watt says his decision to keep the status of a rare Tasmanian skate species as endangered rather than change it to critically endangered is based on scientific advice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e900785b0c8d8f08f1f99a4eaf01e576</guid></item><item><title>Australia in danger of World Cup elimination after 'unbelievable' loss to Zimbabwe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/cricket-australia-zimbabwe-t20-world-cup-live-blog-scores/106327068</link><description>Australia's hopes of advancing out of Group B are dealt an almighty blow as Zimbabwe claims one of the biggest upset wins in T20 World Cup history in Colombo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">476ca6531e7d6c07f466b52971129dba</guid></item><item><title>How do you find modern dating? Share your highs and lows with us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/audience-callout-modern-dating-love-stories/106287262</link><description>Whether you've shed tears of joy, sadness or even laughter in the process, we want to hear it all — but keep it under 150 words.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e85c8d73dd7cdf15e05f480eb2c663e8</guid></item><item><title>Out of 38,000 people fined for non-voting in NT local government elections just 3 per cent have paid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/-38-000-fined-for-non-voting-in-the-nt-3-per-cent-have-paid/106342158</link><description>Just 3 per cent of voters fined for not voting in last year’s Northern Territory local government elections have paid the penalty. Debate is growing over whether the system is working — or unfair to voters in remote areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7e516b49aab0aa22c5101d34c71fe0d</guid></item><item><title>Sydney children's author Oliver Phommavanh jailed for sending sexually explicit messages to minors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/childrens-author-oliver-phommavanh-jailed-for-grooming-minors/106342160</link><description>Oliver Phommavanh is sentenced to six-and-a-half years in prison with a non-parole period of four years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c59431758c6b35c4dc27a1b4299ab7a8</guid></item><item><title>Coroner finds police tactic not the cause of Toowoomba Indigenous man's death in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/steven-nixon-mckellar-coronial-findings-death-in-custody/106343656</link><description>A Queensland coroner finds the cause of Indigenous man Steven Nixon-McKellar's death during an arrest was "multi-factorial".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7cece3525e620fdc4a4921898494d2a</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Josie Baff claims Australia's second gold with stunning snowboard cross triumph</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/josie-baff-wins-winter-olympics-gold-australia/106343706</link><description>Josie Baff has become Australia's second gold medallist at the Milano Cortina Winter Olympics, claiming victory in the women's snowboard cross.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f7032bae169f89a7f2c743d729ef218</guid></item><item><title>Ley didn't define herself by her gender but women might relate to her workplace woes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/liberal-party-women-sussan-ley-leadership-spill/106340280</link><description>The issue for the Liberal Party is not simply the toppling of a female leader. It's also about what happened to that leader while she was in the job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">596c3a295f267e6667ca697953519fbd</guid></item><item><title>Josie Baff wins 2026 Winter Olympic gold, a testament to the power of self-belief</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/josie-baff-winter-olympics-snowboard-cross-gold-belief/106344394</link><description>Self-belief is the most powerful tool at an athlete's disposal, and Josie Baff utilised it to its fullest extent with a magical run to gold in the 2026 Winter Olympics snowboard cross.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">416a081074ebb50e93862255aaeab98d</guid></item><item><title>Michael Mohammed Ahmad confronts traumatic childhood abuse in his new novel, Bugger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/michael-mohammed-ahmad-new-book-bugger/106331764</link><description>Michael Mohammed Ahmad, author of The Lebs, marks turning 40 with the publication of his most confronting novel yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a057fc717dc6c9c31f1c40b18e69a8e</guid></item><item><title>Traders 'excited for the future' after lengthy Jetty Road disruptions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/jetty-road-glenelg-after-roadworks/106306338</link><description>After a difficult time for many traders in Glenelg, an air of optimism is starting to emerge as the impact of major construction projects eases and the algal bloom has all but vanished from metropolitan beaches. But some businesses along Jetty Road are still hurting from the disruptions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4407a06690e2e5d3682f5d0874abac21</guid></item><item><title>Musical Matches: Harpist Emily Granger and composer Tristan Coelho</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/musical-matches-harpist-emily-granger-composer-tristan-coelho/106343946</link><description>For Valentine's Day, this Australian composer wrote his wife a harp concerto. She's about to premiere it with the Queensland Symphony Orchestra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbefcaa905952815c641d386942fa2af</guid></item><item><title>Chickens help autistic teen Summer Farrelly make sense of humans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/chickens-help-summer-farrelly-understand-humans-autism-book/106308084</link><description>While growing up, people didn't make much sense to Summer, but chickens always did. Now, Summer is using what they learnt to help other children with autism understand human interactions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69b349a86894794e632c23899a5e2185</guid></item><item><title>What chickens can teach us about socialising.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/what-chickens-can-teach-us-about-socialising/106310344</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2649f1ee118f6ad2700c1b6be9107f2c</guid></item><item><title>Solo diver recounts brush with mako sharks off Tasmanian coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/diver-recounts-experience-with-mako-sharks-pulfers-reef/106307276</link><description>Phillip Ellis Wells was solo diving roughly 7 kilometres off the east coast of Tasmania when he noticed a shadow pass overhead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bf60fbc295b53fac0d5390d1a2f6c7f</guid></item><item><title>Innovative cattle loading ramp puts animal welfare at centre of design</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/wide-cattle-loading-ramp-reduces-transport-stress/106305408</link><description>A retired truck driver has developed a wide, steel, cattle-loading ramp that allows animals to walk side by side, mimicking natural herd behaviour and reducing noise, agitation and the risk of injury during transport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae83b1c62371e347cfe86622f6a1efe5</guid></item><item><title>Heat of summers gone by still fresh in the memory of 98yo Clarence 'Clack' John</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/clarence-clack-john-renmark-summer-heat-history-climate-change/106292966</link><description>Clarence "Clack" John has been through 98 summers in Renmark, South Australia. But as the town sweltered through its hottest recorded day last month, he remembers hot weather before records began.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69efc479fca218e7d45b431dfe41ad19</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri raises safety concerns ahead of F1 Australian Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/oscar-piastri-raises-safety-concerns-f1/106340156</link><description>Oscar Piastri has raised concerns about safety issues at the upcoming Australian Grand Prix, worried about potential chaos at the very start of the F1 season opener.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a19793fef3d4f087577e45c38422ab30</guid></item><item><title>Former AFL captain Dyson Heppell speaks about unhealthy relationship with food during playing career</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/former-afl-captain-dyson-heppell-disordered-eating/106344044</link><description>Former Essendon captain Dyson Heppell has spoken about the unhealthy relationship he had with food early in his career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1c46dc0b0fdb0805ca8c10bdd23d02e</guid></item><item><title>Wool price jumps ahead of industry-first Chinese New Year break</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/wool-price-rising-ahead-of-chinese-new-year-break/106339658</link><description>As wool growers enjoy their best prices since 2019, the market will now pause to respect China's request for a week off to celebrate Lunar New Year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62ad96df10ee1750f91b3b33f2f16b56</guid></item><item><title>Major construction starts on Adelaide's first skyscraper Festival Tower Two</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/major-construction-starts-on-adelaide-skyscraper-festival-tower/106345112</link><description>Festival Tower Two is set to tower over South Australia's Parliament House, which the premier says will bring money and people into the city, but others remain against the $800 million project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3de9dd2f69ba1ba4dfe31d2b03269b73</guid></item><item><title>Carlton star taken to hospital as Victoria holds off WA in AFL Origin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/afl-state-of-origin-wa-victoria-live-blog/106345370</link><description>Victoria holds off a spirited WA side to win the first Aussie rules State of Origin clash for 27 years, though the game is marred by a serious injury to Carlton star Jacob Weitering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">654d718df060bf5c09e6ff92eed7385c</guid></item><item><title>Dry January hits southern Australia as east coast lows drop off the radar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/dry-january-southern-australia-east-coast-lows-decline/106340260</link><description>Rainfall was below average for most of Australia's south-east, far-west and central regions in the first month of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35e0de73fc86cfd94960467f03e96dec</guid></item><item><title>Sharing emergency resources becoming more complicated as fire and flood seasons overlap</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/emergency-resources-bushfires/106340108</link><description>With fires and floods occurring simultaneously, and overlapping with international deployments, sharing critical resources is becoming an increasingly complex task.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5be04f47974abf20f48cfef1f3b2e012</guid></item><item><title>Faaletino Tavana scores stunning try in NRL trial, Canterbury Bulldogs star Matt Burton limps off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/faaletino-tavana-scores-stunning-try-in-nrl-trial/106346352</link><description>Wests Tigers rookie Faaletino Tavana has laid claim to one of the best tries in 2026 during a preseason trial against the Sydney Roosters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2cfee729b56ca0f7ea35f8b101926f7</guid></item><item><title>Easy ways to help protect your hair from chlorine and saltwater damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/how-to-avoid-chlorine-and-saltwater-hair-damage-when-swimming/106334202</link><description>Regular beach days or laps at the local pool can leave our hair looking and feeling quite different.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ed59e0b1894ab058082b567c448eb32</guid></item><item><title>NT film industry on national stage as Kangaroo, Top End Bub and Journey Home win AACTA Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/nt-film-industry-on-national-stage-at-aacta-awards-movies/106345258</link><description>The NT's small but mighty presence is shining on the global stage 40 years after Crocodile Dundee rocketed its film industry into the stratosphere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6b91e7462a835a8868e55cdd28f79a5</guid></item><item><title>AFL State of Origin coaches hail success of concept following Victoria's win over Western Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/afl-state-of-origin-coaches-hail-success-of-concept/106346486</link><description>Winning Victoria coach Chris Scott and his Western Australia counterpart Dean Cox call for State of Origin to be played every year after the concept's stunning return in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a2310e59675ad0bac9b0b865d9ebaef</guid></item><item><title>WA hop growers gear up for harvest as craft beer tastes evolve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/hop-growers-gear-up-harvest-western-australia/106340116</link><description>Local brewers are experimenting with new flavours, while some farms invest in US-made machinery to modernise and streamline the harvest process.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0bb847882a1ace0ae5e8db0cba3fd16</guid></item><item><title>Statues of Amy Sherwin, Australia's first opera star, unveiled at Hobart's Hadley's Hotel in bid to cement legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/peter-schipperheyn-statues-of-amy-sherwin-opera-star-unveiled/106344982</link><description>An effort to bring new recognition to a Tasmanian opera star who became world famous, but who died poor, culminates in the unveiling of two statues of her in Hobart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0073ccc352d93326f0623615a91690e2</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous side overturns 14-0 deficit to down Maori in women's All Stars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/womens-all-stars-indigenous-maori-jada-taylor/106347124</link><description>The Indigenous team overturns a 14-0 deficit to score a rousing comeback win over the Maori in the Women's All Stars clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f14485169561b894f2afb767bb7402d</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous and Māori All Stars play out dramatic 16-all draw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/nrl-all-stars-mens-indigenous-maori-result/106347244</link><description>It went down to the final seconds, but the Indigenous and Maori NRL All Stars could not be separated with both sides left to rue missed chances after a 16-all draw.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d01cc349479a0292d97ba58d32f2571c</guid></item><item><title>City of Melbourne quiet on plan for Southbank's 'ugly' red stairs, long after design competition announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/city-of-melbourne-southbank-red-stair-replacement-plan-stalls/106274362</link><description>A Melbourne council unveiled a lucrative competition to replace Southbank's much-derided red stairs. But a year after it was due to start, the plan appears to have gone nowhere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">074f26e344537a0ab6c98a25242c702d</guid></item><item><title>What is FAFO parenting and is it good for kids?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/what-is-fafo-parenting-and-is-it-good-for-kids/106321924</link><description>Is FAFO the 1980s parenting style today's generation of kids need, rebellion against gentle child-rearing, or exhausted parents just throwing their hands in the air?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27dfd8358d59f5a02bd8ef50448007a0</guid></item><item><title>ACCC takes Coles to court over 'illusory' discounts in 'case of the century'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/accc-coles-federal-court-case-discount-pricing/106294956</link><description>The "case of the century" is set to play out in the federal court this month, with the ACCC taking on supermarket giant Coles for what it claims are "illusory" discounts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a8938d5ebc9b334251e02015fddc7f9</guid></item><item><title>Australia defeated by India in opening T20 as Sophie Molineux era gets off to wobbly start</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/australia-women-beaten-in-t20/106347920</link><description>Australia slumps to a rain-affected 21-run loss to India in their opening T20 at the SCG, after selectors opted to drop vice-captain Tahlia McGrath.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1d3ad1921ec592fc795d54bc3787c1b</guid></item><item><title>Cape Barren Island uses greenhouse and traditional foods to keep fridges full</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/alternative-foods-keep-pantry-full-on-cape-barren-island/105893250</link><description>A tiny island off the coast of Tasmania is embracing old and new techniques to keep food on the table.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6bcc5499da65ccb48471f2c099cdbf7</guid></item><item><title>How the ABC Young Performers Awards helped launch the careers of these Australian musicians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/abc-young-performers-awards-launch-australian-classical-artists/106341202</link><description>The ABC Young Performers Awards have launched the careers of some of Australia's most successful musicians. Here are some of their stories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd1d1f42c12f0cd8f19af90e90ca9734</guid></item><item><title>Fisheries compliance officers inspection November 2023</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/fisheries-compliance-officers-inspection-november-2023/106343188</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63de07d2668638f887406d31c1ea3466</guid></item><item><title>Halls Gap businesses reinventing themselves after bushfires wiped out trade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/halls-gap-pomonal-tourism-bushfire-recovery/106331718</link><description>After two consecutive summers devastated by bushfires, businesses in the region are reinventing themselves to stay afloat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60e94f2fcc4428c36c260d3a2cded9a2</guid></item><item><title>Meet GayC/DC, the world's only all-gay AC/DC tribute band</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/gaycdc-interview-gay-acdc-tribute-band-australia-tour/106331786</link><description>They worship the riffs, rewrite the lyrics and win over the toughest crowds. GayC/DC is a tribute band like no other.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d75dfaf3925eb31093fd2815687fbbc</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners 'won't accept' handback of rehabilitated Argyle diamond mine site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/argyle-diamond-mine-closure-traditional-owner-concerns/106339850</link><description>East Kimberley traditional owners are concerned Rio Tinto's closure plan will leave them with "a giant hole in the ground forever".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">920c2b711109c2ab18519ecaf2822c30</guid></item><item><title>Maugean skate still faces 'catastrophic' risk from salmon farming, Commonwealth advice says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/maugean-skate-endangered-status-analysis/106348446</link><description>Official advice is unequivocal that salmon farming remains the main threat to the endangered Maugean skate. It remains to be seen if the federal environment minister will ask Tasmanian salmon farms to scale back their operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f16f18ad7cc496224dc41ec49e1e0093</guid></item><item><title>Hospital boss says changes already made at child gender service criticised in review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/advocates-say-cairns-report-not-justify-gender-care-restrictions/106343356</link><description>Advocates have called for for better regional services after a Cairns children gender clinic was restricted following a scathing report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ff6c4a104086209c6800093c04c7e53</guid></item><item><title>Protester takes to roof of Geraldton fisheries building over WA government's demersal fishing ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/demersal-fishing-ban-rooftop-protest-geraldton/106350184</link><description>A Geraldton fisherman locks himself to the roof of a government building — and says he has swallowed the key — in a protest over Cook government restrictions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a4f232b4772dc60a2946f241500c3d9</guid></item><item><title>'Devastated' Australia on the brink of World Cup exit after Sri Lanka's record chase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/cricket-australia-sri-lanka-t20-world-cup-live-blog/106351564</link><description>Australia is on the cusp of a group stage exit from the T20 World Cup after crashing to an eight-wicket loss against tournament co-hosts Sri Lanka.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c69a6c4d3d6ed2d91ae06e9e0fd7374d</guid></item><item><title>The night snow came to Livigno, turning this surreal valley into an even greater paradise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/snow-livigno-winter-olympic-games/106351744</link><description>Livigno is an Italian outlier in more ways than one. Already known for its special tax status and fairytale quality, the town has had a phenomenal dumping of snow, causing a significant shuffling of events.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74681b168ba228a59936a1522013ca77</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, February 17: 20 years since The Chaser's War on Everything premiered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/the-chasers-war-on-everything-20-year-anniversary/106340294</link><description>The Chaser's War on Everything didn't start the fire, but the embers from the beloved satirical current affairs show are still warm after two decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">745f78b8b02649b29035b0cec81e7085</guid></item><item><title>Tradies consider leaving careers over lack of onsite toilets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/tradies-created-go-company-to-help-accessability/106244286</link><description>Tradies are walking out. Not over ability or aptitude but toilets — in a symbol of the sector's persistent barriers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2da70745cc00dda920be7b9032002395</guid></item><item><title>Carlton's Jacob Weitering suffers rib fracture after AFL State of Origin, but cleared of other injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/carlton-jacob-weitering-afl-origin-rib-fracture/106352118</link><description>Carlton star Jacob Weitering has received some good news, with the Blues labelling their injured vice-captain as a "good chance" to feature in opening round.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0f4a31c564ffe953194ddf9d3fbcac4</guid></item><item><title>Mould, asbestos, collapsed ceilings plague some South Australian schools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/sa-schools-in-need-of-repair/106334244</link><description>Almost two years after a state government report revealed 35 per cent of all buildings within the Department for Education's portfolio were past their design life, many schools are still plagued with issues including mould, asbestos and rotting windows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fabb2b4476c5886be92e1dda09f3283</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the ISIS-linked families in Syria who want to return to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/who-are-isis-linked-australian-families-in-syria-al-roj-camp/106352074</link><description>Australia has made limited progress in clearing a passage for the Australian women and their children, citing safety issues in and around the camps, and security concerns back home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b94dd1490b366423951626bba907299</guid></item><item><title>Juanella Donovan reflects on People's Choice win at National Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Art Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/artist-juanella-donovan-wins-natsiaa-peoples-choice-award/106350062</link><description>Juanella Donovan has taken out the People's Choice category at the National Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Art Awards for the second time, emerging as the public favourite from more than 200 entries across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">729bb7b7ed08ea9b03a622bdc521303a</guid></item><item><title>Illegal fishing vessels threaten Australia's agricultural sector as biosecurity concerns grow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/farmers-fear-pest-disease-outbreaks-from-illegal-foreign-boats/106349882</link><description>Australian primary producers say they are concerned about the risk of foreign pests crippling entire industries if overseas fishing boats continue to enter the nation's waters illegally.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8f3a85baf70328cdbd85ce22cd6d1ae</guid></item><item><title>Own goal ends Macclesfield's FA Cup fairytale against Brentford</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/fa-cup-macclesfield-brentford-fourth-round/106352296</link><description>Non-league English football club Macclesfield's tremendous FA Cup run has come to an end, falling to Premier League side Brentford.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ef3637794f7ad3aecb3526517be191b</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Eileen Gu medals despite blizzard, Ilia Malinin breaks his silence — day 10 quick hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/winter-olympics-day-10-quick-hits/106351560</link><description>A Norwegian skier melts down in the Italian cold as the Canadian women's curling team hits back at cheating accusations. Here are the quick hits from day 10 of the Milano Cortina Winter Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3e902ec1235988fcd9d5cb6b4f1c4e4</guid></item><item><title>Nurses vote to go on strike at Lyell McEwin Hospital as SA government gives immediate pay rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/lyell-mcewin-hospital-nurses-vote-to-strike/106351466</link><description>Nurses and midwives at the Lyell McEwin Hospital remain set to walk off the job for 24 hours on Thursday, with the union saying the government's decision to introduce an immediate 4 per cent pay rise still falls short of expectations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d59c7aa464f39cac1635d8dcebe8a148</guid></item><item><title>Peterborough District Council loses fifth CEO since 2024 with latest sacked after two months</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/peterborough-district-council-sacks-ceo-deirdre-albrighton/106348454</link><description>Peterborough District Council has sacked its latest CEO less than two months into her role. The council in regional South Australia has gone through five CEOs in two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57fc6e2fe202b0403c55bc16dda02479</guid></item><item><title>Western Australia's demersal fishing ban hits hard in coastal tourist town of Kalbarri</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/western-australia-demersal-fishing-ban-jackie-jarvis-kalbarri/106336464</link><description>People in the coastal tourist town of Kalbarri say they are already suffering the effects of WA's demersal fishing ban, less than two months after it came into force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b2b2f7a818984b5536b032082a9b2cf</guid></item><item><title>Iran launches military drill as US deploys aircraft carrier on eve of nuclear talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/iran-us-military-drill-trump-geneva-nuclear-talks/106353940</link><description>Representatives from the two nations are set to meet in Geneva on Tuesday, local time, as US President Donald Trump tries to curb Tehran's nuclear program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94646181af842a5e1c582c59df894657</guid></item><item><title>High-pitched anti-homeless noise devices switched off and labelled 'hostile' by WA government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/anti-homelessness-noise-devices-perth-bridge-removed/106354270</link><description>High-pitched noise devices installed under a bridge to deter rough sleepers are labelled "unnecessary" and "humiliating" by housing campaigners and condemned by the WA government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">735727b3767fc5e8a557f1dd188af0e9</guid></item><item><title>VERTICAL VIDEO: Noise device installed in East Perth underpass</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/vvp-homelesssiren-1702/106354990</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7e89892cbbfde0e5d4320d949dccb3f</guid></item><item><title>Australian production company Matchbox Pictures to be closed by Universal International Studios</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/matchbox-pictures-closed-universal-international-studios/106355260</link><description>Matchbox Pictures, the local production house behind Dog Park, The Survivors and Secret City, will be closed by its international parent company, Universal International Studios.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78b9d935e059c11895c3efac8807b716</guid></item><item><title>Father whose son died in house fire accuses lawyer at coronial inquiry of 'degrading him'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/qld-fatal-fire-inquest-father-outburst/106354862</link><description>The father, in an emotional outburst, told the inquest he had spent thousands of dollars on psychiatric and hypnotherapy appointments so he could move on from the tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2817eed5da4210d086772b41a3286cb6</guid></item><item><title>Sydney’s great fatberg hiding in the sewers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/sydney-s-great-fatberg-hiding-in-the-sewers/106355414</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d86c2192d0e5b5504b2ff2bec1bd22ef</guid></item><item><title>Grammy-winning songwriter and hitmaker Billy Steinberg dies aged 75</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/grammy-winning-songwriter-billy-steinberg-dies-aged-75/106356348</link><description>Award-winning US songwriter Billy Steinberg, who wrote several top hit songs including Madonna's Like a Virgin, died on Monday aged 75, according to media reports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb0f5e86348cae84a5923360286fcd40</guid></item><item><title>Richard Roxburgh, Damon Herriman and Toby Schmitz star in 'wickedly funny' play Art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/art-the-play-richard-roxburgh-damon-herriman-toby-schmitz/106051888</link><description>In the 1994 French play Art, Serge spends 160,000 euros on an all-white painting, horrifying his friend Marc. It might just wreck their decades-long friendship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf94795c60e3d3af64640f380e98e6b3</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian salmon industry subject to stricter mortality reporting rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/tas-salmon-mortality-reporting-new-rules/106355012</link><description>Biosecurity Tasmania has introduced stricter requirements for Tasmania's salmon companies reporting on farmed fish deaths — but whether the public finds out is another matter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b4561f315abfbba772d736bf48eab4d</guid></item><item><title>Aerials delay is not unusual, as snow causes chaos at Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/aerials-delays-2026-winter-olympics/106356762</link><description>Delays are nothing new in skiing events, with weather and light a constant battle for event organisers. However, the Australian aerials team has an unusual method to handle the disruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f49e711941aae6ee00c9b528308bb80f</guid></item><item><title>Long-term solution to repeated Waterfall Way landslips on the horizon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/long-term-solution-repeated-waterfall-way-landslides/106353438</link><description>The NSW government hopes to reopen a key east-west transport route by April, as a long-term solution to frequent landslips in the area is explored.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93a127abafb503c04ed7b234a9aa7f0e</guid></item><item><title>Owners win right to demolish Lis Escop house in Rockhampton after appeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/owners-win-appeal-to-demolish-162-year-old-rockhampton-home/106341768</link><description>A couple has won the right to demolish a 162-year-old building in a Queensland city scattered with heritage-listed properties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2e33910bc6ae9d2b7fa35586dc25a14</guid></item><item><title>Disenfranchised Farrer voters turn out in droves to consider One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/one-nation-farrer-federal-by-election/106354342</link><description>This southern New South Wales town of Gerogery is typically dead on a Monday night, but that all changed when One Nation came to town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfeec7877eeface1749af84fb416ce74</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Jürgen Klopp makes Milano Cortina Games cameo, ice hockey fight ban labelled a 'joke' — quick hits from day 11</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-day-11-quick-hits/106356448</link><description>Football manager Jürgen Klopp makes an appearance at the Milano Cortina Games, while French ice hockey players are unhappy about the ban handed to a teammate for fighting. Here are the quick hits from day 11.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9e6fc860b11cec670fa7d512e4c8727</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Writers' Festival announces Randa Abdel-Fattah for 2026 program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/randa-abdel-fattah-to-feature-at-sydney-writers-festival/106357178</link><description>Sydney Writers' Festival has defended featuring Randa Abdel-Fattah on its 2026 program, saying it is "not in the business of cancelling or censoring writers".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27fd50a9ce304983c79c05fe33b13137</guid></item><item><title>Police release man arrested over Galiwin'ku stabbing death without charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/nt-man-released-without-charge-after-fatal-galiwinku-stabbing/106357704</link><description>Police say a 19-year-old man arrested over the stabbing death of another man, 27, on Elcho Island on Saturday has been released without charge "pending further investigations".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a506da9a67db14560688134793469b6f</guid></item><item><title>James Slipper set to play 200th Super Rugby match as ACT Brumbies travel to face Crusaders in Christchurch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/james-slipper-set-to-play-200th-super-rugby-match/106359004</link><description>James Slipper will become the first Australian player to reach the 200-game milestone in Super Rugby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">666672c36683f7dfca20fa7cad0c1916</guid></item><item><title>Potential rugby development in Sydney's Hills district sparks stoush with protesters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/residents-turn-to-blocking-fred-caterson-development/106357890</link><description>Protesters say they will block the council from developing sporting fields for the use of an elite club rugby at a reserve in the city's north-west, as a court challenge to the project is due to be heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86383eb37a77ebed5bc01816183f967b</guid></item><item><title>Jesse Jackson helped lay the groundwork for Barack Obama and kept the fight for justice in the public eye</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/jesse-jackson-groundwork-for-americas-first-black-president/106359248</link><description>Reverend Jesse Jackson, who died on Tuesday aged 84, leaves behind a towering legacy in politics and the fight for justice in the United States and abroad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0665d46428bd50fafd1d8f2ab4989a0</guid></item><item><title>Victoria loses Australian MotoGP with 2026 race to be last in state</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/victoria-loses-motogp-after-refusing-to-move-from-phillip-island/106360086</link><description>Victoria loses the rights to host the Australian Motorcycle Grand Prix, ending a three-decade association with the event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfccc65e1d8b9b3f86fe36579af25b73</guid></item><item><title>Blue Bush Floodway enjoyed by all.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/blue-bush-floodway-enjoyed-by-all/106360146</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbd2f162df0e8fed005d6a35a8340a73</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 12</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide/106357404</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5927607c6b226a4fc3cd81eec0fa5c61</guid></item><item><title>Man fined $32,000 for poaching rare snakes from Far North Queensland rainforest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/man-fined-for-poaching-rare-snakes/106360544</link><description>The court heard Clinton Spiteri was with two others when he visited a rainforest in the Cape York area to steal eight snakes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e054b8dba8caac08516c2d5f4789e82</guid></item><item><title>South Australia could host the Australian Motorcycle Grand Prix from 2027</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/sa-could-host-the-australian-motogp/106360386</link><description>An announcement on the future of the Australian Motorcycle Grand Prix is expected as soon as Thursday amid widespread speculation the event is set to shift to South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b26fba3656006cb6dacc897cffc47d8</guid></item><item><title>Danielle Scott wins silver medal in women's aerials event at 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/winter-olympics-dani-scott-silver-womens-aerials/106361098</link><description>Danielle Scott ends a 12-year drought for Australia by winning the silver medal in the women's aerials final at the Milano Cortina Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3820d5e835f545e590e5477cd6c61b06</guid></item><item><title>Quiz: Which books are these literary quotes from?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/famous-book-quotes-quiz/106321984</link><description>Are you happiest with your nose in a book? Did you spend summer reading at the beach? This quiz is for you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93263cc459c19ed242af066f07f52020</guid></item><item><title>Trump official says US did not censor Colbert interview but is probing The View</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/fcc-confirms-investigation-into-the-view/106361394</link><description>The confirmation of a probe into the daytime talk show came after it interviewed the same Democratic candidate whose interview with Stephen Colbert was allegedly barred from airing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00896e420fd548e96575bb0b6c4b91f3</guid></item><item><title>Renewable energy company abandons native title court application over Darwin solar farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/darwin-solar-farm-court-application-abandoned/106357534</link><description>A renewable energy company planning to build a solar farm near Darwin withdraws a court application that traditional owners argued would "erase" their rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16119d56006ff2c8aae6209ef2b53cf7</guid></item><item><title>Could SA Liberal leader Ashton Hurn lose her seat at the next election?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/could-ashton-hurn-lose-her-seat-at-the-next-sa-election/106357818</link><description>It's an almost unthinkable scenario, but the fact it's even being discussed shows the extent of the Liberal Party's predicament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9786f949730f20ebd11b7fd76ff59c7f</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Channel Nine reporter Danika Mason apologises after viral Today show cross</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/winter-olympics-2026-danika-mason-channel-nine-live-cross/106361740</link><description>Danika Mason has apologised for letting her standards slip during a live cross to the Today show from the Winter Olympics in Milano Cortina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">587053632e396210a542b81ba13dccca</guid></item><item><title>Feed and water supplies dry up in NSW as drought tightens grip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/drought-tightens-grip-nsw-feed-water-supplies-dry-up/106360686</link><description>Over this season's hot and dry summer in New South Wales, farmer Ryan Staniforth has spent much of his time carting water to keep his sheep alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46db9976c248632ce753eccaa9b15e80</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Pickering on his ADHD, satire and the 'ludicrous' Trump era</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/charlie-pickering-the-weekly-interview/106307588</link><description>Political satire occasionally comes at a price, but Charlie Pickering still believes the right joke at the right time can have a huge impact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7c1acd1c8fd008196d50eecb9154256</guid></item><item><title>Wayne Gardner, Casey Stoner slam Victorian government over Phillip Island MotoGP loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/phillip-island-motogp-loss-wayne-gardner-casey-stoner/106361880</link><description>Australian Motorcycle Grand Prix winner Wayne Gardner has lashed out at the Victorian government over the loss of the Phillip Island MotoGP, saying he has been left "disappointed" and "sad" by the decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf3ff0ae76acea3e2fe354f880cbf507</guid></item><item><title>Labor opposition propose five-day kindergarten for Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/tas-labor-announces-five-day-kinder-policy/106362388</link><description>Tasmania's state opposition unveils a policy to extend kindergarten to five days a week in an effort to tackle the state's underperforming education system, but the government says Labor is "light on details".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20d131e8503e551f43bd2fd1d742e601</guid></item><item><title>Alcoa's environmental record 'disappointing' says WA premier after $55m payment for unlawful jarrah forest clearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/alcoa-environment-record-disappointing-says-roger-cook/106363128</link><description>Roger Cook criticises Alcoa's environmental record for being "not at the level we expect", after the US mining giant agreed to pay $55 million for clearing a native jarrah forest in WA's south without approval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">297fe700fe6b245c2b7d9210aafd3c92</guid></item><item><title>Heavy rain through north Queensland leads to multiple floodwater rescues and Bruce Highway closures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/queensland-rain-bruce-highway-closure-mount-isa-rescues/106362844</link><description>Heavy rainfall across north Queensland has led to multiple rescues and the closure of several sections of the Bruce Highway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f93257abf07c3acbc49599880adb87</guid></item><item><title>North Qld Anglican diocese given green light to sell properties to pay compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/north-queensland-anglican-diocese-to-sell-properties/106361784</link><description>A successful Supreme Court application will allow the church to sell assets to help fund its commitments to victims of historical child abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dafc4035f9ff254859cbe8ab50d8accb</guid></item><item><title>For salty South Australians, motorsport revenge is oh so sweet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/for-salty-south-australians-motorsport-revenge-is-oh-so-sweet/106363660</link><description>The last Grand Prix in Adelaide was held in 1995 before its move across the border to Victoria. Now, Adelaide has poached the MotoGP — but will it be enough to appease resentful SA Formula One fans?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ffda5df5fc99fb91a7d77ce30ebe2be</guid></item><item><title>Hanson digs her heels in, Taylor goes on tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/pauline-hanson-barnaby-joyce-angus-taylor-anthony-albanese/106349216</link><description>This week, the new opposition leader revealed his shadow cabinet while Pauline Hanson spun through a cycle she knows well.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ea3a4f2179a8b0064925ee07ccfca6c</guid></item><item><title>What is Skimo? The sport preparing to steal the show at the Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/skimo-debut-winter-olympic-games/106361848</link><description>Skimo, or ski mountaineering, is coming to the 2026 Winter Olympics. But what is the sport and why is it so exciting?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cc7441c0ae245bfcfcc6c6051609c64</guid></item><item><title>Court hears statement murdered woman Irma Palasics made after harrowing assault a year earlier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/act-irma-palasics-trial-hears-statement-from-prior-burglary/106361986</link><description>A statement made by murdered woman Irma Palasics after a burglary at her home a year prior is read to the ACT Supreme Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0c56923a5ad0aebab9da439119af986</guid></item><item><title>Racing NSW disqualifies stablehand and owner Brian Carey over racehorse death in Maryborough</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/brian-carey-city-limits-racing-nsw-racehorse-maryborough/106362914</link><description>Registered owner and stablehand Brian Carey is disqualified after being found guilty by Racing NSW of failing to ensure his racehorse, City Limits, had sufficient food and water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89c623d6aac3515dcfe6d5527459d333</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of 'controlling' the lives of Venezuelan youth group granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/bail-granted-over-alleged-youth-group-servitude/106363616</link><description>An alleged religious leader accused of "controlling every aspect" of the lives of a Venezuelan youth group has been granted release on strict home detention conditions by a South Australian court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91bc9f195f669d568f2a90e1fe9c2a44</guid></item><item><title>SA Premier Peter Malinauskas criticised over aged care workforce comments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/malinauskas-criticised-for-comments-on-aged-care-migrant-workers/106362214</link><description>South Australia's Premier Peter Malinauskas has been criticised across the political divide for comments he made asking One Nation voters "who's going to feed you and bathe you and wipe your bum when you're 90", but a government spokesperson says the comments have been mischaracterised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89e475d7e7fb2bdb64bd8fefb2824fc5</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 13</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide/106361600</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b82fce97399d532a4a35eed6ae6a0ea9</guid></item><item><title>South Korea's ex-president Yoon Suk Yeol sentenced to life in prison over insurrection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/south-korea-president-yoon-suk-yeol-sentenced-insurrection-guilt/106363456</link><description>Former South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol is sentenced to life in prison on charges of rebellion for his attempt to put the country under military rule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8145bfdf54ebbed599a2b489a9edabf6</guid></item><item><title>Greg Lynn applies for bail as retrial for High Country camper murder looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/greg-lynn-applies-for-bail-court/106365580</link><description>The former Jetstar pilot awaits a retrial for the murder of Carol Clay, after his 2024 conviction was quashed in December.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77a388716f1e874a2b4c47724de2d0e3</guid></item><item><title>Abandoned Antarctic base is now a pollution threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/abandoned-antarctic-base-is-now-a-pollution-threat-/106365360</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49846b03030ffc2b913431f02159b7f8</guid></item><item><title>Michael Brian Becton sentenced to more than 24 years in jail for child sex offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/man-sentenced-to-24-years-in-jail-over-child-sex-offences/106365380</link><description>Michael Brian Becton, 33, is handed a 24-and-a-half year prison term after pleading guilty to 77 child sexual offences against children and babies. WARNING: This story contains details that some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">388c384c47b78f4a85d064f1750a1efd</guid></item><item><title>Former premier joins community calls for speed reduction at 'dangerous' fatal intersection in Newham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/community-calls-for-speed-reduction-newham-intersection-victoria/106364280</link><description>A community in central Victoria is calling for a 20 kph speed limit reduction at a "terribly dangerous" intersection after four major accidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d28bf645384eca294d072c5b45849511</guid></item><item><title>Calls for protection of Tasmania's penguins amid reports of birds 'handled by the neck'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/people-interacting-with-tasmanian-penguins-and-harming-them/106361614</link><description>Each summer, tourists flock to Tasmanian beaches to marvel at penguins, but for some, admiring the birds from afar is not enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a8bc422a73f9012a025e072732b4fbb</guid></item><item><title>Police guarding former prince Andrew's residence in Sandringham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/police-guarding-former-prince-andrew-s-residence-in-sandringham/106366520</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">230140cfa446b0397fb1807d140d3ab6</guid></item><item><title>The 2026 South Australia election is here — Have your say about what matters to you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/your-say-sa/106310300</link><description>We want to know what issues matter most to you and what you want us to find out ahead of the March 21, SA election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8775ae3583b363e14b02f155e2e28dce</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's arrest could end monarchy's 'never complain, never explain' mentality</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrest-a-problem-for-monarchy/106365934</link><description>British royals have lived by the adage "never complain, never explain", but these days, many of their subjects are demanding answers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69ce80bb0d80419516702662a1c32494</guid></item><item><title>Can Angus Taylor get beyond slogans to craft a sound immigration policy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/angus-taylor-immigration-pauline-hanson/106349268</link><description>The rifts in Australia's social cohesion can be seen in the blow-up over the so-called ISIS brides and their children, who want to come to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81483ff7c63fdba169c22b024c766cea</guid></item><item><title>Wild horse art on birth certificates is 'hypocritical', says brumby welfare group</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/brumby-birth-certificate-art-outrage/106363854</link><description>A limited-edition birth certificate released to mark the Chinese Year of the Horse is being labelled "hypocritical" as a cull of wild horses continues in the NSW high country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">036d3db4d54a10ba8cdd2c50a1ae692e</guid></item><item><title>Car driving Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor leaves UK police station.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-released-after-being-in-custody/106366694</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5d1b414c5b63a2abd8afd19a7fb4208</guid></item><item><title>Amyl and the Sniffers singer in escalating legal battle with photographer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/amy-taylor-amyl-and-the-sniffers-court-cases-copyright/106361084</link><description>What began as a photo shoot with champagne, ice cream and humorous glamour shots of Amy Taylor, singer from punk band Amyl and the Sniffers, has escalated into a legal fight over copyright, the US Constitution and an application for a restraining order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2eecb7daec40c63d6dec04c319e48120</guid></item><item><title>More rainfall expected for parts of northern Queensland after wet week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/more-rainfall-forecast-for-northern-qld/106362726</link><description>A risk for further heavy rainfall and thunderstorms is possible in northern parts of the state today and into the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e9add29fa1f01a82340402c2e1aad56</guid></item><item><title>First NT women's prison opens in Alice Springs with focus on rehabilitation to break 'cycle of reoffending'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/first-nt-womens-prison-opens-in-alice-springs/106357580</link><description>Thirty-five female prisoners have moved into the Northern Territory's first women's prison, near Alice Springs, with more expected in the coming months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b13e3f1982f1c6fef53a91ff356eabb1</guid></item><item><title>Major US fund's credit squeeze could 'blow up' — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-friday-20-february/106366740</link><description>Shares in US asset manager Blue Owl have fallen sharply after it announced it was having challenges meeting investors' cash demands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8cfa058595f0f84f2b91273acd73f15</guid></item><item><title>Sam Altman and Dario Amodei refuse to hold hands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/sam-altman-and-dario-amodei-refuse-to-hold-hands/106366810</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28360275abe5f689dc70a72962b98b0f</guid></item><item><title>Is it OK to feed Australia's wild birds?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/is-it-ok-to-feed-australias-wild-birds/106349168</link><description>Many of us love interacting with and feeding wild birds, but experts say giving them the wrong types of food can do more harm than good.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eec910366a2f5aeb070b335682010295</guid></item><item><title>NT hit-and-run driver Jake Danby's sentence extended on appeal, now to serve two years in home detention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/jake-danby-sentence-extended-on-appeal-2-years-home-detention/106366800</link><description>The sentence of NT hit-and-run driver Jake Danby has been extended on appeal, meaning he will serve two years in home detention. Danby hit two pedestrians with his car in June 2024, killing one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f57345975c6d0ea9d3ea8d0e24b086a</guid></item><item><title>NT cattle sector backs draft buffel grass plan as environmental and Aboriginal groups say it favours industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/buffel-grass-weed-draft-plan-groups-say-it-favours-industry/106309368</link><description>Cattle producers support the NT's draft buffel grass weed management plan, but it has attracted criticism from traditional owners and environmental groups.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f63e14c6d52852a5e04560d27f31045b</guid></item><item><title>Commercial fishing licence buybacks recommended in latest harmful algal bloom report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/sa-parliament-report-into-harmful-algal-bloom-handed-down/106363850</link><description>Fishing licence buybacks and long-term restocking plans are some of the recommendations in the latest report into South Australia's harmful algal bloom, which has been labelled as "vanilla" by one scientist turned political candidate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d3a00e55feef726ec2f63dce3afd3b3</guid></item><item><title>WA councils could make laws to stop cats roaming under proposed state legislation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/wa-councils-could-soon-have-power-to-stop-cats-roaming/106365476</link><description>The WA government announces plans to give local councils the power to require cats to be contained to owners' properties, to protect native birds and other wildlife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9304ac0385f2634a77bf6bab016498b8</guid></item><item><title>Senior Constable Stuart Parsonage charged with illegal surveillance by WA Police sex crime division</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/wa-police-officer-court-computer-crime-surveillance-charges/106365724</link><description>Geraldton Senior Constable Stuart Parsonage has been charged with the illegal installation of a surveillance device and unlawful use of a computer by WA sex crime detectives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ef0a162b68b5d35ea9dcd87f112ee98</guid></item><item><title>Parents speak at sentencing hearing for Christopher Turner over fatal gas mix-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/christopher-turner-gas-pipe-mix-up-hospital-victim-impacts/106367440</link><description>The parents of two babies given nitrous oxide in a fatal gas mix-up at a Sydney hospital almost a decade ago express their pain and trauma at the sentencing hearing for the man responsible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e2ecb02a7ac2a45488be9175b75450f</guid></item><item><title>Mercedes F1 boss Toto Wolff defends team over engine drama ahead of Australian Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/mercedes-f1-boss-toto-wolff-calls-rivals-over-engine-saga/106368722</link><description>Toto Wolff accuses rival Formula 1 manufacturers of ganging up on Mercedes to pressure the governing FIA to change engine rules, but says it will make no difference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf062a44fa8f20ae64da57f3e573fc38</guid></item><item><title>Coroner delivers findings into James Tsindos's death from allergic reaction to delivery meal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/coroner-delivers-james-tsindos-nut-allergy-findings/106367040</link><description>A Victorian coroner hands down her findings into the death of a teenager who suffered a severe allergic reaction to a delivery meal — but it's unclear if more urgent treatment would have saved his life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebac18c8be8e4bab52fd1a3ef61d1b64</guid></item><item><title>Kyra Wheatley ready to ride the chaos and speed of ski cross at Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/kyra-wheatley-ski-cross-speed-chaos-winter-olympics/106366406</link><description>The speed and chaos of ski cross is what attracted Kyra Wheatley to the sport, and to realise a dream 12 years in the making of competing at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1a4056e5ff034ff263b9864448b4429</guid></item><item><title>Darwin prisoner Clinton Daylight found, returned to custody two days after being freed from jail by mistake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/clinton-daylight-prisoner-mistakenly-released-nt-darwin-found/106368724</link><description>A 52-year-old inmate who was mistakenly released from the Darwin Correctional Centre two months before his sentence was due to end, due to an "administration error" by prison staff, has been found following a police search.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ab77d54005b5f557cf182cfc9c9d924</guid></item><item><title>Scientists model best-case and worst-case climate scenarios for Antarctica</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/antarctica-faces-devastating-impacts-under-climate-change/106354182</link><description>Scientists say parts of Antarctica face "devastating" and "irreversible" impacts from climate change unless urgent action is taken to limit greenhouse gas emissions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f426dd0a1878420ce756c07766ef447c</guid></item><item><title>MotoGP Adelaide move raises concerns about rider safety, transport and trees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/motogp-adelaide-move-raises-safety-concerns/106368608</link><description>A rider, a reporter and a road safety expert say it will be difficult to make it safe for motorcycles to race around the Adelaide Parklands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25090531a9db489ad194e965a6815079</guid></item><item><title>How Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's 10 hours in police custody unfolded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrest-and-birthday-in-police-lockup/106367644</link><description>Ostracised by his family and stripped of his titles, Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor celebrates his 66th birthday with police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7bfb3145d616df7e291cfa8889b3a52</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on day 14</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/winter-olympics-2026-quick-guide-what-to-watch-on-day-14/106369576</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">066e1fb6ed6f781b86c77bb6a6e1fa05</guid></item><item><title>Glider pilot creates aviation history in Central Australia flying 1,266 kilometres</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/glider-pilot-makes-history-central-australia/106364374</link><description>A Queensland pilot has made aviation history in Central Australia, flying more than 1,200 kilometres without an engine in a record-breaking glider flight launched from Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3a3e44b629b032cc34ddda0931e8d1e</guid></item><item><title>Ellyse Perry's evolution cements greatness as Australian cricket milestone looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/ellyse-perry-australia-cricket-350-matches/106369982</link><description>Cricket superstar Ellyse Perry will become the first woman to play 350 matches for Australia across all formats on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">588cdbd7c7f7eac8850144d63f6e89e7</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle man avoids jail for child abuse images and bestiality videos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/man-avoids-jail-for-possessing-bestiality-and-child-abuse-images/106369722</link><description>A man has avoided time behind bars and instead been handed a three-year community corrections order for possessing 34,000 child abuse images and more than a dozen bestiality videos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91107be62e03814cc5d9c575bcf0edc7</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters used aerial assets on Friday to douse a fire burning near Gaffneys Creek.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/gaffneys-creek-bushfire/106370356</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9662bdb0c9c04b80ab84e721c8af66e0</guid></item><item><title>Licence for use of antibiotic florfenicol in Tasmanian salmon industry may be suspended</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/antibiotic-florfenicol-licence-tasmanian-salmon-may-be-suspended/106370212</link><description>The federal agency that approved the use of an antibiotic for Tasmania's salmon industry has proposed to suspend that licence, in the wake of news the antibiotic has been found in native species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6c610d3b2ff6cbefab9c1f1ac62000e</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106369880</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dee6a5fc24b6baae934b701b2e8b0ec5</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand man Tamaohungia Joseph Tepatu-Edwards jailed for 26 years for attempted cocaine importation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/new-zealand-man-jailed-attempted-cocaine-importation/106368264</link><description>A man who tried to smuggle more than 800 kilograms of cocaine into WA – and was only caught when his boat broke down — will spend two decades in jail and "likely" be deported.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe96af322e56c9cc85664c9573f21026</guid></item></channel></rss>