<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 05:44:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel returns, addressing Charlie Kirk and 'un-American' axing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/jimmy-kimmel-returns-thanking-supporters-speaks-to-free-speech/105808410</link><description>Despite the late-night host's return, several US ABC affiliates did not air the episode, excluding an estimated one-quarter of American households.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac8b78a8e557c0d2a91d42ed04e2eed</guid></item><item><title>How #RedundancyDiaries are busting the stigma of being let go</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/busting-the-stigma-on-redundancy-by-sharing-online/105751880</link><description>Camille says being made redundant was hard, so she began sharing her experiences on TikTok hoping to help others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69e9a0930ebbcb9805519c817968e9ee</guid></item><item><title>Report recommends gondola access to Jenolan Caves near the Blue Mountains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/report-recommends-gondola-access-to-jenolan-caves/105809918</link><description>A report recommends building a gondola to the tune of $44 million to bypass catastrophic road failures that have long plagued the Jenolan Caves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27aa154744525803a917b0b5069cde36</guid></item><item><title>Doctor who lost daughter to brain cancer receives grant in race to clinical trials</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/doctor-receives-grant-to-continue-brain-cancer-research/105810368</link><description>A professor who lost his daughter to brain cancer in 2018 is hopeful the research to find a cure in children is just five years away from clinical trials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc0272343034af8958b1ec9f51c4c20f</guid></item><item><title>Optus admits procedural failure before outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/optus-admits-procedural%C2%A0failure-before-outage%C2%A0/105811978</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b84c417046bbfc3acea16532e90a47cf</guid></item><item><title>Optus to pay $100m fine, as crisis engulfing Australia's second biggest telco continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/optus-fined-100-million-for-sales-misconduct/105810174</link><description>In enforcing the fine today, the Federal Court's Justice Patrick O'Sullivan described the company's conduct as "extremely serious" and "appalling".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5b8ef086dc95c25b9efd2536b1850d6</guid></item><item><title>AFL boss hints at Brownlow voting shake-up after Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/afl-boss-hits-at-brownlow-voting-shake-up-after-controversy/105812086</link><description>Voting for the Brownlow Medal has been a hot topic again in the wake of Monday night's count, with the AFL open to letting umpires have access to statistics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5d9c582b445942c6c11e6f1591db872</guid></item><item><title>Christopher John Sullivan sentenced for stabbing partner Pauline Mountford in Gooseberry Hill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/christopher-john-sullivan-domestic-violence-sentencing/105812460</link><description>A 74-year-old man who slashed his partner's throat in their Perth Hills home is sentenced to 10 years in jail over the near-fatal attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b34ba7512fda4d4c878ff84234b915f6</guid></item><item><title>Former A-League footballers Clayton Lewis and Kearyn Baccus sentenced over betting scam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/a-league-betting-clayton-lewis-kearyn-baccus-sentencing/105811400</link><description>Both players were paid $10,000 each to intentionally get themselves yellow cards while playing for Macarthur FC against Sydney FC to influence overseas bets on the game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4d047a9369284c7941aaf5cccc0a654</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast posts record tourism spend as mayor warns of public transport 'time bomb'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/record-gold-coast-tourism-spend-prompts-public-transport-warning/105811046</link><description>International tourists are spending more than ever on the Gold Coast, but mayor Tom Tate says the city faces a public transport "time bomb" that could ruin its reputation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c6df1c0bdc0bbebd9425d3678241991</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of Australians fighting 'cruel' battle for COVID vaccine injury compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/fight-for-compensation-for-covid-19-vaccination-injuries/105808630</link><description>Thousands of Australians who were injured by COVID vaccines say they are facing a 'cruel and complex' system to get compensation from the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc0182bdb4d37c0f24454edad8263808</guid></item><item><title>Productivity Commission to review state and territory GST deal, including $60b WA windfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/australia-gst-review-under-review-wa-gst-deal/105813372</link><description>Western Australia's GST deal, expected to cost the Commonwealth $60 billion by 2029, will form part of a review by the Australian Productivity Commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b22ae8ce5ff8afaa0d867d88f15dc4f0</guid></item><item><title>Australian War Memorial updates Ben Roberts-Smith display to mention recent High Court rejection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/war-memorial-updates-ben-roberts-smith-exhibit-again/105813004</link><description>The war memorial's revised display now mentions Ben Roberts-Smith's failed bid to the High Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9edc3cc4a1fb29debf8f915faecacf6</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Lions trust Lachie Neale to make right call ahead of AFL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/brisbane-lions-lachie-neale-right-afl-grand-final-call/105813604</link><description>All eyes are on Lachie Neale's bid to make a remarkable grand final return from injury, and his teammates will back him to make the right call.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b33183c69e679601c3ad83c2c662b7b</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105813848</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbeee129e3122b06287a24ba6aa752ed</guid></item><item><title>Senate inquiry examines federal environment department's SA algal bloom response</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/murray-watt-briefing-algal-bloom-july/105813252</link><description>Officials from the federal environment department say they were not aware of the impact of SA's algal bloom until the state government contacted them in May, two months after the bloom was first detected. Speaking at a senate inquiry, department officials say the federal environment minister was not formally briefed on the bloom until July.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47629bf3fc1342b70bb629add33dbfd9</guid></item><item><title>Alzheimer's drug Lecanemab approved by Therapeutic Goods Administration for use in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/alzheimers-drug-lecanemab-approved-by-tga/105813710</link><description>The Therapeutic Goods Administration approves the drug Lecanemab, which can slow down cognitive decline in the early stages of Alzheimer's.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4467a4bcfcdb0b2847fe165e1550be39</guid></item><item><title>Super Typhoon Ragasa hits south China as death toll rises to 14</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/super-typhoon-ragasa-kills-several-people-many-others-missing/105813684</link><description>Super Typhoon Ragasa has killed at least 14 people in Taiwan as it struck the southern Chinese coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3debe7584f1c0715ebb83364e81b822c</guid></item><item><title>One dead in 'targeted' shooting at Dallas immigration centre, DHS says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/multiple-dead-at-dallas-ice-shooting/105814138</link><description>Police were first alerted to the incident at 6:40am on Wednesday, local time, and later found the shooter on a nearby roof dead from an apparent self-inflicted gunshot wound.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41372aed6a1e8513347f563b066ef004</guid></item><item><title>Kimmel monologue racks up millions of views on social media as Joe Rogan slams government 'dictating'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/kimmel-video-and-rogan-lashing-viral/105814274</link><description>Kimmel's program was indefinitely suspended last week after he made comments about the late conservative commentator Charlie Kirk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">125445d0de8a02f7060a350896e799ff</guid></item><item><title>Australia's social media ban wins praise from Europe at UN event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/united-nations-general-assembly-social-media-ban/105814246</link><description>Australia's willingness to take on the social media giants is drawing significant international interest, winning the support of the European Commission president at a forum in New York.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13cbd1fcaa9fc632384fa2b086577151</guid></item><item><title>Australia in a 'dangerous place' as AI adoption ramps up, prompting calls to protect jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/australia-in-dangerous-place-as-ai-adoption-ramps-up/105807430</link><description>Artificial intelligence is coming for our jobs — but will it take them away, or just give us a powerful new assistant?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48e1ecb4ff4fc7a8cb46b98272af471f</guid></item><item><title>Who is really pulling the strings at Optus and what does that mean for you?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/who-really-controls-optus/105813620</link><description>The Singapore government's sovereign wealth investment vehicle is the majority owner of Singtel, which owns Australia's second-largest telco provider.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6aded4f6f61a6898c3ed39fc7af059c2</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie taunted over claim that high immigration is making Australians 'strangers in our own home'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/hastie-migration-strangers-liberal-policy/105813654</link><description>The home affairs minister says Andrew Hastie should name which visa classes he would cut after the shadow home affairs minister suggested "unsustainable" immigration was making Australians "feel like strangers in our own home".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13e71a456d250f5a995b477b981c4622</guid></item><item><title>Hastie downplays 'mischievous' leadership speculation – as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/federal-politics-live-sept-25/105812720</link><description>Liberal frontbencher Andrew Hastie brushes off suggestions he is a threat to Sussan Ley's leadership after a series of outspoken social media posts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a1855533ef7e4ee2263abc39c01aed0</guid></item><item><title>AFL super fans prepare for the grand final clash between Geelong and Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/afl-football-fans-brisbane-lions-geelong-cats-2025-premiership/105812254</link><description>From a unique tattoo to a personalised burger, the AFL grand final is more than just a game for these super fans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85ea949cc04c0beee30263008e182e01</guid></item><item><title>Will food prices ever come down? Don't bet on it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/will-food-grocery-prices-ever-come-down/105811296</link><description>While recent cuts to interest rates may have given mortgage holders a bit of a financial breathing space, the cost of food continues to creep upwards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fce87e998f0daf4d07d83c36c6038f70</guid></item><item><title>Free speech pathologist sessions turning poor literacy rates around in Logan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/qld-logan-children-literacy-boost-free-speech-pathologist/105809794</link><description>A federal government backed weekly reading session led by experts is helping improve literacy rates in Queensland children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6f3a9ca2aa561db64986a266e4fcdcd</guid></item><item><title>Independent review launched into fire ant eradication program amid 'closing window of opportunity'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/fire-ant-eradication-program-review-launched/105811790</link><description>Authorities launch an independent review of Australia's national fire ant eradication program to evaluate the country's fight against one of the world’s most destructive pests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c444298e462f9192611f3572f0c28de3</guid></item><item><title>Families demand inquiry into NSW Police handling of missing persons cases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/families-of-missing-persons-call-for-probe-into-police/105693338</link><description>Nikii Smith is one of 10,000 people who signed a petition calling for a NSW inquiry into the handling of missing persons cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86bd1e4db1094cebb0f4277ff0ad4c3b</guid></item><item><title>China retains narrow edge over US as South-East Asia's most influential partner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/china-us-influence-south-east-asia/105812866</link><description>New research shows that China retains a very narrow edge over the United States as South-East Asia's most influential partner, with experts predicting it will soon pull further ahead as the Trump administration's policies begin to bite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7b10409c8753c731ed70c5ed5ed7bea</guid></item><item><title>Solar, batteries and the 'phone charger dilemma': How a standards gap threatens clean tech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/smart-tech-benefits-at-risk-over-lack-of-common-standard/105808798</link><description>In the same way Apple and Samsung used different phone chargers, many clean tech products are not compatible with others. Experts say it is a big problem for the energy transition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84ec00dd3b63db045677af76a0c64880</guid></item><item><title>Family calls for change amid frustration at seven-year coronial inquest wait</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/anger-at-seven-year-coronial-inquest-wait/105805234</link><description>Robert Hall was killed when he was struck by partially blind driver John Charles Robertson on the Horrocks Highway in 2018. It has been a long wait for the family ahead of the release of coronial findings into his death next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dedbef63ba8aa61b8045e0d358939858</guid></item><item><title>Rodeo attendees told to practise safe sex as STIs continue to rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sti-cases-continue-to-rise-indigenous-overrepresented-in-data/105809704</link><description>Health providers in outback Queensland are taking a light-hearted approach to promoting safe sex, as new data shows sexually transmitted infections are on the rise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a991448f6d24b7d59719d012fdc3e584</guid></item><item><title>Elevated E. coli levels recorded at major NT crocodile farm owned by luxury label Hermès</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/lambells-lagoon-crocodile-farm-nt-high-e-coli-levels-in-water/105806340</link><description>One of Australia's largest crocodile farms, owned by a subsidiary of luxury label Hermès, is consistently irrigating with water containing E. coli concentrations almost 500 times the national guidelines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcebaaf92f52cb686dddde475db8c67b</guid></item><item><title>Police launch fresh search of WA outback over Ray and Jennie Kehlet cold case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/wa-police-search-sandstone-kehlet-cold-case/105813086</link><description>Detectives are this week revisiting the site in WA's outback where the body of prospector Ray Kehlet was found. His wife Jennie is still missing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eda36c180ee83ef793f5a6e386ed8ef6</guid></item><item><title>Former AFL boss Andrew Demetriou insists league would embrace a gay men's player</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/andrew-demetriou-says-afl-a-safe-space-for-gay-players/105813820</link><description>Former AFL boss Andrew Demetriou says the public would embrace a gay men's player and rejects that the AFL is an unsafe environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d77a4e9f1c05a3808354f694994d6ee</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous teen speaks out against heckling of Welcome to Country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/indigenous-writes-essay-against-heckling-welcome-to-country/105808140</link><description>An Indigenous high school student's essay on the Anzac Day heckling of an Indigenous elder by far-right supremacists has earned her a nationally recognised award.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d0978c16ddeb79e39b966dd2e565459</guid></item><item><title>Magnitude-4.1 earthquake rattles Tasmania from Maydena to Hobart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/tasmania-rattled-with-magnitude-4-1-earthquake/105814558</link><description>Tasmania records a magnitude-4.1 earthquake in the state's south-west that was felt from Maydena to Hobart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84775edf57cd76c9bc0ca385f3b919d5</guid></item><item><title>Who is Samoa's new prime minister, Laaulialemalietoa Polataivao Fosi Schmidt?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/new-samoa-prime-minister-election/105789496</link><description>Supporters are fervent in their enthusiasm for Samoa's new prime minister, but voters who are more sceptical of Laaulialemalietoa Polataivao Fosi Schmidt, question his motives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">625c6497fc8280a6929fa5f29c6e97f3</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of new dust-related lung disease cases recorded in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/new-cases-deadly-lung-disease-recorded-in-queensland/105800886</link><description>Nearly 300 workers from mines and work sites have had cases of lung cancer, black lung and other illnesses recorded by the state's dust disease register in the space of 12 months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2884483a655c30376f0362816224a66</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final sprint won't feature all teams, as Gout Gout and Harry Garside to feature at the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/afl-grand-final-sprint-gout-gout-and-harry-garside/105814536</link><description>The AFL announces that only seven AFL players will run in the traditional grand final sprint, with Olympic boxer Harry Garside also joining in.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90c0207e2a6dabd51c17d24fbfdde78c</guid></item><item><title>Macquarie to repay Shield investors after super platform failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/macquarie-admits-to-shield-contraventions/105814728</link><description>Macquarie commits to repaying thousands of Australians who invested hundreds of millions of their retirement savings in the collapsed Shield Master Fund amid admissions it contravened the Corporations Act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6ef3dcad386254cfbd1a1063f29bbf1</guid></item><item><title>China's President Xi Jinping announces new climate goal to cut emissions by 2035</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/china-plans-carbon-emissions-cut-by-2035/105814492</link><description>Outlining China's new carbon targets in a video link to the UN climate conference in New York, President Xi Jinping says "green and low carbon transition is the trend of our time".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f28b3d1c00395f4695e9369d6c444f2</guid></item><item><title>Katanning drivers fear the worst as untagged livestock roam roads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/katanning-farmers-fed-up-with-livestock-wandering-rural-roads/105753144</link><description>A Katanning school bus driver and local farmers are calling for urgent action to address a growing danger posed by wandering livestock on rural roads.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13a15cf930e91758bba06110e305613a</guid></item><item><title>Nottingham Forest draws 2-2 with Real Betis in opening UEFA Europa League match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nottingham-forest-draws-with-real-betis-europa-league/105814730</link><description>Nottingham Forest's long-awaited return to European competition ends 2-2 at Real Betis, with Igor Jesus's first-half double cancelling out by a late Antony strike.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7da92da66bbef30024c541232032313</guid></item><item><title>ARIA Award nominations 2025: Ninajirachi, Dom Dolla, Amyl &amp; The Sniffers lead the pack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/aria-award-nominations-2025-aria-nominees-full-list/105815074</link><description>All the contenders are hopefuls vying for ARIA Awards glory at the music industry's glitzy ceremony, taking place next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">959594b1e7f091dd3de19e45dc3888ab</guid></item><item><title>Peter Tonagh to replace Catherine West as Nine's chair</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/peter-tonagh-to-become-chair-of-nine/105814974</link><description>He replaces Catherine West, who spent 18 months in the position.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2a5f2c444b61e900f222e4b49c5f0b5</guid></item><item><title>New stats reveal highest number of criminal incidents in Victoria since records began</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/victoria-crime-statistics-agency-new-stats-highest-number/105814382</link><description>The latest figures from Victoria's Crime Statistics Agency show the highest number of criminal incidents in at least two decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">500fef92cd2f6d069d1fe5f61f29fcd2</guid></item><item><title>Andrea James to lead Ilbijerri Theatre Company as artistic director Rachael Maza steps back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/ilbijerri-theatre-company-artistic-director-andrea-james/105806022</link><description>Andrea James will take the helm of Australia's oldest Indigenous theatre company Ilbijerri, as outgoing artistic director Rachael Maza steps back after almost 18 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4a3dbe4751b97f43dde74a8c6965376</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with multiple offences over pursuit, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/vale-park-man-arrested-over-alleged-dv-incident/105815044</link><description>South Australia Police says a Vale Park man has been charged following a pursuit that led STAR group officers and police negotiators to a unit in Adelaide's western suburbs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55d31264009557887152139ca68f0250</guid></item><item><title>Liberal candidate Gisele Kapterian abandons court challenge for Sydney seat of Bradfield</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/liberal-gisele-kapterian-abandons-bradfield-court-challenge/105815662</link><description>Gisele Kapterian abandons her court action challenging the election result in the federal Sydney seat of Bradfield.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72e919021e6b203c2c61364023ef65cb</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese addresses UN on climate goals, Gaza and Australia's security council bid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/albanese-united-nations-general-assembly-speech/105815200</link><description>The prime minister uses his UN speech to talk up Australia's emissions plan after Donald Trump called climate change a "con job", and confirms Australia is still seeking a temporary seat on the body's security council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a232f435066d64bce12998bbb55c68d5</guid></item><item><title>Nicho Hynes shrugs off personal barbs ahead of NRL preliminary final between Melbourne and Cronulla</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nicho-hynes-cronulla-sharks-nrl-preliminary-final/105815774</link><description>Accused by some of being too nice and not nice enough by others, polarising Cronulla star Nicho Hynes "doesn't give a rats" about criticism that comes his way anymore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab3262fd8438997bf3566bc3f3afd340</guid></item><item><title>New head of Queensland's troubled DNA lab says backlog of testing could take years to clear</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/queensland-dna-lab-forensic-lab-mick-fuller-investigation/105815548</link><description>More than 170 rape kits caught up in the Forensic Science Queensland laboratory's backlog will be sent offshore next week for vital forensic testing, as the facility's new boss says it will take years to clear them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f10104713dca5809a4ee3120e1d5a35</guid></item><item><title>Postal voting issues identified ahead of 2025 WA local government elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/postal-voting-problems-for-2025-local-government-election/105815250</link><description>Incorrect ballot papers are among several problems identified with postal voting packages sent out ahead next month's local government elections in WA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4995a33060a008be1386f30e6e5a7afe</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian MPs to receive $30,000 pay rise against government's wishes after upper house tussle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/tasmanian-politicians-pay-to-rise-despite-gov-wishes/105816164</link><description>Tasmanian politicians will receive a 22 per cent pay rise despite the government's attempts to block it, after upper house MPs voted to accept a determination by Tasmania's Industrial Commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">760f80a393afa047ecf95a03ee9dfac5</guid></item><item><title>Scott Selwood takes break from AFL after 'personally challenging year'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/scott-selwood-steps-away-afl-collingwood/105815996</link><description>Scott Selwood will take time away from football, stepping down as an assistant coach with Collingwood, following a year marked by personal tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41d251b3ccf71ca56edd70b60deeeab9</guid></item><item><title>AI image recognition technology used to detect traffic offences raises privacy concerns, Queensland audit finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/ai-image-technology-phone-speeding-offences-privacy-audit-qld/105815134</link><description>Queensland's transport department uses AI in its cameras to detect mobile and seatbelt offences, but a new audit has ordered called for a review into how that's done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11d46c909160642ceb7265e8809e201c</guid></item><item><title>Breastfeeding in public is protected in Australia. So why are mothers still facing discrimination?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/why-are-we-still-asking-mothers-to-hide-breastfeeding/105789046</link><description>Last week a breastfeeding mother was asked to leave a Virgin Australia lounge for pumping. Experts says while there is a level of awareness that breastfeeding in public is protected, some people in the community still view it as "inappropriate".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5341713f4b5168cc3ed1630a81ef91c6</guid></item><item><title>What are Australia's chances of returning to the UN Security Council?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/australia-renews-un-security-council-bid/105816596</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese makes a fresh push for Australia to get a seat on the United Nations Security Council in 2029-30.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12bbee71870039ed7798c50667d1fea5</guid></item><item><title>Snoop Dogg says AFL grand final is 'a way of life' ahead of headline show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/snoop-dogg-afl-grand-final/105816718</link><description>Snoop Dogg has strutted into the MCG for his official appearance ahead of a fascinating, somewhat controversial, AFL grand-final entertainment set.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b66d08f7f421a2cabf591d770048f0f</guid></item><item><title>Denmark PM apologises to indigenous Greenlanders who faced forced contraception</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/denmark-pm-apologises-to-greenland-over-contraception/105816090</link><description>The apology by Mette Frederiksen in Greenland’s capital, Nuuk, hopes to close a traumatic chapter in Greenland's history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10e2f68d02a379a76e33cb0667531d03</guid></item><item><title>Forestry industry says it can meet demand for biofuels as climate targets near</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/forestry-wood-waste-into-biofuel-ships-planes-climate-targets/105806578</link><description>With biofuels earmarked as a way to power the transport sector in the future, one industry says its waste can be converted into aviation and shipping fuel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c43fb3bd94bcaa6f5b6b2cc07bb8ea3a</guid></item><item><title>Perth grandmother Donna Nelson loses appeal over Japan drug smuggling conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/donna-nelson-loses-japan-drug-smuggling-appeal/105804346</link><description>Convicted drug smuggler and Perth grandmother, Donna Nelson, loses her appeal against her conviction for smuggling two kilograms of methamphetamine into Tokyo Airport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47b528f98203d1300e8e1b40978bdddc</guid></item><item><title>Trio of space weather satellites launched to study the Sun's violent side</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nasa-launch-three-spacecraft-sun/105815108</link><description>NASA successfully launches multiple satellites designed to get a better understanding of the Sun's influence on Earth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59a16bd185eeee6f5d85c73a75953dbf</guid></item><item><title>TGA approves new brain stimulation device for treatment of depression</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/brain-stimulator-device-approved-for-treatment-of-depression/105816064</link><description>Some international users of Flow Neuroscience's device have labelled the wearable tech as a game-changer in treating depression, but not everyone is convinced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d613860a63e9e5d904cc9b6ac0bd749</guid></item><item><title>Key takeaways from day two at the UN General Assembly's world leaders week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/united-nations-general-assembly-day-two-takeaways/105814272</link><description>The world's most powerful people are meeting in New York this week. Here are the key takeaways from the UN summit's second day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddb580a737f4f04170f65ae765ac9dd6</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies vs All Blacks Bledisloe Cup: Team lists, what time is kick-off? How can I watch?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/wallabies-vs-all-blacks-bledisloe-cup-team-lists/105814670</link><description>Wallabies prop James Slipper will notch an important milestone against New Zealand on Saturday, while James O'Connor will start at fly half.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03e6a514a7b10816017fc77c6d1b0aaa</guid></item><item><title>South Australia passes laws to protect victims of personal injury from 'claim farmers'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sa-claim-farming-laws-pass-parlia/105816232</link><description>Individuals who contact a survivor of abuse or personal injury without their permission to encourage them to make a claim for compensation could face fines of up to $50,000 under new laws which have passed in South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70085da5c5bdc719bc2ab735b7ccda09</guid></item><item><title>Ahead of the biggest game of his NRL career, Nicho Hynes returns to where it all began</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/storm-sharks-nicho-hynes-nrl-preliminary-finals/105816184</link><description>Ten years to the day since his first moment in the spotlight, Nicho Hynes returns to AAMI Park for the most important game of his NRL career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ba9e5f21df0896a8a84e51f1a77817b</guid></item><item><title>SA government grapples with whether it should issue daily bloom updates during summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/algal-bloom-persists-on-adelaide-metropolitan-beaches/105815614</link><description>South Australia's Premier says the government is grappling with whether it should give daily updates on the bloom's location during summer, and says it has been "actively engaged" in conversations with the federal government since its emergence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58acb5d5694220c60122ae3f346438b9</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters race to set hazard reduction burns across Greater Sydney ahead of fire season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/firefighters-race-to-set-hazard-reduction-burns-across-sydney/105801784</link><description>Sydney's wettest August on record has dampened efforts by fire authorities to meet hazard reduction burn targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c594b646d35e85e315447033ddb7a1b</guid></item><item><title>Liberal veteran Amanda Vanstone chides Andrew Hastie for not being a team player, warns of runaway ego</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/andrew-hastie-warned-of-division-amanda-vanstone/105817288</link><description>A doyenne of the Liberal Party and veteran of leadership battles dating back to the 1980s Howard–Peacock era has chided Andrew Hastie for not being a team player.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7155a17bde099fcac4270569e823ea49</guid></item><item><title>Matildas strike force could benefit from having both Sam Kerr and Michelle Heyman firing fit up front</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/matildas-could-have-sam-kerr-and-michelle-heyman/105817900</link><description>A fit-again Sam Kerr doesn't necessarily spell the end for Michelle Heyman's time in the Matildas, if anything the A-League star can't wait for her return.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c878d14058b221a67d55c4c8bdc80e94</guid></item><item><title>SA Water fined $60k for causing 'environmental harm' during botched maintenance of Warren Reservoir</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sa-water-fined-after-botched-maintenace-warren-reservoir/105817688</link><description>SA Water — which is owned by the SA government — has been fined for polluting the waterways with grey clay silt when draining the Warren Reservoir, in the Barossa Valley, in May 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fba0457dd1912373941155d18bca081c</guid></item><item><title>Lachie Neale and Rhys Stanley named in AFL grand final teams as Jarrod Berry fails to recover from shoulder injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/afl-grand-final-geelong-brisbane-lions-team-selections-live-blog/105812378</link><description>Brisbane's co-captain returns just weeks after doctors gave him as little as a five per cent chance of featuring in his third straight grand final as Geelong welcomes back a familiar face to take the place of Tom Stewart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd6e232727e7d0a979b313cd8bef11d5</guid></item><item><title>Measles case detected in Brisbane, prompting calls for vaccination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/measles-brisbane-qld-health-alert-disease-infection/105817886</link><description>Queensland's health department says the person was believed to have contracted the virus in Bali, before visiting a number of businesses across Brisbane and the Sunshine Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69d52cc929c6deec63f591815c89b60a</guid></item><item><title>Gympie Regional Council votes to remove fluoride from town's water supply</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/gympie-removes-fluoride-water-supply-dental-health-fears/105814678</link><description>Gympie scraps fluoride from its water supply and becomes the third region in Queensland to reject the practice in just over a year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9960f09af437f02819e5359d8481878</guid></item><item><title>Coroner finds Monash Health provided unreasonable care before toddler Dio Kemp's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/coroner-finding-into-death-of-dio-kemp/105816186</link><description>Three-year-old Dio Kemp was taken to Monash Medical Centre four times over 10 days before she died of sepsis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37b865829bea191edfe0af886035c9e4</guid></item><item><title>Mass puffer fish deaths and red-bell jellyfish bloom put Pilbara coast on alert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/pilbara-coast-alert-jellyfish-bloom-toxic-puffer-fish-deaths/105815554</link><description>Hundreds of dead puffer fish are found on a Pilbara beach, as an epic red-bell jellyfish bloom prompts a warning from the region's ports authority.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39c787a5232b58cd251e6bebea3ae077</guid></item><item><title>All the latest finance news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/all-the-latest-finance-news/105818574</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">024e11ae51d50a5a396284951c067a9d</guid></item><item><title>Fourth NZYQ member issued Nauruan visa as Labor steams ahead with deportation plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/fourth-nauruan-visa-issued-to-nzyq/105817222</link><description>The former detainee was returned to immigration detention on Thursday and could be the first person transferred under the multi-billion-dollar deal inked with Nauru earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad0acd68e16e51eb3bff42b299e11dc0</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy says he will step down as president after Ukraine war ends</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/zelenskyy-to-leave-office-after-war/105818790</link><description>Ukraine's president has been in office since 2019, with elections slated for last year suspended by martial law as a result of Russia's ongoing invasion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">473d9a464ce1fda89fe9d2c223665ebf</guid></item><item><title>Sean 'Diddy' Combs seeks to appeal to prostitution conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/sean-combs-returns-to-court/105819070</link><description>The former hip-hop mogul was found guilty by a jury on prostitution charges but cleared him of the more serious counts of sex trafficking and racketeering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">939980e64084cf527632d2ce32f228d4</guid></item><item><title>Out-of-pocket costs, eroding trust contributing to decline in childhood vaccination rates, new report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/research-urges-action-on-declining-childhood-vaccination-rates/105815232</link><description>A new report finds out-of-pocket costs and eroding trust are contributing to a "concerning" decline in childhood vaccination rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfdd1a56127bc667f2e5ffab313e2712</guid></item><item><title>China's 'soft' 2035 climate target frustrates experts amid rapid renewable growth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/chinas-new-climate-target-is-both-historic-and-inadequate/105814784</link><description>China baffles climate experts by setting the bar low with its 2035 emissions reduction target amid speculation the renewables superpower will most likely exceed its ambitions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9faa430fbc4d58914719cd9df045ca3</guid></item><item><title>China aid and investment returns to Solomon Islands's Malaita province after ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/china-aid-solomon-islands-malaita-road-development/105789780</link><description>The Solomon Islands's province of Malaita made global headlines five years ago when it banned Chinese investment. But today, a new China-funded road project is on the way — and the people are all for it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aef86fbb6ca57b72f9ef6089dc9580e9</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners slam state premiers for 'disgraceful' call to push ahead with Santos gas project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/peter-malinauskas-under-fire-over-santos-gas-project-gomeroi/105817448</link><description>The debate over Santos's Narrabri gas project reignites, with traditional owners condemning 'disgraceful' comments made by two state premiers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ff7b86ab36f41d01a1fc6371f793a89</guid></item><item><title>Imported potatoes threaten Tasmanian growers, as companies look for cost savings overseas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/imported-potatoes-price-cuts-threaten-australian-potato-industry/105815458</link><description>Cheap potato imports from India and China are threatening the livelihoods of Tasmanian growers, as stalled negotiations with potato giant Simplot leave some farmers about to plant this year's crop without a contract.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddc6d456a4e47433bae32855e5b52bae</guid></item><item><title>2025 AFL season quiz: Twenty questions before the AFL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/afl-2025-season-quiz/105806256</link><description>There are just four quarters of footy left in the 2025 men's AFL season, so now is as good a time as any to see how much you remember about the year just gone with our quiz.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63ca7ae077d47b2b6fd2fe7c3941c026</guid></item><item><title>As the government rejects Trump's UNGA rhetoric, Liberal leadership aspirant Andrew Hastie sounds decidedly Trumpian</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/michelle-grattan-analysis-andrew-hastie-sounds-trumpian/105818330</link><description>As the government rejects Trump's UNGA rhetoric, Liberal leadership aspirant Andrew Hastie sounds decidedly Trumpian.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49c96c4dc166bae257c09eb46d443893</guid></item><item><title>Police search for alleged Porepunkah gunman Dezi Freeman hits one-month mark</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/porepunkah-gunman-dezi-freeman-shooting-latest/105806284</link><description>A month into the high country search for alleged Porepunkah gunman Dezi Freeman, a former detective says Victoria Police can not realistically expect to continue the manhunt indefinitely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">232d07227b15324a710ddc69e78d015c</guid></item><item><title>AFL popularity growth fuels calls to move the Barassi Line separating codes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/barassi-line-rugby-league-aussie-rules-tathra/105782938</link><description>Initially laughed off, these pioneers from Victoria were determined to challenge Australia's sporting status quo, and their legacy continues today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">853354932de7c66115ea465660b6ef08</guid></item><item><title>Sudden 30C temperature rise over Antarctica upends Australia's spring outlook</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/weather-pattern-could-disrupt-australia-for-months/105817572</link><description>Temperatures above Antarctica have risen by 30C, in a rare event that could potentially flip Australia's spring weather for months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c3c265c0efd53b23c81e306c0bfbd10</guid></item><item><title>Southern rock lobster prices finally bounce back amid demand from China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/aussie-rock-lobster-prices-strong-china-demand-sa/105815982</link><description>After years of export trade disruptions, southern Australian rock lobster commercial fishers are hauling in catches that will fetch up to $125 per kilogram.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4f3eb64091cd22b844cb02f1d763fbf</guid></item><item><title>Albanese-Trump meeting not linked to AUKUS review: Marles — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/federal-politics-live-blog-september-26/105819440</link><description>Anthony Albanese's planned meeting with the US president has "absolutely" no link to the expected finalisation of the Trump administration's review into the AUKUS security pact, Richard Marles says. Take a look back at the day's coverage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c8cce790d919b71b1ce3d3a34da8678</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian Authority president thanks Australia, but points to decades of failure, in UN address</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/united-nations-palestinian-authority-mahmoud-abbas-speech/105819446</link><description>Mahmoud Abbas addresses the UN by video after the US refuses him a visa, as Donald Trump vows he will "not allow" Israel to annex the West Bank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25b349c3dbf1286a48e6bc697929c1ae</guid></item><item><title>FBI finds notes by ICE shooter saying he wanted to target agents, not detainees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/ice-shooter-wanted-to-target-agents-not-detainees-fbi-says/105819378</link><description>The FBI has searched the home of the man who opened fired on an Immigration and Customs Enforcement facility in Texas, finding notes that say he was acting alone and intended to target agents, not detainees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3796b636d369ed92c9beb50a3697283</guid></item><item><title>ASX closes up, Singtel boss flown in to meet Australian government over triple-0 failure — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/asx-markets-business-live-news-26-sept-2025/105819610</link><description>Singtel confirms its CEO will join the Optus chair and CEO in meeting the communications minister as the triple-0 fallout rumbles on. Meanwhile, despite a poor opening, the ASX regains ground to finish the week higher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4be65eb1cbcd8e56b4e7411bef244b6b</guid></item><item><title>Robert Carlyle on the hacking scandal that brought down a Murdoch paper</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/uk-phone-hacking-scandal-robert-carlyle-the-hack/105810728</link><description>Robert Carlyle plays an integral role in The Hack, co-starring David Tennant, which digs deep into the News of the World phone-hacking scandal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a90e196287202fbd21af9cda9ac6774</guid></item><item><title>Former Arsenal-contracted player Billy Vigar dies aged 21 after sustaining brain injury during a game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/billy-vigar-dies-at-21-after-head-injury-in-soccer-match/105819594</link><description>Tributes flow for Billy Vigar, after the former Arsenal-contracted player dies from a brain injury sustained during a match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c247b6a9b1480f06a4e319acbb2b00a8</guid></item><item><title>Bondi's Sculpture by the Sea offered $200,000 lifeline after financial woes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/bondi-sculpture-by-the-sea-to-go-ahead-2025-due-to-lifeline/105819510</link><description>Sculpture by the Sea was facing cancellation with organisers forced to make an urgent public plea for last-minute funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6b9cfa8185df988b1552b57c5404e42</guid></item><item><title>Police say fire at Cheltenham factory deliberately lit by unknown arsonists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/luxury-car-dealer-fire-cheltenham/105819546</link><description>Police say a fire that consumed a factory in Cheltenham and damaged dozens of cars was deliberately lit by arsonists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a1fb293eaec8ac7a8f50c8d7dd8625f</guid></item><item><title>WA government accused of treating Port Hedland's water supply like 'lolly shop'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/port-hedland-residents-lash-water-corporation-bungle/105812946</link><description>An Indigenous elder says the rapid depletion of Port Hedland's groundwater stores has been evident for decades, but the government has prioritised mining interests over people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dba911c331c3d40c04227fbc691550d3</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong and southern China reopen after powerful Typhoon Ragasa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/hong-kong-southern-china-reopens-after-typhoon-ragasa/105819590</link><description>Hong Kong and cities in China's Guangdong province have reopened businesses and schools after the world's most powerful tropical cyclone this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10090b8e1d20790341deb6dcd5bc8e3f</guid></item><item><title>Well-known Adelaide tailor Joseph Uzumcu fined for smoking outside CBD shop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/joseph-uzumcu-adelaide-tailor-fined-smoking/105818722</link><description>A well-known Adelaide tailor has been issued a fine by the Adelaide Magistrates Court for smoking outside his CBD business to cope with stress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dd54fb0496462acf91c278ecc303fb5</guid></item><item><title>Hiker with motor neurone disease takes on WA's 1,000km Bibbulmun Track</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/mullumbimby-motor-neurone-disease-hiker-walks-bibbulmun-track-wa/105810642</link><description>One week into her 1,000-kilometre trek of WA's Bibbulmun Track, 70-year-old Catherine Perversi says "the stillness is sublime" — and she would not be anywhere else.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">562a1176a7305ccb5b4ebc35f0433aaa</guid></item><item><title>Barassi line divide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/barassi-line-divide/105819476</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0fefd96a6df7559e212c7c8d875ab3d</guid></item><item><title>Foster carer shortage in WA's Kimberley forces children away from country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/foster-carer-shortage-in-kimberley-forcing-kids-off-country/105815878</link><description>A shortage of foster carers in regional WA is pushing vulnerable children, especially First Nations kids, thousands of kilometres from their families, culture and country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ce81c66ef721335c43f5ba3654f32c4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump imposes 100 per cent tariffs on branded pharmaceuticals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/trump-100pc-tariff-on-drugs-us-politics-/105820198</link><description>The United States will impose a 100 per cent tariff on imports of branded or patented pharmaceutical products from October 1, unless a pharmaceutical company is building a manufacturing plant in the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">739af64d542d4f460697eb9a7951741d</guid></item><item><title>Freight train derails after collision with sheep truck at Bribbaree</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/freight-train-derails-after-collision-with-sheep-truck-bribbaree/105820076</link><description>A freight train derails following a crash with a truck carrying livestock in central-west New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fa1de29d55673a44a56301cdea1ea8b</guid></item><item><title>Scientist wins peace prize for farmer-managed natural regeneration work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/tony-rinaudo-wins-luxembourg-peace-prize-regenerative-farming/105666674</link><description>A Victorian scientist whose farming technique has revolutionised agriculture in Niger is awarded an international peace prize.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdd4d1ecb9ea1ba749bbf16d1448e605</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle Ocean Baths the setting for new headphone theatre production, Meet Me at the Baths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/meet-me-at-the-baths-ang-collins-newcastle-new-annual-festival/105809954</link><description>A new headphone theatre production is set among the swimmers and sunbakers at a NSW city's much-loved ocean pool.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27e003348ea3b7a57ee535f59076db94</guid></item><item><title>Health minister concedes tobacco black market has 'exploded'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/health-minister-concedes-tobacco-black-market-has-exploded/105820002</link><description>Health Minister Mark Butler admits black market tobacco is now the single biggest threat to public health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05884e55b2091e93d320e424fb5838c7</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final preview — how Geelong's unpredictable set up and late term heroics have set them up for a flag</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/afl-grand-final-preview-2025-geelong-profile-against-brisbane/105819810</link><description>From an innovative ruck set up to an uncanny ability to play out the quarter, the perennially competitive Cats are knocking on the door of another flag.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b332a9a8fd34aa68b5306baa1efb2624</guid></item><item><title>Branxholme Wallacedale Saints focus on club culture to become family-friendly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/branxholme-wallacedale-saints-focus-on-club-culture/105754946</link><description>The Branxholme Wallacedale Saints have worked tirelessly to improve their once-troubled reputation so families and their kids want to play there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afd5403e205bf7f3bbba6c2b15b64b0a</guid></item><item><title>Branxholme Wallacedale Saints under 11s celebrate a win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/branxholme-wallacedale-saints-under-11s-celebrate/105812870</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d1e354fadc4bffdd99339a039272e54</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane hellbent on ending horror NRLW finals run ahead of preliminary final clash with Newcastle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/nrlw-finals-broncos-knights-brigginshaw-upton/105820672</link><description>The Broncos have been almost untouchable through the 2025 NRLW season but the club's poor finals record in recent years means they can not afford to get ahead of themselves leading into this week's preliminary final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d248af9a48662ba232728304794119fd</guid></item><item><title>Australian doctors become unofficial correspondents from hospital in Gaza City</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/australian-doctors-al-shifa-gaza-hospital/105813828</link><description>In a ruined hospital and with little medication, two Australian doctors say the situation inside Gaza City is a "nightmare".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfe47390104719cccc9dafc8afd130a0</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final preview — how corridor control and the hard ball can lead Brisbane to back-to-back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/afl-grand-final-preview-lions-look-for-back-to-back/105820830</link><description>They've had to deal with adversity all year, but the Lions are one step away from historic back-to-back flags — here's how they can do it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39ffbe3a1c41d9fda76aa7ad5e261837</guid></item><item><title>Passionate Geelong and Brisbane fans cheer on their premiership teams at grand final eve parade at MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/afl-grand-final-parade/105819962</link><description>Thousands of Brisbane and Geelong fans have lined the streets around the MCG ahead of the 2025 AFL grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78b691131980abbf2add6ad0883fb91f</guid></item><item><title>Police legal challenge against Aboriginal death in custody inquest fails</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/police-legal-challenge-aboriginal-death-in-custody-inquest-fails/105820812</link><description>A coronial inquest into the death of an Aboriginal woman in custody will be free to assess police actions, after a legal challenge by police was dismissed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3674b51ed40e1a297b85299efa20631</guid></item><item><title>19yo allegedly involved in gang rape granted bail in NSW Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/sydney-teen-accused-gang-rape-granted-bail/105820654</link><description>One of the four co-accused teenagers in an alleged gang rape in Sydney's south-west in December has been granted bail in the NSW Supreme Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63c8a09dc20b71643057a9caa539587c</guid></item><item><title>Even without Trump's tariffs, Australian farmers are losing out on billions of dollars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/non-trade-barriers-trump-australian-farmers/105820528</link><description>Even without Trump's tariffs, Australian farmers and exporters of agricultural produce are already losing out on an estimated $4 billion of annual export trade each year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8da56250820715f66334662c60347158</guid></item><item><title>12yo girl killed in Great Southern road crash as long weekend looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/girl-killed-in-great-southern-highyway-crash-wa/105821522</link><description>The fatal collision occurred hours after police urged motorists to drive cautiously ahead of the long weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ed3a65257132e576f1faa29a826222e</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu minister tells Australia to respect China policing deal, rebukes Pat Conroy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/vanuatu-tells-australia-to-respect-china-policing-deal/105820502</link><description>Vanuatu's internal affairs minister says Australia needs to respect his country's plan to sign a new policing agreement with China, and has taken a swipe at Pacific Minister Pat Conroy as controversy over the proposal rumbles along.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">050f43efa5f6288d7a00530de579d990</guid></item><item><title>Mr Squiggle theme song</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/mr-squiggle-theme-song/105817594</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9fa12b40c81dc64a333a2876b60a81d</guid></item><item><title>Geoff Ayling, composer of some of Australia's most recognised ad jingles, dies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/geoff-ayling-songwriter-dies-famous-ad-jingles/105817238</link><description>The man who wrote the music for many well-known advertising jingles, including Good on You Mum, Tip Top bread and Take Me Away, P&amp;O, is being remembered for his musical skill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b53a6564057672097bb047c151dca62</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged with attempted murder after allegedly stabbing man in Kippa Ring, north of Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/queensland-woman-charged-with-attempted-murder-stabbing/105822044</link><description>Police allege the 24-year-old woman stabbed a man known to her at Kippa Ring, north of Brisbane, in the early hours of Friday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeb3b17c8b2580029205fda509815a17</guid></item><item><title>Why you might consider glass food containers over plastic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/are-glass-containers-better-for-food-storage/105814738</link><description>Compared to plastic containers, glass alternatives can reduce exposure to microplastics when used in the microwave and be easier to clean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62503c861f079a92f249f37bd31d4008</guid></item><item><title>Baby koala rides golden retriever like a racehorse in south-west Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/koala-rides-golden-retriever-like-a-horse-animal-best-friends/105820294</link><description>When Steve Lamplough heard a commotion outside his south-west Victorian home, the last thing he expected to see was a joey koala riding his dog like a racehorse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8f146a530bc61ff11d04f67fce57f11</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste scraps lifetime pensions after student-led protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/timor-leste-scraps-lifetime-pensions-student-protests/105822222</link><description>Timor-Leste votes to cancel the lifetime pension law for MPs and public officials, following student-led demonstrations against lavish perks in one of South-East Asia's poorest countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45a5c26bb186d48e726ba42169e2ac69</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne thrashes Gold Coast as Kangaroos, Blues and Bulldogs claim wins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/aflw-melbourne-hammer-gold-coast/105822324</link><description>Melbourne, with Tyla Hanks and Kate Hore starring, has trounced Gold Coast by 87 points in their AFLW clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">758bff113f0bed1af2a29ef33a1a9d21</guid></item><item><title>Cobblebank stabbing victim, 12-year-old Chol Achiek, farewelled at funeral in Melbourne's west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/cobblebank-stabbing-victim-chol-achiek-farewelled-at-funeral/105821324</link><description>Chol Achiek, one of two boys killed in Cobblebank earlier this month, has been remembered as a loving brother and son who dreamed of a career in basketball and was wise beyond his years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3bbb2794f7824e7f09b9ad421fb9e50</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios talking about Gungahlin tennis facility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/nick-kyrgios-talking-about-gungahlin-tennis/105821914</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df5f0b6edba01b29c768c228e32eacd5</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios spruiks construction of $9.9 million Gungahlin tennis facility in Canberra's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/act-9-million-tennis-facility-construction-begins/105821980</link><description>Construction on a new $9.9 million tennis facility in the Gungahlin has begun five years after the ACT government pledged funding for it ahead of the 2020 territory election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f140dc898fba699bca2f89fcd4262dab</guid></item><item><title>At least three shark deaths linked to algal bloom, investigations show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/sa-shark-deaths-algal-bloom/105820996</link><description>Investigations into nine white shark deaths this year have revealed at least three are likely to have been killed by the toxic algal bloom. Warning: This story contains images that some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79ddca541da983c2087bb440bc5fe637</guid></item><item><title>Six men jailed after police foiled 2.4 tonne cocaine importation operation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/men-jailed-cocaine-importation-shambles/105822590</link><description>Six men involved in a drug importation operation described by the prosecutor as a "comedy of errors" are jailed in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8d0a510c0be4786f4dad60cf83becaa</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm reach NRL grand final with 22-14 win over Cronulla Sharks in preliminary final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/nrl-preliminary-final-live-melbourne-storm-cronulla-sharks/105812604</link><description>Jahrome Hughes leads Melbourne back into the NRL grand final, scoring a try in a 22-14 win over the Cronulla Sharks just 22 days after breaking his arm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75da4fc54a216f86411f3ab5eb5b0821</guid></item><item><title>Jess Fox puts aside shock of surgery to support teammates at home ICF Slalom World Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/jess-fox-surgery-recovery-icf-slalom-world-championships/105821814</link><description>Jess Fox says she's recovering well from her recent surgery, and while she's disappointed to miss her home world championships, she's willing to play the role of 'cheerleader'.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07d5cc11b66a91add389bacd3e14b2f3</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur powers through at China Open, Aleksandar Vukic set for big-name quarterfinal in Japan Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/alex-de-minaur-powers-through-in-china/105823034</link><description>Aussie Alex de Minaur is through to the China Open round of 16 thanks to a crushing straight-sets win over a local wildcard, while in Japan Aleksandar Vukic has recorded a second win to set up a tasty quarterfinal clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">536d835a42b45245a5e4b71e9f9aff13</guid></item><item><title>260 alleged fraudsters from African countries caught in Interpol's romance scam crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/interpol-african-romanc-scam-arrests/105823060</link><description>The scams targeted more than 1,400 victims who lost nearly $US2.8 million ($4.29 million).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c847a1b10d1899b3895a05e53e9be00f</guid></item><item><title>Latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/latest-financial-news/105823140</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a99f716d6cc9d9350073146aa3f0fa84</guid></item><item><title>Top stories from ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/top-stories-from-abc-news/105823366</link><description>Listen to ABC News interviews and commentary and analysis from radio programs like AM, PM and The World Today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f476abec419abb0441221228e9378a7</guid></item><item><title>Benjamin Netanyahu rails against foreign leaders at UN as Donald Trump flags Gaza deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/benjamin-netanyahu-walkout-united-nations-general-assembly/105823442</link><description>Dozens of diplomats stage a walkout at the UN ahead of the Israeli prime minister's speech, as US President Donald Trump says: "I think we have maybe a deal on Gaza."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35d9d0c0a30c9578b7d31b4dcbe35aaf</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese says Aussies are 'concerned' about far right's rise abroad, ahead of Donald Trump meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/anthony-albanese-says-aussies-are-concerned-about-far-right-rise/105819050</link><description>Anthony Albanese warns against the rise of populism and the far right ahead of his in-person meeting with Donald Trump next month, saying governments should "not seek to divide people".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26f76d3a7768af90f019f28385e9129a</guid></item><item><title>Gulf states reevaluate US relationship as Israel replaces Iran as a threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/gulf-states-united-nations-general-assembly-donald-trump/105801292</link><description>The Gulf, along with Israel, will be wondering just how far Donald Trump really is prepared to push Benjamin Netanyahu.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e0e64a2d1db9bd1d64b2ebafe1d2ab8</guid></item><item><title>Australia's climate target doesn't eclipse today's tough questions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/climate-announcement-targets-emissions/105801294</link><description>As a nation, it's as if we're arguing about where to have a family holiday in 2035, and whether we fly economy or business. Meanwhile, nobody can agree on dinner tonight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4146131c7945d7a9befae50175a86f11</guid></item><item><title>How Alliyah's community missed the signs of a female predator</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/female-child-abusers-hidden/105806706</link><description>Gender stereotypes "play a role" in allowing predators like Kellie Whiteside to fly under the radar, but that's not the whole story.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5212f82642c02bf7652806df1582ca0</guid></item><item><title>The drug smuggling case of Japanese tourist Chika Honda and its parallels with Donna Nelson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/chika-honda-1992-drug-smuggling-case-australia-and-donna-nelson/105812710</link><description>A Japanese tourist who served 10 years in an Australian prison for drug smuggling offences sees her story reflected in the case of Australian Donna Nelson, who was sentenced to six years in a Japanese prison for smuggling 2 kilograms of methamphetamine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b06cef5818c953eb5ee9e418eeb4d004</guid></item><item><title>Soldier, Shakespeare die-hard, and the next Liberal leader? Andrew Hastie's week in the headlines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/andrew-hastie-liberal-party-leadership/105822510</link><description>The West Australian veteran has a clear vision for the future of the Liberal Party — and he's making it known.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c9cd9bedbb6ade58671fe793227f3da</guid></item><item><title>Geelong and Brisbane's AFL grand final meeting a clash of 21st-century titans 25 years in the making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-geelong-brisbane-grand-final-21st-century-titans/105817210</link><description>When they meet at the MCG on Saturday afternoon, Geelong and Brisbane are bidding for more than just the 2025 premiership. For the two most dominant clubs of a generation, true greatness is at hand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a8fca4f4487c82e1257eae08d6d9ec0</guid></item><item><title>Indians in Australia continue to face racist abuse one month on from anti-immigration protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/indians-racism-march-for-australia-protests-anti-immigration/105782222</link><description>Nearly a month after anti-immigration protests swept across Australia, some in the Indian diaspora say they are still facing racist abuse and constantly "looking over their shoulder".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50a690450fbc31f7c53d0d4ea03d629f</guid></item><item><title>Swinburne University engineers team with builder to deliver Ballarat's first 3D-printed home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/ballarat-gets-its-first-3d-printed-home-swinburne-university/105805530</link><description>A new 3D-printed home build in Victoria's west is due to be completed in October, with the construction team hoping the technology could be another solution to the housing crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb33cdc03a1044502d724b1fe5827f1b</guid></item><item><title>Epstein files show flight with Prince Andrew and meetings with Elon Musk, Bill Gates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/epstein-files-six-pages-released/105823750</link><description>The documents include flight logs, massage messages and cash transactions in Jeffrey Epstein's ledger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f78ee953397b3a507669a6560c685081</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast venue refuses entry to Māori man due to cultural tattoo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/maori-man-barred-from-gold-coast-venue-over-cultural-tattoo/105803294</link><description>Caleb Pokai says he was banned from entering the Burleigh Pavilion while out dinner with friends due to his tā moko.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36e9bee7980f29d8dd3548676fd7d8db</guid></item><item><title>Sydney student compares his autism to 'limited edition Lego' in uplifting viral speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/sydney-student-leo-speech-on-autism-like-limited-edition-lego/105819812</link><description>Twelve-year-old Leo is the talk of his community thanks to a speech he made for his school's public speaking competition where he opened up about his neurodiversity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acbfc98d682b5458b7c616d84f85cb29</guid></item><item><title>Sydney schoolboy explains his autism and ADHD to peers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/sydney-schoolboy-explains-his-autism-and-adhd-to/105820440</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d120291fa023df6845d40764a23cb49</guid></item><item><title>Medical examiner reveals gunman who blamed NFL for hiding brain injuries had CTE</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/nfl-office-gunman-had-cte-medical-examiner-confirms/105823776</link><description>Medical examiners confirm the gunman who blamed the NFL for hiding brain injuries had CTE, after he left a note asking for his brain to be studied.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c70b44c070314feed97d3fafdb5681c</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with performing Nazi salute at AFL semifinal was former political candidate with history of racist posts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/qld-man-charged-with-performing-nazi-salute-political-candidate/105815900</link><description>An ABC investigation reveals Tylere Baker-Pearce, a former political candidate who has posted a selfie smiling outside Auschwitz, was the man charged with performing a Nazi salute at an AFL game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30e54f094513d67b34962af67d4ac555</guid></item><item><title>The majority of Queensland councils are washing their hands of fluoridation under the watch of both sides of politics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/qld-fluoride-water-supply-tooth-decay-politics-washing-hands/105820504</link><description>Attacks by Queensland Opposition Leader Steven Miles against Premier David Crisafulli over fluoride this week are more than hard to swallow after another local government's decision to stop adding the mineral to its water supply, writes Janelle Miles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3f79307107db030116e62bb5f9c648d</guid></item><item><title>Crocodile industry stakeholders urge Australian government to reform outdated code of practice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/code-of-practice-wild-farmed-australian-crocodiles/105821646</link><description>Thrust back into the international spotlight by the recent trial of Outback Wrangler star Matt Wright, questions are being raised about the Top End's lucrative crocodile industry and its outdated code of practice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5f0239291a3bab11069711c4f720cb3</guid></item><item><title>Best books out in September, from Ian McEwan, Patrick Ryan and Lee Lai</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/best-books-september-ian-mcewan-patrick-ryan-lee-lai/105805520</link><description>Wondering what to read next? This month's best books include the latest from literary giant Ian McEwan and Buckeye, a multigenerational family saga set in America's Midwest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0348b42f488a06fcaa90b607ac100204</guid></item><item><title>Retiring paramedic sounds alarm over plummeting job retention rate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/retiring-paramedic-sounds-alarm-over-low-retention-rate/105805372</link><description>Peter Maxwell and wife Rachel spent a combined 77 years as NSW paramedics, but they might be the last of a generation of lifers, with one in 20 leaving the workforce every year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ceb0b45376909c99278c668ab146956</guid></item><item><title>Persistent algae bloom causing political headaches as scientists are copping the flak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/algae-bloom-political-headaches/105821302</link><description>South Australia's algal bloom continues to cause political headaches for state and federal Labor. Perhaps that's why scientists are copping some of the flak now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4eda47c6abdb95b5e7cb1558c679e6d</guid></item><item><title>Nooramunga Land and Sea buys private islands to save them from development</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/non-profit-buys-bullock-and-little-dog-islands-off-vic-coast/105666678</link><description>For roughly the price of an inner-city apartment, conservationists have bought multiple small islands off the coast of Gippsland to protect their ecosystems and wildlife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c31e60140fdbcc5dfafc1267bf95eb5</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump warns 'there will be others' after James Comey's indictment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/trump-says-there-will-be-others-after-comey/105823804</link><description>Donald Trump expects more indictments to be issued against political figures after the former FBI chief was charged.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52700f3b187e6e4b599041821740bea8</guid></item><item><title>AI can't teach our kids to be curious and think critically</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/ai-revolution-classrooms/105756868</link><description>The AI dystopia might already be here but there are some things only humans can teach our children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a55b864c2b25cccc3569eb1e7b2df7c5</guid></item><item><title>Detailed designs of new lyric theatre inspired by Canberra's natural landmarks revealed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/act-new-lyric-theatres-detailed-designs-revealed/105823106</link><description>Detailed designs show plans for the new 2,000-seat lyric theatre, inspired by Canberra's natural landmarks, which will host major musicals, ballets and operas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32104f4565bc9ee2f42947c31b206b9c</guid></item><item><title>Is it worth moving to Tasmania for the cooler climate?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/moving-tasmania-climate-positives-and-negatives/105815096</link><description>Each of these eight families left the mainland in search of Tasmania's cooler, milder climate. But with challenges like health care, transport and limited services, do they have any regrets over the decision?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe4bcc9ccaae6e62bab1625ddabe94d0</guid></item><item><title>Conservation notice issued for alleged native vegetation clearing at Chittering</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/dwer-issues-notice-over-alleged-native-tree-clearing-chittering/105807210</link><description>Western Australia's environmental regulator has issued a property owner with a vegetation conservation notice for the alleged clearing of a significant amount of native trees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a73ca93c90bcc1f5bb19f601570855d0</guid></item><item><title>What time is the 2025 AFL grand final? Here's how to watch and everything you need to know as Brisbane and Geelong clash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-grand-final-2025-what-time-does-the-game-start/105823862</link><description>Wondering what time the AFL grand final starts and how you can watch it live? We've got you covered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">961b6e51ce3e13209f14691157297bb3</guid></item><item><title>UN officials walk out during Netanyahu's address</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/un-officials-walk-out-during-netanyahus-address/105823876</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a92ef539d01e3e6bacbcefb0871cb81</guid></item><item><title>Wool price soars as production crashes and Chinese demand lifts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/australian-wool-price-three-year-high-as-china-demands-rises/105819768</link><description>Australian wool prices lifted sharply this week for a few reasons, including a shrinking amount of wool being produced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58344a18424792f395eadbda8b6e6d6b</guid></item><item><title>Investigations underway after several Launceston General Hospital staff reported feeling nauseated and faint</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/launceston-general-hospital-incident-staff-reported-feeling-sick/105823900</link><description>Tasmania Police initially said the incident at the Launceston General Hospital was potentially a gas leak, but the Tasmania Fire Service later said it did not detect any gas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4fc62e9e3e20ebfcf52e8625114d8d6</guid></item><item><title>Lachie Neale expected to start as sub for Brisbane against Geelong in the 2025 AFL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-grand-final-2025-lachie-neale-set-to-start-as-sub/105823894</link><description>Brisbane Lions captain Lachie Neale is likely to start as sub in today's grand final as he battles a calf injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91a67c83197e1c6ed6df3a535f58e980</guid></item><item><title>UN sanctions 'unfair, unjust and illegal', says Iran's president</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/iran-says-un-security-council-sanctions-unfair/105823898</link><description>The UN Security Council rejects another last-ditch effort to delay the reimposition of sanctions on Iran over its nuclear program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff1a6a0c02c16e1d84e6b2947a01c58c</guid></item><item><title>Police reveal link between man and woman found dead in New South Wales home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/police-investigate-after-two-bodies-found-in-coffs-harbour/105823928</link><description>Police found the bodies of a man and woman in their 60s when doing a welfare check at a Coffs Harbour property on Friday evening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47e234f9b8ecd79651a27ee1302b040c</guid></item><item><title>The banal, brutal life of traffic police in South West WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/ride-along-with-south-west-road-traffic-police/105820992</link><description>As WA experiences its worst year for road deaths in over a decade, the ABC shadows two traffic officers as they try to stop the number climbing higher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">607dd8386b70fdaac1a7dbd4afc9ea3f</guid></item><item><title>For four years, Yuna and Minu Jo lay in a suitcase in a New Zealand storage unit. Now they have justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/nz-suitcase-deaths-aftermath/105811894</link><description>Minu and Yuna Jo's bodies lay in a storage unit for four years. They finally have justice after their mother was found guilty of their murders seven years after they were killed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c20fa9f4daa00b724ebbc96dbed5d5c6</guid></item><item><title>Gladstone Strollers walking group creates a village for postpartum mums</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/postpartum-mum-walking-group-mental-health-benefits/105820070</link><description>A Queensland mum desperate to have a positive postpartum experience when she had her second child found that just a few small steps were enough to make a huge difference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4aabdb9b02f032a6f0dfa2b02445682e</guid></item><item><title>Trump visit to Ryder Cup not enough to inspire Americans as Europe dominates day one</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/ryder-cup-golf-trump-visit-fails-to-inspire-americans/105823802</link><description>President Donald Trump visits on the opening day of the Ryder Cup, but it's the Europeans who dominate heading into day two.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">971dd8b151a82436219cb0443b384982</guid></item><item><title>WA teenager starts petition for shearing to be in Brisbane 2032 Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/wa-teen-starts-petition-for-shearing-to-be-in-the-olympics/105721670</link><description>We saw break dancing added to the Olympic program for the Paris Games, and now there is a push for shearing to be included for the Brisbane Olympics in 2032.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ce5973b6762c550d39695066a2eff91</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final 2025 Geelong vs Brisbane live updates — Cats and Lions blog, scores and stats from the MCG, Charlie Cameron kicks wonder-goal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-grand-final-2025-geelong-vs-brisbane-live-blog/105822258</link><description>Geelong and Brisbane are fighting it out for the 2025 premiership in the AFL grand final at the MCG. Follow all the action in our live blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14ca0c766669a84c1c64d308b07e389c</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Storm Bualoi sweeps through Philippines leaving 10 dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/tropical-storm-bulaoi-philippines-flood-corruption/105823944</link><description>The death toll from a tropical storm that swept across the central Philippines and southern Luzon has risen to 10, as the country's north continued recovering from Super Typhoon Ragasa.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2df415b803d0ecbfbe0362606b7d507</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's last flying-fox cash dispenser gains Lifeline in Gayndah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/lifeline-for-queenslands-final-flying-fox-cash-dispenser/105789280</link><description>A not-for-profit organisation has created a new era for a heritage-listed shop and its nostalgic flying-fox change dispenser, which is the last remaining in Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43234991c230220980a87add3ea50db7</guid></item><item><title>Fortescue offers measles vaccine boosters after Christmas Creek outbreak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/fortescue-measles-vaccine-boosters-christmas-creek-outbreak/105820426</link><description>Iron-ore giant Fortescue says it will offer vaccine boosters after three measles cases were confirmed at its Pilbara mine earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26e09d8753cc469c42fac166c15b08d3</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government investigating 'bungled IT system' which may have led to child safety information going missing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/qld-government-it-error-child-safety-department/105823978</link><description>Queensland's child safety minister is warning missing information could have serious consequences, including the death of a child.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfd0e5e2f585c511b044243e54e5ff89</guid></item><item><title>Tourist dies at Tasmania's Cradle Mountain National Park after group becomes 'overwhelmed' by extreme weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/cradle-mountain-walker-dies-extreme-weather/105824188</link><description>A group of tourists who were unprepared for the extreme conditions at Cradle Mountain National Park is rescued, but one member of the group dies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c2bacc1d4008463c044ab40ec94a7ab</guid></item><item><title>Cyclist on a gruelling journey to fight for a better future for people with dementia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/nic-tremaine-cycling-around-australia-dementia-fundraising-trip/105730642</link><description>Nicholas Tremaine is cycling more than 40,000 kilometres to raise $1 million to fight the condition that's befallen his mother and is now Australia's leading cause of death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08add1d8f7252bd94b473e9688d5ae02</guid></item><item><title>Painting of Gardening Australia host Costa Georgiadis unveiled at National Portrait Gallery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/act-painting-costa-georgiadis-unveiled-national-portrait-gallery/105823964</link><description>The National Portrait Gallery invited the public to identify a person who was missing from its collection — the winner, chosen from a shortlist of 25 remarkable Australians, was Gardening Australia host Costa Georgiadis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e987ca83d10ea62ee1819cce247f662</guid></item><item><title>Clive Palmer ordered to pay more than $13 million after foreign investor claim dismissed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/clive-palmer-foreign-investor-claim-dismissed/105823966</link><description>The decade-long dispute was related to WA government legislation, which impeded Clive Palmer's ability to extract damages over the Balmoral South Iron Ore Project in the Pilbara.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b97d0fa74d42a0e0aad8a2eb639f05fe</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous teenager teaches Paakantyi language to teachers at Menindee school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/aboriginal-paakantyi-language-teacher-outback-nsw-school/105815440</link><description>Jaz Fusi has been passionate about learning Paakantyi language for most of her life. Now, she teaches it to her local school's teachers and is eager to see other kids do the same.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffc9b2d6c78f4e662e2f96fe4e5bf8a9</guid></item><item><title>Cobblebank stabbing victim, 15-year-old Dau Akueng, farewelled at funeral in Melbourne's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/teen-dau-akueng-farewelled-at-funeral-in-melbourne-north-west/105824068</link><description>More than a thousand mourners gather at a church in Melbourne's north-west to farewell a 15-year-old boy whose life was tragically cut short earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d5649ecaeed96d87e8c78ff75531791</guid></item><item><title>WA government facing $400m cost blowout over Peel Health Campus redevelopment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/peel-health-campus-cost-blowout/105824094</link><description>The long-awaited redevelopment of Peel Health Campus is facing a $400 million cost blowout and potential delays, a leaked document reveals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7295950907094099603d65d0a0b06af</guid></item><item><title>Live updates: All Blacks vs Wallabies, Bledisloe Cup at Eden Park, Auckland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/live-updates-all-blacks-vs-wallabies-bledisloe-cup-in-auckland/105816056</link><description>The All Blacks host the Wallabies in the first Bledisloe Cup match of 2025, with the hosts smarting after a woeful, record defeat against South Africa last time out. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13406db2d00d984b62fdf93c8404b3c6</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters battling boat fire at Hillarys Boat Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/boat-fire-causes-smoke-at-hillarys-boat-harbour/105824336</link><description>Thick plumes of smoke billowed over Hillarys Boat Harbour after a boat was engulfed in flames on Saturday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c37fd3b7ccf8e09b4734682a5e3ffb98</guid></item><item><title>More outdoor live entertainment for NSW after changes to 'outdated' development applications</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/nsw-removes-development-applications-live-outdoor-events/105823902</link><description>Using outdoor public spaces for events and venues has been made easier in NSW under changes to development applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">900baaaf0953e92e8c0b8d4aa1fae752</guid></item><item><title>Relationship experts on the signs that it may be time to call it quits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/signs-it-might-be-time-to-end-a-relationship/105675792</link><description>If you are feeling indifferent about your relationship, have high conflict, or just don't really enjoy their company anymore, it is possible the partnership has reached its end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">499d5b97aa70d0462b93fa23afce5eb8</guid></item></channel></rss>