<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:53:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Kazuaki Ono's photo exhibition Southern Crust melds Australian scenery with our bakery culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/southern-crust-bakery-photography-exhibition/106169972</link><description>Kazuaki Ono wanted to entice people from Japan to visit Australia by showing we have as much to offer with our food culture as we do with our iconic scenery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92d7b7dca9079219e2846df04f166a65</guid></item><item><title>The best documentaries to binge in the weird week after Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/best-docos-to-binge-over-christmas-summer/106022170</link><description>Summer is here and so are those long leisurely days of nothing following Christmas. Here are five documentaries that will help you while away the time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e551aa5c5e8b609e0c5d9d9e10e9bab2</guid></item><item><title>Australia's batting headaches masked again by dismal English failure on wild Ashes Boxing Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/cowardly-english-batting-spares-australia-s-boxing-day-blushes/106180182</link><description>Australia's batting order is unsettled, unbalanced and out of form, but it matters little as England throws in the towel and considers the challenge of a Boxing Day Ashes Test all too hard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">187ff36f0baab20891ef104286fac289</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy plans to meet with Trump as peace plan with Russia inches closer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/volodymyr-zelenskyy-donald-trump-meeting-peace-plan-russia/106180632</link><description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy says he is planning to meet with US President Donald Trump on Sunday to search for ways to end the war with Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c94842f6bc240f2c1f589fba07963d6d</guid></item><item><title>At least 14 injured in a knife and chemical attack at factory in Japan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/at-least-14-injured-in-japan-knife-and-chemical-attack/106180698</link><description>A man has been arrested after stabbing eight people at a factory in the Japanese city of Mishima.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f722fd9947b691159d1707229f25d577</guid></item><item><title>Today in history, December 27: Benazir Bhutto assasinated at election rally by teenage militant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/today-history-december-27-benazir-bhutto-assasination-pakistan/106165790</link><description>During the tense campaign for her third term as prime minister of Pakistan, Benazir Bhutto survived one attempt on her life before she was shot dead by a teenage suicide bomber on December 27, 2007. She helped to build a political dynasty that continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">493a29be57b003ed7d2fcd17f5ab5bf9</guid></item><item><title>ABC 50/50 Megaquiz: This week we're testing your knowledge on Die Hard, pizza and princesses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/abc-50-50-quiz-december-27/106157446</link><description>Every question has only two options: one is right and the other is wrong. You have an even chance of guessing correctly each time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33b6e6f179eac330d4007f957f77b475</guid></item><item><title>A quick guide to the best fabrics and fibres for summer and their sustainability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/what-fibres-and-fabrics-to-wear-in-summer/105981546</link><description>What our clothes are made of can make a big difference when it comes to keeping cool, but not all fabrics are created equal. Here is what to look for — and avoid — during the warmer months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dc31cbc8f4af5932b93e4fb5b030ee6</guid></item><item><title>25 years on, the search continues for stars of the Sydney Olympics' closing ceremony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/sydney-olympics-kewpie-doll-search/106169888</link><description>For Trevor Harvey, honouring a departed mate meant one thing — finding a 6-metre-tall Kewpie doll from the Sydney Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2db87d7aa3f1086c01d0693d98b03505</guid></item><item><title>Sydney to Hobart race crews doing it tough in challenging conditions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/sydney-to-hobart-yacht-race-day-two/106180992</link><description>Crews are battling sea sickness and tough conditions as teams head for the finish in the 2025 Sydney to Hobart yacht race.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0256d5474c3476a9c0ba3461c1ee630d</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal community tension in Victoria's north amid health board division</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/aboriginal-community-tension-mallee-board-division/106170928</link><description>An annual meeting to elect a new board at Mallee District Aboriginal Services has led to divisions among members and incoming board members as the chair announces elections will be re-run.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f068d39e8567f078e563191fa53cb96</guid></item><item><title>When green energy threatens what it is meant to save</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/nelson-wetlands-green-energy-boom-planning-protections/106097868</link><description>In a tiny town near the Victoria–South Australia border, a proposed wind farm near a protected wetland is posing a big question for Australia's planning regulators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cce00efa3282f14d1cb581e60a16068</guid></item><item><title>The best vantage points and everything else you need to know about Sydney's New Year's Eve fireworks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/where-to-watch-the-new-years-eve-fireworks-in-sydney-2025/106175504</link><description>Sydney's New Year's Eve celebrations will this year pay tribute to the victims of the Bondi terror attack, with events to feature a heavy police presence. Here is everything you need to know to plan your night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf93969efada38d9bce589ed6247600b</guid></item><item><title>South Australian playwright pays tribute to late partner in new production</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/anthony-nocera-log-boy-play/106095628</link><description>An upcoming South Australian playwright was writing a horror, comedy show about the prospect of losing a much older partner, then it happened to him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">459b7018fcf05da5cd1894814562d377</guid></item><item><title>Australian medical history – the heart donor who still walks the earth 20 years later</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/qld-domino-transplant-lucinda-simpson-cystic-fibrosis/106127132</link><description>Lucinda is a member of an exclusive club — living heart donors, and is the only woman to have a baby after a heart-lung-liver transplant</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fdc746668c7434580fe039bc48bbe9f</guid></item><item><title>13 long reads to catch up on for your summer holiday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/long-reads-2025-virginia-trioli/106175224</link><description>Here we've gathered a bunch of other things to read while you're relaxing over summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96a03c3f95f56c5d4532a4ecf3388352</guid></item><item><title>Ladybirds set loose at Australian Parliament House in Canberra over summer to take out pests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/ladybugs-released-at-canberra-parliament-house/106160100</link><description>When politicians and most staff are away for the summer holidays, a ravenous group of fly-in workers descend on Parliament House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d0fc288cf443c20ee792420a6420b93</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with string of offences after burglaries that began on Christmas Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/melbourne-christmas-burglaries-arrest-victoria-police/106181074</link><description>A man is arrested following a Melbourne crime spree that allegedly began about 7pm on Christmas Day and ended with burglaries of two restaurants about 6:30am on Boxing Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">586d0a6317c6e08768b05fa34fd680d3</guid></item><item><title>Northern parts of Queensland bracing for heavy rainfall, potential flooding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/queensland-weather-rain-and-flood-weekend-forecast/106180424</link><description>Holiday travellers are being urged to check road closures before setting off on their journey, with parts of the state expecting rain into the middle of next week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72cfc7364a99693d7110bd5756144916</guid></item><item><title>175-year-old Nor' West Bend Station reopened to public after decades of restoration work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/175-year-old-nor-west-bend-station-reopened-to-public/106028646</link><description>History is being brought back to life at a former pastoral station that has seen drought, boom and bust over the course of its 175 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8940f35a06954e50ec7e7c189ecb994a</guid></item><item><title>Somalia, Arab nations denounce Israeli recognition of Somaliland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/somalia-arab-nations-denounce-israeli-recognition-of-somaliland/106181060</link><description>Matters of strategy are behind Israel's drive to recognise Somaliland, analysts say, as Arab nations worry about instability in the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90cd83b662f7981d74e54e2b1206eef6</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar's first election in five years begins – but experts warn it's a sham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/myanmar-first-elections-in-five-years/106180094</link><description>Five years after the military toppled a democratically elected government and imprisoned its leaders, the country is preparing to hold national elections beginning on December 28.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7076d82ea1efed8789a7b4ce43e02d86</guid></item><item><title>Trio of retirees from Dongara win award for community rubbish collection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/dongara-roadside-relics-group-collecting-litter-wins-award/106154988</link><description>Armed with gloves, bags, buckets and tongs, a trio of passionate rubbish removalists have picked up an award in this regional Western Australia town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfadfe96068151ef0ee3f0fa86954cde</guid></item><item><title>Storm Hunter returns for the Australian summer targeting a top doubles ranking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/storm-warning-aussie-wants-to-regain-world-number-one-status/106181154</link><description>Popular Australian Storm Hunter is back from injury and adamant she can return to the form that made her the world's top-ranked doubles player.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd5d5e8783ea370e7a17bcad44a8bacc</guid></item><item><title>Australians are drinking less, but one cohort won't give up the booze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/australians-drinking-less-older-taking-bigger-health-risks/105371018</link><description>Health-conscious Australians may be thinking twice about having that first or second beer, but not all of us are getting the message when it comes to alcohol and risky drinking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fd92f06e70a0c7e12bc8de8191b8249</guid></item><item><title>China hits US defence firms with sanctions over arms sales to Taiwan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/china-sanctions-us-defence-firms-over-arms-sales-taiwan/106181220</link><description>China urged the US to "stop the dangerous moves of arming Taiwan" after its multi-billion-dollar sale of weapons last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33227ba851bab9d9f659aabc61e30a14</guid></item><item><title>How a tsunami in Sri Lanka sparked a push to prevent drowning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/sri-lanka-tsunami-solutions-to-drownings-waterways/106173020</link><description>What began as tsunami relief, has become something more powerful — teaching children not to fear the water that surrounds them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e4eb5c147fe58006ee735956f6a75f7</guid></item><item><title>Thailand and Cambodia agree to ceasefire, ending weeks of clashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/thailand-and-cambodia-agree-to-ceasefire-/106181650</link><description>The ceasefire will take effect on Saturday at noon local time, in a conflict which has displaced more than half a million people on both sides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3865afc2e60cb84e441f304589306cc</guid></item><item><title>Urban water restrictions likely across Victoria as dam levels drop and dry summer predicted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/urban-water-restrictions-likely-across-victoria-dam-levels-drop/106181336</link><description>Victoria's water storage levels have dropped to 61 per cent capacity after most of the state recorded below average rainfall in 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">802ede04d18fcccb9d3a0a58674a6485</guid></item><item><title>Robots, AI and 'smart tourism' will change how we travel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/tourist-new-technology-ai-travel-smart-tourism/105956560</link><description>Will new technology lead to streamlined service and stress-free travel, or will it fundamentally change tourism and tourist destinations?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6265082f5c6968dacc7e1d1fd35c0efb</guid></item><item><title>Police overseeing Bondi terror response investigate tattooed man at Newcastle beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/police-investigate-tattooed-man-at-newcastle-beach/106180310</link><description>Police overseeing the response to the Bondi terror attack are investigating after a man was seen at a NSW beach allegedly showing a tattoo of a banned Nazi symbol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8294c2c1aef91af579261a260d4c364b</guid></item><item><title>Hobart family reunited with dog nearly four years after it disappeared from home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/tasmanian-family-reunited-with-missing-dog-found-living-wild/106181610</link><description>A blurry photo on social media has led to a Hobart family reuniting with their missing dog nearly four years after it vanished from their home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a92c519decdd8e65e93256421933dd9b</guid></item><item><title>Australia belted, England vindicated and Test cricket wounded in MCG Ashes Test farce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/australia-belted-england-vindicated-test-cricket-wounded-mcg/106181362</link><description>As England deservedly celebrates a long-awaited Test win in Australia, everyone else involved counts the cost of a farcical and damaging two-day disaster at the MCG.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b8c1e011213e214665690d118a882bc</guid></item><item><title>Three charged after fatal Christmas Eve stabbing in Perth suburb of Aubin Grove</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/man-charged-over-aubin-grove-fatal-stabbing/106181894</link><description>Three males are charged over the fatal stabbing of a 19-year-old in the Perth southern suburb of Aubin Grove on Christmas Eve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67bc1a7da4fbcccdb1c31069871b1133</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Calls for MCG Boxing Day Test pitch to be rated 'poor' as England and Australia batting criticised</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/boxing-day-ashes-test-ends-inside-two-days/106181452</link><description>After the first Test of the Ashes series sensationally ended in just two days, Cricket Australia hoped it wouldn't see that again for a century. It's happened again five weeks later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bef5f9857484c314cb5ce8fecde9597f</guid></item><item><title>The vibe shift is here and it's not what we expected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/vibe-shift-ai-misinformation-reality-future/106098002</link><description>From the rise of misinformation and AI to escalating political tensions, vast economic disparity, and the erosion of social bonds, the vibe shift is now understood as a deep, unsettling change in our collective reality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc0d6215f5c83ea0df13f74db44af334</guid></item><item><title>Today in History: Top-secret Manhattan Project quietly approved</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/manhattan-project-roosevelt-nuclear-bomb-oppenheimer-japan/106174568</link><description>On December 28, 1942, a US president formally approved an investment in the top-secret project to create nuclear weapons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b97d3cfa3d0bc0fb02cbfcc70b2cd52</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz tournament: Think you are good at quizzes? I dare you to try these 50 questions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/hard-quiz-tournament-weekly-trivia/106130622</link><description>Looking to settle who is the smartest in your family? Challenge them to a Hard Quiz tournament: five rounds, 50 questions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcd07256f1bb8166d44f0919bc31e28f</guid></item><item><title>Steroid use is 'exploding' — but there are no clinical guidelines on how to quit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/steroid-use-increase-quit-guidelines-australia/106043898</link><description>A rising number of Australians are using steroids. But one expert says a lack of knowledge and widespread stigma make it tough to get clinical support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c5f65de8977165f59203d14fa8e06ac</guid></item><item><title>Parents in China use AI technology to monitor children's homework</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/parents-in-china-using-ai-monitor-children-homework-social-media/106176546</link><description>AI is becoming a regular presence at homework time in many Chinese households. Experts say where families draw the line matters more than the technology itself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7ba3d6cc4fd5d41e9f23b056dc5c3ab</guid></item><item><title>More than a quarter of Sydney to Hobart fleet retires as leaders head down Tasmania's east coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/sydney-to-hobart-yacht-race-retirements-rough-conditions/106181970</link><description>Crews have been battling challenging conditions, damage and sea sickness as the leading yachts are expected to arrive in Hobart later today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05c650c16301bfe04ba6f9a8c2a071d9</guid></item><item><title>Cyber attacks that occurred this year and how you can protect your data</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/cyber-attacks-2025-and-ways-to-protect-your-data/106113950</link><description>More than 500 data breaches were reported in Australia over the first half of 2025 alone, but there are some ways you can minimise your risk of being caught up in one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6598bb0502d89389e7d5e5b3034648f</guid></item><item><title>How the teen social media ban is impacting Australia’s multicultural communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/teens-stay-connected-to-overseas-family-post-social-media-ban/106177038</link><description>Sydney teenager Ilia Kyrychenko was relieved to delete his accounts after the social media ban, but the change is making it more difficult to connect with his loved ones in Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a741447e2137a617d80fba502cade1e</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Heat beats Adelaide Strikers by seven runs, thanks to debutant Tom Balkin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/heat-call-on-lightning-fast-debutant-in-rollicking-bbl-win/106182342</link><description>Injury to Shaheen Afridi leaves debutant Tom Balkin to bowl the final over, and the 21-year-old delivers to help Brisbane Heat to a seven-run BBL win over Adelaide Strikers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf24169f767377c226a5fad18d15e2da</guid></item><item><title>Experts say climate change bigger threat to biodiversity than renewable energy projects</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/renewable-energy-impacts-kentbruck-wind-farm/106157018</link><description>As the green energy boom gathers pace, experts say climate change is a bigger threat to biodiversity than wind farms and other renewables projects.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e664a3bfdc63f8077cf844a68acce4f</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with two counts of murder after stabbing at Quakers Hill in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/man-charged-two-counts-of-murder-after-stabbing-quakers-hill/106182386</link><description>Emergency services were called to a Quakers Hill home just before 5am after reports of a disturbance to discover a woman dead and a man fatally wounded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1b73f6b2ba17ebd42fdac9e4c61a9e0</guid></item><item><title>Matthew Hauser became world triathlon champion in 2025. Now, he wants to win Olympic gold for Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/matthew-hauser-triathlete-world-champion-olympic-dreams/106179648</link><description>Matthew Hauser has always dreamed of becoming a triathlete. After achieving incredible feats this year, the world champion is now eyeing a spot on the Australian Olympic squad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">967d7f94c6d0a6b0dfb3bfadb99528f4</guid></item><item><title>What was on summer reading lists 100 years ago, in 1925?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/summer-reading-list-1925-human-experience-time-travel/106172974</link><description>There are books from authors that would become household names — F. Scott Fitzgerald and A.A Milne among them — and books that are now banned in some countries. But what can we learn from what people were reading in 1925?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d08c1d2e3ba6ff50a847933c46b8cd8a</guid></item><item><title>Mentors gave me confidence to navigate life with a disability. Now I'm giving back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/mentors-gave-me-confidence-to-navigate-life-with-a-disability/106169450</link><description>Other people with lived experience of blindness gave ABC reporter Nas Campanella the confidence to navigate life. Her mentee, Lily, is enjoying similar benefits.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f2710fbd235d36e292f977452d42c6</guid></item><item><title>NTFL umpires say FIFO growth to blame for declining standards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/ntfl-umpire-shortage-lower-standards-more-injuries/106171760</link><description>Jared Collins has officiated nearly a thousand NT footy games, but says an ongoing dispute between AFLNT and its umpires has forced him to hang up the whistle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e91512cc107198a8e3a7dea833183b0</guid></item><item><title>A rescued dingo puppy explores its new surroundings.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/a-dingo-puppy-walks-awkwardly-across-some-grass/106127112</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1548d921911e3b45201eeeaee566b96</guid></item><item><title>Dingo management should be 'non-lethal', traditional owners say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/non-lethal-dingo-management-push-by-traditional-owners/105807306</link><description>When Sonya sees a black-and-tan dingo, she feels a connection to family and Country, but many landholders see them as livestock-killing pests. Can graziers and dingoes co-exist?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dbd93a43b5a77e1ac9c73c36cabab5e</guid></item><item><title>Kennedy Center boss criticises musician who cancelled performance after Trump rebrand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/kennedy-centre-criticises-musician-cancelled-performance-rebrand/106182404</link><description>Musician Chuck Redd cancelled his Christmas Eve show days after the White House announced the venue would be renamed the Trump Kennedy Center.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47ac5e0cd46893de5399850e25e97e12</guid></item><item><title>Weatherald, Labuschagne, Green under Ashes selection pressure after MCG loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/australias-shaky-batters-face-scg-selection-scrutiny/106182432</link><description>Jake Weatherald, Marnus Labuschagne and Cameron Green all face selection pressure following double failures in Australia's jarring loss at the MCG.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50bc3003c4bc68d8bf3b70a89abf98a5</guid></item><item><title>What to know about the Islamic State militants targeted by US air strikes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/trump-us-air-strikes-is-militants-nigeria/106181242</link><description>With US President Donald Trump hinting at plans for further strikes on IS militants in Nigeria, here's a rundown on what you need to know about the conflict.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">409b97b5b2a7281b8083c6c8490f3f06</guid></item><item><title>Hands-on memories spark connection for dementia residents at western NSW aged care home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/adult-activity-board-for-dementia-patients/106173414</link><description>Creating meaningful, sensory activities for people living with dementia can be challenging, particularly when many traditional options feel more suited to children than adults with a lifetime of lived experience behind them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a77900a93309dfceb04ffb9fbaf8f904</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate death of woman in Port Macquarie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/port-macquarie-woman-dead/106182606</link><description>A crime scene has been established after a woman died from unexplained injuries in New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ad5370394c4ded7958e20e860ceaf6e</guid></item><item><title>Man charged for allegedly displaying hate symbol tattoos at Newcastle beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/man-charged-for-allegedly-displaying-antisemitic-tattoos/106182526</link><description>A man has been charged for allegedly displaying what police have called "hate symbol" tattoos at a beach in Newcastle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f53322ab0acd29d0350f0c5924bc74bc</guid></item><item><title>Rockingham's leap to major AUKUS defence hub leaves some locals trepidatious</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/rockingham-locals-worried-about-impact-of-aukus-defence-hub/106153364</link><description>Rockingham in Perth's south is fast becoming a crucial part of the AUKUS nuclear submarine deal, with promises of a big boost in jobs and infrastructure — but it's also leaving residents afraid for their lives and lifestyle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ebc36485eb2bb6c367b21f80c2942a0</guid></item><item><title>From soapboxes to social media: Two artists shaping Queensland's bush art scene</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/artists-shaping-queensland-s-bush-art-scene/106175014</link><description>Marion Moore is 101. Zarabella Bambling is 23. Despite their differences, both women have just celebrated the same major achievement as bush artists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">427d241e1ba0b484ea9d0a3fced806c4</guid></item><item><title>Veteran train driver calls time on 70-year career that 'will never happen again'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/veteran-train-driver-peter-sawtell-calls-time-after-70-years/106128706</link><description>Peter Sawtell remembers making friends and enemies, keeping fit behind a diesel engine, and even meeting King Charles III during his "legendary" career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f3c6dc67ff8ee0876f1ab0e0eb8d991</guid></item><item><title>Former Australian fast bowler Brett Lee inducted into the Australian Cricket Hall of Fame</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/aussie-speedster-brett-lee-given-hall-of-fame-nod/106182682</link><description>Renowned for his express pace, former fast bowler Brett Lee is the latest inductee into the Australian Cricket Hall of Fame.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40162193553c6a743c9d53320dcd5be1</guid></item><item><title>The case of the Guayaquil Four places scrutiny on Ecuador's security crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/guayaquil-four-sentence-lays-bare-racism-and-security-in-ecuador/106173084</link><description>In the weeks before Christmas, four boys under 16 left home to play a game of soccer. Their forced disappearance at the hands of Ecuador's military has been labelled a national "turning point".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49b1ef624f5f479dd3ab2d8593a6c9e2</guid></item><item><title>Spanish soccer coach missing after tourist boat sinks in Indonesia's Komodo National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/spanish-soccer-coach-missing-after-boat-sank-komodo-park/106182542</link><description>The Labuan Bajo port authority attributes the sinking to high waves of up to three metres, but rescuers say they are "determined" to find survivors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5441712670751126c6e63aca3be00d2</guid></item><item><title>'Grumpy' seal disrupts Blairgowrie boat race on Victoria's Mornington Peninsula</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/grumpy-seal-blairgowrie-petersville-regatta/106182708</link><description>A wild seal dubbed "Grumpy" causes some commotion at an annual boat race on the Mornington Peninsula, outside Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">083e2941bae98fafdb7d5202d1fe7c23</guid></item><item><title>MCG curator Matt Page admits Boxing Day Test pitch 'favoured the bowlers too much'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/mcc-boss-defends-curator-after-two-day-ashes-test/106182802</link><description>MCC boss Stuart Fox staunchly defends chief curator Matt Page after a wild Boxing Day Test finishes within two days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1acfc9a80c189932f3941f9cf9cb33be</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with assaulting Labor identity Tim Picton granted bail in Perth court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/tim-picton-family-statement-alleged-northbridge-assault/106182738</link><description>A 20-year-old man is granted bail after allegedly assaulting Tim Picton, a prominent Labor Party identity — an attack police prosecutors say may leave him permanently disabled, if he survives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">582a30d244334d7fc711737f77e529db</guid></item><item><title>Coral Adventurer runs aground off Papua New Guinea with 120 people onboard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/cruise-ship-coral-adventurer-runs-aground-off-papua-new-guinea/106182788</link><description>The Coral Adventurer has run aground off the coast of Papua New Guinea with more than 120 people aboard, two months after the death of a passenger allegedly left behind on a Great Barrier Reef island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6567446a57129047ac675b525e0e1c3</guid></item><item><title>SA independent MP Nick McBride charged with assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/sa-independent-mp-nick-mcbride-charged/106182668</link><description>Police say they responded to reports of a domestic assault at a home in South Australia's south-east on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc915b603692b5192afe65dd47c0b132</guid></item><item><title>Taiwan's cunning tax compliance makes most shopping receipts a ticket in a lottery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/taiwan-receipt-lottery-win-money-from-shopping/106140828</link><description>Most shopping receipts in Taiwan are also tickets for a lottery run every second month by the government to increase tax compliance, and there are some big prizes up for grabs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25f5e0a517eb8eafa70303f39fc1010c</guid></item><item><title>Comanche takes out line honours in 2025 Sydney to Hobart Yacht Race — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/live-blog-sydney-to-hobart-yacht-race-tracking-the-finish/106182756</link><description>Master Lock Comanche claims line honours in the 80th edition of the gruelling Sydney to Hobart yacht race, with a stunning daylight hours finish, making up for retiring early in last year's race.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">338d82dc7e18ccdd20b895f471a22571</guid></item><item><title>Teenagers charged after alleged aggravated carjacking in Melbourne's south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/alleged-aggravated-carjacking-police-chase-hampton-park-pakenham/106183114</link><description>An overnight police chase across multiple suburbs has ended with the arrest of three teenagers after an alleged aggravated carjacking in Melbourne's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edb125df654714026d70f2fd71fcd94e</guid></item><item><title>Comanche wins Sydney to Hobart line honours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/comanche-wins-sydney-to-hobart-line-honours/106183250</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a72afefec57b8ae17123abe534199049</guid></item><item><title>Brigitte Bardot, iconic French actor, sex symbol and animal rights campaigner, dies aged 91</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/brigitte-bardot-dies-age-91/102626484</link><description>The French actor and singer was a screen siren of the 1950s and 1960s who in later life became a prominent animal rights campaigner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a8bea482f12114393ea501ba0b3a9a0</guid></item><item><title>Brigitte Bardot was the world's 'sex kitten'. Her nonchalance was all French</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/brigitte-bardot-sex-symbol-fashion-darling-and-french-icon/105927998</link><description>Few epitomised French chic like Brigitte Bardot, the doe-eyed beauty whose sensuality rocked a post-war world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60d23ab3a781560aba2c74662576b8d4</guid></item><item><title>Families of Bondi victims call for federal royal commission</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/bondi-beach-victim-families-call-for-federal-royal-comission/106183188</link><description>Loved ones of those killed and injured in the Bondi Beach attack say rising antisemitism requires a "powerful national response", piling pressure on Anthony Albanese for a royal commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6fc9a1e1906617a1395c8773838364e</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios defeats Aryna Sabalenka in latest 'battle of the sexes'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/nick-kyrgios-aryna-sabalenka-battle-of-the-sexes-live-blog/106182808</link><description>Australia's Nick Kyrgios defeated women's world number one Aryna Sabalenka in the latest "battle of the sexes". The Aussie, who has fallen outside the ATP top 600 after barely playing for three years, won 6-3, 6-3.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">190b8c7e84e5d376abc1085871d67f15</guid></item><item><title>A growing number of older women surfers are showing age is just a state of mind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/older-women-surfing-trends/105867538</link><description>When Katie Pahlow turned 60, she decided to finally bite the bullet and book herself in for some surf lessons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7393da40072bb0d63dcf47898161a0db</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Larcombe's journey back to the top of the paraclimbing world after devastating injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/sarah-larcombe-paraclimbing-injury-arapiles-world-championships/106018328</link><description>When Sarah Larcombe fell off Mount Arapiles in February, she thought she just sprained her ankle. What followed was months of ups and downs ending in a stunning world championships result.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f086b176ddcd0acf46baf29b3420471</guid></item><item><title>Aid agencies fear lifesaving program banned in Gaza under new Israeli requirements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/aid-agencies-fear-lifesaving-program-blockage-into-gaza-/106181964</link><description>The Israeli government has introduced new rules for aid organisations, including that they must not engage in any activities or criticism which "delegitimise" the state of Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd0ed41a1ad1defc29299a64e4369121</guid></item><item><title>Furious customers slam ASIC for ignoring Zone RV whistleblower complaints before collapse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/furious-customers-asic-whistleblower-zone-rv-caravan-collapse/106169334</link><description>Anger is growing after revelations the corporate watchdog failed to investigate allegations against luxury caravan manufacturer Zone RV.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c22815f3508ce96be6e70f36ef42f7d3</guid></item><item><title>Australia's driver courtesy wave dying out, say truckies, but experiment proves wave still alive on back roads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/australian-drivers-truckies-courtesy-wave/106152822</link><description>For generations, the courtesy wave has been etched into the Australian culture, but is it on the verge of dying?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab1044fced53244ab59b2127f9073c74</guid></item><item><title>Overall winner yet to be decided as Sydney to Hobart yacht race enters fourth day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/sydney-to-hobart-yacht-race-enters-day-four/106183294</link><description>The yacht race has entered the fourth day, after Master Lock Comanche claimed line honours late on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4cba130833aabf1a653c8633a657a2a</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy says progress made on peace deal, but Donald Trump says 'thorny issues' remain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/trump-meets-zelenskyy-to-discuss-ukraine-peace-plan/106183658</link><description>Volodymyr Zelenskyy says a security guarantee between Ukraine and the US as part of a peace deal is "100 per cent agreed", while Donald Trump says there are still one or two "thorny issues" to finalise in the deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06163790a274f36391c30a19988e561a</guid></item><item><title>Concerns medical weight-loss treatments are being advertised to vulnerable eating disorder patients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/juniper-telehealth-concerns-weight-loss-treatment-glp1/106114626</link><description>Eating disorder bodies are raising concerns about weight-loss treatments being prescribed by telehealth companies, one of which ran a Black Friday sale to promote its services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d11ae8b27f1bc3eef0a9dee97b0a2f</guid></item><item><title>Young women join Country Women's Association Sydney branch in droves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/country-womens-association-cwa-in-sydney-young-women-joining/105941208</link><description>More young women are joining the Country Women's Association's city branches, with a passion for jams and scones along with social connection and purpose.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67607c13646f850e0435fa1c89495c0d</guid></item><item><title>Voter turnout lower than expected in Myanmar's first election since 2020</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/voter-turnout-low-myanmar-first-election-2020/106183648</link><description>Myanmar's election has been widely dismissed as a sham by many governments and human rights activists who have said the military will use proxy candidates to legitimise their rule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d51e58cecc72915c62d1db7781e09955</guid></item><item><title>Travis Head happy to see out Ashes as Australian opener before working out future role</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/australias-travis-head-not-fazed-on-opening-role-in-future/106183666</link><description>Australia star Travis Head says he is not precious about continuing to open the batting beyond this Ashes and will bat wherever the coaches tell him to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">922094f96e3a457a294c7309ef6a65a5</guid></item><item><title>AI powered 2025's economy to record highs. So why are only robots smiling?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/end-of-year-economics-analysis-wrap/106176480</link><description>This year saw economies survive tariff shocks and markets burst through record highs, but it doesn't feel like a party because so many people aren't invited.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6da1698c0a40d26aaf7b2833b7f573d8</guid></item><item><title>Deadly varroa mite threatens half of Canberra’s beehives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/act-varroa-mite-wipe-out-half-bees-two-years/106148658</link><description>A fast-spreading parasite is expected to devastate local bee colonies over the next two years, affecting commercial and backyard crops.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8efde471e61f47b153c0556497f33df6</guid></item><item><title>LGBTQIA+ focused boxing class combatting loneliness amid warnings about social isolation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/lgbtqia-boxing-class-tackling-loneliness/106034550</link><description>One in three adults experience social isolation in what experts say is a "dangerous" issue in society. One suburban boxing group is working to tackle the issue, focused on the LGBTQIA+ community more at risk of loneliness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be1b7e6c38093ce747c6d1f9fa059918</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Hayley upgraded to category two system, as northern WA residents told to prepare</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/cyclone-hayley-forms-off-wa-coast-broome-in-watch-zone/106182876</link><description>Residents in WA's north are on alert following the formation of Tropical Cyclone Hayley off the coast overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf432452bba2d586f8686b2bbf83b502</guid></item><item><title>Wet season's arrival prompts moves to shore up food security in Far North Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/flooded-roads-cause-food-insecurity-in-far-north-queensland/106176990</link><description>Earlier this year, a once-in-a-century flood devastated Ingham and cut the main supply route between Cairns and Townsville. Now, as intense rainfall once again triggers multiple warnings and floods roads across northern Queensland, communities are taking steps to prevent another food shortage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9171d9c772b41bbf73794cbd198be777</guid></item><item><title>How vintage black-and-white films are making a splash back in colour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/revitalising-vintage-films/105721412</link><description>Would those classic black-and-white films be the same if viewed in full colour?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">920bdb4c48f10f5d070dc6a984c533b4</guid></item><item><title>Australian rowers targetting Los Angeles Olympics after breakthrough medal in coastal beach sprints</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/quiet-confidence-aussie-rowers-who-shocked-the-world/106183784</link><description>After claiming Australia's first world championship medal in rowing coastal beach sprints, these athletes are turning their attention towards the LA Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7248c9d35428b3a9488993e8a3850876</guid></item><item><title>Victorian master builder transforms Warrnambool house into castle for his son</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/builder-transforms-warrnambool-home-into-castle-for-son/106176624</link><description>They say "a man's home is his castle," but one builder from south-west Victoria has taken that literally when creating a dream home for his son.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">695b846b83e8f11dbad0909f3c891cba</guid></item><item><title>Australia coach Andrew McDonald says Usman Khawaja will play the final Ashes Test amid retirement speculation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/khawaja-guaranteed-for-scg-future-unclear-after-that/106184310</link><description>Usman Khawaja will play in the Ashes finale at the SCG, but Australian coach Andrew McDonald remains in the dark about the 39-year-old's future beyond that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d906fedef83a721543a674e8516f4cb</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese announces terms for Richardson review of Bondi terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/bondi-breaking-announcement/106184434</link><description>The PM says a former head of ASIO will assess whether multiple security and law agencies worked as effectively as they should have before the attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78790121282cd6631c15dcb53f6684a5</guid></item><item><title>NT police arrest woman for allegedly stealing from patients in Alice Springs Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/elderly-theft-alice-springs-hospital/106184326</link><description>A 30-year-old woman faces court after allegedly stealing from multiple elderly patients recovering from surgery in Alice Springs Hospital over an extended period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dadea0f3cdc0d06e06262cda42d00b4</guid></item><item><title>Coolongolook Rural Fire Service volunteers 'gutted' after robbery during fire season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/coolongolook-rfs-robbery/106184106</link><description>The volunteers discovered the theft when they arrived at the Coolongolook RFS shed to attend a car crash. Thieves stole hoses, breathing masks, radios and chainsaws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffcd8748790754acacd5a3346ef0c2ae</guid></item><item><title>Wu-Tang Clan's RZA reflects on the legendary hip-hop group's place in history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/wu-tang-clan-s-rza-on-being-in-one-of-/106176230</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02631ae97147b460167ea17ab6059f4d</guid></item><item><title>Jack Black and Paul Rudd reveal their surprise encounters while filming in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/jack-black-and-paul-rudd-reveal-their-surprise-encounters/106176344</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78f06ed9562be7ef672b8b8d52f86060</guid></item><item><title>England's pace bowling stocks stripped bare with Gus Atkinson out of SCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/gus-atkinson-england-ruled-out-scg-test/106184680</link><description>England's pace bowling stocks will be stretched to their absolute limit for the final Ashes Test with Gus Atkinson ruled out with a hamstring injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22aefbd0e149e9e30254a8f87eca7bee</guid></item><item><title>Bondi hero recounts how he disarmed one of the gunmen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/bondi-hero-recounts-how-he-disarmed-one-of-the-gunmen/106184738</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e27bf827203d6933c058dfc0d1f0dc34</guid></item><item><title>Ahmed Al Ahmed recounts how he disarmed one of the gunmen in Bondi Beach terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/bondi-hero-ahmed-al-ahmed-recounts-story-of-wrestling-gunman/106183900</link><description>Father-of-two Ahmed Al Ahmed, who risked his life to disarm one of the Bondi gunmen during a terrorist attack, says he feels sorry for the 15 people who were killed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6a49f3b62dec473e7ffccc0ed4079a2</guid></item><item><title>The right way to stack your dishwasher and the verdict on rinsing beforehand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/the-verdict-on-rinsing-dishes-before-stacking-the-dishwasher/106022382</link><description>Rinsing can actually send a message to your dishwasher that your plate doesn't need as much washing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b16a5e33ffb32c5a75404f38ecdbd73d</guid></item><item><title>Celebrating New Year's Eve in Melbourne? Here's how and where to bring in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/how-to-celebrate-new-years-eve-in-melbourne/106183938</link><description>Half a million people are expected in the CBD as Melbourne farewells 2025 and ushers in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a16b07aac66c36c7a236913dce6ccff6</guid></item><item><title>Stranded passengers to fly home from PNG after failed efforts to free Coral Adventurer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/coral-adventurer-cruise-passengers-to-fly-home-from-png/106184296</link><description>Passengers on the Australian cruise ship stranded off the coast of Papua New Guinea will be flown out of the country after efforts to refloat the vessel failed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f76911ebbee1286772ba5bf89ef00380</guid></item><item><title>South Australian MP Nick McBride to remain in custody for next seven days</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/nick-mcbride-remains-in-custody/106183758</link><description>South Australian independent MP Nick McBride will spend the next week in custody, after being arrested and charged over the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23cfb7d551970cb59aa18a5b3f9cb66b</guid></item><item><title>China launches military exercise warning against Taiwan independence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/china-taiwan-military-exercise-independence/106184600</link><description>China has moved its military to surround Taiwan warning against its independence. But Beijing's action has been condemned by Taiwan calling for regional peace and de-escalation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37ecc5e002b8f8f0e07100aae2ff9ccb</guid></item><item><title>Sydney to Hobart competitors tell of 'horrendous' conditions during 2025 race ordeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/2025-sydney-to-hobart-competitors-endure-rough-seas/106184046</link><description>Those now safely onshore after finishing the 2025 Sydney to Hobart tell of "horrendous" conditions, resulting in injuries, broken boats and seasickness — even among experienced crew members.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3d61d78845f12e1a58903944ac9f4eb</guid></item><item><title>Prosecutors wrap up bribery investigation into South Korea's former first lady</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/kim-keon-hee-bribery-accusations/106184962</link><description>Kim Keon Hee, the wife of disgraced ex-president Yoon Suk Yeol, is alleged to have accepted lavish bribes including fine art, jewellery and designer handbags, and to have meddled in state affairs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b0d782413b3369dcb0aae4239acdf2c</guid></item><item><title>Kempsey community marks 10 years since death in custody of David Dungay Jr</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/david-dungay-jr-death-anniversary-rally/106183046</link><description>A decade after his death in a Sydney prison, David Dungay Jr's family hold with a memorial rally calling for change to a corrections system they say still fails to protect Indigenous people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bdd7f9e29a766e460ae327c8d02e857</guid></item><item><title>Slow TV for kids: Relax and unwind with low-stimulation shows on ABC iview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/low-stimulation-kids-tv-shows-stream-iview-abckids/106024290</link><description>Looking for screen-time options that won't leave your kids overstimulated? 'Slow TV' shows, with their soothing visuals and soundtracks, could be the answer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">428e608956327dc581fd5e961f4708a4</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Sydney Test a golden opportunity for Cameron Green to belatedly shine in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/ashes-cameron-green-home-test-struggles/106185032</link><description>He has already proven his quality away from home, but heading into the final Test of the Ashes summer, Cameron Green remains in search of his breakthrough moment in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58a0cbd79c3cf2c39cce515515f91558</guid></item><item><title>Legal loophole in Queensland's double jeopardy law closed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/dna-double-jeopardy-cases-qld-law-changes/106184178</link><description>Last-minute amendments to Queensland's double jeopardy laws could allow for the retrial of botched DNA cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1ca9a578ce596f77c5d8a343e7e5f45</guid></item><item><title>Australia is considered a "lifeboat" region for some threatened rhino ray species, but the numbers worldwide are grim.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/rhino-ray-numbers-northern-territory-indonesia-extinction/106185030</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a7a7eaa5ae38567db7ecf4dd704011b</guid></item><item><title>Man faces court over alleged Boxing Day murder in remote NT community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/greg-shaun-williams-faces-court-over-alleged-boxing-day-murder/106185286</link><description>A 39-year-old man appears in court charged with the stabbing murder of a man in a remote Northern Territory community north of Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5478d4449ea06d23f01082c453ddfd97</guid></item><item><title>Dozens of shark heads dumped outside WA Fisheries minister's office as demersal fishing ban looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/shark-heads-dumped-outside-jackie-jarvis-office-fisheries/106184674</link><description>Hundreds of kilograms of shark heads have been left dumped outside the WA Fisheries minister's office in Margaret River, just three days before a permanent commercial demersal fishing ban comes into effect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52da2612172243bdd59c8424d34d39b0</guid></item><item><title>Menorah to light up Sydney Harbour Bridge on New Year's Eve after open letter from Jewish creatives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/nsw-nye-sydney-changes-after-jewish-creatives-open-letter/106185368</link><description>More than 30 Jewish-Australian creatives wrote to Lord Mayor Clover Moore on Monday morning, urging for a "Jewish-specific symbol" to commemorate the victims of the Bondi Beach terror attacks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00b316968710e16f09894837bc2fc7ee</guid></item><item><title>ICC gives MCG pitch 'unsatisfactory' rating as two-day Test fallout continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/mcg-boxing-day-test-pitch-icc-verdict-unsatisfactory/106185382</link><description>The ICC has handed down their verdict on the controversial MCG pitch which led to this year's Boxing Day Test wrapping up after just two days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3eb403942ca3ba789e82b7d7f5975ab9</guid></item><item><title>Thailand accuses Cambodia of breaching ceasefire deal after 250 drones flown over border</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/thailand-accuses-cambodia-of-breaching-ceasefire-deal/106185620</link><description>Bangkok has accused Phnom Penh of violating the peace deal that was struck on Saturday, after it claimed some 250 drones had been flown over the disputed border region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7147b1fd623dc9f4c30fa238964acc9a</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy says US offers Ukraine 15-year security guarantee as part of peace plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/us-ukraine-peace-plan-15-year-security-trump-zelenskyy/106185584</link><description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy has held talks with US President Donald Trump, and says he would prefer a commitment of 50 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0aa54df231a7cd807859e7b8cfd504cc</guid></item><item><title>Hamas confirms death of ex-leader Mohammed Sinwar and spokesman Abu Ubaida</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/hamas-confirms-deaths-of-mohammed-sinwar-and-abu-ubaida/106185808</link><description>In a statement, the Palestinian militant group also confirmed the death of spokesman Abu Ubaida.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f362a4936393650952976ac9e08b35e</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy denies attacking Putin's Novgorod home with long-range drones</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/russia-claims-ukraine-tried-to-attack-putin-residence/106185906</link><description>Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov says Moscow will review its position on a planned peace deal with Ukraine due to the alleged attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2bb515b90280fabf7c9901edf450149</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 30: Beatles star George Harrison stabbed at home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/today-in-history-december-30-george-harrison-stabbed/106171844</link><description>Unlike his former bandmate John Lennon, George Harrison survived an attack by a fan, but the musician's friends and family speculated it hastened his death less than two years later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5de21d23cf56392fd7ed419a58dc08c2</guid></item><item><title>Remembering the celebrities and public figures who died in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/celebrities-public-figures-who-died-2025-obituaries/105869472</link><description>From actors and designers to a Holocaust survivor and a broadcaster, these people made their mark.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8ff6e8e6521b3764b05e9eb7af0051d</guid></item><item><title>Your most read ABC News stories of 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/your-most-read-abc-news-stories-of-2025/106150728</link><description>It was a year that bought us a federal election, ongoing war in the Middle East and Ukraine and a trial in a small Victorian town watched keenly around the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0d7321c1ba593a47553562e53ff4f2d</guid></item><item><title>What happened when we tested a 'safe' AI mental health chatbot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/safe-mental-health-artificial-intelligence-chatgpt/106136202</link><description>Is it possible to make a "safe" AI therapy bot? We tested the limits of a new Australian-designed chatbot that's been carefully designed not to hallucinate or be your best friend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">845b6e5b1edf763fd5784d8b8777cd9e</guid></item><item><title>Household battery uptake booms on back of 'game-changer' rebate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/home-battery-uptake-soars-due-to-government-subsidy/106120730</link><description>Battery uptake is booming since the federal government rebate came into effect in July. Here's what you need to know if you are thinking of joining the thousands of Australians adding a battery to their home solar systems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30708c31c5d2c6ad77f5cc6b6d8e3c4c</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth Bank convinced regulator to delay news it was breaking spam laws until after AGM</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/acma-backdown-commonwealth-bank/106125460</link><description>The Commonwealth Bank persuaded a key regulator to delay announcing it had broken spam laws until after its AGM, new documents reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d4fb093373fffb3c37561da117692a8</guid></item><item><title>ASIC's remarkable turnaround as the tiger that found its teeth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/asic-the-tiger-that-found-its-teeth/106170504</link><description>After 20 years in the wilderness, the Australian Securities and Investments Commission's rehabilitation as a law enforcement agency seems almost complete.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f57bf412f7f38aa6ae3447a6261192d</guid></item><item><title>Josh Burns on juggling politics and fatherhood and being a Jewish MP</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/josh-burns-baby-federal-parliament-georgie-purcell-antisemitism/106162418</link><description>In a broad-ranging interview for the Politics Now podcast, the rising Labor star reveals he plans to take extended leave to care for his baby daughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79bb53732ced6ee8fa0288579b707fca</guid></item><item><title>Police search for alleged carjacker who was fought off by bystanders in inner Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/vic-police-investigate-carjack-attempt-richmond/106185972</link><description>Police are looking for a man who allegedly tried to steal a woman's car in Richmond earlier this year but was foiled by bystanders, including one person wielding a golf club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26e5e8466580c32f89d01a9fa9f34ac5</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill records seven earthquakes in 2025 — the most in recorded history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/broken-hill-records-seven-earthquakes-2025-most-recorded-history/106171264</link><description>It is not unheard of for the ground to shake in Broken Hill, but what is unusual is the number of earthquakes recorded by Geoscience Australia this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">326190426ea8ff0dda00f320deaf4623</guid></item><item><title>Transforming soft plastics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/transforming-soft-plastics/106185050</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6094f402939257049978e2d7b4f55c9d</guid></item><item><title>Soft plastics recycling is back in Australia. How does it work and where does it go?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/soft-plastics-recycling-is-back-in-australia-how-does-it-work-/105912070</link><description>Australia's first large-scale soft plastics recycling facility is processing huge loads each day, turning waste into a useful raw material.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d37c808f6bf403492a2a2b8dc150e76</guid></item><item><title>South-east Queensland's largest dam is 'full'. What does it mean?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/qld-how-wivenhoe-dam-works/106166620</link><description>South-east Queensland's largest water reservoir provides drinking water and protection from flooding. So, how does it all work?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f007ea1b086bd4b4b1ac973bbf0b4df</guid></item><item><title>Emergency warning issued as Cyclone Hayley nears WA's Kimberley coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/cyclone-hayley-strengthens-as-it-approaches-kimberley-coast/106184894</link><description>Tropical Cyclone Hayley continues to barrel towards the Dampier Peninsula on the Western Australian coast, where residents are being told to prepare for "severe impacts" when it makes landfall tonight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9170328b144f4be398818fe70b5d7545</guid></item><item><title>Hobart Hurricanes beat Melbourne Renegades thanks to vital cameo from Matthew Wade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/what-a-difference-a-wade-makes-as-canes-beat-renegades-in-bbl/106186014</link><description>Matthew Wade's fuss-free cameo helps Hobart chase down the Melbourne Renegades's 163 at Bellerive Oval, lifting the Hurricanes well clear of the pack in second spot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcdb9eef9e02f8f842aa649ae744602b</guid></item><item><title>Hiker Stella Thurbon leads herd of goats on trek through Victoria's High Country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/victorian-high-country-hiking-with-a-herd-of-goats/106119216</link><description>With bells tinkling, tails flicking, and panniers packed to the brim, adventurer Stella Thurbon has spent 26 days winding through the Victorian High Country with nine goats trotting faithfully behind her.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6002a583dc507156847c083070b68f08</guid></item><item><title>Noongar elders say WA prescribed burn went ahead despite warnings of cultural heritage sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/noongar-elders-say-sacred-site-warnings-were-ignored-before-burn/106086072</link><description>Elders on WA's south coast say they tried to warn the state government about unregistered cultural sites in the path of a prescribed burn, but the burn went ahead anyway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c864bc1e20cca2ab1cdd845af6e7a45e</guid></item><item><title>Bushwalker survives 50-minute wait for antivenom after brown snake bites at Morton National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/bushwalker-survives-brown-snake-bite-morton-national-park-venom/106184490</link><description>Swift-acting bushwalkers and emergency crews "absolutely" saved a woman bitten twice by an eastern brown snake as she hiked on the NSW south coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92320294b712d15eba3d3b8e29205334</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says US 'knocked out' a 'big facility' in Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/trump-says-us-knocked-out-big-facility-in-venezuela/106186078</link><description>A US strike on Venezuelan soil would be the first known land attack in the country since the Trump administration began ratcheting up pressure on its ruling regime, which Donald Trump accuses of "narco-terrorism".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f10cbadecf7188ee83cb32bce91c1d5</guid></item><item><title>Flooding, heavy rain and damaging winds hit north Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/flooding-north-queensland-weather-rainfall-severe/106184268</link><description>North-west Queensland is on alert as flooding is expected to increase across northern parts of the state. The SES is sending additional crews to the outback amid flood rescues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ef3825a52aeb74cb98779082589dd97</guid></item><item><title>Victoria Police make more than 100 arrests, seize 30 weapons during first weeks of shopping centre operations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/vic-police-shopping-centre-arrests/106186088</link><description>A 15-year-old carrying a hunting knife was among more than 100 arrests during the first few weeks of a police operation at four of Melbourne's biggest shopping centres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eebe5b8532f4619245d8ae290a1bd689</guid></item><item><title>Charles Darwin University researchers leading the way in fight to protect globally threatened rays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/rapid-decline-rhino-ray-indonesia-northern-australia/106168084</link><description>Australian researchers are leading the way in the fight to protect a group of globally threatened fish species, which look like "a shark and ray joined together".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d46b9b263f05e0812c8e68978b30e6a</guid></item><item><title>Deaf people saying no to cochlear implants choosing 'different way of seeing the world'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/cochlear-implants-debate-in-the-deaf-community/106044156</link><description>Cochlear implants can be a life-changing tool for people with hearing loss, but some Deaf people argue their use risks compromising their community's identity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c2c83166ba67cdac1d4df501e80252f</guid></item><item><title>Sportsbet fined $313,000 by NT Racing and Wagering Commission for 'systemic failure'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/sportsbet-fined-313k-for-systemic-failure-slap-on-wrist/106185320</link><description>Australia’s largest online bookmaker has been fined $313,000 for breaching its licence conditions, in what one gambling researcher described as a "slap on the wrist".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f5631bca084fb36afddaabdf4cb7d19</guid></item><item><title>How to protect against scams when buying and selling online on Facebook Marketplace and Gumtree</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/how-to-protect-against-marketplace-scams/106118280</link><description>Savannah thought she had taken all the right steps to protect herself while selling items on Facebook Marketplace — but that did not stop her from being scammed. Here is what you need to know when buying and selling via online marketplaces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9c9db51f70b049a1edbb53db533329e</guid></item><item><title>Justice Department slammed for lack of strategic leadership as problems mount within WA prison system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/wa-justice-department-slammed-by-report-lack-of-leadership/106185476</link><description>A wide-ranging review into Western Australia's Justice Department finds that "forward planning is often overshadowed by immediate operational demands" which means it fails to address rising pressures like prison overcrowding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc650b98a523bb8c424d703f690ecca2</guid></item><item><title>Daria Kasatkina set for Brisbane International and Australian Open after mental health break</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/crowds-will-love-her-kasatkina-s-landmark-home-australian-open/106186126</link><description>Daria Kasatkina is being backed to return from her mental health break and quickly become a fan favourite at her new home grand slam, the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b501ed752fb06314d115d319194d988b</guid></item><item><title>How to celebrate New Year's Eve in Australia's capital cities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/new-years-eve-celebrations-and-fireworks-in-capital-cities/106184300</link><description>There are plenty of free events around the country to see out 2025 and welcome 2026. See what's happening in your city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3df11ee6558df8bcaf3428fcbe01e611</guid></item><item><title>The importance of preparing for death and creating an end-of-life health care plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/preparing-for-death-and-creating-an-end-of-life-health-care-plan/105886810</link><description>Dying in sudden, unexpected circumstances is not something people often consider, but there are plenty of reasons to create an end-of-life plan. So why do so few people have one?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5cd6645b8bb831142f96e95a26be9b7</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump calls for Hamas to disarm after meeting with Benjamin Netanyahu</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/donald-trump-calls-hamas-disarm-netanyahu-meeting/106186218</link><description>The US president has been hosting Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu at his residence in Florida for talks on Gaza and several other issues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32b65161fa32767ba4f01bfadf8d2ce8</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with Dan Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/new-data-about-australia-s-population-released/106186308</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f27196e52353f5e12b52ab97c8011630</guid></item><item><title>Overall Sydney to Hobart leader switches as boats race to get ahead of wind change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/tas-sydney-to-hobart-yacht-race-more-boats-finish/106186132</link><description>The two-person crewed BNC is the current favourite to secure an overall victory in the Sydney to Hobart, after crossing the finish line at 10:40 this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">156a49947e5d4819b67e8dd1ddb2c61b</guid></item><item><title>Metal detectorist discovers 1880s Zanzibar coin at Port Macquarie beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/1880s-zanzibar-coin-at-port-macquarie-beach-using-metal-detector/106184392</link><description>Metal detectorist Dale Oldham at first thought he had found a rusted Australian coin, until an online search revealed it was something much older and far more exotic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4210a4b87d548c95164d598de356af04</guid></item><item><title>NSW Parliament powerless to force witnesses to front inquiries after 19th-century laws struck down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/nsw-parliament-powerless-to-force-witnesses-to-front-inquiries/106185518</link><description>The president of the NSW Legislative Council says he will not try to overturn a decision to strike down laws that purportedly allowed witnesses to be arrested for failing to appear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6d3dc528483abdb73cf850c25e53967</guid></item><item><title>It's backed by Maggie Beer and researchers alike, so why don't we eat more offal?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/eating-offal-and-why-we-should-eat-more/106093422</link><description>Despite becoming less popular in recent years, advocates like Maggie Beer say offal can be a delicacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46c988bca4e62653baff9eaa39fa9cbb</guid></item><item><title>Record number of NSW Police officers to patrol New Year's Eve events after Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/nsw-police-increase-presence-at-new-years-eve-post-bondi-attack/106185980</link><description>More than 2,500 police officers will be out in force at New Year's Eve celebrations in Sydney in a bid to bolster revellers' confidence in the wake of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86ecb30515d3b6e2eea71ed64622d3aa</guid></item><item><title>Boxer Anthony Joshua involved in deadly car crash in Nigeria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/boxer-anthony-joshua-involved-in-deadly-car-crash-in-nigeria/106186500</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecf762deb8912bbd1a5bb88546a70a37</guid></item><item><title>Former boxing world champion Anthony Joshua stable, two people dead after car crash in Nigeria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/boxer-anthony-joshua-stable-two-dead-fatal-car-crash-in-nigeria/106186330</link><description>Boxer Anthony Joshua escapes serious injury in a car crash in Nigeria that leaves two of his close friends and team members dead, a week after his multi-million-dollar fight with Jake Paul.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf62d02d3343abbd3ebcd09b72e73b66</guid></item><item><title>SA avoids major bushfire during extreme danger, but home and sheds destroyed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/sa-avoids-bushfire-during-extreme-danger-forecast/106186140</link><description>South Australia avoided a major bushfire as the state sweltered through a day of extreme danger on Monday, while two structure fires left a damage bill of $1 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ed19eec573ba107ba5711bfb40045ff</guid></item><item><title>China hasn't said it wants war in 2026. But it's showing the world it's ready for one</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/chinas-military-drills-around-taiwan-a-message-to-united-states/106186794</link><description>While Donald Trump was distracted, China launched its strongest-ever challenge against Taiwan. Beijing is showing it is ready for war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2396db44fea5a52c39bd09e3d8eb8a9c</guid></item><item><title>No evidence Bondi attack gunmen operated as part of a terror cell, AFP says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/bondi-attack-gunmen-operated-alone-afp/106186662</link><description>AFP Commissioner Krissy Barrett says there is no evidence the men were instructed to carry out the attack, which left 15 people dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84a0948716ba95899b69f3d9522c9b28</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire near Rockingham closes Mandurah train line, Warnbro station in Perth's south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/fire-near-rockingham-closes-warnbro-train-station-and-train-line/106186550</link><description>A major train line and Warnbro station are closed as firefighters battle a bushfire burning near Rockingham in Perth's south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7509e8187abad58e22cf473c1439609e</guid></item><item><title>Ambulance Victoria reports increase in violence against paramedics over Christmas holiday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/violent-attacks-paramedics-christmas-period-ambulance-victoria/106186398</link><description>Ambulance Victoria says paramedics were assaulted, spat on and sexually harassed in a series of serious incidents over the festive period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6c96067a3fa4ada8769d73de5d41e88</guid></item><item><title>Shoppers spending billions on post-Christmas sales, but small retailers feel forgotten</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/spending-billions-post-christmas-sales-small-retailers-forgotten/106186838</link><description>Outlet centres around Australia were bustling on Boxing Day, but just down the road, some small retailers were feeling the sting. It's a trend that could shape the future of the Boxing Day sales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b88a27e6af003388ee98622e92bcc03e</guid></item><item><title>Donald Bradman's baggy green to go under the hammer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/donald-bradman-baggy-green-auction/106186852</link><description>A baggy green worn by Sir Donald Bradman during the 1947-48 series against India has gone to auction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45a4ea5f89b071b0f9bb4e2772af8c8b</guid></item><item><title>Nick Offerman hopes The Pout-Pout Fish delights tough child critics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/nick-offerman-hopes-the-pout-pout-fish-will-delight-children/106185350</link><description>This Australian animation stars an international and local voice cast led by Nick Offerman and Nina Oyama, who can't wait for children to see the film.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0020d02c138202fc048dfeb5e6b91b11</guid></item><item><title>Coral Adventurer passengers begin journey home as cruise ship remains stranded on PNG reef</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/coral-adventurer-passengers-begin-journey-home/106187482</link><description>Passengers of an Australian cruise ship that ran aground off the coast of Papua New Guinea have begun their journey home, as efforts to free the ship remain unsuccessful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1367a553c7dfdc2f4a388df36c7add99</guid></item><item><title>Gold, silver and palladium prices pull back sharply, worrying some economists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/precious-metals-gold-silver-palladium-crash/106187288</link><description>The price of palladium — used in electronics — tumbles from recent highs while the prices of other precious metals, including gold and silver, have also sharply declined in recent days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09492488be8fcdcec44fb283fd56f0fb</guid></item><item><title>Women wearing hijabs targeted in anti-Muslim abuse post-Bondi attack, says Imams Council</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/rise-in-islamophobic-incidents-post-bondi-beach-terror-attack/106186118</link><description>There are concerns women wearing hijabs are bearing the brunt of a "horrifying" wave of Islamophobia in the wake of the Bondi Beach terrorist attack, with the Australian National Imams Council reporting a rise of hate incidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d913d18ca4a43c398b550fff985d2d8</guid></item><item><title>Floods across western and northern parts of Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/floods-across-western-and-northern-parts-of-queensland/106187600</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">719b935069868e22b9576efd64e88ee7</guid></item><item><title>Impact of abbreviated Boxing Day Test stretches far beyond the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/mcg-pitch-boxing-day-test-two-days-losses/106184878</link><description>The economic and social impact of the Boxing Day Test reaches far past the pitch and the repercussions of the two-day finish rippled all across Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d2b4fc5df4f281402988170ecdfbd88</guid></item><item><title>Police search for alleged carjacker who broke into Latrobe Valley home with axe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/carjacking-theft-breaking-entry-axe-moondarra/106187634</link><description>Police are combing eastern Victorian bushland for a man they allege broke into a house with an axe and stole multiple cars in the Latrobe Valley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2ed44a68fe403cc81cd1aded69d4818</guid></item><item><title>MH370 vanished in 2014. A new search aims to find answers families desperately want</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/mh370-search-resumes-for-malaysia-airlines-missing-plane/106186962</link><description>Malaysia Airlines missing flight MH370, which vanished in 2014, remains one of aviation's enduring mysteries. A new search is aiming to provide answers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cb79e844eeb1b7e91d3be489f74d30c</guid></item><item><title>Russia's claim Ukraine attacked Putin's home 'doesn't make any sense', experts say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/putin-drone-strike-ukraine-experts-say-no-evidence-russia/106187456</link><description>A defence analyst tells the ABC an attack on the Russian President's state residence would be "technically" possible but would not make sense strategically for Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0818e8fdaab6370d04a12fe2c8e511f1</guid></item><item><title>NT Environment Protection Authority orders Santos, Inpex licence conditions review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/nt-epa-santos-inpex-licence-review-emissions-error/106185488</link><description>The Northern Territory environment regulator will re-examine the licence conditions of major gas facilities in Darwin, after one of its biggest operators admitted to under-reporting potentially toxic emissions at its Ichthys LNG plant on Darwin Harbour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">366601fe83aede9fa18c4a99b62dc8eb</guid></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia, Bangladesh's first female prime minister, dead at 80</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/khaleda-zia-bangladesh-first-female-prime-minister-dead/106187666</link><description>Begum Khaleda Zia was leader of the main opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party which was seen as the frontrunner to win the next parliamentary election in February.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bbe92168a4742ebaf2972720cbe6e25</guid></item><item><title>Furniture factory destroyed by massive blaze in Sydney's south-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/nsw-greenacre-firefighters-battle-flooring-factory-blaze/106188018</link><description>More than 60 firefighters with 20 trucks were called to a factory in Greenacre just before 3pm on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f372d1b9561f41941937d66b865c90</guid></item><item><title>Australian laws changed in six important ways in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/australian-laws-change-ubereats-pets-sovereign-citizens/106187302</link><description>From food delivery to sovereign citizens, Australia's laws underwent some important changes this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a18d0b9e12e643b0d2c323088a0972dd</guid></item><item><title>Massive factory fire in Western Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/massive-factory-fire-in-western-sydney/106188154</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0e1d47a738aefa98b9ec8d9bcba704b</guid></item><item><title>Everything you need to know if you are headed to NYE fireworks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/brisbane-fireworks-guide-nye-gold-coast-sunshine-coast-/106184840</link><description>Where to watch, road closures and entry requirements for the hottest seats in town — here's all you need to know for the New Year's fireworks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b84bbd42dc615c54c3d8df1b59c70f06</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide public transport, stations and interchanges join list of declared public precincts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/adelaide-public-transport-join-list-of-declared-public-precincts/106187762</link><description>Police have been given expanded powers to search people for weapons on every public bus, train and tram in the Adelaide metropolitan area ahead of New Year Eve's celebrations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">152f1e795e6672267dd0734ad7fde0a8</guid></item><item><title>The man was arrested in 2024 at his previous suburban residence for his role in the people smuggling scheme.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/people-smuggler-arrest-darwin/106187328</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17d2e1c7359a7fabbcc94c9cbd512310</guid></item><item><title>Australian people smuggling operation laid bare in NT Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/nt-darwin-chef-sentenced-over-people-smuggling-operation/106186976</link><description>A brazen example of people smuggling has been recounted in the Northern Territory Supreme Court, after three Chinese nationals made it into Darwin Harbour on a small wooden fishing boat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d6907e5b5546ba8dd42b51c5a50e4b6</guid></item><item><title>Here's what we know about the Coral Adventurer, the cruise ship that ran aground in PNG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/coral-adventurer-ran-aground-papua-new-guinea-explainer/106187276</link><description>The Coral Adventurer was carrying 80 tourists into the remote reaches of Papua New Guinea when it came to an abrupt halt on a reef off the Pacific nation's coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c0becda7da09f9389e9cdce6adf9424</guid></item><item><title>Bizzi Lavelle uncovers the hidden history of Blak burlesque in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/blak-burlesque-bizzi-body-lavelle/106148190</link><description>Bizzi Lavelle, a Queer Wakka Wakka and Arrernte writer and burlesque dancer known in the scene as Bizzi Body, is reclaiming the hidden legacy of this art-form one tassel twirl at a time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c77f27ecf9f0afac3611eda7ff1d27f</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian youth alleged to have 'large amount' of child exploitation material on phone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/youth-charged-child-exploitation-material-kik-messaging/106188268</link><description>Police have charged a southern Tasmanian youth after allegedly discovering a "large amount of serious child exploitation material" on his phone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5ddcacaf37a38b865771841a4fa655d</guid></item><item><title>BNC's two-man crew describes being unable to eat or sleep in rough seas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/bnc-crew-describes-tough-journey/106187968</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ec9c3a8ddfb465bc7be85e324d28826</guid></item><item><title>BNC, on brink of historic Sydney Hobart yacht race victory, faces a protest by rival Min River</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/protest-lodged-against-bnc-by-min-river/106188442</link><description>The two-person crewed yacht on the brink of winning the prestigious overall handicap prize in the Sydney to Hobart race is the subject of a protest by a rival, which could potentially deny it victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d63456818dfe61babc72bd9a6cf26b7</guid></item><item><title>Woodford Folk Festival's thirty-eighth year platforming Australian artists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/woodford-folk-festivals-thirty-eighth-year/106186650</link><description>More than 110,000 people have already walked through the gates of Woodfordia to be entertained by the 450-plus acts scheduled across the six-day folk festival — now in its 38th year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34d9f8a0bd0948cdb3228890b917263a</guid></item><item><title>Ocean Infinity search for MH370 from 2018.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/ocean-infinity-search-for-mh370-in-2018/106188474</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">419049a950fce92f04fd9b65cde0baf3</guid></item><item><title>Man in his 70s has died in floodwaters at Normanton in north west Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/qld-flood-death-normanton-/106188576</link><description>Police were called to a vehicle submerged in floodwaters near Normanton where they found the man aged in his 70s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a0152c1b443946285be0b6d361c8392</guid></item><item><title>Severe Tropical Cyclone Hayley crosses Western Australia's Kimberley coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/severe-tropical-cyclone-hayley-crosses-kimberley-coast/106187730</link><description>Severe Tropical Cyclone Hayley has been downgraded, after bringing severe winds and heavy rain to parts of the north-west Kimberley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf862726a1bd46dc415d390d71fcf19d</guid></item><item><title>South Korea bans bear bile farming with jail for those who breach the law</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/south-korea-bans-bear-bile-farming/106188716</link><description>South Korea is one of the few countries that allow farming to extract bile from bears, for traditional medicine or food believed to promote vitality and stamina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0a7ab9247aa9d1b35313e29e81bf61f</guid></item><item><title>Eurostar train services cancelled across Europe due to power issue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/eurostar-trains-to-paris-london-brussels-amsterdam-cancelled/106188734</link><description>A disruption on Tuesday prompted the rail company to request train customers postpone their journeys until another time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de3ccb9beca340e7942d3ba01eaf20c9</guid></item><item><title>Christmas cruise ends in chaos as Coral Adventurer passengers return home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/christmas-cruise-png-passengers-return-coral-adventurer/106186660</link><description>Around 80 passengers on the Coral Adventurer have been flown home after the cruise ship ran aground on a reef off Papua New Guinea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a12b92f399d1d29cd366ffaec633591</guid></item></channel></rss>