<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:29:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Australia's surging expectations at the Winter Olympics come thanks to Geoff Henke's strident advocacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/winter-olympics-success-for-australia-geoff-henke-revolution/106302018</link><description>Australia is hoping Milano Cortina 2026 will be its most successful Winter Olympics in history. The reason for Australia's winter sports surge has its roots in a 70-year-old snubbing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">864e05b9f59b0989d860aae75009df3d</guid></item><item><title>The easiest way to clean your microwave and a common mistake to avoid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/what-is-the-best-way-to-clean-a-microwave/106307346</link><description>When was the last time you cleaned your microwave? According to experts, it's actually a lot simpler than cleaning other appliances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b708e459302ab8131d3d781a896a62ad</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Mitchell expected to form into category two system in WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/tropical-cyclone-mitchell-forecast-pilbara-kimberley/106310802</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says Tropical Cyclone Mitchell has a high chance of forming into a category two system, bringing destructive winds and heavy rain to northern WA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee400f88b198bb7c1d1db47c86f20493</guid></item><item><title>Premier Chris Minns says Newcastle Writers Festival 'crazy' to invite author Randa Abdel-Fattah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/randa-abdel-fattah-author-to-attend-newcastle-writers-festival/106312828</link><description>The festival's director said Dr Abdel-Fattah was invited in August last year and denied the state government pressured her to remove the writer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6e1886c2439b2a6c3591dab671487e5</guid></item><item><title>WA author Craig Silvey has child exploitation bail conditions altered after complaining of media attention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/craig-silvey-court-appearance-bail-conditions-altered/106312848</link><description>WA children's author Craig Silvey gets his bail conditions altered by a Perth court after complaining of "significant media attention" since being charged with child exploitation offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">863da9d2b143ceee4249717f0ee1f2da</guid></item><item><title>Handful of residents remain in Daly River amid impending major flooding, as hundreds evacuated to Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/nt-daly-river-flood-handful-of-residents-stay-after-evacuation/106313380</link><description>Some long-term residents have decided to stay behind in Daly River to help amid impending major flooding, after more than 200 people were evacuated to Darwin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2206b76eb8bd7df0127affd68712616</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's free influenza vaccine program to return this year with nasal spray for children aged two to five</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/free-flu-vaccine-program-with-nasal-spray-for-children/106314974</link><description>The program — which will run from March to September — will provide free flu vaccinations, including a nasal spray option for children aged two to five years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6535ffc1b447b733a2730a130f983211</guid></item><item><title>RecipeTin Eats' Nagi Maehashi is normalising taking time off for pets. Here's why that matters.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/recipetineats-nagi-maehashi-time-off-work-care-for-dog-dozer/106313752</link><description>Experts say our pets have become such an important part of our lives that it's important to take a step back from responsibilities, if possible, when they are sick or dying.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9cbd7b56d7377cd2c066ce8db744bca</guid></item><item><title>Man faces court charged with possessing extremist material after phone search at Brisbane Airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/extremist-material-charge-after-phone-search-brisbane-airport/106315576</link><description>Police allege a 25-year-old man intercepted at Brisbane International Airport had violent extremist material on his phone, after an investigation into an alleged Nazi flag delivery to the man.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">507bf1b576bc371496a5d69577c3b4b6</guid></item><item><title>Bullock says government spending not sole factor pushing inflation higher as political fight heats up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/rba-governor-refuses-to-blame-government-for-rising-inflation/106313266</link><description>RBA governor Michele Bullock has refused to blame the Albanese government for rising inflation, as a political fight breaks out in the wake of the bank's rate hike.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c98b12981d05c59ed145353062642772</guid></item><item><title>Josh Hazlewood out of T20 World Cup with injury in another blow to Australia's hopes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/josh-hazlewood-out-of-t20-world-cup-injury-australia/106315684</link><description>Josh Hazlewood is ruled out of Australia's T20 World Cup campaign as he continues to recover from the injuries which kept him from playing in the summer's Ashes series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc2eaa2ecdfd92d77e913bc4aef7b367</guid></item><item><title>Patrol boats out of action in Cairns shipyards as foreign fishers reach Australian shores</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/patrol-boats-out-of-water-amid-illegal-foreign-fishing-influx/106309428</link><description>A "continuous" influx of illegal foreign fishing boats in Queensland waters coincides with at least two of the nation's fleet of patrol boats being out of commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4161f0b872e22c9609c84a3991e94649</guid></item><item><title>Why it took police nine days to declare the Invasion Day attempted bomb attack in Perth terrorism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/process-to-declare-invasion-day-alleged-attack-terrorism-/106314916</link><description>When a homemade fragment bomb was allegedly thrown into a crowd on January 26, it took nine days for it to be declared an act of terrorism. The WA police commissioner explains why, as Indigenous leaders raise concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3aa7ffedfadafcc72701809222cd8964</guid></item><item><title>Showers and storms to move towards south-east Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/showers-and-storms-to-move-towards-south-east-australia-/106316116</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d88b30d6a70113381085e40d48b0101b</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Snook, The Newsreader and Bring Her Back triumph at AACTA Awards — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/aacta-awards-2026-live-blog-winners-sarah-snook-celeste-barber/106295178</link><description>Australia's answer to the Oscars — the AACTAs — lit up the Gold Coast tonight, with horror Bring Her Back and The Narrow Road to the Deep North dominating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">473742d5b25ca33648f2c7c0647748d5</guid></item><item><title>Student allegedly raped by Hobart teacher in 1980s disclosed concerns, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/hobart-matriculation-college-student-alleged-rape-trial/106314120</link><description>A student who was allegedly raped by a Hobart teacher in the 1980s was told to focus on her studies after raising concerns with the teacher's behaviour, a court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">699c796ee3d839d6dceb2b50fb9f7c92</guid></item><item><title>Accused murderer Shaun Michael Dunk told police he wanted to kill 'a few people', court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/shaun-michael-dunk-murder-trial-police-interview/106315738</link><description>A recorded police interview reveals that a man accused of killing a woman at a real estate business in Adelaide was not satisfied with his alleged murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51f8e90094cc16ff3b586f8adca7dbbc</guid></item><item><title>Friday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106316284</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">442d545004b23100d0c522b6883e3f48</guid></item><item><title>Pentagon reportedly asked to probe SpaceX for potential Chinese ownership seen as a 'national security threat'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/pentagon-asked-to-probe-spacex-chinese-ownership/106311868</link><description>Chinese investment in Elon Musk's company SpaceX has been cited as a "national security threat", according to senators Elizabeth Warren and Andy Kim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a14c66ba0a91388f5002547f0fc8165b</guid></item><item><title>Evidence concludes in inquest into psychiatric patient's death at Alice Springs Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/kumanjayi-brogus-inquest-nt-alice-springs-hospital-death/106309452</link><description>A coronial inquest has heard that the death of a 34-year-old mother who was repeatedly sedated during a schizophrenic episode was "entirely preventable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e37e11908baa219401597f522da46fe7</guid></item><item><title>AACTA 2026 winners list: Gory horror wins best film, Jacob Elordi drama dominates TV</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/aactas-winners-list-jacob-elordi-key-moments/106315590</link><description>Directors Danny and Michael Philippou clean up at the 2026 AACTA awards, taking home 10 statues for their chilling horror film Bring Her Back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">180771fbc8035cfdbeeb3540d53fab91</guid></item><item><title>TC Mitchell set to become severe category 3 system off WA's Pilbara coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/wa-pilbara-warnings-cyclone-mitchell/106314534</link><description>Residents along WA's Pilbara coast have been warned to prepare to shelter as Cyclone Mitchell builds into a severe category 3 system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b97a227aadadcc4688c45e3310259768</guid></item><item><title>Daisy Thomas, competing without an ACL, suffers heavy crash at Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/daisy-thomas-acl-milano-cortina-2026-winter-olympics/106316542</link><description>Australian freestyle skier Daisy Thomas, who is competing at the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games without an ACL, suffers a heavy fall in slopestyle training and has withdrawn from the event to focus on big air.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f025e657abeae9134b373e8a2e58473</guid></item><item><title>US accuses China of secret nuclear testing as Washington calls for Beijing to be part of new arms deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/us-accuses-china-of-secret-nuclear-testing/106316826</link><description>The claim comes as the US calls for China to be involved in a new deal limiting the use of nuclear weapons, after the New START deal expired this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cb9e860548f8785bbe0b55a630e419e</guid></item><item><title>Budget reform is back as Labor shapes second term agenda</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/interest-rate-hikes-capital-gains-tax-federal-budget/106294868</link><description>As the opposition and government wrestled in the hay barn over who's to blame for this week's Reserve Bank interest rate increase, there's a much bigger story unfolding in the wings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dc0206816713526b054a2235c2c6cbb</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's invitation to Herzog is a shift in his approach to Israel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/isaac-herzog-visit-australia/106294858</link><description>Unravelling the threads of antisemitism and anti-Israeli sentiment will require both more political courage and more community tolerance than we have seen to date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0a6a89c96284aff250024f0220ea9d0</guid></item><item><title>'Another world is possible': Calls for unity at Winter Olympics opening</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/winter-olympics-opening-ceremony-live-blog/106305458</link><description>The 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics are here, launched in an historic opening ceremony held in a number of Italian locations simultaneously.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0991b17313ac249b3564bdd43d3536aa</guid></item><item><title>Former ambassador Ian Kemish writes about Europe's 'forgotten' war in debut novel Two Islands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/ian-kemish-ambassador-book-two-islands-balkan-war/106309626</link><description>Former ambassador Ian Kemish draws on his 25-year diplomatic career in his debut novel, Two Islands, set against the backdrop of the Balkan War.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05ef96597ffb663c7a85cc4469dd35e3</guid></item><item><title>Elders say truth-telling 'critical' to combatting racism after alleged terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/perth-first-nations-elders-call-for-truth-healing-and-justice/106314644</link><description>For Noongar Elders, the alleged attack on Boorloo/Perth is viewed against the background of a long history of violence. They are calling for a truth-telling commission to heal deep scars and help to combat racism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5a4e6692d897a27ad96d0fecbf58894</guid></item><item><title>ICC T20 World Cup: Everything you need to know and who to support as a neutral cricket fan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/cricket-t20-world-cup-ultimate-guide-who-to-support/106307782</link><description>As another T20 World Cup sneaks up on us, here's everything you need to know about the tournament, including a guide on how to pick which team to support, depending on your needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">244273c35ff46c6ce067b4171a530bce</guid></item><item><title>Did Ouyen break Victoria's heat record? A Bureau of Meteorology issue means the town may never know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/missing-maximum-temperature-ouyen-heatwave-bom-rejected/106303790</link><description>It was tipped to be one of the hottest places on Earth last week, but we may never know exactly how hot it got in Ouyen — at least officially.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d0b2adc68ef3e0384ae75c5588b9f93</guid></item><item><title>Vaibhav Sooryavanshi, India's 14-year-old batting prodigy, breaks records in Under-19 World Cup final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/vaibhav-sooryavanshi-india-14yo-world-cup-final/106316944</link><description>The 14-year-old prodigy Vaibhav Sooryavanshi breaks Alyssa Healy's record with the highest score ever in a World Cup final to power India to the global under-19 crown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9a291c39d2bac1693c6f902371b6cd0</guid></item><item><title>Weather sees nationwide soaking as tropical humidity reaches south-east Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/rainy-weather-for-most-australia-due-to-tropical-humidity/106314658</link><description>Almost every corner of Australia will pick up rain during the next seven days, including heavy falls and pockets of flooding in multiple states.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7969504c93bd1af8ab23366660a7793</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide Festival leader Julian Hobba reflects on Writers' Week controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/sa-adelaide-festival-director-says-writers-week-saga-preventable/106306654</link><description>As Adelaide Writers' Week went up in flames, Julian Hobba contemplated resigning as Adelaide Festival's executive director. He now says "we needed to trust the judgement" of the literary event's former leader, Louise Adler.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6512b46457dc635dd9be1ece4907ad35</guid></item><item><title>Collision sport Run Nation Championship in Sydney sells 5,000 tickets despite head injury concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/run-nation-championship-sydney-injury-concern/106309620</link><description>The Run Nation Championship will see two athletes run at each other, in a sport criticised for its head injury risks. Organisers argue the championship has been professionalised, and will grow to be as big as boxing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23e3635bb32c11200b36934e253da646</guid></item><item><title>Golden bandicoot numbers triple at Newhaven Wildlife Sanctuary in Central Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/golden-bandicoot-population-triples-newhaven-wildlife-sanctuary/106280368</link><description>A population of threatened golden bandicoots is booming at Newhaven Wildlife Sanctuary, north-west of Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">127ab3e60e9dc2ca6cffb951c58e803e</guid></item><item><title>Meringandan collector sells vintage tractors, trucks, machines on Queensland farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/meringandan-collector-sells-vintage-tractors-trucks-machines-qld/106305032</link><description>As the last man standing, 78-year-old cattleman Mervyn has parted with his collection of tractors and utes, pledging his estate to charity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">467219dc24b07990a0bbb37f1d3c6d41</guid></item><item><title>Epstein files reaffirm even a conviction doesn't taint 'good bloke' status</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/jeffrey-epstein-good-character-reference/106307992</link><description>The rich and powerful were all too happy to stay connected to Jeffrey Epstein until it became the less convenient option.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ccb9e603f7a0840f1ddee0df072a838</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man who murdered ex-wife in kitchen believed he had been badly treated, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/act-man-faces-court-for-murdering-ex-wife-in-their-home/106315142</link><description>Disturbing new details emerge about the 2023 stabbing death of a woman in her Bruce home as her former partner faces sentencing for her murder in the ACT Supreme Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12b5a2540a02a7cc87777374c8869d52</guid></item><item><title>PFAS foam was used to extinguish a tanker crash just off the M1 Motorway at Ourimbah, on December 8, 2000.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/tanker-crash-just-off-the-m1-motorway-at-ourimbah/106303218</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">341aa7e2b3523d4ec7b91c5164453751</guid></item><item><title>‘Absolutely horrified’: Community left in the dark about PFAS contamination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/pfas-contamination-investigation-ourimbah-creek-catchment-nsw/106037472</link><description>For 25 years this waterway was polluted with toxic "forever chemicals". It was only disconnected from a major drinking supply 18 months ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8f44774d8f3802eb99d4f9f000c87ef</guid></item><item><title>Australian athletes to watch at the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/aussies-to-watch-milano-cortina-winter-olympic-games-2026/106273742</link><description>Australia is taking its strongest ever team to the Winter Olympics in 2026, with a number of genuine medal chances. Here's a handful of the stars you need to pay attention to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bd59a489c46987c65b9466b27e8d05c</guid></item><item><title>Easy homemade granola that will last you weeks - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/easy-chunky-granola-with-nuts-and-seeds/105442842</link><description>When it comes to batch cooking, don't forget breakfast. This granola can make mornings easier and will last weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a385d3e380c821e791d0def365c56e1</guid></item><item><title>What is the AIN at the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics? Why Russian and Belarusian athletes are allowed to compete in Italy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/russia-belars-winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-ain/106306898</link><description>The Winter Olympics of Milano Cortina 2026 is another where Russian and Belarusian athletes will be largely absent, although there are a handful competing as individual neutral athletes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b156810fb69debab515ba1c4d4cfceb</guid></item><item><title>Trump endorses Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi ahead of Japan's election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/trump-endorses-japan-pm-takaichi-ahead-of-sunday-election/106317102</link><description>One of Sanae Takaichi's first engagements after she was elevated to prime minister in October was to host Donald Trump in Tokyo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f8f972cb70cce67dc98a1070d0a9d46</guid></item><item><title>Nine-year-old world record deadlift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/nine-year-old-world-record-deadlift/106314846</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd226f4275ac3be2fac8723c9d6c97b5</guid></item><item><title>Family from Netherlands calls for change after 27yo dies of suspected heatstroke in remote WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/tiffani-phelps-de-wildt-suspected-heat-death-remote-australia/106301164</link><description>Tiffani Phelps de Wildt died after collapsing on a remote station in WA's north. Her family says, had they known the risks, they would have tried to stop her from going out in the heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0267267dea2a216fb1a6ff830706a4a</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 opening ceremony quick hits: Mariah Carey and Valentino Rossi ignite an historic evening as Snoop Dogg makes an appearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/winter-olympics-2026-opening-ceremony-quick-hits/106308482</link><description>Athletes parade across Italy, Mariah Carey ignites a historic evening, and 'Coach Snoop' makes an appearance at the curling. Here are the quick hits from the Milano Cortina Winter Olympics opening ceremony.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f58563c217d154493971876cd3e5b89</guid></item><item><title>A 2026 Winter Olympics opening ceremony message of harmony and peace, rammed into a world of division</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/winter-olympics-2026-opening-ceremony-chilly-global-outlook/106316092</link><description>As the Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics Opening ceremony pleads a message of peace, the world outside the Olympic bubble burns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55c5f67fe73425a4675fe57a1c27a807</guid></item><item><title>Why 13yo Austin Appelbee's story of survival resonated so strongly across the globe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/austin-appelbee-quindalup-rescue-global-phenomenon/106306482</link><description>The remarkable story of Austin Appelbee's marathon swim for help went around the world, so why did it spark such an emotional reaction?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df0506ffba50ac7075d62dfa75270cd6</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Mitchell tracker map: When will it hit Pilbara coast in WA?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/cyclone-mitchell-map-tracker-pilbara-wa/106317220</link><description>Track the path of Tropical Cyclone Mitchell and monitor wind speeds as the system approaches the Pilbara coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16f9cd90b76f66e898eb6bb581e1cd7c</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 1, Saturday, February 7</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-day-one/106287722</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46c776b730057ca497c0c6b947cce9df</guid></item><item><title>Accused militant in deadly 2012 Benghazi attack on US compound taken into custody in United States</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/libyan-zubayar-al-bakoush-arrested-extradited-america/106317146</link><description>Zubayar Al-Bakoush, 58, has been wanted by the United States for more than a decade for his alleged role in the attack, which killed four Americans, including the US ambassador to Libya.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da4c915a8eb2989c66aa09d8ca9da2bc</guid></item><item><title>The Mark of Cain lead singer on a lifetime masking the truth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/the-mark-of-cain-lead-singer-josie-scott-transgender/106315830</link><description>The lead singer of legendary Adelaide rockers The Mark of Cain this week announced she was transgender, but it comes after nearly 60 years of hiding the truth from everyone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f38fc9591c45b6185b51090540bed25</guid></item><item><title>US prosecutors seek 46-month sentence for conspiracy theorist linked to Wieambilla killers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/wieambilla-shooting-daniel-day-sentencing/106317202</link><description>US prosecutors are seeking a sentence of almost four years for a conspiracy theorist linked to the trio behind the Wieambilla shooting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecaaafab7f7a654e969eb656226771fd</guid></item><item><title>Pregnant women in WA's Kimberley face big distances to hospital and high rates of heart condition, diabetes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/pregnant-women-kimberley-high-rates-heart-condition-and-diabetes/105995596</link><description>Pregnant women in WA's Kimberley experience high rates of preventable health conditions, hours of travel to receive basic care and limited support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a989455c0a62c3be3f08588519da209</guid></item><item><title>Thailand election stakes are high as progressives mount new challenge against establishment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/thailand-election-stakes-high-as-progressives-mount-challenge/106312802</link><description>As Thailand prepares to head to the polls, voters remain wary that in their version of democracy, the party they vote for is not always the one that takes power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0569a9a2b0e10f4a080427f63b37d5b2</guid></item><item><title>What you need to know about skiing in Japan and how to keep yourself safe on the slopes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/how-to-keep-safe-skiing-and-snowboarding-in-japan/106310604</link><description>Australians flock to Japan each year to take advantage of its unique and plentiful snow, but it's not just the travel costs that are mounting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17215f0a9c755ba21ee9e86b1e92d22c</guid></item><item><title>Collectors snap up Royal Australian Mint's Queen Elizabeth II coins, despite criticism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/queen-elizabeth-ii-commemorative-coins-royal-australian-mint/106317232</link><description>The portrait of Queen Elizabeth on two coins released by the Royal Australian Mint has drawn criticism, despite proving popular with collectors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc74caa9fdd653a711ef645f3b3a0056</guid></item><item><title>Luigi Mangione speaks out against prospect of back-to-back trials over Brian Thompson's killing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/luigi-mangione-speaks-out-against-dual-state-and-federal-trials/106317270</link><description>Accused killer has spoken out in court against the prospect of back-to-back trials over the shooting of UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson, telling a judge "it's the same trial twice".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">390fec098a01b2229cd8a97c02e0ad2d</guid></item><item><title>Mayor of flood-hit Daly region accuses governments of inaction over long-term planning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/nt-long-term-flood-planning-victoria-daly-river-mayor/106317292</link><description>The Northern Territory and federal governments are being accused of failing to plan long term to protect Indigenous communities in the Victoria Daly region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86a569a8f6ddd8608406b0f482e4a898</guid></item><item><title>Latest Epstein files documents reveal links to multiple monarchies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/epstein-files-rock-global-monarchies/106316380</link><description>The latest release of the so-called Epstein files has revealed the convicted child sex offender was in contact with members of — and people close to — monarchies across Europe and the Middle East.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96f0f632ab3802486dbc61abcadd585b</guid></item><item><title>What our teeth reveal about the growing gap between rich and poor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/teeth-reveal-growing-gap-rich-poor/106314470</link><description>Teeth are one of the most visible markers of poverty: structural circumstances that are individually borne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e2a46b225f27cf30eb053acaf6146e0</guid></item><item><title>The moment turtle Terry was released from Sydney Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/the-moment-turtle-terry-was-released-from-sydney-harbour/106317662</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49c7dbf6c3e6b92b9cc8ad7b4bef2adc</guid></item><item><title>Why Wests Tigers hopeful Pat Herbert jumped off an excavator and into an NRL pre-season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/pat-herbert-nrl-wests-tigers-train-and-trial/106317620</link><description>After three years away from first grade, Pat Herbert was ready to get on with the rest of his life but a call from Wests Tigers got him off the job site and into an NRL pre-season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">916a7b8e20ff292d6a9e4fe1704fad62</guid></item><item><title>Colorado funeral home owner sentenced over nearly 200 counts of corpse abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/colorado-funeral-home-owner-sentenced-over-corpse-abuse/106317582</link><description>A funeral home owner who stashed 189 decomposing bodies in a building over four years and gave grieving families fake ashes has been sentenced to 40 years in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1ed1d9518b6ba4db182caf8b5e83261</guid></item><item><title>Daly River to hit major flood level on Sunday night, damage to homes expected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/nt-daly-river-major-flood-update-damage-evacuation/106317688</link><description>Almost 300 people from Daly River have been evacuated to Darwin, with just a handful of residents staying behind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40c7391489924e4c95d3971aa7147bfc</guid></item><item><title>Karratha residents warned to prepare for 200km/h winds as Tropical Cyclone Mitchell intensifies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/tropical-cyclone-mitchell-karratha-pilbara-dangerous-winds/106317724</link><description>While avoiding a direct hit, Karratha is still expected to feel the force of the category three cyclone as it tracks along the Pilbara coast tonight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcbcdfe98a2e5e0d8736fcde1ee1600a</guid></item><item><title>Aussie snowboarder Guseli finishes outside medals at Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/winter-olympics-day-one-live-blog-updates-guseli/106317886</link><description>Australia's Valentino Guseli falls short of reaching the podium in the men's snowboard big air final on day one of the Milano Cortino Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bcc9d97fc427e3a730c60850a929116</guid></item><item><title>If you could learn your baby's genetic disease risk at birth, would you?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/map-genome-dna-genetic-disease-newborn-screen/106305482</link><description>From rare cancers caught early to dementia foretold decades in advance, newborn genomic testing raises an unsettling question: Just because we can know, should we?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10b515034a68a9bbb421fb5da7cbb002</guid></item><item><title>How the Liberals will justify Sussan Ley's ousting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/sussan-ley-liberals-coalition-leadership-spill-angus-taylor/106295860</link><description>A permission structure has been crafted for Liberals to ditch the first woman to lead the federal party room before she has even had a year in the role.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bc84b8c3a351135cabe86c86fa06316</guid></item><item><title>Xavier Rudd on visiting Echuca, playing solo, and the spiritual being that follows him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/xavier-rudd-riverboats-tour-live-shows-solo/106299686</link><description>Xavier Rudd performs solo these days, but he carries a spirit with him wherever he goes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">524cef1858a02519f4777fc1222fcba8</guid></item><item><title>Big swings in Australia's electricity market have a frustrating effect on our power bills</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/big-swings-in-australias-electricity-market/106305696</link><description>The benefits of extremely low energy prices during the day are "washed away" by extremely high ones after dark. But there is light at the end of the tunnel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76d3f734a2bc40841c8251af34d1cd6f</guid></item><item><title>$203 million crackdown on dodgy doctors and advocates targeting veterans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/crackdown-on-doctors-advocates-targeting-veterans-fraud/106309512</link><description>Fraudsters taking advantage of people with disability now appear to be targeting veterans, prompting a $200 million crackdown by the federal government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7588808674a2c5aeb4db08c4ad599984</guid></item><item><title>After the uprising, Bangladesh returns to the ballot with its wounds still open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/bangladesh-returns-to-the-ballot-with-its-wounds-still-open/106296274</link><description>Bangladesh is heading back to the ballot box in what is being billed as its first free and fair election in more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8836801d915258a766ff8ef0bd45738e</guid></item><item><title>How Super Bowl half-time moments became flashpoints from the 'wardrobe malfunction' to caged kids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/super-bowl-half-time-show-janet-jackson-justin-timberlake/106307184</link><description>For a show that lasts roughly 13 minutes, the Super Bowl half-time performance has fuelled decades of conversation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5ff29a641957847844fbaf70655c0c1</guid></item><item><title>Australia's men and women unbeaten in Perth Sevens to set up semifinal opportunities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/australias-men-and-women-make-perfect-start-to-perth-sevens/106318568</link><description>Australia makes a hot start to the Rugby Sevens in Perth, with both the men's and women's teams going unbeaten in securing semifinal berths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efaad4c55d2717b9f28329c308b9b6f7</guid></item><item><title>As the West wakes up to the reality of the Epstein class, China plans a global reserve currency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/renminbi-global-reserve-currency/106317290</link><description>As the West reacts to the revelations in the latest batch of Epstein files, China has plans for the renminbi to become a global reserve currency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aacbcca5799241d0cad7000111351276</guid></item><item><title>Couple praise country doctors and nurses after lifesaving surgery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/couple-praise-country-doctors-and-nurses-after-aneurysm-miracle/106305104</link><description>The barking of a dog kicks off a marathon medical effort that ends in a rare lifesaving surgery at a remote hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bff35ee1456e0b1df2284729b9f134e0</guid></item><item><title>United States send India a T20 World Cup scare before Suryakumar Yadav settles hosts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/india-survives-massive-scare-from-minnow-us-in-t20-world-cup/106318592</link><description>India is briefly left reeling at 6-67 against an underdog United States team, but captain Suryakumar Yadav helps the hosts avoid a horror start at the T20 World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b4cfa036b792e7378042063ed8c7311</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Mitchell continues to hit the Pilbara as Karratha residents start cleanup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/cyclone-mitchell-karratha-impact-pilbara/106317910</link><description>Onslow, Exmouth and Coral Bay remain in the firing line, while an emergency warning for Karratha has been lifted, as Tropical Cyclone Mitchell continues to track along the Pilbara coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fe5302b9c687a897ae146d07cc4a7ec</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 day one quick hits: Mariah Carey accused of lip-syncing, Eileen Gu channels inner 'nerd'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/winter-olympics-2026-day-one-quick-hits/106318022</link><description>A Finnish skier makes a questionable fashion choice on the slopes, while Mariah Carey faces claims she was lip-syncing at the opening ceremony. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdbe8b25341547e8aee34f10f9adff31</guid></item><item><title>Seasonal Australian produce to make the most of in February</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/february-seasonal-fruit-and-veg/106308194</link><description>From grapes to red capsicum, here's how to prioritise some of this season's best fruit and veg.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5184a825d458dccc2d1d1b5d79ff1709</guid></item><item><title>Lee Lovell calls for expansion to victim of crime assistance as Queensland government makes almost $500 million in payments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/qld-victim-of-crime-payments-500-million-lee-lovell/106314616</link><description>The ABC can reveal the state government has paid almost $500 million to tens of thousands of victims of crime over the past three financial years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa487ea4337837a8f2fdf2b866171337</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania looks at allowing public hospital midwives to help with homebirths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/tasmania-looks-at-homebirth-model/105899984</link><description>The Tasmanian government is developing a public homebirth model that would allow midwives working in the public system to support women to labour from their homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b288cd9590708ea54ac6e8efd974f327</guid></item><item><title>How a Canberra-based refugee fled the Maduro regime along with millions of other Venezuelans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/act-how-a-venezuelan-fled-the-maduro-regime/106313290</link><description>Josh Madrid was arrested for attending a pro-democracy protest in Venezuela. 24 hours later, he fled his homeland, fearing he would be killed by the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d635939cd740a309d45cc1fc12ccddb7</guid></item><item><title>New hope for national gun register 30 years after it was first proposed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/new-hope-for-national-gun-register/106305464</link><description>First proposed after the Port Arthur massacre in 1996, Australia still doesn't have a national gun register. As Queensland parliament sits for the first time since national gun reforms became law, advocates say it is time to centralise firearm information.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74192cdd2461fea71f9cbad573cf1db5</guid></item><item><title>Coalition reunited after last-minute deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/deal-done-to-bring-coalition-back-together/102760848</link><description>The Liberals and Nationals have reached a breakthrough deal to reunite the Coalition after 11th-hour talks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03d631d89d350d9986b7badfae6006de</guid></item><item><title>Heat and fires expose ancestral remains in Victoria's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/heat-fires-expose-ancestral-remains-in-victorian-mallee/106304308</link><description>Ancestral remains that could be thousands of years old have been uncovered by erosion, dust storms and bushfires in Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49ce14146e6918e7cee89f1e59175fb2</guid></item><item><title>The slow death of Keir Starmer's prime ministership after Peter Mandelson's 'betrayal'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/keir-starmer-leadership-peril-over-mandelson-epstein-scanda/106318588</link><description>Starmer's decision to hand the plum job of UK ambassador in Washington to Lord Peter Mandelson, despite knowing Mandelson had maintained a friendship with Jeffrey Epstein well past Epstein's conviction for soliciting underage prostitution, may simply be too large an error of judgement for the public to accept.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">397ccf8ff9c1e397f0aa8049cd1433d1</guid></item><item><title>Before opening Meg's Bookshop in 1991, the Arnolds were told kids 'didn't read' in Port Pirie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/meg-s-bookshop-port-pirie-closes-after-35-years-south-australia/106277430</link><description>In one of Australia's most disadvantaged regions, more known for its lead than its literature, a couple wanted to open a book store but were told children didn't read books there. They did it anyway, and it went on to become a "world class" institution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">488cbf932021fe26386b52895acbaa59</guid></item><item><title>Valentino Guseli missed out on a bonus 2026 Winter Olympics medal, but won something even more important</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/valentino-guseli-2026-winter-olympics-big-air-snowboard/106318724</link><description>It was 18 months ago that Valentino Guseli blew out his ACL attempting a backside 1800 at the Beijing big air. At the Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics snowboard big air final, he put that ghost to rest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6cb85fcb30e9b60ce1daa388c5f7d61</guid></item><item><title>3 Doors Down frontman Brad Arnold dies after stage four cancer battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/3-doors-down-frontman-brad-arnold-dies/106318798</link><description>Brad Arnold, a founder and the lead singer of American rock band 3 Doors Down, dies nine months after revealing he had kidney cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cbbceb57b53ce8d7ad340e98b862894</guid></item><item><title>Train delays in Italy during Winter Olympics opening weekend after damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/winter-olympics-italy-railway-sabotage-allegations/106318876</link><description>Police are investigating three incidents of damage on lines around Bologna, and have not ruled out a potential link to the Milan Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54f40c4b9d300363d1667f309b32f0dd</guid></item><item><title>Jim Chalmers says next federal budget will focus on lifting economy's 'speed limit'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/may-federal-budget-to-focus-on-lifting-speed-limit-on-economy/105435282</link><description>Treasurer Jim Chalmers says the federal government's budget in May will focus on productivity, spending restraint and tax reform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da4b1c57606aca371fd50217191fb699</guid></item><item><title>Equine photography in demand in Australian performance horse industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/equine-photography-in-demand-in-performance-horse-industry/106298426</link><description>From leaf blowers to dance moves, photographers use every trick they can think of to get the perfect shot for the biggest performance-horse sale in the southern hemisphere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22805fcce898863bfe3fedf070b53d08</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 2, Sunday, February 8</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-tess-coady/106307392</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f9218347b9ff96081f5253512a17b47</guid></item><item><title>Why young people say they are not the only ones hooked on screens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/generational-screen-time-brain-rot/106278964</link><description>The focus of discussion around screen time is on teenagers and young adults, but young people say they are noticing older people are in the grips of their devices too.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72ffc41b830d319fbaf67593d8e5438e</guid></item><item><title>Man dead, five others hospitalised after Sydney's Dreamstate music festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/nsw-dreamstate-man-dead-five-hospitalised-sydney/106318948</link><description>Several people suffered "medical episodes" at the trance music festival at Sydney's Olympic Park, according to police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb0b81cbc6c892cc70ef52c02bb20db5</guid></item><item><title>New Zealanders hoped never to see the Christchurch terrorist again. Now he wants to appeal his sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/new-zealanders-hoped-never-to-see-christchurch-terrorist-again/106317996</link><description>Extraordinary arrangements are in place in Wellington, New Zealand, as a convicted terrorist prepares to address the country's Court of Appeal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23b0ec4742644544facc21fdb7ac1d84</guid></item><item><title>Piper James's parents say dingo management reform needed to prevent further deaths on K'gari</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/piper-james-parents-call-for-more-dingo-warnings-on-kgari/106317706</link><description>Piper James's parents are leaving Australia with their daughter's ashes and a determination to ensure she hasn't died in vain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ccf19d954997c8989ad2001fd781236</guid></item><item><title>Palestine Action Group takes court action against extra police powers ahead of protests against Israeli president's Sydney visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/palestine-action-group-to-challenge-police-powers-herzog-visit/106319078</link><description>The Palestine Action Group lodged submissions late on Sunday afternoon, arguing the declaration was "draconian" and imposed rules unsuitable for protest activity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d620aa168abe72abd53aa441463941cb</guid></item><item><title>Payne Haas quits Brisbane to sign three-year deal with South Sydney Rabbitohs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/payne-haas-signs-with-south-sydney-for-2027/106319316</link><description>South Sydney have pulled off one of the biggest recruitment moves in NRL history after signing Brisbane enforcer Payne Haas to a three-year contract from 2027.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4006492fb182ade2ddeeb67451c5ec53</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian government says illegal tobacco sales crackdown will deliver some of the 'toughest' laws in the country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/tasmanian-illegal-tobacco-vapes-crackdown/106318886</link><description>The Tasmanian government announces increased penalties for those caught selling illegal tobacco products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abb1e0b80c97bfdd83a60a814abd6175</guid></item><item><title>In the Australian outback, we're listening for nuclear tests. What we hear matters more than ever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/australian-outback-nuclear-tests-listening-warramunga-facility/106307478</link><description>As the New START treaty curbing the US and Russian nuclear weapons programs expires, the work we do here in the red centre has become more important than ever before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0e5b08cded46dedfceb1992d9d6b4b6</guid></item><item><title>WA photographers reminisce about bygone Goldfields era as gold's price surges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/photographers-remember-bygone-era-wa-gold-prospecting/106299710</link><description>In 1989, two photographers travelled from Fremantle to Western Australia's Goldfields to capture the end of a gold mining era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83d7ae07fe11c173f4fe0efc06d5eacf</guid></item><item><title>Police recover pilot's body from croc-infested marsh after Normanton plane crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/police-recover-pilot-body-normanton-plane-crash/106319446</link><description>Police officers armed with rifles guarded their colleagues while they recovered the man's body from the crash site in difficult terrain near Normanton, in the Gulf of Carpentaria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6bcdff91b2f00027265cf151c25bc13</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberals promise new stamp duty concessions, Labor tackles aged care bed backlog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/sa-liberal-party-stamp-duty-election-promise/106318938</link><description>Less than six weeks from the South Australian election, the Liberal Party has announced an election promise on stamp duty while the Labor government unveil its plan to create 1,300 new aged care beds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6efd5f5722fbf5b7fcc9dba155108442</guid></item><item><title>Daly River flooding expected to reach 14m peak on Monday, as first damage to homes reported</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/nt-daly-river-flooding-homes-damaged-ahead-of-monday-peak/106318936</link><description>Several homes in the remote community of Daly River have sustained minor flood damage, as waters continue to rise ahead of an expected 14m peak level on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe93bd355478f5142fa25e391a32a338</guid></item><item><title>Two Australians reach big air final after tense qualifying runs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/winter-olympics-day-two-live-blog-updates/106319558</link><description>Olympic medallist Tess Coady and fellow Australian Meila Stalker reach the snowboard big air final, after a dramatic day where American superstar Lindsey Vonn crashes in women's downhill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eabe2255ae86c9fbbf5b0a4f952c27ac</guid></item><item><title>Grandmother Bishnu Kumari Gurung killed as car ploughs into Perth home, family pays tribute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/bishnu-kumari-gurung-himali-killed-rivervale-house-crash/106319748</link><description>The family of a grandmother who died sleeping in bed when a car crashed into a Perth home pays tribute to her in an emotional press conference, after a man is charged with manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2de2519b4d66efba2a889f992fe3603d</guid></item><item><title>Danish people using apps to help boycott American goods over Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/greenland-denmark-app-boycott-us-made-goods-donald-trump/106319620</link><description>After Donald Trump's repeated threats to acquire Greenland, many Danish people felt powerless but new apps are helping them make choices to boycott US-made products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2297548a311c1a6d4f30bc1eec67099</guid></item><item><title>Lindsey Vonn's horror crash at the 2026 Winter Olympic Games was always on the cards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/lindsey-vonn-2026-winter-olympic-games-horror-downhill-crash/106319806</link><description>Lindsey Vonn's shocking downhill crash at the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games was always a possibility given the American was competing just nine days after rupturing her ACL. But it was never going to stop her from trying.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3298a9e82bd89310260dbbb7b476aef6</guid></item><item><title>Man extradited from Dubai to Moscow over top Russian general's shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/russian-general-shooting-dubai-moscow-extradition/106319910</link><description>Lieutenant General Vladimir Alexeyev is the deputy head of Russia's vast GRU military intelligence service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a718dd9de19d878789e384eddfec8f8</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Mitchell downgraded to category one system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/tropical-cyclone-mitchell-downgraded-to-category-one-system/106319648</link><description>Residents are sheltering as destructive winds and heavy rain lash the tourist towns in north-west WA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e2ddb87fca8e99040d2e0b173b590de</guid></item><item><title>One Nation capitalises on anti-immigration sentiment in a housing crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/one-nation-pauline-hanson-housing-crisis-immigration/106304670</link><description>Pauline Hanson might not have any substantive policies, but her rhetoric about reducing migration is clearly finding an audience.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23968ca9459afcd8c2cf60c2582e68d7</guid></item><item><title>Coalition's rushed reunification does not solve their respective branding problems</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/coalition-reunification-liberals-nationals-sussan-ley/106304664</link><description>The Coalition has reunited, but the new agreement does not address underlying party tensions nor the surging fragmentation of the right.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4015c0b9e86f13b0cbf1a5cc8413b8c5</guid></item><item><title>Telstra mobile tower sparks backlash in St Helens despite poor phone coverage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/st-helens-locals-concerns-about-telstra-phone-tower/106308180</link><description>It's known for fishing boats, a pristine coast, a skyline without a high-rise in sight — and notoriously patchy phone reception. So, a new phone tower would be welcome, you'd think.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53ab70f898080072416904e0da0192b7</guid></item><item><title>The Tasmania Devils start selling memberships later this month — how will they work?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/tasmania-devils-membership-reserved-seating-how-will-it-work/106315102</link><description>The Tasmania Devils will start signing up members later this month, but there's some confusion about what is required to secure a seat for AFL games in 2028. Here's how it will work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb0c918108d8e59c0b88b8f5e5d450ae</guid></item><item><title>Five simple steps to saving cash (while still having a life)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/finance-tips-saving-money-new-year/106303046</link><description>Saving money is not about beating yourself up. It's also not about depriving yourself of all sources of joy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59b760f5e77d65279a49b68106aa5c6d</guid></item><item><title>This week in history quiz, February 9: How well do you know the past?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/this-week-in-history-quiz/106276538</link><description>Groundhog Day, an audacious art theft and a new chief mouser: how well do you remember these events?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34b2c03bbdcecbeecdee865a592b0059</guid></item><item><title>Young people could get massive pay boost in 'totemic' wage case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/millions-of-young-people-could-get-massive-pay-boost-in-totemic/106101186</link><description>"I'm paying adult fuel with still a child's wage," says Ben Walker, one of the almost half a million young people who could see a huge boost to their wage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c8ac9ab718a2220257ac5a49545a466</guid></item><item><title>UK prime minister's chief of staff Morgan McSweeney quits amid Epstein fallout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/morgan-mcsweeney-resigns-epstein-mandelson/106320216</link><description>Sir Keir Starmer's leadership is under threat after revelations that one of his former US ambassadors had close ties with Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cee5f2015f6214e64864f3870d049084</guid></item><item><title>Japan PM Sanae Takaichi leads coalition to landslide election victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/japan-election-sanae-takaichi-landslide-victory/106320228</link><description>Sanae Takaichi's Liberal Democratic Party and its coalition partner are expected to hold upwards of two-thirds of the seats in Japan's lower house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fb71b428c5bbf7507c7f3ce7b77658c</guid></item><item><title>$740m veterans plan to fund social 'rehabilitation' and psychedelic treatments for PTSD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/veterans-funding-social-rehabilitation-mdma-ptsd/106309994</link><description>A $740 million program will expand support for veterans and include funding for social activities such as yoga and language classes, with new treatment including MDMA and psilocybin for the worst forms of PTSD also funded for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fae87a317eaabd51c41fe0364bba0f6b</guid></item><item><title>Ghislaine Maxwell to testify before US Congress as Epstein files reveal more about her role</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/epstein-files-spotlight-maxwells-role/106313368</link><description>This week, Ghislaine Maxwell could be a very unwelcome distraction for Donald Trump as she appears before one of America's top political institutions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d78d90e2cb3b37efeeb57864347d1e6</guid></item><item><title>Thailand PM Anutin Charnvirakul confident of forming government after election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/thailand-election-result-anutin-results/106320270</link><description>South-East Asia's second-largest economy went to the polls on Sunday in a tight race between conservatives aligned with the military and the monarchy, and progressive elements represented by the reform-driven People's Party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea445c2de3e44242cdf9e5b0f4e49cf0</guid></item><item><title>Investors driving up regional house prices with some buying sight unseen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/regional-housing-investors-driving-up-prices/106298600</link><description>Local buyers are facing stiff competition from outside investors, with regional house price rises tipped to continue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">580552bc67817077cc0f778f4d6c40d8</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Diamonds smash Jamaica again to seal three-game series in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/all-too-easy-for-the-diamonds-in-sealing-series-win-over-jamaica/106320414</link><description>Kate Moloney celebrates her 50-game milestone in style as the Australian Diamonds post a 32-goal victory over an understrength Jamaica in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17c58aaad7fd1ed71acafd10afe3d217</guid></item><item><title>Why Payne Haas's move from Brisbane to South Sydney changes the game for two NRL giants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/payne-haas-brisbane-broncos-south-sydney-nrl/106319624</link><description>Payne Haas's decision to leave Brisbane for South Sydney in 2027 didn't just shock the rugby league world, it transformed the futures of two of rugby league's most powerful clubs in an instant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3870c2c914c0402e56a618be411dd7e9</guid></item><item><title>Japanese prime minister confirms sweeping election win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/japanese-prime-minister-confirms-sweeping-election-win-/106320386</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">384bb30f1e8e2c1d75e666b3ce5bab10</guid></item><item><title>Businessman and bad gambler Sam Kanjo linked to Australia's biggest illegal tobacco fine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/sam-kanjo-linked-to-australias-biggest-illegal-tobacco-fine/106286014</link><description>He's been declared bankrupt repeatedly, and was a gambling addict. Now he's linked to a $1.5 million fine for illegal tobacco.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f50f644637f1f8f64249db0e52537e9</guid></item><item><title>Australia's women beaten by New Zealand in Perth Sevens final, but men claim bronze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/aussie-women-settle-for-perth-sevens-silver-new-zealand/106320454</link><description>The Australian women are forced to settle for silver at the Perth Sevens, while the Aussie men claim bronze in thrilling fashion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23861d2dad88948210d071dce4f97e17</guid></item><item><title>Green turtle released from Taronga Zoo's wildlife hospital after horror injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/green-turtle-released-taronga-zoo-after-fishing-line-injury/106317556</link><description>After surviving one of the worst fishing line injuries vet Rebecca Robey had ever seen, Terry the turtle has been set free.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b197fd3fc2005d27d37f85e98809f573</guid></item><item><title>Bullying surges in ACT public schools as parents, teachers speak out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/bullying-reports-rise-in-act-public-schools/106269450</link><description>Reports of bullying in ACT public schools have risen sharply in four years. Parents and teachers say children are paying the price, and the system is not coping.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7cda36cd7ac7cd9196735a6516e4323</guid></item><item><title>Extreme heat returning for south-east Queensland before weekend showers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/queensland-weather-heat-showers/106319132</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology is forecasting "locally severe heatwave conditions" from Tuesday, culminating in a maximum of 35 degrees in Brisbane on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b30ddf4d4ab44e838d7d574f7e1be3ec</guid></item><item><title>ASX jumps 1.9 per cent in $60b rally, another Optus exec sacked — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-january-09/106319466</link><description>The ASX has recouped the losses of last week with a broad-based $60 billion rally.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1e7915364d79ad3062ddde2e4b76baa</guid></item><item><title>Labor faces questions on economic management in QT — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/federal-politics-ley-littleproud-albanese-coalition-estimates/106314548</link><description>Labor has faced questioning over its economic management in Question Time today as the government returned fire over the Coalition's leadership woes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">044df03007b1052227e072f6d5ea3299</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout opts out of Commonwealth Games as he seeks to follow in Usain Bolt's footsteps</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/gout-gout-out-commonwealth-games-usain-bolt/106320530</link><description>Sprint sensation Gout Gout pulls out of the Glasgow Commonwealth Games in a major blow to the Australian team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a577baa77f3c2a9c5823e922dfd5551</guid></item><item><title>Israeli President Isaac Herzog tells Sydney event antisemitism has been 'festering' in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/nsw-sydney-israeli-president-isaac-herzog-lands-bondi-attack/106320482</link><description>Isaac Herzog was invited by the governor-general and prime minister to join the Jewish community grieving the loss of life in the December 14 massacre of mostly Jewish Australians at a Hanukkah event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8477437267014ce2c5d1873b72d0a6d</guid></item><item><title>Mother claims missed warning signs in NT hospital led to baby's lifelong disabilities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/mother-claims-nt-hospital-missed-warning-signs-during-birth/106273516</link><description>Mia Pilbrow is taking legal action against a Northern Territory hospital and calling for the territory to adopt tailored pre-term labour guidelines, after medical staff sent her home seven times during her pregnancy, repeatedly assuring her the baby was fine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d45744f2a0878ebedd4d9fb2b49e40b6</guid></item><item><title>As AFL prepares to reboot State of Origin, there are hopes it can capture the imagination of a new generation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/afl-state-of-origin-game-does-it-have-place-in-modern-footy/105781418</link><description>The AFL is about to reboot the State of Origin concept, with the clash between Western Australia and Victoria at Perth Stadium next Saturday — on Valentine's Day — set to show if there's any love left for the idea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c46379064496246d0108e4942b1d209</guid></item><item><title>Explain the Internet: Why Wuthering Heights is one of the year's most controversial adaptations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/wuthering-heights-controversy-emerald-fennell-jacob-elordi/106305404</link><description>Days away from the release of Emerald Fennell's highly anticipated adaptation of Emily Brontë's classic novel, critics and fans alike are still fighting about text fidelity in the comments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51691c38c09e7e812fe2f8ae70e9ae0d</guid></item><item><title>Deua River Valley and Cobargo still rebuilding six years after Black Summer bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/cobargo-deua-river-still-rebuilding-after-black-summer-bushfires/106273804</link><description>Residents who lived through the 2019-20 bushfires on the NSW South Coast say this summer's fires triggered traumatic memories, and highlighted the recovery and resilience projects that remain unfinished.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75a6395d574e8ce915a53455bd5abe17</guid></item><item><title>Liberals despair at prospect of 'non-existence' and weigh leadership change after catastrophic Newspoll</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/liberals-despair-after-disastrous-poll-weigh-sussan-ley-spill/106320642</link><description>Sussan Ley could face a challenge to her leadership from Angus Taylor this week after a disastrous opinion poll showed the Coalition parties falling further behind One Nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d6794b583bc82ebb66b82a29f4dee89</guid></item><item><title>Kimberley cotton hits record high in first season with new processing gin in Kununurra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/kimberley-growers-wrap-up-first-season-processing-cotton-locally/106303718</link><description>From farm to fabric, West Australian cotton growers are finally able to grow, process and export record amounts of cotton locally.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">463c2f3636108857669737fceede0d6c</guid></item><item><title>Aussie stars as Seahawks use ferocious defence to claim Super Bowl win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/super-bowl-lx-live-blog-seahawks-vs-patriots-bad-bunny/106320762</link><description>The Seattle Seahawks overawe the New England Patriots in Super Bowl LX as punter Michael Dickson becomes the second ever Australian NFL champion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fad6557763c143875756ac2daf86b7c</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian minister Nick Duigan to go on medical leave for heart surgery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/minister-nick-duigan-takes-leave-to-undergo-heart-surgery/106320766</link><description>Tasmanian minister Nick Duigan will take extended medical leave to undergo heart surgery, the state government has announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f674506d34ea92eed94098d36ef4d93</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Lindsey Vonn breaks her leg, Breezy Johnson breaks her gold medal — quick hits from day two</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/winter-olympics-2026-day-two-quick-hits-lindsey-vonn/106319962</link><description>US great Lindsey Vonn breaks her leg, and her compatriot breaks her gold medal as Tess Coady sneaks through to the final after a nervous wait on the bubble. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">271eb82bfbfbeb3c22aa7602ccb93659</guid></item><item><title>Cyclists slam 'nightmare' shared path at new Sydney Fish Market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/cyclists-slam-shared-path-at-new-sydney-fish-market/106307556</link><description>The decision to put a shared bike path in front of the new Sydney Fish Market is causing a clash between commuter cyclists and visitors to the site, riders say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53e99d860ab88303dcd0b2c2dabf0a99</guid></item><item><title>'Punitive' bail law amendments have increased and First Nations people are affected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/bail-law-amendments-resulting-in-more-first-nation-remands/106315210</link><description>A study has found increasing "punitive" bail law amendments are negatively affecting First Nations people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bebd2244ed8d3de1cb17c7226d169513</guid></item><item><title>Thousands rally around Australia as protests against Herzog's visit turn violent— as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/isaac-herzog-to-visit-israel-president-bondi-attacks/106320994</link><description>Thousands of people have gathered across Australia to protest the visit of Israeli President Isaac Herzog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0cf37da38773a17a6f3be276ce40f06</guid></item><item><title>Darkwaves research allows scientists to measure impact of 'underwater blackouts' on marine life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/darkwaves-research-scientists-measure-impact-on-marine-life/106314712</link><description>For the first time a group of international scientists have measured the impact of what happens to marine life when the lights go out underwater.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70eaaa35d2df02cbcf1d34ac0e2a4c3b</guid></item><item><title>Greens politician Kat McNamara quits NT parliament 18 months after historic Nightcliff win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/nt-greens-mla-kat-mcnamara-quits-politics/106320616</link><description>Kat McNamara is leaving the role effectively immediately due to "ongoing health challenges". It comes 18 months after she became the first Greens candidate to win a seat in NT parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce0325863d6027503a10b02026025aa3</guid></item><item><title>Backyard pods won't fix the housing crisis but they signal a shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/backyard-pods-wont-fix-the-housing-crisis/106314472</link><description>Australia's biggest hardware retailer has started selling tiny homes. Are backyard pods the answer to a national housing crisis?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dd2b8a3992ec554b10d8b236bba7c64</guid></item><item><title>Iran sentences Nobel Peace Prize winner Narges Mohammadi to six more years in prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/nobel-peace-laureate-narges-mohammadi-sentenced-iran/106314130</link><description>Women's rights activist Narges Mohammadi is sentenced to a further six years in jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a361ee5a20a3e359c2b25fbca523621</guid></item><item><title>Broome North Primary School students swelter through wet season with broken air conditioning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/broome-school-air-conditioning-issues/106314502</link><description>Classroom temperatures at Broome North Primary School in the Kimberley are reportedly pushing 30 degrees, with long-reported air conditioning breakdowns yet to be fixed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e74e6078bd7ccad5c759b5dfabc6f7a</guid></item><item><title>Laura Tingle says Herzog visit links Israel's actions with antisemitism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/laura-tingle-says-herzog-visit-links-israel-s-actions/106321346</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5abb16cc18541b821c47d76abcaa06b4</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 3, Monday, February 9</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-holly-harris-jason-chan/106307460</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b8f3992831865843a3ea28399b9cf1f</guid></item><item><title>HESTA CEO Debby Blakey resigns after superannuation administration outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/hesta-superannuation-ceo-debby-blakey-resigns/106321478</link><description>HESTA's boss is calling it quits after 11 years in the role. Her exit follows an outage that left members unable to access their accounts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2aa4f7459e81fc5b96c6dfeaeae7d5b</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Lindsey Vonn hailed as 'idol' by downhill rivals after Milano Cortina crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/winter-olympics-rivals-pay-credit-to-lindsey-vonn/106320254</link><description>Lindsey Vonn's 2026 Winter Olympic Games ended in disaster, but her teammates and rivals have heaped praise on the three-time Olympic medallist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d1e30943c1086fc7cce481c2af84273</guid></item><item><title>Jon Kudelka, Walkley-winning Tasmanian cartoonist, dies from brain cancer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/jon-kudelka-tasmanian-cartoonist-dies/106321714</link><description>Award-winning Tasmanian cartoonist Jon Kudelka dies after being diagnosed with brain cancer in 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b64794da6dd1ff79a97006ebfd7d1f1b</guid></item><item><title>Christchurch terrorist gives testimony in NZ appeal court as he attempts to vacate guilty pleas over 2019 attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/christchurch-terrorist-in-court-of-appeal/106320628</link><description>The convicted Christchurch terrorist and murderer is giving testimony in the New Zealand Court of Appeal as he seeks to vacate his guilty pleas over his 2019 attack on two mosques.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7059761925b534c1c89ac119dab5a9e9</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong media mogul Jimmy Lai sentenced to 20 years in landmark case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/hong-kong-media-mogul-jimmy-lai-sentenced-to-20-years-jail/106321070</link><description>Jimmy Lai, one of Hong Kong's most outspoken critics of China, has learned his fate after being sentenced this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03525059e67690dbcf8a35c0db81456f</guid></item><item><title>Independent inquiry launched into NACC chief's handling of defence ties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/independent-inquiry-launched-into-nacc-chief-defence-ties/106320954</link><description>The body responsible for holding the federal integrity watchdog to account will formally investigate it for agency maladministration and its chief, Paul Brereton, for officer misconduct.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9eb72c36c774cffcae6b73bcb70d699</guid></item><item><title>Mitchell Freeway head-on crash in Butler leaves two dead after ute driven on wrong side of road</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/two-people-dead-after-mitchell-freeway-butler-head-on-crash/106321408</link><description>A 56-year-old-woman and a 24-year-old man are dead after a head-on collision involving a utility that was being driven on the wrong side of the Mitchell Freeway in Perth's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">366c71a2ba852d44551f4bb42a51335e</guid></item><item><title>Rain brings relief and road closures after record heatwave in South Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/rain-brings-relief-and-road-closures-in-outback-sa/106321082</link><description>High rainfall in north-eastern South Australia brings some relief for pastoralists after record-breaking heat, with a reprieve expected for metropolitan Adelaide this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8abb8433aa6e8a46aaa308bd29d9653</guid></item><item><title>Five simple, tasty vegetarian recipes that are perfect for meat-free Mondays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/five-simple-tasty-vegetarian-recipes-for-meat-free-monday/106309846</link><description>Looking to add some more vegetarian dishes to your weekly rotation? We have you covered with these five recipes that are perfect for meat-free Mondays.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8ccc6ae83e7b914cda93001f414be5d</guid></item><item><title>Queensland coroner hears father showed no concern for children caught in fatal house fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/fatal-queensland-house-fire-inquest/106322354</link><description>An inquest has started probing a fatal house fire, with a coroner tasked with trying to determine what sparked it and whether either parent may have been involved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78710984851c5b1a448311680b813808</guid></item><item><title>NFL Super Bowl LX quick hits: Mack Hollins dresses as a prisoner, Bad Bunny hosts a wedding and Michael Dickson's punts help Seattle Seahawks win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/nfl-super-bowl-lx-quick-hits-mack-hollins-bad-bunny-/106321254</link><description>The most important match of the NFL season crowns a champion, but also provides eye-catching moments on and off the field. Here are five quick hits from Super Bowl LX.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1dd04beb634bf19744e31966ae73569</guid></item><item><title>Dimitri D'Elio, Kylie Stott jailed for Christmas Eve killing of Charlie Gander in Bunbartha, Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/charlie-gander-dimitri-delio-murder-manslaughter-sentence/106320770</link><description>Charlie Gander’s body was found in a burnt-out car on a country road on Christmas Eve, 2022. Today, two people were sentenced to a combined 36 years in prison over his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d3f8fc30d2257d50cb749a40e84e872</guid></item><item><title>Family rallies to save pets left behind in Daly River flood evacuation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/family-creates-makeshift-animal-shelter-daly-river-flooding-nt/106319036</link><description>When hundreds of people evacuated the Daly River community due to flooding, most had to leave their pets behind. But a nearby family swung into action to help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a64bdce8d15fa7b49eb8035ac084d64d</guid></item><item><title>Bad Bunny's Super Bowl half-time show features surprise guests Lady Gaga and Ricky Martin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/bad-bunny-super-bowl-half-time-show-lady-gaga-ricky-martin/106321192</link><description>Global superstar Bad Bunny performs at the Super Bowl LX, sharing the stage with surprise guests Lady Gaga and Ricky Martin, while a couple weds on stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">991a08560eae442223c0026326bb6a2b</guid></item><item><title>Ben Batterham receives payout from NSW government for wrongful prosecution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/ben-batterham-gets-payout-from-state-for-wrongful-prosecution/106322122</link><description>A Newcastle man will receive a confidential payout from the NSW government for wrongful prosecution by police for an alleged home invasion murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6c1ff78372dd9ba63fb088e5a78ed5e</guid></item><item><title>SpaceX to build 'self-growing city' on Moon, Elon Musk says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/spacex-building-lunar-self-gowing-city-moon-elon-musk/106322472</link><description>Billionaire chief executive says the company will shift its focus from Mars and the project could be achieved within 10 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60090cd3e2417da1cd2217d495e8de23</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos captain Adam Reynolds announces retirement at end of NRL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/brisbane-broncos-captain-adam-reynolds-announces-nrl-retirement/106322932</link><description>Adam Reynolds will finish his stellar career at the end of the season after fulfilling his Broncos mission to perfection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">169322d9299a44e0989b53593be68e74</guid></item><item><title>Palestine Action Group loses court challenge to extra police powers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/palestine-action-group-loses-extra-police-powers-legal-battle/106320780</link><description>A Supreme Court challenge was launched by Palestine Action Group on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75d84690f8d9c2aec306eebd3c63f75c</guid></item><item><title>New gun ownership laws announced by Queensland Premier David Crisafulli</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/queensland-gun-laws-premier-bondi-response/106322868</link><description>The laws aim to crack down on rising gun crime and include tougher penalties for drive-by shootings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9e0505970320f994bd598f7cdc457d3</guid></item><item><title>Inside Minnesotan homes these people are hiding from ICE and living in fear for their children and parents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/inside-minnesota-familes-at-risk-from-ice-arrest-speak-out/106322022</link><description>What was once a hindrance is now "a paranoia like I've never known before", one Minnesotan man says, as his family hides from immigration agents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b02e0fe5c465309c1c3d7f4d3c6850a</guid></item><item><title>Daly River expected to surpass major flood level before reaching peak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/nt-daly-river-expected-to-reach-major-flood-level-today/106320860</link><description>Flooding at the Daly River community is expected to surpass the major flood level late Monday, with a peak of 14.1 metres expected by Tuesday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee956724ec301301f81352410e8d51f8</guid></item><item><title>Heavy rain in central Australia causes celebration and concern</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/heavy-rain-central-australia-causes-celebration-concern/106321708</link><description>Rain across central Australia has been welcomed at cattle stations, but flooding and road damage have cut off some remote communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f942437247ff1b6fcb96ff6e4bb6f47c</guid></item><item><title>Crocodile wrangler Matt Wright fined $10k for landing helicopter in backyard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/nt-outback-wranger-matt-wright-fined-landing-helicopter-backyard/106321446</link><description>The Netflix star, who is currently behind bars on unrelated charges, pleaded guilty to a single count for landing his chopper and taking off in the backyard of his former home in Darwin's rural area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a84969dedee4c7c55505ce6e58c62f1d</guid></item><item><title>Police and protesters clash in Sydney rally against Israeli President Issac Herzog's visit to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/crowds-protest-israeli-president-isaac-herzog-in-australia/106321716</link><description>Thousands of people attend protests across the country against Israeli President Isaac Herzog's visit to Australia in the wake of the Bondi terror attack, with demonstrators in Sydney sprayed with pepper spray and led away in handcuffs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf9c9e3b1bab97471914ed882c6b5903</guid></item><item><title>Heavy police presence at Sydney Town Hall as protesters gather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/heavy-police-presence-at-sydney-town-hall-as-protesters-gather/106323658</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6890622b1f36b1d8373ef68a68fcec15</guid></item><item><title>Another Optus tech 'issue' affects hundreds of thousands of customers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/optus-tech-issue-affects-customers-no-service/106323474</link><description>Optus says an issue is affecting mobile services for some customers, who are seeing "no service" or "SOS" on their device.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47d7fc7e21afa43e3c80749b4b4950a2</guid></item><item><title>Families of Laos methanol poisoning victims say they've been left in the dark on investigations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/laos-methanol-poisoining-bianca-jones-holly-morton-bowles/106321336</link><description>The families of Bianca Jones and Holly Morton-Bowles say they have been left in the dark following the 2024 poisoning deaths of their daughters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2580145a0bf20f8945a54bc153c8c054</guid></item><item><title>Sanae Takaichi's stomping victory will have profound consequences for Australia and the Asia-Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/japanese-pm-sanae-takaichi-s-election-victory/106323082</link><description>A stomping victory by the ruling coalition government of Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi has opened the way for a major geo-strategic realignment in the Asia-Pacific region, with big implications for Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65ca2c9fe328e0e0981fb58f90e534b5</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106323636</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">968ecebb9b9600345e1566ed32833449</guid></item><item><title>Protesters gather at Flinders Street Station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/protesters-gather-at-flinders-street-station/106323806</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">267a877d67f741c07ea235e2ab8c954b</guid></item><item><title>ASIO was told about Bondi shooter's terrorist links years before attack, former spy claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/bondi-shooting-spy-claims-told-asio-terror-links-four-corners/106306092</link><description>The former undercover agent spied on the Akrams when he infiltrated a Sydney IS terror cell for Australia's intelligence agency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38e7d75b35ff2d3c4a5b6be5b9bb9d73</guid></item><item><title>'Massive' Indonesian ghost barge washes up on tiny Torres Strait island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/mystery-indonesian-ghost-barge-washed-up-in-torres-strait/106323116</link><description>The barge drifted into Australian waters from Indonesia after breaking from its moorings during bad weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08b39ef063e5e2f00075ab3cf9dbea37</guid></item><item><title>Live: Gremaud beats Gu to go back-to-back in slopestyle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/winter-olympics-day-two-live-blog-updates/106322542</link><description>Holly Harris and Jason Chan will become the first Aussies in 12 years to represent the country in ice dancing, while Tess Coady and Meila Stalker will compete in the big air final. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ab5c808eefcaa38bad83f2aee6e5fb7</guid></item><item><title>Shaun Dunk asks to be 'locked up' 15 days before alleged stabbing murder, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/shaun-dunk-asks-to-be-locked-up-weeks-before-alleged-murder/106323324</link><description>Fifteen days before he allegedly killed a woman and attempted to kill another, Shaun Michael Dunk asked to be taken into custody so he would not be a danger to anyone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">776a71d9c1219b80be2c49f508bed9c7</guid></item><item><title>Police and protesters clash at Sydney's Town Hall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/police-and-protesters-clash-at-sydney-s-town-hall-/106323954</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d617c31f1bfdae141ee155484c6f77c1</guid></item><item><title>Prince William and Kate say they are 'deeply concerned' about Epstein files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/prince-william-kate-epstein-deeply-concerned-statement/106323984</link><description>The Prince and Princess of Wales say their thoughts remain focused on the victims of the late sex offender Jeffrey Epstein, in their first statement on the issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d612c2a641317f685b27655f77ed980a</guid></item><item><title>Queensland health minister orders review of Toowoomba Hospital maternity unit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/toowoomba-hospital-maternity-unit-audit/106323798</link><description>Announcement comes after a woman reveals her support person was prevented from entering the birth suite while she was in labour by Toowoomba Hospital security.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99b063ed21a492a5f313bd8e1046e624</guid></item><item><title>Maritime safety regulator investigating luxury Carnival cruise ship after whistleblower concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/amsa-investigating-carnival-cruise-ship-exploitation-claims/106323754</link><description>The maritime union says crew members of a luxury Carnival cruise ship allege they are being made to sleep in crowded rooms, lack access to safe free drinking water, and that some are earning as little as $2.50 an hour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aac8562047e40499a73214ddcb3bb039</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth files defence against Linda Reynolds legal action in federal court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/commonwealth-files-defence-against-linda-reynolds-legal-action/106324034</link><description>The Commonwealth files its defence against former senator Linda Reynolds, who is suing the government and its lawyers over a $2.4 million payout it made to Brittany Higgins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">868917d636420ea166ce9e95e7cd1d3f</guid></item><item><title>WA's north braces for impact as Tropical Cyclone Mitchell remains offshore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/tropical-cyclone-mitchell-rainfall-offshore/106322566</link><description>Tropical Cyclone Mitchell is yet to make landfall along the Gascoyne coast, but it has already brought wild weather to the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09ff2e232d21c20ae91993345c75dd53</guid></item><item><title>Scottish Labour leader calls for UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer to quit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/scottish-labour-leader-calls-for-starmer-to-resign/106324396</link><description>Keir Starmer is facing calls to resign after damaging revelations about the man he picked to represent the UK in Washington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e65648acd6fbd0990a4a439c0fd4709</guid></item></channel></rss>