<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 13:16:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>From a Springsteen biopic to a doggy horror: here are the movies out in October</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/october-movie-wrap-what-to-watch/105893300</link><description>From the highly anticipated Bruce Springsteen biopic to a horror movie from the viewpoint of the family pup, here are the films filling up cinemas in October.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f217a9477d3de1211d4744ae2ba19bd8</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne's record-setting AFLW winning streak is clear in the numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/north-melbourne-setting-aflw-standards/105905842</link><description>Having developed the program layer by layer since joining the AFLW in 2019, North Melbourne's disciplined, professional style of footy is forcing the rest of the league to rise to their level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3f69ec228f1094f89b081dd9d305cb5</guid></item><item><title>Cool weather prescribed burn on WA's south coast should be expanded, environmental group says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/call-to-expand-cool-weather-burns-to-protect-the-environment/105896512</link><description>The success of a small, autumn prescribed burn on WA's south coast has prompted calls to replace the regular program to reduce environmental damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">164585befee231bbcfbedee418ccc7bd</guid></item><item><title>NT's top judge tells government not to interfere with court independence, in leaked email</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/nt-judge-accuses-government-of-interfering-with-court-operations/105904858</link><description>A leaked email shows the Northern Territory's highest-ranking judge wrote to a government department asking it not to interfere with the Supreme Court's independence. A courts spokesperson has since said the email was the result of a misunderstanding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69ad31302102fadb90b3e422f9c25327</guid></item><item><title>Phoebe Litchfield learning from opening partner Alyssa Healy at Women's Cricket World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/phoebe-litchfield-alyssa-healy-womens-cricket-world-cup/105907312</link><description>Alyssa Healy has joined an elite band of women batters with 7,000 international runs, and Australia's captain is giving her brilliant young opening partner something to aim for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a50f38a0dacc4756881494b6edf4d5e</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne CBD stabbing victim faces long emotional recovery after daylight attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/melbourne-cbd-stabbing-victim-wan-lai-recovering-family-says/105907294</link><description>A woman stabbed in Melbourne's CBD is making a physical recovery from the incident, but is still struggling with the emotional aftermath, her family says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bea6413cdcba2517eb6e32322951abbe</guid></item><item><title>Minister flags compulsory voting in local government elections, 4-year terms amid low voter turnout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/compulsory-voting-flagged-for-wa-local-government-election/105901804</link><description>Voting in council elections could become mandatory in Western Australia if the turnout for this weekend's poll continues to plummet, the local government minister warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90ce7dc5327df5d0b3904814e2638839</guid></item><item><title>Heavy horsemen keep farming traditions alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/heavy-horsemen-keep-farming-traditions-alive/105887988</link><description>Aleks Berzins is farming the land in the same way his grandfather did, using draught horses for jobs now widely done by machines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f47d3bf2b7c8199053c352b6aaf54536</guid></item><item><title>Gulgong woman changes career to honour murder victim Michelle Bright</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/michelle-bright-murder-leads-abby-honeysett-on-forensic-career/105866588</link><description>The murder of Michelle Bright altered Abby-Lee Honeysett's childhood in Gulgong, New South Wales and guided her towards a career in forensic medicine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b220bc940fcd8f7c374cc9f9976a5291</guid></item><item><title>Coroner finds snakebite death of 11yo Tristian Frahm preventable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/coroner-finds-snakebite-death-of-tristian-frahm-preventable/105907556</link><description>The death of an 11-year-old Queensland boy from a snakebite may have been prevented had he received early medical attention, according to the findings of an inquest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7845efcc529ff7078aaecea2c035d784</guid></item><item><title>Gungahlin United Football Club to fold after losing NPL licence, leaving 2,000 grassroots players club-less</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/gungahlin-united-fc-fold-capital-football-licence-revoke/105907530</link><description>Just last year, the club won the league, and a former president was jailed for stealing $20k. Now they are going to fold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b94409bd3e5cff77f2199cae368e6fbf</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce hasn't quit the Nationals yet but he's got one foot out the door</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/speers-analysis-barnaby-joyce-has-not-quit-the-nationals-yet/105907744</link><description>In declaring he won't be recontesting his lower house seat and letting speculation run that he might jump ship for One Nation, Barnaby Joyce is declaring he's had enough with the Nationals under David Littleproud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f61bd6ea4984b1bc51fdcb3bae580b</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos defeat Crows by 40 points to move closer to winning record as Saints, Dockers and Demons notch victories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/aflw-demons-swans-kangaroos-crows-giants-dockers-blues-saints/105907762</link><description>North Melbourne moves one victory away from equalling the all-time VFL/AFL and AFLW winning record with a 40-point drubbing of Adelaide as St Kilda moves closer to a maiden finals appearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3036c640f5f12f4b89b3526d94476ea</guid></item><item><title>CCTV footage from PlayShack in Palmerston shows the moment the small business was broken into.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/cctv-footage-playshack-palmerston-break-in/105907746</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bf5bb07bd1b55215484b20d94b9d222</guid></item><item><title>NT chief minister claims tough-on-crime approach has led to 'significant' crime drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/nt-chief-minister-claims-tough-on-crime-led-to-crime-drop/105906588</link><description>NT Chief Minister Lia Finocchiaro says the Country Liberal Party's tough-on-crime approach "is working". But after two teens broke into a play centre and left a trail of destruction, operator Steve Mason is not convinced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ceb1811e211ef03f608859e94141ede6</guid></item><item><title>Collingwood cult hero Mason Cox not offered new contract for 2026 AFL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/mason-cox-leaves-collingwood-magpies/105907852</link><description>Mason Cox, the first American to become an AFL regular, confirms he will not be with the Magpies in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faaa19652e592fb7fd468bdd25c33d4d</guid></item><item><title>Nottingham Forest sack manager Ange Postecoglou immediately after loss to Chelsea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/ange-postecoglou-sacked-nottingham-forest/105908162</link><description>Nottingham Forest sacked the winless manager moments after their 3-0 defeat by Chelsea on Saturday local time, which left the club 17th in the standings and on the brink of slipping into the relegation zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57c551c6fd2ddff4af0d49de00cd0a77</guid></item><item><title>China's economic slowdown has become its diplomatic weapon in the Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/china-economy-pacific-australia-united-states/105884758</link><description>For Australia and the US, the Pacific is no longer a comfortable backyard — it's a battleground of credibility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2b0e48dd4fde1249a89b421640ef595</guid></item><item><title>The deep Indigenous history of Australia deserves to be up in lights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/deep-time-indigenous-history-65000-years/105693082</link><description>We've flipped the script to put Indigenous Australians back at the centre of telling their own stories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1b24be62527f979869b9fe019461e17</guid></item><item><title>BOM's first long-range summer forecast shows increased chance of extreme heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/bom-summer-weather-forecast-hot-and-dry-with-high-fire-risk/105899594</link><description>Hot nights coupled with high daytime temperatures could see Australia heading into an extremely hot summer, BOM's first long-range forecast indicates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f141a77feebbff9dd877f9c172a7d949</guid></item><item><title>Native mussel restoration project supported by Victor Harbor community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/mussel-bed-rebuilding-at-encounter-bay-after-algal-bloom/105887684</link><description>Victor Harbor was one of the first areas affected by SA's harmful algal bloom. Now its citizens are funding and supporting research into rebuilding native mussel populations as it looks to the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5482853b2341d466e8d2331ff929036a</guid></item><item><title>China's 'special forces'-style tourists packing big itineraries in small budgets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/china-hong-kong-special-forces-style-travel-sleep-mcdonalds/105902602</link><description>Young Chinese tourists with limited time and money are travelling 'special forces'-style — inspired by the efficiency, endurance, and intensity of military units.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecc8983a388385cd9855eaf49fa6fe2b</guid></item><item><title>How Mother Teresa helped Steve Waugh channel his 'power' for children in need</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/steve-waugh-on-meeting-mother-teresa/105671818</link><description>When Steve Waugh retired from cricket, he knew he wanted to use his influence to make a difference. It was meeting Mother Teresa that made him realise his new path.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f532c8e947e73fb6c25eb280850294d</guid></item><item><title>'Gellung Warl' and other Victorian Aboriginal words that are part of Australia's first Treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/victoria-treaty-aboriginal-language-words-gellung-warl/105874164</link><description>Victoria's first Treaty with First Peoples' was debated in state parliament last week. The Treaty introduces some Victorian Aboriginal words you may not have heard before — here's how to say them and what they mean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5888d4d050285e49bfa8b0319e6bfc2c</guid></item><item><title>Mural of Sydney's queer history removed from Surry Hills Police Station days after going up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/queer-sydney-history-mural-removed-surry-hills-police-station/105906396</link><description>The artwork, Queer Sydney: A History, was hung at Surry Hills Police Station, metres from where the annual Gay and Lesbian Mardi Gras parade is held.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18b1a6dd261ce61a763340e63c32d468</guid></item><item><title>Aussie Bird Count brings together students, photographers and nature-lovers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/aussie-bird-count-students-volunteer/105903124</link><description>A primary school teacher is getting her students involved in a volunteer-led bird count, to gather a snapshot of birds across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1902614b6d2d117e4440091bf145ffb</guid></item><item><title>Sheffield Shield round two quick hits: Marnus Labuschagne confirms form ahead of Ashes, Scott Boland bullies and spinners offer reminder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/sheffield-shield-summary-marnus-labuschagne/105907142</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne's magical early season form continues with the bat, Scott Boland and a pair of spinners offer a reminder of their skill, while Sam Konstas turns on the flair at round two of the Sheffield Shield.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">054ff0d8e5945ea2d312a9468fd3278e</guid></item><item><title>James Duckworth falls at Almaty Open semi-final stage against Daniil Medvedev</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/james-duckworth-falls-almati-open-semi-final-daniil-medvedev/105908658</link><description>Australian seed-slayer James Duckworth has finally met his match in Almaty, where Daniil Medvedev dug deep to beat him in three sets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0d127a1f537ae19f3d552f01bce600f</guid></item><item><title>North Queensland by-election to provide snapshot of state's politics a year on from LNP victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/qld-hinchinbrook-by-election-analysis/105902784</link><description>The looming by-election in Hinchinbrook will not have a significant impact on the makeup of Queensland parliament, but it will give insight into the state of play of politics a year after the LNP swept to power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">172765f854cdca401a9862668704f49f</guid></item><item><title>It's been called Canberra's 'forever government' — but ACT Labor's brand is growing tired</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/act-canberra-forever-government-but-labor-brand-growing-tired/105904332</link><description>It's been a year since Canberrans re-elected an ACT Labor government for a seventh consecutive term — but as budget pressures bite, analysts say Labor's stocks are suffering from brand fatigue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ee3cbb31b12feb0dbf9a314f57eeb6d</guid></item><item><title>Mike Hewson creates controversial children's playgrounds. Explore his latest creation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/mike-hewson-takes-kids-four-storeys-underground/105896640</link><description>This designer's "risky playgrounds" are often divisive. His latest is four storeys underground in a former World War II oil tank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5af465a6bbf0383d41c1060eddfa1af6</guid></item><item><title>New Tasmanian Integrity Commission head will decide whether to release report from six-year investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/tasmanian-integrity-commission-finishes-six-year-investigation/105894390</link><description>Seven years after allegations were made against a practitioner who was allegedly misusing public resources, Tasmania's Integrity Commission has finalised its investigation into the matter. However, the report has not been released to the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c5fd50bb3ddf358b3e61158eed83e42</guid></item><item><title>Social media promotion of raw milk 'misleading and dangerous'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/raw-milk-trend-worries-experts/105636166</link><description>A public health expert says social media content creators are undermining years of scientific research by promoting raw milk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be479a18a9b8b5bd2c9c5515b5b11008</guid></item><item><title>GPs with extra skills who want to work in Tasmania say there are no suitable jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/rural-generalists-tasmanian-health-service-say-no-suitable-jobs/105907346</link><description>Rural generalists are GPs with training in emergency care and one other advanced skill area. While Tasmania has a training program for rural generalists, doctors say their skills are not properly recognised by the Tasmanian Health Service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa38354b32d3f313d4fb620c7e2db87f</guid></item><item><title>International chefs share signature flavours as part of Lambassador program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/international-lambassadors-arrive-in-australia-for-lamb-lessons/105903950</link><description>A delegation of international chefs from 11 countries have landed in Australia to gain a deeper understanding of locally produced Australian lamb.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71e07198c67015e99c324d0292653818</guid></item><item><title>Nationals leader wants Barnaby Joyce to 'stay', amid rumour of One Nation defection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/nationals-littleproud-barnaby-joyce-stay-party-one-nation/105908722</link><description>Announcing he would not re-contest his seat of New England for the Nationals, Barnaby Joyce cited an irreparable breakdown with his party leader David Littleproud. Mr Littleproud says he still wants Mr Joyce to stay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9848481613384650c56cadeda692b7be</guid></item><item><title>National Disruption Group to be established to crush tobacco black market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/national-distruption-group-tobacco-black-market/105908764</link><description>A new "National Disruption Group" will be convened to stamp out the exploding illicit tobacco market and other "converging" threats, the home affairs minister has announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cc3bdda511d1e9aa7bb583dee35ef1e</guid></item><item><title>Five suspected rat poison cases detected in south-east Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/qld-rat-poisoning-symptoms-reported-to-hospitals/105908798</link><description>Queensland Health is investigating after five people were hospitalised with symptoms of ingesting rat poison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17e5b91d5e833fa2e54a07c383a89f60</guid></item><item><title>Committed band of skateboarders trying to preserve Fremantle's best spots</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/fremantle-skateboarding-community-fighting-development/105905606</link><description>WA's bustling port city of Fremantle is changing, and in between a swathe of redevelopment stands a persistent, dedicated and vocal group experiencing some mixed results — the skateboarding community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c906228a8685aa2fbf624bd8d81dc06c</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou's Nottingham Forest stint a classic case of wrong place, wrong time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/ange-postecoglou-nottingham-forest-wrong-team-brian-clough/105908712</link><description>Ange Postecoglou was on a hiding to nothing at Nottingham Forest, his sacking the result of terrible recruitment and a knee-jerk appointment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0adc426b55b3caeb01dc1561cdfadbc</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan and Afghanistan agree to immediate ceasefire after peace talks in Doha</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/pakistan-afghanistan-agree-to-immediate-ceasefire-doha-talks/105908852</link><description>A week of fierce border clashes has seen the worst violence between the two countries since the Taliban seized power in Kabul in 2021.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ae3ed5418e4616f7f9a9cc4b9feaba5</guid></item><item><title>'Green bans' saved Sydney's historic buildings and taught economists a lesson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/green-bans-sydney-1970s-unions-nimby-yimby-milton-friedman/105903850</link><description>The "green bans" in the 1970s saved many of Australia's historic buildings and our cities are richer for them. But a famous economist didn't like them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abdb337970b734f91db4e99387b96c1a</guid></item><item><title>ACT Labor's 'forever government' brand is growing tired</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/act-labor-forever-government-growing-tired/105909058</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27ab69ee69dee4ea5f2abee1c869453c</guid></item><item><title>Trent Dalton's Boy Swallows Universe wins the Top 100 Books countdown — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/top-100-books-of-the-21st-century-radio-national-live-updates/105900036</link><description>Trent Dalton's debut novel Boy Swallows Universe has won Radio National's Top 100 Books of the 21st Century countdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a93d820be1134030d36a0450e5827bd4</guid></item><item><title>Search for missing Tasmanian bushwalker Daryl Fong 'under review' as challenging conditions continue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/missing-bushwalker-daryl-fong-search-continues-mount-field/105909192</link><description>Rescue crews continue to face challenging conditions in the search for Daryl Fong, who has been missing in Tasmania's Mount Field National Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79317a802b551f057750daca1b564099</guid></item><item><title>How Claire's decision to be 'one and done' was rocked by divorce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/how-claire-feels-about-being-one-and-done-after-divorce/105870074</link><description>After a traumatic birth, followed by mental and physical health challenges, Claire was "one and done". But divorce made her think twice about her decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c4071ab0f2b41bc5ba8af85bdc44b4</guid></item><item><title>Tiger snake slides over passenger's foot during a drive on NSW far south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/tiger-snake-encounter-passenger-narooma-rescue/105909112</link><description>A passenger in a car has the fright of his life when a tiger snake slithers across his feet during a drive on the NSW far south coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2664ddc2ecf35a9e1c24c1ee8681b6ac</guid></item><item><title>North Adelaide golf course safeguards fall short, some Kaurna community members say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/liv-golf-aboriginal-heritage-reaction/105908982</link><description>As the Malinauskas government proceeds with its $50 million North Adelaide golf course upgrade, some Kaurna elders are grappling with the prospect that the redevelopment could uncover Aboriginal remains.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9101d5e10e56032ae087ac48805699a</guid></item><item><title>The story of the 1970 West Gate Bridge disaster features in Melbourne Theatre Company's 2026 season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/melbourne-theatre-company-mtc-2026-season-anne-louise-sarks/105896178</link><description>The people impacted by Australia's worst industrial disaster are at the centre of West Gate by Dennis McIntosh, one of seven new Australian plays coming to Melbourne Theatre Company in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de0ad7e53c23dbee737f8a5d0098d29e</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Reynolds to remain City of Perth Lord Mayor as counting continues in WA local government elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/wa-local-government-election-results-perth-lord-mayor/105905464</link><description>Bruce Reynolds has held onto the title of City of Perth Lord Mayor, while early figures from WA's local government elections show voter turnout is below what authorities hoped for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a54bf02a0f8001516a58239517b18816</guid></item><item><title>Wadeye traditional owners say Yidiyi cultural festival brings community together as 'one family'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/wadeye-nt-yidiyi-festival-2025-brings-community-together/105908796</link><description>Traditional owners of the remote NT Aboriginal community of Wadeye say the community has been brought "together as one family" at this year's Yidiyi cultural festival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d233684dc20b0f2b15cd1d575b533874</guid></item><item><title>More than $6 million of cocaine and methylamphetamine seized during vehicle stop in southern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/highway-patrol-drug-haul-in-hay-nsw-vehicle-stop/105909462</link><description>Highway patrol stopped the black luxury SUV on a major New South Wales highway for a random drug and alcohol test on Friday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0b12cb731bfba08c1331b8020ab344b</guid></item><item><title>Bulldogs keep finals hopes alive with 66-point Suns trouncing, Lions and Tigers pick up wins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/aflw-bombers-lions-magpies-tigers-suns-bulldogs/105909452</link><description>The Western Bulldogs hammer Gold Coast by 66 points to keep their finals flame flickering, while Brisbane returns to the top four with victory over Essendon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">220f543ca713782ae1e2a21e7e2fa7c0</guid></item><item><title>Trent Dalton's Boy Swallows Universe wins Radio National's Top 100 Books of the 21st century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/top-100-books-trent-dalton-boy-swallows-universe/105872764</link><description>The results are in — Trent Dalton's Boy Swallows Universe has won Radio National's inaugural Top 100 Books of the 21st Century.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cef78d8d8b4ac4e460acf0badccc758</guid></item><item><title>Hunt for thieves continues after 'priceless' jewellery stolen from Louvre museum in Paris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/louvre-museum-in-paris-robbed/105909826</link><description>The robbers used a basket lift to reach a window where they broke in, France's Interior Minister Laurent Nunez said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e953ebb539487579a0d2605ae291124</guid></item><item><title>Australia cruises to seven-wicket victory over India in rain-shortened ODI</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/odi-australia-defeats-india-by-seven-wickets-perth/105909904</link><description>Surviving a series of rain delays in Perth, Australia records a seven-wicket win over India in the first of three men's ODI matches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bfda650a8c1f1f7cac905e46ef4fbd7</guid></item><item><title>If AI and crypto aren't bubbles, we could be in big trouble</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/ai-crypto-bubbles-speculative-mania/105884508</link><description>Speculative manias where the first investors win because there isn't a bust are rare occurrences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">283c30df2984a269ddf09fef3456e7d6</guid></item><item><title>Reused signature among string of issues as home owner left with unfinished build</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/reused-signature-among-string-of-failures-on-home-build/105792444</link><description>When Matthew Mapley questioned why the bank had paid his builder for unfinished works, it said it had his written authority — except he hadn't signed it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">145bbaf8d8739f0ee1789f78d179e3e6</guid></item><item><title>How much do you really know about Australia's epic 65,000-year history?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/deep-time-indigenous-history-introduction/105907302</link><description>First Nations people have survived and thrived through an ice age and massive landscape changes — as well as sharing the land with giant animals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fac48bc54ea66e8592dfbaf1bfce506</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese's meeting with Donald Trump could hardly be timed better</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/albanese-trump-meeting-timing-critical-minerals/105909072</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is about to set foot inside the gilded cage of the Oval Office — and the timing could hardly be better.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d20e6cfd5af8252e5277f8c4a4af005</guid></item><item><title>Most OECD countries get to work within 30 minutes. This is how Australia compares</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/australia-work-commute-times-compared/105888860</link><description>Over the past few years, daily commutes have changed with flexible work arrangements. Most OECD countries' commute times are about 30 minutes. So how does Australia compare?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a63582c54c385a16e1911ae416c9c620</guid></item><item><title>Three teenagers injured in attack involving machete outside Luna Park in St Kilda</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/group-with-machete-attack-teenagers-in-st-kilda/105910510</link><description>Investigators are looking for a group of males who attacked a group of teenagers with a machete outside Luna Park on Sunday evening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2b7e43be77efc7e8da96bd6d90209cf</guid></item><item><title>Teenager who died by suicide sent final message to Gold Coast health service, but it went unanswered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/neve-wright-gold-coast-health-service-death-calls-investigation/105902752</link><description>The ABC has uncovered the case as part of an examination of Gold Coast Hospital and Health Service's treatment of mental health patients and their suicides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80b94bbccc9715cedfe4fc21a97e430c</guid></item><item><title>Rabbit populations boom in parts of Australia as ideal conditions see pests return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/rabbit-populations-on-rise-in-southern-australia-after-rain/105903702</link><description>A resurgence of rabbit populations following recent rainfall is driving experts to urge for increased control measures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f0b63e3021992436e68289f3f87b2a2</guid></item><item><title>Daniil Medvedev wins Almaty Open, Elena Rybakina closes in on WTA Finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/atp-wta-tours-daniil-medvedev-elena-rybakina-win/105910582</link><description>Daniil Medvedev claims his first ATP Tour tournament win since 2023, while Elena Rybakina's push to reach the WTA Finals gathers momentum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d27928b89915e24efb9812cfeeed4e7</guid></item><item><title>All the numbers behind Radio National's Top 100 Books of the 21st century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/top-100-books-radio-national-trent-dalton-numbers/105876550</link><description>The winner for the Top 100 Books has been announced. What do the votes behind it say about us?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eceddbdf78c0567b7386f67a77686872</guid></item><item><title>Millions being spent as Australia prepares for deadly H5 strain of bird flu</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/australia-prepares-for-deadly-h5-strain-of-bird-flu/105906562</link><description>The bird flu outbreak that saw millions of chickens culled and a national shortage of eggs has been declared eradicated, but scientists warn a much deadlier strain of avian influenza could arrive this spring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e83ea2739e1cc6e0699c27dab01c0b6a</guid></item><item><title>Healthscope under fire over proposal to farm millions in employees' tax benefits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/healthscope-proposal-for-workers-tax-benefits-under-fire/105894910</link><description>In-receivership hospital group Healthscope is taking radical steps to stay alive, converting to a charity and proposing to take up to 90 per cent of a benefit intended to reduce workers' taxable income.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54fe6626e9683e97ff7c755dc0f3b158</guid></item><item><title>Multiple sclerosis support group tries to fill gaps as Northern Territory services dwindle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/multiple-sclerosis-support-group-tries-fill-nt-service-gaps/105839144</link><description>Being diagnosed with multiple sclerosis can often be an isolating experience, and even more so for those in Darwin who lack access to on-the-ground supports. Despite these barriers, a group of local women have created a support group to help fill the service gap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14749aee6ee20b3feba95efcd80cf469</guid></item><item><title>England records four-run Women's World Cup win over India to join Australia in semifinals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/cricket-world-cup-england-defeats-india-to-reach-semifinals/105910632</link><description>England secures its Women's World Cup semifinal spot with a tense four-run win over tournament co-host India at Indor's Holkar Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca127f26cc1b519429233a14a7576b44</guid></item><item><title>Tourism dollars roll into Carnamah a year after arrival of big tractor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/worlds-biggest-tractor-tourism-wa-midwest-town-carnamah/105893574</link><description>One year on from its opening, the orange icon has brought people from all over Australia — and the world — to WA's Midwest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e006f37718ddfa2b762776c7387048c2</guid></item><item><title>India backs Virat Kohli to rebound after ODI duck against Australia in Perth series opener</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/cricket-odi-india-australia-virat-kohli-duck/105910756</link><description>Virat Kohli failed to score in the opening men's ODI in Perth. However, his India teammates expect their ex-skipper to quickly recapture his best form.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bc80acf1d0f546076475e758c726a92</guid></item><item><title>Holiday from Hospital virtual reality to transport patients to Australia's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/holiday-from-hospital-virtual-reality-program/105904452</link><description>A leukaemia survivor designs a VR program that will help patients travel to some of Australia's iconic locations from their hospital beds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86e927a78d6931f5a5bc765a1bd0349f</guid></item><item><title>Richmond is starting to play good footy. But in AFLW's short season there's no time left to build momentum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/richmond-aflw-short-season-limits-chance-to-build-momentum/105910676</link><description>After a 0-7 start to the season, Richmond are starting to notch wins on the board. But it's too late for much momentum to build in the short women's season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">069e771beb7b5a18b4ca2823e445cde9</guid></item><item><title>Some scientists challenge logic of Victoria's fuel reduction burns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/scientists-challenge-fuel-load-burns-victoria/105666680</link><description>Dry winter conditions have resulted in extra fuel reduction burns in regional Victoria ahead of the fire season. But some scientists are asking if fuel burns are the best way to reduce fire risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24063f01e48736dadc0cd1dc663f5536</guid></item><item><title>Severe winds and hail hit WA's Kimberley as wet season approaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/wild-weather-batters-far-north-wa-unusual-hailstorm/105909234</link><description>Wild weather hit the Kimberley over the weekend, with some residents witnessing hail falling on their lawns despite it being a 38-degree day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">759b0e13b14ba30ecea0dbed924de7c7</guid></item><item><title>Warning over rare but deadly virus after bat bites Pilbara woman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/pilbara-bat-bite-lyssavirus-treatment/105903464</link><description>A Pilbara resident says an attempt to save a small bat stuck in her house has resulted in painful treatment for a deadly virus that can be passed onto humans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7649b3e7c5d127072e9734a5e6389db2</guid></item><item><title>Melt Festival is giving queer artists a space to be themselves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/melt-at-pip-queer-arts-festival-stand-up-comedy/105876434</link><description>Brisbane's Melt Festival has rapidly expanded in the past decade, inviting numerous venues into the celebration of queer artistry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82f95541593c2dd6615f166a0fa29834</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr backed by Matildas coach Joe Montemurro to make impact in friendlies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/matildas-sam-kerr-joe-montemurro-wales-england-friendlies/105911490</link><description>Sam Kerr will return to the Matildas fold off the back of limited minutes at Chelsea, but coach Joe Montemurro is confident she will shine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55b775730bad08a65eaa25450f51842f</guid></item><item><title>Mossman sugarcane industry on its last legs as haulage deal ends</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/mossman-sugarcane-mulgrave-mill-transport-costs-too-high/105905656</link><description>A deal between Mossman sugarcane growers and a mill 100 kilometres away has been deemed unviable, leaving farmers without a place to send their product after this season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4f1c7e046b4e98aead821af1d28a44d</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the Louvre jewellery heist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/what-we-know-about-the-louvre-jewellery-heist/105910640</link><description>Here are the details on the items stolen in the Louvre heist that unfolded in broad daylight in Paris.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d269eaf9f556b0ba4f01c08707826645</guid></item><item><title>Cargo plane slides off runway in Hong Kong killing two airport staff</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/hong-kong-airport-cargo-plane-crash/105911458</link><description>The flight arriving from Dubai was landing at Hong Kong International Airport when it skidded off the runway, leading to the deaths of two men in a vehicle on the ground, according to police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">949790ffe37f5f7d2047c0e6ac8b0cee</guid></item><item><title>Former Toowoomba Chronicle journalist Peter Hardwick sentenced over indecent treatment of child</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/qld-former-journalist-peter-hardwick-child-indecent-treatment/105911288</link><description>Peter Hardwick is sentenced after pleading guilty to two counts of indecent treatment of a child under the age of 12.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5215ec6b2a4623b1d02131cfd00d22d9</guid></item><item><title>Deep Time, a story 65,000 years in the making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/deep-time-launch-live-blog/105911270</link><description>ABC's Story Lab team has created an interactive tool to help Australians better understand the ancient history of our continent and its First Nations peoples. Look back at our blog to see how it works.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9204ef8f5d9eebc4f3e76e50be4721ac</guid></item><item><title>Shane Wanganeen pleads guilty to criminal neglect following son's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/shane-wanganeen-pleads-guilty-to-criminal-neglect/105911944</link><description>A South Australian father has pleaded guilty to the criminal neglect of his seven-year-old son, who died after not being treated for pneumonia in 2022. WARNING: Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander readers are advised this article contains the name of a person who has died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3dddd8946d0112422d50d9ca6f97346</guid></item><item><title>Samoa down to 17 fit players after Pacific Championships loss to New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/samoa-to-call-in-replacements-after-brutal-kiwi-defeat/105912418</link><description>Samoa's brutal loss to New Zealand leaves them needing to call fresh troops into their squad, with the Pacific powerhouse down to just 17 fit players.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b4e1cb8410d3d6e41561f33c4befb1e</guid></item><item><title>Tatiana Dokhotaru told mum she was 'very afraid' of ex-partner before her death, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/nsw-danny-zayat-murder-trial-tatiana-dokhotaru-mother-olga/105911540</link><description>Danny Zayat has pleaded not guilty and is facing a Supreme Court trial over the alleged murder of Tatiana Dokhotaru in May 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ff4265f79917f345faf843c0c7d1395</guid></item><item><title>Central Land Council CEO Lesley Turner sues senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price over defamation claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/nt-clc-lesley-turner-sues-senator-jacinta-nampijinpa-price-court/105911056</link><description>A seven-day Federal Court defamation case, alleging senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price "trampled" the reputation of an NT land council leader, has begun in Darwin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8420ac7f16d0a99cba30c47990ca4485</guid></item><item><title>Has Australia just killed its cultural cringe?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/books-100-cultural-cringe-australian-literature/105911414</link><description>How wonderful for Australian writers to receive this recognition from the very people who consume their work, as part of ABC Radio National's Top 100 Books countdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6955af048b4c6e6460e149afd7da2d97</guid></item><item><title>Election campaign donation laws would have blocked $8m in Climate 200 funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/climate-200-donations-millions-blocked-election-reforms/105910960</link><description>Climate 200 would have been blocked from making $8.34 million in donations to independent candidates if new election donation laws were in place at the 2025 poll.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a105858ce5aba7b87125fcecf773b3e4</guid></item><item><title>New England voters divided by Barnaby Joyce's flirtation with One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/barnaby-joyce-future-uncertain-as-new-england-voters-react/105910950</link><description>Support for the politician remains strong in his electorate despite his apparent flirtation with One Nation, a party enjoying a surge in popularity in the seat of New England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5fd341f9bae412bf8bef068aa17b4f9</guid></item><item><title>Space junk found near WA mine linked to Chinese rocket launch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/space-junk-chinese-rocket-jielong-newman-bhp-iron-ore/105912162</link><description>Suspected space junk which crashed near an iron ore mine in remote WA has been linked to a Chinese rocket launch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24854cc69cdd74ae88771488846a683b</guid></item><item><title>Bonza's financial backer 777 Partners co-founder charged with fraud</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/bonza-us-financier-charged-500-million-alleged-fraud/105910734</link><description>The FBI investigation resulted in 777 Partners co-founder Joshua Wander being charged with stealing US$500 million from lenders and investors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e392cffcb519df7c5888daa3070bb23a</guid></item><item><title>Patients at centre of suspected rat poisoning cluster in south-east Queensland are all from Logan. This is what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/south-east-qld-rat-poison-cluster-from-same-city-logan/105912822</link><description>South-east Queensland authorities are continuing to investigate the source of the cluster, with contact tracing underway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70d8c5b4606af35b4f66793f5f9df39a</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew is no longer the Duke of York but will likely remain a prince. Here's why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/how-does-being-stripped-of-a-royal-title-work/105911378</link><description>The second son of the late Queen Elizabeth II will no longer be called the Duke of York, but he still remains a prince and in the line of succession, despite calls for his remaining title to be stripped. Here's why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcc480b17f85a98ca2b072bb33bf703f</guid></item><item><title>Temporary bans on fishing popular species floated to address dwindling populations off WA coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/wa-fishing-bans-floated-address-species-shortages/105913198</link><description>A temporary ban on fishing iconic species, including WA dhufish and pink snapper, could be on the table as the state government scrambles for solutions to WA's at-risk fish populations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57ce6ad300f7bec9a9eaa714428b06db</guid></item><item><title>Mitch Marsh dismisses suggestion he should open for Australia in the first Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/six-beers-deep-marsh-s-ashes-plan-is-not-about-opening/105912940</link><description>Michael Vaughan wants Mitch Marsh opening the batting for Australia in the Ashes but it would require a serious leap of faith from Test selectors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84ef3c8bde1f51f97c40040a93279935</guid></item><item><title>NSW police searching for armed bank robber who threatened Bendigo Bank staff and customers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/wentworth-bendigo-bank-robbery-pole-theft/105912580</link><description>Police are still hunting for a man responsible for a bank robbery in south-west New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7ceb98ad6ecd78e46c01e18bbad2d2d</guid></item><item><title>Australian and New Zealand shearers set new world record with 2,301 sheep shorn in eight hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/gun-team-of-five-shearers-sets-world-record/105912092</link><description>A new world record for sheep shearing has been set in southern New South Wales by a team of five shearers who clipped on average a sheep a minute for eight hours straight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b36cd1f4f8cf1bdadc6b189339ea62d</guid></item><item><title>Fast and easy dinners for busy weeknights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/fast-easy-low-effort-dinners-busy-weeknights/105731730</link><description>Make life easier with some of our simplest dinner recipes, including a 15-minute creamy pasta and air-fryer salmon fillets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca82c101073b2325f491bf70e520a749</guid></item><item><title>Voter turnout dips again at 2025 WA Local Government elections amid calls for mandatory voting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/wa-council-elections-turnout-results/105911966</link><description>The number of West Australians who voted at the weekend's local government elections is slightly down on previous years, following calls for participation to become mandatory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">504f2098aa38fa7e3529412db62fa9b2</guid></item><item><title>Chinese fighter jet released flares 'very close' to Australian aircraft</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/chinese-fighter-jet-released-flares-close-to-australian-aircraft/105913308</link><description>Defence Minister Richard Marles says the incident was "unsafe and unprofessional" and the government has made representations to China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d5d4ce46fc1b59552abe10865158072</guid></item><item><title>Work begins on UNSW's billion-dollar Canberra campus in the 'education capital'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/work-begins-on-unsw-camberra-campus-expansion/105911670</link><description>Once complete, the new UNSW campus will be an education hub for thousands of students and staff, and is expected to provide a much-needed injection to the city's economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2bcb88310b1f23f8d036712ff2ef416</guid></item><item><title>ACT Chief Minister Andrew Barr says it has been a 'challenging first year' in minority government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/act-chief-minister-andrew-barr-one-year-in-minority-government/105912376</link><description>The ACT's chief minister brushes off criticism that his government is "tired", but acknowledges the 12 months since the election have been "difficult" for the territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc10b94fa7ea07f36073003ea1fef5b2</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanians buffeted by spring winds, but conditions not unusual, BOM says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/tasmanians-buffeted-by-spring-winds-conditions-not-unusual/105912682</link><description>Springtime typically means gardens come to life and the winter chill eases — for Tasmanians, it also means whatever isn't nailed down might get blown away.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6eaa5247e8e932d2697776dbceea8aa</guid></item><item><title>The moment authorities move a piece of space junk that crashed in Western Australia.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/space-junk-removal/105913574</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72a4417dd8cbbba89ec350034e6936d5</guid></item><item><title>Scott Pendlebury launches legal action against former financial adviser over alleged secret withdrawals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/afl-collingwood-scott-pendlebury-sues-financial-adviser/105913420</link><description>The Collingwood player alleges Jason Sourasis, who helmed A-League club Western United before its collapse, misappropriated more than $2 million over a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6ecd6960b929b61007c9f264fb6ae95</guid></item><item><title>Inquest finds death of Mount Barker man waiting for ambulance 'potentially' preventable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/coroner-finds-death-of-john-kennedy-potentially-preventable/105910896</link><description>The cardiac arrest death of a man who waited more than 20 minutes for an ambulance could have been "potentially" prevented if a paramedic had not interfered with the dispatch process and had help arrived sooner, a South Australian coroner has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee1d0e0a27105e5d015c0ea287fb1521</guid></item><item><title>Monday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105913294</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87f26fb07d22402da8afe2600c076558</guid></item><item><title>Amazon cloud unit AWS experiences major global outage disrupting hundreds of platforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/amazon-aws-experiencing-online-outage/105913856</link><description>Amazon's cloud unit AWS has experienced a major global services outage that also disrupted hundreds of other platforms, including Robinhood, Snapchat, Roblox and Perplexity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f69822d7088a0b7e47296f3179cb8d7f</guid></item><item><title>Nashir Hassani forced to pay fine after impersonating security guard at Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/court-fake-melbourne-grand-prix-security-guards/105913682</link><description>Nashir Hassani was fined $4,000 after sneaking into the Formula 1 disguised as a security guard using fake identification and a hi-vis vest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90c30d9350054176ea781422f208ce6c</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine accuses Russia of detaining scientist ahead of Antarctic conference in Hobart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/ukraine-accuses-russia-of-detaining-scientist-antarctic-hobart/105912586</link><description>A diplomatic row has broken out at an international conservation conference in Hobart after Ukraine accused Russia of detaining one of its scientists for alleged security threats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d362443d4d5959aa919960ff002394b</guid></item><item><title>Amazon says outage issue is 'fully mitigated' as sites return to normal— as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/amazon-cloud-systems-outage-as-it-happened/105913922</link><description>Amazon's cloud unit AWS experienced an outage that also disrupted several other global platforms, affecting customers worldwide — as it happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ea7be8e00d10a46b4cd78fbd190c92</guid></item><item><title>Advocates accused of exploiting veterans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/advocates-accused-of-exploiting-veterans/105913486</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9531372b1086e52a67ee245b11c7ab37</guid></item><item><title>Coroner probes death of Alice Springs psychiatric patient who was repeatedly sedated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/nt-kumanjayi-brogus-inquest-psychiatric-patient-sedation/105912198</link><description>NT Coroner Elisabeth Armitage is investigating the death of a 33-year-old Alice Springs mother of three who was unable to be revived after repeated medical sedations in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f45eb3e7586382d4b06686c776d0362c</guid></item><item><title>Colombia recalls ambassador to the US after Trump announces tariffs increase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/colombia-recalls-us-ambassador-after-trump-tariff-increase/105914158</link><description>The Colombian foreign ministry said Daniel García-Peña had returned to Bogotá from Washington DC after Donald Trump also announced the US would slash financial assistance to the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c468d4e382a5141ea746dd893c70464</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump hits out at Kevin Rudd</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/donald-trump-hits-out-at-kevin-rudd/105914568</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec0d53acfc4cf367be1cd4c6a51cc7e4</guid></item><item><title>IN FULL: Albanese-Trump meeting at White House</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/in-full-albanese-trump-meeting-at-white-house/105914602</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f10aad2d02b2c86de204ccc28ba05311</guid></item><item><title>Australians turning to ChatGPT and other AI for financial advice warned to tread with caution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/using-ai-chatgpt-for-financial-advice/105882042</link><description>When Georgina Doll was looking to buy a home, generative artificial intelligence was one of the sources she turned to for advice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31dfe56a757dbf400518a430139816b9</guid></item><item><title>How bankers have learned to operate outside the rules in the murky world of private credit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/could-private-credit-spark-the-next-financial-market-meltdown/105912494</link><description>In recent months, there's been a growing focus on private credit, the alter ego of private equity, and the potential it may have to destabilise the system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b5102a83b080e9d88cf1e8ee42917d5</guid></item><item><title>Trump praises Australia and takes swipe at Rudd during White House meeting with Albanese</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/donald-trump-and-anthony-albanese-meet-in-washington/105914030</link><description>Donald Trump lavishes praise on Australia and Anthony Albanese during the pair's landmark meeting in Washington, but takes a swipe at a former prime minister in the room.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7300b47ce981f4e235c6ae1fd3ef2a90</guid></item><item><title>Destructive winds, storms and record heat to blast south-east Australia in wild weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/winds-wild-storms-record-heat-for-south-east-australia-weather/105912462</link><description>From record October heat to dangerous thunderstorms and gale force winds, the next 36 hours could bring extreme weather across south-east Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0825244e29b1997ee2ddd3702c377444</guid></item><item><title>Highlights of Trump-Albanese meeting at White House</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/highlights-of-trump-albanese-meeting-at-white-house/105914622</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54f39103b31b95a180c59b5e00880540</guid></item><item><title>Weapons maker Saab 'directly linked' to human rights harm over missile at Lake Hart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/saab-linked-to-human-rights-harm-over-woomera-missile/105911274</link><description>Traditional owners win a decision against a multinational weapons manufacturer after finding one of the company's missiles at a heritage site in the remote South Australian outback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">944f17d9574ffd98ced64a4f0b26e76f</guid></item><item><title>US steps up diplomacy as Israeli strikes test Gaza ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/us-steps-up-diplomacy-as-israeli-strikes-test-gaza-ceasefire/105914460</link><description>US officials travel to Israel as new strikes threaten to unravel progress towards achieving peace in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b12c21dff2e69a1d86485212f7d348e</guid></item><item><title>Surprise exhibition at Hamilton Art Gallery celebrates Hamish Elsmann</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/hamilton-gallery-exhibition-hamish-hidden-artist-secret-show/105869326</link><description>A country Victorian art gallery has surprised local artist Hamish Elsmann with an exhibition of work he never knew it was keeping. The community response has changed his life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45e47858d150c7ff2cab6ab258f13b12</guid></item><item><title>McLaren not panicking about defending F1 champion Max Verstappen's resurgence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/f1-mclaren-oscar-piastri-lando-norris-max-verstappen/105914662</link><description>McLaren boss Andrea Stella says the Formula 1 drivers' championship is still in his team's hands despite Max Verstappen's dominant performance at the US Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d49335b7ac7e8d30afb169dd4865541c</guid></item><item><title>Independent distributors calling for action on perceived monopoly on remote food distribution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/outback-store-outrage-independent-distributors/105911180</link><description>Independent wholesale distributors are calling on the federal government to reconsider the $50 million food subsidy scheme for remote stores that rolled out on July 1 of this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f0782ab919ed00f4fd043df077f1eaa</guid></item><item><title>Severe heatwave warning with Birdsville reaching 46 degrees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/severe-heatwave-warning-south-west-qld-birdsville-46-degrees/105911858</link><description>A severe heatwave warning is in place for parts of western Queensland with Birdsville poised to tip the record for the hottest October day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce213e7b0c0506e660fb8f141d678d1b</guid></item><item><title>CSIRO voyage discovers new species of shark and crabs off West Australia's Gascoyne coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/lanternshark-porcelain-crab-species-discovered-gascoyne-coast/105912604</link><description>After years of work, the CSIRO officially confirms the discovery of a glowing lantern shark and two armour-less crab species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">131227e05889b51a80c3884927fca46c</guid></item><item><title>'Gammon' assistant minister roles charge NT taxpayers thousands on travel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/nt-backbenchers-assistant-ministers-travel-costs-trips-clp/105911598</link><description>Northern Territory government backbenchers charge taxpayers thousands of dollars in travel as "assistant ministers", a role not officially recognised by the parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7a62254ab8d0031042e2a2596f2d074</guid></item><item><title>Natural Spoonfuls creator Stacey Hatfield dies after giving birth at home, family says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/nutrition-influencer-stacey-hatfield-dies-after-childbirth/105914672</link><description>Stacey Hatfield's husband revealed the nutritionist and social media influencer died in September after giving birth to the couple's first child.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c4ba91ca9a3b6544653465ded5e99ac</guid></item><item><title>ASX closes on fresh record high after US–Australia investment deal — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/asx-markets-business-live-news-october-21-2025/105914064</link><description>The ASX200 closed on a fresh record high after the US–Australia investment deal saw materials stocks surge. Catch up on the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7372ac62692b586a2b902f985ed7e22a</guid></item><item><title>Forgotten skate parks leaving the NT behind may be key in preventing crime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/nt-skate-parks-outdated-crime-prevention-social-infrastructure/105853732</link><description>Outdated and forgotten skate parks in the NT forced skaters to build their own underground spot. After years of neglect, experts ask why a region struggling with youth crime can't maintain one of the simplest crime prevention tools there is.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af9d8244633a5e2fa41582331966ec0b</guid></item><item><title>Sri Lanka scores World Cup win over Bangladesh following stunning final over</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/cricket-world-cup-sri-lanka-beats-bangladesh/105914724</link><description>Sri Lanka remains a chance of progressing in the Women's Cricket World Cup, but Bangladesh is out after an extraordinary finish in Navi Mumbai.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02d3a4f2f77a7c2d2f2907d3674f0d9f</guid></item><item><title>Vocalist Samara Joy is taking the jazz world by storm and she's bringing some new music to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/grammy-winning-jazz-vocalist-samara-joy-first-australian-tour/105911728</link><description>Samara Joy has been compared to singers like Ella Fitzgerald and Sarah Vaughan. She's performing in Australia for the first time and bringing some new music.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c47cb1e5f3ceebf14854861f53785b5b</guid></item><item><title>WA government asks EPA to investigate water taken from Pilbara aquifer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/wa-government-to-investigate-water-abstraction-in-pilbara-region/105904300</link><description>Traditional owners and pastoralists in WA's Pilbara are hoping a government-ordered review into the usage of a significant aquifer will better protect it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07ebb3888030e95d60034c4a459fc3cd</guid></item><item><title>Two West Australians in draft for first US women's professional baseball league in decades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/west-australians-draft-usa-womens-professional-baseball-league/105905754</link><description>Two West Australians are on the cusp of making history as professional women's baseball returns to the US after a 70-year hiatus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23d4b21c4e48a807a8d2157dbb8278a0</guid></item><item><title>SA government hopes selling generators can recoup costs of scrapped hydrogen plant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/sa-government-confident-of-recouping-hydrogen-power-plant-costs/105910680</link><description>South Australian taxpayers are set to pay more than $250 million on generators for the scrapped hydrogen plant — but the state government says it is in an "excellent position" to recoup the costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30afe5bf78e13275a9eff77fc64ffb62</guid></item><item><title>Premier Chris Minns announces 'in principle' $190m deal to take over Northern Beaches Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/chris-minns-government-takeover-northern-beaches-hospital/105914848</link><description>Joe Massa's parents, Elouise and Danny, have advocated for management changes of the Northern Beaches Hospital since their son's death there last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66e2eef0791c338a8708b1427b7b3693</guid></item><item><title>Strawberry supplies expected to return to normal after weather extremes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/strawberry-shortage-in-supermarkets-as-growers-face-challenges/105911558</link><description>Queensland strawberry growers are finishing their season early due to hot weather, while cold temperatures have delayed ripening in the south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1796a204e00c5bf4411f600bf21dcb95</guid></item><item><title>Political donations for Tasmania's federal election candidates disclosed in AEC returns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/tasmanian-political-donations-disclosure-aec-returns/105911172</link><description>A $100,000 donation from a sole donor was one of 212 declared by anti-salmon campaigner Peter George in his federal politics tilt, newly released Australian Electoral Commission returns show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa52705ad972f3a092dfadf9d8603ca3</guid></item><item><title>Legendary WS Cox Plate winner So You Think dies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/horse-racing-ws-cox-plate-winner-so-you-think-dies/105914886</link><description>A 10-time Group 1 winner, So You Think – who claimed back-to-back WS Cox Plate victories – is remembered as one of greatest race horses hit the turf in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4488e588f15d5ed4a9f656cc20b1e832</guid></item><item><title>The Mona Lisa, a gold toilet and now the Louvre's royal jewels: a fascinating history of art heists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/mona-lisa-gold-toilets-louvre-jewels-history-art-heists/105914884</link><description>This latest heist at the Louvre highlights the vulnerability of objects in public collections. The irony is they are often gifted to such institutions for safekeeping.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5e2688217f461635ffcaad734c9b3be</guid></item><item><title>Australian PM's first official meeting with US President</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/australian-pm-s-first-official-meeting-with-us-president/105915184</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2910aaca7357f662d16e3703312bc7f</guid></item><item><title>Trump tells Rudd 'I don't like you', reportedly offers forgiveness off-camera</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/donald-trump-kevin-rudd-i-dont-like-you-albanese-meeting/105914928</link><description>President Donald Trump has told Australia's ambassador to the US, Kevin Rudd, "I don't like you, and I probably never will" during a meeting with Anthony Albanese at the White House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3fdde6214d3477a382f513d315b472a</guid></item><item><title>How the genre of agricultural livestock art became so popular</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/agricultural-livestock-big-cow-art-popular-genre-paintings/105858568</link><description>An oil painting of an enormous bull is the star attraction at a regional Australian gallery. How did the genre of massive livestock art become so popular?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">498b8eba406c9befdc7ea2c86736ee61</guid></item><item><title>Amazon's AWS nears recovery after major outage disrupts apps, services worldwide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/amazon-aws-nears-recovery-after-major-outage-worldwide/105915042</link><description>Amazon says its cloud computing unit at a US data centre has largely contained the fallout of a worldwide outage but some services are still reportedly disrupted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23a31256e7773fa3f602162130ce2ca9</guid></item><item><title>American chess grandmaster Daniel Naroditsky dies aged 29</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/american-chess-grandmaster-daniel-naroditsky-dies/105915456</link><description>American chess grandmaster Daniel Naroditsky has died unexpectedly at the age of 29, his family has said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfd8e49f98872ce8943e8d43c720e0e4</guid></item><item><title>How to uncover a workplace's culture before you take the job</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/uncovering-a-workplace-culture-before-you-take-the-job/105862476</link><description>Organisational culture drives worker satisfaction and performance, and it's about more than having a pool table in the lunch room.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4eeb84dfd279b8fc8185914042ef1590</guid></item><item><title>Rare earths and critical minerals are used in everything from AI to medical tech, renewable energy and defence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/critical-minerals-deal-what-do-we-use-them-for/105898652</link><description>Many of Australia's critical minerals can be found in a wide range of everyday items, but their application at the cutting edge of medical research and military intelligence are among the most strategically important reasons governments in the West have been trying to build a supply chain outside of China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06756de3d83464daaa3839cafdcea708</guid></item><item><title>Chris Scott and Dean Cox named Victoria and Western Australia coaches for AFL Origin match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/afl-state-of-origin-coaches-chris-scott-dean-cox-victoria-wa/105915218</link><description>Chris Scott and Dean Cox are appointed as the AFL State of Origin coaches for next February's standalone exhibition match in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f615b96fca95068822cae6685487398</guid></item><item><title>At the Louvre museum, all the gold and grandeur could not stop thieves with power tools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/louvre-museum-heist-how-crown-jewels-became-and-easy-target/105913348</link><description>As French authorities scour Europe for some of their nation's most prized possessions, closer inspection of the Louvre museum itself reveals just how vulnerable it was to the type of attack that saw some of the French crown jewels disappear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93fe2bdffd3d1a14c9fd7e1c3878314c</guid></item><item><title>Former SA MP Troy Bell jailed for fraud and theft offending</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/troy-bell-sentenced-for-fraud-offences-in-sa-district-court/105912850</link><description>Former South Australian MP Troy Bell will spend at least two-and-half years in jail for stealing more than $430,000 in public money meant for not-for-profit education organisations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83d8ed950b5f60c450ff7acb0c561284</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says critical minerals deal with Australia will produce 'so much' in race against China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/australia-us-critical-minerals-framework-trump-china/105914736</link><description>Donald Trump and Anthony Albanese have inked a deal for "critical mineral and energy dominance" in a new partnership that will tip billions into mining projects in the US and Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2703ef1b96e61d11bfc510e4c4edfb70</guid></item><item><title>Maya Rudolph plays a billionaire trying to do good in season three of Loot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/maya-rudolph-on-playing-a-billionaire-trying-to-do-good/105914852</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4919562921a6a2914503c5a124ccbcd6</guid></item><item><title>Thieves steal Cowangie sign honouring local racing legend Larry Perkins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/cowangie-sign-honouring-racing-legend-larry-perkins-stolen/105911228</link><description>A small town near the Victoria-South Australia border is calling for thieves to return a sign paying tribute to local racing legend Larry Perkins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9053989e4460803d09f72d73a83f753e</guid></item><item><title>Fears for endangered Tasmanian crayfish species after 'unauthorised' earthworks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/fears-for-tasmania-crayfish-species-after-cement-australia-works/105913730</link><description>A creek in northern Tasmanian known to be home to the endangered giant freshwater crayfish has sustained "serious environmental harm" from land clearing and earthworks, the Environment Protection Agency has advised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c00ecd5245c8cbaa74355b2ade5fe8a0</guid></item><item><title>Tony Armstrong feels 'I could have an impact' tackling racism in sport in End Game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/tony-armstrong-tackles-racism-in-sport-in-end-game/105897492</link><description>Proud Gamilaroi man and TV presenter Tony Armstrong has felt the sting of racist trolling online. Now he's using it as ammunition as he tackles racism in sport in the new documentary series End Game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ef831dffd7fad88aff2700c255ce9cb</guid></item><item><title>Magistrate rejects bid by accused rapist Michael Wilson to limit media coverage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/accused-paedophile-michael-wilson-failed-suppression-bid/105915650</link><description>A magistrate rejects an application by an accused rapist to prevent media from reporting on his alleged links with accused paedophile childcare worker Joshua Dale Brown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e93edfdfa8c536a320a604b6d04e588b</guid></item><item><title>Albanese played it smart with Trump and walked away with everything he wanted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/albanese-trump-meeting-white-house/105916318</link><description>Anthony Albanese leaves Washington with everything he came for: a deal on critical minerals, an assurance on AUKUS, and an alliance reaffirmed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9508c8afb72089863d63535c4e9c2866</guid></item><item><title>Botany Bay seagrass monitoring shows the diversity of marine life.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/botany-bay-seagrass-monitoring/105916636</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09c0192e878361def6b0f65b9337f282</guid></item><item><title>Trump ends AUKUS uncertainty with firm backing for Albanese</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/trump-aukus-albanese-firm-support-pact/105915668</link><description>The US president's comments, made during his first in-person meeting with Anthony Albanese, put an end to months of speculation the US would back out of the agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7edca40f2c473a2e0d02d48dd25965f4</guid></item><item><title>'Cluster inquest' to be held into three patient suicides inside secure Brisbane mental health wards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/qld-cluster-inquest-suicide-prince-charles-hospital-brisbane/105915134</link><description>A coronial inquest will be held into a "cluster" of three patient suicides inside the secure mental health wards of a major Brisbane hospital within just seven months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c46448972ba4825a16ef4fc1ae4f6514</guid></item><item><title>Gungahlin United Football Club's debt exceeds $550,000 as closure leaves families 'totally blindsided'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/gungahlin-united-football-club-debt-increases-players-clubless/105915468</link><description>Families have been left "totally blindsided" by the closure of Gungahlin United Football Club, as the club's debts more than double to $550,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17967c3f23bde826fba806a92e7a9c10</guid></item><item><title>Rockhampton's Fitzroy River passes initial testing to host 2032 Olympic events</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/rockhampton-fitzroy-river-2032-brisbane-olympics-giica-testing/105915800</link><description>Despite backlash from national and international bodies, Rockhampton's Fitzroy River receives positive feedback following initial water testing to prove it is up to standard to host rowing and canoeing events for the Brisbane Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b85665be515db053b739ac6d6030178e</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith says he's happy to give Sam Konstas batting advice ahead of the Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/smith-says-door-open-if-konstas-wants-advice-ahead-of-ashes/105916680</link><description>As speculation swirls about Sam Konstas's spot in the Australian side ahead of the Ashes series, Steve Smith says he's happy to offer some advice to the struggling young gun about batting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">017798d31864bbcdc7d557b05565d82a</guid></item><item><title>Virginia Giuffre haunted by 'ghosts' of Jeffrey Epstein and Ghislaine Maxwell, Nobody's Girl memoir reveals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/virginia-giuffre-epstein-prince-andrew-nobodys-girl-memoir/105911280</link><description>The late Virginia Giuffre's memoir details how she became involved in the shadowy world of notorious sex offender Jeffrey Epstein, which led to her abuse at the hands of some of the world's "wealthiest and most powerful" people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">542a903ca5500e64a247a3bc6942e8f4</guid></item><item><title>Drone pilot course in doubt as Queensland reviews school-based training</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/drone-pilot-course-queensland-reviews-school-based-training/105915536</link><description>A popular drone pilot course for high school students is in doubt as the Queensland government reviews which vocational training it will subsidise in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de2331fda38110ce0c23615942969c8e</guid></item><item><title>Perth's new Women and Babies Hospital being built on time, but could tip over $1.8b budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/perth-women-and-babies-hospital-update-budget-construction/105916440</link><description>Perth's new Women and Babies Hospital will open on time in 2029, the state government insists, but it says the $1.8 billion budget may blow out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2d0d6df4e10cfcffd092cc08d5e91c2</guid></item><item><title>Sniper who killed Nick Martin at Kwinana Motorplex had killed before, David Pye murder trial hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/nick-martin-assassin-told-david-pye-he-had-killed-before/105911190</link><description>The assassin who murdered a former bikie boss in a sniper-style attack at a suburban speedway tells a Perth court he had killed people in targeted assassinations before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e04efa11d7389339f7111d0da063791f</guid></item><item><title>When Donald Trump was ready to take his pound of flesh, Kevin Rudd was here to help</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/trump-albanese-meeting-rudd-pound-of-flesh/105916336</link><description>From his humble early days as a child reading Hansard in the regional Sunshine State pocket of Eumundi, Kevin Rudd has been preparing for this martyrdom. But the Passion Of The Kevin, when it came, was a million miles from home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d35797ff528d2f35de2aae40ce3c4b7f</guid></item><item><title>Jason Thomas King sentenced to life in prison for murder of landlord Susan Walker on Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/jason-thomas-king-gold-coast-murder-trial-susan-walker-verdict/105917448</link><description>Jason Thomas King has been sentenced to life in prison after being found guilty of beating 74-year-old Susan Walker to death at her Gold Coast home, where he rented a room.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea18c2054e34583a48600daaed172c2d</guid></item><item><title>AFLW fights for fans' attention after a long men's season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/aflw-struggling-against-footy-fatigue-after-mens-season/105911454</link><description>One of the biggest challenges the AFLW faces is end-of-year "footy fatigue", according to diehard fans and industry insiders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">219ec25d00debc7a951fdc50a6d35de4</guid></item><item><title>A 1.3m crocodile sitting in the resort pool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/a-1-3m-crocodile-sitting-in-the-resort-pool-/105917422</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78d0eecc396e748b8a705e41abb3129b</guid></item><item><title>Wildlife ranger rescues croc from resort pool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/wildlife-ranger-rescues-croc-from-resort-pool/105917672</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">283b8353b4836c4be96359781fdcf07f</guid></item><item><title>Sanae Takaichi becomes Japan's first female PM, but some say it is not a win for women</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/japan-first-female-pm-sanae-takaichi/105911682</link><description>In the world of male-dominated politics, Sanae Takaichi has broken through an incredibly tough glass ceiling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7edfd07542db10ae864ca0583c58ffd6</guid></item><item><title>'Sheraton' the crocodile set for new life after being found in Port Douglas resort pool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/croc-relocated-from-resort-pool-port-douglas/105916692</link><description>A young female crocodile is transported to a nearby wildlife park after causing a stir with a dip in a resort pool.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9657f279d0dd0b6fb5c1f9dc0b76ba0e</guid></item><item><title>Electric vehicles have been stored at Jamberoo Action Park.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/electric-vehicles-stored-at-jamberoo-action-park/105917406</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2767dcbed017179cfff0a40667334739</guid></item><item><title>ACT government introduces bill to restrict same-day alcohol deliveries in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/act-government-proposes-bill-to-restrict-alcohol-deliveries/105916738</link><description>The ACT government introduces a bill that would restrict alcohol deliveries to Canberra homes to between 10am and 10pm, and cap the amount of alcohol a consumer could receive in a 24-hour period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28b4f43778de24aaecada34732ec6325</guid></item><item><title>State government refuses mandatory catch reporting for recreational fishers amid fish stock crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/wa-fishing-council-shocked-by-state-government-fishery-approach/105916462</link><description>Western Australia's commercial fishing industry says live data is essential to improve the health of the state's fisheries, but the WA government and recreational groups say it is not needed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2bb7f83c5480de85ccb5d6b51a8a73f</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar military detains more than 2,000 people in cybercrime centre raid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/myanmar-military-shuts-down-cybercrime-centre/105917612</link><description>The military raided KK Park which is a well-documented cybercrime centre as part of its operations to suppress crimes like online fraud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06bb80bf41a3f85e573f9e1cd2a24571</guid></item><item><title>Trump begins demolition to prepare for White House ballroom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/trump-begins-demolition-to-prepare-for-white-house-ballroom/105915632</link><description>Demolition work has begun for Donald Trump's new ballroom. It is one of many changes to the White House over the years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ca9f9a75963a1dd36ec454fecf68903</guid></item><item><title>Border Force seizes 3D-printed guns and parts in national crack down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/border-force-seize-3d-printed-guns-and-parts/105917850</link><description>An Australian Border Force operation leads to the seizure of more than 1,000 firearms and parts, including 281 made via 3D-printing processes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">400593e56d416095e39a34944c8e1751</guid></item><item><title>Queensland police called in to investigate after five people hospitalised from rat poison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/qld-rat-poison-cluster-logan-patients-police-investigating/105917342</link><description>A public health probe has so far failed to identify the source of the poisonings, which authorities say aren't being treated as suspicious.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fde6d408d7ec23156bbaa246d62a362</guid></item><item><title>Timothy Hunt sentenced to life in prison over murder of missing Darwin man Tony Rowe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/nt-timothy-hunt-sentenced-life-in-prison-over-tony-rowe-murder/105915660</link><description>Timothy Hunt is sentenced to life in prison for the murder of missing Darwin man Tony Rowe, in what Justice Sonia Brownhill described as a "bizarre, brutal and cowardly attack".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c6d1c71d032893d4e6b8b2925eb94c9</guid></item><item><title>Trump's take on China should shift the tone of war talk in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/trump-take-china-taiwan-shift-tone-war-talk-australia/105916520</link><description>Trump's remarks downplaying the threat of confrontation over Taiwan are highly significant for Australia. They should also shift the tone of much of the strategic discussion among China hawks on the prospects of imminent war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95d9007f43df93bfd4f448cb193e378b</guid></item><item><title>Friends' School staff member charged with child abuse offence after Hobart raids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/friends-school-staff-member-child-abuse-charge/105918150</link><description>The non-teaching member of staff at The Friends' School was arrested and charged following two police raids in Hobart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ff4bdaa230b00f831cb949217c6d008</guid></item><item><title>Scott Boland takes heart from match-winning Sheffield Shield spell ahead of the Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/top-sheffield-shield-spell-boosts-boland-for-ashes/105918176</link><description>Australian Test paceman Scott Boland says his five-wicket spell for Victoria last Friday was important for his confidence ahead of the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35ac36e9e015d984d7c03deea1582eae</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man jailed for part in 'cruel, calculated' attack on woman with baseball bat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/act-man-jailed-for-part-in-brutal-baseball-bat-attack/105918202</link><description>A Canberra man has pleaded guilty to his part in a "cruel" and "premeditated" attack on a woman, helping trick her into a car before driving her around, hitting her with a baseball bat, choking her and demanding $10,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9026ab1aa7a0e86883a24c970366d0bd</guid></item><item><title>Senator Nampijinpa Price civil trial hears land council CEO's reputation took a 'sustained hit' after media coverage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/nt-clc-lesley-turner-jacinta-nampijinpa-price-defamation-claim/105915448</link><description>On day two of the senator's defamation trial, a witness told the court the chief executive of one of the NT's largest land councils took a "sustained hit" to his reputation when news broke about an alleged no-confidence motion last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7455fb603de769458bc55063e3fcf13d</guid></item><item><title>Rex Airlines finds US buyer after entering into voluntary administration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/nsw-rex-airlines-administrators-find-buyer-air-t/105918688</link><description>Regional Express Airlines has found a buyer after the company went into voluntary administration last July.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23e81bf430b5bce5dc3eec801f504ccf</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105917806</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63a17fa67db074457eb1a618a5014730</guid></item><item><title>Kevin Rudd should not be sacked after Donald Trump's rebuke, Malcolm Turnbull insists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/rudd-should-not-be-sacked-after-trump-rebuke-turnbull-insists/105917016</link><description>Former prime minister Malcoim Turnbull says any talk of removing Kevin Rudd as ambassador to the United States should be ignored.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">397e35247996c6112ae30d5705344b35</guid></item><item><title>Yarra City Council mayor Stephen Jolly vows to fight 'nonsense' assault charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/yarra-mayor-stephen-jolly-to-fight-assault-charge/105918388</link><description>Yarra City Council mayor Stephen Jolly says he will fight an assault charge linked to a local government election afterparty last November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74f19e792c2ed6e659f8fc48d6ae34f5</guid></item><item><title>What we know about Amazon's AWS outage and why it was such a big deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/amazon-web-services-aws-outage-explained/105917274</link><description>Millions of apps, websites and services rely on AWS, one of the world's largest cloud computing platforms. Here's what we know about the outage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1de28de9fb10e4532cd4e8add0d912ec</guid></item><item><title>Injured Australian captain Alyssa Healy out of Women's Cricket World Cup match with England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/healy-out-of-australia-s-blockbuster-world-cup-clash-injury/105918786</link><description>Alyssa Healy suffers another injury at the pointy end of a World Cup, ruled out of Australia's clash against England with the finals on the horizon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">594dd5edd56b83b0c6686ae1a066025a</guid></item><item><title>Why are Queensland councils voting to remove fluoride from their water?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/remove-fluoride-from-their-water/105918022</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">703b3e3d259179d45ad76df4ffdfde43</guid></item><item><title>Former French president Nicolas Sarkozy leaves home ahead of prison sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/former-frech-president-nicolas-sarkozy-leaves-home-ahead-of-pris/105918858</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18112a2901cf393b90329d3822bd81e4</guid></item><item><title>Brittany Higgins drops appeal against former WA Senator Linda Reynolds' defamation win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/linda-reynolds-brittany-higgins-david-sharaz-defamation-trial/105918850</link><description>Brittany Higgins abandons her appeal of a WA Supreme Court finding that she defamed her ex-boss and former Liberal Senator Linda Reynolds in a series of social media posts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">082536e1f5c9e0eca6f5ff766a303b0f</guid></item></channel></rss>