<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 05:12:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Samoa's prime minister proposes ban on non-Christian faiths after vowing 'God-centred' leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/samoa-prime-minister-religion-restrictions/106225328</link><description>Samoa's prime minister has thrown the future of its religious minorities into doubt after flagging potential restrictions on non-Christian faiths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebae72323b0b85847169eb6d895b9309</guid></item><item><title>Death of Tim Picton puts spotlight on Australia's 'one-punch' laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/tim-picton-death-one-punch-law-national-state-breakdown/106245498</link><description>The death of Labor identity Tim Picton more than three weeks after he was allegedly assaulted outside a Perth nightclub has shocked Australia's political and business worlds and put the nation's one-punch laws under the microscope.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbdb1d300d1e36c3d586f70d5414bce8</guid></item><item><title>First Nations people will protest this January 26, a legacy dating back 88 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/why-first-nations-peoples-protest-on-jan-26/106248728</link><description>Invasion Day rallies will go ahead on Monday after being exempted from NSW protest bans. Here's the story of how they started in the first place.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">099647a352d14be82852c414e0e38460</guid></item><item><title>Scientific study documents Austrian cow using a tool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/scientific-study-documents-austrian-cow-using-tool/106247598</link><description>A pet cow in Austria has been filmed picking up a tool and scratching herself. An Australian hobby farmer says she is not that surprised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea86ccea34accc0a1ccb2c65d9691ef0</guid></item><item><title>Austrian study shows a cow using tools for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/austrian-study-shows-a-cow-using-tools-for-the-first-time/106249324</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e93ee64327f2f7b329361f0c4b81d487</guid></item><item><title>Queensland teenagers create coding app to bridge digital divide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/qld-teenagers-create-coding-app-code-lab-sri-lanka-students/106225842</link><description>Young coding whizzes Neth Dharmasiri and Chinmay Lal believe learning the language behind computer software shouldn't depend on where you were born.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3629ca2497c48acad1816ae6ba32176c</guid></item><item><title>Insurance industry hoping to break a major barrier to expanding cultural burning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/cultural-burning-insurance-breakthrough/106214712</link><description>Insurance has been a major stumbling block to the scaling up of cultural burning, but a breakthrough could be on the way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70b301662ea2f423238a1d5c9e30bd2f</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump, the madman theory, and why even Australia is not safe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/donald-trump-greenland-threat-madman-theory-analysis/106251358</link><description>One year into Trump's second term, something has become clear: even those who leave the Oval Office with a deal, beware. It might not be worth the paper it's written on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17a15eeef7276e5175a8d9725cbfee47</guid></item><item><title>Mitchell Starc shoulder injury concerns Sydney Sixers after BBL qualifier loss to Perth Scorchers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/sixers-sweat-on-starc-injury-after-bitter-scorchers-blow/106251462</link><description>The Sydney Sixers are thrust into a do-or-die final on Friday after losing to Perth, and star quick Mitch Starc is no guarantee to play.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eefe7c22daed676aa248b269f9e31aae</guid></item><item><title>Naomi Osaka brings fashion to RLA and Monfils says goodbye — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/australian-open-2026-quick-hits/106248012</link><description>Naomi Osaka took to Rod Laver Arena in a white, flowy jellyfish fashion piece on day three as Gael Monfils waved goodbye to Melbourne Park. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ad648002c1830c934b1b9a8e22a3c1b</guid></item><item><title>Canegrowers celebrates 100 years of fighting for fairness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/canegrowers-100-year-anniversary/106250648</link><description>Australia's sugarcane industry looks back on a century of representation as peak body Canegrowers turns 100.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d577715ca993aecd95ab753297f6b75</guid></item><item><title>Parents of Piper James, found dead surrounded by dingoes on K'gari, shattered by loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/kgari-dingoes-and-death-of-piper-james/106251528</link><description>The body of Canadian Piper James was found on K'gari (Fraser Island) surrounded by a pack of dingoes after she told friends she was going for an early morning swim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efdd2902e34ed5279d20f59d66213d10</guid></item><item><title>Perth Fringe World to feature over 3,000 performers across venues in Northbridge, CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/perth-fringe-world-to-feature-over-3000-performers/106248818</link><description>This year's Perth Fringe World is about more than just racy burlesque shows, spicy cabaret and acrobatic performances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9272b2c44bd3bb74d2fc5018ab0043a4</guid></item><item><title>Senior Nationals quit frontbench after defying shadow cabinet on hate speech laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/nationals-ministries-doubt-coalition-split-hate-speech/106251594</link><description>Senior Nationals Bridget McKenzie, Ross Cadell and Susan McDonald quit the shadow cabinet, after defying its position on the government's hate speech reforms in a late-night vote on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe681e902b030d99c1bea78cce0b26e2</guid></item><item><title>Nationals threat of mass resignation from shadow ministry a 'live option', Liberal source says — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/federal-politics-live-blog-jan-21/106251764</link><description>A Liberal source has told the ABC that multiple Nationals resignations from the shadow ministry is a "live option" after three Nationals quit the shadow cabinet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fca17b16aaff7da2dbb84db7b9dfd8d6</guid></item><item><title>JD Vance and wife Usha Vance expecting fourth child due in July</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/jd-vance-and-wife-usha-vance-expecting-fourth-child-due-in-july-/106251768</link><description>The vice-president and the second lady have been married since 2014 and share two sons and a daughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f75227b49324959b9c5fa3a9dd75e317</guid></item><item><title>The Pool Show at Penrith Regional Gallery casts a critical eye over Australia's pool culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/the-pool-show-penrith-regional-gallery-marian-abboud/106244548</link><description>A new exhibition in Western Sydney interrogates Australia's enduring love affair with the pool.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08cbaa5bbc3726f2bead7cb0590a1c96</guid></item><item><title>Aurora australis seen across Australia as geomagnetic storms deliver spectacular light show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/spectacular-aurora-australis-seen-across-australia/106251474</link><description>A severe geomagnetic storm has hit Earth, painting a colourful cosmic display in Australia's skies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">825db3e352f03ade701fdbbad7920a6a</guid></item><item><title>Europe weighs how to deal with Donald Trump's Greenland threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/donald-trump-heading-to-davos-world-economic-forum/106251386</link><description>America's rattled European allies are debating how to stand up to Donald Trump after he escalated his threats to take over Greenland and pledged to punish its supporters with tariffs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ed00c0f7e345e462f4e65c2cd40b8a1</guid></item><item><title>Griffith's Filipino community in shock at Kuya 'Butch' Buscato drowning in paddleboard mishap</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/kuya-butch-buscato-paddleboarder-drowning-tributes/106247502</link><description>A regional Filipino community is rallying around the family of 41-year-old Kuya "Butch" Buscato, who drowned after falling off a paddleboard in a New South Wales lake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65de6506855b30500b53872864d13118</guid></item><item><title>Chocolate manufacturers look to cocoa bean alternatives to tackle global market uncertainty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/cocoa-free-chocolate-alternatives-grow-cadbury/106243908</link><description>Cocoa substitutes are entering the chocolate market as the confectionery industry responds to volatile bean prices and supply.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a73b7c2268c81994845f7d663398c2fe</guid></item><item><title>Prime minister's national security adviser Philippa Brant resigns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/prime-minister-national-security-adviser-resigns/106252214</link><description>Philippa Brant has resigned just months after the PM's top foreign policy adviser departed to run the Office of National Intelligence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">763f42a5aafcf9f8eac55afeda3e30ce</guid></item><item><title>Trash and treasure trike proves powerful tool for brain health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/trash-treasure-trike-broken-hill-brian-slater-brain-health/106234034</link><description>Brian Slater, 77, is heeding advice to "use it or lose it" as he devotes his retirement to cognitive challenges that keep his mind healthy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b18a19aba6c1c38aadd2e1cbd0a8bc9</guid></item><item><title>Carney pledges Canadian support for Greenland and Denmark</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/carney-pledges-canadian-support-for-greenland-and-denmark/106251558</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e37b4ee0745743ac347e5e8f1a6519c</guid></item><item><title>WA meat processor says using AI for counting livestock has improved accuracy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/ai-camera-counting-sheep-at-wa-abattoir/106249366</link><description>One of WA's largest meat processors is using AI technology to count thousands of head of cattle a day with pinpoint accuracy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3d77b876e3e1623dcb17ef294264615</guid></item><item><title>Sheep under the eye of AI</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/using-ai-to-count-sheep/106250690</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c5af840e880887503748d0dd1f0eb2a</guid></item><item><title>A year into Trump's second term, the Supreme Court's docket is full of legal challenges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/trump-supreme-court-cases-breakdown/106249160</link><description>A wide range of cases challenging Donald Trump's actions have landed on the Supreme Court's docket in the past year. Here's what to know</description><guid isPermaLink="false">204d8408bab6913672663f8f59c38658</guid></item><item><title>Towns brace for potential 50-degree days as heatwave grips Pilbara and Gascoyne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/wa-towns-brace-for-possible-50-degree-days/106244600</link><description>Towns in WA's north-west could be about to experience Australia's hottest day on record, with the weather bureau expecting temperatures of 50 degrees Celsius in some areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd0dbc66d0f14f7042e6a44511e6e27d</guid></item><item><title>NT pomelo growers fear imports from Vietnam will flood market, risk reintroducing citrus canker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/pomelo-growers-citrus-canker-disease-fears-vietnam-imports/106250118</link><description>The Top End's pomelo industry is worried about the impending importation of the citrus fruit from Vietnam. They say it will depress the local market and bring a biosecurity risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e675248017bdeb51be021cca1210a130</guid></item><item><title>Angus Crichton to leave Sydney Roosters and NRL to chase Wallabies World Cup dream</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/angus-crichton-leave-roosters-chase-wallabies-world-cup-dream/106252548</link><description>Star second-rower Angus Crichton will leave the Sydney Roosters at the end of the NRL season to pursue a career in rugby union.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a295c7e2e59bb0b91dbf8ffd55deb05</guid></item><item><title>What is skimo? All you need to know about the new Winter Olympics event ahead of Milano Cortina 2026 Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/what-is-ski-mo-australia-names-2026-winter-olympics-team/106229150</link><description>Skimo is the newest sport at the Winter Olympics, but what is it? And who are the Aussies that will take on the challenge on the slopes of the infamous Stelvio climb?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3efdefa22173991050e8a1240bd089cf</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government to change construction industry after inquiry finds productivity declining</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/qld-construction-productivity-report-government-response/106252040</link><description>Changes will be made to everything from procurement to workplace health and safety legislation as the state government seeks to tackle declining productivity in the construction industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">227fd12bf4f54d52fae109f0449439d5</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's America-first policies are pushing countries into China's embrace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/donald-trump-is-a-gift-to-china-that-keeps-on-giving/106249578</link><description>Inside China, there's a nickname for Donald Trump that tells you everything you need to know about how the US leader's actions are increasingly seen as a gift to Beijing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e84cef9503369eecbd2a2ca690b2398</guid></item><item><title>Crime gangs restocking shops 'up to 10 times a day' with illegal cigarettes and vapes, WA police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/behind-the-scenes-of-wa-s-illegal-tobacco-business-model/106252960</link><description>WA's police commissioner says the restocking is happening faster than authorities can seize the products, as tobacco black market violence escalates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c85e3ad402b68eddf68bb31ca5929a65</guid></item><item><title>American rider and brumby complete 4,400km journey across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/american-rider-brumby-journey-across-australia/106238888</link><description>Gin Szagola and her brumby, Fable, have completed a coast-to-coast journey, covering 4,400 kilometres in eight months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c87bb28b98216d3d360a3f82c9d902b5</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs Mayor Asta Hill will not attend Australia Day ceremony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/alice-springs-mayor-will-not-attend-australia-day-ceremony/106252002</link><description>Asta Hill will not take part in celebrations of Australia Day, which she sees as a day causing harm to First Nations peoples — a decision described as "disgraceful" by the local member of the Northern Territory Legislative Assembly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">948bb6a11a41e328ce594aca829df759</guid></item><item><title>WA premier Roger Cook extends embattled Griffin Coal's lifeline, citing energy security concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/roger-cook-extends-griffin-coal-financial-lifeline/106250998</link><description>Since 2022, the WA government has already tipped $300 million into propping up the insolvent Indian-owned miner, which is more than $1 billion in debt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67e740016a3de5b8c9985d9a5054f374</guid></item><item><title>Canadian PM says smaller nations must 'band together' to stop larger countries overpowering them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/carney-blasts-trump-canada-davos-world-economic-forum/106252354</link><description>Canadian PM Mark Carney told the World Economic Forum "middle powers must act together".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3d402b5ff2519732956effe5b696207</guid></item><item><title>Chun Lai Yuen jailed after teenager Caitlyn Dickson seriously injured in Burswood crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/crown-perth-car-cruise-driver-jailed-caitlyn-dickson/106253204</link><description>The driver of a speeding car which hit and seriously injured a teenage girl after a car club meet-up at the Burswood Casino precinct has been sent to prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f220e6312335175671f756a46ab73f6b</guid></item><item><title>NZ Prime Minister Christopher Luxon calls for election on November 7</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/nz-pm-calls-for-election-to-be-held-on-november-7/106253286</link><description>NZ's Prime Minister Christopher Luxon has announced the election date for 2026, promising economic prosperity if New Zealanders vote for him again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2151ed94bdf31735ca532b3eee1999e3</guid></item><item><title>Liberals 'not that stressed' by leak — but Labor seizes on attempt to 'destabilise' leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/labor-liberal-war-of-words-over-sa-document-leak/106251982</link><description>The leaking of an SA Liberal document two months before the state election has been described by the Labor government as a "calculated and methodical" attempt to "destabilise" new leader Ashton Hurn — but her party says it is "not that stressed" because the policy is old.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfcdecbed89774f218970ce8605ff790</guid></item><item><title>What we know about changing UK passport requirements effective February 25</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/what-we-know-about-changing-uk-passport-requirements-explainer/106252182</link><description>Hundreds of confused UK and Irish dual citizens in Australia have written to the ABC with questions around the new changes for entry requirements into the UK. Here's what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ad4283cc2e20810a878022673bc9745</guid></item><item><title>Australian NATO envoy Di Turton warns North Korea has 'combat-ready troops in our region'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/turton-warns-north-korea-has-combat-ready-troops-in-our-region/106246654</link><description>Australia's outgoing military envoy to NATO is preparing to return to Canberra after two years in the role, and she is coming home with a warning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b24fa33cd95a9f83851e93c8d2239d49</guid></item><item><title>Why Elina Svitolina is prioritising her mental health at the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/australian-open-elina-svitolina-prioritises-her-mental-health/106253922</link><description>In the highly competitive world of professional tennis, it is refreshing to learn that Elina Svitolina has her priorities in order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">231dc2e91147acfd4cd1936346129dc9</guid></item><item><title>New South Wales man charged with allegedly threatening prime minister</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/man-charged-threatening-politician-bellingen-prime-minister/106252292</link><description>A NSW Mid North Coast man is granted bail after he allegedly threatened to shoot the prime minister, in a video uploaded to social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a162f7503002a63f89c62572cb4f408</guid></item><item><title>Midnight Oil's Rob Hirst died of pancreatic cancer. It's one of Australia's deadliest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/midnight-oil-rob-hirst-pancreatic-cancer-death/106252876</link><description>Rob Hirst was first diagnosed with pancreatic cancer in 2023. It is estimated to be the third most common cause of cancer death in Australia, and has among the lowest survival rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9ddc9310c0db0de11b44dad7f91d666</guid></item><item><title>Have you been gifted an ancestry DNA test? The results could be 'life-altering'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/why-ancestry-dna-tests-arent-just-a-bit-of-fun/106225222</link><description>If you're thinking of taking an ancestry DNA test as "a bit of fun", experts warn there is the risk of uncovering more than you bargained for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c18adfae6ecc122d7b0786df99d29aa2</guid></item><item><title>Shane Marshall pleads not guilty to manslaughter charge over infant's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/shane-marshall-pleads-not-guilty-to-infant-manslaughter/106254184</link><description>An Adelaide man has been ordered to stand trial after pleading not guilty to a charge of manslaughter following the death of a seven-week-old baby who had allegedly been in his care. WARNING: This story contains details that some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a93023575c22fb9d852afd34e94351c</guid></item><item><title>Zeynep Sönmez thrills Turkish fans with latest Australian Open win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/australian-open-zeynep-sonmez-turkiye-second-round-melbourne/106254442</link><description>In front of her loyal supporters, Türkiye's Zeynep Sönmez advances to the Australian Open third round, as her remarkable run continues at Melbourne Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22727b155241893e1895d1a9d793586a</guid></item><item><title>New hate laws have passed parliament. What do they actually do?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/what-will-new-hate-laws-do/106253754</link><description>The new laws grant powers for the government to list so-called hate groups, more easily deport or cancel the visas of individuals associated with hate groups and create new aggravated penalties for leaders who advocate violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22f42220711e3e177be96bf784d2def9</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's second presidency is about 'might makes right' and reshaping the world order be it in Venezuela or Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/donald-trumps-year-one-lays-ground-for-new-world-order/106252232</link><description>As Donald Trump celebrates one year of his second term in the White House, he is rewriting all the rules for global order, and no-one seems ready to stop his "imperial ambitions".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68e8d76ada9efedaa2427ff84102d70f</guid></item><item><title>WA gold companies 'floating on a sea of cash' as the commodity hits new price record</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/gold-price-continues-to-smash-historic-records/106252736</link><description>A Kalgoorlie miner hopes the soaring price of gold will incentivise investment into regional WA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">727c087761f0b6ae2a28d0df6ed03a2c</guid></item><item><title>Why Emmanuel Macron was wearing sunglasses at Davos World Economic Forum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/why-emmanuel-macron-wore-sunglasses-to-davos/106252204</link><description>The French president's appearance at the annual meeting of the World Economic Forum makes headlines, but not for any policy reasons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae7b6da24375daf367a7ce77fd45d66d</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106254400</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96b2d0610f77559240b421960b39fc7a</guid></item><item><title>Banned Adelaide doctor Bill Tolis in court over steroid importation charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/adelaide-banned-doctor-bill-tolis-charged-steroid-importation/106253698</link><description>A man who was banned from working as a doctor in 2022 appears in court charged with importing steroids and peptides that the Australian Border Force allegedly found in a medical clinic and at his home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15ae84013164210499851a72702a1db6</guid></item><item><title>Groups targeted by federal hate laws quietly scrub social media channels and website</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/neo-nazis-coached-on-how-to-avoid-arrest-hate-laws/106250932</link><description>Two groups in the sights of the government's new hate crackdown have moved to scrub their online profile.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d23db8cfaced150be4c3ac579fab2320</guid></item><item><title>Benjamin Netanyahu, Azerbaijan agree to join Trump's 'Board of Peace' as Norway and Sweden reject invitations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/israel-and-azerbaijan-to-join-trumps-board-of-peace/106254994</link><description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu agrees to join US President Donald Trump's "Board of Peace" despite his office previously criticising the makeup of the executive committee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a809f7bafb25060ffc5b77861c179cb</guid></item><item><title>Father of Adelaide girl who died due to mother's alleged neglect tells court of coffin threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/jasmine-willmott-father-gives-evidence-in-manslaughter-trial/106254726</link><description>The father of a 15-year-old girl whose mother is accused of her manslaughter, tells the South Australian Supreme Court of a threat made against his daughter and punishment she was made to do.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">877e18523e326afbcffe861376220e59</guid></item><item><title>Coalition on the brink as Nationals quit shadow ministry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/nationals-coalition-littleproud-ley-hate-laws/106254676</link><description>Opposition leader Sussan Ley says the Nationals' mass resignation from her frontbench is "unnecessary" and has urged the rural party to remain in the Coalition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2506e2c3d1df8a3e6b416a4e1ad58809</guid></item><item><title>K'gari traditional owners raise dingo management issues after teen's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/kgari-traditional-owners-dingo-management-issues/106252220</link><description>The body of Piper James, 19, was found surrounded by dingoes on a beach on the island's eastern coast, but how she died may not be known for some time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac54ad630f52e053a14ca4033cf0af1e</guid></item><item><title>Real estate prices set records with six capitals now in 'million-dollar club' and Melbourne rebounding strongly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/australian-real-estate-median-home-prices-domain-report-millions/106251932</link><description>The Melbourne real estate market is leading a "decisive recovery", according to property portal Domain, as the city hits a four-year high for its median house price after strong growth across the country last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ecae4dcc6d7b32b532b527df98b5815</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump drops Greenland tariffs threat as he heralds 'future deal' with NATO</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/donald-trump-tells-davos-he-wants-greenland-deal-with-denmark/106255244</link><description>Donald Trump says he has agreed to a "framework of a future deal" on Greenland after talks with NATO's secretary-general, and he will no longer impose tariffs on European nations that had opposed a US takeover.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f89614fd2c7c59f2ce651d55a6edb4</guid></item><item><title>Japan restarts nuclear power plant almost 15 years since Fukushima disaster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/worlds-biggest-nuclear-power-plant-restarted-after-fukushima/106255280</link><description>The world's biggest nuclear power plant has been rebooted by the same company that operated the Fukushima facility, despite concerns about safety from some locals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">449f4979bd3a97dd3cade26e5436d195</guid></item><item><title>Emotional Prince Harry says media made his wife Meghan Markle's life 'an absolute misery' at Daily Mail trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/prince-harry-gives-evidence-at-high-court-in-privacy-case/106255216</link><description>An emotional Prince Harry held back tears as he described the impact of media coverage on his wife Meghan Markle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0303b3d89bae8745f194d9374bac2748</guid></item><item><title>Why Ukrainians are shivering through their fourth winter in wartime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/energy-crisis-kyiv-winter-ukraine-russia-blackouts/106255468</link><description>The war-ravaged country has been plunged into an energy crisis as temperatures plummet below freezing, leaving millions unable to heat their homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccb3c54d802b1a2340a3cc49537ca8e3</guid></item><item><title>Children and journalists killed by Israel in separate incidents in Gaza, Palestinian medics say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/children-and-journalists-killed-by-idf-in-gaza/106255512</link><description>According to Palestinian medics, two boys aged 10 and 13 were among those killed on Wednesday in the latest violence which threatens to undermine a fragile ceasefire deal between Israel and Hamas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd3c1332546ddcee2f19fb827ee29a26</guid></item><item><title>Royal Hobart Hospital medical scan backlog creating late diagnosis risk, AMA says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/royal-hobart-hospital-medical-scans-outsourced/106250608</link><description>The Royal Hobart Hospital is facing a significant backlog of medical scans, with at least one patient experiencing a late diagnosis. The AMA and a union say it's a sign of a system facing a range of pressures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b176a825f6f77ae4bd8c9f6625b7666e</guid></item><item><title>How closely have you been following the 2026 awards season?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/mid-awards-season-quiz/106236836</link><description>Fancy yourself an awards season whiz? Test your knowledge as we rocket towards the 2026 Academy awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17381a39bd7b2538186d35a6037811fe</guid></item><item><title>Republicans push to hold Clintons in contempt of Congress over Epstein probe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/clintons-us-house-contempt-over-epstein/106255510</link><description>The Clintons are refusing to testify before a committee in the US House of Representatives, accusing Republicans of leading a weaponised process against them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c80ed23b03f8eb6f6c2be9bc2e08dae</guid></item><item><title>Calls to bring back hard-hitting anti-smoking campaigns to warn off gen Z</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/calls-to-bring-back-hard-hitting-anti-smoking-campaigns/106076928</link><description>Experts say Australia risks becoming complacent in the war against tobacco, with big companies pivoting to social media to "greenwash" their products to generation Z.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a3755c5faf71c4ae310c4fa1f70cef6</guid></item><item><title>Nationals' walkout leaves Coalition in tatters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/national-walkout-coalition-on-life-support/106252042</link><description>The departure of every single member of the Nationals from the frontbench is bizarrely both a failure of the Coalition agreement and a result of it functioning as intended.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87d0ee925d656b9cc5bc9005730349bd</guid></item><item><title>Australia earns global praise for economic 'soft landing' but still dependent on China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/reserve-bank-earns-global-praise-for-economic-soft-landing/106254000</link><description>A new report from the OECD says Australia's economy is returning to normal but remains vulnerable and lacks dynamism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05e404f80625145a36267752e37fcb5d</guid></item><item><title>Europe holds the trump card as the US faces a mountain of debt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/trump-us-debt-carney-davos-fractured-world-order/106254272</link><description>For decades, global investors have bought US government debt as a safe haven when things turn pear-shaped. But investor attitudes are changing, and America's financial domination is at stake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef5ba145fdb46fb1740c5e13e6f77eb3</guid></item><item><title>'Ten-pound Pom' vows to boycott UK over 'money grab' passport changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/ten-pound-pom-boycotting-uk-over-passport-changes/106252052</link><description>People who came to Australia as children from the UK as part of an organised migration scheme say they the UK's new regulations for dual citizens unfairly targets them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">589e215128e03f85233423439cb2ca67</guid></item><item><title>Hobart Hurricanes beat Melbourne Stars in rainy thriller to keep BBL title defence alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/hurricanes-win-in-the-rain-to-get-bbl-title-defence-alive/106255630</link><description>The Hobart Hurricanes hold their nerve to beat the Melbourne Stars in a rain-shortened Big Bash elimination final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b3de8ccef426aa4a98bc8ad84b9fc29</guid></item><item><title>Sinner weighs up Kyrgios and Kim Jong-Un, plus an Aussie exodus — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/australian-open-2026-quick-hits/106252228</link><description>Jannik Sinner was stuck in an awkward moment discussing Nick Kyrgios and Kim Jong Un while Coco Gauff shared her top artists. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">910ec10d7ff7c87b7739ef59bc8e52af</guid></item><item><title>Taskforce set up to address ongoing power outages across SA from dust pollution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/power-outages-across-regional-south-australia-from-dust/106252096</link><description>Ongoing dry conditions across South Australia since 2024 are causing dust and salt to build up across inland and coastal power networks, polluting insulators and leading to mass blackouts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfa755b708992c638b64e4eaec702edf</guid></item><item><title>Nationals leave 'untenable' Coalition after mass frontbench resignation — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/politics-live-blog-nationals-coalition-liberal-ley-littleproud/106255658</link><description>After National frontbenchers quit the shadow ministry en masse in solidarity with three colleagues dumped for crossing the floor on hate laws, leader David Littleproud says the Coalition has been forced into a "position that can no longer continue".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a1735a6d8a7f4c354e01bf028d78b9c</guid></item><item><title>Trump rules out using force to acquire Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/trump-denies-possibility-of-using-force-to-acquire-greenland/106255572</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">055ef0c7ec96765a861e340c4f3ff2fe</guid></item><item><title>Back-to-school budgeting a chance for kids to learn financial literacy and empathy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/how-to-involve-your-kids-in-back-to-school-budgeting/106225314</link><description>Managing back-to-school costs, especially when kids want expensive brand name items, can cause a lot of stress for families. But including children in the budgeting and decision-making process is key to helping everyone get on the same page.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37b64c02787d589912788d033586f11c</guid></item><item><title>Manchester City players reimburse travelling fans after shock Champions League loss to Bodo/Glimt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/man-city-players-reimburse-fans-champions-league-bodo-glimt-loss/106255684</link><description>Manchester City players combine to pay back the cost of match tickets to fans who travelled to freezing Norway for a shock Champions League defeat to Bodø/Glimt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3961b71b542f027eda47766f4098781a</guid></item><item><title>Former and current presenters share 50 years of memories at ABC Classic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/abc-classic-presenters-celebrate-50-years-of-broadcasting/106245866</link><description>From late-life love stories to musical discoveries, presenters reveal what has made ABC Classic special for audiences for 50 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e95bb9135719c0184072ebc1bb2d1890</guid></item><item><title>More than one disaster a week raises concerns over mental health support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/mental-health-natural-disasters-floods-bushfires/106248008</link><description>Mental health experts warn of significant barriers to support in disaster-affected communities, as Australia records more than one natural disaster a week since January 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1754a727c59bc8d6ab652edb65847dd</guid></item><item><title>$10 billion data centre planned for Hazelwood in Victoria's Latrobe Valley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/keppel-data-centre-latrobe-valley/106123748</link><description>Victoria's east is set to become home to a $10 billion data centre that will support the technology necessary for artificial intelligence systems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9956deb90fefb9d8c74ef249d8393b13</guid></item><item><title>Concerns raised after sawfish, sharks and turtle found mutilated on northwest WA beaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/sawfish-shark-turtle-found-dead-in-carnarvon/106254342</link><description>Residents and experts say they are shocked and concerned after social media images showed a number of endangered and protected marine animals impaled and severed on a stretch of WA coastline in just a few weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14db6bd51044c50feade70e00cdb04e5</guid></item><item><title>Plan to rebuild world's largest living coral aquarium explained after years of delays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/townsville-reef-hq-aquarium-great-barrier-reef-australia-rebuild/106233472</link><description>The world's largest living coral reef exhibit is yet to be rebuilt five years after the Queensland aquarium closed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8a00984196c7af8a42ee31f3ff4fcb0</guid></item><item><title>Tour website's AI sends visitors to Tasmanian sites that do not exist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/ai-images-of-tasmania-on-tour-website/106253448</link><description>Weldborough in remote north-east Tasmania has lots of natural beauty. But it does not have hot springs — and it is causing headaches for locals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17596b208021bc09f69e25ce3d3ee9cf</guid></item><item><title>Administrators seek buyers for Sanjeev Gupta's Tahmoor Coal mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/tahmoor-coal-sale-gupta-administrators/106254968</link><description>Administrators have put Sanjeev Gupta's Tahmoor Coal mine up for sale, seeking buyers to recover value for creditors and potentially restart operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc73e72ea7427583d3403e8301d3c525</guid></item><item><title>AJ Ogilvy, former NBL player, comes out as gay on eve of league's Pride Round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/aj-ogilvy-former-nbl-comes-out-gay-pride-round/106255856</link><description>Former NBL player AJ Ogilvy publicly reveals he is gay in a one-on-one conversation with fellow basketball trailblazer Isaac Humphries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80eb63b342830bb88108f2a6e89f5eb6</guid></item><item><title>Why did Queensland's flood warning gauges fail when they were needed most?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/how-queenslands-flood-gauges-broke/106236592</link><description>Queensland's flood emergency exposed vast holes in the patchwork of river gauges relied on for early warnings. But getting them back online will take a lot more than a reboot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f5b6c8f6a565b9ea8df5000357371c9</guid></item><item><title>Coalition splits for second time since election after Nationals quit shadow cabinet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/coalition-splits-for-second-time-since-election/106255898</link><description>David Littleproud says the Nationals have been put in an "untenable" position and are not willing to serve in a shadow ministry led by Sussan Ley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da003f94bbd7e082339a8bd3ef36d5c7</guid></item><item><title>'You have no idea what fair play is': Osaka and Cirstea in tense exchange</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/australian-open-2026-live-novak-djokovic-kyrgios-kokkinakis/106256036</link><description>There is no love lost between Naomi Osaka and Sorana Cirstea after the Japanese star prevails in a hard-fought three-setter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc3dbf5886ebf502a83d62ef67ff3bdc</guid></item><item><title>Sydney council explores offshore sand dredging as locals fear losing beaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/sutherland-shire-explores-offshore-sand-dredging-cronulla-beach/106251664</link><description>A group of passionate locals have called for a long-term solution to the disappearing sand from beaches in Sydney's Sutherland Shire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58c0ea5fd754280000e1a36d1fef918d</guid></item><item><title>Nationals leader explains decision to split up Coalition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/nationals-leader-explains-decision-to-split-up-coalition/106255942</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f75ba7679df47ab0f3098326608c3164</guid></item><item><title>Murray-Darling water-sharing study proposes combining agriculture and conservation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/water-sharing-policy-proposal-for-murray-darling-basin/106251850</link><description>Can breeding birds and growing rice combine to help both conservation and agriculture in the basin?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64845f1f36a9ad2ae78f48d4f6d928ef</guid></item><item><title>Frances Tiafoe psyched up to play Alex de Minaur in Australian Open third round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/australian-open-alex-de-minaur-frances-tiafoe-third-round/106256130</link><description>It says a lot about the presence of youth in professional tennis that Alex de Minaur and Frances Tiafoe can already be considered veterans on the tour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad79a2741bd570aac7d24180c8fae85f</guid></item><item><title>Unemployment rate drops to 4.1 per cent ahead of RBA's next rates meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/abs-jobs-unemployment-december-2025-figures/106256288</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate fell from 4.3 to 4.1 per cent in December, according to seasonally adjusted figures from the Australian Bureau of Statistics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca9a4c57a25ef4052b004d05710e2490</guid></item><item><title>Young girl among several missing after landslide at NZ campsite — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/new-zealand-landslide-search-for-missing-people/106256570</link><description>Several people are missing after a landslide at a campsite in the tourism hotspot of Mount Maunganui, south-east of Auckland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23379a7a711cb4f2aedc78ee1266c283</guid></item><item><title>March for Australia administrators encouraged members to join White Australia political party</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/verify-neo-nazi-group-linked-to-political-party/106254196</link><description>March for Australia organisers are planning a fresh round of mass demonstrations across the country on January 26, with members encouraging others to join the now disbanded White Australia Party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61c84afa4ed39ce502156f3c3e35ad8b</guid></item><item><title>PhD candidate Sepehr Saryazdi, accused of planning terror attack on Australia Day, denied bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/sepehr-saryazdi-faces-court-on-terror-charge-australia-day-csiro/106256410</link><description>Sepehr Saryazdi has been accused of planning to use Molotov cocktails and lead a "riot" at the Gold Coast on Australia Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ecb762097d3b8e934762d0a9df97185</guid></item><item><title>Somerville House school principal Sandra Hastie announces resignation after leaking scandal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/somerville-house-principal-resigns/106256792</link><description>A prestigious Brisbane girls' school principal will resign, following a scandal where personal student information was leaked to the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2834e86129d59d1552d5a5a7d397d301</guid></item><item><title>The optics are diabolical for Liberals and Nationals, as chaos reigns on a supposed day of mourning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/optics-diabolical-liberals-nationals-split-chaos-reigns/106256942</link><description>Littleproud and his team have now basically broken one of the most fundamental political rules of the Coalition — the Nationals are now effectively dictating to the Liberals who their leader should be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfc29a319f10b7654b1744b2408480f8</guid></item><item><title>In Davos, European leaders met Donald Trump with strength and he backed down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/european-leaders-stood-up-to-trump-at-davos/106256300</link><description>European leaders will be breathing a sigh of relief that the extraordinary threat of a US invasion of Greenland has receded. But some things cannot be undone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbd4efa493fa52920fc34df51ab08033</guid></item><item><title>Mount Hot Pools damaged in landslide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/mount-hot-pools-damaged-in-landslide-/106257412</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2367d81a746a6d3b8eaa418a7889faa5</guid></item><item><title>Former Texas police officer acquitted of child endangerment in Uvalde school shooting trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/former-police-officer-acquitted-response-uvalde-school-shooting/106257186</link><description>A former officer charged with child abandonment and endangerment over the police response to the Uvalde school massacre in 2022 is acquitted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17708e8c1b29425fc797e317e56d6675</guid></item><item><title>Territorians working hard to cull cane toads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/territorians-working-hard-to-cull-cane-toads/106254792</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01dc070978534f4b990110319cca61b2</guid></item><item><title>More than 1,000 cane toads captured in first Darwin botanic gardens bust in years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/nt-cane-toads-community-bust-invasive-pest-darwin-rain/106254926</link><description>Volunteers in Darwin have chipped in to capture more than 1,000 cane toads at one of the city's main attractions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b11df1d2cdc1b23fc82c0ad1ac738a15</guid></item><item><title>Australian writer Murray Hunter apologises to Malaysian regulator over criminal complaint in Thailand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/australian-writer-murray-hunter-faces-prosecution-in-thailand/106071904</link><description>Rights groups slam Thai authorities' detention and legal proceedings against Australian writer Murray Hunter, after Malaysia's communications regulator submitted a criminal defamation complaint.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a398c92859ab9deed27a35a44ed1eedc</guid></item><item><title>Darwin locals volunteer at local cane toad bust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/darwin-locals-volunteer-at-local-cane-toad-bust/106257890</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85b6d139a7f1ea346764657bb5f1b245</guid></item><item><title>What's next, as Liberals and Nationals go their own way?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/what-next-sussan-ley-leadership-coalition-split/106256498</link><description>In the wake of the Coalition's divorce, there are few options for besieged Opposition Leader Sussan Ley, who must again reshuffle her cabinet and return to parliament with a diminished Opposition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">994575ca7514db7940e29e80b787ba77</guid></item><item><title>The 'Golden Dome' and why Trump wants the defence system in Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/why-trump-wants-golden-dome-missile-defence-in-greenland/106255982</link><description>Donald Trump wants a US "Golden Dome" missile defence system to be built in Greenland. This is what it involves and why some experts are skeptical of the plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7283312beb72caebfa691b8786b889d2</guid></item><item><title>Jay Vine climbs into Tour Down Under ochre jersey after UAE Team Emirates XRG underlines its dominance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/jay-vine-wins-tour-down-under-stage-two/106257102</link><description>Australian Jay Vine claims the overall race lead at the Tour Down Under after an awesome display of dominance on the Corkscrew climb.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb9e394e9534f79c841df8035f841ba4</guid></item><item><title>Woman who assaulted psychiatrist and other healthcare workers remanded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/woman-who-assaulted-psychiatrist-healthcare-workers-remanded-vic/106256858</link><description>A judge tells a Victorian court the safety of healthcare workers must be protected while remanding a mentally ill woman to jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9a8a342d45019c7e529a6831781d169</guid></item><item><title>Perth financial advisor Anthony Paul Torre jailed for taking more than $1 million from clients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/anthony-paul-torre-jailed-stealing-fraud-1million-from-clients/106255256</link><description>Victims of a Perth financial adviser jailed for misappropriating more than a million dollars from investors say his six-year jail term is not enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d61027d39caaea38c6adc2658d7601e</guid></item><item><title>Forbes man Lawrence Wilfred Norris intends to plead not guilty to historical child sex offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/lawrence-norris-intends-to-plead-not-guilty-child-sex-offences/104852292</link><description>A NSW court hears the former vice-president of a local show society intends to plead not guilty to dozens of historical child sexual assault charges if he is found fit to stand trial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f13bb702d228f8cf1e73d4fef38f24e</guid></item><item><title>National Party's Coalition split timing deemed 'unbelievable' on National Day of Mourning for Bondi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/regional-voters-react-to-national-party-liberals-coalition-split/106256646</link><description>The second messy break-up between the National and Liberal parties is concerning regional voters across the country, even in diehard conservative heartlands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70ea918e48b086454d41c22e7c84bed8</guid></item><item><title>Australia's anti-slavery commissioner asks Tony Burke for visa reform after inquest into Jerwin Royupa's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/jerwin-royupa-inquest-training-visa-program-risk-exploitation/106256652</link><description>Australia's anti-slavery commissioner has written to Home Affairs Minister Tony Burke asking for reform on the 407 training visa, following the inquest into the death of Jerwin Royupa.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78c2b89799ced9a7c99a9e0c8149bf9c</guid></item><item><title>Hot air mass travels across the country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/hot-air-mass-travels-across-the-country-/106258982</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6350b2e40cb4ca343f7d6fa28c5888b</guid></item><item><title>Severe heatwave to affect eastern Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/severe-heatwave-to-affect-eastern-australia-/106258990</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">402399edc4093f7ebc9cfd5549cfb37a</guid></item><item><title>St Vincent's Hospital charged over 2024 death of Makalie Watts-Owen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/melbourne-st-vincents-hospital-worksafe-makalie-watts-owen/106258858</link><description>Makalie Watts-Owen died by suicide while admitted to St Vincent's Hospital's mental health unit, a month before her 24th birthday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">481fed42fae5b1f13529ac9d555f0b95</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Reynolds being interviewed by Gary Adshead in 2025.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/bruce-reynolds-interview/106258878</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db30559dfeea5ac89674f1a6e7a8959a</guid></item><item><title>City of Perth probe lays bare workplace 'crisis', erosion of trust between Mayor and CEO</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/city-of-perth-workplace-behaviour-probe-/106250502</link><description>The City of Perth has rapidly descended into a workplace of psychological harm, according to a secret report obtained by the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64fc50ebb57a43747397b8920642f9ac</guid></item><item><title>From Bone Temple to Oscar hopefuls, here are January's best movies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/what-to-watch-in-cinemas-january/106233164</link><description>Multiple Oscar hopefuls are finally hitting Australian shores this month, as well as the return of zombie franchise 28 Years Later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2272f4f6ef3115ef6805bda843c70c9</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106258766</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e59c5ef1942298829e1214a0c64fd5dc</guid></item><item><title>Two people die in suspected drowning at Crystal Creek, north of Townsville</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/couple-dead-suspected-drowning-north-qld-crystal-creek/106259082</link><description>Emergency services were called to Crystal Creek near Mutarnee just before 3pm on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24c5c84eefc05264faea327654b71c72</guid></item><item><title>First LNG cargo from Santos Barossa gas project bound from Darwin to Japan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/nt-first-cargo-lng-santos-barossa-gas-leaves-darwin-for-japan/106258638</link><description>After a series of delays, Santos announces the first gas from its $5.6 billion Barossa project will be shipped from Darwin bound for Japan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd8bba37d4f040d1881712e836830e01</guid></item><item><title>Mackay council gives evicted rough sleepers 24 hours to move on from riverfront</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/mackay-homeless-given-notice-to-move-on-from-riverfront/106258276</link><description>Mackay Regional Council tells rough sleepers evicted from riverfront camps to pack up and move within 24 hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f48c5f10652cf15c7726a34ab73bebd</guid></item><item><title>Maddison Inglis wins epic Australian Open second-round match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/australian-open-maddison-inglis-wins-second-round-melbourne/106258820</link><description>With a 10-point tiebreaker to decide her Australian Open fate, Maddison Inglis knew there was only one avenue to victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7da89e4d1adfe1038099cca78fbd4468</guid></item><item><title>Nationals senator Matt Canavan questions if government and agencies can be trusted on hate speech laws and attacks Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/matt-canavan-coalition-split-attacks-asio-government-ley/106259282</link><description>Nationals senator Matt Canavan has questioned why anyone should trust any government when it comes to the powers over hate speech laws, and unloaded on Sussan Ley's leadership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9a65ee94a1a53fc1f7f43539a06fa28</guid></item><item><title>Albanese apologies for Bondi Beach terror deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/albanese-apologies-for-bondi-beach-terror-deaths/106259358</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94b82df021fca2826d2b7b9e1c9e2f51</guid></item><item><title>Naomi Osaka apologises for 'disrespectful' post-match comments aimed at Sorana Cirstea after tense Australian Open exchange</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/tennis-naomi-osaka-apologises-sorana-cirstea-aus-open-exchange/106259566</link><description>Naomi Osaka walks back her aggressive retort to a tense handshake between her and second-round opponent Sorana Cirstea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09581ba0cb5ce587403760bbfce3cced</guid></item><item><title>Oscars 2026: Sinners break record with nominations, Jacob Elordi and Rose Byrne receive nods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/oscar-nominations-2026-academy-awards-sinners-jacob-elordi/106259128</link><description>Vampire film Sinners broke the Academy Award record for nominations with 16, while Rose Byrne was recognised for If I had Legs I'd Kick You and Jacob Elordi got a nod for his role in Frankenstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48c475fdedf71590ecb11f7edcbff1a8</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan shopping centre fire in Karachi kills at least 55 people as recovery efforts continue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/death-toll-from-pakistan-shopping-centre-fire-rises/106259932</link><description>Investigators are continuing to search for others who died in the disaster, with authorities yet to announce what caused the blaze.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5675475904019bb62a9711d4410804c</guid></item><item><title>Climate change increased the chance of intense Australian heatwave fivefold, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/climate-change-increased-australian-heatwave-january-study/106253192</link><description>A study by World Weather Attribution has analysed temperatures during the intense early January heatwave. It found that what was once a rare event is now happening far more often.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c1638010033b66e55d7fe8893d1a603</guid></item><item><title>France seizes suspected Russian 'shadow fleet' oil tanker in Mediterranean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/france-seizes-oil-tanker-that-left-russia-in-mediterranean-sea/106260102</link><description>The move is the latest by Western allies to crack down on a so-called "shadow fleet" of tankers suspected of carrying Russian oil against international sanctions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43d6477f8aa1dc4292de5def3f75e127</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy flags trilateral Ukraine, Russia and US talks, while slamming 'lost' Europe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/zelenskyy-announces-ukraine-talks-with-russia-us/106260134</link><description>The Kremlin has confirmed the Ukrainian president's announcement, made at the World Economic Forum in Davos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7545f1ac1fc90719bebdd764e896542e</guid></item><item><title>Death toll from Spanish high-speed train disaster rises to 45</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/spain-train-death-toll-hits-45/106260198</link><description>Train drivers in the country are striking after a string of rail accidents in less than a week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">143c5b51c32ad15e4cd58f05c34af47d</guid></item><item><title>Questioning your relationship in the new year? You're not alone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/why-the-new-year-exposes-relationship-problems-/106224924</link><description>The fresh start of a new year causes us to reassess many parts of our lives, including relationships. Knowing whether it's time to call it quits or give things more time requires reflection — and support — as our experts explain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a8679e8fb180c317100f0812cb15f67</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: A political break-up, a fashionable entrance and Macron's aviators</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/weekly-news-quiz-january-23/106258548</link><description>Another week, another quiz. Are you ready to test yourself?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54cbf4b01ab6495cdb58b22385dc9242</guid></item><item><title>The Nationals split shows the foundations of right-wing politics are shifting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/liberals-nationals-split-coalition-right/106257774</link><description>It is impossible to view this week’s events without the broader context of the relationship between the Liberals and the Nationals, how the electoral map is changing and what that means for right-wing politics in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e5d77a30c76d5a35cb630af005cbb89</guid></item><item><title>Trump touts 'total access' Greenland deal as NATO asks allies to step up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/trump-greenland-deal-access/106260210</link><description>The leaders of both Denmark and Greenland say they don't know what's in the deal, announced by the US president after he backed away from threats of tariffs and military force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c54c670db00f8511a0c0a5ef5e47e881</guid></item><item><title>Australia names second-largest Winter Olympic team in history for 2026 Milan-Cortina Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australia-names-athletes-for-2026-winter-olympics-milan-cortina/106257140</link><description>From five teenagers making their Winter Olympics debut to five-time Olympian and gold medal hopeful Scott James, Australia has named its second-largest team in history for the Milan-Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9364382cbf12d3eab2d2239d3c30bf50</guid></item><item><title>Anger and confusion after Australian courier Sendle collapses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-courier-tech-sendle-collapses/106237380</link><description>The Australian company's customers feel like they have been "ghosted", while investors and shareholders are angry and confused about what happens next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75d4d8cc352fa82cac285f1a0bcac529</guid></item><item><title>Venezuela's El Helicoide was built as a world-leading retail hub. Then it became a notorious 'torture prison'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/venezuela-el-helicoide-history-from-shopping-centre-to-prison/106232826</link><description>Nestled among shanty homes, mountains and forestry, a giant building once touted to become Venezuela's world-leading retail mecca later turned into a centre for alleged human rights abuses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76e6bc139f10a583017d798a7f71355c</guid></item><item><title>Seven-day heatwave to engulf south-east states, raising bushfire danger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/seven-day-heatwave-for-south-east-australian-states/106258360</link><description>South-east states are predicted to bake through a prolonged severe heatwave from Saturday onwards, which has the potential to break all-time temperature records and fuel another round of dangerous bushfires.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e206661f047d7153c78444b4bf38fcc</guid></item><item><title>Fiji police allegedly seize $780m cocaine shipment in drug operation targeting Pacific Ocean 'narco sub'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/fiji-vatia-alleged-cocaine-bust/106252766</link><description>Fijian chiefs reported suspicious activity along their stretch of coastline to law enforcement agencies — which then swooped on an alleged $780 million drug operation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7b65c9bfdd418c9e913eeb19db1490c</guid></item><item><title>Daylesford op shop may permanently close after donation causes bed bug infestation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/daylesford-op-shop-closed-after-bed-bug-donation/106257322</link><description>The future of a Victorian op shop is in doubt after a worker opened a bag containing the stuff of nightmares, leading to the destruction of stock and hefty cleaning bills that may prove to be a deadly financial blow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92343d5a6b3a6f9e91a7d081f2faf352</guid></item><item><title>Six people confirmed missing in landslide at New Zealand's Mount Maunganui</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/new-zealand-landslide-search-at-mount-maunganui-continues/106259556</link><description>Specialist officers have worked through the night with earthmoving equipment to try and find those trapped under the rubble at a popular tourist spot on New Zealand's North Island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b56c3c64c991749e723a32a089f025b8</guid></item><item><title>Gunman wanted over triple shooting could be difficult to find, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/police-search-for-lake-cargelligo-gunman-after-three-shot-dead/106260214</link><description>Police have warned residents in villages neighbouring Lake Cargelligo to remain vigilant after three people were shot dead in a domestic violence attack on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6237034df4c10ee4887c72324b79c0b</guid></item><item><title>'Catastrophic' fire danger forecast for eastern Eyre, Yorke Peninsula, on Saturday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/adelaide-australia-day-forecast-fire-danger-yorke-peninsula/106257684</link><description>Catastrophic fire conditions are forecast for both the Yorke Peninsula and the eastern Eyre Peninsula for Saturday, while Adelaide is forecast to have its hottest Australia Day on record and its hottest day since 2019.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a53a3d4adffd3b13e7a584d13132823a</guid></item><item><title>David Speirs not entitled to public campaign funding, electoral commission says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/david-speirs-not-entitled-to-campaign-funding-commission-says/106252588</link><description>Former opposition leader David Speirs would "not fulfil the nomination requirements" if he applied to be a candidate at the upcoming state election, the state's electoral commission says, raising significant doubts about his chances of a political comeback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b51d1258f01f889f9ffa8d09f9b01925</guid></item><item><title>Solid start to AI camera trial with rock fisher rescue at one of NSW's deadliest locations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/ai-camera-rescue-rock-fisher-kiama-blowhole/106252572</link><description>Surf Life Saving NSW says the successful rescue of a rock fisher at Kiama Blowhole using two AI-enabled surveillance cameras proves the technology works.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e967a1d1c2cfc39de99b807ffaa9f852</guid></item><item><title>triple j's Hottest 100 of 2025 — when it happens, how to listen and more</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/triple-j-hottest-100-of-2025-date-start-finish-time/106255830</link><description>Australia's favourite music poll is back for another year — here's when it happens and how to listen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1040e2c0baec6105e30c997bf6a0c8f8</guid></item><item><title>Former childcare worker sentenced to community service after pleading guilty to assaulting five-year-old</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/qld-childcare-abuse-court-beenleigh/106257348</link><description>A former Queensland childcare worker who dunked a child in a "muddy" puddle, causing him to hit a toy and injure his face, has been sentenced to 100 hours of community service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19283855a6e721356bc514d5d85a2141</guid></item><item><title>Wawrinka's post-match recovery beer and an 'elite coffee snob' — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-open-2026-quick-hits/106256482</link><description>Madison Keys praises Melbourne coffee, Stan Wawrinka says he deserves a beer and Nick Kyrgios back to racquet throwing ways. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdb19a2b8f7adeb672b77b643c9797c4</guid></item><item><title>Albanese predicts 'at least one more' Coalition MP will defect to One Nation — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/politics-live-blog-coalition-nationals-liberal-ley-littleproud/106258084</link><description>The PM's comments came after Nationals leader David Littleproud said he was open to working with Liberal leader Sussan Ley again "at some point", but right now the two parties need "a bit of time apart".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">654dbfefff1e7fe6f19497082344c400</guid></item><item><title>Homeschool 'drop-off' groups are booming but some say they are unregulated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/homeschool-drop-off-groups-australia-regulation/106192824</link><description>Education experts say homeschooling's exploding popularity has sparked a growing market of "drop-off" groups.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0ca7121cc29813c44dbfbed385a671b</guid></item><item><title>DNA found in an ancient Colombian skeleton may hold answers to origin of syphilis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/ancient-dna-in-colombian-skeleton-syphilis-finding/106257238</link><description>A previously unknown strain of syphilis bacteria has been discovered in human remains in Colombia, dating back 5,500 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">761f4136bcbedf14e3f88cb864e27b50</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios and Thanasi Kokkinakis lose first round Australian Open men's doubles clash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/special-k-nick-kyrgios-thanasi-kokkinakis-aus-open/106260326</link><description>After playing like "shadows of our former selves", Nick Kyrgios and Thanasi Kokkinakis are out of the Australian Open men's doubles and into an uncertain future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c0855d44f970a7bd97e76435b181e56</guid></item><item><title>Live: ASX up, Australian dollar hits 15-month highs, gold breaches $US4,900</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/asx-markets-business-live-news-jan23-2026/106260382</link><description>The Australian share market has made modest gains after a rally on Wall Street, as investors showed signs of relief a day after US President Donald Trump dropped tariff threats against eight European countries and ruled out seizing Greenland by force. Follow the latest updates in our live blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40932dc245b230489389510db47af34d</guid></item><item><title>Inside the Syrian city of Raqqa, once known as Islamic State's 'Roundabout of Hell'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/inside-raqqa-syrian-government-kurdish-fighters/106259928</link><description>Syrian government forces have wrested back control of vast parts of its territory in recent weeks, as a new president moves to assert control over the war-torn country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7976dc278e108c80f77b0c705e6920d</guid></item><item><title>Woman sentenced for illegal use of pepper spray as NT government looks to make laws permanent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/darwin-woman-sentenced-over-illegal-use-of-oc-spray-nt/106255114</link><description>A Darwin woman is handed a community corrections order for attacking someone with OC spray in a nightclub fight just weeks after the Northern Territory government announced a 12-month trial of the product.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3932d3b6bca7945308a5322d8d1504e</guid></item><item><title>How cool rooms and cold storage work to keep fruit fresh year-round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/cool-rooms-keep-apples-fresh-year-round/106244706</link><description>Apples only grow for three months of the year — but thanks to an ancient technique, that doesn't stop us grabbing one from the grocery store year round.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18d4e3c1e52e7cd899af23bc7bc1ad00</guid></item><item><title>Calls for state government to provide greater support for venue owners wanting to remove pokies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/lord-gladstone-removes-pokies-calls-for-more-to-support-venues/106258678</link><description>Mitch Crum thought removing pokies from his pub was a good thing, but the costly and confusing process made him feel like a criminal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11bffa204dd9c950796047f61d4d87d0</guid></item><item><title>Defiant Sussan Ley downplays Nationals' split, vows to remain leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/defiant-sussan-ley-vows-to-remain-leader/106260460</link><description>The Liberal leader did not speak about the Nationals' decision to terminate the Coalition on yesterday's National Day of Mourning, but on Friday insisted her focus was on the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a7f9d5a8b73b778d178181d0ad4f49c</guid></item><item><title>Clermont couple build online flood tracker in just hours to warn neighbours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/clermont-flood-tracking-website/106243686</link><description>The 'Gauge' site was built in just four hours by IT professionals Steve and Emma Coochin and has expanded to include river and rain data from across Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf95207740915c40a8c0727439d39906</guid></item><item><title>Japan's demand for Australian table grapes drives export growth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-table-grapes-export-to-japan-demand-rises/106237572</link><description>A rise in demand is making it feasible for some Australian grapes to be on sale in South-East Asia within 48 hours of being dispatched.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7648010b07efe81af52be5bcd7df448c</guid></item><item><title>Tropical low forecast to bring heavy rain to northern Cape York, Gulf of Carpentaria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/tropical-low-heavy-rain-cape-york-gulf-of-carpentaria/106260620</link><description>Saturated catchments along the Gulf of Carpentaria and north-west Queensland are bracing for more heavy rain next week, although the weather bureau says the likelihood of a cyclone is low.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75a8cf68a1a2c07acaa78e3d7876813e</guid></item><item><title>Oscar nominations 2026: All the snubs, successes and surprises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/oscar-nominations-2026-snubs-successes-surprises/106260530</link><description>Hybrid horror Sinners came up as the big winner in the 98th Academy Award nominations, with Aussie actors also eyeing up gold, and Wicked: For Good wiped off the map.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d761bb2879eaa9851b2172d6c644d374</guid></item><item><title>Live: Aussie wildcards dump out top seeds as Osaka urged to 'say less'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-open-2026-live-sabalenka-alcaraz-de-minaur-osaka/106260854</link><description>A pair of tennis greats suggest Naomi Osaka may want to quiet down on court after her clash with Sorana Cirstea, while Australian wildcard pair James McCabe and Li Tu beat the men's doubles top seeds on day six of the Australian Open. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a04cafe18c649afd498aa7f1f3f47fbb</guid></item><item><title>NBL star urges middle ground on Pride Round after Breakers jersey boycott</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/nbl-star-urges-pride-round-middle-ground/106260522</link><description>As the NBL's Pride Round begins, Marcus Lee warns an all-or-nothing approach could shut down the very conversations the round is meant to start.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58242609ac0484472fb20c7700974f98</guid></item><item><title>Australian-born dual citizens confused, frustrated over new UK passport rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/british-australians-caught-up-in-passport-bungle/106252142</link><description>Confused dual citizens are voicing their frustrations as they grapple with changes to the UK's entry requirements, which roll out next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">425f1782f91f4a16c4bb6da1d72f8e07</guid></item><item><title>Taylor Fritz pays tribute to 40-year-old Stan Wawrinka ahead of Australian Open match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-open-stan-wawrinka-taylor-fritz-third-round/106261080</link><description>It was meant as a compliment, rather than a show of disrespect, when Taylor Fritz answered a question about Australian Open rival Stan Wawrinka's age.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c2e005d319489a9f8a0eccc72657f11</guid></item><item><title>1,000 cakes and eight complaints: Brisbane picnic event under investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/qld-cake-swap-food-safety/106254312</link><description>An investigation has been launched into a viral Brisbane 'cake swap' event after attendees raised concerns over food safety and hygiene, with cakes reportedly left uncovered in hot weather for hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1e5dc3e8811ac8635e15909c20516d4</guid></item><item><title>ICE officers detain five-year-old Minnesota boy as he arrives home from preschool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/ice-officers-detain-5-year-old-minnesota-boy/106260888</link><description>School officials and the family's lawyer say the boy and his father were taken to a detention facility in Texas, making the boy the fourth student from Minneapolis detained by immigration officers in recent weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f1e66129057f445bb42e4ec7cae6d7</guid></item><item><title>Man allegedly doused Gungahlin Police Station foyer in petrol and lit fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/man-arrested-for-lighting-fire-in-canberra-police-station-foyer/106261084</link><description>Police allege the man entered the station with a jerry can, poured petrol onto the floor and lit it on fire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f76650c41aafda93d65436a756e99021</guid></item><item><title>Fresh melioidosis infections spark warnings for North Queensland flood clean-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/melioidosis-infections-mackay-region-flood-clean-up/106260730</link><description>Health authorities investigate a spike in case numbers for the soil-borne disease melioidosis over the past year as heavy rains again bring the bacteria to the surface.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1876832b56ff04f3a85e502de592162</guid></item><item><title>Illegal dumping creates eyesore and hard work at Sunshine Coast op shops</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/sunshine-coast-op-shops-frustrated-with-illegal-dumping/106247800</link><description>Volunteers say they are tired of "lazy" residents dumping their unwanted goods outside op shops to avoid paying tip fees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">871279b041aa2167b88a4b69d8849176</guid></item><item><title>Lanlan Yang admits to breach of bail after Rolls-Royce crash in Sydney's east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/nsw-lanlan-yang-court-rolls-royce-crash/106261518</link><description>The 23-year-old has sparked curiosity and intrigue among Chinese Australians due to her apparent wealth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b43c3604703b1dd2574a016e52f8ee24</guid></item><item><title>$17 million announced to push Wollongong sports and entertainment precinct closer to reality</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/wollongong-sports-entertainment-precinct-funding-announced/106261074</link><description>The NSW government has unveiled long awaited plans for the redevelopment of Wollongong's sporting precinct as it commits $17 million to develop a business case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff60335d34dbbef747d64f935b214079</guid></item><item><title>Paris Hilton brings sex tape story to Washington for AI deepfake porn fight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/paris-hilton-returns-to-washington-for-deepfake-porn-fight/106260660</link><description>The party girl turned anti-abuse advocate throws her glamorous celebrity heft behind a push to tackle deepfake pornography.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be3bdab756405b29eee8fe4b96735764</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone warning extended as tropical low edges closer to Kimberley coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/tropical-low-cyclone-kimberley-coast-weekend/106257742</link><description>A tropical cyclone warning has been issued for residents along the far north WA coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40b1ded951323489c7af96436cdb5857</guid></item><item><title>Interstate police reviewing use of force in Kumanjayi White's death in custody in Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/kumanjayi-white-case-update-death-in-custody/106261098</link><description>After resisting calls for an arms-length investigation, NT police are "facilitating" prosecutors' request for an independent review of the arresting officers' use of force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b04ff3a2a2c57cfe96d3912780dbf7f4</guid></item><item><title>US and China sign off on TikTok agreement to avoid ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/us-and-china-sign-off-on-tiktok-agreement-to-avoid-ban/105946464</link><description>Social media giant TikTok reaches a deal for a new joint venture in the United States to avoid being banned for American users. The platform's Beijing-based parent company, ByteDance, will retain a 19.9 per cent stake in the company.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98db492f98dbae94336107116f99f2ec</guid></item><item><title>What Bernard Fanning and Ben Lee's Hottest 100 topping hits tell us about them in 2005</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/ben-lee-bernard-fanning-2005-tea-sympathy-precocious-awake-sleep/106254430</link><description>In 2005, Bernard Fanning and Ben Lee were very different men with very similar struggles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4104fb0576195f6d49333b282b330b1c</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump is obsessed with Greenland, but now his comments point to the 'entire Arctic'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/donald-trump-greenland-maps-explain-battle-for-arctic/106248192</link><description>After a week of escalating rhetoric over Greenland, Donald Trump says he has now secured "total access" to the Arctic island. This is why that region is so important.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80258e25c9b73d3a371cfd33873c0456</guid></item><item><title>Queensland brothers charged by Australian Federal Police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/queensland-brothers-charged-by-australian-federal-police/106260960</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbe8574470d5b56affd5bb91706d698d</guid></item><item><title>Queensland brothers charged with child abuse material offences after US tip-off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/ashley-and-kaden-millard-gladstone-charged-child-abuse-offences/106260552</link><description>Australian Federal Police investigators allege the men accessed child abuse material on social media platforms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b379ecc2a299291d7b0566fdc26d53e</guid></item><item><title>Who is Indra Brown, the 15-year-old Melbourne schoolgirl going for gold at Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/indra-brown-australia-15-year-old-freeski-halfpipe-star/106220172</link><description>When 15-year-old Indra Brown reached the podium in her first World Cup event, she needed help from global superstar Eileen Gu to pop the cork on her champagne. She's had plenty more practice since, as she heads into the Milan Cortina 2026 Winter Olympic Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1bd2a59bbb1851f70a1c81a87c262dc</guid></item><item><title>Regional NSW principal to stand aside amid antisemitism investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/riverina-principal-to-stand-aside-antisemitism-investigation/106260992</link><description>The principal of an Islamic school in regional NSW has stood aside while investigations into alleged antisemitic comments continue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66bbf4776663885e6118d7122c516844</guid></item><item><title>Letter sent to Lakemba Mosque threatening violence on Australia Day investigated by police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/nsw-australia-day-mosque-threat-police-investigation/106260802</link><description>The note, seen by the ABC, incited violence against several groups, including Middle Eastern communities, Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islanders and a number of political figures from Labor, the Greens and "socialists" were also singled out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40a93d7c9c85c5131545560539c3e2e1</guid></item><item><title>Decision to suspend Tasmanian councillor Louise Elliot for 'child-like' comments upheld in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/councillor-sanctioned-over-clown-man-comments/106261958</link><description>A Tasmanian councillor says she is being "censored and unfairly punished" after being sanctioned for social media posts she made regarding a fellow councillor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15db2611739d68e4253bc14a8e7bf7f6</guid></item><item><title>Trump sues JPMorgan Chase for $US5 billion, alleging bank closed accounts for 'political reasons'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/trump-sues-jp-morgan-chase-jamie-dimon-closes-accounts-political/106260598</link><description>Donald Trump is suing banking giant JPMorgan Chase and its chief executive for $US5 billion ($7.3 billion) over allegations that JPMorgan stopped providing banking services to him and his businesses for political reasons in January 2021.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89430bef8f415825580494dd7adb60f5</guid></item><item><title>US officials tout 'New Gaza' plans filled with shiny luxury skyscrapers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/us-touts-new-gaza-filled-with-luxury-real-estate/106261524</link><description>US officials have presented their vision for a "New Gaza" that would turn the shattered Palestinian territory into a glitzy resort of skyscrapers by the sea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">332468f105e8f38eeb197372324b59be</guid></item><item><title>Townsville mother says she warned authorities before suspected drownings at north Queensland swimming hole</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/townsville-mother-warns-over-suspected-drownings/106260772</link><description>Local mother Jordan Pryce says she witnessed multiple near-drownings at the swimming hole on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f99789714191e9b4596c2d89b1fb66f4</guid></item><item><title>Track temperatures as heatwave sweeps across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/temperatures-heatwave-tracker-australia-day/106261904</link><description>Use our tracker to keep an eye on temperatures as a heatwave moves across much of the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e57e1f2214ee021677fa9f1ede08fbdd</guid></item><item><title>Final report urges Queensland to opt out of building accessibility requirements, government says it won't</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/qld-building-accessibility-standards-productivity-construction/106261950</link><description>A final report by the Queensland Productivity Commission recommended the state opt out of standards outlined in the National Construction Code.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44412ebf5637154213ddf0ac0f84d478</guid></item><item><title>Launceston City Council staff to vote on four-day, full-pay work week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/council-seeks-to-usher-in-four-day-work-era-on-full-pay/106261380</link><description>Launceston City Council and the Australian Services Union have reached in-principle agreement on a deal for employees to work 30.4 hours over four days, and be paid their full salaries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6de6e4998c9225528e97f7a38ee2254</guid></item><item><title>Who is the Neo-Nazi who was booed at Hobart's March for Australia rally?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/who-is-neo-nazi-nsn-member-at-hobart-march-for-australia/106243774</link><description>With the organisers of March for Australia rallies saying they "are in no way concerned by the presence" of members of the National Socialist Network, the ABC can confirm a Tasmanian man whose words were too extreme for many in the Hobart crowd is believed to be a leader within the state's Neo-Nazi movement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dd9e1cf44e49a7d888aa48587dc3692</guid></item><item><title>Labor identity Tim Picton remembered at Perth Stadium memorial service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/tim-picton-memorial-service/106255116</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is among political figures and business leaders who travel across the country to pay their respects to Mr Picton.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5d7055f3334cbd3e08a1546f091c39f</guid></item></channel></rss>