<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 20:49:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Myanmar military detains more than 2,000 people in cybercrime centre raid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/myanmar-military-shuts-down-cybercrime-centre/105917612</link><description>The military raided KK Park which is a well-documented cybercrime centre as part of its operations to suppress crimes like online fraud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06bb80bf41a3f85e573f9e1cd2a24571</guid></item><item><title>Trump begins demolition to prepare for White House ballroom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/trump-begins-demolition-to-prepare-for-white-house-ballroom/105915632</link><description>Demolition work has begun for Donald Trump's new ballroom. It is one of many changes to the White House over the years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ca9f9a75963a1dd36ec454fecf68903</guid></item><item><title>Border Force seizes 3D-printed guns and parts in national crack down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/border-force-seize-3d-printed-guns-and-parts/105917850</link><description>An Australian Border Force operation leads to the seizure of more than 1,000 firearms and parts, including 281 made via 3D-printing processes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">400593e56d416095e39a34944c8e1751</guid></item><item><title>Trump's take on China should shift the tone of war talk in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/trump-take-china-taiwan-shift-tone-war-talk-australia/105916520</link><description>Trump's remarks downplaying the threat of confrontation over Taiwan are highly significant for Australia. They should also shift the tone of much of the strategic discussion among China hawks on the prospects of imminent war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95d9007f43df93bfd4f448cb193e378b</guid></item><item><title>WA government considers legislating 'climate targets', but refuses to explain those targets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/wa-government-flags-legislating-climate-targets/105918114</link><description>The WA government is foreshadowing the introduction of legislated "climate targets" next year but refuses to clarify what those targets will be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc9d5b17fb3cf6dc7bbf66dce3b00674</guid></item><item><title>Scott Boland takes heart from match-winning Sheffield Shield spell ahead of the Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/top-sheffield-shield-spell-boosts-boland-for-ashes/105918176</link><description>Australian Test paceman Scott Boland says his five-wicket spell for Victoria last Friday was important for his confidence ahead of the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35ac36e9e015d984d7c03deea1582eae</guid></item><item><title>Kaurna ancestral remains re-buried in emotional repatriation ceremony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/kaurna-ancestral-remains-re-buried-repatriation-ceremony/105917020</link><description>An emotional ceremony for the repatriation of Aboriginal remains that had been held by institutions, including the South Australian Museum, has been held in Adelaide's north at a site that is now a resting place for hundreds of Kaurna ancestors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f24b1fb630348f041f5e3f60720497cf</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105917806</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63a17fa67db074457eb1a618a5014730</guid></item><item><title>What we know about Amazon's AWS outage and why it was such a big deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/amazon-web-services-aws-outage-explained/105917274</link><description>Millions of apps, websites and services rely on AWS, one of the world's largest cloud computing platforms. Here's what we know about the outage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1de28de9fb10e4532cd4e8add0d912ec</guid></item><item><title>Injured Australian captain Alyssa Healy out of Women's Cricket World Cup match with England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/healy-out-of-australia-s-blockbuster-world-cup-clash-injury/105918786</link><description>Alyssa Healy suffers another injury at the pointy end of a World Cup, ruled out of Australia's clash against England with the finals on the horizon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">594dd5edd56b83b0c6686ae1a066025a</guid></item><item><title>Critical minerals deal signed by Anthony Albanese and Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/critical-minerals-deal-signed-/105918016</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e2301a3a503d04d4d1562de3bf80706</guid></item><item><title>Why are Queensland councils voting to remove fluoride from their water?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/remove-fluoride-from-their-water/105918022</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">703b3e3d259179d45ad76df4ffdfde43</guid></item><item><title>Scientists prepare to release captive adult Maugean skates as attention turns to captive breeding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/scientists-prepare-to-release-captive-adult-maugean-skates/105856276</link><description>From a specimen unexpectedly launching itself out of a tank, to another dying from a gastrointestinal blockage, and bite marks made during mating rituals, the ABC can reveal the challenges scientist face keeping the endangered Maugean skate species alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7fe66af3db8fb93044c802f6edd7017</guid></item><item><title>US Vice-President JD Vance visits Israel amid Gaza ceasefire concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/jd-vance-visits-israel-amid-gaza-ceasefire-concerns/105919276</link><description>The vice-president urged Israel to have "a little bit of patience" with Hamas as the militant group tries to find the remains of deceased hostages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3043491283d3bd4912a90cb7430cecd5</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese defends Kevin Rudd after criticism from Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/albanese-defends-kevin-rudd-after-donald-trump-criticisms/105919238</link><description>Anthony Albanese strongly endorses his hand-picked ambassador to the United States, Kevin Rudd, as he seeks to draw a line under Monday's awkward encounter with Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b328bb1152e989268562113e7e558274</guid></item><item><title>Critical minerals industry cheers deal that will 'encourage greater investment' as stock prices swing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/critical-minerals-industry-us-china-deal-rare-earths-stocks/105915274</link><description>Australian critical minerals companies could expect more international and domestic investment in producing and processing following the deal, experts say, however, more investment is needed in refineries and magnet production.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">943031dad3eede489e5f12e2370df947</guid></item><item><title>Industry warns building houses in Australia slower than it was a decade ago, construction targets missed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/housing-construction-slower-than-a-decade-ago-australia/105918352</link><description>Industry experts warn – despite improvements – Australia will fail to meet its housing targets if skills shortages and regulatory barriers are not addressed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d7e9e79afa4c3af009f7860839a94a7</guid></item><item><title>A survivor of the digital wave and Parramatta's growth, independent record store celebrates 30 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/record-store-survives-digital-wave-parramatta/105858366</link><description>Tucked away at the end of an old arcade strip, a local record store has survived three decades of change, from new technology to the construction of Sydney's second CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3efe2384ece38df777b60f547c8c1ef3</guid></item><item><title>AUKUS architect says concerns remain over deal's future despite Donald Trump backing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/concern-remain-over-aukus-following-trump-talk/105918678</link><description>The federal government is celebrating the US president's emphatic backing of AUKUS, saying his statements should kill off speculation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e736a086b67eaa4ae6d147fcebd937ae</guid></item><item><title>Louvre robbery not the first to resemble a heist film this century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/21st-century-museum-jewellery-heists/105912910</link><description>The theft of several royal treasures at the Louvre on Monday was not the first museum jewellery heist this century to resemble a Hollywood movie. Here's a look back at two infamous capers to steal near-priceless jewels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4aae7b4100afa1e9f89ce3ae274b7769</guid></item><item><title>Access to road accident compensation for Indigenous Australians is falling short, study says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/aboriginal-road-accident-compensation-not-culturally-safe/105623090</link><description>A first-of-its-kind South Australian study finds access to compensation after a road accident is not good enough for First Nations people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b20a533ad3d4b785cf66857e4cdc1f1</guid></item><item><title>Mark Nawaqanitawase becomes dual international as Kangaroos name Ashes Test squad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/australia-kangaroos-mark-nawaqanitawase-test-squad-england/105919382</link><description>Ex-Wallabies winger Mark Nawaqanitawase and Reece Walsh are among four players named to make their debuts for Australia in the opening Ashes rugby league Test against England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6302b6977720dd7f2cf7bd410e47b9b4</guid></item><item><title>Unsuccessful independent's $2m election campaign spend highest in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/election-donations-spending-independent-caz-heise-kate-hook/105915020</link><description>An MP says new donation caps on political groups such as Climate 200 mean the days of independents spending up to $2 million on election campaigns are "gone".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2cbdb737b05690e8d69a5fb7d110db9</guid></item><item><title>Official list of Sydney's cleanest and most polluted beaches in annual Beachwatch report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/beachwatch-report-reveals-sydneys-cleanest-beaches/105917024</link><description>As Sydney prepares to swelter, the city's beaches have been graded — and two local government areas dominate the list for cleanliness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ee8e09b0203472431ccc2b014072bd6</guid></item><item><title>AI chatbots could be accelerating the loneliness epidemic, according to new research</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/ai-relationship-study/105917858</link><description>Some Australians would rather stay home and talk to an AI bot than go out with friends, according to a YouGov survey.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6724fbbc008de5cc21b29984b2e4ba9</guid></item><item><title>Millions of red crabs begin annual migration on Christmas Island as numbers 'skyrocket'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/red-crab-migration-begins-on-christmas-island/105916362</link><description>Christmas Island residents are once again sharing their home with millions of red crabs as they make their way to the ocean, with their numbers having "skyrocketed" in recent years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">591d45e4bd26fc4130dbc7f379ddb373</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Island crabs begin migration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/millions-of-red-crabs-begin-christmas-island-migration/105917986</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31fcb844cdbb945f75cfbd8b2bd06f80</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: PM's plane resumes journey home after medical emergency — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/federal-politics-live-blog-oct-22/105918300</link><description>The prime minister's plane has resumed its journey back to Australia after it was diverted to the US city of St Louis because of a medical emergency involving an RAAF officer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">678ac8326105ed530e869c114b33a06f</guid></item><item><title>Prime minister defends Ambassador Rudd's position after Trump remarks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/prime-minister-defends-ambassador-rudd-s-position/105919356</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24b4103041f8bb3b9a51c0694b6c242d</guid></item><item><title>How Boomers deal with big paydays and LeBron's possible last season among five things to watch as NBA returns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/basketball-nba-giddey-daniels-okc-lebron-retirement-celtics/105917312</link><description>Two young Aussies have gotten paid, teams continue to plot to take down the Thunder and LeBron's future continues to be a talking point. Here are five things to keep an eye on as the NBA season gets underway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">537b57e06fa2717b605865a47165ca98</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's fluoride fear to leave lasting impact on dental health for generations to come</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/queensland-fluoride-in-water-being-removed/105917056</link><description>Many people would say the benefits of fluoride in water are clear but in this state it's often not there and there will be lasting health impacts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">519535b23202071833d69a241b79cd11</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs women face long waits for IUD birth control</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/nt-alice-springs-iud-pain-birth-control-barriers-health/105915114</link><description>IUDs can be inserted by GPs, gynaecologists and family planning doctors, but in Alice Springs there aren't enough local professionals trained to do so.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36f7e6011b4e7c39ca15221bdd1458e2</guid></item><item><title>Australian 'admiral' peddling disaster donation relief scheme exposed as 'fake'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/fake-admiral-exposed-peddling-disaster-relief-scheme-25-years/105890312</link><description>A NSW man has claimed to be an admiral for 25 years while peddling a disaster relief scheme, but he has never served in the navy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62c0b4d61ed8bc81b1a61e114692eeaa</guid></item><item><title>ASX falls from record high as gold and silver prices plunge — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/asx-markets-business-live-news/105919498</link><description>The Australian share market falls after the spot price of gold and silver experienced their worst single day in years, all while solid corporate earnings on Wall Street drove the Dow Jones index to its highest level ever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf2bef342809bcafb960079a517fad5b</guid></item><item><title>Trump and Putin's Budapest summit on hold after rejection of immediate Ukraine ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/trump-putin-ukraine-war-budapest-summit-on-hold/105919394</link><description>President Donald Trump's plan for a swift meeting with Russian leader Vladimir Putin is on hold in the latest twist in his stop-and-go effort to resolve the war in Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39faceebcf9c6415f920b4cd79701d14</guid></item><item><title>Critics question how $13 billion US–Australia critical minerals deal will benefit WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/what-us-australia-critical-minerals-deal-means-for-wa/105917058</link><description>Western Australia's slice of the critical minerals deal is being heralded as a huge win, but critics are asking how much US aluminium giant Alcoa's boon will benefit Western Australians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d90983fb0f88dbee5bbbe13b312db584</guid></item><item><title>Pilbara communities disconnected from culture, health services due to road damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/remote-aboriginal-communities-isolated-by-road-damage-pilbara/105877672</link><description>Indigenous elders and advocates fear worsening roads in the Pilbara, which are littered with the rusted skeletons of abandoned cars, are isolating remote residents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">786999b61ea8130c215920754d41f52d</guid></item><item><title>After learning to walk and talk again, Laura is walking 50km in October to raise money for the RFDS</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/seatbelt-warning-wa-road-crash-rfds-fundraiser/105915366</link><description>After surviving a car crash and a stroke, Laura McKenney was told she may never walk again. Now, she's trekking 50-kilometres to raise money for the service that saved her life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61447439023bae1f51729f2a394f2067</guid></item><item><title>Acting electoral commissioner labels WA council elections successful despite concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/acting-electoral-commissioner-discusses-wa-council-elections/105915918</link><description>The acting head of WA's Electoral Commission is lauding the recent local council poll as a success, despite reports of missing ballot papers and low voter turnout.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce6f55bcaf5403e43b53955128c85371</guid></item><item><title>Expert tips for used-car buyers to spot 'widespread' odometer tampering</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/tips-to-protect-used-car-buyers-from-widespread-odometer-fraud/105911276</link><description>Odometer fraud is "widespread" in the second-hand car industry, but experts say there are warning signs to look for when buying a used car.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c86e77f5f698004a03a397fb0794f07a</guid></item><item><title>Australian flower growers want shoppers to know where their blooms originate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/tasmanian-flower-growers-call-for-country-of-origin-labelling/105901208</link><description>About half of Australia's cut flowers are imported, but there is no requirement to add a label informing consumers of their origin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b13c4c6f8d6bbc45bb31fd9df948937</guid></item><item><title>Donald rare earth mine given major project status by Australian government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/donald-mineral-sands-mine-given-major-project-status/105917530</link><description>The federal government grants major project status to a joint Australian-US mine in regional Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">764adf75e9997cd64369c8f4b49126c1</guid></item><item><title>Inquest probes death in custody of Phillip Walton at Casino Police Station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/phillip-walton-casino-death-in-custody-coronial-inquiry/105915614</link><description>A senior police officer defends the actions of officers during the violent arrest of a man who later died in custody at Casino Police Station in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">497deedb8899b75e15642838af05b82f</guid></item><item><title>Blind baby wombat Gundy adapts to new home at wildlife sanctuary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/wildlife-carers-help-blind-baby-wombat-adapt-to-a-new-home/105903660</link><description>Gundy the wombat suffered vision loss after his mother was killed by a car while he was in her pouch. Wildlife carers are finding creative ways to give him a new chance at life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30aff38c624cd2a105c8aefca99a7d19</guid></item><item><title>Regional cultural icon Anita's Theatre celebrates 100 years of entertainment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/anita-theatre-in-wollongong-celebrates-100-years/105894492</link><description>After starting life as a movie theatre and later a roller-skating rink, it was the bold vision of a Wollongong property developer that turned the 100-year-old Anita's Theatre in Thirroul into a cultural icon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cba77c18d64e232ecd33457ee613fe8</guid></item><item><title>North Korea fires ballistic missiles a week before leaders meet in South Korea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/south-korea-says-north-korea-fired-ballistic-missile/105920146</link><description>The launch comes days before South Korea hosts APEC and world leaders including the US and Chinese presidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8ce7ab7454d4ca827e18384001477c6</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley backtracks on call for Kevin Rudd to be sacked as US ambassador</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/sussan-ley-walks-back-kevin-rudd-ambassador-sacked/105920516</link><description>After a Liberal colleague calls Sussan Ley's claim that Kevin Rudd cannot remain US ambassador "churlish", the opposition leader walks back from her call.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a29d28518177d0ad8987efade870b0fa</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Island's red crab migration underway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/christmas-island-red-crab-migration-underway/105920342</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b4573733fb09a3d65277a164ebdb94b</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after running over dog, crashing caravan with children inside</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/man-charged-allegedly-stealing-caravan-children-inside/105919982</link><description>A 59-year-old man is taken to hospital under police guard after crashing an allegedly stolen caravan. A family's dog was run over during the incident in the Gold Coast hinterland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f8532a5458eeb18dc12fa15b0a33e03</guid></item><item><title>Rock climbers' celebrations crushed as government confirms Grampians, Arapiles bans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/rock-climbing-bans-remain-arapiles-grampians-despite-speculation/105915428</link><description>The Victorian government clarifies rock climbing bans remain in place in the Grampians and other sites after a message spread online that the bans "were off".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">076cda4bef57d812542ec60186d391d5</guid></item><item><title>Red crabs make their annual march on Christmas Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/red-crabs-make-their-annual-march-on-christmas-island/105920982</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e280c0b4f77bb665c61957afb63ff865</guid></item><item><title>Man charged in Melbourne after police seize dozens of Labubu dolls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/man-arrested-alleged-stolen-labubu-dolls-in-melbourne/105920204</link><description>Police seize Labubu dolls found during a search at a property in Melbourne's west. The dolls, worth an estimated $9,000, were allegedly stolen from a CBD shopping centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6a9be9d1dcf86b3e4860408535870b5</guid></item><item><title>Red crabs make their annual march on Christmas Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/red-crabs-make-their-annual-march-on-christmas-island/105921010</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">488fcc4e29eb8888bda1fb017efd95de</guid></item><item><title>China accuses Australia of twisted 'propaganda' over Paracel Islands airspace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/china-accuses-australia-of-propaganda-airspace-intrusion/105920712</link><description>Beijing ramps up criticisms of Australia over a tense military encounter over the South China Sea on Sunday, accusing the Australian Defence Force of distributing "twisted and absurd propaganda" and "provoking" China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f41ba76368fbb1976ad5472d4a6845e</guid></item><item><title>Mysterious military shipwreck appears on Target Beach in Jervis Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/shipwreck-appears-on-jervis-bay-beach/105920008</link><description>Remnants of a shipwreck in Jervis Bay have maritime archaeologists puzzled and wondering what else could be nearby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdacdbc973b4fbefde59c8b5eb42afbe</guid></item><item><title>Lidia Thorpe refers NT attorney-general to corruption watchdog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/senator-lidia-thorpe-refers-nt-attorney-general-to-icac/105917560</link><description>Senator Lidia Thorpe refers Northern Territory's attorney-general to the corruption watchdog after allegations of government interference in the NT Supreme Court's media activities that were later deemed "a misunderstanding".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d8d75816f1da3913d38e857502c284c</guid></item><item><title>'Climate trigger' formally ruled out of environment laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/climate-trigger-formally-ruled-out-of-environment-laws/105919546</link><description>A "climate trigger" that could be used to block coal and gas projects has been formally excluded from the government's overhaul of Australia's environment laws, minister Murray Watt confirms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c1a2a6fff2c15f94e5a6155f42263f4</guid></item><item><title>Chris Scott says Geelong's recruitment of Bailey Smith is an 'outrageous success'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/afl-chris-scott-bailey-smith-success-state-of-origin-injuries/105921548</link><description>Geelong and Victoria coach Chris Scott gets on the offensive about his star midfielder Bailey Smith while urging fans and pundits not to over-react when State of Origin returns next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97880ee57a333d67f13dad4b5fc36756</guid></item><item><title>Rex Airlines creditors seek answers as sale to US company Air T moves closer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/regional-express-airlines-takeover-creditors-owed-millions/105914690</link><description>Creditors owed millions of dollars remain in the dark despite a new owner being found for the embattled airline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f36fd85e61d0d0af03b171b5e7fbae8</guid></item><item><title>Telstra testing reveals some Samsung mobile phones unable to make triple-0 calls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/samsung-mobile-devices-triple-0-telstra-network/105920816</link><description>Some Samsung mobile phone users may be unable to call triple-0 in an emergency after Telstra announced testing had revealed more than 70 models were not connecting correctly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b180dfd30e319001175e3dfcd4ea0b84</guid></item><item><title>Donald Day Jr, US conspiracy theorist connected to Wieambilla killers, formally enters plea deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/qld-donald-day-premier-reacts-to-plea-deal/105921610</link><description>Queensland Premier David Crisafulli says the crime "rocked the state", and the news would "hurt" the families of those murdered at Wieambilla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d40c4064b9808b8f8f732625637eee7</guid></item><item><title>Two dead as severe weather across Victoria downs trees, cuts power and postpones Geelong Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/severe-weather-sweeps-victoria-wreaking-havoc/105921826</link><description>Two men have died in rough waters at Frankston as part of the state recorded wind gusts up to 130 kilometres per hour during a severe weather system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fa4c5cf099aa95ead69a7a5ae2d35d6</guid></item><item><title>I moved from Brisbane to the outback at 18 to work on sheep stations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/moving-from-brisbane-to-outback-for-work-art-cooper/105897704</link><description>Art Cooper was almost a year into a panel-beating apprenticeship in Brisbane when he realised it wasn't the career for him, so he packed his belongings and drove 1,300 kilometres to the outback to work as a rouseabout on sheep stations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c8030fef45a6e51f108e10eb0fb223f</guid></item><item><title>South Australian MP Nick McBride charged with further counts of assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/nick-mcbride-further-charges-assault-south-australia/105919754</link><description>Member for MacKillop Nick McBride is facing another three counts of assault dating back to January and September of 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b7d41eef605976bf06febf0e7d78d03</guid></item><item><title>Investigation into Townsville Hospital urology care finds more impacted patients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/urology-healthcare-investigation-townsville/105920928</link><description>Tim Nicholls says an investigation, launched in September, identified that 11 patients were adversely affected, but that number had since more than doubled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b36eab5bf095a5b19b4c9f980b2bea45</guid></item><item><title>Our homes are full of hidden microplastics that could be harming our health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/hidden-microplastics-at-home-and-impact-on-health/105917972</link><description>Microplastics are everywhere, including our bodies and brains, and the exposure risk may be highest within our own homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18690c64251c79c309a9913425622790</guid></item><item><title>NT politicians call for inquiry into Australia's de facto online gambling regulator</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/nt-parliament-requests-online-gambling-regulator-inquiry/105921322</link><description>More than 40 of Australia's corporate bookmakers are based in the Northern Territory for its low taxes and what critics describe as weak regulation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3b7377d7f8cdec5a4d99f5052c0097c</guid></item><item><title>Canberra boy's parents detail impact of former childcare worker Muhammad Ali's sexual abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/canberra-childcare-worker-to-be-sentenced-for-child-sexual-abuse/105920350</link><description>Former childcare worker Muhammad Ali, 31, will be sentenced for the 2022 abuse of the boy on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5412d425d889c27b72cffc65c295e44f</guid></item><item><title>Tonga rugby league team meets with king ahead of Test match against Samoa in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/tonga-rugby-league-team-meet-with-king-ahead-of-test-match/105922598</link><description>Lunch with the king of Tonga and quality time spent with his subjects have Jason Taumalolo primed to deliver a blockbusting display against Samoa.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21063f91b8d11d8f74f0efc9bbbab8a1</guid></item><item><title>OpenAI launches Atlas web browser to compete with Google's Chrome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/openai-launches-atlas-web-browser-to-compete-with-google/105922212</link><description>The owner of ChatGPT, OpenAI, launches its own web browser, Atlas, as more people rely on artificial intelligence to answer questions on the internet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">035912db61d38708493abbbf17238c35</guid></item><item><title>Op shop purchase of The Hobbit could be worth tens of thousands if verified as first edition Tolkien</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/tasmanian-woman-op-shop-selling-jrr-tolkien-the-hobbit/105921072</link><description>A woman who bought a copy of The Hobbit from an op shop in the 1990s says even then she suspected it could be worth a considerable amount — experts now say she could be sitting on a first edition copy, worth tens of thousands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2919bb95ee3eac24182e5b967591143</guid></item><item><title>Australian official to join Trump-led Gaza peace taskforce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/australian-official-to-join-trump-gaza-peace-taskforce/105922746</link><description>The official will participate in planning and coordination efforts related to humanitarian and security challenges in implementing the ceasefire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bf7e27f33fc38ba0ad4ea10301b45a7</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105921882</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e6279cd8f29139973fe425cd355b58b</guid></item><item><title>Mate Stipinovich, Aristides Avlontis, Karl Whitburn jailed for bungled Albany drug smuggling attempt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/drug-smugglers-who-clung-to-esky-off-albany-sentenced/105920248</link><description>Three men forced to cling to an esky to survive in wild seas off Albany as they tried to import hundreds of kilograms of cocaine into Western Australia are described by a judge as "Keystone criminals" at their sentencing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3a907b92905039815d6a864be91a54d</guid></item><item><title>How worried should we be about microplastics in our homes?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/how-worried-should-we-be-about-microplastics-in-our-homes/105923098</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44869c3e630bb673ba45455441770045</guid></item><item><title>What the critical minerals deal means for Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/what-the-critical-minerals-deal-means-for-australia/105923100</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d668b79151e7614c59596991073b90bd</guid></item><item><title>Inquest into deaths of Stanley Obi and Sarah Mudge hears of events during hours before fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/qld-stanley-obi-sarah-mudge-coronial-inquest-logan/105922700</link><description>The mother of a woman who allegedly broke into her former partner’s home and set it alight, before dying in the fire herself, gives evidence at a coronial inquest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c59e1ec53c121be68ac61ea36b5eee8d</guid></item><item><title>Australia continues dominance against England as Sutherland and Gardner put on monster stand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/live-australia-vs-england-women-s-cricket-world-cup-scores-stats/105922176</link><description>Australia is rescued by an incredible stand between Ash Gardner and Annabel Sutherland at the Women's World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">477d5c29ed6fe1e24fd3e3e1d66f84e9</guid></item><item><title>Supreme Court in Brisbane reserves decision on Queensland's puberty blocker freeze after legal challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/queensland-court-reserves-decision-on-puberty-blocker-ban/105923126</link><description>The mother of a trans teenager launched legal action over the state's freeze on puberty blockers earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b89c70a0198a1a471131e89eeb91c10</guid></item><item><title>Delegates discussed 'getting rid' of land council boss during men's meeting, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/jacinta-nampijinpa-price-defamation-case-land-council-meeting/105919748</link><description>A defamation trial over a press release issued by Northern Territory senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price has been derailed by an "unusual and significant" application to have a man barred from the court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af47f07fb7cd4f7ceb6c102d71240f4a</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds dominate Silver Ferns to take 2-0 lead in Constellation Cup series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/diamonds-vs-silver-ferns-second-test-constellation-cup/105922576</link><description>Australia is one win away from regaining the Constellation Cup after dominating New Zealand in the second netball Test match in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be7d38a2f2feab1621ca6ea454baa5cd</guid></item><item><title>AC Milan Serie A game will be played in Perth despite backlash, deputy premier says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/ac-milan-serie-a-perth-game-update/105922940</link><description>The state government is doubling down on its plan to bring European football heavyweights AC Milan to Perth to play a historic Italian league game, despite significant backlash from fans and players.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4af059711217c189b72dab3189cc3a7b</guid></item><item><title>Serbian president labels shooting and fire outside parliament building a 'terrorist act'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/serbian-shots-fired-and-fire-ignited-outside-belgrade-parliament/105923266</link><description>One person has been detained and at least one person injured after a shooting and a fire broke out outside of Serbia's parliament in Belgrade, in an incident that President Aleksandar Vučić has called a terrorist act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e409138657ffa02353bf062ea77546c</guid></item><item><title>Sir Keir Starmer backs calls for parliamentary inquiry into Prince Andrew's Royal Lodge lease deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/keir-starmer-backs-parliamentary-probe-prince-andrew-royal-lodge/105923348</link><description>Sir Keir Starmer has told British parliament he supports scrutiny of Crown property deals but getting Prince Andrew to answer questions at Westminster might not be easy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2157fd907bc4a8a06bba7a60909993b2</guid></item><item><title>Trump seems relaxed about Taiwan and analysts are concerned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/donald-trump-anthony-albanese-china-taiwan/105919780</link><description>There was something Donald Trump said that alarmed strategic analysts. And it had nothing to do with disliking Kevin Rudd.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b09727993adc1f99b586851208f3b20d</guid></item><item><title>Luna Park machete brawl accused free on bail after alleged St Kilda attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/vic-st-kilda-luna-park-machete-brawl-accused-free-on-bail/105920760</link><description>Three men charged over a machete brawl outside Melbourne's Luna Park have been freed on bail, despite police urging magistrates to keep the trio locked up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">597d4cc833e7c6a2a0ff34753fc30d43</guid></item><item><title>The move to break China's iron grip on world's supply of critical minerals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/australia-us-join-china-in-race-to-bottom-on-rare-earth-prices/105921278</link><description>America dominates the global financial system. The Middle East controls energy. And China, during the past 40 years, has created a vice-like grip on the mining, refining and production of global metals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d4352ba09b87fc1dd1206a1a824d91a</guid></item><item><title>As Europe proposes a ban on all PFAS, some researchers say Australia should do the same</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/calls-to-ban-entire-pfas-class-in-australia/105787430</link><description>As the European Union proposes a ban on the entire PFAS chemical class, some researchers say Australia should do the same.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e04ed432a807d5c6fca30c5667ca447</guid></item><item><title>Where Matildas coach Joe Montemurro wants to take the team and women's football</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/matildas-coach-joe-montemurro-vision-australian-womens-football/105912590</link><description>Matildas coach Joe Montemurro has no shortage of ideas or passion for how to reshape women's football in Australia, and it's a contrast from his predecessor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd1cec1f5763be070ccdf86a5517ae73</guid></item><item><title>Keeping Tasmania's radar network operating a labour of love for BOM's Brendan Hanigan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/tasmania-bom-weather-radar-network-brendan-hanigan/105912464</link><description>Songs about radars strike a chord — personally and professionally — with Brendan Hanigan. He is tasked with leading the team that keeps Tasmania's weather radars in good working order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc082d84e0df7fa8df3fce80488937ec</guid></item><item><title>IOC says sports events should not be hosted in Indonesia after Israeli gymnasts banned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/ioc-no-sporting-events-in-indonesia-after-israeli-athletes-ban/105923342</link><description>The world's most populous Muslim nation refused to issue visas to Israeli athletes last week because of the war in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6201f64c96b553f20c28595377f8cadd</guid></item><item><title>Seafood has undeserved reputation as source of microplastic exposure, scientists say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/seafood-unfair-microplastics-reputation-puts-off-consumers/105912838</link><description>There are microplastics in almost everything, so why does seafood get such a bad reputation? Scientists say it is down to disproportionate research and media attention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8567870a03b1df65e2a20ba21bc314a2</guid></item><item><title>'Localised extinction' risk for seagrass in Botany Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/localised-extinction-risk-for-seagrass-in-gamay-botany-bay/105903236</link><description>It is estimated half of the local seagrass habitat in Gamay (Botany Bay) has already been lost. Researchers and Aboriginal rangers are replanting seagrass fragments and using biochar to restore the area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecdd76f0fa0000dab7a916d234e1a86e</guid></item><item><title>Amid a small investor rush on precious metals, have the gold and silver bubbles popped?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/gold-price-silver-price-fall-after-record-runs/105919932</link><description>Precious metal prices have been pushing record highs and, as queues lengthened outside bullion traders, gold and silver prices suddenly fell back. But positive signs remain, analysts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85df381e3c773d3666ff2d41e431258c</guid></item><item><title>Why mpox cases in Australia in 2025 are a fraction of what they were last year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/nsw-mpox-cases-australia-2025-scientists/105842962</link><description>Mpox transmission surged between July to September last year, but there have been far fewer cases recorded in 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88dbfb4e2d3e282dfa8c1c7b16bf4dc2</guid></item><item><title>After 37 years, mystery still surrounds the death of Mark Haines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/mark-haines-death-still-surrounded-by-mystery/105902802</link><description>Some key questions about the death of Indigenous teenager Mark Haines are still unanswered after a coronial inquest spanning five weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">baad175ed7981a98ee6ddb26820019e5</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri confident in F1 championship battle against Lando Norris and Max Verstappen in Mexico</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/oscar-piastri-f1-championship-max-verstappen-lando-norris-mexico/105917790</link><description>This year may be the first time in F1 that Oscar Piastri has been under the cosh of a title fight, but it is not the first time he has been in a three-way fight for a championship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ebaf21cbbf4bb580ca4d8a0c8c713f3</guid></item><item><title>ICJ rules Israel must allow aid groups unimpeded access to Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/icj-rules-israel-must-allow-aid-groups-unimpeded-access-to-gaza/105923408</link><description>The International Court of Justice rules Israel must allow aid groups access to Gaza and that the nation's attempts to stop a UN agency delivering aid to Palestinians are illegal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8a95ec13ab473ea403107a4b00db52d</guid></item><item><title>South-east Queensland bracing for 'exceptional' temperatures amid record-breaking heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/south-east-queensland-braces-for-record-breaking-temperatures/105921596</link><description>The mercury in parts of the state's south-east is today forecast to reach the mid to high-30s as a heatwave sweeps through.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0215d16f78b2c650b5e0c1e5fb3ed9f</guid></item><item><title>Russian youths gather to sing defiant anti-war song in St Petersburg</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/russian-youths-gather-to-sing-defiant-anti-war-song/105923400</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">322563990afb8887a9b864960da14833</guid></item><item><title>Russia jails teen musicians for viral anti-Kremlin song performance amid censorship crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/russia-jails-musicians-banned-anti-kremlin-song-viral/105919236</link><description>An ongoing censorship crackdown in Russia sees a teenage band jailed after a performance of an anti-Kremlin song went viral, but the protest keeps growing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78c1b9719c8d25ebaf254bbe05a71cd1</guid></item><item><title>Brazen crime and protest clashes have made Melbourne's CBD less safe, traders say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/brazen-crime-heated-protests-make-city-unsafe-traders-say/105913296</link><description>Business owners say recent incidents — including a random daylight stabbing and clashes between protesters and police — are deterring customers from the heart of the Victorian capital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdea6b2a0483f121ef68654757cb9b9e</guid></item><item><title>How a climate adaptation 'shortfall' is being felt in northern Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/northern-australia-struggles-to-adapt-to-climate-change/105841310</link><description>Shaded and green spaces can be hard to find in northern towns and cities where summer temperatures regularly surpass 40 degrees Celsius.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7d3002a3bc79b18ecd9a182e49c7a99</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Nationals senator says 'malicious intent' behind Barnaby Joyce One Nation push — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/federal-politics-live-blog-oct-23/105922588</link><description>Bridget McKenzie says she thinks Barnaby Joyce will remain in the Nationals party room after he left the door open to joining One Nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03ec27d633693a56dfa20212175845cb</guid></item><item><title>Designer Amy Lawrance's new collection Total Recall is a mix of medieval and sci-fi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/amy-lawrance-fashion-designer-total-recall/105905406</link><description>Award-winning fashion designer Amy Lawrance blends 90s sci-fi with the medieval in her new collection, Total Recall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea78787d197aa80e9e98691d3fe5a513</guid></item><item><title>Majority of NT prison rehabilitation programs are being cancelled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/custodial-rehab-programs-plummet-as-prison-population-soars/105923286</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f49984af578b9bc3bfe5695f17441c1</guid></item><item><title>Masses of NT prison rehabilitation sessions cancelled as prisoner numbers surge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/majority-of-nt-prison-rehab-programs-cancelled-overcrowding/105916564</link><description>As the Northern Territory prison population continues to reach all-time highs, data reveals a majority of the NT's rehab program are being cancelled more often than they are being delivered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70fee00a47f2a73f47e0da6b21b749c7</guid></item><item><title>Claims foster care payments have been cut spark concern for kids with complex needs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/foster-care-payments-claims-of-cuts/105915512</link><description>Foster carers in Victoria say sudden allowance reductions for children with complex needs have left them feeling "undervalued and confused".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">290f7f0f209c4f37ad30fb2ca338f5ad</guid></item><item><title>South Energy plans 100-megawatt battery project for Victoria's Macedon Ranges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/macedon-battery-site-proposal-south-energy-in-fire-zone/105920150</link><description>A proposed energy storage facility in Macedon could power thousands of homes — but not everyone is convinced it is being built in the right place.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57367107a833ee15f4bd22b1939535df</guid></item><item><title>'Daughter's promise' inspires Darkinyung dictionary to revive sleepy language</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/daughters-promise-inspires-darkinyung-dictionary-revive-language/105536842</link><description>With the help of a linguist and her community, Aunty Bronwyn Chambers has revitalised a sleepy language.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a24bd8d4af7b8738937f7d3ae67a569</guid></item><item><title>Two senior executives leave Optus, ASX finishes flat — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/asx-markets-business-live-news-october-23/105923594</link><description>Two senior Optus executives are leaving the telco as it continues to face scrutiny of a major triple-0 outage that may have claimed lives. The ASX finishes flat as BHP sidesteps questions on its China iron ore negotiations. Look back at how the day's business and market action unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2530ca05e1299381761e381a423c84e</guid></item><item><title>Parts of NSW and Victoria 'absolutely battered' by howling winds, storm damage in Greater Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/damaging-winds-damage-sydney-and-nsw-amid-wild-weather/105923502</link><description>Howling winds overnight will lead to extensive clean-up work today in NSW's south-east and parts of Victoria, with October heat records also broken in Western Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">736a6689acf417333720c384ceaa765a</guid></item><item><title>Mount Stirling Resort financial deficit prompts review of winter operations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/mount-stirling-winter-operations-under-review-financial-deficit/105921394</link><description>The managing body of Victoria's six alpine resorts says it is reviewing winter operations at its Mount Stirling resort, which has been "operating at a financial deficit" for some time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">defbb82f65c793e59b689c95ccbcb355</guid></item><item><title>KAPCO deal with NT abattoir to supply communities with affordable Kimberley beef</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/kapco-branded-beef-for-sale-in-kimberley-communities/105890452</link><description>A cattle company in Western Australia's Kimberley has struck a deal with a Northern Territory abattoir to get local beef to consumers in remote communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25fe008938e380014edc09ae37eac45c</guid></item><item><title>Waroona weighs up planned gallium refinery funded by US-Australia critical minerals deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/waroona-weighs-up-gallium-refinery-from-critical-minerals-deal/105923056</link><description>Locals in the WA community of Waroona are welcoming a US-Australia deal set to build a new rare earth refinery south of Perth, but others warn the project will further entrench mining interests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a68b7d21b8bbd286c5a1420e728a78b4</guid></item><item><title>Australia's first fluorite mine faces 'deep opposition' from Kimberley traditional owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/tivan-speewah-fluorite-project-opposited-by-traditional-owners/105920700</link><description>Traditional owners have raised cultural and environmental concerns about a proposed fluorite mine in Western Australia's remote Kimberley region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efdb89f0ff517cf2828ffb7c1c2afd25</guid></item><item><title>Forced adoption redress scheme to offer compensation for impacted Tasmanians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/tasmania-forced-adoptions-redress-scheme/105923474</link><description>More than 13 years after the Tasmanian state government delivered an apology to mothers impacted by the historical practice of forced adoptions, a redress scheme will offer compensation to those affected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9e233d73a03968984e5e44b24557626</guid></item><item><title>Louvre chief blames CCTV gaps for $150m jewellery heist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/louvre-director-acknowledges-failure-after-jewellery-heist/105923584</link><description>The Louvre chief says she repeatedly raised concerns about CCTV coverage at the museum, only for her fears to come "horribly true".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99315f3e0a3e5504191af2333fe36547</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's hobby gold-diggers under threat from law giving veto power to miners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/law-change-locks-queensland-gold-fossickers-out-of-state-land/105917922</link><description>Gold prospectors are being locked out of some fossicking areas by a new law that allows mining companies with pending leases to say no.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85a7b5aaba311b4d1d00b68e1673a4ee</guid></item><item><title>More Australian-grown coffee to become available as industry grows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/australian-coffee-industry-grows-as-new-varieties-available/105921496</link><description>The Australian coffee industry is growing as new varieties become available and local demand increases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6c87086f9f3d9ec9979146c33619d97</guid></item><item><title>Frankston drowning victims were inexperienced surfer and friend who tried to rescue him, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/frankston-drowning-victims-yet-to-be-identifed/105923626</link><description>Police say two men who drowned on Wednesday were a British national who was surfing in extreme conditions and his friend who came to his aid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec3497c2ab41d5c6cb203ecb66c9ece6</guid></item><item><title>Alexander Isak injured as Liverpool ends four-match losing streak with Champions League win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/champions-league-wrap-liverpool-ends-drought-chelsea-madrid/105923734</link><description>Liverpool wins for the first time in five matches, but comes out of the match with more issues as two off-season recruits fail to finish the match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7897c8eef4af750de153f4ce035a63eb</guid></item><item><title>Swimming Australia takes on Meta over fake quotes attributed to Kyle Chalmers, Mollie O'Callaghan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/swimming-australia-meta-fake-quotes-kyle-chalmers-mollie-quotes/105923830</link><description>Two weeks after after Mollie O'Callaghan was targeted, Swimming Australia has asked Meta to take down fake quotes attributed to Kyle Chalmers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f795af90cb0d05de25f7772525d9a63</guid></item><item><title>Criticism over rodenticide review delays as study finds poison in northern quolls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/apvma-delays-rodenticide-review-despite-quoll-concern/105891008</link><description>Rat bait poison has been found in threatened northern quoll populations as an overdue report into their use by the federal pesticides regulator is again delayed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49bba0b00d15e090d19a9695528b4cb4</guid></item><item><title>Mapping rare earth supplies and the challenges of turning these minerals into magnets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/rare-earths-reserves-global-critical-minerals-australia-china-us/105913262</link><description>Unlike the name suggests, rare earths are not very rare at all. The critical minerals are found in abundance in many countries, but being big on reserves may not mean big business.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ddfebc841ee6318f2335037eafb611f</guid></item><item><title>Australia wins double bronze at UCI Track World Championships, team pursuit men to race for gold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/australia-sprint-teams-win-bronze-uci-track-world-championships/105924084</link><description>Australia's two team pursuit squads both claimed bronze medals on day one of the UCI Track World Championships in Santiago, while the Olympic champion team pursuit squad will race for gold on day two.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f6ca636ffd63dedbb1d1698a6d45066</guid></item><item><title>US hits Russia's biggest oil firms with sanctions over Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/us-announces-sanctions-against-russias-two-biggest-oil-firms/105923888</link><description>The White House makes a sharp move to pressure Moscow to secure peace in Ukraine just one day after a summit between US President Donald Trump and Russian President Vladimir Putin falls apart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5148d7b66a9ed5008e197f1624fa3d7</guid></item><item><title>Vladimir Kramnik facing investigation over attacks on Daniel Naroditsky before his death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/chess-vladimir-kramnik-daniel-naroditsky-death-investigation/105924414</link><description>The International Chess Federation says it will examine Vladimir Kramnik's public attacks on Daniel Naroditsky, the American grandmaster who died at the age of 29 this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c38fbe13fed22a611c24f830a2990e3</guid></item><item><title>Funky animal hairdos and a smoking duck among 2025 Comedy Wildlife Photo Awards finalists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/comedy-wildlife-photo-awards-2025-finalists/105924038</link><description>The 40 shortlisted images pair talented nature photography with humour that often relies on capturing a moment at just the right time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cf991d1c5656f5992afd5e37bae6bf3</guid></item><item><title>State of Origin battleground experience a bonus for Kangaroos against England in Ashes trilogy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/state-of-origin-a-bonus-for-kangaroos-against-england/105924964</link><description>The Ashes clash with England is a three-Test contest and Origin rivals Nathan Cleary and Harry Grant believe experience in the state head-to-head could be telling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a024e0af020d527eca0fb362a4822126</guid></item><item><title>Two teenage boys stabbed, one with a screwdriver, during alleged daylight brawl in Broadmeadows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/broadmeadows-station-brawl-screwdriver-machete-stabbings/105925064</link><description>Two teenage boys were hospitalised with stab wounds after an alleged brawl between two groups armed with a screwdriver and possibly a machete at a train station in Broadmeadows on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b3aae3e8bb739a159250f2870888544</guid></item><item><title>Queensland coach Johan Botha baffles Cricketers' Association with stance on injured players being paid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/cricket-johan-botha-injured-players-payment-aca-response/105925350</link><description>Australian Cricketers' Association boss Paul Marsh will seek clarification from Queensland coach Johan Botha over his comments regarding player payments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b24fae5c54211515b378c57e9505f03</guid></item><item><title>Cheryl Grimmer confession read in NSW Parliament under privilege</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/cheryl-grimmer-confession-read-in-nsw-parliament/105923732</link><description>A NSW MP invokes parliamentary privilege to name the man who confessed as a teenager to killing three-year-old Cheryl Grimmer, and reads aloud a long-suppressed confession.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4b215bc52fbac35c6b9f6914216c032</guid></item><item><title>Jack Bowd pleads not guilty to Newell Highway crash that killed four people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/newell-highway-fatal-crash-driver-jack-bowd-pleads-not-guilty/105842498</link><description>A 23-year-old pleads not guilty to dangerous driving and drink driving charges after a crash that claimed the lives of two friends and a husband and wife last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4df2a7a2674f7ead4af00da2819e1709</guid></item><item><title>Coles to appear at Kumanjayi White coronial inquest after Alice Springs death in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/nt-kumanjayi-white-coronial-update-family-speaks-outside-court/105923958</link><description>Supermarket giant Coles is among the parties expected to take part in a coronial inquest into the death in custody of a young Aboriginal man inside its Alice Springs shop earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57cae39432a2f9acece58217a2dd16a8</guid></item><item><title>Australia's institutions are what make us freaking amazing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/justin-wolfers-boyer-lecture-australia-democracy/105922196</link><description>The world changes, yet Australia keeps being great. Our institutions permit us to be nimble, and we adapt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dffb7d7a76e996bb90c250cc8fedf101</guid></item><item><title>Australia beats India in second ODI in Adelaide to clinch three-game series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/australia-india-second-odi-adelaide-oval-live-scorecentre/105925988</link><description>Australia completes a two-wicket win over India, clinching the three-game ODI series as Cooper Connolly and Mitch Owen combine to lead Australia's run chase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09d9e7a380edc4e84fbbde426a78ef4e</guid></item><item><title>Backlash over Bureau of Meteorology's 'confusing' new website</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/bureau-of-meteorology-bom-new-website-changes-outrage/105924016</link><description>As wild weather wreaked havoc across the country, the Bureau of Meteorology launched a new website.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcd7a595a8a85c57ad7276d0adf530fc</guid></item><item><title>Stop-work action to affect Tasmanian public schools and health services next week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/stop-work-action-tasmanian-shools-health-services/105925826</link><description>Unions are unhappy with the state government's latest public sector pay offer and are planning stop-work actions next week. Schools and health services for non-urgent patients will be affected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fb024e94793b276871b16cb272ba02e</guid></item><item><title>What a film reviewer who is also a twin thinks of Twinless</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/what-a-film-reviewer-who-is-also-a-twin-thinks-of-twinless/105924720</link><description>Montearo Brown is a TV and film reviewer who blogs under the name Sprite Lee. He also happens to be a twin. So, what does he think of the movie Twinless?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c65c6c04a99379cf1c85bdc15c57082b</guid></item><item><title>Group of juveniles accused of chasing Kununurra police in stolen cars, with video posted online</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/video-police-car-stolen-vehicles-kununurra/105924600</link><description>A video of an erratically driven vehicle chasing a police car in Kununurra has been posted on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ecb115a52256b8be486ebe6cfa6b7ec</guid></item><item><title>North Queensland health authorities issue warning over flying foxes after more exposures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/flying-fox-health-concern/105915766</link><description>An increase in people being injured by bats sparks a health warning over the deadly Australian bat lyssavirus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96a3d651d9acbfdda2b14ae456ad0dea</guid></item><item><title>School bus on fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/school-bus-on-fire/105926142</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af3d643524bf8e2be3f2d2ac28320fd0</guid></item><item><title>Coalition sours over proposed reform to 'broken' environment laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/coalition-sours-over-proposed-environment-laws-epbc/105923700</link><description>Optimism that a deal can be found to amend Australia's environment laws fades, as the Coalition raises concerns over details just days after parts of the legislation were shared with stakeholders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f9b159125f963e87d883b00d5340b6b</guid></item><item><title>Artificial nests trial underway to save Queensland's endangered palm cockatoo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/artificial-nest-trial-for-cape-york-palm-cockatoo/105925758</link><description>Few birds have nesting requirements as finicky as Australia's largest parrot, the palm cockatoo, which is facing its own housing crisis due to a shortage of breeding habitat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38b5c14841513d18a26729b5408f5edd</guid></item><item><title>Central Land Council boss testifies against senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price in Federal Court defamation trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/nt-senator-jacinta-nampijinpa-price-sued-over-defamation-claims/105923738</link><description>Central Land Council chief executive Lesley Turner — who is suing Jacinta Nampijinpa Price for defamation — testifies in Federal Court, and denies being "embarrassed" by the senator pointing out alleged "failures" of the council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">847c001aa784b1748eea85fc42770bc4</guid></item><item><title>Violent clashes outside hotel housing asylum seekers in Dublin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/violent-clashes-outside-hotel-housing-asylum-seekers-in-dublin/105925974</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43340e0e86b8794665061a270070a35f</guid></item><item><title>Why have protesters clashed with police in Dublin?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/dublin-protests-asylum-hotel-violence/105923890</link><description>The head of the Irish police service condemns what he has called "thuggery" by "a mob intent on violence".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">101a139b9e9a08d7dc6cde10a7f8f14f</guid></item><item><title>Hanson rubbishes Joyce leadership speculation, Albanese gets two thumbs up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/barnaby-joyce-pauline-hanson-anthony-albanese-donald-trump/105920314</link><description>This week in politics Barnaby Joyce became a "free agent" and the PM's meeting with Donald Trump got two thumbs up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5df28780e3e41d8abdf5ffa75fe6fe1b</guid></item><item><title>Ways to reduce pollen and dust at home this allergy and hayfever season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/ways-to-reduce-dust-pollen-in-your-home-allergy-hayfever-season/105887900</link><description>Hayfever symptoms can be debilitating. Experts give their tips and tricks on helping reduce allergens in the home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a6f1e49281635efb970909e28a519f0</guid></item><item><title>Promised police beat to tackle Burleigh 'thugs' but acting mayor questions limited hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/police-beat-promised-to-tackle-burleigh-thugs/105924090</link><description>The state government says a promised police beat in Burleigh Heads will be operating by the end of the year, but the acting mayor has questioned why it won't be open at night or on weekends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ff0ea97a3295f24236cbfae6630b7d3</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Premier David Crisafulli backs state's puberty blocker freeze with legal challenge underway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/qld-premier-david-crisafulli-backs-puberty-blocker-ban/105926344</link><description>A pause on puberty blockers was issued in January, which is being challenged in court. David Crisafulli says the decision was made to "keep kids safe".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4069f7d7168456f04cbb98cd147a503</guid></item><item><title>The US military released a video of a strike on an alleged drug vessel in the Pacific.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/us-military-releases-video-of-strike-on-drug-vessel-in-pacific/105926086</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94ac7d5da1ec04c21d2f304cd778adfb</guid></item><item><title>Trump administration conducts military strikes on suspected drug-courier boats in the Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/trump-conducts-military-strikes-on-drug-boats-in-pacific/105925884</link><description>The Trump administration has expanded its target area in its 'narco-trafficking' offensive, conducting two military strikes in the Pacific and bringing the death toll from its attacks to at least 37.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a46a9a6b02e2bf8cfd638137aff833b5</guid></item><item><title>Former Canberra childcare worker Muhammad Ali sentenced for sexually abusing boy in his care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/act-former-childcare-worker-muhammad-ali-jail-sexual-abuse-boy/105925990</link><description>Muhammad Ali, 31, who is already behind bars for a similar incident, has been sentenced to two years in jail for indecently touching a boy in his care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6e9646d46c7bc52e6d3db6116b2354a</guid></item><item><title>Leading Australian jockey Zac Purton laughs off 'big sissy' slur from UK racing identity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/jockey-zac-purton-shrugs-off-criticism-from-uk-racing-identity/105925628</link><description>Just days after winning the world's richest horse race, Australian jockey Zac Purton defends himself over what one UK racing identity describes as the worst ride she has seen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b31d18f02bb49dfaeefd1baebdfcc81</guid></item><item><title>Spotted-tail quoll discovered at Coffs Harbour marina amid rewilding effort</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/vulnerable-spotted-tail-quoll-spotted-at-coffs-harbour-marina/105923582</link><description>An unusual sighting of a spotted-tailed quoll at a boat marina has surprised residents and prompted parks and wildlife experts to monitor the usually forest-dwelling creature.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edd21e50d75559e5fae100d7ea055ae3</guid></item><item><title>Sport has a role to play in addressing harmful gender stereotypes, says Carlton defender</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/harriet-cordner-on-carlton-respects-and-violence-against-women/105923910</link><description>Carlton defender Harriet Cordner says sport has a key role to play in challenging gendered stereotypes in society, particularly given its reach within communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d204662d618f48e535520e14f7eff3a</guid></item><item><title>Private email chain released by NT government amid political interference claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/emails-revealed-between-nt-top-judge-and-department/105926238</link><description>The NT attorney-general's department has taken the extraordinary step of releasing private emails between a top judge and bureaucrats, to try and address allegations of interference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f5a59e1c60fbb6b40ad7cbb13ba40c8</guid></item><item><title>Inquest finds fisherman died after being dragged overboard by shark near Newcastle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/fisherman-paul-barning-dragged-overboard-by-hark-inquest-finds/105926506</link><description>An inquest finds a Sydney fisherman likely drowned after being pulled overboard by a large Mako shark during a game fishing competition near Newcastle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0e1dc02dd8b8f2550ca37546a157088</guid></item><item><title>Temporary commercial and recreational fishing restrictions announced amid ongoing algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/fishing-restrictions-announced-amid-ongoing-algal-bloom/105926488</link><description>The SA government is placing temporary restrictions on fishing in the Gulf St Vincent and Spencer Gulf as results from fish stock monitoring show declining numbers of some species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf20fc4355e416dc49bd319eea97e9b3</guid></item><item><title>Torranzino wins Geelong Cup, giving trainer Paul Preusker a Melbourne Cup runner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/torranzino-wins-geelong-cup-earns-melbourne-cup-place/105926372</link><description>The Geelong Cup is run and won, with King Charles III's horse Gilded Water beaten at the finish to miss out on a spot in this year's Melbourne Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70cd139492e3ba83f7c344dbf62fc6f9</guid></item><item><title>High speed camera captures how venomous snakes bite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/viper-strike-high-speed-camera/105913278</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5221b3a3cef0e11c8f94fbe4d678b328</guid></item><item><title>High speed camera captures how venomous snakes bite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/snake-bite-camera-colubridae/105926354</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c64d98557d75c7464c1bd86149b88f11</guid></item><item><title>High speed camera captures how venomous snakes bite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/snake-bite-camera-3/105926212</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">608eec0bd7426e48ade3e4539f05f467</guid></item><item><title>High speed camera captures how venomous snakes bite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/elapid-snake-high-speed-camera/105913286</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8985fd9490ff9803e28a1a862fe8cf44</guid></item><item><title>Business Correspondent David Taylor explains Optus' management structure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/david-taylor-optus-executives-step-down/105927562</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33499d08788ad403adfa817e071004f6</guid></item><item><title>Coronial investigation into Solomone Taufe'ulungaki's death lays bare tragic reality of Victorian knife crime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/victoria-coronial-findings-solomone-taufeulungaki-youth-crime/105926518</link><description>The data are included in the findings into the death of 15-year-old Solomone Taufe'ulungaki, who died after being chased by a gang who thought he was a member of a rival group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">376c7fb0b2ec8217b6f0d17f00a7570d</guid></item><item><title>Phillip Mark Walton's family tell inquest of their heartbreak about his death in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/walton-inquest-day-4/105926812</link><description>The family of a man who died in police custody in northern New South Wales say they thought he had overcome his problems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07288cf36f87b9d44e29cc8e9b3fa714</guid></item><item><title>South West paramedic sentenced for stealing fentanyl, replacing vials with saline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/south-west-paramedic-sentenced-fentanyl-theft/105925616</link><description>A paramedic has been sentenced for stealing vials of an opioid used for pain relief, refilling them with saline and returning them into circulation in WA ambulances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">752259b2c0432ecb8ea7593a03ef065a</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man found guilty of raping 16-year-old girl as co-accused has charge dismissed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/act-man-guilty-raping-teen-girl-co-accused-charge-dismissed/105927648</link><description>Canberra man Josh Fenwick, 29, is found guilty of raping a 16-year-old girl he took home from Civic with her friend after a night out drinking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d543cfc18bd528119d1f3140073f669</guid></item><item><title>Australian runner Phil Gore wins Backyard Ultra World Championship after five gruelling days of running</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/phil-gore-wins-backyard-ultra-world-championship/105757780</link><description>Ultra-athlete Phil Gore is Australia's newest world champion after five days of near-continuous running in Bell Buckle, Tennessee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bb9eef60c49ccbdafd3c5d3001f3054</guid></item><item><title>A political storm is brewing over long-overdue environmental protection laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/government-s-planned-changes-to-environment-laws/105927432</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0599d09ba8d4dfa5ade7b34e77b0a672</guid></item><item><title>King Charles becomes first British monarch to pray with pope in five centuries in service at Sistine Chapel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/king-charles-pope-leo-historic-religious-service/105925462</link><description>King Charles and Pope Leo have become the first British monarch and pontiff to pray together at a church service in at least five centuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2d5ca5615ce41207adde952909ef55a</guid></item><item><title>Former British soldier found not guilty of 1972 Bloody Sunday murder charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/bloody-sunday-1972-massacre-british-soldier-found-not-guilty/105928006</link><description>The only British soldier ever charged in the 1972 Bloody Sunday massacre is found not guilty of all counts of murder and attempted murder, in a ruling handed down in a Northern Ireland court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">020db12c1a608425a856c20804b9c59b</guid></item><item><title>Chinese Communist Party body replaces 11 members amid corruption purge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/chinese-communist-party-replaces-11-members-at-key-congress/105927988</link><description>The personnel turnover is the highest since 2017 and shows Xi's determination to crack down on corruption, say analysts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0713d89fed50edcc77631eac414c2bd1</guid></item><item><title>Armed with Snapchat and a photo, detectives set about identifying a sexual predator</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/how-snapchat-led-detectives-to-a-sexual-predator/105927598</link><description>Police did not know his name but they did have his Snapchat handle. From there, detectives pieced together a case that would reveal the true identity of sex offender 'Alec'.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a33d16db0483801e5a843b88913d592</guid></item><item><title>King Charles and Pope Leo pray together in Vatican's Sistine Chapel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/king-charles-and-pope-leo-pray-together-in-vatican/105928592</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f52e2c0fc8575ca2fcce17d8ec63854f</guid></item><item><title>Vodafone customer unable to ring triple-0 with Samsung phone says telco failed to help her fix problem</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/vodafone-customer-service-samsung-triple-0/105922288</link><description>A Vodafone customer who was repeatedly unable to ring triple-0 says the major telco failed to help her fix the problem for months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb45f4a15310e3076db7e65e77dc8aa5</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne crime prevention program provides mentoring for multicultural youth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/youth-crime-melbourne-centre-for-multicultural-youth-mentoring/105922620</link><description>Lueth Akue turned to crime during a childhood plagued by hardship. He is using his experience to help young offenders turn their lives around in Australia's "crime capital".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9b9568cadf6cfa0b86a159d9d6ca3f8</guid></item><item><title>Coalition's climate strategy could learn from the proverb about a dog returning to its vomit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/liberals-coalition-proverb-dog-vomit-climate-policy/105919794</link><description>The Liberals have faced an existential crisis over climate and energy twice in recent memory. The damage must live in the memory of today's parliamentarians, who face the prospect of another episode.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b4261ed35e4f4a9c014387726b12a75</guid></item><item><title>The Dish still helping unravel secrets of the cosmos 25 years after film's release</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/dish-movie-25th-anniversary-australia-role-in-moon-landing/105915320</link><description>The film The Dish helped reintroduce a new generation of Australians to the critical role the Parkes Observatory played in the Moon landing. Twenty-five years after its release, the film has had a lasting impact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d3e939b63051b8f008dee345b8474d8</guid></item><item><title>How to tell if a book is valuable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/what-makes-some-books-so-valuable/105924004</link><description>There are many factors that can determine the monetary value of a book, so what can make an edition worth tens of thousands of dollars?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">180abc4ea316320cff098bcae2fc6f5c</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's trade moves with China put South-East Asian countries in the crossfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/us-china-trade-shift-hits-south-east-asian-nations/105924246</link><description>As US President Donald Trump visits South-East Asia amid global trade tensions, Indonesian exporters worry the region could bear the brunt of his protectionist policies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ff0cb1575f3309d3297bacec596d92a</guid></item><item><title>Women push for flexible construction jobs amid building delays in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/nsw-women-builders-flexible-construction-jobs-delays/105921604</link><description>Experts say unlocking flexible hours, gender diversity and migrant workers could help Australia meet its housing targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebafd488245f8c16ee8d73adf614cb0c</guid></item><item><title>Australia is all in on AUKUS. In Donald Trump's America, it's more complicated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/us-aukus-commitment-welcomed-but-questions-remain/105928396</link><description>In Washington on Monday, Anthony Albanese made something clear once again: Australia is all-in on the trilateral defence pact. Clarifying what US powerbrokers think remains a multi-billion-dollar question.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2097e546d99243d4faca7eb0a1113d6</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners handed 900,000ha of Cape York land after 255 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/cape-york-land-returned-to-traditional-owners-native-title/105926650</link><description>A native title claim in the region where Captain James Cook made landfall after his ship crashed into the Great Barrier Reef in 1770 is among one of three to finally be settled by the Federal Court this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">628998917e10c5d82b1709ecf427d004</guid></item><item><title>University of Adelaide admits to $1.25m underpayment of 838 staff</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/adelaide-university-underpayment/105911148</link><description>The vice-chancellor of the University of Adelaide says the underpayments, which occurred between 2017 and 2025, were "unfortunate and very regrettable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cb5325673f0ad055dd1ce50a7f6a6fd</guid></item><item><title>Three men charged with Bankstown murder of Thi Kim Tran</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/three-men-charged-with-bankstown-murder-of-thi-kim-tran/105928608</link><description>Three men have been charged with murder after a Sydney woman was kidnapped and killed over her husband's drug debt earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a975243015b6297bb0cc8036144a60a</guid></item><item><title>Parliamentary privilege used to name Cheryl Grimmer murder confessor, but legal limits remain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/nsw-parliament-privilege-cheryl-grimmer/105927602</link><description>NSW MP Jeremy Buckingham used parliamentary privilege to read a 1971 confession in the Cheryl Grimmer case, bypassing decades of legal silence. Outside parliament, the man's identity remains legally suppressed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36733a4ca15a0296a5011bc639441aec</guid></item><item><title>NSW program helps mothers restore dignity, rebuild lives outside of prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/nsw-women-prison-program-from-now-wagec-mothers-homelessness/105787934</link><description>The program from the Women's and Girls' Emergency Centre helps pregnant women in, or at risk of incarceration find safe accommodation and keep families together.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">130f9d1b4ce2f26b7907dd3236ade820</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government announces pilot program to subsidise apprenticeships, but industry warns more needed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/queensland-apprentices-funding-but-industry-warns-more-needed/105927430</link><description>The Queensland government has announced a pilot program which would subsidies the wages of about 7 per cent of the state's apprentices if taken on by eligible businesses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4fa9b11ae8fcd5c2daa797bbf97ba1e</guid></item><item><title>Live: ASX set to rise, Wall Street, Trump to meet Xi, oil bounces</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/asx-markets-business-live-news-date-year/105928654</link><description>The Australian share market is poised to open higher on Friday, following gains on Wall Street. Investor sentiment has been buoyed by news that Donald Trump plans to meet with Xi Jinping, while US sanctions on Russia have pushed oil prices higher. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44f9106973278938ae8d1d449270d170</guid></item><item><title>Sydney 2000 Paralympics changed everything for the Paralympic movement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/sydney-paralympics-changed-everything-elizabeth-wright/105872756</link><description>Sydney 2000 was a turning point — not just for me, but for the entire Paralympic movement, writes silver medallist Elizabeth Wright.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">092136bc1972dc772bb30f1718b69b4c</guid></item><item><title>ABC news quiz: A jewel heist, an awkward Trump moment and a mysterious burning object in the outback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/abc-new-quiz-october-24-donald-trump-louvre-theft-prince-andrew/105922120</link><description>How closely were you following the news this week? Test yourself to find out!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c98b5aec7b57b223d6eb29ed7816a8a</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: Coalition says it’s in no rush to pass environmental reforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/federal-politics-live-blog-oct-24/105928628</link><description>Shadow Environment Minister Angie Bell says Labor's proposed environmental protection laws don't strike the right balance. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50c30ee6c3b274d9ece8ede11a368c5d</guid></item><item><title>NBA head coach Chauncey Billups, player Terry Rozier arrested over sports betting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/basketball-billups-rozier-arrested-nba-betting-poker-schemes/105928658</link><description>Chauncey Billups, the coach of Portland, and Miami Heat guard Terry Rozier are among more than 30 people arrested in two cases alleging sprawling criminal schemes to rake in millions by rigging sports bets and poker games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c1adda1a7bfd5e98d96964fe5622c73</guid></item><item><title>Innovators rethink bike seat design to combat cycling saddle pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/innovative-bike-seat-designs-to-combat-cycling-saddle-pain/105898628</link><description>"Saddle soreness" is a common complaint among cyclists. These innovators are looking at creative ways to prevent it by redesigning the bike seat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6022273d98d73660d31032c869b90541</guid></item><item><title>ADHD support groups help women in Geraldton navigate life after diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/adhd-support-groups-for-women-in-geraldton/105920570</link><description>Jessie Carrie could not find the support she needed after being diagnosed with ADHD as an adult, so she started groups to help others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22b713181dd93c35dad55fe09e8d7be2</guid></item><item><title>Mudgee's Regent Theatre bought by residents with big plans for grand revival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/movies-to-mudgee-regent-theatre-bought-by-residents/105926030</link><description>After sitting idle for two decades residents of the NSW town of Mudgee have purchased the iconic Regent Theatre, with plans to return it to its former glory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f751cc691c737c4a8150cf9a7ec5388a</guid></item></channel></rss>