<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 23:48:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Agent Inside</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-21/the-agent-inside/105198860</link><description>Four Corners is the home of Australian investigative journalism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe5267caa680beaa0cc4c1c6c2a8a4fc</guid></item><item><title>Tiwi Islanders eager to have their say as remote voting for the federal election begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-22/early-voting-starts-in-remote-communities-tiwi-islands-aec/105201318</link><description>Voters in the small remote community of Pirlangimpi on the Tiwi Islands, north of Darwin, have become some of the first to cast their votes for the federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0c419fe3ae44debe7edf27241c0e5c1</guid></item><item><title>Mobile coverage is an election issue in regional areas. What's been promised?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-23/telecommunications-mobile-coverage-federal-election-promises/105080674</link><description>For many regional and remote Australians, reliable mobile coverage can be life-saving. They are desperate for both sides of politics to take meaningful action towards eliminating black spots.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ceda72e552d98e5f293d3c037efeefa</guid></item><item><title>Ketamine nasal spray to become cheaper for Australians with treatment-resistant depression</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-28/ketamine-nasal-spray-added-to-pbs-for-depression-treatment/105217432</link><description>A new nasal spray that uses a form of ketamine to treat stubborn depression will be added to the PBS, making treatment cheaper for thousands of Australians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f6ad4a5944cef7ea5d44f9120d66e00</guid></item><item><title>Health, climate and community sport: What older voters in the Tasmanian seat of Bass are talking about this election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-29/health-climate-sport-election-older-voters-bass-tasmania/105224138</link><description>The federal seat of Bass is held by a margin of just 1.4 per cent. For these older voters who live in the electorate, health, climate and community sport are the issues that will decide their vote.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a3579db910b5a7ee8e11d2618bf798f</guid></item><item><title>Elizabeth Holmes's partner Billy Evans reportedly raising millions for a blood-testing start-up — and it's not Theranos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-12/elizabeth-holmes-husband-raising-money-for-blood-testing-company/105282240</link><description>The partner of disgraced Theranos CEO Elizabeth Holmes has reportedly raised millions of dollars in order to start a new blood-testing company, according to a report from the New York Times.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b898fcc846697e818f9af78d96e483c5</guid></item><item><title>The winners and losers of the 2025-26 NT budget, from prisons to roads and health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-13/nt-budget-2025-winners-and-losers-corrections-health/105280846</link><description>With net debt to soon surpass $12 billion, the Northern Territory government's latest budget is headlined by record funding for corrections but little for new infrastructure projects.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26cfb88f3b7a737b2294f1bce397520e</guid></item><item><title>Israel is targeting Iran's nuclear uranium enrichment plants. Here are the contamination risks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-06-20/israel-attack-iran-nuclear-uranium-enrichment-contamination-risk/105441886</link><description>Israel has targeted five key Iranian nuclear facilities over the past week. Experts say attacks on uranium enrichment plants are mainly a "chemical problem", not radiological.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6222c3e51ed0cbba0e68e224315ac47</guid></item><item><title>Is Iran set to leave the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-06-22/is-iran-set-to-leave-the-nuclear-non-proliferation-treaty-/105438606</link><description>As the bombs keep landing and Israel continues its devastating attacks on Iran's nuclear program, it's easy to forget Iran remains a signatory of the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a25e889f8a9bb4289b752d1ce074415</guid></item><item><title>Radiation at Montebello Islands still 4,500 times higher than WA coast after nuclear blasts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-06-22/radiation-montebello-islands-western-australia-nuclear-blasts/105420894</link><description>Three atomic bombs were detonated on the Montebello Islands in the 1950s. Scientists say they've now precisely measured how much radiation remains, with some locals re-evaluating fond memories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc5a4a6c1455c7cee1f1caf2e0132742</guid></item><item><title>Trump doubles down on US 'obliteration' of Iranian nuclear sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-06-25/marco-rubio-says-iran-is-much-further-away-from-nuclear-weapon/105461250</link><description>Donald Trump's assertion comes after a leaked preliminary US intelligence assessment reportedly found the weekend strikes only set back Iran's nuclear program by less than six months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f3bb1fb9815e30c1bd1ee3805a39e6</guid></item><item><title>North Korea has 'undeclared' ICBM base near China border, according to new report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-22/north-korea-secret-missile-base/105684760</link><description>A secret North Korean missile base that likely houses six to nine nuclear-capable intercontinental ballistic missiles has been located close to the border with China, a new report says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1facef7576a0dfb77113659990147dfe</guid></item><item><title>Illawarra groups want Port Kembla ruled out for AUKUS nuclear submarine base</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/port-kembla-declaration-against-aukus-nuclear-submarine-base/105815986</link><description>The federal government says it will not make a decision on the location of the nuclear submarine base until later this decade, but Illawarra institutions — from unions to churches — are sending a strong message now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9576ab16c1d1be2862cfa1862bc87c3</guid></item><item><title>Darwin ship lift project cost blowout rivalling Snowy 2.0, economist says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/nt-taxpayers-billion-dollar-ship-lift-pearling-giant-paspaley/105856034</link><description>It’s taken 10 years, blown out by hundreds of millions of dollars, and is still nowhere near becoming operational. Now there are calls for the Darwin ship lift project to be scrapped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c825f0a31c74d4890b2904a10fbbc5ed</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the Louvre jewellery heist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/what-we-know-about-the-louvre-jewellery-heist/105910640</link><description>Here are the details on the items stolen in the Louvre heist that unfolded in broad daylight in Paris.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d269eaf9f556b0ba4f01c08707826645</guid></item><item><title>Temporary bans on fishing popular species floated to address dwindling populations off WA coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/wa-fishing-bans-floated-address-species-shortages/105913198</link><description>A temporary ban on fishing iconic species, including WA dhufish and pink snapper, could be on the table as the state government scrambles for solutions to WA's at-risk fish populations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57ce6ad300f7bec9a9eaa714428b06db</guid></item><item><title>Coverage of embattled Perth builder, WA's 'most vulnerable child', among award-winning journalism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/abc-stories-recognised-at-meaa-awards-/105989352</link><description>Coverage of the collapse of Perth builder Nicheliving, WA's 'most vulnerable child' and the state's guardianship system is among the award-winning journalism at the state's media awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eb6943dc996eb5c2f9706004c0d3c41</guid></item><item><title>BBC boss rallies staff in face of leadership crisis and Trump legal threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/bbc-boss-rallies-staff-amid-leadership-crisis-trump-legal-threat/105999184</link><description>The outgoing boss of the BBC sought to rally his journalists on Tuesday, as the British broadcaster confronts legal action by US President Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">789ba736dde580179f8f9b6a5aa1df3d</guid></item><item><title>F1 standings after Las Vegas Grand Prix disqualification, Lando Norris leads Oscar Piastri and Max Verstappen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/f1-standings-las-vegas-grand-prix-norris-piastri-verstappen/106042984</link><description>Here is how the drivers' championship is poised with two rounds remaining.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1be7c513c92bc3ec40b1a5afea7b85db</guid></item><item><title>Domestic violence survivors left 'deeply traumatised' in efforts to keep temporary accommodation access</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/nsw-dv-victim-survivors-temporary-accommodation-dcj-ordeals/105862232</link><description>Two women who fled their violent partners say their efforts to stay in emergency accommodation via state government housing offices left them "deeply traumatised".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cfce545bc323cd9b395ed8637537209</guid></item><item><title>Super Netball could grow to 10 teams as Netball Australia invites licence bids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/super-netball-could-grow-to-10-teams-by-2027/106077068</link><description>Super Netball could have two additional teams by 2027, with Netball Australia calling for expressions of interest to expand the competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f51d1aadcd45af0382e9a8ea5524b8e</guid></item><item><title>Snowy Mountains farmers call for support in managing spread of invasive weed African lovegrass</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/african-lovegrass-weed-chokes-out-native-grass-snowy-mountains/106006854</link><description>To the untrained eye, African lovegrass is just another plant in the NSW Snowy Mountains. But this golden plant is a deceptive invasive weed that is choking out the landscape, causing some farmers to leave the land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97336bfbd9984ec7e511ae69aa52d050</guid></item><item><title>Watchdog updates warnings for Ozempic-style drugs over potential risk of suicidal thoughts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-01/updated-warning-for-ozempic-mounjaro-glp-1-drugs/106087650</link><description>Australia's medicines regulator issues a safety warning over the potential risk of suicidal thoughts and behaviours when taking Ozempic-style drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57f9160386d3a06fca529fbf8ad4084e</guid></item><item><title>MPs to probe Crown Estate property portfolio after Mountbatten-Windsor lease revelations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-03/uk-mps-launch-iry-into-royal-family-living-arrangements/106094472</link><description>MPs in the United Kingdom will investigate the Crown Estate, after revelations Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor — Queen Elizabeth II's second son — had not paid rent for two decades sparked outrage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed1f0ba27870114eb8ee59c7195642e</guid></item><item><title>Arthur Higgins, veteran sports broadcaster who also covered the Moon landing and 9/11, dies aged 85</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/arthur-higgins-channel-nine-abc-journalist-obituary/106100804</link><description>A sports aficionado whose baritone voice earned him the nickname "Big Daddy", Higgins read the news on Channel Nine, the ABC and a slew of radio stations over the course of his 57 years in the media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da83acdbbec9e4b75a3fef2d125fa6a2</guid></item><item><title>F1 title contender Oscar Piastri non-committal about helping Lando Norris win in Abu Dhabi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/oscar-piastri-and-lando-norris-in-abu-dhabi-grand-prix/106104724</link><description>Oscar Piastri dodges the question of whether he might help Lando Norris lift the world F1 title in Abu Dhabi, saying McLaren has not discussed the issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7501564d8239c082852e90c9916d0fe5</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne public housing tower attracts heritage nomination ahead of demolition plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/north-melbourne-public-housing-towers-heritage-nomination-alfred/106058886</link><description>A 1960s North Melbourne public housing tower slated for imminent demolition has been nominated for protection under state heritage laws, following a successful appeal by a tenants group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ce3056e0e38157451f25d51d0b69f39</guid></item><item><title>Lando Norris claims F1 world title after dramatic Abu Dhabi Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/f1-live-abu-dhabi-grand-prix-oscar-piastri-lando-norris-max/105995116</link><description>Max Verstappen has won the Abu Dhabi Grand Prix ahead of Oscar Piastri, but Lando Norris finishes third to claim the world title.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fd6f8c94f3d969c2ad20a822600258a</guid></item><item><title>Where Oscar Piastri lost the Formula 1 world championship, McLaren teammate Lando Norris claims ultimate prize</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/oscar-piastri-missed-f1-world-title-through-minor-moments/106113184</link><description>Oscar Piastri missed out on winning the Formula 1 drivers world championship by just 13 points to his teammate Lando Norris, the culmination of multiple small moments throughout the season that cost him dearly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb082e3701f1fe8b29d4db1328f26f4e</guid></item><item><title>Public housing residents in Roebourne swelter through heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/public-housing-residents-in-roebourne-swelter-through-heatwave/106129428</link><description>WA's Pilbara has already endured a seven-day heatwave this month, but many in the town of Roebourne have little more than a hose and wet sheets to keep them cool as temperatures top 45 degrees Celsius.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd37452858bfa7de9710ef2891b41309</guid></item><item><title>UK police won't probe claim former prince Andrew asked bodyguard to investigate Virginia Roberts Giuffre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/uk-police-wont-probe-andrew-claim/106140752</link><description>London's police force says it will not take further action over claims that former prince Andrew asked his protection officer to carry out checks on Virginia Roberts Giuffre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">804859bb33197ef5054bd889c0dbd03a</guid></item><item><title>Bondi terrorists travelled to Philippines for 'military-style training', security sources say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-gunmen-went-to-philippines-for-military-style-training/106148662</link><description>Father-son gunmen Sajid and Naveed Akram travelled to the Philippines to receive "military-style training" in the month before they killed 15 people at a Hanukkah celebration at Bondi Beach, security sources have confirmed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52edb6122488935f51e540d7c1ade39e</guid></item><item><title>'Children aren't born antisemitic': Education review aims to make Jewish students safer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/antisemitism-education-taskforce-review-david-gonski/106158642</link><description>The focus will turn from the threats outside the gate to those some critics say are embedded within education from a lack of Holocaust education to the harassment of Jewish students at universities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c28629c71488122314f4634803c7887</guid></item><item><title>Life on Adria Downs, one of Australia's most remote cattle stations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/life-on-one-of-australia-s-most-remote-cattle-stations/106155078</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d7fbcf81c588959cd0e9c828a30dba9</guid></item><item><title>In pictures: Thousands honour Bondi victims in emotional paddle-out tribute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/bondi-terror-attack-paddle-out-in-pictures/106161604</link><description>Thousands of locals packed the Bondi beachfront for an emotional paddle-out in honour of the victims of Sunday's terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80b6bdcff0b11b7f238ce68b0cd09872</guid></item><item><title>Epstein files contain new photo of former prince Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/new-photo-former-prince-andrew-mountbatten-windsor-epstein-files/106166672</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor, the former prince, appears in the first tranche of the so-called Epstein files.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6eecd6194d73f15e27e79dd511e68c0</guid></item><item><title>How domestic violence offenders use the court system to inflict more pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/domestic-violence-perpetrators-abuse-court-system/106047916</link><description>Jessica Seage fought for six years for the man who raped her to be convicted. Experts say her experience is a stark example of how perpetrators abuse the system to inflict more pain on their victims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f60810c44353ad6c998ba40286d3c2fa</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder after woman's death at Northfield</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/man-charged-with-murder-after-woman-s-death-northfield/106169300</link><description>A 42-year-old man has been charged with murder after a woman was found dead in a home in Adelaide's northern suburbs on Sunday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb60343fedbc20ed6ab2e59a36bffee0</guid></item><item><title>Prince William and son George visit homelessness charity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/prince-william-and-son-george-visit-homelessness-charity-/106171302</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">764d03c1a8d8cc3ba491b17e9ac824c2</guid></item><item><title>The Christmas display at West Hindmarsh delighting children, adults and nuns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/adelaide-christmas-display-with-more-than-50000-lights/106169742</link><description>Families from all over Adelaide visit Joe Ferraro's home to marvel at his Christmas display, which he has amassed a collection of more than 50,000 lights since he began nearly 20 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2338cd0eb9ddf16d0907b6d947de1ab</guid></item><item><title>Poor sleep, unhealthy diets and stress compound to leave homeless at risk of dying decades early</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/homelessness-poor-health-life-expectancy-falls-wa-research-finds/106165168</link><description>Western Australian research is showing a strong link between homelessness and poor health, with life expectancy more than 30 years lower for people without secure housing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">082793cf40319386a9f52dfc3194b670</guid></item><item><title>US approves Wegovy pill, giving Novo Nordisk an edge in obesity drug competition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/wegovy-pill-approved-in-us-new-obesity-treatment/106175652</link><description>A daily weight-loss pill will soon be available in the US, after the regulator gave approval to Danish drug company Novo Nordisk's oral version of the popular injectable, Wegovy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2a5ee3d3b6d8085cb49ee03f61d25e8</guid></item><item><title>Before Prince Harry fled the royals there was love-sick Edward</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/royal-family-prince-edward-history-love-harry/105522404</link><description>Before Harry fled the royals for Meghan and Montecito, this would-be king of England was famous for trading his title for love. And the cracks began to show on a trip to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0ca9182ddc5496c024a43a96389693c</guid></item><item><title>25 years on, the search continues for stars of the Sydney Olympics' closing ceremony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/sydney-olympics-kewpie-doll-search/106169888</link><description>For Trevor Harvey, honouring a departed mate meant one thing — finding a 6-metre-tall Kewpie doll from the Sydney Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2db87d7aa3f1086c01d0693d98b03505</guid></item><item><title>The right way to stack your dishwasher and the verdict on rinsing beforehand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/the-verdict-on-rinsing-dishes-before-stacking-the-dishwasher/106022382</link><description>Rinsing can actually send a message to your dishwasher that your plate doesn't need as much washing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b16a5e33ffb32c5a75404f38ecdbd73d</guid></item><item><title>Dozens of shark heads dumped outside WA Fisheries minister's office as demersal fishing ban looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/shark-heads-dumped-outside-jackie-jarvis-office-fisheries/106184674</link><description>Hundreds of kilograms of shark heads have been left dumped outside the WA Fisheries minister's office in Margaret River, just three days before a permanent commercial demersal fishing ban comes into effect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52da2612172243bdd59c8424d34d39b0</guid></item><item><title>Russia claims nuclear-capable Oreshnik missiles have been deployed in Belarus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/russia-deploys-missiles-in-belarus/106189110</link><description>Belarusian President Alexander Lukashenko, a staunch ally of the Kremlin, announced the deployment of the Oreshnik intermediate-range ballistic missiles earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99fce8983aa1195491b577050eab8701</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill gardeners chop down trees in battle with Queensland fruit fly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/fruit-fly-war-in-broken-hill/106179748</link><description>There was no fruit fly to be found in Broken Hill 20 years ago, but now gardeners are facing an uphill battle trying to rid themselves of the pest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce1af482ebd6c6b880eb979a75966489</guid></item><item><title>Permanent commercial demersal fishing ban begins for large part of WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/permanent-commercial-demersal-fishing-ban-begins-for-part-of-wa/106182868</link><description>From today, commercial demersal fishing is banned along hundreds of kilometres of the WA coastline in an effort to recover fish species numbers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2b9a6a2246d889c750fc2d0dcfefe13</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne's Victoria Street has been on a downward slide, but a brighter future may be beckoning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-02/victoria-street-richmond-long-term-decline-solutions/106051394</link><description>Richmond's Victoria Street, once a buzzing area home to dozens of restaurants and grocers, has seen better days. What can be done to bring it back to its bustling best?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">828e3ea64293c180e8586ad71248a690</guid></item><item><title>Repeated brain injuries linked to memory changes in intimate partner violence survivors, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/brain-injury-concussion-strangulation-partner-violence-study/106159980</link><description>An Australian-first study finds evidence of previously undetected, long-term cognitive changes in women more than six months after they experienced repeated concussions and strangulation during intimate partner violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3515faea792fbbea3ef26d94212d5fbf</guid></item><item><title>WA fishing ban sees fishers flock to coastal hamlet Windy Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/wa-demersal-fishing-ban-crowds-at-windy-harbour/106206190</link><description>WA's new ban on demersal fishing sees fishers flock to a coastal hamlet unaffected by the new rules, but locals say the crowds are unsustainable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7e8e64cd04b4c294f9f1e3b82a81601</guid></item><item><title>WA antique shop forced to shut after almost four decades in business as rent spikes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/wa-antique-shop-forced-to-shut-after-almost-four-decades/106207366</link><description>George Nakhoul has been operating Furniture Restoration on James Street in Guildford since the late 1980s, but a rent spike means the shop will have to close its doors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79c12cbbc843dac1afb2b5cd9c31d519</guid></item><item><title>How I have fun with friends without spending money</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/perspective-koren-on-free-fun-with-friends/106055938</link><description>I've kept low-cost, high-fun habits alive for years, even after returning home to a city where socialising often seems to mean shelling out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a76d75b2115ed8d249c4c6396faeda38</guid></item><item><title>Australian driver Jack Doohan released by Alpine Formula 1 team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/jack-doohan-released-by-alpine-f1-team/106227130</link><description>Alpine and Australian Jack Doohan agree to part ways so the 22-year-old driver can "pursue other career opportunities".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b9182710e9c97371ebc36c99243e9a2</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106230046</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fb5bd6a65b0dccbba4c91afd2db760e</guid></item><item><title>Drought-hit grain growers make every drop of rain count</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/drought-hit-grain-growers-make-every-drop-of-rain-count/106207304</link><description>New techniques and technology are allowing southern NSW grain growers to produce a harvest, despite significantly below-average rainfall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">408dff5d16fb21cc039faec44c0873b1</guid></item><item><title>From dumped shark heads to rising fury — how WA's demersal fishing ban turned ugly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/wa-demersal-fishing-ban-leaves-fishers-frustrated/106229426</link><description>Western Australia's ban on demersal fishing has left fishers frustrated. Will the government be able to soften the blow for an angry industry?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b641c0b367c639c58057e28322f15fa1</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Fish Market vendors to prepare for 'teething problems', ferry wharf still to come</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/sydney-fish-market-teething-problems-concerns-ferry-wharf/106232864</link><description>More than $600 million over budget, the Sydney Fish Market will open its doors, but traders and visitors are being warned to prepare for teething issues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0352d503aa8e33fcdbb6c3f2e22c2510</guid></item><item><title>Chalmers backs Bullock, global markets up on 'massive' AI chips deal — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/asx-markets-business-live-news-january-16-2026/106235816</link><description>Federal Treasurer Jim Chalmers has come out in support of Michele Bullock after the Reserve Bank governor signed a joint statement in solidarity with Mr Powell, who is facing criminal prosecution driven by US President Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c7302d4b1860cd392ad8e28dfba5dca</guid></item><item><title>Grandmother's support group becomes a lifeline for Lithgow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/grandmother-led-support-group-becomes-a-lifeline-for-lithgow/106098374</link><description>It started as a Facebook page and now it is a vital charity. Here is how this group run by grandmothers is fighting loneliness in the NSW Blue Mountains.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2eb9d750a3d061eaece11cc2cee617bd</guid></item><item><title>Tunarama's return lures big fish back to seafood capital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/return-of-port-lincoln-tunarama-festival-sees-big-fish-seafood/106238468</link><description>Port Lincoln's world-famous Tunarama Festival has returned to the South Australian event calendar, with thousands of people lining the streets to celebrate the seafood industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50fb7a302777aa8ce7782e61821b28b7</guid></item><item><title>Denver Broncos quarterback Bo Nix's season-ending ankle injury throws Super Bowl race wide open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/nfl-playoff-denver-broncos-bo-nix-quarterback-ankle-injury/106242230</link><description>As the final four NFL teams prepare to battle it out for a place in the Super Bowl, a last-minute injury to Denver quarterback Bo Nix has thrown the race for the championship into chaos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c034ea9c6f12ed153bb2d45859cff93d</guid></item><item><title>Body found among wreckage of Indonesian plane that lost contact mid-flight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/body-found-among-wreckage-of-plane-in-indonesia/106242700</link><description>A body has been found among the wreckage of an Indonesian plane that lost contact mid-flight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db885b01bccd5ca18317d0cde9a36a3e</guid></item><item><title>At least 39 dead after two high-speed trains derailed in Spain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/many-dead-after-high-speed-trains-derailed-in-spain/106243428</link><description>At least 39 people have died and dozens are severely injured after two high-speed trains derailed in southern Spain, local authorities say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4bfd8134627a082bb0f0a5bccab5340</guid></item><item><title>Women's captain departs football club after men's offensive Silly Saturday costumes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/box-hill-north-fc-womens-captain-leaves-club-after-men-behaviour/106190266</link><description>A women's senior football captain has stepped away from her local club after photos of the senior men's leadership team were posted online during their "Silly Saturday" post-season celebrations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ffb103fdb7886c68801e2562aeef8ca</guid></item><item><title>Hawthorn's Will Day to miss first half of the AFL season with shoulder injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/will-day-hawthorn-shoulder-injury-return-afl/106250104</link><description>Hawthorn star Will Day is set for a lengthy stint on the sidelines after dislocating his right shoulder during pre-season training and undergoing surgery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d307d6fe71f40e6d700287b246f166</guid></item><item><title>Hobart Hurricanes lose captain Nathan Ellis and Test batsman Jake Weatherald for Big Bash knockout final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/two-big-names-to-miss-bbl-knockout-final/106250756</link><description>Hobart's quest for back-to-back Big Bash titles has copped two major blows with captain Nathan Ellis and Test player Jake Weatherald to miss the Hurricanes' knockout final against Melbourne Renegades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b67761843ab9ed0f2e8dd6d75d499e78</guid></item><item><title>David Beckham breaks silence after son Brooklyn cuts ties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/david-beckham-brooklyn-davos-children-make-mistakes/106251360</link><description>The soccer superstar tells broadcasters at the World Economic Forum that "children are allowed to make mistakes" in his first public comments since his son's allegations went public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eea9ba1d2b7ca4efca871fee6767d24b</guid></item><item><title>Mitchell Starc shoulder injury concerns Sydney Sixers after BBL qualifier loss to Perth Scorchers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/sixers-sweat-on-starc-injury-after-bitter-scorchers-blow/106251462</link><description>The Sydney Sixers are thrust into a do-or-die final on Friday after losing to Perth, and star quick Mitch Starc is no guarantee to play.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eefe7c22daed676aa248b269f9e31aae</guid></item><item><title>One dead, at least 15 injured after passenger train derails near Barcelona</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/commuter-train-derails-near-barcelona-after-wall-collapse/106251708</link><description>One person has died and at least 15 others have been injured after a wall fell on a train track due to heavy rain near the Spanish city of Barcelona, local authorities say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e932850efc859db7d5d9da9b61c3373</guid></item><item><title>Sheep under the eye of AI</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/using-ai-to-count-sheep/106250690</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c5af840e880887503748d0dd1f0eb2a</guid></item><item><title>Father of Adelaide girl who died due to mother's alleged neglect tells court of coffin threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/jasmine-willmott-father-gives-evidence-in-manslaughter-trial/106254726</link><description>The father of a 15-year-old girl whose mother is accused of her manslaughter, tells the South Australian Supreme Court of a threat made against his daughter and punishment she was made to do.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">877e18523e326afbcffe861376220e59</guid></item><item><title>First LNG cargo from Santos Barossa gas project bound from Darwin to Japan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/nt-first-cargo-lng-santos-barossa-gas-leaves-darwin-for-japan/106258638</link><description>After a series of delays, Santos announces the first gas from its $5.6 billion Barossa project will be shipped from Darwin bound for Japan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd8bba37d4f040d1881712e836830e01</guid></item><item><title>Questioning your relationship in the new year? You're not alone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/why-the-new-year-exposes-relationship-problems-/106224924</link><description>The fresh start of a new year causes us to reassess many parts of our lives, including relationships. Knowing whether it's time to call it quits or give things more time requires reflection — and support — as our experts explain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a8679e8fb180c317100f0812cb15f67</guid></item><item><title>Gunman wanted over triple shooting could be difficult to find, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/police-search-for-lake-cargelligo-gunman-after-three-shot-dead/106260214</link><description>Police have warned residents in villages neighbouring Lake Cargelligo to remain vigilant after three people were shot dead in a domestic violence attack on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6237034df4c10ee4887c72324b79c0b</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith delivers again as Sixers down Hurricanes to cruise into BBL decider</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/steve-smith-fires-sydney-sixers-into-bbl-final/106264300</link><description>Steve Smith top scores for the fifth time in as many innings as the Sixers down the Hurricanes to book a place in Sunday's BBL decider in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e348c53fcfa7f88f916aeae4be93ff8</guid></item><item><title>Prince Harry takes on the Daily Mail in High Court privacy showdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/prince-harry-duke-sussex-daily-mail-court-case-principle-anger/106261250</link><description>The Duke of Sussex takes on the publisher he believes poisoned his childhood, his marriage, and his peace of mind in a legal battle driven by anger as well as principle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0734b45ec2433eaff1d6c9115bfcbc11</guid></item><item><title>Future of Canberra's Black Mountain Tower in limbo as Ngunnawal cultural site plans stall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/black-mountain-tower-indigenous-cultural-site-stalled/106263224</link><description>Custodians say they have been excluded from talks between Telstra and the ACT government about plans to develop the iconic tower into a Ngunnawal cultural site.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0308dda5f51e68e7f5117a2dda31603a</guid></item><item><title>Police confirm possible sighting of Julian Ingram in Mount Hope after Lake Cargelligo shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/julian-ingram-possible-sighting-at-mt-hope/106266998</link><description>A large-scale search is underway in the Mount Hope district after a possible sighting of the alleged triple murderer overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ccfd0fa14b664d8eddeabb588e0be60</guid></item><item><title>English veteran stars in Scorchers' record-extending sixth BBL title</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/scorchers-claim-sixth-bbl-title-against-sixers/106265840</link><description>The Perth Scorchers have easily accounted for a meek Sydney Sixers in the BBL final, cruising to a six-wicket triumph at a raucous Perth Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5025b1b0b5907ebcef2b0060df278c66</guid></item><item><title>Explorers Bass and Flinders named five Illawarra islands after themselves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/history-of-five-islands-nature-reserve-in-nsw-illawarra-region/106050352</link><description>Home to migratory sea birds, seals and penguins, the history of Wollongong's five islands goes back well beyond Bass and Flinders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cec7a4643668a99c73476143199ed7da</guid></item><item><title>Two people die in light plane crash near private Gold Coast airstrip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/emergency-services-to-gold-coast-light-plane-crash/106272486</link><description>Police say the plane crashed shortly after take-off from the private airstrip, killing two men and sparking a large fire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5d9832692fa7305ad0b5d13717b1634</guid></item><item><title>Overland Telegraph Line documentary features First Nations accounts of violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/central-australian-film-director-tells-story-overland-telegraph/106247528</link><description>Aboriginal filmmaker Kieran Satour's documentary tells of murders and massacres by settlers and First Nations people during construction of the Overland Telegraph Line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9daf27fcbcf7e0196b8d816270bddfb0</guid></item><item><title>Charges withdrawn against seven men accused of illegally trafficking abalone on NSW South Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/abalone-trafficking-charges-dropped-nsw-south-coast/106213172</link><description>Seven Aboriginal men from the NSW South Coast, accused of illegally trafficking thousands of blacklip abalone, walk free after police prosecutors withdraw all charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f73546154ee0fac10a78dd558d430a35</guid></item><item><title>Why time feels like it speeds up as we age</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/why-time-feels-like-it-speeds-up-as-we-age/106223834</link><description>The perception that time is flying by can sometimes make us feel stressed and anxious. So how do we slow it down?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a0daa65cbbf696213c3b66e4297bd5e</guid></item><item><title>Rado Vidisic, A-League title winning coach and Australian football figure, dies aged 64</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/a-league-title-winning-coach-rado-vidosic-dies-aged-64/106276864</link><description>Rado Vidosic, a highly-regarded Australian football figure and coach across a number of A-League clubs and teams, dies of cancer aged 64.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16da6dfa221a94bba24b8ebe472c71a4</guid></item><item><title>Meet the 2026 Trailblazers changing regional Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/heywire-26-trailblazers-changing-regional-australia/106154604</link><description>Jayden is helping youth go from feeling "lost, angry and unheard" to "proud strong and seen". He's one of our 2026 Trailblazers, announced today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07e1f1bd2e589d52d1a28389012efec4</guid></item><item><title>'Doomsday Clock' set to 85 seconds to midnight, closer than ever to catastrophe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/doomsday-clock-85-seconds-to-midnight-nuclear-threats/106261766</link><description>Atomic scientists set the Doomsday Clock to 85 seconds midnight, with threats such as nuclear weapons and conflicts pushing humanity closer than ever to the point of annihilation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b81ce68e6e053ed4255e01382385ac1d</guid></item><item><title>Wine Australia's export report for 2025 shows consumers sobering up as cost of living bites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/wine-australia-export-report-for-2025-global-market-decline-sa/106277572</link><description>Global demand for Australian wine is continuing to dwindle, with the latest Wine Australia export report showing an 8 per cent decrease in 2025 as consumers opt for alcohol-free trends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea608f774b9ac7ff068b1669d2fdaeb6</guid></item><item><title>Rain has transformed the outback from parched to puddles.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/from-thirsty-camels-mud/106279410</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38a8b5daea7a9f23748c75a79557e4d4</guid></item><item><title>DC mid-air collision that killed 67 was '100 per cent preventable': NTSB</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/ntsb-says-dc-mid-air-collision-that-killed-67-was-preventable/106280300</link><description>Investigators and families are calling for major reforms, with more than 30 safety recommendations issued to prevent a similar tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">006b4c4c70d3d7334ef583e17193d58a</guid></item><item><title>What is India's Nipah virus outbreak, what are the symptoms of the illness and how can you protect yourself from it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/what-do-we-know-about-india-nipah-virus-outbreak/106280738</link><description>Two cases of the Nipah virus have been detected in India, prompting a raft of screening measures to be enacted in countries across Asia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1450cb0be69b0ff6f046cde421748e6</guid></item><item><title>Sophie Molineux named Australian cricket captain, succeeding Alyssa Healy ahead of India series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/molineux-named-healy-successor-as-australian-captain-cricket/106281600</link><description>Sophie Molineux becomes Australia's new multi-format captain, taking over from Alyssa Healy ahead of a home series against India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3c004078c58d9d0e5319eb299a36155</guid></item><item><title>Parramatta provided with emails from Zac Lomax's lawyer as contract drama plays out in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/zac-lomax-eels-contract-case-lawyer-agent-storm/106284054</link><description>Parramatta has been given nine emails sent by Zac Lomax's lawyer as the case between the former Eels winger and his former club prepares to hit the courtroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6fab00ca9fdf9b673ff2ad88952bce4b</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: BAFTA nominations, a new cricket captain and departing pandas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/weekly-news-quiz-january-30/106282664</link><description>Think you've been paying attention to the news cycle?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fda808678e7347ad9a8a5250a0565d7d</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government urged to use careful diplomacy to defuse Darwin Port row with China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/farmers-urge-careful-diplomacy-in-darwin-port-row-with-china/106288346</link><description>Industry groups that suffered three years of damaging Chinese trade tariffs on products including barley are appealing to the federal government to exercise careful diplomacy to defuse tensions with China over the ownership of Darwin Port.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d329f53011599b0e1e704d744857ffe</guid></item><item><title>Catherine O'Hara from Home Alone and Schitt's Creek dies aged 71</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/catherine-o-hara-from-home-alone-and-schitts-creek-dies-aged-71/106290662</link><description>The Canadian-born actress died at her home in Los Angeles at the age of 71 "following a brief illness", according to a statement from her agency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cec17b0e9c8d5e5c57455b7b63492832</guid></item><item><title>Push for retailers to play role in 3D-printed gun crackdown after Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/3d-guns-retailers-and-the-bondi-aftermath/106286252</link><description>Hardware stores would report customers suspected of building 3D-printed guns to the authorities under fresh calls for corporate Australia to play a role in thwarting access to the deadly weapons</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c6ac0fc6d7819fd48f5e27a930359de</guid></item><item><title>Ensay's annual Mountain Calf Sale moved to Bairnsdale for animal welfare</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/ensay-mountain-calf-sale-moved-bairnsdale-due-to-animal-welfare/106286930</link><description>The tiny Victorian town of Ensay has proudly hosted the annual mountain calf sale for decades, but the yards will be empty this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0862129768c2c7973f043a1b434c3fe</guid></item><item><title>Beckham saga is an age-old heartache with an uncomfortably modern twist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/virginia-trioli-template/106252054</link><description>Cutting ties with your parents isn't a new phenomenon but having it painstakingly documented across social media is a contemporary problem.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab0df9a75b077d3b19090787e9d7ff93</guid></item><item><title>The tide takes away his work each day, but learning to let go has transformed this artist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/sand-art-helps-surfer-connect-community-gold-coast/106214956</link><description>Mal Leckie has spent every morning over the past 50 years at the beach, but when illness hurt his ability to surf, he had to find a new reason to get out of bed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e0faa4b4547e6aea40cd6eb9ea1f00c</guid></item><item><title>Fruit tree netting installations to increase over next decade as heatwaves persist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/heatwaves-mean-netting-installations-for-fruit-crops-to-increase/106278420</link><description>Sales of netting to protect fruit crops from extreme weather have increased in the past five years as researchers warn heatwaves will continue to impact agriculture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">687d8d67030a8be834892249633a7b71</guid></item><item><title>Outback racing officials salute world's oldest bookmaker, Doug Carroll, after death at 100</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/world-oldest-bookmaker-doug-carroll-dies-100-australia/106282718</link><description>Former Broken Hill bookmaker and likely the world's oldest has died at the age of 100. Doug Carroll worked at multiple race meetings across outback New South Wales over the decades, before finishing up at 98.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80429aad564b30380bad1b09347b855d</guid></item><item><title>Woman hospitalised after Juniper prescribes weight-loss drugs her GP refused</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/woman-hospitalised-telehealth-provider-weight-loss-drugs-juniper/106273356</link><description>Claire Munch says she was hospitalised with an eating disorder after a telehealth provider approved weight-loss drugs her GP had refused — and that even after she complained, she was later sent marketing promotions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a297fd29d6c11e941d169586df4c0075</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan claims T20 World Cup warm-up series with 90-run thrashing of Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/pakistan-thrashes-australia-in-t20-world-cup-warm-up/106291668</link><description>Pakistan thrashes Australia by 90 runs to claim an unassailable 2-0 series lead in the T20 World Cup warm-up series in Lahore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">170a571b206b8fe09583c919f03cba70</guid></item><item><title>New Epstein documents reveal details about his friendship with former prince Andrew</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/new-documents-reveal-details-about-epstein-andrew-friendship/106292352</link><description>The royal family faces a fresh round of embarrassment after the latest tranche of Epstein files reveal unsavoury details about the convicted sex offender's relationship with Andrew.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca64175170556e6cb019b6bb50476993</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan spinner Usman Tariq dismisses Australia's Cameron Green's gesture about his action in second T20I</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/pakistan-spinner-usman-tariq-dismisses-cameron-green-gesture/106293176</link><description>Pakistan spinner Usman Tariq responds after Cameron Green appeared to mimic his action in Australia's comprehensive T20 loss in Lahore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d15be44ae0c50a4f29a58f43967333e5</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic praises Carlos Alcaraz after Spaniard wins first Australian Open title</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/australian-open-carlos-alcaraz-novak-djokovic-final/106293372</link><description>Despite the hollow feeling of defeat, 24-time major winner Novak Djokovic heaps praise on Carlos Alcaraz following the Spaniard's history-making Australian Open victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87c4c2aa20dbeaeb5ed2b49f3037427b</guid></item><item><title>ASX swept into global sell-off as gold miners tumble on precious metals rout — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/106293384</link><description>The ASX has had its biggest fall since November, led by hefty falls for gold miners as the precious metals rout continued. See how the session unfolded plus insights from our business reporters on the ABC News markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e561e3a7a16f4de986faea6e878f480</guid></item><item><title>Mary Fowler returns to the pitch as Manchester City hammer Chelsea in Women's Super League</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/mary-fowler-returns-for-manchester-city-wsl/106294082</link><description>Matildas star Mary Fowler returns to football after a nine-and-a-half-month injury lay-off, as Manchester City thumps Chelsea in the Women's Super League.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6fddfef04c27a8081d5b0c66234c26b0</guid></item><item><title>Rescued cygnets released back into the wild</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/rescued-cygnets-released-back-into-the-wild-/106293172</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">000dddad5b22b87f6a73cd761e52491d</guid></item><item><title>Dalai Lama's Grammy win slammed as 'anti-China' by Chinese government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/china-says-dalai-lama-grammy-win-anti-china/106297758</link><description>The 90-year-old, who lives in exile from his Tibetan homeland, says he accepts the award with "gratitude and humility" but it has sparked a furious response from China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e426129bd0771d848581ce4d4df41338</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Ferguson called Epstein a 'legend', told him to 'just marry me', new emails show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/fergie-emails-epstein-files-legend/106297980</link><description>The former Duchess of York's friendship with the late sex offender is back in the spotlight after the latest release of documents about the Epstein case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e97603600426faf0b2647f43f40bee8</guid></item><item><title>How decluttering your digital streaming subscriptions can save you money this year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/how-decluttering-your-digital-subscriptions-can-save-you-money/106294296</link><description>With Australian households now holding an average of 3.7 digital entertainment subscriptions each, doing an audit on what you're using and whether it's providing value can be a good place to start when looking to cut costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c13fa3915e6c9c3a59644cc8b377541</guid></item><item><title>Amber Wraith's parents say medical professionals dismissed her suicidal thoughts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/amber-wraiths-parents-say-suicidal-thoughts-downplayed-dismissed/106213582</link><description>A hospital has apologised to the parents of 19-year-old Amber Wraith, who took her own life in 2022. Her family hopes her death will prompt changes in the way mental health patients are treated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2a360c9e244c2fecc308c79af403c7b</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroo Island's sea lions.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/kangaroo-island-s-sea-lions/106152240</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6da9b03c3506f606888829ac56721a3</guid></item><item><title>Sita Walker's debut novel, In a Common Hour, takes place across a single hour at a state high school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/sita-walker-author-in-a-common-hour/106272552</link><description>Sita Walker, an English teacher from Brisbane, explains how she tackled her first work of fiction, set in a single hour at a state high school.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04fa39d46b8cdc0621342a7ae8b5a249</guid></item><item><title>Aussie dollar climbs as RBA raises rates and leaves door open to more hikes — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/asx-markets-business-live-news-03feb-2026/106298200</link><description>The Reserve Bank has hiked the cash rate 0.25 percentage points to 3.85 per cent, in its first rate rise in more than two years. The Aussie dollar rose back above 70 US cents after the decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b42f830cea274bb82911f5597fb674b0</guid></item><item><title>Behind the music of hit Australian indie game Hollow Knight: Silksong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/christopher-larkin-hollow-knight-silksong-music-at-acmi/106127840</link><description>The video game soundtrack will be performed live for the first time by Orchestra Victoria at ACMI in February.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56a776d3a39c7522f7d9a4501e65808a</guid></item><item><title>NT to introduce strongest penalty for domestic violence murder in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/nt-government-increases-non-parole-dv-murder-life-sentence-jail/106298466</link><description>Domestic violence killers in the Northern Territory are set to serve longer prison sentences without parole than others charged with murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">125be98a2433ae5ef325c08b7627540a</guid></item><item><title>Teachers in NSW schools face sack for hate speech in classrooms, premier says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/hate-speech-crackdown-in-nsw-schools-chris-minns/106299244</link><description>Teachers or school staff found to have breached bolstered NSW hate speech laws face tough sanctions, including the possibility of being fired.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60a12fc172920c4c7bc302f26bccc97f</guid></item><item><title>Major potato company Zerella plans NT expansion with proposed Katherine seed farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/potato-company-zerella-plans-nt-katherine-expansion/106296502</link><description>Potatoes have not been grown in the Northern Territory at commercial scale for many years but could change if a planned seed potato venture goes ahead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7f85bf9c4ee325502a9239ed174836a</guid></item><item><title>RBA lifts interest rates by 0.25pc as inflation rises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/reserve-bank-lifts-interest-rates-february-2026/106298696</link><description>RBA lifts interest rates by 0.25 per cent, to 3.85 per cent, after inflation rose "materially" in the second half of 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42f190caa823d3fb1803e159ff505609</guid></item><item><title>Federal parliament condemns attempted bombing at Perth/Boorloo Invasion Day rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/lidia-thorpe-motion-invasion-day-alleged-bomb-attack-parliament/106298440</link><description>Federal parliament officially condemns the attempted bomb attack at Perth's Invasion Day rally on its first sitting day, acknowledging the harm caused to the First Nations community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0103b72fa857b451dd3fc06e27901fd9</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Mardi Gras pulls plug on party weeks out from parade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/nsw-sydney-mardis-gras-party-axed-financial-loss/106301046</link><description>Chief executive of the Sydney Gay and Lesbian Mardi Gras, Jesse Matheson, announced the post-parade celebration will not go ahead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0da779dd70ea8a433ef837cd0fafc67e</guid></item><item><title>Austin Appelbee speaks after 'superhuman' swim off Quindalup to save family in Geographe Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/teen-speaks-after-saving-family-in-geographe-bay/106298798</link><description>A WA mother says asking her teenage son to swim 4 kilometres through rough seas to get help after their family was swept out to sea, was "one of the hardest decisions" she has ever made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">498dc56b9b0ded2fcee4d47f8ec5eafd</guid></item><item><title>Luxury Gnarabup Development granted approval by WA Environment Minister Matthew Swinbourn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/gnarabup-development-approved-wa-environment-minister/106302028</link><description>A controversial $138 million luxury resort slated for construction in WA's South West is given a long-anticipated green light by the state's environment minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">318352032ebe8695184f63153a2a55b4</guid></item><item><title>Son of Norway's crown princess tells rape trial sex was consensual</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/son-norway-crown-princess/106302292</link><description>Marius Borg Høiby pleads not guilty to four counts of rape and one of domestic violence but guilty to a count of offensive sexual behaviour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">402ea0fa721a64c5ff0edc7185b3003e</guid></item><item><title>Officers find signs of forced entry at home of TV host Savannah Guthrie's mother</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/signs-of-forced-entry-at-savannah-guthrie-mother-nancys-home/106302442</link><description>Investigators reportedly found evidence of a deliberate night-time kidnapping at the property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fb195a998af869580b598a9415c06df</guid></item><item><title>How to know if you're experiencing PTSD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/how-to-know-if-you-are-experiencing-ptsd-symptoms/106287082</link><description>Louise was experiencing nightmares for five years before being diagnosed with post-traumatic stress disorder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93d1325bb199373e4f1bf9b01b5f6fff</guid></item><item><title>What the Epstein files tell us about Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's 'car crash' 2019 interview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/epstein-files-shed-more-light-on-mountbatten-windsor-interview/106302294</link><description>Documents released last week have shed more light on what the former prince might have been lying about in that fateful sit-down with the BBC's flagship current affairs program, Newsnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6779dc32f34e97d931db509a2116209a</guid></item><item><title>Otways residents burnt out of their 'paradise' determined to rebuild home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/gellibrand-residents-plan-rebuild-after-otways-bushfire/106298822</link><description>The Cochrane family has called the Otways home for more than four decades. Even after fires destroyed their property, they do not plan to move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ac632500ce00dd1d79fb0abb32dfde6</guid></item><item><title>Dr Karl's How Things Work quiz: How much do you really know about guitars?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/dr-karl-how-things-works-guitar-quiz/106087196</link><description>From shaping to tuning — how much do you know about how an acoustic guitar is made?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fb9bed30875263bd1cde77dae2ff4de</guid></item><item><title>Forestry industry sounds alarm over 'cheap' timber imports landing in Australia and threatening jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/cheap-timber-imports-into-australia-threatening-jobs-forestry-sa/106277274</link><description>Imported timber is coming into Australia at nearly half the price of domestically manufactured products and is increasingly being used in local homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a52aa70cb7c741f4282a0f544e25a26</guid></item><item><title>Survival expert praises WA family's calm decision-making during miracle Geographe Bay rescue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/survival-expert-praises-teen-family-geographe-bay-rescue/106301816</link><description>"Outback Mike" Atkinson says the Appelbee family's ability to stay calm and make smart decisions was critical to their survival after they were swept out to sea off Geographe Bay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f435077eb20063df3172c768b75873f3</guid></item><item><title>Randa Abdel-Fattah to appear at one-off Adelaide literary festival Constellations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/randa-abdel-fattah-to-attend-adelaide-writers-event/106302864</link><description>Palestinian Australian author, lawyer and activist Randa Abdel-Fattah will be appearing at the one-off literary event created to fill the void left by the cancellation of this year's Adelaide Writers' Week, organisers have announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4904fed8fc7c1243585bf6ff6358a34</guid></item><item><title>Art exhibitions to see this summer, from Ron Mueck to Hobart Current and Olafur Eliasson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/art-exhibitions-ron-mueck-hobart-current-olafur-eliasson/106295866</link><description>From Aussie expat Ron Mueck's hyper-realistic sculptures and Icelandic Danish artist Olafur Eliasson's thought-provoking installations to the best contemporary artists in Tasmania, here are three exhibitions to see.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">298caa8ff84eba3f4959fca7878c20aa</guid></item><item><title>Ski racing event planned for SA's Lake Bonney cancelled amid permit requirement issues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/ski-racing-event-lake-bonney-riverland-cancelled-south-australia/106299936</link><description>A ski racing event which was advertised to go ahead this weekend in South Australia's Riverland has been cancelled by organisers at the 11th hour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c44b894be0dea3861ce04aea29b8fd9</guid></item><item><title>Police lecture teen caught driving 189km/h on Sunshine Motorway at midnight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/police-teen-midnight-189kmh-sunshine-motorway-mountain-creek/106304564</link><description>The teenager on his P-plates was pulled over by police along a Sunshine Coast motorway driving at almost 200km/h.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">472c3c0a3258dde9fc72c9927268faec</guid></item><item><title>Former deputy Liberal leader Sam Groth quits Victorian parliament, triggering Nepean by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/sam-groth-quits-victorian-parliament-nepean-by-election/106304976</link><description>Retired tennis star and former deputy Liberal leader Sam Groth will quit Victorian parliament next week, about a month after announcing he would not contest November's state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d29850448a7da913aecd9ebf4c2c8f66</guid></item><item><title>Northern Territory mum wrangles Humpty Doo crocodile near Arnhem Highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/nt-mum-helps-wrangle-crocodile-humpty-doo-bottle-shop-arnhem-hwy/106303792</link><description>Melody Wehipeihana was dropping her kids off at school when she pulled over to see what a crowd had gathered to look at in a puddle outside a Northern Territory pub.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3391dee89a5e7c013bfaf9e4aeb786b7</guid></item><item><title>Scammers staged a fake AFP set in a Cambodian compound. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/fake-afp-office-scam-centre-cambodia/106303328</link><description>A fake AFP office staged by scammers who operated from a Cambodian scam centre reveals much about their tactics, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23bc847ad2e5565c35a14e7b47e8d707</guid></item><item><title>FOI documents reveal how Anika Wells's New York trip costs escalated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/foi-docs-show-details-of-anika-wells-new-york-trip/106305526</link><description>The final New York travel bill for Communications Minister Anika Wells and her staffer rose $7,000 from an initial booking due to last-minute changes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96ba52c6d67a0db4813ff41da47a6fa5</guid></item><item><title>Raymond Reddington's trial told wife Sharon Fulton was murdered for insurance money</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/sharon-fulton-murder-raymond-reddington-trial/106305196</link><description>Raymond Reddington failed to report his wife missing for several days, changed his story multiple times and wrote a fake confession letter to the state coroner, a Perth court hears.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c73e0387be31319c0a408c07b2cc2f2</guid></item><item><title>Austin Appelbee's incredible tale of survival has made international headlines. How did the 13yo do it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/austin-appelbee-13yo-boy-swims-to-shore-to-save-family-australia/106301468</link><description>Austin Appelbee, 13, has made international headlines after swimming for four hours in rough seas to save his mum, sister and brother stranded in the ocean. How did he do it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">178c976d4aeb49f1fcb20f8290878d75</guid></item><item><title>Australia announces Jakara Anthony, Matt Graham as 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics flag bearers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/australia-announces-2026-winter-olympics-flag-bearers/106306688</link><description>Jakara Anthony and Matt Graham have been named as flag bearers for the 2026 Winter Olympic Games in Milano Cortina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dd17f2d42429c1b56d68a37e9849f4c</guid></item><item><title>Ryan Routh sentenced to life in prison for attempted assassination of Donald Trump on Florida golf course</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/ryan-routh-given-life-sentence-for-attempted-trump-assassination/106307006</link><description>Ryan Routh will spend the rest of his life behind bars for his 2024 assassination attempt on the then US presidential hopeful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75ae6551ab5fe840df0155638e8254e7</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania trials school collaborations to boost students' results under education reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/tasmania-trials-new-education-reform-modelled-off-uk/106304340</link><description>As Tasmanian students return to school today, three primary schools will kick off a nation-leading trial the government hopes will stop the state's education system lagging behind the rest of the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e52af1e7ff400461e202eddd0cda7a8</guid></item><item><title>Psychiatrist of Westfield Bondi Junction attacker referred for review by coroner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/bondi-junction-westfield-stabbing-coronial-inquest-findings/106294950</link><description>Findings from the coronial inquest into the Westfield Bondi Junction stabbing have been handed down, almost two years on from the attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">babc262080a5894c153088a2849da980</guid></item><item><title>In Zak Hilditch's horror movie We Bury the Dead, the zombie apocalypse devastates Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/we-bury-the-dead-movie-interview-zak-hilditch/106298866</link><description>These Final Hours writer and director Zak Hilditch drew on personal tragedy to produce We Bury the Dead, his biggest cinematic epic yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f08c892351946b5092876fe0022699c</guid></item><item><title>Thousands left in limbo as National Rental Affordability Scheme comes to an end this year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/national-rental-affordability-scheme-housing-stress/106281856</link><description>Vulnerable and elderly residents in homes subsidised by the National Rental Affordability Scheme are staring down decade-long waitlists for social housing as the scheme draws to a close.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42e3d4712914e1e27958a7e2f656315f</guid></item><item><title>Authorities say Appelbee family's rescue highlights unexpected dangers in WA's South West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/geographe-bay-water-safety-austin-appelbee/106306336</link><description>Marine Rescue workers tasked with monitoring WA's Geographe Bay say last week's astonishing rescue of a Perth family highlights the dangers facing tourists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13e4bb920220ee89906831f1827453fb</guid></item><item><title>Police launch investigation into sudden death in Toowoomba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/police-launch-investigation-into-sudden-death-in-toowoomba/106307100</link><description>Police have closed part of Bell Street and the Toowoomba bus terminal car park on Chronicle Lane in Toowoomba's CBD as part of the investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b8806170d7bec631fc6c26704d033eb</guid></item><item><title>Homeless Whitsunday boaties begin long rebuild after Tropical Cyclone Koji carnage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/homeless-sailors-tropical-cyclone-koji-aftermath/106304140</link><description>Around a dozen boats recovered by Marine Safety Queensland were part-time or permanent liveaboard boats, with boaties in the Whitsundays facing a long journey to find a new permanent home on or off the water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbed372baa692d7226e9b5fc59f9157c</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump, gold, interest rates and AI data centres to dominate company reporting season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/donald-trump-gold-interest-rates-ai-reporting-season/106306266</link><description>Australia's mining sector is expected to lead the earnings charge for this reporting season, boosted by signs of a stabilisation in the Chinese economy and a turbo-charged commodities market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56354f78af37bcda67f3e92d68cb1d7b</guid></item><item><title>Lockhart River Mayor Wayne William Butcher pleads guilty to Cairns bail breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/lockhart-river-mayor-wayne-william-butcher-bail-breach/106309858</link><description>A Far North Queensland mayor has pleaded guilty to two counts of breaching his bail conditions after he was found drinking tea in a casino with a person he must avoid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d25d211015b67c4f5a1d5efb7ea9fda9</guid></item><item><title>NSW government contacts Newcastle Writers Festival about author Randa Abdel-Fattah's inclusion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/nsw-government-newcastle-writers-festival-randa-abdel-fattah/106310270</link><description>The NSW government makes contact with the board of next month's Newcastle Writers Festival about the inclusion of Palestinian-Australian author Randa Abdel-Fattah, the ABC understands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f89720cdcf51ab246cbcc55ed24f0196</guid></item><item><title>How capital gains tax changes could impact you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/how-capital-gains-tax-changes-could-impact-you/106309066</link><description>According to a well-sourced leak, changes to capital gains tax discounts could form the centrepiece of the next federal budget in May. And while the government has downplayed the idea, it has not been ruled out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">566800855cbc95596fa22fe075eeef0e</guid></item><item><title>Man convicted of grooming one girl and raping another at Canberra Reptile Zoo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/man-convicted-sexual-assault-girls-canberra-reptile-zoo/106310784</link><description>A 26-year-old man has been convicted in the ACT Supreme Court of sexually assaulting two girls at Canberra Reptile Zoo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33ab35ad4d2b0b48e7630e638b33075e</guid></item><item><title>Nationals issue Ley with reunion counteroffer as deadline looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/nationals-issue-ley-with-reunion-counteroffer/106311354</link><description>The minor party has given the opposition leader terms that one Nationals MP said they did "not expect" would be acceptable in what has been described as a bid to push out her self-imposed deadline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ad11d81c208265b1abb07a42b719062</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Junction inquest saw recommendation for supported housing for homeless, some are already benefitting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/bondi-junction-stabbing-inquest-habilis-mental-health-housing/106309484</link><description>An inquest into the Bondi Junction stabbing has recommended that the NSW government support long-term accommodation for homeless people experiencing mental health issues. It's a model that is already finding success.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a81fc4ebb5907745acfeae2e974efbeb</guid></item><item><title>Porsches, Maserati allegedly stolen from Melbourne homes during overnight crime spree</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/luxury-cars-stolen-melbourne-victoria-police/106311510</link><description>Four young men are charged after allegedly stealing three luxury vehicles from homes across Melbourne on Thursday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17e9e07691648c70fb20f7e7cf67d7a2</guid></item><item><title>New study reveals how stressful footy fandom can be</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/study-reveals-how-stressful-footy-fandom-is/106310960</link><description>A new study reveals how much high-stakes sporting events can get the heart pumping by strapping trackers to over 200 German football fans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c31f01f9ec961ff01d3df42c41faafef</guid></item><item><title>Russia and Ukraine conduct POW swap after latest US-led peace talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/ukraine-russia-talks-united-states-trump/106312078</link><description>The Kremlin says it sees progress and positive movement in the talks, brokered by the United States, as Donald Trump urges both sides to reach a peace deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0de94a61b88dd48205673f167c316711</guid></item><item><title>Epstein files reveal the men who looked away after women had spoken up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/jeffrey-epstein-files-allegations-melinda-gates/106308164</link><description>The millions of pages of documents related to the late convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein have shone a light on how many influential men were ready to disregard the experiences of countless women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40d57aedebb5b5169d68dfe86d5517cc</guid></item><item><title>Country Fire Authority volunteers speak out about aging firefighting fleets, volunteer shortages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/victoria-country-fire-authority-facing-uncertain-future/106306632</link><description>Volunteer firefighters battling blazes that razed homes and destroyed livestock in Victoria last month say they contended with failing radios and broken down trucks, as questions mount over the viability of the Country Fire Authority.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1939e2b9e0384eb4bf0efffe062d9060</guid></item><item><title>Positive spin from Liberal leader as retiring MP Sam Groth forces Nepean by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/member-for-nepean-sam-groth-resignation-analysis/106309684</link><description>When retiring first-term Liberal Sam Groth told his leader he was quitting politics, forcing a by-election, Jess Wilson didn't try to talk him out of it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d064ed909c98a4fe8b1620483b07061</guid></item><item><title>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese to sign security treaty with Indonesia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/pm-to-sign-security-treaty-with-indonesia/106311374</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is in Jakarta to sign the treaty, which the Australian government calls the "biggest step" the countries have taken together in 30 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">542b9e5f54b180e31559e9247cbd743e</guid></item><item><title>Former attorney-general Mark Dreyfus warned anti-corruption chief to 'manage' or 'avoid' conflicts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/mark-dreyfus-warned-anti-corruption-chief-to-avoid-conflicts/106311478</link><description>A letter from Mark Dreyfus to Paul Brereton provides new insight into the expectations set for the inaugural chief of the anti-corruption watchdog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e67d41ae94005c162be09aa4254b2e2</guid></item><item><title>Jim Chalmers's appetite for economic reform is about to be tested</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/jim-chalmers-inflation-interest-rates-economy-federal-budget/106294832</link><description>Jim Chalmers could face his biggest test yet as treasurer over the next few months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a3a90492a5e83271ed0e7dfbd2089e3</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: When does it start, what sports are there and who is competing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/winter-olympics-milano-cortina-2026-when-where/106188146</link><description>Australia is tipped for enormous success over the next couple of weeks so now might be a good time to clue yourself up. Here's everything you need to know about the 2026 Winter Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a93b24614f2e1ae879ffc8503e731c6</guid></item><item><title>An ex-jihadi and terror experts agree on one thing about extremism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/bondi-terror-attack-radicalisation-islamic-state-group/106300484</link><description>As police probe what led to the deadliest terror attack on Australian soil in December, radicalisation researchers and a former Islamic State group supporter have shed light on how people are recruited.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5cd14c9f76f47554b7f5454f0088c8a</guid></item><item><title>Satellite images reveal build-up of US fighter jets and missile defences ahead of US-Iran nuclear talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/us-military-escalation-iran-middle-east-nuclear-talks-satellite/106309628</link><description>Ahead of planned nuclear talks between the United States and Iran, satellite imagery reveals how the US is positioning itself for potential military escalation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed602ad892f5d9ee098d6c3222a26202</guid></item><item><title>World Anti-Doping Agency bosses 'will look at' claims of penis enlargement in ski jumping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/wada-will-investigate-ski-jumper-penis-enlargement-allegations/106311706</link><description>The World Anti-Doping Agency will investigate bizarre claims in German newspaper Bild that ski jumpers are injecting substances into their penises to aid aerodynamics — and other stories from the Winter Olympics a day out from the opening ceremony.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84586ef0f66b1f30261a833dd26efe85</guid></item><item><title>Racehorse owner charged after gelding found dead on Maryborough property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/city-limits-racehorse-maryborough-racing-nsw-rspca/106281308</link><description>A six-year-old gelding had career winnings of $90,000 before it was found dead on a central Victorian property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bae863fc6c32c02435974a492897f96d</guid></item><item><title>US hopes to challenge China's critical minerals dominance with new trading bloc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/us-pitches-new-critical-minerals-trading-bloc/106309202</link><description>The US is urging dozens of countries to follow Australia's lead and sign on to a plan to stop relying on China for the critical minerals used in modern technology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4c34d4de059770202fdc288ddc3883b</guid></item><item><title>After the ICE shooting of Renee Nicole Good in Minneapolis, a week of chaos unfolds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/renee-nicole-good-minneapolis-ice-shooting-timeline/106283054</link><description>Renee Good and her wife moved to Minneapolis "to make a better life" with their six-year-old son. But just over two minutes into an encounter with ICE agents she was fatally shot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e825dd4bb27569e03b8e78c060ecdeb</guid></item><item><title>State coroner recommends NSW government adopt Escape. Hide. Tell awareness campaign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/bondi-junction-stabbing-inquest-findings-armed-offender-campaign/106309276</link><description>The recommendation was one of 23 handed down on Thursday as part of the Bondi Junction stabbing inquest findings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c01cf5da170857f715bee4dd03b54267</guid></item><item><title>What Israel's President Isaac Herzog has said about Gaza, and why he won't be arrested in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/herzog-will-be-aware-controversy-wont-be-arrested-in-australia/106311734</link><description>When Israel's president lands in Australia this weekend, he can expect an official red carpet treatment. But he will be all too aware of the controversy his visit is generating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ffdecd9e59cf515e239536238754ac7</guid></item><item><title>ATO debt continues to drive record level of calls to small business financial helpline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/debts-to-ato-drive-record-level-of-financial-helpline-calls/106308516</link><description>Financial counsellors say small businesses struggling to pay debts owed to the tax office are driving calls to Australia's Small Business Debt Helpline higher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5e7106c0d32cd232b4538e4271760e1</guid></item><item><title>Mark Parton admits negotiations for a Greens and Liberals coalition were 'very serious'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/parton-admit-negotiations-greens-liberals-coalition-very-serious/106311088</link><description>The leader of the Canberra Liberals has confirmed for the first time that talks with the ACT Greens about forming a coalition to unseat the ACT Labor government were "very serious".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ea0c53bae867582b596c309e271e137</guid></item><item><title>Two young sisters die in hospital days after fire ripped through their Townsville home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/townsville-housefire-fatal-sisters-died-in-hospital/106312218</link><description>Two children die in hospital after a fire ripped through a Queensland home earlier this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66f700459e25e048e2ab7a18d1fd627b</guid></item><item><title>Savannah Guthrie's missing mother is 'still out there,' police say, but no suspects</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/samantha-guthrie-today-mother-still-out-there-police-say/106312206</link><description>US investigators believe the missing mother of Today show host Savannah Guthrie is "still out there" despite having no proof she is still alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3f661ed6f3ea9b584959ea3221e64d7</guid></item><item><title>Voters in David Littleproud's seat of Maranoa weigh in amid Coalition split, One Nation surge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/david-littleproud-seat-of-maranoa-weigh-coalition-split/106305146</link><description>As One Nation announces its plan to open an office in Longreach, the ABC speaks to voters in David Littleproud's electorate to get their thoughts on the Nationals leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78476b785e998ff817539d1db814fbeb</guid></item><item><title>Live: Jane Hume says Liberals can go it alone without Nationals, One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/federal-politics-live/106310298</link><description>Liberal senator Jane Hume says her party can go at it alone without joining forces with the Nationals or One Nation. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6336bed62f747957f082b887d6fdb45f</guid></item><item><title>Man flown to hospital with burns after assault at Bacchus Marsh property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/man-burnt-in-assault-at-bacchus-marsh/106312170</link><description>Detectives from the Arson and Explosives Squad are investigating an assault that left a man critically injured with burns at Bacchus Marsh.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37f1a471c808b219764bff2d38c7bb36</guid></item><item><title>Outback mayor says Queensland government is building homes on flood-prone land</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/burketown-public-housing-built-flooding-state-government/106156964</link><description>Locals, the council and a Queensland MP are questioning the wisdom of a Queensland government plan to build dwellings in an area of Burketown known to flood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">621e11bf41da1f76434fbedaed51eafc</guid></item><item><title>The fisheries minister defends WA's controversial fish ban.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/the-fisheries-minister-defends-the-controversial-ban-/106311508</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">024b9dfcd90ad3a3ac46c40b9f4c8d04</guid></item><item><title>When is the Super Bowl 2026? Here's what to know about American football's biggest game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/super-bowl-how-to-watch-australia-2026/106272636</link><description>Here's everything you need to know about the Super Bowl, including when it will start, how to watch, and who you'll see on the stage at half-time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbcbeb645bbc7b6ddc8463474dbb5762</guid></item><item><title>Pharmacy apologises after customers given wrong medicines, scripts in Broome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/pharmacy-customers-detail-wrong-medicines-and-scripts-in-broome/106308810</link><description>More than a dozen customers have come forward over concerns two Broome chemists have handed out the wrong medications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f538e97e2b860296b05ed825dc97371</guid></item><item><title>NSW chief justice criticises Tony Abbott's comments on Sydney Harbour Bridge protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/judge-andrew-bell-criticises-tony-abbott-gaza-protest-comments/106308690</link><description>The former prime minister said it should not be for judges to decide when a political protest was justified, which are remarks NSW's top judge called "regrettable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98ab6cec7508f3de2ac09cc3f44222b3</guid></item><item><title>Queensland man to face court after allegedly threatening federal politicians on social media</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/qld-man-beenleigh-court-allegedly-threatening-politicians/106312368</link><description>Police allege the 39-year-old posted threatening messages to parliamentarians on X in December.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5e2767dac1662f2799f1039aa304fe9</guid></item><item><title>Magnetic fields, psychedelics and ketamine helping to treat the brain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/mental-health-facility-offers-ketamine-psilocybin-treatments/106090572</link><description>A Queensland not-for-profit mental health clinic that delivers novel therapies such as ketamine and psilocybin is expanding its services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">777a273bd12425d8facfba3249d6e2a9</guid></item><item><title>Nearly 70 people rescued from New York ski mountain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/nearly-70-people-rescued-from-new-york-ski-mountain-gondolas/106312400</link><description>Rescuers have saved nearly 70 skiers who were stranded for hours, with some trapped up to 21 metres in the air, after a gondola malfunction in New York.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">261f6081b37000bb87f9f8c9e7dbfaa1</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri defends McLaren and says he expects 'fair shot' at F1 title in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/oscar-piastri-defends-mclaren-expects-fair-shot-at-f1-title/106312458</link><description>Oscar Piastri insists the painful ending to his F1 title bid last season has only strengthened his resolve to be the "nice person" who brings the Formula 1 world drivers' crown back to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f69e6d4d4fe6ae4def48a780606469e8</guid></item><item><title>US-Russia nuclear weapons treaty expires as Trump rejects Moscow's one-year extension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/us-russia-nuclear-weapons-treaty-expires/106312346</link><description>The last remaining nuclear arms pact between Russia and the United States has expired after Donald Trump rejected an offer from his Russian counterpart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d429e07a7e5037ed4a467628e59a2d3b</guid></item><item><title>Jason Steinberg describes visiting the site of the Bondi terror attack.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/jason-steinberg-bondi-attack/106310750</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c9f0d7aa45caf3d8a81ec94b1a17881</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Jewish leader wants stronger crackdown on symbols, flags, and slogans in wake of Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/qld-jewish-board-of-deputies-bondi-attack-antisemitism/106310388</link><description>Queensland Jewish Board of Deputies president Jason Steinberg has called on the state government to ramp up anti-hate laws in the wake of last year's Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">657fe1e021667e15565d5bcf8e958757</guid></item><item><title>Louvre releases photos of squashed crown abandoned by jewel heist gang</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/louvre-heist-empress-eugenie-crown-to-be-restored/106312526</link><description>The thieves who robbed the famed Paris museum last October dropped the diamond and emerald-studded crown as they escaped, leaving it crushed and broken.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80c91de186b4aa4f509ce7c72582cf12</guid></item></channel></rss>