<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 15:49:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>New Zealand coach Stacey Jones calls for greater scrutiny of warm-ups as NRL continues probe into Eliesa Katoa incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/rugby-league-stacey-jones-eliesa-katoa-warm-ups-scrutiny/105976068</link><description>New Zealand coach Stacey Jones says his thoughts are with Eliesa Katoa as he prepares his side to take on Samoa in the final of the Pacific Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1c60b917a6b66b573f077d0cf70324c</guid></item><item><title>Logan City Council commissions independent review into flood map modelling after receiving thousands of complaints</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/qld-logan-city-council-flood-modelling-independent-review/105974734</link><description>A south-east Queensland council has commissioned an independent review of its flood zone mapping modelling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6af7b2511dd5d2498d6e6027b7afb5d</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105975122</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e91d0465be4ab338c89eeb1fe81826c2</guid></item><item><title>Perth Football League's suspension of Osborne Park FC a 'line in the sand' moment, says league boss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/perth-football-league-osborne-park-ban-line-in-sand/105975548</link><description>The boss of the Perth Football League urges clubs to treat the suspension of Osborne Park FC over an end-of-season costume stunt as a "line in the sand moment" for their culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d14c5720caea0299a7ea4e19c1fa4a2c</guid></item><item><title>One in 10 homes bought using first home buyers guarantee in October</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/one-in-10-homes-bought-using-government-incentive-in-october/105976010</link><description>About one in 10 homes sold last month were bought by Australians using Labor's expanded 5 per cent deposit scheme to enter the market for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">105390b5913544e9cb6aac68340591e5</guid></item><item><title>Danielle North leaves Ambulance Victoria executive role after parliamentary inquiry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/victoria-ambulance-danielle-north-covid-funerals/105974020</link><description>Executive director Danielle North has departed Ambulance Victoria, after the service said she may have misled a parliamentary committee about her knowledge of gatherings during COVID lockdowns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85051c441df0330f241c97cf81bf1f76</guid></item><item><title>Evidence concludes in murder trial of man who fatally stabbed his wife in NT remote community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/steven-john-murder-trial-nt-supreme-court-evidence-concludes/105974990</link><description>Evidence has concluded in the three-day murder trial of a man who fatally stabbed his wife following an argument in a Northern Territory remote community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4023f63c6519c03625e8ce595d7fb081</guid></item><item><title>Japan deploys troops to the northern town of Kazuno to trap bears after record wave of attacks and deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/japan-bears/105976502</link><description>In September, the government relaxed gun rules to make it easier for hunters to shoot bears in urban areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea9232eba3986ac940dcc01dca20642f</guid></item><item><title>Five injured after driver rams car into pedestrians and cyclists in France</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/10-injured-driver-rams-car-into-pedestrians-cyclists-oleron/105976562</link><description>A prosecutor has said a 35-year-old man deliberately rammed his car into pedestrians and cyclists on the French island of Oleron.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f953057e54ca923052b741438026e383</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine and Russia locked in intense clash over key strategic city of Pokrovsk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/ukraine-and-russia-clash-in-pokrovsk-strategic-city/105976672</link><description>Moscow says it is making advances in the key city, which it says would allow Russian forces to claim more territory in Ukraine's eastern Donbas region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff832ca5fdcd517e53e31fb69fab57bb</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested after groping Mexican president Claudia Sheinbaum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/man-arrested-after-groping-mexican-president/105976744</link><description>Claudia Sheinbaum says her government will review the country's laws on sexual harassment, saying she has filed a complaint to stand up for other Mexican women who are not in positions of power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0da601ce6cf0adff9eb7fe78165663de</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley's net zero problem won't only impact the Coalition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/coalition-net-zero-energy-labor-sussan-ley-thin-ice/105965502</link><description>If, as expected, the net zero target is abandoned, the long delay in reaching this point will leave the Liberals looking like they've capitulated once again to the Nationals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2e607eecea9396eefa4c5ba767b7bd9</guid></item><item><title>Launceston General Hospital air-conditioning upgrades won't be complete for summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/air-conditioning-delayed-results-in-hot-temps-for-patients/105964806</link><description>Exhaust fans from patient bathrooms at Launceston General Hospital are being used to instead suck in cold air from the air-conditioned corridors, documents obtained under Right to Information laws show, as summer approaches again without crucial cooling upgrades being complete.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3420cd17a73b5ff187adf9dd6c8a3afa</guid></item><item><title>Artificial intelligence, therapy and education: How AI is reshaping our lives whether we like it or not</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/artificial-intelligence-rise-australia-readers-concerns/105861182</link><description>We asked readers if they had thoughts or concerns about the rise of AI. This is what they told us.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5990ae1c1c1cb564c80d90272b32ae0</guid></item><item><title>AI is changing jobs fast — and Australians are beginning to wonder how they’ll stay relevant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/workers-face-career-change-ai-technology/105926750</link><description>AI's rapid uptake in Australian workplaces has many workers asking how they can stay relevant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7beaa4878a0d8fa04e57c73fcfcf8632</guid></item><item><title>Secret WA government report casts doubt on claims domestic gas will help other countries in energy transition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/wa-government-gas-industry-energy-transition-deloitte-report/105970038</link><description>A secret report undermines the WA government's claim that domestic gas production is helping the rest of the world decarbonise, while the state's own greenhouse gas emissions rise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98e0108e91777c9ddfa5b797bb1c12bc</guid></item><item><title>Builders face daunting mission to boost housing supply despite 'green shoots'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/builders-how-to-solve-housing-crisis-construction-industry/105950578</link><description>The building industry is reporting a lift in approvals and new home sales, but says planning delays and skilled labour shortages are holding back construction, amid calls to unlock higher density development.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abde6ce9d71b731de8c6f3148a2538ab</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Festival 2026 line-up includes Hot Chip, The Crown star Khalid Abdalla and a The Smiths cabaret</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/sydney-festival-2026-kris-nelson-hot-chip-khalid-abdalla/105922318</link><description>The 50th anniversary of Sydney Festival — and the first from new artistic director Kris Nelson — features a mix of Australian and international artists taking over spaces across the city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee019987000001eeb35bcdab0ce7aa24</guid></item><item><title>Free buses and child care part of Zohran Mamdani's planned socialist overhaul of New York City</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/zohran-mamdani-new-york-city-mayor-policies-explainer/105970926</link><description>New York City's newly elected mayor Zohran Mamdani is promising to make people's lives cheaper, but even some of his supporters are sceptical about whether he can deliver.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">460d32093b8f9be4c0b1616b93774b91</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian town of Longford urges authorities to find source of mystery stink</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/longford-smell-odour-pongford-tasmania-epa-sewage-abattoir/105966730</link><description>Authorities say $38 million has been spent trying to stop this town from stinking, but residents say they are still being forced indoors, put off meals and subjected to humiliating jokes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8254afb59669ac96315bf2e8f6be1bb5</guid></item><item><title>Latrobe Valley manufacturer pivots from coal to wind as region braces for energy shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/gippsland-renewable-energy-local-jobs-offshore-wind/105919426</link><description>As major offshore wind developers wait for an auction process in Victoria to begin, work is already underway to ensure Gippsland's long energy legacy translates into new opportunities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12ec0e78eb55090de5a3e912718897fc</guid></item><item><title>What is the new species detected in SA's algal bloom?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/new-species-detected-in-algal-bloom-explained/105973280</link><description>New research awaiting peer review has provided a few revelations about the make-up of South Australia's algal bloom, with a new predominant species — Karenia cristata — identified by scientists. Here's what we know so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d242cb8692a6a254497f3c200df8db9</guid></item><item><title>Doctors at Northern Beaches Hospital issue warning over loss of private beds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/northern-beaches-hospital-doctors-warning-private-beds/105975904</link><description>Medical staff at Northern Beaches Hospital say a potential loss of private beds could mean less expertise, fewer services and more travel for patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0cdced0c93d7626ad29045e776969cc</guid></item><item><title>Queensland breeder says she 'would have apologised' if buyers told her of dogs' health issues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/qld-puppy-buyers-allege-breeder-sold-dogs-with-health-issues/105974618</link><description>A Queensland dog breeder has been accused of selling puppies with broken teeth, gunky eyes, lice and hookworms, years after being fined for failing to care for animals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26875446a4005e5a2be5a9582b8fa99c</guid></item><item><title>Young men rejecting 'cookie-cutter' masculinity but many still feel pressure to act tough, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/young-men-masculinity-adolescent-man-box-study/105970962</link><description>Many young men are rejecting the "Herculean cookie-cutter mould" of masculinity, but a new report warns boys who hold rigid views are suffering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af12d37436d70df244dcae3497a09f50</guid></item><item><title>Venus Williams's Auckland Classic entry sparks hope of Australian Open appearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/venus-williams-aims-for-another-australian-open-appearance/105976852</link><description>Venus Williams is to start her 33rd straight season in women's tennis at the Auckland Classic, with another Australian Open appearance for the 45-year-old now a possibility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a84d0232bb6179da5afcd97218afbc87</guid></item><item><title>Owner of seven cats modifies home to keep them away from wildlife</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/cat-owner-creates-enclosure-to-keep-animals-safe/105951784</link><description>Tim Bestwick has modified his northern NSW so his beloved seven cats do not spoil his other passion, bird watching.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84b2ee3ea37cf9411b656b80cd8da07e</guid></item><item><title>Jess Jonassen keen for Australia recall as Brisbane Heat skipper nears WBBL milestone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/jess-jonassen-keen-for-australia-recall-wbbl/105976812</link><description>Jess Jonassen is not holding her breath for an Australian recall, but the Brisbane Heat captain believes she can still contribute at the international level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfcaafd6aaa5457a1a4f7a4d542a9795</guid></item><item><title>Build townhouses to lower rents and house prices, Grattan Institute report says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/three-storey-city-zoning-property-rental-price-grattan-report/105975946</link><description>Rents and house prices would be 12 per cent lower than otherwise within a decade if all capital cities are rezoned to allow three-storey buildings, a report finds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db4a0066fbb266cd8c8a5b5f6c1089f9</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: PM unveils official portrait of Bob Katter — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/federal-politics-live-blog-nov-6/105975894</link><description>Anthony Albanese unveils an official portrait of Bob Katter to commemorate his more than 50 years of service to Queensland and federal parliaments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a0f63cbc42b241e78d52d88dc0b2f19</guid></item><item><title>Image of stranded humpback whale wins Ocean Photographer of the Year award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/ocean-photographer-of-the-year-winners-2025-craig-parry/105976036</link><description>Craig Parry is used to capturing beautiful photographs of the ocean at its best, but this heartbreaking image won him a prestigious Ocean Photographer of the Year award.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b0bd7575bed965871c1434042cd9617</guid></item><item><title>Doctor heard about $600k Julia Creek job from truck-driving brother, not from viral campaign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/julia-creek-outback-doctor-gp-job-600k-hired/105501740</link><description>Julia Creek welcomes a rural Australian GP after running a viral job campaign and receiving 95 applications from across the globe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c72a7d69f8579d8f7ae23a24e43639d</guid></item><item><title>Family of Australian man accused of cocaine smuggling speak ahead of possible Bali death sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/australian-man-lamar-ahchee-family-speaks-to-abc-news-in-bali/105974682</link><description>The sister of Australian man Lamar Ahchee, who has been on trial on drug charges in Bali, describes the moment she heard the news of his arrest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">271d268e1f515e85a72bb2001ee899e1</guid></item><item><title>Millions are going unpaid and hungry as the US federal government shutdown breaks records</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/us-federal-government-shutdown-data/105965562</link><description>The ongoing federal government shutdown has surpassed the record for the longest in US history, leaving thousands of workers without pay. Here are some of the key numbers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9046281db4ecb4a0fbeb7b27f517f64b</guid></item><item><title>Isaah Yeo returns as Kangaroos look for Rugby League Ashes clean sweep in Leeds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/isaah-yeo-returns-as-kangaroos-rugby-league-ashes-third-test/105976876</link><description>Isaah Yeo is back after concussion but, with the Ashes series already won, Kangaroos coach Kevin Walters has still opted against changes for the last Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdbf04925f197ceefad46a311336ea0f</guid></item><item><title>UPS plane death toll rises, authorities say engine fell off before crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/ups-cargo-plane-crash-investigations-data-recorders-recovered/105976950</link><description>Louisville Mayor Craig Greenberg has confirmed the death toll has risen to at least 12, with several people still missing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5e1b0377c01a52fb6a96296fd1298cc</guid></item><item><title>Who could benefit most from free power hours under Labor's proposed Solar Sharer scheme?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/solar-sharer-scheme-free-power-electricity-who-benefits/105973232</link><description>The federal government wants to introduce a retail offering that gives people in certain states free electricity in the middle of the day, but one expert fears there could be hidden costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">662ff5de9afe452fcc3bedbff6492d87</guid></item><item><title>Spud King expands business with $14 million South West orchard investment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/tony-galati-group-buys-apple-avacado-orchards/105973692</link><description>WA's "Spud King" Tony Galati has expanded his empire with a $14 million bid to purchase two South West orchards which will see his business move into apples and avocados.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1472c01a66d95d1cba6cf7782ecf5855</guid></item><item><title>Microsoft to refund customers for 365 subscription price hike after ACCC action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/microsoft-to-refund-customers-for-365-subscription-price-hike/105977094</link><description>Microsoft apologises to customers and says it will refund them, after the consumer watchdog alleged the tech giant misled about 2.7 million Australians over subscription costs so they would remain on more expensive plans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ff6ead53e7a3a71017bdb325ebc306b</guid></item><item><title>Man suffers stab wounds during citizens' arrest of knife-wielding man in Melbourne's CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/melbourne-cbd-stabbing-arrest/105977238</link><description>Two bystanders have helped detain a man who was allegedly seen wielding a knife and behaving erratically in Melbourne's CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">813a6c0176c91ed26d1057e086f95e2d</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios aims to play Australian Open after 'miracle' knee recovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/nick-kyrgios-aims-to-play-australian-open-after-knee-recovery/105977346</link><description>A revitalised Nick Kyrgios has revealed his shock plans to make a summer comeback and hopefully play the Australian Open in January.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d505be6541d69a67266950d3c53aff3</guid></item><item><title>Australia captain Pat Cummins says he is still trying to keep the second Ashes Test as a 'live option'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/pat-cummins-feeling-good-for-gabba-test-but-rest-may-be-needed/105977454</link><description>Pat Cummins says his return to bowling has gone better than expected, with Australia's captain still eyeing off a return for the second Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebd5056092829c69de1c407ff84d2579</guid></item><item><title>Norway transport firm steps up controls to avert potential hacking of public transport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/norway-controls-avert-potential-hacking-of-transport/105977160</link><description>A Norwegian public transport operator is to introduce stricter security requirements and step up anti-hacking measures after a test on Chinese-made buses showed the manufacturer could remotely turn them off.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">483d04da1f64ded62167206dff308c4a</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested after allegedly crashing vehicle into Bolton Rural Fire Service building and stealing fire truck</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/man-arrested-for-stealing-fire-truck/105977008</link><description>Police say the man stole the fire truck from a Rural Fire Service garage in southern NSW and allegedly drove it with the lights and sirens on before he was stopped in Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4effcb16630bebc5bedb1336f8b5b9f9</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Swans AFLW part ways with inaugural coach Scott Gowans after missing finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/sydney-swans-inaugural-aflw-coach-scott-gowans-leaves-club/105977414</link><description>The Sydney Swans are in need of a new AFLW head coach after parting ways with Scott Gowans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09be5dd3ce2b26ec53cf598df352c9da</guid></item><item><title>'Conscious consumers' embrace of Australian goat meat presents a quality challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/conscious-consumers-drive-goat-meat-demand/105969236</link><description>Producers will have to balance consistent supply with the ethical expectations of America's "conscious consumers" as international demand for wild-caught rangeland goat meat surges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4086676422a603f55e0be2136fc9ae25</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Trains worker dead after cherry picker crashes into rail overpass in Lithgow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/bridge-collapses-after-truck-crash-lithgow-nsw/105977736</link><description>A cherry picker passenger has died after the vehicle crashed into a bridge in the NSW Central West, causing it to collapse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe165e38e127746941c198dd6d7e2a51</guid></item><item><title>WA government to buy St John of God Mount Lawley Hospital, fund major hospital upgrades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/wa-government-scrap-convention-centre-plan-buys-private-hospital/105977696</link><description>A major upgrade of the Perth Convention and Exhibition Centre is axed to help pay for three major Perth and Mandurah hospital projects under a $1.5 billion health infrastructure fund.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">109f63b6228a7145f27996cdfcd34aec</guid></item><item><title>Theatre-maker Lamine Sonko explores Senegalese cosmology in his latest show, Guewel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/guewel-lamine-sonko-theatre-senegal-cosmology/105923684</link><description>When Lamine Sonko arrived in Australia 20 years ago, audiences didn't understand his work. Now he is sharing the rituals and rhythms of Senegal with a willing crowd.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">109a463fcc2f00961a462d5bcab6f478</guid></item><item><title>NSW Health to review regional hospital security after Tamworth guard bitten</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/nsw-hospital-security-review-after-tamworth-assault/105956344</link><description>The New South Wales health minister says he intends to review security powers at regional hospitals after four guards were injured at Tamworth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72eafd83a5e64fdd97500fc9e1a5dc21</guid></item><item><title>Man suffers stab wounds during citizen's arrest in Melbourne's CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/man-suffers-stab-wounds-during-citizen-s-arrest-/105978436</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4160f4c1fb503a54eeeafd89a7c6c1ac</guid></item><item><title>Healthcare professionals accused of negligence in Diego Maradona's death to face fresh trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/football-maradona-healthcare-professionals-facing-new-trial/105978626</link><description>The seven healthcare professionals accused of negligence in the death of Argentine soccer great Diego Maradona are facing a new trial after a mistrial last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94c62df8eb238d1ee58ac593db8bef3b</guid></item><item><title>Prime minister confident social media ban will work and will empower parents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/prime-minister-says-social-media-ban-will-work/105978424</link><description>Anthony Albanese says he is confident Australia's social media age limit will be a success when it begins next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f87884cab9104c1c546e2a65f9c0105</guid></item><item><title>The potential use of fracking continues to divide West Australians, particularly in the Kimberley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/kimberley-fracking-controversy-explained/105968978</link><description>As WA's EPA assesses a proposal to drill and frack in the Kimberley's Canning Basin, groups call for WA Labor to enforce a ban across the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99d38dec5b4682adca06a646a3d9d8f2</guid></item><item><title>Jake Weatherald's route to the Australian Ashes Test squad a path less trodden</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/who-is-jake-weatherald-ashes-opening-option/105950984</link><description>Jake Weatherald could become the latest player to represent Australia in the Ashes following a superb 18 months in the Sheffield Shield. But his path to the Test squad has not been conventional.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36ec25a04bbf49543a5055b9bda18682</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder and coercive control after Claire Austin's death in Randwick unit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/claire-austin-man-randwick-death-man-arrested/105979148</link><description>The 44-year-old is charged almost seven months after Claire Austin's death in Randwick.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e2c3bde3dace9797f5e143ee9e3e735</guid></item><item><title>SA Police begin search at property 37 years after disappearance of Mount Gambier woman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/sa-cold-case-search-margaret-burnie/105978990</link><description>Major Crime Detectives have started searching a property for the remains of Mount Gambier woman Margaret Bernie, who SA Police believe was murdered almost 40 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9925d8ab85801048c467c143580df081</guid></item><item><title>Prince William joins Kylie Minogue, Shawn Mendes for green-carpeted Earthshot Prize awards in Rio de Janeiro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/prince-william-joins-kylie-minogue-at-earthshot-prize-awards/105978164</link><description>Prince William has joined Kylie Minogue and Shawn Mendes, along with a swag of world leaders and celebrities, for the annual Earthshot Prize awards in Rio de Janeiro.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">725a1fa02588aa2e7a906c46476e4cff</guid></item><item><title>RePoly defends Moss Vale plastic recycling project amid court appeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/repoly-land-environment-court-plastics-recycling-plant-appeal/105977786</link><description>RePoly accuses a Southern Highlands community group of spreading misinformation about its proposed plastic recycling plant as a campaign against the project is launched.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">233af0398f4a433f286cc8194978fd5e</guid></item><item><title>Taylor Swift sings about 'eldest daughter syndrome', but is it real?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/eldest-daughter-syndrome-explained-in-taylor-swift-song/105957100</link><description>Jess King says being the firstborn child in her family brought a weight of responsibility and she still struggles with feelings that she's "not doing enough".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">378530744ac6d8d9be2979a264c7f163</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian budget 2025 shows lower forecast state debt, few new savings measures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/tasmania-state-budget-2025-eric-abetz/105975908</link><description>Tasmanian Treasurer Eric Abetz has vowed to take "decisive action" to rein in the ballooning debt, but the "interim" state budget contains few major initiatives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d9e0dfb5a646e46ad7f1f5ff0ec2a1f</guid></item><item><title>Cassowary wandering 150km from home in Queensland's Gulf Savannah baffles residents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/mount-surprise-cassowary-sighting-baffles-outback-residents/105976574</link><description>Queensland's department of environment says it has no plans to relocate a cassowary spotted roaming the dry Gulf Savannah.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b6411ff810166264a14b873951ce30e</guid></item><item><title>Hail and heavy rain batter West Australia's Great Southern and Wheatbelt region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/wild-weather-wreaks-havoc-for-west-australian-farmers/105978410</link><description>Severe weather has swept through large parts of the Great Southern and Wheatbelt, causing significant damage to crops during the critical harvest period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab1243c2637f701d0a104525f22b5197</guid></item><item><title>World Club Challenge returns as NRL premiers Brisbane Broncos schedule clash with Super League champions Hull KR</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/world-club-challenge-brisbane-broncos-hull-kr-2026/105979980</link><description>Brisbane will take on Hull Kingston Rovers in the World Club Challenge in late February with the NRL premiers confirming the return of the showpiece event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c115a6445c0023654348a8c78dc24615</guid></item><item><title>Port Adelaide coach Josh Carr denies Warren Tredrea has been kicked out of club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/afl-port-hasnt-kicked-out-tredrea-despite-board-sacking-carr/105979702</link><description>Warren Tredrea's premiership teammate Josh Carr says he will always remain a Port Adelaide legend despite being sacked from the club's board last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecb351caf43a6cbe86052df252e47321</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide artist Peter 'Jungle' Phillips dies aged 69 in his gallery home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/adelaide-artist-jungle-phillips-dies-in-his-gallery-home/105978944</link><description>Known for his generosity and a spectacular art gallery home filled with colourful works, Peter "Jungle" Phillips is remembered by those who loved him dearly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74cd35336a1a33fe6f9e4085f9876c8e</guid></item><item><title>David Wayne Jenkins's family describe heartbreak during sentencing submissions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/george-town-murder-david-wayne-jenkins-sentencing-submissions/105978592</link><description>Family members of murder victim David Wayne Jenkins describe the anguish they felt when hearing about his death during sentencing submissions at Launceston's Supreme Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83e1e8832f6903532f03c7cc64350b91</guid></item><item><title>Katter's present comes early, Coalition stalls on net zero New Year's resolution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/bob-katter-portrait-albanese-net-zero-coalition/105965242</link><description>"There will be a corner of this Parliament House that is forever Bob Katter," the prime minister said this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c305281e43e73daab6bb1a7f19966fb</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder over fatal vehicle strike during Timber Creek brawl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/nt-timber-creek-fatal-pedestrian-strike-murder-charge/105979596</link><description>Police have charged a 21-year-old man with murder for allegedly killing another man by driving a car into him during a brawl in a remote Northern Territory town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25e6733836e322baa4dbbd073e69ae40</guid></item><item><title>Walgett councillor charged over alleged assault of female bowling club worker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/walgett-shire-councillor-alf-seaton-charged-with-assault/105979450</link><description>A Walgett Shire councillor stands down while investigations continue into an alleged assault at a bowling club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02fabb09bc528759b2c954cf09122eea</guid></item><item><title>The art of price baiting — how real estate agents lure buyers to auction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/real-estate-agents-bait-buyers-to-auction-by-underquoting-prices/105973828</link><description>To advertise a property for $1 million, knowing it must sell above $1.3 million, is illegal. It is called underquoting, and in NSW it is rife, according to data analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad152ea0bc248bbeb98993ec6a464f97</guid></item><item><title>Boyfriend welcomes coronial findings about Simone Strobel's murder 20 years ago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/simone-strobel-inquest-findings-into-lismore-murder/105950872</link><description>The findings of a coronial inquest into the death of German backpacker Simone Strobel in Lismore in 2005 have been delivered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42466c411b08a01b8d9575837309708b</guid></item><item><title>Serial rapist Graham Kay pleads guilty to sexually touching Sydney schoolgirl without consent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/graham-kay-pleads-guilty-to-sexual-touching-young-girl/105980416</link><description>Convicted rapist Graham Kay will remain in custody after sexually touching a 16-year-old girl in the Sydney CBD while on a strict supervision order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">064862d4079098783e59817c5fa86f68</guid></item><item><title>Murdered doctor's family confronts killer during plea hearings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/ashley-gordon-murder-stabbing-plea-hearing-supreme-court/105440348</link><description>The convicted killer, who cannot be named, showed no emotion as Ashley Gordon's family members confronted him one by one during a plea hearing at court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2b7886121652da0f4332118d1dd698a</guid></item><item><title>NT man Steven John found guilty of wife's murder in unanimous jury verdict</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/steven-john-found-guilty-of-dv-murder-wife-nt-supreme-court/105980258</link><description>A jury has unanimously found Steven John guilty of murdering his wife when he stabbed her in the back following a drunken argument in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19d257e41d895872f782bd3cd13479e1</guid></item><item><title>Federal government approves expansion of Victoria's largest gold mine near Bendigo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/expansion-of-victorias-biggest-gold-mine-fosterville-approved/105820838</link><description>Fosterville Gold Mine in central Victoria is approved to continue running until 2045 despite concerns from neighbours and environmental advocates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82d57c3f7c894ffb523c7212f98b01f5</guid></item><item><title>Toddler dies after vehicle accident on rural property in Abergowrie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/toddler-dies-vehicle-accident-rural-property-north-queensland/105980178</link><description>A two-year-old boy has died in an accident involving a vehicle on a rural property in north Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37ebc0f513ba883de49eddc7a90c3b90</guid></item><item><title>Liberals recalled to parliament to thrash out net zero problem</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/liberals-recalled-to-parliament-to-thrash-out-net-zero-problem/105980878</link><description>Liberal MPs will return to parliament on Wednesday to thrash out a position on the party's net zero commitment ahead of a joint party room meeting with the Nationals next Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc6311e8941c1307e54a41f449b07dc4</guid></item><item><title>Opposition parties respond to State budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/labor-greens-interim-budget-tasmania/105980702</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba0c3a760bfb926afab67c2e6f6a479b</guid></item><item><title>Canberra teenager behind bars over detailed plans for public attacks, possessing violent extremist material</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/act-teen-behind-bars-over-detailed-plans-for-public-attacks/105980252</link><description>A 17-year-old Canberra boy is behind bars after shocking allegations he developed detailed plans for public attacks and had equipment to create a bomb in his bedroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fe64fc6696ae57e2474bf3323c24da8</guid></item><item><title>Male nurse charged over alleged rape of two elderly women at Greenslopes hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/male-nurse-charged-rape-elderly-women-greenslopes-queensland/105980938</link><description>Police allege the 41-year-old committed the offences against two women in their 80s in 2020 and 2024 at a hospital in Brisbane's south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">629a56f60615894c48c61a067fd0fd71</guid></item><item><title>Anti-corruption commission watchdog inquiring into NACC chief Paul Brereton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/nacc-inspector-inquiring-brereton-complaints/105980792</link><description>The inspector of the National Anti-Corruption Commission is inquiring into the agency's head, Paul Brereton, in relation to several complaints including from a former employee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cc388dddda1b38961125058526d275c</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos not offended Hawthorn players missed Jasmine Garner's guard of honour after 100th AFLW game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/aflw-kangaroos-respond-hawthorn-garner-100th-game-snub/105981256</link><description>Hawthorn players were noticeably absent from the guard of honour for North star Jasmine Garner after her 100th AFLW game, but the reigning champs are not too fussed about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">947b1b6e8038390076adca24bebe6512</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/105980726</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce1026aaae1d4162b44c6311a14f390b</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian unions and community organisations respond to Tasmanian state budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/tasmanian-unions-and-community/105980794</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">857e60897d387a151b569d455ca811c6</guid></item><item><title>Economist Saul Eslake on Eric Abetz's first State Budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/economist-saul-eslake-on-eric-abetz-s-first-state-budget-/105980590</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1551c8f2c647e8edb76457e6fd842d90</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's state budget 'less worse' than feared but still 'dire' with enormous budget repair ahead, economists say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/economists-react-to-tasmanias-interim-budget/105977690</link><description>Independent economist Saul Eslake and Deloitte's Cedric Hodges warn there is no easy way out of Tasmania's dire budget situation, after the treasurer delivered an "interim" budget with little in the way of concrete solutions for fixing the state's debt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aff5af94eff9d323d8c92a2e95a45a57</guid></item><item><title>India beat Australia in fourth T20I by 48 runs on Gold Coast, lead series 2-1</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/cricket-australia-india-fourth-t20i-gold-coast-live-score-centre/105981170</link><description>Australia lost 9-52 as India's spinners took control in a 48-run win in the fourth T20 international on the Gold Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">722f6d4d71e8d60751df3f2d947e6fe9</guid></item><item><title>Sena needed surgery, but she couldn't understand her doctors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/calls-for-more-translators-australian-medical-industry/105981340</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41daf6331b86a7c662ce645ab1e5cbb7</guid></item><item><title>Martin Dole and Leanne Liddle unveil anti-racism plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/martin-dole-and-leanne-liddle-unveil-anti-racism-plan/105981258</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e048e32a4ebecf2c1c5a77dbe1489a52</guid></item><item><title>NT Police Force announces anti-racism action plan in bid to drive cultural change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/nt-police-announces-anti-racism-strategy-for-cultural-change/105974362</link><description>The Northern Territory Police Force has released its first anti-racism strategy for staff, following years of headlines about racist attitudes that have dogged the organisation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5834a33da566676ec93669ddd492b69</guid></item><item><title>As Russian drone incursions rattle Europe, Poland and Romania deploy a new defensive system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/drone-defence-system-poland-and-romania/105981642</link><description>The United States-built Merops system can identify drones and close in on them, using artificial intelligence to navigate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff1bfb390d76d1e1f7b5f26eef6187db</guid></item><item><title>Australia's $4 billion illicit tobacco trade has become one of the nation's most violent criminal markets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/black-market-cigarettes-cost-australia-4bn-in-one-year/105981786</link><description>Authorities stress the $4 billion figure is conservative, as it does not include illegal vapes and e-cigarettes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">358fd392575026d8d0bfb9140f325913</guid></item><item><title>German police investigate swastikas drawn in human blood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/german-police-investigate-swastikas-drawn-in-human-blood/105981882</link><description>The Nazi symbol was smeared dozens of times on cars, letter boxes and building facades, with tests confirming they were daubed in human blood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41adc70d01452049c09c2ce3b49ad188</guid></item><item><title>Typhoon Kalmaegi brings destructive winds and heavy rains to Vietnam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/typhoon-makes-landfall-in-vietnam/105981940</link><description>Typhoon Kalmaegi lashes Vietnam with fierce winds and torrential rain as it makes landfall, after leaving at least 188 people dead and 135 missing in the Philippines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">969151d8c2fd5d6cd66a0a856d0a86a8</guid></item><item><title>Louvre managers prioritised art over upgrading security in years before heist, report says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/louvre-security-flaws-years-report-finds/105982046</link><description>France's highest auditor says the theft of $157 million worth of jewels was a "deafening alarm bell" for the world-renowned Parisian museum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b9b0a8a2d754a58367472453e9a8c75</guid></item><item><title>Nancy Pelosi will not contest next US midterm elections, ending storied career</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/nancy-pelosi-announces-retirement-from-politics-us/105982126</link><description>Ms Pelosi was the first woman to serve as US speaker of the House of Representatives, and her decision will bring to an end a political career spanning four decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbd2134668961a6eda086b3c0329dc7a</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten Windsor summoned by US Congressional panel over Epstein ties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-summoned-by-us-congress-over-epstein/105982208</link><description>A US congressional panel has summoned the former British prince Andrew Mountbatten Windsor for questioning over his ties to convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce8bbed50888172fde1dcfa784d4c6ae</guid></item><item><title>Inaction on 1.5C climate change target a 'moral failure', says UN secretary-general at COP30</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/cop30-moral-guterres-climate-change/105982176</link><description>Missing from the line-up at the key summit in Brazil are the leaders of four of the world's five most-polluting economies — China, the United States, India and Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a07f6a0bb6e4029d17283697f316ce4</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian Liberals won't want to take too slow a path back to financial stability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/tasmanian-interim-budget-2025-analysis/105977734</link><description>For all the talk about avoiding slashing and burning, the Tasmanian Liberals will not want to take too slow a path back to financial stability, writes Adam Langenberg.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c616a32e46bb0d49c658968936d6c9b</guid></item><item><title>Australia's 'no fail' submarine mission set for shake-up as admiral in charge exits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/aukus-australian-submarine-agency-boss-quits/105981820</link><description>Vice Admiral Jonathan Mead's retirement will come just a year before the first US nuclear-powered submarine is due to be deployed to Western Australia in 2027 under the AUKUS agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5c9ba982dbd1ea83957bc3a7bdcc29c</guid></item><item><title>2025 among three warmest years on record, according to World Meteorological Organization</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/world-meteorological-organization-climate-report-2025/105978288</link><description>According to the global meteorological organisation, each of the past 11 years has been the warmest in 176 years of observations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cb2977efff310d29297c5ea7c8054f8</guid></item><item><title>Fashion boss Shmuel Tal to face trial over alleged violent sexual offences in Byron Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/fashion-boss-shmuel-tal-charged-with-rape-in-byron-bay/105979790</link><description>A millionaire fashion boss is banned from entering Byron Bay's party precinct as he awaits trial over violent sexual offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39d0212f0351f9768a4f4f594e3d8351</guid></item><item><title>Emerald community grieving after four people die in central Queensland house fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/emerald-community-reeling-after-four-people-die-in-house-fire/105979960</link><description>Investigators are trying to piece together the cause of a blaze in central Queensland that has left a family devastated and residents in shock.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4869f5fcc50042882bf3438ed8495173</guid></item><item><title>Carter Gordon named at flyhalf for Wallabies look to avenge Italy defeat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/carter-gordon-wallabies-fly-half-against-italy/105982282</link><description>The code-hopping Carter Gordon will be back in the starting No.10 shirt for the Wallabies against Italy in Udine as Tane Edmed reverts to the bench.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">421667137c4bd3e075b030baf7429356</guid></item><item><title>Alleged killers travelled from NSW for fatal hit on Melbourne man Athan Boursinos, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/nsw-link-to-athan-boursinos-melbourne-shooting/105982232</link><description>Police believe two men travelled to Melbourne from NSW to carry out the fatal shooting of 21-year-old Athan Boursinos in July.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6cfe7dfad8258196c99df263a140587</guid></item><item><title>Calls for more interpreters in Australian medical industry to help those falling behind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/calls-for-more-translators-in-australian-medical-industry/105978352</link><description>Sena Husic left a war-zone in Bosnia 30 years ago for Australia, and went on to suffer debilitating spinal pain because of the language barrier she struggled to overcome. Now she's finally received treatment, but there a calls for interpreters to bridge the gap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf1b2b89266e8e0e585c19938a037eca</guid></item><item><title>Former RAH electrician to receive $2.26 million asbestos cancer damages claim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/electricians-asbestos-mesothelioma-damages-payout/105966144</link><description>An electrician diagnosed with a rare asbestos-related cancer has been awarded a $2.26 million payout for exposure to toxic dust and fibres while working for various employers, including at the old Royal Adelaide Hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e9d88e80042912bf743047d0cb690e0</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of Queensland babies may have missed vital newborn blood screening tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/queensland-newborn-heel-prick-test-genetic-conditions-screening/105979844</link><description>The ABC can reveal that in July last year, Queensland Health department became aware of "inconsistencies" in records of the newborn blood spot screening program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dce3c083fc6551907134d80e0b9251f</guid></item><item><title>Muswellbrook bans dongas at renewable energy and construction project sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/muswellbrook-shire-bans-temporary-workers-accomodation/105861466</link><description>An Upper Hunter council is banning donga-style temporary work camps and demanding that developers build permanent, reusable housing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8736d6937a9ef35c446f0370cf581bd</guid></item><item><title>Queenslanders warned about 'disaster chasers' targeting storm-hit homeowners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/queensland-disaster-chasers-storm-home-warning/105979750</link><description>When three men turned up on Geoff Wilson's doorstep offering to check his roof for damage he took them up on it. But a requirement that the repairs must be done by a builder of their choice put him on alert.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">170bd10a323106fec42ec1a570fcd0bc</guid></item><item><title>Dashcam video captures moment of plane explosion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/dashcam-video-captures-moment-of-plane-explosion-/105982392</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a014127b31f013d77d73cb0334958ea</guid></item><item><title>Coalition climate turmoil is spreading to NSW when Mark Speakman can least afford it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/nsw-speakman-leadership-faces-new-test-over-net-zero-revolt/105976966</link><description>While Sussan Ley is pulling out all stops to survive the so-called "killing season" before Christmas, the threats to Mark Speakman's leadership are perhaps not as clear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9b42c716789d3c3cf5ee794492789b8</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur learns ATP Finals fate as Carlos Alcaraz, Novak Djokovic await</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/alex-de-minaur-learns-atp-finals-fate/105982352</link><description>Australian hope Alex de Minaur must get past world No.2 Carlos Alcaraz and 24-time grand slam winner Novak Djokovic to progress at the ATP Finals in Turin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b4b740aa7d8f7cc3f42025e57e13637</guid></item><item><title>Israel strikes several areas in southern Lebanon, says it targeted Hezbollah weapons storage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/israel-strikes-several-areas-in-southern-lebanon/105982170</link><description>The Israeli military carries out air strikes on southern Lebanon after issuing evacuation orders for several locations, saying it targeted weapons storage facilities for Hezbollah.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e78a9f52dd05e8e93efb56b76f5439c</guid></item><item><title>AI therapists don't judge, sleep or need an appointment — but experts urge it be used with caution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/australians-use-artificial-intelligence-ptsd-trauma-recovery/105946020</link><description>Artificial intelligence chatbots like ChatGPT are embedded in modern life, with some Australians using them to help work through PTSD and toxic work environments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b43e94f4a3d925501bbe637e2b4514c</guid></item><item><title>These charts show the effect of migration on Australia's housing story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/effect-of-migration-on-housing-in-several-starts/105980904</link><description>The role of migration is one of the most contentious elements to the housing debate. So what does the evidence show?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8543740585b56b408ae3d040ac180260</guid></item><item><title>NFL player Marshawn Kneeland of Dallas Cowboys dead aged 24</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/nfl-marshawn-kneeland-dead-aged-24-dallas-cowboys/105982398</link><description>The NFL is in mourning after the tragic and sudden loss of Dallas Cowboys defensive end Marshawn Kneeland, who was just 24.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fa36b309916c3ba3d69693814d15293</guid></item><item><title>Steven Miles not drawn on whether future Labor government would keep adult crime, adult time laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/queensland-steven-miles-on-adult-crime-adult-time/105980264</link><description>Former premier Steven Miles says Queenslanders have told him the issues of crime and community safety motivated them to switch their vote to the LNP at the 2024 poll.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9df880648e959f40ce5afc3ec35083ef</guid></item><item><title>Fears IDF's 'Yellow Line' splitting Gaza in two</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/fears-idf-yellow-line-creating-two-gazas/105981796</link><description>A small sense of normalcy has returned in some areas of Gaza, but other parts remain under Israeli military control, fuelling concerns the strip is being divided.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73582d1d727183bda315cc15415deb25</guid></item><item><title>ASX closes lower as Macquarie shares tumble, Tesla shareholders approve Elon Musk's trillion-dollar pay deal — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/asx-markets-business-live-news-nov-7/105981694</link><description>The Australian share market finished lower on Friday — its second consecutive weekly drop, with Macquarie shares tumbling on a disappointing earnings update.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1cb6c7aa7f3b84489f52bc0cc38a800</guid></item><item><title>Safety issues delay the reopening of six regional South Australian hospital helipads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/regional-hospital-helipads-delay-safety-issues-government-sa/105964072</link><description>Paul Logos may never know for sure if his wife's recent death could have been preventable by helipad access. Six helipads throughout regional South Australia remain closed due to issues in certifying their safety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e41031a0a9ad4474703657f20e5b6cb</guid></item><item><title>Graphic flutterer dragonfly voted 2025 ABC Australian Insect of the Year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/2025-abc-insect-of-the-year-graphic-flutterer-dragonfly/105972966</link><description>What flies like a helicopter and devours mosquitoes? Meet the 2025 ABC Australian Insect of the Year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82a33712fb583edc2607c1fd29e62127</guid></item><item><title>How AFLW pioneer Daisy Pearce is helping the next generation of female footballers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/how-the-daisy-pearce-effect-is-helping-aflw-shine/105980538</link><description>With her West Coast AFLW side on the cusp of its first finals appearance, coach Daisy Pearce reflects on the huge strides the women's game has made since her own playing days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">514fa1e5403a2cdc7d246932800dffdc</guid></item><item><title>$300-million potato chip factory approved opposite Victorian heavy mineral mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/farm-frittes-factory-opposite-heavy-mineral-mine/105978190</link><description>The Victorian government has fast-tracked a potato processing factory next to a proposed heavy mineral concentrate mine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b7fe66b9fc5dafb5abb0a8979ad1ade</guid></item><item><title>SunCable looks to Muckaty Station for solar project's proposed expansion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/nt-suncable-seeks-expansion-to-muckaty-station-solar-farm/105979824</link><description>An ambitious outback solar project backed by billionaire Mike Cannon-Brookes could soon grow even bigger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed167482908fbd833aa5f034d8b85f90</guid></item><item><title>Charles Leclerc announces engagement to Alexandra Saint Mleux ahead of Brazilian Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/charles-leclerc-announces-engagement-to-alexandra-saint-mleux/105982546</link><description>Charles Leclerc announces his engagement to Alexandra Saint Mleux as he looks to move up the driver rankings ahead of the Brazilian Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f040ea57af4516424a01a131a2ee89f9</guid></item><item><title>China agrees to import 65,000 tonnes of Australian canola after five-year lockout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/china-imports-first-australian-canola-shipment-in-five-years/105974992</link><description>China is accepting the first bulk shipment of Australian canola in five years and farmers are hoping the trial leads to a formal resumption of the trade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd1ffdc4427559986ac764bd34757455</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri says he still has what it takes to win F1 world championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/oscar-piastri-says-he-still-has-what-it-takes-to-win-f1-champ/105982570</link><description>Oscar Piastri has said he is still a serious contender for the Formula 1 world championship despite seeing his lead evaporate over the past five races.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff57cd80f16f081c606c43761fd855eb</guid></item><item><title>Worker dies after being hit by vehicle at New England Highway construction site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/man-dies-hit-by-vehicle-workplace-incident-hunter-roadwork/105982476</link><description>Just before midnight, emergency services were called to the highway at Tarro, following reports a man had been hit by a vehicle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">751d19d3529d80cd2c68c2ee0d353b30</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters extinguish brake fire on Virgin Australia plane after landing at Brisbane Airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/qld-plane-brake-fire-after-landing-brisbane-airport/105982588</link><description>Virgin Australia says all 180 passengers aboard flight VA454 were able to disembark as normal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">401b9b6f4f68a6e203b6b7ed563f881a</guid></item><item><title>Actress Pauline Collins of Shirley Valentine fame dies aged 85</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/shirley-valentine-ctress-pauline-collins-dead-at-85/105982708</link><description>Pauline Collins was adept at playing an array of roles, all of which she infused with her trademark authenticity that earned her the status of a "national sweetheart" in the UK.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29d512ce66a277e8ef1289555ba788c2</guid></item><item><title>Mount Gambier search for remains of missing woman Margaret Bernie unsuccessful</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/search-for-missing-woman-margaret-bernie-remains-unsuccessful/105982678</link><description>Police are not ruling out returning to a property near Mount Gambier where they searched yesterday for the remains of Margaret Bernie, who was last seen in the South Australian city in 1988.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcabe232d2b591b682db26c83b455018</guid></item><item><title>On November 11, 1975 I watched history being made, from the best seats in the house</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/michelle-grattan-whitlam-dismissal-november-11-1975/105965350</link><description>The main characters are dead. Some of those still around from the time maintain their rage, which has lasted through the decades, long after that election campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">877f155b72c8e81b6b8cbaeffe350c80</guid></item><item><title>Queensland considers allowing dingoes to be kept as pets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/queensland-biosecurity-changes-would-allow-dingoes-as-pets/105936892</link><description>People could be allowed to keep dingoes as pets in Queensland under proposed changes to biosecurity regulations, but experts say the native animal is fundamentally different to domestic dogs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60df5a7da837045c29c745a761a545b8</guid></item><item><title>MasterChef icon Nat Thaipun on her new cookbook THAI: Anywhere and Everywhere</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/masterchef-icon-nat-thaipun-on-her-new-cookbook/105982500</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ab0e3f4e81e5708878bc0ac0e5a2075</guid></item><item><title>NCIS stars Cote de Pablo and Michael Weatherly on their new spin off series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/ncis-stars-cote-de-pablo-and-michael-weatherly-/105978130</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2130a54a8c47116ab83322e15e4076f4</guid></item><item><title>Aussie hyper-pop royalty Ninajirachi wins 2025 Australian Music Prize</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/aussie-hyper-pop-royalty-ninajirachi-wins-australian-music-prize/105982946</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d6286a8778fc44ed847b9816ee69d9c</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos name Manchester United teen for upcoming friendlies against Venezuela and Colombia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/socceroos-name-teen-for-upcoming-friendlies-venezuela-colombia/105983334</link><description>Two crucial Socceroos return for friendlies against Venezuela and Colombia while a teen sensation is among those earning a maiden call-up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c67d8b12b6f09e8f9f1a48cdfdb56162</guid></item><item><title>Man who threw sandwich at federal agent in Washington found not guilty of assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/man-who-threw-sandwich-at-federal-agent-found-not-guilty-of-assa/105982820</link><description>Sean Charles Dunn became a symbol of resistance to Mr Trump's deployment of federal agents in the nation's capital following a viral video showing him tossing a sandwich at a Customs and Border Protection agent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00ed29b7fc6f7b84c6f3f498ec2ba5e8</guid></item><item><title>Daly Cherry-Evans leaves Manly-Warringah Sea Eagles for Sydney Roosters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/daly-cherry-evans-leaves-manly-for-roosters/105983484</link><description>Daly Cherry-Evans' decorated stint at Manly, spanning 352 games and plenty of highlights, is officially over after his move to a rival NRL club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fc70577bf63acfec6e98b1aae699f03</guid></item><item><title>What do statistics tell us about Victoria's crime wave?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/victoria-melbourne-crime-statistics-2025/105934040</link><description>As Victoria grapples with a crime wave, the ABC takes a deeper look at some of the numbers behind the rise in offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eaf5c44065cfacc2552fccd487b30615</guid></item><item><title>Youth crime funding for bail accommodation in Moree and more therapeutic services for at-risk youth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/23-million-in-state-government-funding-to-tackle-youth-crime/105982422</link><description>The NSW government funding will be used to provide more therapeutic services for young offenders, as well as more caseworkers and bail accommodation in Moree.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61d691f15e8d69825aedecaddb2a878c</guid></item><item><title>Overseas-born workers filling a void in local government while loving country life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/overseas-workers-regional-shire-staff-wa/105944266</link><description>As rural shires struggle to attract workers, a wave of overseas born professionals are stepping into the roles and celebrating all that country life has to offer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fda2b764c3ae73eae267bbf17d89a18</guid></item><item><title>Shein, Temu face more pressure after claims pleas on sex dolls were 'ignored'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/shein-and-temu-child-sex-dolls-ban-call-ignored/105972978</link><description>Temu and Shein are under increasing pressure to explain how child sex abuse dolls were sold worldwide on their multi-billion-dollar platforms following international outrage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff4a949b4e408d4f6906cc65510b6573</guid></item><item><title>US prepares for travel chaos as one in 10 flights to be cut amid shutdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/us-domestic-flight-cuts-in-government-shutdown-explained/105978408</link><description>As many as one in 10 domestic flight services are set to be cut from daily operations at 40 major US airports due to the ongoing government shutdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2b704da6c63ce26d7b7568354c6c163</guid></item><item><title>Ex-NAB employee charged over alleged $200 million bank fraud syndicate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/nsw-nab-bank-fraud-charged-bonnyrigg/105983058</link><description>Police will allege the man used his position as a bank employee to assist the syndicate in applying for approximately $10 million worth of business loans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd6f670f6517e7e872a6ae5fc181f213</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios not taking Aryna Sabalenka lightly in Battle of the Sexes clash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/nick-kyrgios-not-taking-aryna-sabalenka-lightly/105983950</link><description>Nick Kyrgios insists he won't be taking Aryna Sabalenka lightly but nor is he ready to be rolled by the women's world number-one in their Battle of the Sexes clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9651a459fee21a1de4bfb301b4f35ab3</guid></item><item><title>ACT Chief Minister Andrew Barr says succession looms but his experience still needed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/act-chief-minister-andrew-barr-stateline/105984456</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d40b96561fee9b871791a7345be239e8</guid></item><item><title>Jake Weatherald's 'pinch-yourself moment' as potential Ashes Test debut looms in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/jake-weatherald-pinch-yourself-moment-potential-test-debut/105984276</link><description>Jake Weatherald feared playing for Australia was out of reach when dropped by South Australia, but a move to Tasmania has him on the verge of a Test debut.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d3dbfe63278eccf4fae4239e0b4b1b9</guid></item><item><title>Trial date set for Bogie triple-murder accused Darryl Valroy Young</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/trial-date-set-for-darryl-valroy-young-alleged-bogie-murders/105983678</link><description>A trial date has been set for a Queensland grazier accused of shooting three people dead at a rural Queensland property in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01b0088e139a94ebff9ed96269dca11d</guid></item><item><title>Leanne Liddle speaks on the personal toll of tackling racism within the ranks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/leanne-liddle-speaks-on-the-personal-toll-of-tackling-racism/105981720</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fd20a7bcfb6239e072fdb0c26c6d071</guid></item><item><title>New NT Police anti-racism strategy to drive cultural reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/leanne-liddle-stateline-nt-police-anti-racism-strategy-reform/105976362</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17cd16e590a042703d4e822e8fe0672a</guid></item><item><title>Leanne Liddle on the importance of fairness and avoiding judgement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/leanne-liddle-on-being-fair-and-avoiding-judgement/105981718</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">339781d75806927e64662af77f68a3ab</guid></item><item><title>Leanne Liddle says chief minister's position won't influence new NT Police anti-racism strategy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/chief-minister-will-not-influence-nt-police-anti-racism-strategy/105981712</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6643c755218734a551b80282067ed714</guid></item><item><title>Architect of NT police anti-racism strategy describes 'hardest job' of her life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/nt-police-culture-racism-leanne-liddle-interview-stateline/105971332</link><description>Leanne Liddle knows what it takes to cut it as a police officer, but says tackling racism within the ranks has been her toughest assignment yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34d254c595a75d0c1d2b6613e9d10e39</guid></item><item><title>Proposed job cuts at NSW EPA alarm industry and environmental groups</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/proposed-epa-job-cuts-alarm-industry-and-environmental-groups/105982462</link><description>Conservation groups warn that proposed job cuts to the NSW Environment Protection Authority will leave the state vulnerable to waste dumping and illegal logging.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04f5f0d4a33614aec8b10f615544c966</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley refuses to bite on leadership jab, as Liberals pour cold water on spill threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/ley-leadership-speculation-liberals-cold-water/105983516</link><description>Sussan Ley has refused to bite on speculation about her leadership, after a Liberal colleague suggested she was losing the support of her party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a30736f94a86333c443950e1f1dc04d3</guid></item><item><title>Elon Musk dances with robot at Tesla shareholder meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/elon-musk-dance-with-robot/105983990</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3628c33836ad17f4f57b154655b6af50</guid></item><item><title>Robot dances on stage at Tesla 2025 annual share holder meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/robot-dance-tesla-shareholder-meeting/105983996</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff8de58943b5881fd84bbb1589c66b43</guid></item><item><title>How Elon Musk lined up a potential trillion-dollar payday as Tesla shareholders approve deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/tesla-shareholders-vote-on-elon-musk-trillion-dollar-pay-package/105977686</link><description>Shareholders at Tesla's Texas factory chanted "Elon, Elon" as they overwhelmingly approved the largest-ever CEO compensation package for the company's controversial boss.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87ef753ceac02f2a7a0c3fc7a0797751</guid></item><item><title>Child and woman die after car crash in remote Aboriginal community of Doomadgee</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/child-woman-dead-doomadgee-after-car-crash-aboriginal-community/105983714</link><description>A 30-year-old woman and a 10-year-old girl are dead and another passenger remains in intensive care in the remote Aboriginal community of Doomadgee after a serious traffic crash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa8f007dd6390885e4cc1ba985f46a31</guid></item><item><title>India's World Cup victory will be remembered as a historic turning point for women's cricket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/cricket-india-womens-world-cup-historic-turning-point-analysis/105983948</link><description>In a short period of time, women's cricket in India has travelled from uneven, dusty grounds to floodlit stadiums packed with roaring fans. The team's upset victory promises yet more investment in the women's game from the world's most fanatical cricketing nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b44d34914bbae8743c29945fb53bf40</guid></item><item><title>Michael Jackson biopic trailer released online after reported legal troubles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/michael-jackson-biopic-trailer-released/105984044</link><description>Antoine Fuqua's movie was meant to be released months ago, but was delayed twice because of reshoots and eventually pushed back to April 2026 — a whole year behind schedule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c1fff10fe96f681805afc59d5d2e59e</guid></item><item><title>School sorry for 'unacceptable' Charlie Kirk Halloween outfit allegedly worn by teacher</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/school-sorry-over-dress-up-charlie-kirk-halloween-costume/105984618</link><description>A school investigation has been launched after an Adelaide teacher allegedly dressed up as slain US conservative activist Charlie Kirk for Halloween, with the school's principal slamming the decision to wear such a costume as "completely unacceptable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">526100a815916c010f41bf2100696acb</guid></item><item><title>Pilbara man charged with running over man in swag at Robe River Rodeo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/man-charged-after-teen-run-over-pannawonica-robe-river-rodeo/105984248</link><description>Police charge a man after an investigation into an incident at a WA rodeo that left an 18-year-old with a collapsed lung and broken ribs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2abec447b4cac4c5b8c7efe7c7340ce4</guid></item><item><title>US teacher shot by six-year-old student awarded millions in damages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/us-teacher-shot-by-6yo-student-awarded-millions-in-damages/105984208</link><description>The teacher was critically wounded when the boy shot her in front of a full classroom almost three years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1af2b2bf03dd7c36e3b908856083f47</guid></item><item><title>US Supreme Court lets Donald Trump block transgender and non-binary people from choosing passport sex markers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/trump-block-transgender-nonbinary-passport-sex-markers-upheld/105984508</link><description>The US Supreme Court allows Donald Trump's administration to enforce a policy blocking transgender and non-binary people from choosing passport sex markers that align with their gender identity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b433630e12380493d8c43648ec67c316</guid></item><item><title>Internal documents show Meta is earning billions of dollars from a deluge of fraudulent ads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/meta-making-billions-from-scam-ads/105983808</link><description>Users of Facebook, Instagram and WhatsApp are exposed to fraudulent e-commerce and investment schemes, illegal online casinos, and the sale of banned medical products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06dd69d27da436a436a9a30faeca98b1</guid></item><item><title>Kai Ellice-Flint wins WSL men's longboard title in El Salvador on board he shaped himself</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/surfing-kai-ellice-flint-wins-mens-longboard-title-el-salvador/105985338</link><description>Kai Ellice-Flint joins fellow NSW Central Coast native Molly Picklum to become Australia's second world surfing champion as he wins the longboard title in El Salvador.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48913de6c0b2d77183313221701e04d4</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian farmed salmon industry granted emergency federal approval to use florfenicol antibiotic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/salmon-florfenicol-antibiotics-approved-tasmania/105983426</link><description>The industry's use of the drug is in response to an "endemic" bacterial disease that caused the deaths of up to 15,000 tonnes of salmon from January to April, resulting in dead fish material washing up on multiple beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60bcc94ef2d33d50f5f02dfc6b42ac6e</guid></item><item><title>Min Woo Lee emphatically ends rumours of a LIV Golf defection ahead of Australian summer campaign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/min-woo-lee-rejects-liv-golf-defection-rumours/105985492</link><description>Min Woo Lee will not be joining countryman Cameron Smith by defecting to LIV Golf, saying he aims to join his sister as a major champion on the PGA Tour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b5a9afee959f30e272dc4153173d1f5</guid></item><item><title>Ramping in SA at six-month low as Health Minister apologises to patient stuck outside FMC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/sa-ambulance-ramping-hours-lowest-in-six-months/105983214</link><description>SA's Health Minister has apologised to a patient who was ramped outside hospital for several hours as the government releases its ambulance ramping data for October, which is at a six-month low.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b78bf2135ba9b2df3e7210cfa6c867ea</guid></item><item><title>Readers on the grief that comes with euthanasing a dog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/readers-share-grief-pet-death-euthanasia/105950642</link><description>This is what you had to say about the heartbreak that comes with the death of a pet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e585d7b537ab0957b2f0bb70820ce1a</guid></item><item><title>Fire danger information missing from new Bureau of Meteorology website</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/fire-danger-information-missing-from-new-bom-site/105984576</link><description>As bushfire season approaches, firefighters say the BOM's redesigned website is missing crucial safety data — a gap some fire chiefs fear could put lives at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62a0f103fe824d7430e18776e05f0f3c</guid></item><item><title>Craig Robert Dale jailed for $2.77 million fraud of Aboriginal community of Warmun</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/craig-robert-dale-warmun-fraud-sentencing/104871062</link><description>Craig Robert Dale is jailed for seven years for defrauding the remote Aboriginal community of Warmun out of $2.7 million, to fuel his gambling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39c7d051dac9804f3067b26c950cb1ea</guid></item><item><title>WA Premier says upgrade to Perth Convention Centre not value for money, after plans scrapped</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/why-plans-for-perth-convention-centre-upgrade-were-scrapped-/105983466</link><description>The WA premier insists a cancelled upgrade of the Perth Convention and Exhibition Centre would not have been value for money, despite the deputy premier previously describing the building as a "cockroach".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">598d3581ebc3719708686455df720a6b</guid></item><item><title>Florida centre Olivier Rioux becomes tallest-ever college basketball player at 236cm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/basketball-olivier-rioux-college-debut-tallest-player-ever/105985666</link><description>Olivier Rioux causes pandemonium as he debuts for Florida and becomes the tallest player ever to grace the hardwood at the college level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0f966589636c336cdf4b70415e9d3e1</guid></item><item><title>Former NSW Police officer sentenced to 10 years' prison for $100,000 robbery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/nsw-police-sentenced-for-lightning-ridge-robbery-/105971126</link><description>A former police officer who travelled more than 700 kilometres to steal $100,000 from a convicted sex offender has been jailed for 10 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d306117e1fc00992589858bc912d84d</guid></item><item><title>CCTV captures Blacktown crash.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/blacktown-crash-cctv/105985868</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">331f96d42fb82b19c39f47e961ace532</guid></item><item><title>Three men critical after car mounts footpath following Blacktown crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/three-critical-blacktown-crash-mounts-footpath/105985050</link><description>Three men are in a critical condition after a car veered onto a footpath where they were standing following a collision with another vehicle in Sydney's west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">582762ece63578f5b34c2c760befe72d</guid></item><item><title>One man dead and another critically injured after brawl at Goonellabah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/one-man-dead-and-another-critically-injured-in-goonellabah/105985940</link><description>Homicide detectives are investigating the death of a man whose body was found on a walking track near Lismore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a40afddb5ccda034c9ea77f53036871</guid></item><item><title>Queensland man charged with selling stolen sheep.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/queensland-man-charged-with-selling-nearly-900-stolen-sheep/105985390</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ce747cee7d171b1a9ff0878b1a25c81</guid></item><item><title>Alleged sheep rustler charged in southern Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/southern-queensland-sheep-theft/105985558</link><description>A 69-year-old man has been charged after allegedly stealing 880 sheep and selling them through a saleyard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f0935de27f0e9505b498c0e0fe3d563</guid></item><item><title>Victorian coroner to reopen investigation into 2011 death of Louisa Ioannidis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/coronial-inquest-renewed-for-louisa-ioannidis-death-drowning/105985026</link><description>New evidence reopens a coronial investigation into the death of a 24-year-old woman whose body was found in a river in Melbourne's north in 2011.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20e1307b6c012530a1e3a85aa8850a81</guid></item><item><title>Questions raised after key election pledge TasInsure fails to appear in Tasmanian budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/tasinsure-fails-to-receive-interim-budget-funding/105983758</link><description>There were hats, jackets and a shop front, but when it came to budget day, there was no money set aside for the creation of TasInsure, which the Tasmanian Liberals promised would save households up to $250 a year during the election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">432264942f7d89e9259ca9d4c6ce513d</guid></item><item><title>Former Neighbours star Damien Richardson found guilty of public Nazi salute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/neighbours-nazi-salute-guilty-damien-richardson/105985852</link><description>Former Neighbours star Damien Richardson performed an illegal Nazi salute in public but was not intending to display loyalty to Adolf Hitler, a magistrate says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6699f60df28cc97fdbb8f5a6f325277c</guid></item><item><title>China commissions new aircraft carrier Fujian as it seeks to extend power far from its coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/china-new-aircraft-carrier-bid-to-extend-power-from-its-coast/105985988</link><description>China commissions its first home-built aircraft carrier, which experts say will help what is already the world's largest navy expand power beyond its own waters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f39d3701b6447d519ed616d57a51e34</guid></item><item><title>Former Australian captain Mark Taylor tells Sam Konstas to ditch ramp shots in bid to earn Test recall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/cricket-mark-taylor-advice-sam-konstas-ramp-shots-test-recall/105986336</link><description>The former Australian captain believes it is time for the talented opener to go back to basics as he finds himself on the outer as the Ashes begin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4309a871a57a9bff1e954defbdf58491</guid></item><item><title>Chinese-made electric buses on Australian roads spark cybersecurity concerns after Norway flags issue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/chinese-electric-buses-in-australia-spark-security-concerns/105982738</link><description>The same Chinese company that makes electric buses now under review in Denmark and Norway also has electric buses on Australian roads.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77608d57816d5695bf284b6f9cf56ba8</guid></item><item><title>Friday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/fins-frifinance-20251107/105986400</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e78a48d7370d3ad7e0bc67fb28165c8</guid></item><item><title>Father-of-five sentenced to life behind bars for stabbing murder of wife in remote NT community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/steven-john-sentenced-to-life-in-prison-for-dv-stabbing-murder/105984232</link><description>In sentencing the man to life behind bars on Friday, the Northern Territory Supreme Court's highest judge described the victim's death as a "profound tragedy".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d5f2fb9e67e5a4d7462a432335f1754</guid></item><item><title>Elena Anita Begovic pleads guilty to negligent driving causing death of Marshall Oakley-Stagg</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/elena-anita-begovic-guilty-plea-crash-cosgrove-high-school/105983934</link><description>Marshall Oakley-Stagg died after being struck by a car outside in Hobart's northern suburbs last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24e443f116f8e96765a56a37339f8640</guid></item><item><title>Queensland teachers to hold statewide rallies but stop short of announcing strike date</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/queensland-teachers-strike-action-planned-no-date/105976976</link><description>The Queensland Teachers' Union says after-school rallies will be held across the state next Thursday in the wake of its rejection of a state government pay offer last month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ccd27e90b08c5913e57c2414ff4482c</guid></item><item><title>India's top court says Air India crash report does not insinuate anything against pilot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/air-india-crash-preliminary-report/105986486</link><description>The latest preliminary report on an Air India crash that killed 260 people in June does not insinuate anything against the captain, India's top court says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce1055847812a5795f7a1c4d1070e60d</guid></item><item><title>Perth man charged with sending sexualised messages to '14-year-old boy' then meeting at shopping centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/perth-man-charged-over-sexualised-messages-to-teens/105983648</link><description>A 31-year-old Riverton man appears in court after allegedly sending sexualised messages to two teenagers pretending to be a 14-year-old boy and then arranging to meet in Perth's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2f2106d73eab3e03d4be32dbd109d0a</guid></item><item><title>Compromise on WA's GST deal not an option, Treasurer Rita Saffioti says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/wa-government-offers-no-compromise-on-gst-deal/105986398</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c70f2551a227c4686691e4666b9e90d6</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos defeat Hawks by 39 points in first AFLW qualifying final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/kangaroos-defeat-hawks-aflw-qualifying-final/105986600</link><description>North Melbourne registers its 25th consecutive win with a 39-point drubbing of Hawthorn in the first AFLW qualifying final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20e0b0150b9dfebf0a497d96ff59493b</guid></item><item><title>Blasts injure dozens at Indonesian mosque, student suspected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/blasts-injure-dozens-at-indonesian-mosque-student-suspected/105986730</link><description>A 17-year-old student from an adjacent school is being investigated by Indonesian police after explosions injured 55 people on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b092c938db1f6b3bd6dc5b814b314e0</guid></item><item><title>Polish woman found guilty of harassing Maddie McCann's parents, but acquitted for stalking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/mccann-stalker-found/105986732</link><description>Prosecutors said there was "unequivocal scientific evidence" Julia Wandelt had no familial link to the McCanns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fad2f32ad56cbdbd304609a07eee6df5</guid></item></channel></rss>