<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 09:52:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Update your ABC News homepage for more local stories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2020-09-03/update-to-abc-news-homepage/12579988</link><description>We've got an ABC News homepage for you. Adjust your settings for the right mix of local and national news.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">146f1699ce6b1b7420a91b6bb80d0309</guid></item><item><title>Having eating disorder clinics available could be the difference between life and death for Shania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2020-10-18/eating-disorder-treatment-in-wa-hard-to-access-over-16/12772004</link><description>Shania Nicholls should be hanging out with friends and preparing for university, but an eating disorder is robbing her of a normal teenage life — and to compound the pain, getting access to proper treatment is almost impossible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">272f7e88c5af5bf0b8cf817bd31c842e</guid></item><item><title>Tour de France cyclist Jonas Abrahamsen gains 20kg to become king of the mountain leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-07-06/tour-de-france-cyclist-gains-20kg-to-become-king-of-the-mountain/104066914</link><description>Obsessed with being as light as possible, Tour de France cyclist Jonas Abrahamsen went to extreme lengths to stay skinny. He's since put on 20kg of weight and is cycling better than ever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85fca1abc0e42f1b2320e65440ffab9f</guid></item><item><title>Small businesses repurpose historic South Australian churches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-01-05/historic-church-restoration-small-businesses-south-australia/104735274</link><description>Old churches are being transformed into shops, cafes, accommodation and breweries in South Australia, where small business owners are putting their heart and soul into preserving a part of history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">810b223241b51e4c8b197b0e5ea8a70a</guid></item><item><title>Have Your Say: What was the issue, policy or event that decided your vote?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-02-26/federal-election-your-say/104788518</link><description>After a five-week campaign, the results are in with Labor returned to government. Is there a policy or issue that swayed your vote? Have Your Say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">320dfcbec9cd8fe02e449407ce78e618</guid></item><item><title>Voters tell ABC's Your Say they want politicians with a vision, not bickering</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-13/abc-your-say-federal-election-politicians-with-vision/105164874</link><description>Voters tell ABC's Your Say campaign they want courage and vision from politicians, not bickering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">033ddce5ad54070fbce620dc6760d9ba</guid></item><item><title>Push for seniors' dental scheme grows ahead of federal election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-13/aged-care-dental-scheme-australia-federal-election/105149782</link><description>Imagine living in aged care and not having your teeth or dentures properly cleaned and checked each day. That's a risk faced by elderly Australians, prompting calls for the next federal government to boost oral health training and services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36d312d336a36247fd1c01e78814112b</guid></item><item><title>Australians tell ABC's Your Say they are struggling more than ever with housing costs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-15/abc-your-say-federal-election-2025-housing-policies/105175180</link><description>Voters tell ABC's Your Say campaign they are struggling more than ever with housing costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54451646ec8e9f100cc2fe59fc9c08c5</guid></item><item><title>Trump administration slammed by judge for doing 'nothing' to retrieve man wrongly deported to El Salvador</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-16/kilmar-abrego-garcia-deportation-el-salvador-court/105181198</link><description>A judge who ruled that Kilmar Abrego Garcia was wrongfully deported to El Salvador last month has slammed the Trump administration for doing "nothing" to facilitate his return.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f9f3e971d8167b99725a09ab48a724</guid></item><item><title>Graduates in 'debt vortex' as HECS front and centre for first time in an election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-16/federal-election-2025-hecs-student-debt-policies/105177248</link><description>New research shows a sharp rise in HECS debts, despite graduate earning power declining, as student loans become a potent election issue for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48707ffafbe02c400b1200e6269fd40e</guid></item><item><title>Housing advocates seek federal funding election promise for co-op model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-17/housing-cooperative-solution-proposed-for-rental-crisis/105108816</link><description>Advocates admit co-operative housing models are not for everyone but say for the right residents, they offer more security and affordable pricing than traditional rentals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3608b0c1ae56f5a5b36968898f65df5e</guid></item><item><title>Next-generation voters call for better engagement ahead of federal election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-18/federal-election-rural-next-generation-voters/105173450</link><description>Young people in Albury say issues that directly affect them and their communities are not being addressed by major parties for the 2025 election campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ae182892b8c9591cd9ec35e6e57fcb9</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne seat of Calwell highlights Labor woes as Gaza pain galvanises Muslim voters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-20/calwell-labor-backlash-over-gaza-islamophobia/104850500</link><description>Dissatisfaction with the Albanese government's stance on Israel-Palestine among many Arab and Muslim voters threatens to unseat Labor MPs, in some places for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63e7f9854fee5bc20e54ee2f5bd136f4</guid></item><item><title>Energy projects in South West WA threaten votes for major federal parties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-21/energy-projects-south-west-wa-federal-election-labor-liberals/105152524</link><description>Australia's two major parties have tied their federal election fates to controversial energy projects in WA's South West where the issues have polarised voters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8962a53de05f0293b3a104690022111a</guid></item><item><title>Tiwi Islanders eager to have their say as remote voting for the federal election begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-22/early-voting-starts-in-remote-communities-tiwi-islands-aec/105201318</link><description>Voters in the small remote community of Pirlangimpi on the Tiwi Islands, north of Darwin, have become some of the first to cast their votes for the federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0c419fe3ae44debe7edf27241c0e5c1</guid></item><item><title>Mobile coverage is an election issue in regional areas. What's been promised?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-23/telecommunications-mobile-coverage-federal-election-promises/105080674</link><description>For many regional and remote Australians, reliable mobile coverage can be life-saving. They are desperate for both sides of politics to take meaningful action towards eliminating black spots.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ceda72e552d98e5f293d3c037efeefa</guid></item><item><title>Health, climate and community sport: What older voters in the Tasmanian seat of Bass are talking about this election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-29/health-climate-sport-election-older-voters-bass-tasmania/105224138</link><description>The federal seat of Bass is held by a margin of just 1.4 per cent. For these older voters who live in the electorate, health, climate and community sport are the issues that will decide their vote.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a3579db910b5a7ee8e11d2618bf798f</guid></item><item><title>Anglican diocese seeks to sell property to pay child sex abuse claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-19/anglican-diocese-restructure-to-pay-child-sex-abuse-victims/105273092</link><description>The Anglican Diocese of North Queensland is on the brink of financial collapse as it struggles to pay millions in compensation to victims of historic child sexual abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23e2ec582cbf2e292dd9fd9525fdf01c</guid></item><item><title>From Formula 1 to creating the 'world's best' croissant, how baking saved Lune founder Kate Reid's life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/cars-to-croissants-kate-reid-and-the-lune-empire/105750472</link><description>Kate Reid's Lune croissants have been called the world's best. But how did a young woman struggling with a near-fatal eating disorder end up perfecting pastry?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d09b350f758690100795053d1425df1</guid></item><item><title>Labor has pivoted from health to housing. How will SA voters respond?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/labor-pivots-from-health-to-housing-ahead-of-sa-election/105938990</link><description>If Labor’s 2022 campaign was all about ambulance patients locked out of hospitals, then 2026 is all about young people locked out of home ownership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f26c47e1d6e839ea1aeaf57064be0a4</guid></item><item><title>Albury's Macquarie Textiles celebrated for decades of manufacturing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/alburys-rich-wool-and-textile-history-celebrated-in-exhibition/105958750</link><description>Textile manufacturing took Albury's work to the Opera House, federal parliament, the Olympics and beyond.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e79d3a3fce1ccbf4621429603303d231</guid></item><item><title>Super Netball could grow to 10 teams as Netball Australia invites licence bids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/super-netball-could-grow-to-10-teams-by-2027/106077068</link><description>Super Netball could have two additional teams by 2027, with Netball Australia calling for expressions of interest to expand the competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f51d1aadcd45af0382e9a8ea5524b8e</guid></item><item><title>ASIO examined Bondi Beach gunman Naveed Akram in 2019 for close ties to Islamic State cell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-beach-attack-gunmen-father-and-son/106142630</link><description>Australia's domestic intelligence agency, ASIO, examined one of the Bondi Beach gunmen six years ago for his close ties to a Sydney-based Islamic State terrorism cell, the ABC understands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61d8702038585ef6be9d3817b6662640</guid></item><item><title>Bondi terrorists travelled to Philippines for 'military-style training', security sources say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-gunmen-went-to-philippines-for-military-style-training/106148662</link><description>Father-son gunmen Sajid and Naveed Akram travelled to the Philippines to receive "military-style training" in the month before they killed 15 people at a Hanukkah celebration at Bondi Beach, security sources have confirmed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52edb6122488935f51e540d7c1ade39e</guid></item><item><title>WA farming community loses 500 sheep, thousands of hectares of crops in fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/western-australian-farming-community-loses-500-sheep-in-fires/106153256</link><description>A bushfire emergency in Warradarge is over, but farmers say the work to recover what was lost has only just begun.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80cdd9268fb9fd905e22ffb4920dd350</guid></item><item><title>The 'Golden Dome' and why Trump wants the defence system in Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/why-trump-wants-golden-dome-missile-defence-in-greenland/106255982</link><description>Donald Trump wants a US "Golden Dome" missile defence system to be built in Greenland. This is what it involves and why some experts are skeptical of the plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7283312beb72caebfa691b8786b889d2</guid></item><item><title>Second illegal foreign fishing boat spotted in Torres Strait waters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/second-illegal-foreign-fishing-boat-spotted-torres-strait/106256490</link><description>A Torres Strait resident has flown a drone out to capture images of a second foreign fishing boat spotted in Australia's northern waters, just days after Australian Border Force officials intercepted a boat that almost reached the mainland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">262e539bdf7ccaa8facf56250fa1090a</guid></item><item><title>David Speirs not entitled to public campaign funding, electoral commission says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/david-speirs-not-entitled-to-campaign-funding-commission-says/106252588</link><description>Former opposition leader David Speirs would "not fulfil the nomination requirements" if he applied to be a candidate at the upcoming state election, the state's electoral commission says, raising significant doubts about his chances of a political comeback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b51d1258f01f889f9ffa8d09f9b01925</guid></item><item><title>How Olympian Michael Klim reinvented himself and his definition of success after muscle-wasting disease CIDP</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/reinvention-of-olympic-swimmer-michael-klim/106098230</link><description>Olympian Michael Klim forged his reputation on strength and athleticism. But after being blindsided by an incurable muscle-wasting disease, he was forced to reinvent himself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3913461b6ef8196fe3dae0375b59dd8</guid></item><item><title>Four teenage boys credited with saving three swept out by rip at Tasmanian beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/teenagers-save-swimmers-in-distress-blackmans-bay-tasmania/106292754</link><description>Police have praised the efforts of four teenage boys who helped three other young people swept out by a rip at a Tasmanian beach, with a dad saying his son was probably "30 seconds from drowning".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47f1f57e76ae795efc0d049febe2f680</guid></item><item><title>Australian woman killed in ski lift accident at popular snow resort in Japan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/australian-woman-killed-in-ski-lift-accident-in-japan/106295672</link><description>Police in Japan confirmed to ABC News the woman’s name is Brooke Day, from Queensland's Sunshine Coast, who was taking a lift at the Tsugaike Mountain Resort when she became caught and suffered critical injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1c35785da8d7211c080f4cd9346f02a</guid></item><item><title>Cory Bernardi to contest SA state election for One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/cory-bernardi-to-lead-one-nation-sa-state-election/106297448</link><description>Former federal Liberal senator Cory Bernardi will lead One Nation's Legislative Council ticket at the upcoming state election in South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82327f03ddfe8f054bc1364e0c41712e</guid></item><item><title>Trump's failure to extend nuclear treaty leaves door 'wide open' to arms race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/start-treaty-russia-america-donald-trump-nuclear-arms-race/106303426</link><description>The last remaining nuclear arms pact between the United States and Russia has come to an end at a time of global instability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc3f69c281ddb28c7f975bb1833daccc</guid></item><item><title>Magnetic fields, psychedelics and ketamine helping to treat the brain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/mental-health-facility-offers-ketamine-psilocybin-treatments/106090572</link><description>A Queensland not-for-profit mental health clinic that delivers novel therapies such as ketamine and psilocybin is expanding its services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">777a273bd12425d8facfba3249d6e2a9</guid></item><item><title>Elders say truth-telling 'critical' to combatting racism after alleged terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/perth-first-nations-elders-call-for-truth-healing-and-justice/106314644</link><description>For Noongar Elders, the alleged attack on Boorloo/Perth is viewed against the background of a long history of violence. They are calling for a truth-telling commission to heal deep scars and help to combat racism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5a4e6692d897a27ad96d0fecbf58894</guid></item><item><title>Leo Howard's family pays tribute after three men died in light plane crash near Goolwa South</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/three-men-died-in-light-plane-crash-off-sa-coast/106316980</link><description>One of three people who died in a light plane crash south of Adelaide has been identified as an experienced pilot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dfcf45ccd0ecee92f936a26fe8aa6f0</guid></item><item><title>3 Doors Down frontman Brad Arnold dies after stage four cancer battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/3-doors-down-frontman-brad-arnold-dies/106318798</link><description>Brad Arnold, a founder and the lead singer of American rock band 3 Doors Down, dies nine months after revealing he had kidney cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cbbceb57b53ce8d7ad340e98b862894</guid></item><item><title>Extreme heat returning for south-east Queensland before weekend showers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/queensland-weather-heat-showers/106319132</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology is forecasting "locally severe heatwave conditions" from Tuesday, culminating in a maximum of 35 degrees in Brisbane on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b30ddf4d4ab44e838d7d574f7e1be3ec</guid></item><item><title>Kimberley cotton hits record high in first season with new processing gin in Kununurra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/kimberley-growers-wrap-up-first-season-processing-cotton-locally/106303718</link><description>From farm to fabric, West Australian cotton growers are finally able to grow, process and export record amounts of cotton locally.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">463c2f3636108857669737fceede0d6c</guid></item><item><title>Native title holders take appeal over one of Australia's largest groundwater licences to High Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nt-high-court-singleton-station-aboriginal-groundwater-rights/106322626</link><description>The cultural value of water will be front and centre in the High Court in Canberra today as a group of native title holders from Central Australia fight to assert cultural rights over an aquifer under their lands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d334f651d8d34fed9db2b05f2f04adba</guid></item><item><title>Chappell Roan no longer represented by talent agency led by Casey Wasserman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/chappell-roan-no-longer-represented-by-casey-wasserman/106327330</link><description>Pop star Chappell Roan says she is no longer represented by the talent agency led by Los Angeles 2028 Olympics chief Casey Wasserman, who has faced criticism for flirtatious email exchanges with convicted sex trafficker Ghislaine Maxwell more than 20 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfd514ef3d53768e08f6b605a9551524</guid></item><item><title>Deadly light plane crash raises questions about adequacy of flight training system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/luke-smith-light-plane-crash-failures-flight-training/106314630</link><description>When a young pilot crashed his aircraft he and his two passengers died, but there are questions as to why he was even flying after failing two exams.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60f7650354045caa1da27a34945818b2</guid></item><item><title>No body-worn video evidence available for inquest into Krista Kach's death, coroner hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/krista-kach-inquest-no-body-worn-camera-evidence/106330358</link><description>A court hears a NSW inquest will need to rely on eyewitness accounts of the 2023 death of Krista Kach, who was shot with a beanbag round following a 10-hour stand-off with police in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e1eb69fc8206627f42ed509806f3904</guid></item><item><title>Britney Spears sells rights to music catalogue in reported $281m deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/britney-sells-rights-music-catalogue-primary-wave/106333696</link><description>Spears is the latest music star to sell the rights to their work, a decade after the release of her ninth and last studio album.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46d37ff06c7881b67f6362f876d81145</guid></item><item><title>Australia Diamonds defeat Jamaica 80-33 in third netball Test to claim 3-0 series win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/australia-diamonds-defeat-jamaica-80-33-in-third-test/106333890</link><description>Coach Stacey Marinkovich believes a refreshed Diamonds squad has found its "identity" ahead of attempting to become the first Australian netball team to defend Commonwealth Games gold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">572f0f2c0fcd545047cd50c575ce4950</guid></item><item><title>Baker Boy talks new album Djandjay, Riverboats festival and family legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/baker-boy-djandjay-album-riverboats-festival-racism-fresh-prince/106321578</link><description>The Yolŋu artist known as the Fresh Prince of Arnhem Land is the king of feel-good bilingual bangers. But heavy is the crown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a7e4fe54da381b9b3169df148ff7976</guid></item><item><title>Authorities warn Alice Springs flash flooding threat isn't over, more Central Australian rain predicted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/nt-alice-springs-flooding-wet-weather-emergency-rain/106334186</link><description>Authorities are warning Alice Springs could face further flooding overnight, with forecasts of more wet weather posing a threat to slowly receding water levels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f0111c3d67d09aaf04530f675a2283b</guid></item><item><title>More than 100 Stolen Generations survivors gather for apology anniversary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/largest-gathering-of-stolen-generations-survivors-for-apology/106322950</link><description>More than 100 Stolen Generations survivors have gathered in Canberra for the apology anniversary. The government is pledging new money to help them heal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c81bef72da28cb61fb66cddb9bf13666</guid></item><item><title>Flower industry peak body pushes for country of origin labelling amid Valentine's Day rush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/flower-industry-peak-body-seeks-country-of-origin-labelling/106340602</link><description>Millions of red roses will fly off florists' shelves this weekend, but the flower industry says there is not much to tell customers where the flowers are from.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85ad6e4fc8075f48a7b72dcf0b7c7234</guid></item><item><title>How do you find modern dating? Share your highs and lows with us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/audience-callout-modern-dating-love-stories/106287262</link><description>Whether you've shed tears of joy, sadness or even laughter in the process, we want to hear it all — but keep it under 150 words.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e85c8d73dd7cdf15e05f480eb2c663e8</guid></item><item><title>Chickens help autistic teen Summer Farrelly make sense of humans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/chickens-help-summer-farrelly-understand-humans-autism-book/106308084</link><description>While growing up, people didn't make much sense to Summer, but chickens always did. Now, Summer is using what they learnt to help other children with autism understand human interactions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69b349a86894794e632c23899a5e2185</guid></item><item><title>Easy, tasty and nutritious recipes for sharing this Ramadan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/easy-tasty-and-nutritious-recipes-for-sharing-this-ramadan/106331120</link><description>Looking for easy, nutritious Ramadan recipes? These options will help you prepare for and break your fast well.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb9d0165cd75c38640ee10f031f1d403</guid></item><item><title>Roads, homes, cars damaged as Alice Springs starts flash flood clean-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/alice-springs-flood-warning-cancelled-clean-up-underway/106343242</link><description>With Alice Springs homes, businesses and roads damaged by flash flooding this week, the government is facing pressure to improve local flood mitigation measures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9e006b90247c86d9b81b9b2c0f9e819</guid></item><item><title>Wool price jumps ahead of industry-first Chinese New Year break</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/wool-price-rising-ahead-of-chinese-new-year-break/106339658</link><description>As wool growers enjoy their best prices since 2019, the market will now pause to respect China's request for a week off to celebrate Lunar New Year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62ad96df10ee1750f91b3b33f2f16b56</guid></item><item><title>Italian migrants who brought 'fancy cheese' to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/italian-migrants-history-of-cheesemaking-australia/106274280</link><description>When John Interlandi's father began making "fancy cheese" in Gippsland, few Australians had heard of parmesan. At 90 years old, Mr Interlandi is still perfecting it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc65fa96aa7a73e1b002718296218199</guid></item><item><title>Townsville marathon swimmer crosses Cook Strait between NZ's South and North islands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/queensland-marathon-swimmer-crosses-cook-strait/106335994</link><description>Swimming in shark-infested waters across one of the most treacherous island crossings in the world was a challenge Townsville woman Liz Denyer could not pass up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1738aa6f290bcdbe2a076c44a027f8b1</guid></item><item><title>ACCC takes Coles to court over 'illusory' discounts in 'case of the century'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/accc-coles-federal-court-case-discount-pricing/106294956</link><description>The "case of the century" is set to play out in the federal court this month, with the ACCC taking on supermarket giant Coles for what it claims are "illusory" discounts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a8938d5ebc9b334251e02015fddc7f9</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners 'won't accept' handback of rehabilitated Argyle diamond mine site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/argyle-diamond-mine-closure-traditional-owner-concerns/106339850</link><description>East Kimberley traditional owners are concerned Rio Tinto's closure plan will leave them with "a giant hole in the ground forever".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">920c2b711109c2ab18519ecaf2822c30</guid></item><item><title>'Devastated' Australia on the brink of World Cup exit after Sri Lanka's record chase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/cricket-australia-sri-lanka-t20-world-cup-live-blog/106351564</link><description>Australia is on the cusp of a group stage exit from the T20 World Cup after crashing to an eight-wicket loss against tournament co-hosts Sri Lanka.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c69a6c4d3d6ed2d91ae06e9e0fd7374d</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested after fatal Merrylands stabbing escaped care 10 days before attack, health authorities say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/man-arrested-after-merrylands-stabbing-escaped-hospital-care/106356218</link><description>A man arrested after a fatal stabbing in Merrylands escaped from mental health care while being transferred between hospitals more than a week ago, health authorities say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac37a20a68838d5f1d8ead99df730433</guid></item><item><title>Richard Roxburgh, Damon Herriman and Toby Schmitz star in 'wickedly funny' play Art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/art-the-play-richard-roxburgh-damon-herriman-toby-schmitz/106051888</link><description>In the 1994 French play Art, Serge spends 160,000 euros on an all-white painting, horrifying his friend Marc. It might just wreck their decades-long friendship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf94795c60e3d3af64640f380e98e6b3</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Highway cut by flooding at Proserpine as coast cops more than 300mm of rain in 24 hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/outback-queensland-communities-prepare-for-major-flooding/106355472</link><description>Parts of the Queensland coast have received more than 300 millimetres of rain in 24 hours, leading to road closures, including the Bruce Highway at Proserpine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b999fa1f13abf874299f6fa93e0343f4</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Writers' Festival announces Randa Abdel-Fattah for 2026 program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/randa-abdel-fattah-to-feature-at-sydney-writers-festival/106357178</link><description>Sydney Writers' Festival has defended featuring Randa Abdel-Fattah on its 2026 program, saying it is "not in the business of cancelling or censoring writers".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27fd50a9ce304983c79c05fe33b13137</guid></item><item><title>Is it ever a good idea to stay together for the kids?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/should-you-ever-stay-together-for-the-kids/106281890</link><description>When a relationships breaks down, sometimes we think staying in the familiar discomfort is less scary — and even protective — for our kids. But is it ever a good idea to stay in an unhappy relationship for the sake of the children?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbe4bbc74caa9ba1918949fae6630fe1</guid></item><item><title>Driver charged over Camden fatal crash escaped Cumberland Hospital mental health care before incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/cumberland-hospital-patient-absconded-before-camden-fatal-crash/106361010</link><description>A driver charged over a double-fatal crash used a staff pass to escape hospital the day before an alleged Sydney stabber fled the same mental health facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9b460c845ba44fdb8e18d6fdf3752c5</guid></item><item><title>Danielle Scott's Winter Olympic silver ends years of pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/danielle-scott-aerials-silver-medal-2026-winter-olympics/106361322</link><description>In this most tension-filled Winter Olympic sport, it's no wonder tears are a by-product of both success and failure. Thankfully for Dani Scott, this time she was crying tears of pure joy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e5d5a3ecb08453f6f6bb9cdeaccc263</guid></item><item><title>How exclusion orders could ban Australian citizens from returning home indefinitely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/australian-citizens-banned-returning-overseas-exclusion-orders/106361634</link><description>One of the Australian women being held in a Syrian refugee camp has been barred from returning home after being given a temporary exclusion order — but the ban may not be as temporary as the name implies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b69ea4e5ccbec5d9f3ed7794e281795c</guid></item><item><title>SA secures Australian MotoGP, world-first street circuit announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/sa-secures-motogp-world-first-street-circuit-announced/106361722</link><description>The South Australian government has confirmed the Australian MotoGP will move to Adelaide from 2027, bringing with it huge economic benefits, but the opposition and Greens say the state has other priorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a957e6c008c2cd348424eaa2acecad49</guid></item><item><title>Unemployment rate remains at 4.1pc in January, leading to talk of another rate rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/unemployment-rate-australia-january-2026-steady/106362428</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate remained at 4.1 per cent in January, with 17,800 more employed people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3deb22f01e8aa72f8fccc75f74faf25b</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Pickering on his ADHD, satire and the 'ludicrous' Trump era</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/charlie-pickering-the-weekly-interview/106307588</link><description>Political satire occasionally comes at a price, but Charlie Pickering still believes the right joke at the right time can have a huge impact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7c1acd1c8fd008196d50eecb9154256</guid></item><item><title>The heartwarming tribute to injured aerials star Laura Peel at the Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/heartwarming-aerials-tribute-laura-peel/106361392</link><description>This Winter Olympics aerials competition saw plenty of Aussies achieve lifetime goals, but they never forgot the one person who was missing — injured champion Laura Peel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">837dd8955b1207595385711ea5af7ba8</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of 'controlling' the lives of Venezuelan youth group granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/bail-granted-over-alleged-youth-group-servitude/106363616</link><description>An alleged religious leader accused of "controlling every aspect" of the lives of a Venezuelan youth group has been granted release on strict home detention conditions by a South Australian court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91bc9f195f669d568f2a90e1fe9c2a44</guid></item><item><title>American star completes comeback with figure skating gold after 'retiring' at 16</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-live-blog-day-13/106363160</link><description>Alysa Liu becomes the first American woman to win singles figure skating gold in 24 years, completing her comeback after retiring in 2022 when she was only 16 years old.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfe1fb096a25edbb2543b23f098e496e</guid></item><item><title>Ally Hickman showed her grit at 2026 Winter Olympics after heavy fall on second run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/ally-hickman-crash-snowboard-slopestyle-2026-winter-olympics/106366350</link><description>In a Winter Olympics beset by both glory and injury, Ally Hickman's heavy fall in the snowboard slopestyle could have turned a happy day into another disappointing one. Instead, the young Aussie showed her grit to get back up and go again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a129ccb67369e26da08c0952f439ed6</guid></item><item><title>Former premier joins community calls for speed reduction at 'dangerous' fatal intersection in Newham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/community-calls-for-speed-reduction-newham-intersection-victoria/106364280</link><description>A community in central Victoria is calling for a 20 kph speed limit reduction at a "terribly dangerous" intersection after four major accidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d28bf645384eca294d072c5b45849511</guid></item><item><title>Calls for protection of Tasmania's penguins amid reports of birds 'handled by the neck'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/people-interacting-with-tasmanian-penguins-and-harming-them/106361614</link><description>Each summer, tourists flock to Tasmanian beaches to marvel at penguins, but for some, admiring the birds from afar is not enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a8bc422a73f9012a025e072732b4fbb</guid></item><item><title>As electric car prices fall, will affordability win over drivers?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/cart-electric-vehicles-becoming-more-affordable/106348534</link><description>The price tag of EVs has been a barrier to uptake. As cheaper models hit the market, will more drivers go electric?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8e8609bc047b4700deb6c7a5c8c5aa4</guid></item><item><title>Can Angus Taylor get beyond slogans to craft a sound immigration policy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/angus-taylor-immigration-pauline-hanson/106349268</link><description>The rifts in Australia's social cohesion can be seen in the blow-up over the so-called ISIS brides and their children, who want to come to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81483ff7c63fdba169c22b024c766cea</guid></item><item><title>Wild horse art on birth certificates is 'hypocritical', says brumby welfare group</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/brumby-birth-certificate-art-outrage/106363854</link><description>A limited-edition birth certificate released to mark the Chinese Year of the Horse is being labelled "hypocritical" as a cull of wild horses continues in the NSW high country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">036d3db4d54a10ba8cdd2c50a1ae692e</guid></item><item><title>Coalition willing to help stop passports for IS-linked women— as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/federal-politics-live-albanese-taylor-labor-coalition/106363700</link><description>Angus Taylor says the Coalition is willing to help the government strengthen legislation so women with ties to Islamic State are not issued Australian passports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e73f6a4c21f2ed041db318fdf5bfddfe</guid></item><item><title>Major US fund's credit squeeze could 'blow up' — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-friday-20-february/106366740</link><description>Shares in US asset manager Blue Owl have fallen sharply after it announced it was having challenges meeting investors' cash demands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8cfa058595f0f84f2b91273acd73f15</guid></item><item><title>Canadian skier Cassie Sharpe's horrific crash in the halfpipe reminds us of Winter Olympics dangers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/cassie-sharpe-canadian-freeski-halfpipe-crash/106366818</link><description>As Cassie Sharpe lay motionless on the base of the Livigno halfpipe, the excruciating tension reminded us all that winter Olympians are only ever seconds from disaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca8a04bde9604f081e69e3f402a12a68</guid></item><item><title>Is it OK to feed Australia's wild birds?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/is-it-ok-to-feed-australias-wild-birds/106349168</link><description>Many of us love interacting with and feeding wild birds, but experts say giving them the wrong types of food can do more harm than good.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eec910366a2f5aeb070b335682010295</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos lose World Club Challenge to Hull KR 30-24</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/brisbane-broncos-lose-world-club-challenge-to-hull-kr/106367354</link><description>After pulling off three straight comebacks to win the NRL premiership, the Brisbane Broncos fall just short of another miracle against Hull KR in the World Club Challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">226460c361ffc36183702882e85cf411</guid></item><item><title>David James Pye found guilty of murdering former Rebels boss Nick Martin after recruiting sniper</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/david-pye-guilty-orchestrating-assassination-nick-martin-sniper/106365638</link><description>Bikie David Pye is convicted of murder after he paid a trained sniper to assassinate his former friend and ex-Rebels boss Nick Martin in front of horrified onlookers at a drag racing event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbf544938badafba7fef8c6ab33f86a3</guid></item><item><title>Eric Dane, star of Grey's Anatomy and Euphoria, dies aged 53</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/eric-dane-star-of-greys-anatomy-and-euphoria-dies/106188556</link><description>The star was best known for his role as Dr Mark Sloan in long-running medical drama Grey's Anatomy, and as the patriarch of the Jacobs family in teen hit Euphoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38f5c65f82f5e42103bcfbd84e4e18ea</guid></item><item><title>WA councils could make laws to stop cats roaming under proposed state legislation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/wa-councils-could-soon-have-power-to-stop-cats-roaming/106365476</link><description>The WA government announces plans to give local councils the power to require cats to be contained to owners' properties, to protect native birds and other wildlife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9304ac0385f2634a77bf6bab016498b8</guid></item><item><title>Cameron William Leslie Clark, accused of Easts Leagues Club stabbing, appears in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/easts-leagues-club-stabbing-accused-appears-in-court/106366762</link><description>Cameron William Leslie Clark is accused of repeatedly stabbing a 20-year-old female employee of the Easts Leagues Club in Coorparoo last Thursday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96ec27e06b17fd9990fde151bd53e7a1</guid></item><item><title>Kyra Wheatley ready to ride the chaos and speed of ski cross at Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/kyra-wheatley-ski-cross-speed-chaos-winter-olympics/106366406</link><description>The speed and chaos of ski cross is what attracted Kyra Wheatley to the sport, and to realise a dream 12 years in the making of competing at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1a4056e5ff034ff263b9864448b4429</guid></item><item><title>Woman who fatally struck 12-year-old Marshall Oakley-Stagg granted restricted driver's licence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/driver-who-killed-marshall-oakley-stagg-drivers-licence/106369656</link><description>A driver who struck and killed a 12-year-old boy outside his school in southern Tasmania in 2024 has been granted a restricted licence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ff01adff427a2aca0847f364c794ea9</guid></item><item><title>Police receive 'reports of crime' in relation to Pauline Hanson interview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/police-investigation-pauline-hanson-afp-one-nation-muslim/106370420</link><description>One Nation senator Pauline Hanson accuses the government of trying to put her "back in jail", after police received reports of a crime in relation to the senator's inflammatory comments about Muslims during a media interview.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">185dd63416cc7c6d747e0e5e37316352</guid></item><item><title>Man whose girlfriend froze to death after he left her mountain convicted of manslaughter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/austria-manslaughter-after-woman-froze-to-death-on-mountain/106371008</link><description>A man who left his girlfriend to freeze to death on an Austrian mountain has been handed a five-month suspended sentence for manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">effae5ababb3ac61ba124a96f11fe003</guid></item><item><title>Andy Griffiths, author of the Treehouse books, named new Australian Children's Laureate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/andy-griffiths-author-australian-childrens-laureate/106331360</link><description>Famous for writing stories about toilets and tree houses, the bestselling kids' author is taking on a new challenge on the national stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4faf4f52c970006ea1d74e0f15c753b</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's future uncertain under monarch willing to let 'the law take its course'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/andrew-arrest-will-go-down-in-history-books/106367696</link><description>Like so many of the elite caught in Epstein's web, Andrew believed he would escape scrutiny for his behaviour. But it is precisely because of his name and position that his alleged wrongdoing has now delivered him into the hands of the law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">876a05a2e2317a3aa1a9f28c7c53ce70</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's arrest shows money talks louder than women's testimony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrest-jeffrey-epstein/106349250</link><description>Why is an email about the trade trip apparently more compelling than the detailed and painful evidence of a woman?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c126708b2400a064fec41430e0ad12c1</guid></item><item><title>Farmer's hands-off approach creates unusual lamb with distinct flavour chefs say is like nothing else in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/braidwood-farmer-new-lamb-cooked-local-restaurant-expat-chefs/106358970</link><description>When Frank was forced to sell the sheep he'd been farming for more than 20 years, something had to change. His "experiment" is helping expats feel at home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">193e31303ed2bfa342879871031db171</guid></item><item><title>Lavender growers say watered-down oil imports are pricing them out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/lavender-oil-imports-pricing-local-growers-out/106308156</link><description>Despite an Australian lavender industry dating back to the 1850s, you're more than likely using an imported and "watered-down" product, local growers say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e706f0f5677eaf283fac61a73d10ba9e</guid></item><item><title>Herby potato salad with green beans and tuna - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/herby-potatoes-with-green-beans-and-tuna/106252480</link><description>Turn a potato salad into a tasty meal with pantry staples and fresh greens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bf3639cafb3b89fadd2f76dbfd84322</guid></item><item><title>Opposition does its best to land blows on WA government in parliament's first week back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/wa-parliament-week-one-analysis-basil-zempilas-roger-cook/106365878</link><description>Housing, health and household stress — that's what WA's opposition leader says he's focused on in 2026 as he and his party face an uphill battle against the state government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56f1332a78e625f94d5312f5b9b52fd4</guid></item><item><title>Concerns over death of iconic salmon gums in WA's Great Western Woodlands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/concerns-over-tree-deaths-great-western-woodlands/106355300</link><description>Kalgoorlie horticulturalist Phil Stanley says he is struggling to get authorities to take the deaths of more than 100 salmon gums near the mining city seriously.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cef65ddf1756cc101cb4a0d10888de3f</guid></item><item><title>How a Belgian techno producer with some old synthesisers has reimagined Terminator 2</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/terminator-2-new-score-hear-my-eyes-mess/106369562</link><description>Terminator 2: Judgment Day is getting the live score treatment, but not in the way you might expect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">689c4da252c634c2c4554ed5d31bba80</guid></item><item><title>NASA boss blasts Boeing and agency over bungled test flight that left astronauts stranded on space station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/nasa-report-reveals-starliner-mission-failings/106371706</link><description>A bungled Boeing mission that left two astronauts stranded on the International Space Station for nine months has been criticised by NASA's new boss.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3928101430826cc338efc88bfa7afd86</guid></item><item><title>South Australian election countdown officially begins, campaign kicks off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/south-australia-election-2026-campaign-begins/106371978</link><description>Election campaigning in South Australia is officially underway, with candidates seizing the opportunity to begin making their formal pitches to voters before they head to the ballot box in March.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9242c102760eb4813ef7943f0f70998b</guid></item><item><title>Hungary and Slovakia threaten Ukraine over stalled Russian oil shipments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/hungary-and-slovakia-threaten-ukraine-russian-oil/106372526</link><description>Hungary and Slovakia, which have both received a temporary exemption from an EU policy prohibiting imports of Russian oil, have accused Ukraine of deliberately holding up supplies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e8c5eda8272aceae2a467ae014b516a</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government bears inflation pressure while premiers spend big, poll well</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/albanese-government-premiers-peter-malinauskas-david-crisafulli/106349260</link><description>High-spending premiers remain popular and seemingly impervious to the rising cost-of-living anxiety piling pressure on the Albanese government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0ff2d992e25fd6ee865c92e0a78f4e5</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Think you're a trivia boss? Show us what you've got</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/106366918</link><description>Well, this is cute — you thinking you're a quiz pro. It's time to play … HARD!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa1afae586e91600568a748b64e08b37</guid></item><item><title>On the frontlines of Australia's fight against vaccine hesitancy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/australia-vaccine-hesitancy-fight-restore-confidence/106353012</link><description>With immunisation rates declining and outbreaks of infectious diseases like measles increasing, the consequences of vaccine hesitancy in Australia are becoming clearer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8359da5691e58e050b22964baecf814e</guid></item><item><title>Bridgerton's Yerin Ha is living her own Cinderella story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/bridgerton-season-four-part-two-yerin-ha-interview/106363336</link><description>Yerin Ha built a name for herself in local and international productions for almost a decade before transforming into Bridgerton's newest paramour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99b5fbc19663ba58a0fb1032c0e7fedf</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump hikes global tariff rate to 15pc after Supreme Court loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/trump-hikes-tariff-rate-to-15pc-supreme-court/106373116</link><description>Donald Trump says he will raise to 15 per cent the global tariff he imposed after the US Supreme Court ruled against previous tariffs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5312a29068d4db1c715343da579c334a</guid></item><item><title>More assault allegations surface against footballers in tiny town of Balmoral</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/hometown-boys-culture-of-football-misogyny-called-out-balmoral/106358784</link><description>More women come forward with allegations of sexual assault in a small Victorian town, years after a rape victim was shunned by the town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e4baf80ef8954cf91ddfdc29c6843b8</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor was the Queen's rumoured favourite. Did she do too much to protect him?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/queen-elizabeth-former-prince-andrew-and-epstein/106371728</link><description>It will be up to King Charles to shepherd his family's institution through its darkest hour. But could his own mother have done more to snuff out this crisis before he inherited it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75d2f85e2faea6fba90af13bf1129d78</guid></item><item><title>Predator Jeffrey Epstein used promises of university scholarships and modelling contracts to lure victims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/how-epstein-lured-girls-using-university-and-modelling/106320804</link><description>Admission into elite universities. A job that promised travel around the world. An audition for Victoria's Secret. This is how Jeffery Epstein lured his victims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a152c09ebc56da809bd762fe0027283</guid></item><item><title>A visual guide to the prices that landed Coles in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/coles-grocery-pricing-down-down-accc-court/106355492</link><description>The pricing patterns of these six products show how Coles stands accused of using its Down Down marketing campaign to dupe shoppers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6972c0ae544a3d055ce6b66632f8a24d</guid></item><item><title>Scammers fleeced pensioner Ian Williams out of $1,338. So he sued his bank for $379 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/ian-williams-on-why-he-sued-nab-bank/106093720</link><description>Ian Williams has brought a whole new meaning to "taking on the big guy". When scammers stole from the pensioner the bank blamed him. So he launched a $379 million lawsuit to "make it right".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93fea5943f6595243ac093002bc3773d</guid></item><item><title>The Miracle on Ice, when an unheralded USA team knocked off the mighty USSR</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/miracle-on-ice-usa-vs-ussr-ice-hockey-lake-placid-winter-olympic/106287402</link><description>On this day in 1980, a group of American students pulled off the most unlikely of victories, beating the greatest team in international ice hockey history in the upset of the century. Some even called it a miracle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f4d5cb63c8a8a13d65063f95b599cf7</guid></item><item><title>Doctors race through Kyiv missile strike to deliver child's donor heart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/ukraine-doctors-operate-under-attack-heart-surgeons-todurov-kyiv/106352796</link><description>Kyiv surgeons who drove through a massive missile strike to deliver a child's donor heart say they will stop at nothing to save lives — even when under attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11ce04a812127cad5b64ddbea55f999a</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Wild Livigno weather puts Indra Brown's medal tilt on hold — day 15 quick hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/winter-olympics-day-15-quick-hits-blizzard-indra-brown-livigno/106372510</link><description>Indra Brown's medal tilt is put on hold as a horror bobsleigh crash and wild weather rock day 15. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79fbdd8b9c884446c2092272f8288188</guid></item><item><title>Punk's boom began 50 years ago in Brisbane — and the scene is still thriving</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/50-years-of-punk-brisbane-the-saints-im-stranded/106363856</link><description>The Saints released their single "(I'm) Stranded" in 1976, kicking off the punk movement in Australia. So how did it all unfold?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ff7aba07da49374830b95165bce08cb</guid></item><item><title>Bodies of nine back-country skiers recovered days after California avalanche</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/california-skiers-bodies-recovered-after-avalanche/106373320</link><description>The bodies of nine back-country skiers killed in a California avalanche four days earlier are recovered, following a harrowing operation hindered by intense snowfall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39af55e600ea9a9ea051ed5cd995ea77</guid></item><item><title>What the Bad Bunny in Australia tour means for Puerto Ricans far from home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/bad-bunny-australia-sydney-puerto-rico-live-concert-latino/106333062</link><description>This weekend Bad Bunny offers Australia a lesson in community, identity and how to belong without diluting your true self.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a17020b4ce51c2572315a7851d6ffd5</guid></item><item><title>Great-grandmother's garlic mushroom artwork puts new spin on managing food waste</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/wa-artist-turns-garlic-stems-old-teabags-into-art/106221554</link><description>Meet the country artist putting a slightly unexpected spin on garlic mushrooms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14ba8dc8bb3072d0a4f0467157374b25</guid></item><item><title>After a rare Supreme Court loss for Trump, here's his record with the bench</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/rare-loss-for-trump-before-the-supreme-court-his-record/106004520</link><description>Donald Trump was furious when the US Supreme Court ruled that his use of tariffs was illegal. Here's how earlier cases in that jurisdiction have fared.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2df862b3b607bed8e4ebdf16a4c5baec</guid></item><item><title>Migraine is more than just a headache. A neurologist explains the four stages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/four-stages-of-migraine/106365424</link><description>Knowing the four distinct phases of a migraine can help you recognise the symptoms and manage pain at each stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ab8f383b80c8679ec99c0a724d8a937</guid></item><item><title>Rescue operation carried out after multiple boats capsize during Bellerive Regatta</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/multiple-boats-capsize-at-bellerive-regatta/106373620</link><description>A gust of wind caused at least eight boats to capsize in the River Derwent during a race.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a69b46f0c607356de805361f316c3f02</guid></item><item><title>Why has Donald Trump issued Keir Starmer a warning about the Chagos Islands?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/chagos-islands-donald-trump-keir-starmer/106372464</link><description>The US president has told the UK it is making a "big mistake" in its decision to transfer sovereignty of the islands to Mauritius.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">380aca464b31a6260cd5aefcccfd9632</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on day 16</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/winter-olympics-2026-quick-guide-what-to-watch-on-day-16/106372248</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a8ac7438b1f136099574ab6f0a0328b</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of 'toxic' poppies stolen from Victorian farm triggers health department alert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/police-investigate-poppy-plant-theft-from-ballarat-area-victoria/106373608</link><description>About 1,700 poppy plants grown for the pharmaceutical industry have been stolen from a regional property north-west of Melbourne, prompting a warning from the state health department.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b46a31ecf8cf87dbc14593028504000c</guid></item><item><title>Labor launches SA election campaign with land and housing promises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/labor-launches-sa-election-campaign-with-housing-policy/106373392</link><description>SA Labor's state election campaign launch is framed around housing, with the premier committing to a scheme for the purchase of land that would then be on-sold to the private sector for development.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f964067ff2a9ebef115ba389630f01ce</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs prepares for possible flooding amid severe weather warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/alice-springs-prepares-for-flood-amid-severe-weather-warning/106373816</link><description>Alice Springs residents and businesses prepare for possible flooding, amid a severe weather warning, and after flash flooding caused the Todd River to rise dramatically last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f51f578419796c6d5833522a6213deaf</guid></item><item><title>Nathan Cleary to risk missing first three Panthers games by challenging ban at NRL judiciary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/cleary-to-risk-missing-first-three-panthers-games-nrl-judiciary/106373966</link><description>Nathan Cleary will either be available to play Brisbane in round one or will miss the opening three rounds after Penrith decided to challenge his high tackle ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf8618780a44487cf3b6b5a9403ca8c3</guid></item><item><title>East West rail corridor cut by flooding amid heavy rain in northern SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/east-west-rail-corridor-cut-by-flooding-and-downpours/106373490</link><description>The cross-country rail line connecting Australia's east and west has been closed after heavy rain and flash flooding washed away significant sections of track, the corridor's manager says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fe5dd9fbf3f5419283e4e472a07177d</guid></item><item><title>Live: Halfpipe final underway featuring Aussie teen Indra Brown as Winter Olympics wrap up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/winter-olympics-day-16-live-updates-indra-brown/106372016</link><description>Australian 16-year-old Indra Brown is in the freeski halfpipe final on the last day of the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf4fef30a439dba6841e8f6da19912f4</guid></item></channel></rss>