<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 07:00:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mark Wood suffers hamstring injury in England's pre-Ashes tour match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/mark-wood-injured-in-england-ashes-tour-match/106007724</link><description>One of England's great bowling hopes for the summer cops a blow, as Mark Wood fails to finish the first day of a tour match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dd66b10f3e1591cffb545c4c3474d06</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian salmon selectively bred to withstand warmer waters and bacterial disease</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/tasmanian-salmon-selective-breeding-for-heat-resistance/106005572</link><description>A salmon mass mortality event caused by a bacterial outbreak has given scientists "a lot of genetic knowledge" to put to use in a selective breeding program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c1e28ba691f2f42b37ca76b3515cc7b</guid></item><item><title>SA prison exec 'motivated by financial greed' in $300,000 prison upgrade rort, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/sa-prison-upgrade-rort-paul-andrew-robinson/106006272</link><description>A South Australian court has heard that a correctional services executive was "motivated by financial greed" when he planned a $300,000 prison upgrade rort to fund his retirement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c48b230f79677522c812b521da5638f0</guid></item><item><title>Labor backbencher Dave Kelly hopes WA government's Dion Barber compensation appeal fails</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/labor-mp-hopes-dion-barber-appeal-fails/106005242</link><description>A Labor MP says he hopes the state's appeal of a multi-million-dollar compensation payout to a child sexual abuse survivor fails, amid mounting criticism from legal experts and advocates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6116c56d2b9ab49cc25ff280dc291991</guid></item><item><title>The Liberal Party officially abandons its net zero by 2050 target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/liberals-dump-net-zero-/106007346</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a70d8b6c9e930e936411816c7798c1a6</guid></item><item><title>Yipirinya School's future in doubt as enrolments plummet and debts mount</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/yipirinya-school-alice-springs-staff-redundancies-closure-fears/106004860</link><description>The future of an independent Indigenous school in Alice Springs is under a cloud after just 50 students turned up to class on Thursday, down from a peak enrolment of 360 in December last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02a0e22ef9fb04e10ef21c215cf6768f</guid></item><item><title>Gaming addiction treatment pioneer, botanist honoured at WA Australian of the Year awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/wa-australian-of-the-year-awards-winners/106007430</link><description>The psychiatrist who pioneered the country's first gaming disorder clinic at a public hospital has been named the 2026 Australian of the Year for WA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0130a5a3892906f733b0cd11d400fba3</guid></item><item><title>Israeli settlers in West Bank torch mosque and scrawl hateful messages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/israeli-settlers-torch-mosque-scrawl-hateful-messages/106008266</link><description>Settler violence against Palestinian communities in the West Bank has been on the rise in recent years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">806d1fddb5efccc0ab087c2bdd41514a</guid></item><item><title>Epstein email says Andrew had photo taken with accuser Virginia Roberts Giuffre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-photo-virginia-giuffre-emails/106008442</link><description>The former prince has repeatedly denied ever meeting Ms Roberts Giuffre, including during an infamous interview with the BBC in 2019.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bc4e069da8bcf13df29626c95c0f515</guid></item><item><title>Have you spotted a 'smiley' graffiti around Tasmania? This is who spray-paints most of them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/tas-smiley-hob-graffiti-who-spray-paints-them/106008562</link><description>Ever noticed the hundreds of smiley faces graffitied on buildings, the back of road signs, guardrails and bridges around Tasmania? The artist says the world needs more joy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90472df55daeff3951e8a8621178565e</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's treaty is here. What does it mean? And is one coming to my state?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/first-nations-treaty-potentially-first-of-many/106006576</link><description>Hundreds of treaties exist between First Nations people and governments around the world. One state in Australia just became one of them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ac8b5a4b3504735a1a7a27d685abbcb</guid></item><item><title>Liberal plan to put public money into coal and gas may do little to help prices or emissions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/liberal-coal-gas-price-emission-doubts/106006866</link><description>Energy experts have cast doubt over the Liberal Party's central claim that it can bring down power prices by backing coal and gas, while questioning how the party plans to actually reduce emissions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90f79a9a2daf4111a3b04e7e728273c6</guid></item><item><title>Trump has floated a 50-year mortgage to help first-time buyers. Could it work?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/trump-administration-floats-50-year-mortgage/106000080</link><description>The average first-time home buyer in the US is older than ever, but a new proposal could leave them paying off a mortgage until old age.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e15809d40e063c35b45ef910df0ff95</guid></item><item><title>Yield could drop but berry grower confident industry will adapt to dimethoate use changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/dimethoate-rules-lower-blueberry-production-growers-adapt/106004944</link><description>New rules around a popular insecticide could lead to lower blueberry production, but growers are confident the industry will adapt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00434e21b4192dcee3cdcf664ad2b968</guid></item><item><title>Allan government crime crackdown continues with focus on retail and hospitality assaults</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/crime-crackdown-hospitality-retail-workers/106007796</link><description>New offences for people assaulting or threatening service workers are expected to be introduced in time for the Christmas shopping rush.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3304c57edfdf9cff254033db40ff90b7</guid></item><item><title>Supercell risk for eastern Australia as peak severe weather season arrives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/supercell-risk-storm-outbreak-across-australia/106007402</link><description>Peak severe weather season is arriving, and an influx of tropical moisture will fuel thunderstorms in all Australian states and territories between Friday and Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df547405ad65dc63611b2b921ca61197</guid></item><item><title>Despondent Liberal moderates fear electoral oblivion in metropolitan seats after net zero scrapped</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/liberal-moderates-split-on-net-zero-scrapping/106007824</link><description>While many Liberals who wanted to keep net zero say they are happy with the position the party has taken, some despondent moderates fear electoral oblivion in metropolitan seats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97a68e68f2f421a759c47b21e9ae026c</guid></item><item><title>Liberals deliver slap in the face to voters by dumping net zero</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/liberals-net-zero-whitlam-andrew-hirst/106007366</link><description>The Liberal conservatives' success in forcing their party to dump its commitment to the net zero emissions reduction target has been a triumph of ideology over pragmatism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d3fba58c83b3931253c948609140986</guid></item><item><title>'Swarm' of fossil fuel lobbyists coming to COP31, former SA premier warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/sa-mike-rann-speech-criticising-gas-industry/106005548</link><description>Former South Australian premier Mike Rann has sharply criticised the gas industry and warned that "battalions" of fossil fuel lobbyists will be descending on next year's UN climate summit to influence negotiations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71f1f206ec05ee2b1f4f91cc45ce3498</guid></item><item><title>Queensland drug testing ban halted research exposing dangers of illegal steroids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/queensland-illegal-steroid-research-drug-testing-ban/105985000</link><description>A researcher who found "dangerous" toxic metals in illegal anabolic steroids is in talks the health department officials to continue his work despite Queensland's drug checking ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c8208a1fed9b6fd14a0d4ffe8a8aa8f</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Malcolm Turnbull says Liberals have 'memory of goldfish and diet of piranhas' on net zero — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/federal-politics-live-blog-nov-14/106007334</link><description>Former prime minister Malcolm Turnbull says the Liberals have the "memory of goldfish and diet of piranhas" after dumping net zero by 2050.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">008b6409c43f741b8fea0902321c4655</guid></item><item><title>Snap closure of schools in Canberra and Brisbane after asbestos found in recalled coloured sand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/brisbane-act-schools-closed-asbestos-risk-coloured-sand/106008648</link><description>Schools in Canberra and Brisbane are closed today due to asbestos in decorative coloured sand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6db868a700514ba5cd7210218bb521d</guid></item><item><title>Photographer David Finlay spends week documenting erupting Kilauea volcano</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/active-kilauea-volcano-photographed-by-david-finlay/106001116</link><description>David Finlay has captured images of bioluminescence, fireflies, ghost mushrooms, meteors and the aurora australis, but seeing one of the world's most active volcanoes spraying lava 450 metres in the air "takes the cake".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83d3b4cfd684a356745fc4d4372f4abf</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur keeps ATP Finals campaign alive by beating Taylor Fritz in must-win clash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/tennis-alex-de-minaur-atp-finals-beats-taylor-fritz/106008656</link><description>Alex de Minaur responds to a crushing loss earlier in the week by toppling America's Taylor Fritz to remain in contention at the ATP Finals in Turin, although he needs a helping hand from a rival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f1b687cddd81d3ff3e499e9e6820a0e</guid></item><item><title>Miloš Degenek savours Socceroos second coming, sets example for others</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/socceroos-world-cup-milos-degenek/106007988</link><description>Socceroos defender Miloš Degenek wasn't sure if he'd ever make it back to the national side, now he's a key cog in the team, and entertaining the thought of a World Cup win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a212baec66206c67e9309feba30fde2a</guid></item><item><title>ASX drops sharply after Wall Street tumbles, TPG Telecom plummets — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/asx-markets-business-live-news-14-nov/106008690</link><description>The ASX falls steeply in response to a sharp drop on Wall Street overnight, which was led by a big decline in tech stocks. TPG Telecom plunged 32 per cent after the stock traded without rights to the next dividend payment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bfa6931bf3028aad4c58a795007c4c7</guid></item><item><title>APY Art Centre Collective sues The Australian's publisher for defamation seeking $4.4m payout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/apy-art-centre-collective-the-australian-newspaper-sued/106000020</link><description>The truth behind claims of "white hands on black art" will be tested in the SA Supreme Court as one of the country's best-known Aboriginal art groups sues Rupert Murdoch's national masthead for defamation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87e5e7cd676d8a359f11d0433b1c97a2</guid></item><item><title>Government urged to increase legal system funding as NT remand prisoner population grows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/nt-remand-prisoner-numbers-spark-legal-system-funding-calls/105999912</link><description>With more than half of all inmates in the Northern Territory's largest prison on remand, legal experts are calling for more funding for legal services and courts to keep up with demand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d5cf9c3af7a19847210700ba4ba469c</guid></item><item><title>Hayley Silver-Holmes takes three wickets in an over and Lizelle Lee stars as Hurricanes dominate Sixers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/cricket-wbbl-silver-holmes-triple-wicket-hurricanes-vs-sixers/106008700</link><description>Hayley Silver-Holmes shows her class after recovering from a nightmare run with injuries before her opening teammates set a record with the bat to deliver the Hobart Hurricanes a win over the Sydney Sixers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48437be089e3624d5305d1aa4b11c5b9</guid></item><item><title>Regional councils call for government intervention to prevent future airline debts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/jetgo-bonza-rex-virgin-regional-airports/106001572</link><description>Regional councils say they want security bonds on airline carriers who use their airports to ensure stability for travellers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0765f72833732d4bc1d677bb9dd0c38</guid></item><item><title>Matildas star Kyra Cooney-Cross nominated for 'Marta' award for goal of the season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/matildas-star-kyra-cooney-cross-nominated-for-marta-award/106008738</link><description>Kyra Cooney-Cross is nominated for the goal of the year award, but has stiff competition from the player the award is named after.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e0e3bbc2f70ac8244d863c8ca47c7e1</guid></item><item><title>Australian artist Lynette Wallworth travels to the Amazon to explore psychedelics and death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/edge-of-life-documentary-amazon-shaman-psychedelic-therapy/105995588</link><description>Australian filmmaker Lynette Wallworth accompanies two palliative care doctors researching psilocybin use deep into the Amazon jungle to see if it can change the end-of-life experience for terminal patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">757002103e44fb559b115708dc886c74</guid></item><item><title>Concussion protocols should be strengthened following Eliesa Katoa incident, neuroscientist says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/eliesa-katoa-concussion-surgery-sparks-calls-for-change/106005016</link><description>A leading concussion expert calls for sporting bodies to strengthen their protocols on players who are concussed before and during matches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0d67dcb9c6829cc16845210c37dba3b</guid></item><item><title>Towns in the Kimberley are struggling to combat youth crime but Fitzroy Crossing has found a way</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/night-place-fitzroy-crossing-youth-crime-success/105967244</link><description>As Kununurra battles with a surge in youth crime, residents in Fitzroy Crossing are celebrating their success in reducing rates through a community-led initiative.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25e3caa3f70117fd32661ed3d12593dd</guid></item><item><title>Perth family still don't know if father's death was linked to Optus Triple Zero outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/optus-triple-0-outage-family-waiting-for-answers/106001908</link><description>The family of a Perth man whose death was tied to the Optus Triple Zero outage claims authorities left them in the dark for weeks and are still unsure how his death was connected to the telco failure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef6675857153831d041ae36a55d45e75</guid></item><item><title>England captain Ben Stokes appears embarrassed by six-wicket haul in Ashes warm-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/cricket-ben-stokes-reaction-six-wickets-ashes-warm-up-match/106008758</link><description>Ben Stokes appears embarrassed with almost every single one of his six wickets as England's bowling attack leaves much to be desired in their only tour match before the Ashes opener in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4e3a47fbdb65c854dec9b58a64a47c0</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast man charged with sharing violent extremist material granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/man-charged-extremist-material-gold-coast-online-terror/106008798</link><description>A Queensland man charged with sharing violent extremist material online after a raid by multiple law enforcement agencies has been granted bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fd0f527a728b8d2aa8e524c7dbccfb8</guid></item><item><title>Blue Origin launches huge rocket carrying twin NASA spacecraft to Mars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/blue-origin-launch-to-mars/106008914</link><description>Blue Origin has successfully launched the 98-metre New Glenn rocket with a pair of NASA spacecraft destined for Mars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a7ca32abf73944f2501f953742c1ee6</guid></item><item><title>Mexican prosecutor requests 210-year prison terms for accused killers of Jake and Callum Robinson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/jake-callum-robinson-homicide-court-hearing-mexico/106008444</link><description>A prosecutor requests jail sentences of more than 200 years for the men accused of murdering Australian brothers Jake and Callum Robinson in Mexico last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4af5cbb43e41619a144b284487765823</guid></item><item><title>Hyperlapse footage showing lights from aurora australis over Connewarre in Victoria.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/southern-lights-from-aurora-australis-seen-over-victoria/106007714</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24bd52fcd5ef1ee80fbc3db3230a58e2</guid></item><item><title>Aurora australis viewed from Mt Stromlo Observatory in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/aurora-australis-mt-stromolo/106005220</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01a177eecf1d8e34408c38252e92a867</guid></item><item><title>When the southern lights are seen further north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/aurora-australis-southern-lights-november-2025/106004326</link><description>The strength of the latest geomagnetic storms has seen the aurora australis light up skies across a larger part of the country than usual.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a951ed2d5cd1f0839b3513cc78acd282</guid></item><item><title>Cristiano Ronaldo receives first red card of international career after elbow to Irishman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/football-cristiano-ronaldo-red-card-elbow-portugal-vs-ireland/106008950</link><description>Cristiano Ronaldo is mocked by Irish fans after being sent off for the first time in his international career following a vicious swinging elbow at his opponent in a World Cup qualifier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23ec2f964365f05ef453f58f55000f72</guid></item><item><title>Blue Origin launches New Glenn rocket on NASA mission</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/blue-origin-launches-new-glenn-rocket-on-nasa-mission/106009074</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">869ec739e02479737e6d3897edb3ffa8</guid></item><item><title>Molly Ticehurst's former partner Daniel Billings pleads guilty to her murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/daniel-billings-molly-ticehurst-guilty-plea-murder/105992580</link><description>Daniel Billings pleads guilty to killing his former partner, Molly Ticehurst, at Forbes in central western New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eeca27cdd73e9158424928fc872c2503</guid></item><item><title>WA grazier accepts wild donkey cull order but refuses to pull the trigger himself</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/grazier-calls-for-compromise-feral-donkey-cull-kachana-station/106004620</link><description>A WA pastoralist says he will not stand in the way of the bullets aimed at the donkeys on his remote property, but he will not kill the animals he says have had a positive environmental impact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35a339e2e0fe1cc13c6573ccf0470941</guid></item><item><title>List of Canberra schools closed after asbestos found in recalled decorative coloured sand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/list-of-canberra-schools-closed-asbestos-coloured-sand/106009044</link><description>The ACT has closed 16 public schools today, with several others partially closed due to potential asbestos exposure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec96e4e36dba26e1100166aabc29cbbf</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the coloured sand recalled from Officeworks, Woolworths over traces of asbestos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/what-is-this-asbestos-sand/106008884</link><description>Fifteen public schools in Canberra are closed today, and several others are partially closed, due to potential asbestos contamination in coloured sand sold at dozens of stores across Australia. Here is what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113cdb879dc95a2163b626535f27b8cb</guid></item><item><title>Hunter Valley wedding bus crash driver Brett Button loses appeal on 32-year jail sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/brett-button-loses-appeal-hunter-valley-bus-crash/106008584</link><description>The bus driver who crashed and killed 10 wedding guests while injuring 25 others in the NSW Hunter Valley has lost an appeal on the severity of his sentence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87162763f6871f06ee52585a2edf3b06</guid></item><item><title>Benjamin Netanyahu insists he won't seek pardon on corruption case after Donald Trump's letter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/benjamin-netanyahu-wont-seek-pardon-after-trump-letter-to-herzog/106008604</link><description>The Israeli PM says he will not push for a pardon or concede guilt in his long-running corruption trial, less than a day after thanking Donald Trump for urging Israel's president to clear his record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd5f8643e3fababb687bbd31ba3251d3</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies announces team to face Ireland in spring tour Test match, James O'Connor returns at fly-half</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/wallabies-team-announcement-ireland-test-match-dublin/106009408</link><description>The Wallabies have recalled several big-name players for their penultimate Test of 2025, as coach Joe Schmidt returns to his old Irish stamping ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ad29eb7e7432c1248b64fc95a81c0ce</guid></item><item><title>Medical waste destined for landfill diverted to wildlife charities in Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/medical-pantry-donating-waste-to-wildlife-rescue-charities/105802946</link><description>A Victorian medical charity helps divert 15,000 tonnes of medical waste from landfill while giving wildlife carers the resources to nurse injured animals back to health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c23d839a0d4a133f3b651341c0166dda</guid></item><item><title>When is the 2025 AFL draft? Here's your guide to bidding, trades and the official pick order</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/afl-draft-2025-everything-you-need-to-know-guide/106009962</link><description>Another AFL draft has arrived, offering dozens of teenage footballers the chance to realise their dreams. Here is everything you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54cb3b828981e4d4295a3f4604d7e5b3</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide man Samuel Joe Frost faces lengthy sentence over child abuse offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/sa-samuel-joe-frost-sentenced-over-child-abuse-offences/106009120</link><description>An Adelaide paedophile who posted images online "boasting" about his crimes has been sentenced to at least 14 years in prison. WARNING: This story contains details of sexual abuse that readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">565593e05b586956d961359c93b13b45</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Spanish football boss who kissed World Cup player gets egged during book launch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/luis-rubiales-eggs-thrown-book-launch-in-spain/106010288</link><description>The former president of Spain's national football federation, who made headlines after his behaviour following the final of the 2023 FIFA Women's World Cup, has had eggs thrown at him during the launch of his book.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc411241c578fda3690674d15d5bc90c</guid></item><item><title>Eliesa Katoa to be moved to Melbourne hospital as brain surgery recovery continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/eli-katoa-to-be-moved-to-melbourne-hospital/106010644</link><description>NRL star Eliesa Katoa faces more time in hospital when he returns to Melbourne as he recovers from a brain bleed after playing for Tonga.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a14419431d607c16e9a37bc01fb7efc2</guid></item><item><title>Daniel Billings threatened Molly Ticehurst days before her murder, court documents show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/molly-ticehurst-murderer-daniel-billings-threats-court-documents/106009788</link><description>Court documents reveal shocking details about the murder of childcare worker Molly Ticehurst at the hands of her former partner in the NSW last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2e6973b952ce6b6689bd35556d91091</guid></item><item><title>Michael Wilson pleads not guilty to rape, possessing child abuse material</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/michael-wilson-pleads-not-guilty-sex-offences/106009892</link><description>Michael Simon Wilson has pleaded not guilty to more than 60 charges, including rape, and possessing and transmitting child abuse material.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e596f6d172eb7fc26ef8f959701fc862</guid></item><item><title>The minimal-effort herbs and edible plants that produce for years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/easy-herbs-edible-plants-that-produce-for-years/105977468</link><description>Fresh herbs can be expensive at the supermarket, but many perennial varieties are cheap and easy to grow at home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcd7be626f49f164c8eb77f4781883c2</guid></item><item><title>Dementia now the leading cause of death nationwide, overtaking heart disease, new ABS data shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/dementia-now-the-leading-cause-of-death-nationwide/106010152</link><description>New data on causes of death reveals more than 17,500 people died of dementia in 2024 nationwide, according to the Australian Bureau of Statistics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c092c2c3c60a512da0998815b0d968f</guid></item><item><title>Illegal tobacco retailer hit with $1.5 million fine following record seizure in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/tobacco-shed-paolo-timpano-illict-tobacco-charges-qld/105951412</link><description>The charges stemmed from a statewide crackdown on the illegal tobacco trade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21ac2babf97a6afa6aaa4f72029cc128</guid></item><item><title>Canberra's Big Splash water park to remain shut over summer despite promises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/act-big-splash-waterpark-to-remain-shut-over-summer/106010490</link><description>Canberra's only water park will remain closed for the summer despite promises by the site's owners it would reopen by mid-November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98677a525355e29f74f0023cf9d92b58</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Sands the latest brand to recall sunscreens over potential SPF concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/bondi-sands-latest-to-recall-sunscreens-potential-spf-concerns/106010758</link><description>A major Australian sunscreen brand, Bondi Sands is the latest to announce recalls over potential SPF concerns, and the first to remove products from shelves that have not been identified as using the same problematic base formulation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e32c8f099881160c6899ee60c25c7abb</guid></item><item><title>Seal escapes orca hunt by jumping onto photographer's boat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/seal-escapes-orca-hunt-by-jumping-onto-photographer-s-boat/106010712</link><description>A wildlife photographer has captured the dramatic moment a seal eluded a pod of killer whales by scrambling onto the stern of her boat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0864a9d73ac87ee1f58d9d4ab9981e9a</guid></item><item><title>Seal seeks refuge on photographer's boat while fleeing orcas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/seal-seeks-refuge-on-photographer-s-boat-while-fleeing-orcas/106010748</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d971b30104a879b2b096dcf83a7b900</guid></item><item><title>Man who drove into floodwater in NSW central west sentenced over boy's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/floodwater-dangerous-driving-death-sentencing/105999200</link><description>A man has been sentenced to a one year intensive corrections order, to be served in the community, after attempting to drive through floodwater in the NSW central west, resulting in the death of a five-year-old.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">655dde42a3c79cb7054571dd211f18b7</guid></item><item><title>NSW government workers' comp changes defeated as premier declares fight is 'over'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/nsw-government-workers-omp-changes-defeated/106010610</link><description>The Minns government has been unable to break an impasse after six months of trying to pass the legislation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af94fab091296f1f79af5bea65f4dae7</guid></item><item><title>Police search Bega wetlands for knife used in fatal stabbing of Gordon Kessey</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/police-search-for-dagger-from-bega-stabbing-of-gordon-kessey/105983680</link><description>Police continue their investigation into the suspected murder of Gordon Kessey on the NSW far south coast, looking for a missing blade in nearby wetlands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ba42e39a6e7a9398134d1e866eedd25</guid></item><item><title>Accused Adass Israel Synagogue arsonist, Giovanni Laulu, granted bail in Melbourne court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/adass-israel-synagogue-alleged-arsonist-granted-bail/106011864</link><description>Giovanni Laulu, a 21-year-old man accused of carrying out an attack that caused more than $20 million in damage to the Adass Israel Synagogue, is granted bail by a Melbourne magistrate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad7b2a0c322b54618f80c612248b71d4</guid></item><item><title>'Chaos situation' as potential asbestos exposure in coloured sand closes Canberra schools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/act-chaos-situation-as-asbestos-sand-closes-schools/106011744</link><description>A recall of children’s coloured sand after asbestos traces were found has led to the closure of multiple public schools in the ACT, leaving parents scrambling for care options and answers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7790b831db8803395ef8a413c422f74c</guid></item><item><title>England hits out in Perth Ashes warm-up match as Joe Root misses out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/england-hits-out-in-perth-as-joe-root-misses-out/106012126</link><description>England star Joe Root is yet to score a Test century in Australia and was out for one run despite the team's strong platform in the warm-up match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32685366ad971a65e1a5c6c7b00d9913</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu flags expulsion of foreign advisers from government buildings as Nakamal Agreement hangs in balance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/vanuatu-expels-foreigners-from-government-buildings/106010390</link><description>The move will affect Australia and New Zealand's multiple police and defence personnel working in Vanuatu, and could set back the signing of the Nakamal Agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66a88eb06dcb5ec623ef9f2d00c0b628</guid></item><item><title>Major feed mill in the Northern Territory getting back on track after fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/feed-pellet-mill-near-katherine-back-on-track-after-fire/106011818</link><description>A feed mill in the Northern Territory is getting back on track after a major fire destroyed more than $3 million of hay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b4d7763085b81565c3a0429581b9428</guid></item><item><title>Friday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106011444</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1af25cc586a77927b1626d122cc4494e</guid></item><item><title>Ratepayers to foot $2m bill to remove contaminated FOGO waste from South West facility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/future-of-fogo-south-west-cost-to-remove-contaminated-waste/106005636</link><description>The City of Bunbury and Shire of Harvey agree to contribute up to $1 million each to remove contaminated organic waste that caused the closure of a regional three-bin waste system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e33c414b3c63942637e8daa95fc5dbc</guid></item><item><title>What is a supercell storm and why are they so destructive?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/what-is-supercell-weather-warnings-storm-season/106011578</link><description>Australia is in its peak severe weather system and there are warnings that supercell storms could hit the east coast this weekend. So what exactly is a supercell?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f053e06590c8cb7b9bc03073209426cf</guid></item><item><title>Jury in Rajwinder Singh trial taken through murdered woman Toyah Cordingley's phone data</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/toyah-cordingley-trial-supreme-court-cairns-enters-day-five/106010578</link><description>A jury trial of former Innisfail nurse Rajwinder Singh, who is charged with the Far North Queensland woman's 2018 murder, has heard details about Ms Cordingley's phone data from the afternoon she disappeared.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c88546a9b95e6d6c32c51ddced13acfb</guid></item><item><title>Australia earns Billie Jean King Cup victory over Portugal, Maya Joint and Kim Birrell claim wins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/australia-takes-billie-jean-king-cup-lead/106012368</link><description>Australia got their Billie Jean King Cup play-off campaign to a successful start, with two straight sets singles victories over Portugal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc58f4b96e882d6420e5bd6a712bef24</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's Lake St Clair confirmed as Australia's deepest with 3D mapping technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/mapping-depth-tasmania-lake-st-clair-csiro-lidar-sonar/106010694</link><description>Recent CSIRO research definitively places Tasmania's Lake St Clair at 163 metres deep, nearly twice the depth of Bass Strait.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e206f304b6fabe6cd90e9571d2581f34</guid></item><item><title>Meg Lanning hits 90* in 100th WBBL game as Stars down Scorchers by 16 runs, Strikers defeat Renegades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/lanning-dominates-stars-down-scorchers/106012420</link><description>Former Australia captain Meg Lanning and South Africa batter Laura Wolvaardt sparkle in wins for the Melbourne Stars and Adelaide Strikers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83fa56a770e3a5a14b3427c802a73446</guid></item><item><title>Rodney Neville Watkins jailed for historic sexual abuse of four Perth schoolboys</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/predatory-perth-teacher-jailed-for-abuse-primary-school-students/106010050</link><description>A former Perth teacher who abused four schoolboys in the 1970s and 80s, in behaviour a District Court Judge described as "predatory", is jailed for 16 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d607af0a91dae07c460c9fafcef73f0d</guid></item><item><title>Free concert in Melbourne CBD cancelled after overcrowding and safety concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/fed-square-amyl-and-the-sniffers-concert-cancelled/106012558</link><description>A free concert scheduled in Melbourne's Fed Square was cancelled at the last minute on Friday night, with organisers citing overcrowding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b4dc17084f55f990ab61f1547ac1a9a</guid></item><item><title>More than 11,000 customers lose power as storms with spectacular lightning hit south-east Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/qld-severe-storms-see-thousands-lose-power-in-lightning-show/106012492</link><description>An intense storm cell with dramatic lightning moves over the Brisbane area, delaying Friday evening commuters with heavy rain, strong winds and large hail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">195124137eee398d85cdc218c7127fd9</guid></item><item><title>Corey Rocchiccioli stars as WA beats Queensland in one-wicket Sheffield Shield thriller</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-14/rocchiccioli-stars-as-wa-beats-queensland-sheffield-shield/106012590</link><description>Spinner Corey Rocchiccioli and No. 11 Cameron Gannon combine for a 23-run final wicket stand to deliver Western Australia a last-gasp Sheffield Shield victory over Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">350b16f5dea0c334618a0a67f0617a2f</guid></item><item><title>Court finds 'pollutant' BHP liable over deadly Brazilian dam collapse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/bhp-found-liable-over-deadly-mariana-dam-disaster-in-court/106012632</link><description>A British court has ruled mining giant BHP liable for a deadly dam collapse in Brazil a decade ago, which sparked one of the world's largest environmental disasters on record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dabafdf511f5264b8516546f774dec2f</guid></item><item><title>Trump's BBC and Epstein sagas dominate attention as international relations are rewritten</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/trump-bb-epstein-sagas-international-relations-rewritten/106010438</link><description>As what's happening in Trump's America dominates our attention there is a lot going on, mostly involving everyone else around the world refashioning their politics in an environment that has never seemed more uncertain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f45432a716a9f37538c96711f649e0f9</guid></item><item><title>The Paris conundrum at the heart of the Coalition's net zero backflip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/the-conundrum-at-the-core-of-the-coalition-net-zero-backflip/106011598</link><description>Liberal shadow cabinet members landed on a plan that has left many inside and outside the party bewildered and confused.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fb746f31ca9dfde8afe0d6a5f5f623a</guid></item><item><title>Jeffrey Epstein emails show he kept tabs on Donald Trump for years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/epsteins-emails-shed-light-on-his-preoccupation-with-trump/106010802</link><description>A trove of Jeffrey Epstein emails released this week reveals his preoccupation with US President Donald Trump in the years before Epstein's death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3711a02a04a2c4302a0d272cc4ff759e</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Forrest is betting on renewable energy in Queensland's coal heartland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/andrew-twiggy-forrest-backing-renewable-energy-in-queensland/105957172</link><description>At a wind farm in central Queensland, the billionaire backer and the local boilermaker offer a glimpse into how the energy transition is reshaping regional communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95ee7ebbe1a095c0c5f23087afe1493f</guid></item><item><title>Financial markets meltdown fears spread as US interest rate cut hopes fade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/financial-market-meltdown-fears-as-hopes-of-rate-cut-fades/106010576</link><description>Markets are heading south over fears about the US economy and interest rates not falling. Analysts fear mortgage holders and superannuates are in the firing line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39645985fb483d777cf6a3cb45de0418</guid></item><item><title>Nationals leader happy to let Liberals 'dream' of net zero in Coalition deal on climate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/nationals-leader-on-coalition-climate-deal/106012386</link><description>The Nationals will be meeting with the Liberals on Sunday to sign off on a climate policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9792d5950828ed60dd7a29460942f4af</guid></item><item><title>Health star ratings likely to become mandatory as food industry misses 70pc target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/food-health-star-ratings-mandate-industry-misses-target/106005758</link><description>Health ministers will meet next year and decide whether or not to make the system mandatory for all packaged food, something public health experts say is overdue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">543820576370a9410e01510f65cc9320</guid></item><item><title>After tireless advocacy and a dark history, Australia has a treaty with its First Peoples</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/australia-signs-first-treaty-with-aboriginal-people-in-victoria/106009328</link><description>Aunty Thelma lived through the mission era, stolen children and forced assimilation. As she witnessed the signing of the country's first treaty, her thoughts were on those who came before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ecc8059bcea9399dd81f5be810c2709</guid></item><item><title>One millionth refugee milestone in Australia on horizon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/australia-one-million-refugees-since-wwii/106005488</link><description>Australia is set to issue its one millionth refugee visa since 1947 in the coming weeks, in a humanitarian program that grew directly out the ashes of World War II.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96fd971fa30c044ec1f872fddde7f4d5</guid></item><item><title>As the social media ban sets in, how do you decide what TV to let your kids watch?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/social-media-ban-decide-kids-watch-tv-mad-men/106010214</link><description>We have navigated this new path of "what to watch/what to censor/what to allow" with stumbling footsteps. I'd love to tell you we have been perfectly consistent. We have not.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">602dd0fed8a47a81410bef8a48886887</guid></item><item><title>Jannik Sinner wary of Alex de Minaur ahead of ATP Finals semis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/tennis-atp-finals-jannik-sinner-alex-de-minaur-semifinals/106013206</link><description>Reigning champion Jannik Sinner says he will need to produce his best tennis to get past Alex de Minaur in the semis at the season-ending ATP Finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de0096d987c9d969cd1f0f77b696a5f0</guid></item><item><title>Football coach Zia Younan found quietly playing in Melbourne suburbs despite FIFA ban for match-fixing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/banned-soccer-coach-zia-younan-found-playing-in-suburban-leagues/106009158</link><description>A corrupt coach who was banned for life by the world football governing body for match-fixing has been quietly playing for clubs in suburban Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c4a876cd451ed856b62d8e9dd1ad55d</guid></item><item><title>Ewens Ponds set to reopen for public snorkelling after environmental concerns prompted closure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/ewens-ponds-diving-reopened-after-water-concerns/105973720</link><description>A date is set for snorkellers to return Ewens Ponds on South Australia's Limestone Coast, after low water flows caused its closure to the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d938e4575624ca15d9252385ce1860a</guid></item><item><title>England great James Anderson tips Australian Ashes win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/cricket-ashes-james-anderson-england-australia/106013276</link><description>Legendary England fast bowler James Anderson says Australia is favourite to win the men's Ashes series on home soil, but feels the hosts will field their "weakest" team in 15 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1df86a6d1f314790c2b88925d10671cd</guid></item><item><title>Dolly Parton heads to Australian desert in unique exhibit celebrating rising art star Kaylene Whiskey</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/act-super-kaylene-whiskey-exhibition-national-portrait-gallery/106012440</link><description>Dolly Parton has never stepped foot on the dry red dirt of Indulkana in remote South Australia, but she is a frequent visitor in the art of Kaylene Whisky, which celebrates sisterhood and strong women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a5888fbf2ada0a905258b072ec37c7d</guid></item><item><title>Guy Sebastian's new album looks back on remarkable career</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/guy-sebastian-reflects-on-his-remarkable-career/105978684</link><description>Guy Sebastian looks back on the good fortune he has enjoyed in his music career, with the release of his 10th studio album, 100 Times Around the Sun.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">716ac837cd4cf2e0b77d74ce9d85deb2</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump seeks probe of Epstein ties to JP Morgan, Bill Clinton and other prominent Democrats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/trump-orders-epstein-probe-into-clinton-jp-morgan-democrats/106013208</link><description>The request comes two days after thousands of documents were released that raised new questions about Mr Trump's relationship with Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a8d351cc456dd6524275933490310a0</guid></item><item><title>Bureau of Meteorology predicting another round of severe storms for south-east Queensland this weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/qld-weather-wrap-saturday-storms-predicted-by-bom/106011002</link><description>Large hail, damaging winds and heavy rainfall are all on the cards, with another round of severe storms due to hit south-east Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8619afaee3c77b31c3f2ebef3d69064</guid></item><item><title>Nearly half of women enrolled in Queensland homebirth program transferred to hospital, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/qld-homebirth-program-public-funded-12-months-report/106009706</link><description>The homebirth program was launched at the Sunshine Coast University Hospital in July 2024, with 74 women enrolled in the service in its first 12 months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d499e9ee78c05de12bd3434b7036759</guid></item><item><title>Federal government's homebuyer scheme helps young couple enter Brisbane property market as unit prices soar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/unit-prices-property-market-brisbane-unit-million/105996524</link><description>A young couple bought a one-bedroom unit in inner-Brisbane using the government’s 5 per cent deposit scheme. Around the same time, a two-bedroom brick walk-up in the same suburb sold for just over $1m, highlighting soaring unit prices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">330a6e3f28b8efa2377cdf8520a80a7f</guid></item><item><title>Thieves steal 65 young pigs from farm at Cranbrook in WA's Great Southern</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/thieves-steal-65-young-pigs-from-cranbrook-property-in-wa/105996932</link><description>A Cranbrook farmer says he feels like "the stuffing has been knocked out" of him after dozens of young pigs had been stolen from his property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85462403fd90446239dd93a35b42958a</guid></item><item><title>Trial of Rajwinder Singh, charged with murder of Far North Queensland woman Toyah Cordingley, concludes first week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/rajwinder-singh-trial-charged-with-murder-/106012200</link><description>Former Innisfail nurse Rajwinder Singh, 41, is standing trial over the 24-year-old's 2018 murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30b7ac58957120dd95352da96f556b81</guid></item><item><title>The Veronicas and Katy Perry songs behind Carlton and Hawthorn's finals campaigns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/the-songs-behind-carlton-hawthorn-aflw-semi-final/106013354</link><description>Before each game, the sides will blast a song to get their energy up, each emblematic of their seasons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b80205dd3e04caba0adbe26af6b1e68a</guid></item><item><title>A Great Act of Love by Heather Rose delves into her family's convict history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/heather-rose-new-book-a-great-act-of-love/106005806</link><description>In A Great Act of Love, the award-winning author interweaves a surprising chapter of Tasmanian history with the story of her ancestor who was transported to Van Diemen's Land in the 1800s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf87a42c95961b9dc560d58e6df29f33</guid></item><item><title>Liz Stringer raises money for housing charities on huge tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/liz-stringer-housing-tour-australia-dates-second-high/106007614</link><description>The renowned singer-songwriter is on the road in support of her eighth album. Now, more than ever, she knows how to focus on what matters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53bcc66ace90f8a59beae29b1b310173</guid></item><item><title>Fuss-free sticky beef and noodles for busy weeknights - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/sticky-beef-with-noodles-mint/105981016</link><description>This tasty, nourishing dish requires minimal prep and is quick and easy to throw together.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8d3d74bee7933d43fc72fd320f634dc</guid></item><item><title>NT government flags new fines for owners whose pet crocodiles escape</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/nt-government-introduces-new-pet-crocodile-ownership-rules/106011808</link><description>Crocodile owners whose pets escape and have to be recaptured by rangers could soon face penalties starting at $300, plus another $100 for each hour the reptiles are on the loose.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83717d2c1421addc1ee177f8590b3373</guid></item><item><title>Mona has lost $408 million since it opened in Tasmania but founder David Walsh doesn't mind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/mona-founder-david-walsh-on-future-of-tasmanian-museum/105982838</link><description>Hobart's landmark Museum of Old and New Art has racked up a staggering amount in losses since it opened in 2011, but founder David Walsh is still building.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f86bad330747f23072b91fc98553bd2b</guid></item><item><title>Amyl and the Sniffers shout Melbourne live music venues $35k in free drinks after gig cancelled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/amyl-and-the-sniffers-massive-bar-tab-after-fed-square-cancel/106012954</link><description>After their homecoming Fed Square gig was cancelled over security fears, Amyl and the Sniffers put $5,000 behind the bar at seven live music venues around Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e21c519850c76a221fe6d3baeb5423a</guid></item><item><title>Here's how Japan's PM found herself in a diplomatic spat with China over Taiwan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/japan-pm-takaichi-sparks-diplomatic-spat-with-china-over-taiwan/106012856</link><description>Sanae Takaichi has been in the top job for less than a month, but her comments detailing what Japan could do if China invaded Taiwan has sparked a diplomatic war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aead0e5f158af4be0ca9cb53d2a901d3</guid></item><item><title>Golf club in the scrub powered by a generator, community spirit and dirt-cheap fees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/toolondo-golf-club-thrives-in-regional-victoria/105945988</link><description>The only flashy thing at this golf club in regional Victoria is the community spirit, but it is enough for them to thrive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e09ec8c42d2a4dbbfa0e1d5434e85cc</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump signs order to drop tariffs on hundreds of foods, including beef</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/trump-agriculture-beef-tariff-exemptions/106013518</link><description>Hundreds of food products, including beef and oranges, are now exempted from US trade tariffs, according to an executive order signed by President Donald Trump on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94cc598b29d020c165df325514a14bac</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies vow to bounce back in Ireland Test as spring tour continues in Dublin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/rugby-union-wallabies-prepare-to-face-ireland/106013576</link><description>Hit hard by last weekend's loss to Italy, the Wallabies are desperate to rebound when they face Ireland in Dublin on Sunday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">226388cffe19ee43d4b7dcbd09b5ac86</guid></item><item><title>What Australia can learn from China to become the world's 'cleaner' rare earth refiner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/australia-refining-rare-earths-environmental-challenges/105969994</link><description>As Australia races to scale up refining of rare earths, a thorny question looms: where does all the toxic wastewater go?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06dc511b156215c9f67c047f0c944bd0</guid></item><item><title>Karratha hopes to become NBL1 West's most remote basketball club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/pitch-for-karratha-australias-most-remote-basketball-team/105987726</link><description>A community brimming with basketball enthusiasts in WA's north aims to join the NBL1 West within five years, becoming the most far-flung team to do so.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">937b1a731786ea6c66e57b75c202ce4e</guid></item><item><title>More than a month into the Israel-Gaza ceasefire, here is what has changed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/israel-gaza-ceasefire-one-month-on-what-has-changed/106013388</link><description>The fragile ceasefire in Gaza has now been in place for five weeks. Here is what has changed, what has not, and where things currently stand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3ba832f0ed79f6adf4011d2be982fba</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos fall to disjointed 1-0 loss to Venezuela in Houston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/disjointed-socceroos-lose-to-venezuela/106012522</link><description>Australia's hopes of a favourable draw for next year's World Cup take a hit with a disappointing 1-0 loss to Venezuela in Texas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45bb2143c8c71278dfa97f6a2a52c4c7</guid></item><item><title>The 'gun' shearer still setting a cracking pace at 85</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/john-harris-shearing-legacy-glengower-victoria/106009312</link><description>Australian shearing legend John Harris has returned to a central Victorian woolshed for the 75th year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94520388e9fce12775284bb46066f5c7</guid></item><item><title>Queensland GPs to be able to diagnose adults with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder from December 1</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/qld-gps-to-diagnose-adhd-and-prescribe-medication/106013548</link><description>From December 1, specialist general practitioners will have the ability to diagnose adults with ADHD and prescribe medication, in an Australian first.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cbb6041c09f20d827857d6db6f779be</guid></item><item><title>Video games are not banned at this Japanese high school, they are part of the curriculum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/the-japan-tokyo-school-where-students-play-video-games/106004378</link><description>Japan's education system is renowned for its rigidity. But one school is providing an alternative, blending typical education classes with intensive video game training.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff35046d95a4ece3835e5c25b0bb30f9</guid></item><item><title>NT's high rates of diabetes and amputations highlighted by territory health professionals on World Diabetes Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/nt-high-rates-of-diabetes-flagged-world-diabetes-day/106009950</link><description>The Northern Territory has some of the highest rates of diabetes globally, with health professionals warning that the cost of living is making it harder for those living in remote communities to access a nutritious diet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bf24a2fe3e09179d2c47ed4dd74f2dc</guid></item><item><title>US President Donald Trump says he plans to sue BBC for up to $US5 billion over documentary edit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/donald-trump-will-sue-the-bbc-over-documentary-edit/106013634</link><description>The US president added that he also planned to raise the issue with British Prime Minister Keir Starmer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efd7bd0d8903063a76eb8e9ec8911535</guid></item><item><title>First school reopens as risk from asbestos exposure deemed 'extremely low'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/first-school-reopens-coloured-sand-asbestos-low-risk/106013676</link><description>Seventeen schools were shut down on Friday after concerns about asbestos exposure. The reopening of one of the schools has been fast-tracked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd8be227610ea56f20751499bf5bc9f9</guid></item><item><title>Cell Block Studios preserves history of Old Geraldton Gaol as a hub for local artists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/cell-block-studios-preserves-history-of-old-geraldton-gaol/105996344</link><description>Once a place of punishment, Old Geraldton Gaol is now a site of creativity after being saved from demolition by a group of local artists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8948073177833970a2075bb853454dff</guid></item><item><title>Urgent review of Federation Square security ordered after Amyl and the Sniffers concert cancelled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/amyl-sniffers-federation-square-security-review/106013698</link><description>The operators of Federation Square promise an urgent security review after locked-out attendees broke through fences at the free concert, but say the band's fan base is not to blame.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56b6b4702f7f6684adfea30bfc0c9473</guid></item><item><title>Restaurant business booms as monsoon rains cause river to flood in Thailand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/thai-restaurant-pa-jit-floods-business-booms/106013384</link><description>Fish are not just on the menu in this Thai restaurant — they are also swimming around the tables and bringing in diners happy to sit in waist-deep river water while enjoying their meals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8ff8f50ba7e59cc858b0d41a4b0ee1b</guid></item><item><title>Coloured sand linked to asbestos contamination scare found at over 100 SA sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/sa-sites-have-sand-linked-to-asbestos-contamination-scare/106013536</link><description>Coloured sand products linked to an asbestos contamination scare have so far been identified at more than 100 sites in South Australia following checks at schools and preschools, the state's education department says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c5f99cd335d0c3e0c00060b8f7b2767</guid></item><item><title>Josh Hazlewood ruled out of Ashes opener in Perth in blow to Australia's hopes against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/hazlewood-out-of-ashes-opener-in-massive-blow-for-australia/106013902</link><description>Australian quick Josh Hazlewood is ruled out of the opening Ashes Test match against England in Perth with a hamstring injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57a8ac180885e0219f5805ad7ca82d87</guid></item><item><title>Hospitality group Norths Collective looking to offload Far North Coast clubs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/sydney-hospitality-group-selling-two-far-north-coast-clubs/105937424</link><description>Sydney-based Norths Collective looks to offload two Far North Coast sporting clubs to cap losses and pay down debt of about $30 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e486bbcba40169de6b7dae1c36c97308</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne comes back to beat Adelaide in AFLW semifinal, Carlton advances with Hawthorn demolition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/hore-leads-demons-in-comeback-semifinal-win-over-crows/106013944</link><description>Melbourne is through to the AFLW preliminary finals as Kate Hore inspires the Demons to a comeback win over Adelaide, while Carlton demolishes a depleted Hawthorn.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c12718b9f928a563915afc3f9529fe08</guid></item><item><title>Three NT residents charged with fraud over alleged $71 million Defence contract scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/afp-charge-three-nt-over-alleged-multi-million-fraud-scheme/106013768</link><description>The AFP has raided homes and businesses across Darwin after a tip-off that a Defence employee, his wife, and a director of a building firm were allegedly involved in a fraudulent scheme to steer multi-million-dollar Defence building contracts their way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f902ce406c177bbb63e2a5bdc98015b</guid></item><item><title>Astronaut Katherine Bennell-Pegg named SA's Australian of the Year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/astronaut-katherine-bennell-pegg-sa-australian-of-the-year/106012362</link><description>When Katherine Bennell-Pegg was growing up, she was "mesmerised by the stars" — an enthusiasm that motivated her to pursue astronaut training, and has now secured an honour of a different kind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9ed5d025c4ab1b48f1f1d28b5c944cf</guid></item><item><title>What France's famous cave replicas can teach Australia about rebuilding lost heritage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/juukan-gorge-replica-rebuild-rio-tinto-ppk-france-/106012544</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49ddd6f3b5399718cc88508e6a5e4ad6</guid></item><item><title>Former Katter's Australian Party MP Nick Dametto ahead in early count for Townsville mayoral by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/counting-begins-townsville-mayor-election/106009322</link><description>Eight candidates are vying for the top role, including the city's former mayor, Troy Thompson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b58350df332ace1e648294f18c50b1fb</guid></item><item><title>England completes sole Ashes warm-up match with flurry of runs to Ollie Pope, Joe Root</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/england-completes-sole-ashes-warm-up-match-pope-root/106014128</link><description>Ollie Pope tunes up for the first Ashes Test with hard-hitting knocks of 100 and 90 in England's only warm-up match at Lilac Hill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eb9ce0564421eda3a89be3065490ab1</guid></item><item><title>Democratic Republic of Congo and M23 rebel group sign new roadmap to peace in Qatar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/democratic-republic-congo-m23-sign-peace-roadmap/106014172</link><description>At the ceremony, Qatar's chief negotiator Mohammed Al-Khulaifi called the agreement "historic", adding that mediators would continue efforts to achieve peace on the ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95ceb80d6aae4e99bec5eb9602986746</guid></item><item><title>Pope Leo XIV urges Hollywood actors to resist algorithms and save neighbourhood cinemas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/pope-leo-meets-cate-blanchett-spike-lee-vatican-audience/106014170</link><description>Pope Leo XIV tells a group of leading Hollywood actors and filmmakers during an audience at the Vatican that more should be done to protect struggling neighbourhood cinemas, to preserve the shared experience of watching movies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39e96906d1f19ddde661905e92e4c716</guid></item><item><title>Social media has changed how we get the news and politicians are capitalising on it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/annabel-crabb-civic-duty-social-media/106007956</link><description>When a delegation of "influencers" appeared at Canberra's budget lock-up this year, joining press gallery journalists in the increasingly arcane tradition of reading a complex document for a few quiet hours before bursting forth in analysis thereof, much comment was made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b63cf42732ea63c2e79f7c330eb395e</guid></item><item><title>The old-school landline is having a cultural moment in a world of screens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/landline-rotary-phone-social-media-ban-family-connect/106010638</link><description>As smartphones swallow childhood, a growing movement of parents is reinstalling landlines, hoping an old-school corded phone can restore patience and connection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12eb6c09a56ba6c0d117f1b31fd62bfc</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur exits ATP Finals as Jannik Sinner reaches decider</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/atp-finals-alex-de-minaur-loses-to-jannik-sinner/106014668</link><description>Alex de Minaur falls to Jannik Sinner for the 13th straight time, as the Italian advances to the final of the season-ending championship for the third consecutive year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e230cee3c88b68baf48d8e9b27e2c161</guid></item><item><title>Survivors of Sudan's El-Fasher conquest say they were attacked while escaping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/survivors-of-sudan-el-fasher-conquest-attacked-while-escaping/106003668</link><description>With Sudan's El-Fasher captured by a militia accused of mass killings, those who escaped are suffering in a refugee camp and mourning the deaths of family and friends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e86b511cd97badb6d078ffe9838c5b86</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fall to record-breaking defeat against late-surging Ireland in Dublin, Mack Hansen scores hat-trick</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/live-updates-ireland-vs-wallabies-dublin/106010192</link><description>The Wallabies's losing run on their spring tour continues, as Ireland records a convincing 46-19 victory on home soil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c58c9c21b234d411d1f115c8675dc91</guid></item><item><title>Property investors say they're 'boosting rental supply', but it can be a rhetorical trick</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/property-investors-boosting-supply-of-rentals-or-dwellings/106012670</link><description>Are they boosting the supply of rental housing by financing the construction of new dwellings, or buying pre-existing owner-occupied homes and converting them to rentals?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6811cb40a36c52cabe97de6b5518a15a</guid></item><item><title>The infamous photo former prince Andrew can't outrun</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/photo-former-prince-andrew-virginia-giuffre/106009338</link><description>More than 20 years after this photo was purportedly taken, it continues to haunt Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac9147d2e1850deea3230203303529f9</guid></item><item><title>England confident Jofra Archer will fire against Australia in Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/ashes-series-england-australia-jofra-archer/106014680</link><description>Injury may have stalled his Test career, but Jofra Archer is showing signs he will be at his best when the men's Ashes series gets underway in Perth on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc054839dab06d6b62fb2ec2a0457e1a</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: We're here to test your trivia smarts. It's time to play … HARD!</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/105996558</link><description>It's the perfect day to confirm just how little you know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ce1fcb28a21f0f1cd82e13df46561e0</guid></item><item><title>Forestry looks to carbon market in wake of Great Koala National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/great-koala-national-park-forestry-future-carbon-market/105954932</link><description>The Great Koala National Park was announced to protect koalas and forests in northern NSW, but the forestry industry has been left wondering how it can fill a shortfall in supply.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59b353918710affce02350d5b8df1756</guid></item><item><title>John Aloisi reflects on the 20-year anniversary with ABC Weekend Breakfast.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/john-aloisi-reflects-on-the-20-year-anniversary/106013624</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54211d41d6ef9adc32c4959de0dc2758</guid></item><item><title>Huge crowds at live sites and pubs around Australia erupted after the Socceroos won.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/socceroos-fans-celebrate/106013560</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fa60136606d8d060ee019ce5352ecce</guid></item><item><title>The other-worldly ecstasy of the Socceroos' penalty shootout against Uruguay, 20 years on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/socceroos-uruguay-world-cup-qualifier-20-year-anniversary/106010284</link><description>Nostalgia can be an intoxicating force, especially when it comes to the 20-year anniversary of the Socceroos' remarkable win over Uruguay on penalties, which remains an Australian cultural touchpoint.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47245075f2a8785886b932f62bc620e3</guid></item><item><title>Rebuilding Juukan Gorge: Traditional owners turn to France for restoration plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/juukan-gorge-replica-rebuild-rio-tinto-ppk-france-inspiration/105949740</link><description>Five years after Rio Tinto destroyed a 47,000-year-old sacred rock shelter to expand an iron ore mine, an ambitious rebuild is underway drawing inspiration all the way from France.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de9425a9476d7c3af156b6d7b2c1414b</guid></item><item><title>Sunbury residents fear waste-to-energy proposal risks health and environment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/sunbury-waste-to-energy-incinerator-hiq-bulla-landfill/106006600</link><description>Sunbury residents say they are tired of being the state's "dumping ground" after waste-to-energy facility proposed nearby a receives a cap license from Recycling Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6845e30ea7b6c660b6e21464de2ca732</guid></item><item><title>Legal experts, civil libertarians warn the NSW government is 'eroding' the right to protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/nsw-protest-laws-eroding-right-to-protest-say-legal-experts/106006324</link><description>When 60 neo-Nazis lined outside NSW parliament last week, the premier's response was swift and familiar — steadily tightening the state's protest laws in response to flashpoint events.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31ea4c2c9ef06864b01f04216911c228</guid></item><item><title>Deadly Indonesian landslide buries victims up to 8 metres deep in Java village</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/indonesia-landslide-cibeunying-central-java/106014696</link><description>After days of heavy rain in Central Java, a landslide buries a dozen houses in Cibeunying village.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52ea7b411bd51e914bdf7346383bbf2f</guid></item><item><title>Endangered bandicoots given new home free of feral predators in regional NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/bandicoots-given-a-new-home-mallee-cliffs-national-park/105995106</link><description>Twenty endangered bandicoots are roaming south-west New South Wales in an effort to return bandicoots to the region after several species were wiped out in the late 1800s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c46dea045a97336604f93f035b9ad0b</guid></item><item><title>Sixers teenager Caoimhe Bray claims WBBL hat-trick in 24-run win over Thunder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/wbbl-sydney-sixers-thunder-caoimhe-bray-hat-trick/106014712</link><description>Sydney Sixers rising star Caoimhe Bray needed to be told she had taken a hat-trick, as the 16-year-old added another WBBL highlight in a thumping derby defeat of the Thunder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0d7e129714674d7783957c8ea49e2e2</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast Schoolies celebrations set to be scaled back and subdued</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/gold-coast-schoolies-scaled-back-and-subdued/106012262</link><description>Schoolies celebrations on the Gold Coast will look different this year due to beach erosion in the wake of Cyclone Alfred.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd6bb9bc6efc1c335447d54cd1a25c29</guid></item><item><title>India and Pakistan have faced the deadliest terror attacks on their capitals in a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/india-pakistan-deadly-terror-attacks-in-delhi-islamabad/106013650</link><description>In just 48 hours, almost 30 people were killed and dozens more injured in the deadliest terrorist assaults on the capitals of both India and Pakistan in more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0e54e563cf82b482504d0bcfb5d5d51</guid></item><item><title>Survival camping isn't for everyone — so how would you go in the wilderness? Take the quiz to find out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/survival-camping-quiz-tasmanian-wilderness/105888688</link><description>For 18-year-old Rivi, knowing what gear to leave behind can be as important as knowing what to take with.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab49ce291cf03e60517a144569b2e9c7</guid></item><item><title>Spectators injured when car crashes into crowd at Walcha showground rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/walcha-derby-rally-crash-nine-people-injured-two-critical/106014754</link><description>Nine people are hospitalised after a car crashed into spectators at a rally event in regional NSW on Saturday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa41a695e098c07af1be8d64f6de54bb</guid></item><item><title>Rain brings relief across much of Victoria but the drought is 'certainly not over'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/victorian-drought-not-over-despite-relief-of-spring-rain/106004802</link><description>Dusty Victorian farms turn muddy as drenching rain brings much-needed relief.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87d1f24f3b4d20878cb22c831a1aa5d7</guid></item><item><title>Rose Byrne plays a mother on the edge in Mary Bronstein's If I Had Legs I'd Kick You</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/if-i-had-legs-i-kick-you-rose-byrne-movie-mary-bronstein/105977540</link><description>The Sydney-born movie star discusses how her creative partnership with If I had Legs I'd Kick You director Mary Bronstein has opened the Oscars conversation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a57ec37515d332a6074b6269009da5c4</guid></item><item><title>Sergey Lavrov was one of Vladimir Putin's top allies on the world stage. And then, he was gone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/mystery-surrounds-missing-russian-foreign-minister-sergey-lavrov/106008516</link><description>For more than two decades, Sergey Lavrov has been Russia's top foreign diplomat, representing the Kremlin's regime around the world, but late last month, he disappeared.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45f8c3cacfd91b10388d63f50b589d5b</guid></item><item><title>Thunderstorms and heavy rain forecast for parts of Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/queensland-sunday-storms-heavy-rain-river-warnings/106014806</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says parts of Queensland and New South Wales will likely see smaller pockets of severe thunderstorm activity on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e83a3e313c7dcee756dcedeb4f73d0a6</guid></item><item><title>Inspection of Weona Park horse stud found several serious animal welfare issues, just weeks before public outcry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/weona-horse-stud/106012012</link><description>Investigators warned the "situation" at a horse stud in the state's south "is likely to [be] the next welfare issue hitting the news".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff8f2c6eb64387a9de9b3397ae1d51b1</guid></item><item><title>Storm Claudia floods town of Monmouth in Wales, after killing three people in Portugal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/storm-claudia-floods-in-wales-portugal/106014746</link><description>Storm Claudia moves to Wales, swamping the town of Monmouth, where dozens of people are rescued or evacuated from their homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e667a7be28a1944f2be23c46ad4589b0</guid></item><item><title>Horned 'devil' bee found in remote Goldfields prompts call for further research</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/horned-lucifer-bee-discovery-goldfields/105997548</link><description>The discovery of a new "lucifer" bee with devil-like horns sparks concerns over land clearing regulations in WA's Goldfields region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae67dce636b1d6d9780e5a16b4b27f80</guid></item><item><title>Amid ongoing drought in South Australia, these women are redefining resilience</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/women-showing-up-for-community-during-drought/105926946</link><description>Dusty paddocks, with no grain crop to harvest, and scarce feed for the few animals left, is the reality of many South Australian farmers right now. Four women are redefining resilience and showing what it means to endure tough conditions despite it all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5497b2acddf11b8b1ea3f54f23673983</guid></item><item><title>Victorian farmer to auction father's vintage tractor collection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/victorian-farmer-to-auction-fathers-vintage-tractor-collection/105990840</link><description>Tony Forrest reflects on his father's love of old tractors as he prepares them for sale.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8c2f2f7c59d020c9c17b7e189a1935c</guid></item><item><title>Indonesian school kids poisoned by free school lunches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/indonesian-school-kids-poisoned-by-free-school-lunches/106010538</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61fbcb16360c16afdcf8e5c097d19b79</guid></item><item><title>Aldo Revaldo taken to hospital with suspected poisoning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/aldo-repaldo-taken-to-hospital-with-suspected-poisoning/106010560</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb1cad64e02ae52dcb0ae19ad430e102</guid></item><item><title>How free school meals gave thousands of children food poisoning in Indonesia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/indonesia-free-school-meals-program-for-kids-in-schools-problems/106009984</link><description>Despite thousands of cases of food poisoning, Indonesia's government intends to expand a controversial program giving schoolchildren free meals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d079a30ad4ea57b0a6fa6d30e61416a4</guid></item><item><title>Accusations of secrecy, abuse of power fly as WA Labor wades through third term</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/wa-government-accused-of-secrecy-abuse-of-power/106010294</link><description>Accusations of secrecy and abuse of process have been levelled at the Western Australian government this week on several fronts. Are they blips on the radar or signs WA Labor is under strain?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">641b8039ba4f80240938b1dff54fec01</guid></item><item><title>Fourth case of measles confirmed after Jelly Roll concert at Brisbane Entertainment Centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/fourth-measles-case-confirmed-after-jelly-roll-concert/106014898</link><description>Authorities say a case had been identified in the Logan region after three cases linked to the concert at the Brisbane Entertainment Centre on October 24 were confirmed on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc09641cf8ec80e2d65bf674da768f83</guid></item><item><title>British government announces its largest asylum policy overhaul in modern times</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/britain-changes-asylum-policy/106014852</link><description>Polls suggest immigration has now overtaken the economy as British voters' top concern.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed1480a7e758d46837266e941caad3ea</guid></item><item><title>Monmouth in Wales is flooded after Storm Claudia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/monmouth-in-wales-is-flooded-after-storm-claudia/106014972</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">486448b36191d2c8078d8f663f5b5416</guid></item><item><title>Wong won't put price tag on COP31 as final host decision looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/cop31-price-penny-wong/106014762</link><description>Foreign Minister Penny Wong has refused to say how much it would cost Australia to hold the COP31 climate conference, as negotiations over hosting rights enter the final stages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a300239a7111e75ab0cafa979cd434c</guid></item><item><title>Winton Hotel changes hands amid 'exceptional' Queensland pub sales</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/winton-hotel-sold-amid-booming-outback-pub-sales/106005676</link><description>As the Winton Hotel in outback Queensland changes hands, an accommodation broker says the cost of housing in coastal areas is driving outback pub and hotel sales, as a place to live and do business.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8ae72c17b98e9cf3e28cb911d0adcdc</guid></item><item><title>Car crashes into crowd at Walcha showground rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/car-crashes-into-crowd-at-walcha-showground-rally/106014990</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e59ec862f30aea2262d1ca9356891b5b</guid></item><item><title>Young people in Ballarat share their stories with ABC Takeover</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/young-people-in-regional-areas-tell-their-stories-abc-takeover/106004344</link><description>Hundreds of young people from Ballarat, Victoria have taken part in ABC Takeover, an initiative that gives young people in regional areas a platform to share their stories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c8e8a84e260c55a3c895f1126d03f06</guid></item><item><title>West Gate Tunnel safety, Metro Rail Tunnel opening and SRL funding in the spotlight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/west-gate-tunnel-walkthrough-metro-tunnel-early-open/106014830</link><description>The Victorian government has defended the safety of the soon-to-be-opened West Gate Tunnel as a visit from Prime Minister Anthony Albanese coincided with key Metro Tunnel and Suburban Rail Loop updates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e84abbffe73efff0559ae2f1c80367e0</guid></item><item><title>Love of toys takes former retailer from Sydney's CBD to Blayney library</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/louise-sheather-hero-of-blayney-toy-library/105994988</link><description>After a career in one of Sydney's busiest department stores, a retail expert takes her tricks of the trade to a toy library in central west NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ed4e3cbc45b5b1c67feede6e2529171</guid></item><item><title>T100 Dubai triathlon 'technical issue' sees extra bike lap and runners stopping short</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/t100-dubai-chaos-hayden-wilde-pto/106014892</link><description>A missed turn on the bike, a miscount on the run and an athlete protest turn the T100 Dubai event into a farce, with New Zealander Hayden Wilde left particularly livid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e91463b784b9a64fdbcd84a83db70416</guid></item><item><title>WA Labor senator slams proposed reduction of speed limits on unsigned roads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/labor-senator-opposed-reducing-speed-limit-on-unsigned-roads/105997390</link><description>A Labor senator says it's "stupidity" for the federal government to propose a reduction to the default speed limit for unsigned roads.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">335663c829b3c48c551d2e14f47a0131</guid></item><item><title>More coloured sand products recalled as ACT set to announce when schools will reopen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/more-coloured-sand-products-recalled-over-asbestos-fears/106014952</link><description>Kmart recalls four coloured sand products over concerns of asbestos contamination, as the ACT's education department is set to announce whether schools closed on Friday will reopen tomorrow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0c60746dd4e3f1d8cbdf98f839bc448</guid></item><item><title>Bail denied to teen accused of causing crash that killed pregnant woman and unborn child</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/teenage-driver-in-court-over-fatal-hornsby-crash/106014038</link><description>The 19-year-old accused of causing a crash at Hornsby on Friday night that claimed the life of a pregnant woman and her unborn child is denied bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12deb9505e88a5004ae005814578d976</guid></item><item><title>Government considers dramatic intervention to save Tomago smelter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/government-considers-intervention-to-save-tomago-smelter/106015238</link><description>The federal government is considering a power-purchase agreement with Tomago to supply electricity at a stable price, after warnings the smelter may need to close because of rising power costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4939cc71d7e33335bf2c9f977ab8634a</guid></item><item><title>Former MP Nick Dametto declares victory in Townsville mayoral by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/townsville-mayoral-by-election-nick-dametto-declares-victory/106014032</link><description>Nick Dametto, a former Queensland MP, has won 61 per cent of the votes counted, succeeding in his campaign to become Townsville's next mayor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e93915c10ec838af548b5920da333d1b</guid></item><item><title>Coalition plans to strip climate from energy operator's objectives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/coalition-joint-net-zero-position-leaked-submission/106015290</link><description>Emissions reduction would no longer be an objective of Australia's energy operator under a Coalition plan endorsed by the Nationals and Liberals, prioritising affordability and reliability over climate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e121017def600970fa4dff5d9f2618b7</guid></item><item><title>Calls for federal government to help 'stranded Australians' waiting in hospital for aged care bed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/critical-shortage-of-aged-care-beds-calls-federal-government/106010318</link><description>About 1,000 people are waiting in Queensland public hospitals for more appropriate care, such as a place in aged care, with infrastructure failing to keep up with the need.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4e9d39ecc3bdbcdbe884b027e9e26c2</guid></item><item><title>More than 90 patients stuck in Tasmanian hospitals waiting for aged care or NDIS support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/tasmanian-hospitals-bed-block-aged-care-ndis-funding-agreement/106015236</link><description>More than 90 Tasmanians who have been medically cleared to leave hospital are not able to because they are waiting for an aged care place or NDIS support. Premier Jeremy Rockliff says it's "not good enough" and is calling on the federal government to increase hospital funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4395de959a9953c7649153fbb7277ff3</guid></item><item><title>Six people remain in hospital after Walcha derby grandstand crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/walcha-motor-sport-derby-crash-multiple-injured/106014902</link><description>Six of 13 patients remain in hospital after a derby car crashed into a grandstand full of spectators at a Walcha council-run rally on Saturday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed4cb762e85610d60b7703248da341da</guid></item><item><title>WA government to cut council planning red tape to fast-track high-density housing in Perth suburbs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/wa-government-planning-reforms-to-fasttrack-high-rise-builds/106015210</link><description>Western Australians must shake off their aversion to apartment living and embrace high-density housing solutions to support population growth across the metropolitan area, the state government says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">523f35fafc85632806666599c1f4cdd8</guid></item><item><title>ACT to close 69 schools as more sand products recalled amid asbestos concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/act-to-close-schools-after-coloured-sand-recall-over-asbestos/106015398</link><description>The ACT will close more schools after additional coloured sand products were recalled by Kmart and Target, while the schools that were shut on Friday will reopen on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9518404fe2157f394c68f2bfa67ac72</guid></item><item><title>From 'female Donald Trump' to 'Wacky' Marjorie — how Taylor Greene's alliance with the president crumbled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/donald-trump-marjorie-taylor-greene-alliance-erupts/106015394</link><description>Once considered one of Donald Trump's most loyal soldiers, Marjorie Taylor Greene has found herself an outcast of the MAGA firm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce47c00f288f5b76e52c94fe74013bf6</guid></item></channel></rss>