<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 23:41:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Experts say it is safe to use paracetamol during pregnancy and Trump's autism declaration is 'baseless'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/taking-paracetamol-during-pregnancy-does-not-cause-autism/105806092</link><description>Donald Trump's advice that pregnant women should limit the use of paracetamol in pregnancy has been criticised as "baseless". So what does it mean for you?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81c81571674ce6c676915af2ca81de9b</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of hitting 42yo with vehicle in Kalgoorlie appears in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/detectives-from-major-crime-investigate-kalgoorlie-mans-death/105801802</link><description>A 29-year-old man has faced court today after detectives from WA Police's Homicide Squad charged him with murder, two days after the death of a man in the state's Goldfields.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46cd053682653a831ef9b4ab4db28ca6</guid></item><item><title>Man known as 'Moore Park Rapist' pleads guilty to series of sexual assaults in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/moore-park-rapist-glenn-cameron-pleads-guilty-sexual-assaults/105806986</link><description>Glenn Cameron has remained in custody since he was arrested in February last year and charged with more than 30 offences in relation to eight victims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c631b0b48e05bf34d6cd7b4127803d77</guid></item><item><title>Kevin Bacon on the importance of music, philanthropy and acting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/kevin-bacon-take-5-actor-music-philanthropy-interview/105793360</link><description>He's a prolific fixture on our screens who's famously six degrees from almost anyone. But Kevin Bacon is also a passionate musician and philanthropist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45104e05b24001759cca6f2985a81b97</guid></item><item><title>Why many Palestinians are underwhelmed by countries like Australia only now recognising statehood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/palestinians-react-to-statehood-recognition-australia-un/105805514</link><description>Australia joined nine other nations in formally recognising Palestinian statehood at the UN this week. But Palestinians have mixed feelings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57a8a3d3134b09135ecae50caa8ec2a8</guid></item><item><title>David Crisafulli stands by election commitments as mining companies criticise coal royalties in State of the State address</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/qld-2025-state-of-state-address-david-crisafulli/105805172</link><description>In his first State of the State address, Premier David Crisafulli says the government is "open for business", but not interested in companies that abandon Queenslanders in "the name of shareholder interests".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a04cca3c658daa48746b610150b5bf46</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu plans to sign police deal with China while Nakamal pact with Australia is left hanging</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/china-vanuatu-police-agreement-equipment-training/105806934</link><description>Vanuatu declares it will sign a new policing agreement with China as the landmark Nakamal pact between Australia and the Pacific Island nation hangs in the balance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e015a5946bffafc3e5c33cd1d8fa895e</guid></item><item><title>Concerns 'off-brand' cigarettes easy to access and cheaper</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/concerns-off-brand-cigarettes-easy-to-access-and/105807734</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e1d889cc16fa1dfacac6368020592c5</guid></item><item><title>Optus triple-0 outage tragedy: What we know and how events unfolded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/timeline-on-optus-triple-0-outage-what-we-know/105805890</link><description>The first sign something was wrong came late on Friday afternoon. Now we have a clearer picture of how the triple-0 outage unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c548c42002e87e4dd015358e8d8279e9</guid></item><item><title>Victoria Police dog on the road to recovery after horror collision in Melbourne's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/victoria-police-dog-injured-car-accident/105805824</link><description>A man has been charged following a collision in Tullamarine that left a police dog and his handler with injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63e90f91a0b55706b1f1ae1fb7432821</guid></item><item><title>Sale of Australia's biggest sheep station at Rawlinna finally gets WA government approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/sale-of-australias-largest-sheep-station-at-rawlinna-station/105807106</link><description>The WA government has finally signed off on the sale of Australia's largest sheep station almost seven months after UK-based Consolidated Pastoral Company announced plans to buy Rawlinna Station.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">453798f3baadfee94d513f7ea0e7efc3</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie's spray at 'muppet', 'coward' Liberal colleagues after post bemoaning loss of Aussie car making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/andrew-hastie-car-making-coward-muppet-liberals/105808280</link><description>Senior Liberal Andrew Hastie has taken aim at colleagues who questioned a social media post where he bemoaned the loss of Australian car making, calling them "nameless cowards" and "muppets".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa8f233e21c3cb087597a2e4648810dd</guid></item><item><title>WA rental protections second-worst in nation, National Shelter report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/wa-rental-protections-second-worst-in-nation/105805970</link><description>Calls to ban no-grounds evictions in WA are rejected despite a new report finding the state has the second-worst protections for renters in the nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee624d070108b4891871de914a709154</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm's Jahrome Hughes and Ryan Papenhuyzen return for NRL preliminary final against Cronulla</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/storm-jahrome-hughes-against-cronulla-broncos-panthers/105808480</link><description>Melbourne recall three big guns, led by star half Jahrome Hughes, as their NRL title hopes go on the line in Friday night's preliminary final against Cronulla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1926a9906773436f42474dc790c296f5</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105809052</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2291dde89e5f6f2e800c553bd2118818</guid></item><item><title>Russia systematically torturing Ukrainian civilians, UN says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/russia-systematically-torturing-ukrainian-civilians-un-says/105809316</link><description>The report is based on detailed interviews with 215 former detainees captured since Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b3ec3854b230344943aa0ea9a1c50f</guid></item><item><title>Could artificial intelligence and a universal basic income eliminate 'meaningless jobs'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/will-we-need-a-universal-basic-income-to-deal-with-ai-job-losses/105747954</link><description>COVID showed just how "fragile" our economic security is. As artificial intelligence potentially takes jobs from humans, a universal basic income might be a solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5953e2ae7f84df41d0ff5021a284652b</guid></item><item><title>Australians are moving to Tasmania to escape climate change, but the island state is not immune</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/australians-moving-to-tasmania-to-escape-climate-change/105785996</link><description>Jack and Anna swapped the humidity of Queensland for chilly days in Tasmania, but is Tasmania really the climate refuge many think it is?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0ff7fbad477aed99626b4746b82c14c</guid></item><item><title>Holbrook Landcare Network wins 2025 Bob Hawke Award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/holbrook-landcare-network-wins-2025-bob-hawke-award/105803040</link><description>A landcare network at "the forefront of technology" has won the 2025 Bob Hawke Award for its innovative approach to sustainable farming practices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">704bd35d01dd4bdc8154c105eb49b76a</guid></item><item><title>Holbrook Landcare wins Bob Hawke award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/holbrook-landcare-wins-bob-hawke-award/105806834</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebdc5b27d20f0774f792387b024bec7b</guid></item><item><title>Dickie Bird, former English cricket umpire, dies aged 92</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/dickie-bird-former-english-cricket-umpire-dies-aged-92/105809586</link><description>One of international cricket's most recognised umpires is being remembered for his "fairness, humour and love of the game".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ea286fdda73733b0f123adaeb2b514e</guid></item><item><title>NT government open to subdividing purpose-built State Square Art Gallery in Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nt-government-open-to-state-square-art-gallery-subdivide-darwin/105807672</link><description>A leading figure in Australia's art world has criticised the Northern Territory government for considering splitting up the lease for a building designed as a major new art gallery, describing the plan as "pure madness".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cea270549341f3bb40e1fafe548161cf</guid></item><item><title>Video record of violence and racism at Purnim Bears, Noorat country football grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/violence-racism-of-80s-country-victoria-football-grand-final/105741080</link><description>The Purnim Bears were supposed to be the feel-good story of country football — a team uniting black and white communities. But their 1987 grand final was so violent it ended with their expulsion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">231bb9fc7a4848fb3114f306c75ce3e0</guid></item><item><title>England names squad to face Australia in men's Ashes series 2025/26</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/england-name-squad-to-face-australia-in-men-s-ashes-series/105809606</link><description>England will bring a strong pace bowling attack, but several members of the squad, including captain Ben Stokes, are under injury clouds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d0a0a9cfab837e21e9251c67e841c3</guid></item><item><title>Mal Lanyon chosen as next NSW Police Force commissioner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/mal-lanyon-new-commissioner-of-nsw-police-force/105701914</link><description>Deputy Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon has been chosen to head up the NSW Police Force, replacing commissioner Karen Webb.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cd3192bee4641f04f5b65931d5fe5d6</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou 'excited' to defend his Europa League trophy with Nottingham Forest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ange-postecoglou-nottingham-forest-europa-league/105809674</link><description>Four months after leading Tottenham Hotspur to Europa League triumph in Bilbao, Ange Postecoglou has returned to Spain and UEFA's second-tier club competition with a new challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d7d5db2308c2c5b39a10ccc3cdf7870</guid></item><item><title>Queensland speed skydiver Natisha Dingle shows off her impressive skills.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/speed-skydiver-natisha-dingle-shows-off-her-impressive-skills/105807064</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c809122700c1bf91a2b261a16e110608</guid></item><item><title>Artemis program on track to take astronauts around the Moon: NASA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nasa-artemis-program-on-track-to-take-people-to-the-moon/105809764</link><description>NASA's first crewed flight in its Artemis program — a trip around the Moon and back — is on track for launch in April 2026 and could potentially be moved up to February, the space agency says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87a63c967423b595bde610ff51e979b6</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fullback Andrew Kellaway ruled out of first Bledisloe Cup Test match against All Blacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/wallabies-andrew-kellaway-ruled-out-bledisloe-cup-all-blacks/105810670</link><description>Wallabies fullback Andrew Kellaway will miss Saturday's Bledisloe Cup Test match against the All Blacks in Auckland, ruled out with a calf strain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11b979e7ef790b13cc2880a8a193f4dd</guid></item><item><title>Trump backs NATO powers to shoot down intruding Russian aircraft</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/trump-backs-nato-powers-to-shoot-down-intruding-russian-aircraft/105811080</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26fadd46aeef6d149deb13f7be4e3177</guid></item><item><title>Sculpture by the Sea could be cancelled due to $200,000 shortfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/sculptures-by-the-sea-facing-cancellation-funding-shortfall/105810510</link><description>Australia's famed sculpture walk is facing cancellation after failing to secure funding less than a month out from this year's event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ca69999aba4ff9483322749a16b717e</guid></item><item><title>Despite past controversy, NSW Police commissioner Mal Lanyon has a strong backing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nsw-police-commissioner-mal-lanyon-premier-chris-minns-analysis/105810774</link><description>For newly-announced Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon, Wednesday morning would have been both one of his proudest moments, and his most uncomfortable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed72f9bcc7ce20d2d722b8b43d539719</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel returns, addressing Charlie Kirk and 'un-American' axing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/jimmy-kimmel-returns-thanking-supporters-speaks-to-free-speech/105808410</link><description>Despite the late-night host's return, several US ABC affiliates did not air the episode, excluding an estimated one-quarter of American households.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac8b78a8e557c0d2a91d42ed04e2eed</guid></item><item><title>Family suspects foul play in Noosa man Byron Dumschat's death in a Bali villa pool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/family-suspects-foul-play-in-bali-death-noosa-man-byron-dumschat/105809846</link><description>An Australian family is asking why Indonesian police allowed three Australian witnesses to return home without being interviewed after their 23-year-old son died on the Indonesian holiday resort island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4e8e32abe23c1a44f62c5e3f023e2a2</guid></item><item><title>How #RedundancyDiaries are busting the stigma of being let go</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/busting-the-stigma-on-redundancy-by-sharing-online/105751880</link><description>Camille says being made redundant was hard, so she began sharing her experiences on TikTok hoping to help others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69e9a0930ebbcb9805519c817968e9ee</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's changed stance on Ukraine could be a challenge for Vladimir Putin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/donald-trump-ukraine-nato-comments-a-challenge-to-vladimir-putin/105810170</link><description>If Donald Trump actually means what he has just said — that NATO countries have a right to shoot down any Russian jets in their airspace — the US president may be contracting out a serious counteroffensive against Russian aggression to NATO countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c624737442bcb04137b18db123e6997</guid></item><item><title>Optus admits procedural failure before outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/optus-admits-procedural%C2%A0failure-before-outage%C2%A0/105811978</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b84c417046bbfc3acea16532e90a47cf</guid></item><item><title>Optus to pay $100m fine, as crisis engulfing Australia's second biggest telco continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/optus-fined-100-million-for-sales-misconduct/105810174</link><description>In enforcing the fine today, the Federal Court's Justice Patrick O'Sullivan described the company's conduct as "extremely serious" and "appalling".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5b8ef086dc95c25b9efd2536b1850d6</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of Australians fighting 'cruel' battle for COVID vaccine injury compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/fight-for-compensation-for-covid-19-vaccination-injuries/105808630</link><description>Thousands of Australians who were injured by COVID vaccines say they are facing a 'cruel and complex' system to get compensation from the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc0182bdb4d37c0f24454edad8263808</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Lions trust Lachie Neale to make right call ahead of AFL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/brisbane-lions-lachie-neale-right-afl-grand-final-call/105813604</link><description>All eyes are on Lachie Neale's bid to make a remarkable grand final return from injury, and his teammates will back him to make the right call.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b33183c69e679601c3ad83c2c662b7b</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105813848</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbeee129e3122b06287a24ba6aa752ed</guid></item><item><title>Senate inquiry examines federal environment department's SA algal bloom response</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/murray-watt-briefing-algal-bloom-july/105813252</link><description>Officials from the federal environment department say they were not aware of the impact of SA's algal bloom until the state government contacted them in May, two months after the bloom was first detected. Speaking at a senate inquiry, department officials say the federal environment minister was not formally briefed on the bloom until July.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47629bf3fc1342b70bb629add33dbfd9</guid></item><item><title>One dead in 'targeted' shooting at Dallas immigration centre, DHS says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/multiple-dead-at-dallas-ice-shooting/105814138</link><description>Police were first alerted to the incident at 6:40am on Wednesday, local time, and later found the shooter on a nearby roof dead from an apparent self-inflicted gunshot wound.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41372aed6a1e8513347f563b066ef004</guid></item><item><title>Kimmel monologue racks up millions of views on social media as Joe Rogan slams government 'dictating'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/kimmel-video-and-rogan-lashing-viral/105814274</link><description>Kimmel's program was indefinitely suspended last week after he made comments about the late conservative commentator Charlie Kirk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">125445d0de8a02f7060a350896e799ff</guid></item><item><title>Australia in a 'dangerous place' as AI adoption ramps up, prompting calls to protect jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/australia-in-dangerous-place-as-ai-adoption-ramps-up/105807430</link><description>Artificial intelligence is coming for our jobs — but will it take them away, or just give us a powerful new assistant?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48e1ecb4ff4fc7a8cb46b98272af471f</guid></item><item><title>AFL super fans prepare for the grand final clash between Geelong and Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/afl-football-fans-brisbane-lions-geelong-cats-2025-premiership/105812254</link><description>From a unique tattoo to a personalised burger, the AFL grand final is more than just a game for these super fans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85ea949cc04c0beee30263008e182e01</guid></item><item><title>Will food prices ever come down? Don't bet on it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/will-food-grocery-prices-ever-come-down/105811296</link><description>While recent cuts to interest rates may have given mortgage holders a bit of a financial breathing space, the cost of food continues to creep upwards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fce87e998f0daf4d07d83c36c6038f70</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy blames Putin for 'most destructive arms race in human history'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/zelenskyy-blames-putin-for-most-destructive-arms-race/105814378</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7700655ee2a3abe520a419b677e6593f</guid></item><item><title>Free speech pathologist sessions turning poor literacy rates around in Logan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/qld-logan-children-literacy-boost-free-speech-pathologist/105809794</link><description>A federal government backed weekly reading session led by experts is helping improve literacy rates in Queensland children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6f3a9ca2aa561db64986a266e4fcdcd</guid></item><item><title>Families demand inquiry into NSW Police handling of missing persons cases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/families-of-missing-persons-call-for-probe-into-police/105693338</link><description>Nikii Smith is one of 10,000 people who signed a petition calling for a NSW inquiry into the handling of missing persons cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86bd1e4db1094cebb0f4277ff0ad4c3b</guid></item><item><title>Solar, batteries and the 'phone charger dilemma': How a standards gap threatens clean tech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/smart-tech-benefits-at-risk-over-lack-of-common-standard/105808798</link><description>In the same way Apple and Samsung used different phone chargers, many clean tech products are not compatible with others. Experts say it is a big problem for the energy transition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84ec00dd3b63db045677af76a0c64880</guid></item><item><title>Rodeo attendees told to practise safe sex as STIs continue to rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sti-cases-continue-to-rise-indigenous-overrepresented-in-data/105809704</link><description>Health providers in outback Queensland are taking a light-hearted approach to promoting safe sex, as new data shows sexually transmitted infections are on the rise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a991448f6d24b7d59719d012fdc3e584</guid></item><item><title>Elevated E. coli levels recorded at major NT crocodile farm owned by luxury label Hermès</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/lambells-lagoon-crocodile-farm-nt-high-e-coli-levels-in-water/105806340</link><description>One of Australia's largest crocodile farms, owned by a subsidiary of luxury label Hermès, is consistently irrigating with water containing E. coli concentrations almost 500 times the national guidelines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcebaaf92f52cb686dddde475db8c67b</guid></item><item><title>Police launch fresh search of WA outback over Ray and Jennie Kehlet cold case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/wa-police-search-sandstone-kehlet-cold-case/105813086</link><description>Detectives are this week revisiting the site in WA's outback where the body of prospector Ray Kehlet was found. His wife Jennie is still missing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eda36c180ee83ef793f5a6e386ed8ef6</guid></item><item><title>Former AFL boss Andrew Demetriou insists league would embrace a gay men's player</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/andrew-demetriou-says-afl-a-safe-space-for-gay-players/105813820</link><description>Former AFL boss Andrew Demetriou says the public would embrace a gay men's player and rejects that the AFL is an unsafe environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d77a4e9f1c05a3808354f694994d6ee</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous teen speaks out against heckling of Welcome to Country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/indigenous-writes-essay-against-heckling-welcome-to-country/105808140</link><description>An Indigenous high school student's essay on the Anzac Day heckling of an Indigenous elder by far-right supremacists has earned her a nationally recognised award.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d0978c16ddeb79e39b966dd2e565459</guid></item><item><title>Alexa Leary and Callum Simpson win gold medals for Australia at World Para Swimming Championships in Singapore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/alexa-leary-callum-simpson-gold-world-para-swimming/105814486</link><description>Alexa Leary's win in the final individual event of Wednesday night's action in Singapore bookended a golden night for Australia after Callum Simpson won gold in the first event of the evening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24509973b18c1db25ad97fe2c3eae8f7</guid></item><item><title>Magnitude-4.1 earthquake rattles Tasmania from Maydena to Hobart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/tasmania-rattled-with-magnitude-4-1-earthquake/105814558</link><description>Tasmania records a magnitude-4.1 earthquake in the state's south-west that was felt from Maydena to Hobart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84775edf57cd76c9bc0ca385f3b919d5</guid></item><item><title>Who is Samoa's new prime minister, Laaulialemalietoa Polataivao Fosi Schmidt?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/new-samoa-prime-minister-election/105789496</link><description>Supporters are fervent in their enthusiasm for Samoa's new prime minister, but voters who are more sceptical of Laaulialemalietoa Polataivao Fosi Schmidt, question his motives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">625c6497fc8280a6929fa5f29c6e97f3</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of new dust-related lung disease cases recorded in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/new-cases-deadly-lung-disease-recorded-in-queensland/105800886</link><description>Nearly 300 workers from mines and work sites have had cases of lung cancer, black lung and other illnesses recorded by the state's dust disease register in the space of 12 months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2884483a655c30376f0362816224a66</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy warns UN of 'the most destructive arms race in human history'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/united-nations-general-assembly-volodymyr-zelenskyy-speech/105814462</link><description>Ukraine's president calls for global action to regulate the twin threats posed by drone technology and artificial intelligence, warning "no-one can feel safe" from Russia's expansionist goals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5f96320cb70d90485b91a1058586e74</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final sprint won't feature all teams, as Gout Gout and Harry Garside to feature at the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/afl-grand-final-sprint-gout-gout-and-harry-garside/105814536</link><description>The AFL announces that only seven AFL players will run in the traditional grand final sprint, with Olympic boxer Harry Garside also joining in.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90c0207e2a6dabd51c17d24fbfdde78c</guid></item><item><title>Macquarie to repay Shield investors after super platform failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/macquarie-admits-to-shield-contraventions/105814728</link><description>Macquarie commits to repaying thousands of Australians who invested hundreds of millions of their retirement savings in the collapsed Shield Master Fund amid admissions it contravened the Corporations Act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6ef3dcad386254cfbd1a1063f29bbf1</guid></item><item><title>China's President Xi Jinping announces new climate goal to cut emissions by 2035</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/china-plans-carbon-emissions-cut-by-2035/105814492</link><description>Outlining China's new carbon targets in a video link to the UN climate conference in New York, President Xi Jinping says "green and low carbon transition is the trend of our time".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f28b3d1c00395f4695e9369d6c444f2</guid></item><item><title>Katanning drivers fear the worst as untagged livestock roam roads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/katanning-farmers-fed-up-with-livestock-wandering-rural-roads/105753144</link><description>A Katanning school bus driver and local farmers are calling for urgent action to address a growing danger posed by wandering livestock on rural roads.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13a15cf930e91758bba06110e305613a</guid></item><item><title>Nottingham Forest draws 2-2 with Real Betis in opening UEFA Europa League match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nottingham-forest-draws-with-real-betis-europa-league/105814730</link><description>Nottingham Forest's long-awaited return to European competition ends 2-2 at Real Betis, with Igor Jesus's first-half double cancelling out by a late Antony strike.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7da92da66bbef30024c541232032313</guid></item><item><title>ARIA Award nominations 2025: Ninajirachi, Dom Dolla, Amyl &amp; The Sniffers lead the pack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/aria-award-nominations-2025-aria-nominees-full-list/105815074</link><description>All the contenders are hopefuls vying for ARIA Awards glory at the music industry's glitzy ceremony, taking place next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">959594b1e7f091dd3de19e45dc3888ab</guid></item><item><title>Peter Tonagh to replace Catherine West as Nine's chair</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/peter-tonagh-to-become-chair-of-nine/105814974</link><description>He replaces Catherine West, who spent 18 months in the position.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2a5f2c444b61e900f222e4b49c5f0b5</guid></item><item><title>Andrea James to lead Ilbijerri Theatre Company as artistic director Rachael Maza steps back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/ilbijerri-theatre-company-artistic-director-andrea-james/105806022</link><description>Andrea James will take the helm of Australia's oldest Indigenous theatre company Ilbijerri, as outgoing artistic director Rachael Maza steps back after almost 18 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4a3dbe4751b97f43dde74a8c6965376</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with multiple offences over pursuit, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/vale-park-man-arrested-over-alleged-dv-incident/105815044</link><description>South Australia Police says a Vale Park man has been charged following a pursuit that led STAR group officers and police negotiators to a unit in Adelaide's western suburbs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55d31264009557887152139ca68f0250</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese addresses UN on climate goals, Gaza and Australia's security council bid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/albanese-united-nations-general-assembly-speech/105815200</link><description>The prime minister uses his UN speech to talk up Australia's emissions plan after Donald Trump called climate change a "con job", and confirms Australia is still seeking a temporary seat on the body's security council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a232f435066d64bce12998bbb55c68d5</guid></item><item><title>Postal voting issues identified ahead of 2025 WA local government elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/postal-voting-problems-for-2025-local-government-election/105815250</link><description>Incorrect ballot papers are among several problems identified with postal voting packages sent out ahead next month's local government elections in WA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4995a33060a008be1386f30e6e5a7afe</guid></item><item><title>AI image recognition technology used to detect traffic offences raises privacy concerns, Queensland audit finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/ai-image-technology-phone-speeding-offences-privacy-audit-qld/105815134</link><description>Queensland's transport department uses AI in its cameras to detect mobile and seatbelt offences, but a new audit has ordered called for a review into how that's done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11d46c909160642ceb7265e8809e201c</guid></item><item><title>Breastfeeding in public is protected in Australia. So why are mothers still facing discrimination?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/why-are-we-still-asking-mothers-to-hide-breastfeeding/105789046</link><description>Last week a breastfeeding mother was asked to leave a Virgin Australia lounge for pumping. Experts says while there is a level of awareness that breastfeeding in public is protected, some people in the community still view it as "inappropriate".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5341713f4b5168cc3ed1630a81ef91c6</guid></item><item><title>Denmark PM apologises to indigenous Greenlanders who faced forced contraception</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/denmark-pm-apologises-to-greenland-over-contraception/105816090</link><description>The apology by Mette Frederiksen in Greenland’s capital, Nuuk, hopes to close a traumatic chapter in Greenland's history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10e2f68d02a379a76e33cb0667531d03</guid></item><item><title>Forestry industry says it can meet demand for biofuels as climate targets near</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/forestry-wood-waste-into-biofuel-ships-planes-climate-targets/105806578</link><description>With biofuels earmarked as a way to power the transport sector in the future, one industry says its waste can be converted into aviation and shipping fuel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c43fb3bd94bcaa6f5b6b2cc07bb8ea3a</guid></item><item><title>Trio of space weather satellites launched to study the Sun's violent side</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nasa-launch-three-spacecraft-sun/105815108</link><description>NASA successfully launches multiple satellites designed to get a better understanding of the Sun's influence on Earth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59a16bd185eeee6f5d85c73a75953dbf</guid></item><item><title>TGA approves new brain stimulation device for treatment of depression</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/brain-stimulator-device-approved-for-treatment-of-depression/105816064</link><description>Some international users of Flow Neuroscience's device have labelled the wearable tech as a game-changer in treating depression, but not everyone is convinced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d613860a63e9e5d904cc9b6ac0bd749</guid></item><item><title>Key takeaways from day two at the UN General Assembly's world leaders week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/united-nations-general-assembly-day-two-takeaways/105814272</link><description>The world's most powerful people are meeting in New York this week. Here are the key takeaways from the UN summit's second day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddb580a737f4f04170f65ae765ac9dd6</guid></item><item><title>Striking a Chord | Astrid Jorgensen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/striking-a-chord-astrid-jorgensen/105816660</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42d06a8633896cd66c178a10750772a5</guid></item><item><title>Ahead of the biggest game of his NRL career, Nicho Hynes returns to where it all began</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/storm-sharks-nicho-hynes-nrl-preliminary-finals/105816184</link><description>Ten years to the day since his first moment in the spotlight, Nicho Hynes returns to AAMI Park for the most important game of his NRL career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ba9e5f21df0896a8a84e51f1a77817b</guid></item><item><title>SA government grapples with whether it should issue daily bloom updates during summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/algal-bloom-persists-on-adelaide-metropolitan-beaches/105815614</link><description>South Australia's Premier says the government is grappling with whether it should give daily updates on the bloom's location during summer, and says it has been "actively engaged" in conversations with the federal government since its emergence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58acb5d5694220c60122ae3f346438b9</guid></item><item><title>Queensland police to receive 8 per cent pay rise over three years after accepting pay offer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/queensland-police-accept-8-per-cent-pay-rise-gov-offer/105817830</link><description>Queensland police officers will receive a wage increase, retention incentive and new allowances after accepting a pay deal from the state government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">888203bc80b607c4a59716509329c554</guid></item><item><title>Matildas strike force could benefit from having both Sam Kerr and Michelle Heyman firing fit up front</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/matildas-could-have-sam-kerr-and-michelle-heyman/105817900</link><description>A fit-again Sam Kerr doesn't necessarily spell the end for Michelle Heyman's time in the Matildas, if anything the A-League star can't wait for her return.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c878d14058b221a67d55c4c8bdc80e94</guid></item><item><title>Lachie Neale and Rhys Stanley named in AFL grand final teams as Jarrod Berry fails to recover from shoulder injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/afl-grand-final-geelong-brisbane-lions-team-selections-live-blog/105812378</link><description>Brisbane's co-captain returns just weeks after doctors gave him as little as a five per cent chance of featuring in his third straight grand final as Geelong welcomes back a familiar face to take the place of Tom Stewart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd6e232727e7d0a979b313cd8bef11d5</guid></item><item><title>Measles case detected in Brisbane, prompting calls for vaccination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/measles-brisbane-qld-health-alert-disease-infection/105817886</link><description>Queensland's health department says the person was believed to have contracted the virus in Bali, before visiting a number of businesses across Brisbane and the Sunshine Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69d52cc929c6deec63f591815c89b60a</guid></item><item><title>Horse trainer Dwayne Schmidt jailed for raping and impregnating 13yo girl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/horse-trainer-raped-and-impregnated-13-year-old-girl/105813440</link><description>New South Wales horse trainer Dwayne Schmidt is sentenced to more than three years in jail for raping and impregnating a 13-year-old girl.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cff6a74bc32102a2a7bdba358773bf49</guid></item><item><title>Gympie Regional Council votes to remove fluoride from town's water supply</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/gympie-removes-fluoride-water-supply-dental-health-fears/105814678</link><description>Gympie scraps fluoride from its water supply and becomes the third region in Queensland to reject the practice in just over a year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9960f09af437f02819e5359d8481878</guid></item><item><title>Coroner finds Monash Health provided unreasonable care before toddler Dio Kemp's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/coroner-finding-into-death-of-dio-kemp/105816186</link><description>Three-year-old Dio Kemp was taken to Monash Medical Centre four times over 10 days before she died of sepsis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37b865829bea191edfe0af886035c9e4</guid></item><item><title>Mass puffer fish deaths and red-bell jellyfish bloom put Pilbara coast on alert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/pilbara-coast-alert-jellyfish-bloom-toxic-puffer-fish-deaths/105815554</link><description>Hundreds of dead puffer fish are found on a Pilbara beach, as an epic red-bell jellyfish bloom prompts a warning from the region's ports authority.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39c787a5232b58cd251e6bebea3ae077</guid></item><item><title>Arts industry leaders call for tax reforms to help struggling sector</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sydney-arts-leaders-calling-for-tax-reform-to-the-sector/105816210</link><description>Arts industry leaders say creative tax form is needed to create greater opportunities for Australian artists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7181bdf23c74d11e765b61f89bc136e</guid></item><item><title>All the latest finance news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/all-the-latest-finance-news/105818574</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">024e11ae51d50a5a396284951c067a9d</guid></item><item><title>Former French president Nicolas Sarkozy found guilty of criminal conspiracy in case linked to Muammar Gaddafi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nicolar-sarkozy-found-guilty-of-criminal-conspiracy-libya-trial/105818560</link><description>Nicolas Sarkozy is found guilty of obtaining millions of euros in illegal financing from late Libyan dictator Muammar Gaddafi for his successful 2007 presidential bid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96ff22933c8a0523f09fb4365a1711db</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy says he will step down as president after Ukraine war ends</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/zelenskyy-to-leave-office-after-war/105818790</link><description>Ukraine's president has been in office since 2019, with elections slated for last year suspended by martial law as a result of Russia's ongoing invasion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">473d9a464ce1fda89fe9d2c223665ebf</guid></item><item><title>Out-of-pocket costs, eroding trust contributing to decline in childhood vaccination rates, new report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/research-urges-action-on-declining-childhood-vaccination-rates/105815232</link><description>A new report finds out-of-pocket costs and eroding trust are contributing to a "concerning" decline in childhood vaccination rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfdd1a56127bc667f2e5ffab313e2712</guid></item><item><title>China aid and investment returns to Solomon Islands's Malaita province after ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/china-aid-solomon-islands-malaita-road-development/105789780</link><description>The Solomon Islands's province of Malaita made global headlines five years ago when it banned Chinese investment. But today, a new China-funded road project is on the way — and the people are all for it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aef86fbb6ca57b72f9ef6089dc9580e9</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners slam state premiers for 'disgraceful' call to push ahead with Santos gas project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/peter-malinauskas-under-fire-over-santos-gas-project-gomeroi/105817448</link><description>The debate over Santos's Narrabri gas project reignites, with traditional owners condemning 'disgraceful' comments made by two state premiers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ff7b86ab36f41d01a1fc6371f793a89</guid></item><item><title>Imported potatoes threaten Tasmanian growers, as companies look for cost savings overseas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/imported-potatoes-price-cuts-threaten-australian-potato-industry/105815458</link><description>Cheap potato imports from India and China are threatening the livelihoods of Tasmanian growers, as stalled negotiations with potato giant Simplot leave some farmers about to plant this year's crop without a contract.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddc6d456a4e47433bae32855e5b52bae</guid></item><item><title>Police search for alleged Porepunkah gunman Dezi Freeman hits one-month mark</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/porepunkah-gunman-dezi-freeman-shooting-latest/105806284</link><description>A month into the high country search for alleged Porepunkah gunman Dezi Freeman, a former detective says Victoria Police can not realistically expect to continue the manhunt indefinitely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">232d07227b15324a710ddc69e78d015c</guid></item><item><title>AFL popularity growth fuels calls to move the Barassi Line separating codes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/barassi-line-rugby-league-aussie-rules-tathra/105782938</link><description>Initially laughed off, these pioneers from Victoria were determined to challenge Australia's sporting status quo, and their legacy continues today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">853354932de7c66115ea465660b6ef08</guid></item><item><title>Sudden 30C temperature rise over Antarctica upends Australia's spring outlook</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/weather-pattern-could-disrupt-australia-for-months/105817572</link><description>Temperatures above Antarctica have risen by 30C, in a rare event that could potentially flip Australia's spring weather for months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c3c265c0efd53b23c81e306c0bfbd10</guid></item><item><title>Southern rock lobster prices finally bounce back amid demand from China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/aussie-rock-lobster-prices-strong-china-demand-sa/105815982</link><description>After years of export trade disruptions, southern Australian rock lobster commercial fishers are hauling in catches that will fetch up to $125 per kilogram.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4f3eb64091cd22b844cb02f1d763fbf</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian Authority president thanks Australia, but points to decades of failure, in UN address</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/united-nations-palestinian-authority-mahmoud-abbas-speech/105819446</link><description>Mahmoud Abbas addresses the UN by video after the US refuses him a visa, as Donald Trump vows he will "not allow" Israel to annex the West Bank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25b349c3dbf1286a48e6bc697929c1ae</guid></item><item><title>Dallas authorities give update on shooting at ICE facility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/dallas-authorities-give-update-on-shooting-at-ice-facility/105819488</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2901193f49033d6a091ea292a7d1a67a</guid></item><item><title>Illawarra groups want Port Kembla ruled out for AUKUS nuclear submarine base</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/port-kembla-declaration-against-aukus-nuclear-submarine-base/105815986</link><description>The federal government says it will not make a decision on the location of the nuclear submarine base until later this decade, but Illawarra institutions — from unions to churches — are sending a strong message now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9576ab16c1d1be2862cfa1862bc87c3</guid></item><item><title>ASX closes up, Singtel boss flown in to meet Australian government over triple-0 failure — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/asx-markets-business-live-news-26-sept-2025/105819610</link><description>Singtel confirms its CEO will join the Optus chair and CEO in meeting the communications minister as the triple-0 fallout rumbles on. Meanwhile, despite a poor opening, the ASX regains ground to finish the week higher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4be65eb1cbcd8e56b4e7411bef244b6b</guid></item><item><title>Former Arsenal-contracted player Billy Vigar dies aged 21 after sustaining brain injury during a game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/billy-vigar-dies-at-21-after-head-injury-in-soccer-match/105819594</link><description>Tributes flow for Billy Vigar, after the former Arsenal-contracted player dies from a brain injury sustained during a match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c247b6a9b1480f06a4e319acbb2b00a8</guid></item><item><title>Bondi's Sculpture by the Sea offered $200,000 lifeline after financial woes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/bondi-sculpture-by-the-sea-to-go-ahead-2025-due-to-lifeline/105819510</link><description>Sculpture by the Sea was facing cancellation with organisers forced to make an urgent public plea for last-minute funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6b9cfa8185df988b1552b57c5404e42</guid></item><item><title>WA government accused of treating Port Hedland's water supply like 'lolly shop'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/port-hedland-residents-lash-water-corporation-bungle/105812946</link><description>An Indigenous elder says the rapid depletion of Port Hedland's groundwater stores has been evident for decades, but the government has prioritised mining interests over people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dba911c331c3d40c04227fbc691550d3</guid></item><item><title>Well-known Adelaide tailor Joseph Uzumcu fined for smoking outside CBD shop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/joseph-uzumcu-adelaide-tailor-fined-smoking/105818722</link><description>A well-known Adelaide tailor has been issued a fine by the Adelaide Magistrates Court for smoking outside his CBD business to cope with stress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dd54fb0496462acf91c278ecc303fb5</guid></item><item><title>Hiker with motor neurone disease takes on WA's 1,000km Bibbulmun Track</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/mullumbimby-motor-neurone-disease-hiker-walks-bibbulmun-track-wa/105810642</link><description>One week into her 1,000-kilometre trek of WA's Bibbulmun Track, 70-year-old Catherine Perversi says "the stillness is sublime" — and she would not be anywhere else.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">562a1176a7305ccb5b4ebc35f0433aaa</guid></item><item><title>Trump has signed an executive order on TikTok. What does that mean?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/donald-trump-signs-tiktok-executive-order-what-does-that-mean/105819550</link><description>Donald Trump has signed an executive order that he says will allay security concerns regarding Chinese influence on social media platform TikTok.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56898e42bde26b739d92f79a2ebd6d02</guid></item><item><title>Foster carer shortage in WA's Kimberley forces children away from country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/foster-carer-shortage-in-kimberley-forcing-kids-off-country/105815878</link><description>A shortage of foster carers in regional WA is pushing vulnerable children, especially First Nations kids, thousands of kilometres from their families, culture and country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ce81c66ef721335c43f5ba3654f32c4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump imposes 100 per cent tariffs on branded pharmaceuticals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/trump-100pc-tariff-on-drugs-us-politics-/105820198</link><description>The United States will impose a 100 per cent tariff on imports of branded or patented pharmaceutical products from October 1, unless a pharmaceutical company is building a manufacturing plant in the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">739af64d542d4f460697eb9a7951741d</guid></item><item><title>Freight train derails after collision with sheep truck at Bribbaree</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/freight-train-derails-after-collision-with-sheep-truck-bribbaree/105820076</link><description>A freight train derails following a crash with a truck carrying livestock in central-west New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fa1de29d55673a44a56301cdea1ea8b</guid></item><item><title>Scientist wins peace prize for farmer-managed natural regeneration work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/tony-rinaudo-wins-luxembourg-peace-prize-regenerative-farming/105666674</link><description>A Victorian scientist whose farming technique has revolutionised agriculture in Niger is awarded an international peace prize.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdd4d1ecb9ea1ba749bbf16d1448e605</guid></item><item><title>Health minister concedes tobacco black market has 'exploded'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/health-minister-concedes-tobacco-black-market-has-exploded/105820002</link><description>Health Minister Mark Butler admits black market tobacco is now the single biggest threat to public health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05884e55b2091e93d320e424fb5838c7</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final preview — how Geelong's unpredictable set up and late term heroics have set them up for a flag</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/afl-grand-final-preview-2025-geelong-profile-against-brisbane/105819810</link><description>From an innovative ruck set up to an uncanny ability to play out the quarter, the perennially competitive Cats are knocking on the door of another flag.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b332a9a8fd34aa68b5306baa1efb2624</guid></item><item><title>Branxholme Wallacedale Saints under 11s celebrate a win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/branxholme-wallacedale-saints-under-11s-celebrate/105812870</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d1e354fadc4bffdd99339a039272e54</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane hellbent on ending horror NRLW finals run ahead of preliminary final clash with Newcastle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/nrlw-finals-broncos-knights-brigginshaw-upton/105820672</link><description>The Broncos have been almost untouchable through the 2025 NRLW season but the club's poor finals record in recent years means they can not afford to get ahead of themselves leading into this week's preliminary final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d248af9a48662ba232728304794119fd</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final preview — how corridor control and the hard ball can lead Brisbane to back-to-back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/afl-grand-final-preview-lions-look-for-back-to-back/105820830</link><description>They've had to deal with adversity all year, but the Lions are one step away from historic back-to-back flags — here's how they can do it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39ffbe3a1c41d9fda76aa7ad5e261837</guid></item><item><title>Marion, Burnside and West Lakes among shopping centres listed by SA Police as Declared Public Precincts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/sa-declared-public-precincts/105820216</link><description>SA Police has announced Declared Public Precincts at eight shopping centres in metropolitan Adelaide, with a knife discovered in the first 15 minutes of a patrol at Marion Shopping Centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b92ca055410bc1b898a51e170aa0a2a1</guid></item><item><title>Police legal challenge against Aboriginal death in custody inquest fails</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/police-legal-challenge-aboriginal-death-in-custody-inquest-fails/105820812</link><description>A coronial inquest into the death of an Aboriginal woman in custody will be free to assess police actions, after a legal challenge by police was dismissed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3674b51ed40e1a297b85299efa20631</guid></item><item><title>12yo girl killed in Great Southern road crash as long weekend looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/girl-killed-in-great-southern-highyway-crash-wa/105821522</link><description>The fatal collision occurred hours after police urged motorists to drive cautiously ahead of the long weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ed3a65257132e576f1faa29a826222e</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu minister tells Australia to respect China policing deal, rebukes Pat Conroy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/vanuatu-tells-australia-to-respect-china-policing-deal/105820502</link><description>Vanuatu's internal affairs minister says Australia needs to respect his country's plan to sign a new policing agreement with China, and has taken a swipe at Pacific Minister Pat Conroy as controversy over the proposal rumbles along.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">050f43efa5f6288d7a00530de579d990</guid></item><item><title>Geoff Ayling, composer of some of Australia's most recognised ad jingles, dies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/geoff-ayling-songwriter-dies-famous-ad-jingles/105817238</link><description>The man who wrote the music for many well-known advertising jingles, including Good on You Mum, Tip Top bread and Take Me Away, P&amp;O, is being remembered for his musical skill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b53a6564057672097bb047c151dca62</guid></item><item><title>Why you might consider glass food containers over plastic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/are-glass-containers-better-for-food-storage/105814738</link><description>Compared to plastic containers, glass alternatives can reduce exposure to microplastics when used in the microwave and be easier to clean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62503c861f079a92f249f37bd31d4008</guid></item><item><title>Baby koala rides golden retriever like a racehorse in south-west Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/koala-rides-golden-retriever-like-a-horse-animal-best-friends/105820294</link><description>When Steve Lamplough heard a commotion outside his south-west Victorian home, the last thing he expected to see was a joey koala riding his dog like a racehorse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8f146a530bc61ff11d04f67fce57f11</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste scraps lifetime pensions after student-led protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/timor-leste-scraps-lifetime-pensions-student-protests/105822222</link><description>Timor-Leste votes to cancel the lifetime pension law for MPs and public officials, following student-led demonstrations against lavish perks in one of South-East Asia's poorest countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45a5c26bb186d48e726ba42169e2ac69</guid></item><item><title>Missing man Mark Sear's vehicle found during Kimberley search</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/wa-kimberley-missing-person-search-mark-ear/105821552</link><description>Mark Sear, 62, has not been seen since he left a station near Halls Creek a week ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d112d1ed20b5caa58964db8cec42e4d3</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios spruiks construction of $9.9 million Gungahlin tennis facility in Canberra's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/act-9-million-tennis-facility-construction-begins/105821980</link><description>Construction on a new $9.9 million tennis facility in the Gungahlin has begun five years after the ACT government pledged funding for it ahead of the 2020 territory election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f140dc898fba699bca2f89fcd4262dab</guid></item><item><title>At least three shark deaths linked to algal bloom, investigations show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/sa-shark-deaths-algal-bloom/105820996</link><description>Investigations into nine white shark deaths this year have revealed at least three are likely to have been killed by the toxic algal bloom. Warning: This story contains images that some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79ddca541da983c2087bb440bc5fe637</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm reach NRL grand final with 22-14 win over Cronulla Sharks in preliminary final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/nrl-preliminary-final-live-melbourne-storm-cronulla-sharks/105812604</link><description>Jahrome Hughes leads Melbourne back into the NRL grand final, scoring a try in a 22-14 win over the Cronulla Sharks just 22 days after breaking his arm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75da4fc54a216f86411f3ab5eb5b0821</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur powers through at China Open, Aleksandar Vukic set for big-name quarterfinal in Japan Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/alex-de-minaur-powers-through-in-china/105823034</link><description>Aussie Alex de Minaur is through to the China Open round of 16 thanks to a crushing straight-sets win over a local wildcard, while in Japan Aleksandar Vukic has recorded a second win to set up a tasty quarterfinal clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">536d835a42b45245a5e4b71e9f9aff13</guid></item><item><title>Latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/latest-financial-news/105823140</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a99f716d6cc9d9350073146aa3f0fa84</guid></item><item><title>Police investigating after woman's body found in the Hobart Rivulet by man walking dog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/body-of-female-found-in-hobart-rivulet-near-molle-street/105823302</link><description>Police say they have notified the family of a woman aged in her 30s whose body was found in the Hobart Rivulet on Friday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b833cae44c2ced572ea0a27f2b63b47</guid></item><item><title>Russia helping China to prepare for potential invasion of Taiwan, defence think tank RUSI says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/russia-helping-china-prepare-for-taiwan-invasion-says-thinktank/105823308</link><description>Leaked Russian documents analysed by a leading UK think tank suggest Russia is selling military equipment and technology to China that could help it prepare an airborne invasion of Taiwan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8da797f22ee0851495fbdb3b01797dc</guid></item><item><title>Australia's climate target doesn't eclipse today's tough questions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/climate-announcement-targets-emissions/105801294</link><description>As a nation, it's as if we're arguing about where to have a family holiday in 2035, and whether we fly economy or business. Meanwhile, nobody can agree on dinner tonight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4146131c7945d7a9befae50175a86f11</guid></item><item><title>How Alliyah's community missed the signs of a female predator</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/female-child-abusers-hidden/105806706</link><description>Gender stereotypes "play a role" in allowing predators like Kellie Whiteside to fly under the radar, but that's not the whole story.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5212f82642c02bf7652806df1582ca0</guid></item><item><title>Geelong and Brisbane's AFL grand final meeting a clash of 21st-century titans 25 years in the making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-geelong-brisbane-grand-final-21st-century-titans/105817210</link><description>When they meet at the MCG on Saturday afternoon, Geelong and Brisbane are bidding for more than just the 2025 premiership. For the two most dominant clubs of a generation, true greatness is at hand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a8fca4f4487c82e1257eae08d6d9ec0</guid></item><item><title>Indians in Australia continue to face racist abuse one month on from anti-immigration protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/indians-racism-march-for-australia-protests-anti-immigration/105782222</link><description>Nearly a month after anti-immigration protests swept across Australia, some in the Indian diaspora say they are still facing racist abuse and constantly "looking over their shoulder".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50a690450fbc31f7c53d0d4ea03d629f</guid></item><item><title>Epstein files show flight with Prince Andrew and meetings with Elon Musk, Bill Gates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/epstein-files-six-pages-released/105823750</link><description>The documents include flight logs, massage messages and cash transactions in Jeffrey Epstein's ledger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f78ee953397b3a507669a6560c685081</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast venue refuses entry to Māori man due to cultural tattoo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/maori-man-barred-from-gold-coast-venue-over-cultural-tattoo/105803294</link><description>Caleb Pokai says he was banned from entering the Burleigh Pavilion while out dinner with friends due to his tā moko.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36e9bee7980f29d8dd3548676fd7d8db</guid></item><item><title>Sydney schoolboy explains his autism and ADHD to peers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/sydney-schoolboy-explains-his-autism-and-adhd-to/105820440</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d120291fa023df6845d40764a23cb49</guid></item><item><title>Sydney student compares his autism to 'limited edition Lego' in uplifting viral speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/sydney-student-leo-speech-on-autism-like-limited-edition-lego/105819812</link><description>Twelve-year-old Leo is the talk of his community thanks to a speech he made for his school's public speaking competition where he opened up about his neurodiversity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acbfc98d682b5458b7c616d84f85cb29</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with performing Nazi salute at AFL semifinal was former political candidate with history of racist posts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/qld-man-charged-with-performing-nazi-salute-political-candidate/105815900</link><description>An ABC investigation reveals Tylere Baker-Pearce, a former political candidate who has posted a selfie smiling outside Auschwitz, was the man charged with performing a Nazi salute at an AFL game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30e54f094513d67b34962af67d4ac555</guid></item><item><title>The majority of Queensland councils are washing their hands of fluoridation under the watch of both sides of politics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/qld-fluoride-water-supply-tooth-decay-politics-washing-hands/105820504</link><description>Attacks by Queensland Opposition Leader Steven Miles against Premier David Crisafulli over fluoride this week are more than hard to swallow after another local government's decision to stop adding the mineral to its water supply, writes Janelle Miles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3f79307107db030116e62bb5f9c648d</guid></item><item><title>Crocodile industry stakeholders urge Australian government to reform outdated code of practice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/code-of-practice-wild-farmed-australian-crocodiles/105821646</link><description>Thrust back into the international spotlight by the recent trial of Outback Wrangler star Matt Wright, questions are being raised about the Top End's lucrative crocodile industry and its outdated code of practice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5f0239291a3bab11069711c4f720cb3</guid></item><item><title>Retiring paramedic sounds alarm over plummeting job retention rate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/retiring-paramedic-sounds-alarm-over-low-retention-rate/105805372</link><description>Peter Maxwell and wife Rachel spent a combined 77 years as NSW paramedics, but they might be the last of a generation of lifers, with one in 20 leaving the workforce every year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ceb0b45376909c99278c668ab146956</guid></item><item><title>Persistent algae bloom causing political headaches as scientists are copping the flak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/algae-bloom-political-headaches/105821302</link><description>South Australia's algal bloom continues to cause political headaches for state and federal Labor. Perhaps that's why scientists are copping some of the flak now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4eda47c6abdb95b5e7cb1558c679e6d</guid></item><item><title>Nooramunga Land and Sea buys private islands to save them from development</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/non-profit-buys-bullock-and-little-dog-islands-off-vic-coast/105666678</link><description>For roughly the price of an inner-city apartment, conservationists have bought multiple small islands off the coast of Gippsland to protect their ecosystems and wildlife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c31e60140fdbcc5dfafc1267bf95eb5</guid></item><item><title>AI can't teach our kids to be curious and think critically</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/ai-revolution-classrooms/105756868</link><description>The AI dystopia might already be here but there are some things only humans can teach our children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a55b864c2b25cccc3569eb1e7b2df7c5</guid></item><item><title>Detailed designs of new lyric theatre inspired by Canberra's natural landmarks revealed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/act-new-lyric-theatres-detailed-designs-revealed/105823106</link><description>Detailed designs show plans for the new 2,000-seat lyric theatre, inspired by Canberra's natural landmarks, which will host major musicals, ballets and operas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32104f4565bc9ee2f42947c31b206b9c</guid></item><item><title>Police locate 10yo boy missing in Victoria's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/missing-boy-campground-chaz-jeparit-victoria-police-appeal/105823820</link><description>A 10-year-old boy has been located safe and well, more than 15 hours after he was last seen near a campground in Victoria's north-west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67c2852121ebcc63490fc24605d75459</guid></item><item><title>Is it worth moving to Tasmania for the cooler climate?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/moving-tasmania-climate-positives-and-negatives/105815096</link><description>Each of these eight families left the mainland in search of Tasmania's cooler, milder climate. But with challenges like health care, transport and limited services, do they have any regrets over the decision?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe4bcc9ccaae6e62bab1625ddabe94d0</guid></item><item><title>Conservation notice issued for alleged native vegetation clearing at Chittering</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/dwer-issues-notice-over-alleged-native-tree-clearing-chittering/105807210</link><description>Western Australia's environmental regulator has issued a property owner with a vegetation conservation notice for the alleged clearing of a significant amount of native trees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a73ca93c90bcc1f5bb19f601570855d0</guid></item><item><title>What time is the 2025 AFL grand final? Here's how to watch and everything you need to know as Brisbane and Geelong clash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-grand-final-2025-what-time-does-the-game-start/105823862</link><description>Wondering what time the AFL grand final starts and how you can watch it live? We've got you covered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">961b6e51ce3e13209f14691157297bb3</guid></item><item><title>Wool price soars as production crashes and Chinese demand lifts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/australian-wool-price-three-year-high-as-china-demands-rises/105819768</link><description>Australian wool prices lifted sharply this week for a few reasons, including a shrinking amount of wool being produced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58344a18424792f395eadbda8b6e6d6b</guid></item><item><title>Investigations underway after several Launceston General Hospital staff reported feeling nauseated and faint</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/launceston-general-hospital-incident-staff-reported-feeling-sick/105823900</link><description>Tasmania Police initially said the incident at the Launceston General Hospital was potentially a gas leak, but the Tasmania Fire Service later said it did not detect any gas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4fc62e9e3e20ebfcf52e8625114d8d6</guid></item><item><title>Lachie Neale expected to start as sub for Brisbane against Geelong in the 2025 AFL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-grand-final-2025-lachie-neale-set-to-start-as-sub/105823894</link><description>Brisbane Lions captain Lachie Neale is likely to start as sub in today's grand final as he battles a calf injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91a67c83197e1c6ed6df3a535f58e980</guid></item><item><title>UN sanctions 'unfair, unjust and illegal', says Iran's president</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/iran-says-un-security-council-sanctions-unfair/105823898</link><description>The UN Security Council rejects another last-ditch effort to delay the reimposition of sanctions on Iran over its nuclear program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff1a6a0c02c16e1d84e6b2947a01c58c</guid></item><item><title>The banal, brutal life of traffic police in South West WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/ride-along-with-south-west-road-traffic-police/105820992</link><description>As WA experiences its worst year for road deaths in over a decade, the ABC shadows two traffic officers as they try to stop the number climbing higher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">607dd8386b70fdaac1a7dbd4afc9ea3f</guid></item><item><title>For four years, Yuna and Minu Jo lay in a suitcase in a New Zealand storage unit. Now they have justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/nz-suitcase-deaths-aftermath/105811894</link><description>Minu and Yuna Jo's bodies lay in a storage unit for four years. They finally have justice after their mother was found guilty of their murders seven years after they were killed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c20fa9f4daa00b724ebbc96dbed5d5c6</guid></item><item><title>Gladstone Strollers walking group creates a village for postpartum mums</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/postpartum-mum-walking-group-mental-health-benefits/105820070</link><description>A Queensland mum desperate to have a positive postpartum experience when she had her second child found that just a few small steps were enough to make a huge difference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4aabdb9b02f032a6f0dfa2b02445682e</guid></item><item><title>Trump visit to Ryder Cup not enough to inspire Americans as Europe dominates day one</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/ryder-cup-golf-trump-visit-fails-to-inspire-americans/105823802</link><description>President Donald Trump visits on the opening day of the Ryder Cup, but it's the Europeans who dominate heading into day two.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">971dd8b151a82436219cb0443b384982</guid></item><item><title>WA teenager starts petition for shearing to be in Brisbane 2032 Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/wa-teen-starts-petition-for-shearing-to-be-in-the-olympics/105721670</link><description>We saw break dancing added to the Olympic program for the Paris Games, and now there is a push for shearing to be included for the Brisbane Olympics in 2032.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ce5973b6762c550d39695066a2eff91</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final 2025: Brisbane Lions thump Geelong Cats by 47 points, Will Ashcroft wins Norm Smith Medal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-grand-final-2025-geelong-vs-brisbane-live-blog/105822258</link><description>Brisbane secures its second straight AFL premiership, taking control in the final quarter of an otherwise gripping grand final against Geelong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14ca0c766669a84c1c64d308b07e389c</guid></item><item><title>Fortescue offers measles vaccine boosters after Christmas Creek outbreak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/fortescue-measles-vaccine-boosters-christmas-creek-outbreak/105820426</link><description>Iron-ore giant Fortescue says it will offer vaccine boosters after three measles cases were confirmed at its Pilbara mine earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26e09d8753cc469c42fac166c15b08d3</guid></item><item><title>Tourist dies at Tasmania's Cradle Mountain National Park after group becomes 'overwhelmed' by extreme weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/cradle-mountain-walker-dies-extreme-weather/105824188</link><description>A group of tourists who were unprepared for the extreme conditions at Cradle Mountain National Park is rescued, but one member of the group dies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c2bacc1d4008463c044ab40ec94a7ab</guid></item><item><title>Cyclist on a gruelling journey to fight for a better future for people with dementia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/nic-tremaine-cycling-around-australia-dementia-fundraising-trip/105730642</link><description>Nicholas Tremaine is cycling more than 40,000 kilometres to raise $1 million to fight the condition that's befallen his mother and is now Australia's leading cause of death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08add1d8f7252bd94b473e9688d5ae02</guid></item><item><title>WA government facing $400m cost blowout over Peel Health Campus redevelopment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/peel-health-campus-cost-blowout/105824094</link><description>The long-awaited redevelopment of Peel Health Campus is facing a $400 million cost blowout and potential delays, a leaked document reveals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7295950907094099603d65d0a0b06af</guid></item><item><title>Snoop Dogg, Baker Boy and Tash Sultana star in AFL grand final entertainment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/snoop-dogg-afl-grand-final-entertainment-mcg/105819406</link><description>The legendary rapper delivered a squeaky clean performance, incorporating local artists and a didgeridoo in a trip through his catalogue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">520a21469afd2968627cca416d5cdb69</guid></item><item><title>Matt Wright's lawyers reveal five grounds of appeal for Netflix star's guilty verdict, including allegation against judge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/matt-wright-five-grounds-of-appeal-revealed/105824618</link><description>Matt Wright's lawyers have revealed the five grounds they are seeking to appeal their client's guilty verdict on, including an allegation that the judge made an "impermissible comment to the jury".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45adde7e87d9110419b85a7a1e1c1ee1</guid></item><item><title>Lions star Will Ashcroft wins second consecutive Norm Smith Medal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-grandfinal-norm-smith-lons-cats-will-ashcroft/105824400</link><description>Will Ashcroft claims back-to-back Norm Smith Medals after playing a starring role in the Brisbane Lions' grand final win over Geelong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d02e668f13c6768be3d2d3f2232c0931</guid></item><item><title>How the internet reacted to the Brisbane Lions winning the AFL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/internet-reacted-afl-grand-final-brisbane-lions-geelong-cats/105802198</link><description>Brisbane completed an historic back-to-back premiership, beating a wounded Geelong at the MCG, and the internet followed along with every kick.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b68c6dfe98a3f3cc3b923023a51e2931</guid></item><item><title>Shark victim Mercury Psillakis's twin brother leads paddle out on Sydney's Northern Beaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/paddle-out-shark-victim-mercury-psillakis-sydney-long-reef-beach/105824476</link><description>The twin brother of shark victim Mercury Psillakis has led hundreds of surfers in a paddle out in his memory on Sydney's Northern Beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0130705e7e9b9976106bd6990598bf9</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final quick hits: Lions' Lachie Neale gamble pays off, Cats' Jeremy Cameron in the wars, and it's Country Road time at the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-grand-final-quick-hits-geelong-cats-brisbane-lions/105821966</link><description>Brisbane's gamble on Lachie Neale's fitness pays off with a team-lifting goal, a brave Jeremy Cameron has a painful day out, and Charlie Cameron's goals provide a Country Road soundtrack at the MCG. Here are the quick hits from the 2025 AFL grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef10be159c2c5da37bc2677e999bc6a9</guid></item><item><title>White House releases photo of Donald Trump and Anthony Albanese</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/albanese-trump-photo/105824944</link><description>A photo of a smiling Donald Trump, alongside Anthony Albanese, his fiancée Jodie Haydon and US First Lady Melania Trump, has been released by the White House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff4eec3691a0dfeed959566549f25d32</guid></item><item><title>When it comes to love, more of us are crossing the religious divide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/more-australians-are-marrying-across-the-religious-divide/105779468</link><description>Exclusive data for 5.2 million couples shows nearly one in five marriages are between people of different religions – double the proportion recorded in 1986.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">013dc6d1c3729b713228afd937c045d6</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump will send troops to 'war-ravaged' Portland, in latest deployment to US cities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/trump-orders-deployment-of-troops-to-portland-ice-facilities/105825548</link><description>The military says it is ready to mobilise as Donald Trump authorises "full force" to protect federal immigration facilities from "domestic terrorists".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7bbd1ebd2ce3c0d838911445a763b29</guid></item><item><title>Guy Sebastian reflects on Titus Day legal case and the lesson he's learned from fans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/guy-sebastian-the-assembly/105671828</link><description>Guy Sebastian opens up about the fan encounter that made him "burst into tears" and a court case with his former manager, Titus Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d1fceb0fd7d9b21cd61a61a6b4f7281</guid></item><item><title>Roosters on cusp of perfect NRLW season after beating Sharks 17-16</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/nrlw-preliminary-final-sydney-roosters-cronulla-sharks/105825564</link><description>Jocelyn Kelleher is relishing the chance to prove her credentials as the Sydney Roosters look to claim back-to-back premierships for the first time in their history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c98d6e82e7da5e596aaac09a0d982f4d</guid></item><item><title>Woppaburra people welcome ancestor's return but face final hurdle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/woppaburra-peoples-fight-to-get-ancestor-home/105788102</link><description>More First Nations remains are being returned to Australia from international institutions, but these Woppaburra men say laying them to rest on country can prove a fresh challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f2752aea82ec37f1fac83229df02a1</guid></item><item><title>England defeats Canada 33-13 in Women's Rugby World Cup final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/rugby-world-cup-final-england-defeats-canada/105825580</link><description>In front of a record crowd of more than 80,000 spectators, England delivers on the biggest stage with a 33-13 defeat of Canada in the tournament decider at Twickenham.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62fcacd86e45554323ddd632300502bc</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's coal royalty regime back in the spotlight after job cuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/qld-coal-mine-royalties-regime-questioned-after-job-cuts/105818488</link><description>Despite a change of government, Queensland's controversial coal royalty scheme remains in place and recent job cuts are prompting renewed discussion about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05fc998cc23e435b2b1e012ba6d8ab22</guid></item><item><title>Sydney stomping grounds of 1920s and 30s crime bosses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/1920s-razor-gang-crime-bosses-that-wreaked-havoc-on-sydney/105749468</link><description>From the "queen of the underworld" to a razor gang slasher in control of an underworld empire, these were the bosses at the centre of an organised crime battle in the late 20s and early 30s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9422096e9eace91d69505b24dca8e33f</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane and Geelong fans experience the ecstasy and agony of AFL's biggest game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/afl-grand-final-lions-and-cats-fan-reactions/105824822</link><description>For the second year in a row, Brisbane Lions fans were celebrating in the streets as their team claimed the premiership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6337aba73bc17913cc11052d6f937e4</guid></item><item><title>Bowie Daly, 9, makes surfing comeback after surviving shark attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/bowie-daly-returns-to-surfing-weeks-after-shark-attack/105788210</link><description>Bowie Daly may be back in the surf but he says the near miss still plays on his mind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4545e4bca232ff37c4b0fe146c7aa2dc</guid></item><item><title>Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov warns NATO, Europe that aggression will be met with a 'decisive response'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/russian-foreign-minister-sergey-lavrov-warns-nato-europe-at-unga/105825572</link><description>While Russia does not intend to attack Europe, its Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov has not ruled out action against NATO aggression.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0368cfa881bd50ea3b87763fb766242f</guid></item><item><title>Fifty years on, Rocky Horror Picture Show proves weird never goes out of style</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/fifty-years-of-rocky-horror-picture-show-film/105804794</link><description>The Rocky Horror Picture Show film still screens in cinemas around the world, captivating a new generation of cinemagoers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c6992f9ff4dec50da0a3cccbfe42ef0</guid></item><item><title>Lions AFL coach Chris Fagan vindicated with Lachie Neale sub call in grand final win over Cats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/afl-grand-final-brisbane-lions-chris-fagan-lachie-neale/105825616</link><description>Brisbane Lions coach Chris Fagan admits he took a punt by naming Lachie Neale as the sub ahead of their stunning win over Geelong in the grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">356d4d2bcf5d986dedc6cb7aff32d029</guid></item><item><title>Rod Barwick has international fame as a daffodil breeder, but what matters to him is a love of gardening</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/rod-barwick-daffodil-breeder-glenbrook-bulb-farm/105803774</link><description>Rod Barwick planted his first daffodil bulbs in the 1970s. Within a few years he was breeding daffodils and has been recognised internationally for his work, but he says enjoying growing plants is the most important part of gardening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca3f901a514528002a7c6ff54fe81d6c</guid></item><item><title>Jindabyne residents priced out as short-term accommodation booms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/jindabyne-short-term-rentals-high-prices-tourism-snow/105761672</link><description>Jindabyne is grappling with how to capitalise on its winter tourism influx while ensuring long-term residents can continue to afford to live there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d127790f6eadfe17d4ce554be39b5dc</guid></item><item><title>Lavrov warns of 'decisive response' to aggression against Russia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/lavrov-warns-of-decisive-response-to-aggression/105825720</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31af8aa621febc5e6f67924394d4008b</guid></item><item><title>Australia finishes World Para Swimming Championships with relay gold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/world-para-swimming-championships-australia-wins-relay-gold/105825652</link><description>Australia claims its ninth gold medal at the World Para Swimming Championships on the final day of competition in Singapore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e76d111fc7d911f30e0f71e638962955</guid></item><item><title>Thirty years ago, Oasis made (What's The Story) Morning Glory? — a Britpop blockbuster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/oasis-morning-glory-30-years-anniversary-review-reunion/105816312</link><description>They'll soon tour Australia, but 30 years ago, Oasis were about to release (What's The Story) Morning Glory? — an enduring British rock classic. Here's how they did it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0332a614c6ebdac441c971670d46b82b</guid></item><item><title>Moment Brisbane Lions win 2025 AFL premiership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/moment-brisbane-lions-win-2025-afl-premiership/105825768</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb7106de6f4f1cb4bf66109d660b5cd7</guid></item><item><title>Ten-year-old mini bull rider from Cape York takes on world's best in Utah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/10-year-old-mini-bull-rider-competes-at-world-finals-in-utah-us/105817314</link><description>In a huge dark hat and shining belt buckle, a 10-year-old from Cape York proves he can mix it with the best at the world finals in Utah.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da9e4e8bec951353c341a9189fe44a20</guid></item><item><title>Calls for fresh probe into Yolŋu leader's mysterious disappearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/dhakiyarr-wirrpanda-disappearance-calls-for-new-probe/105822938</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd387d0cc91ed458af77837e55f1f3b4</guid></item><item><title>Dhakiyarr Wirrpanda's family in calls for fresh probe into mystery disappearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/nt-missing-yolngu-man-cold-case-police-killing-confession/105581636</link><description>The family of vanished Yolŋu leader Dhakiyarr Wirrpanda is calling on the Northern Territory coroner to pursue an ABC investigation's lead on his mysterious disappearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66e217a67165888621851fab3aed8814</guid></item></channel></rss>