<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 11:53:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>'Bloodbath' at Washington Post as massive layoffs announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/washington-post-layoffs/106307024</link><description>The Jeff Bezos-owned paper, which famously brought down US President Richard Nixon, will drastically cut back in size and lay off workers in all its departments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8394731a7449ead8a495e63eba201e42</guid></item><item><title>A 'ghost airport' and sinkhole highway as Timor-Leste gambles on oil and gas with Greater Sunrise project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/timor-leste-greater-sunrise-project-ghost-airport-and-sinkholes/106303186</link><description>The Greater Sunrise gas project was meant to transform Timor-Leste and bring billions in revenue, but locals are still waiting for the jobs and opportunities that were promised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">603ba36a5b4f815803e7ca0f07a4648c</guid></item><item><title>Online safety watchdog says tech giants failing to detect child abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/online-safety-watchdog-says-tech-giants-failing-on-child-abuse/106306564</link><description>Major tech companies including Apple, Google, Meta and Microsoft are still failing to do enough to detect and stop child sexual abuse, eSafety has claimed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ece1344204c760ec445b497d6251da3</guid></item><item><title>Report points to exploitation, Medicare and visa concerns in Pacific islander jobs scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/palm-scheme-report-calls-for-change/106298514</link><description>Changing jobs is a basic right for most people, but it is not so simple for Pacific Australia Labour Mobility workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f21909b4c4949bb2d5b3a261ebd665c</guid></item><item><title>In Zak Hilditch's horror movie We Bury the Dead, the zombie apocalypse devastates Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/we-bury-the-dead-movie-interview-zak-hilditch/106298866</link><description>These Final Hours writer and director Zak Hilditch drew on personal tragedy to produce We Bury the Dead, his biggest cinematic epic yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f08c892351946b5092876fe0022699c</guid></item><item><title>Report calls for Australia to grow security, trade and diplomatic ties with Taiwan because of China's influence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/australia-taiwan-security-trade-ties-should-expand-experts-say/106306736</link><description>Experts say Australia needs to do more to grow its relationship with Taiwan as China works to diplomatically isolate Taipei in the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1330754f2b1cb129cf14b6557beb0af6</guid></item><item><title>Fears SA's endangered glossy black-cockatoo eggs will 'cook' in nesting boxes during heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/kangaroo-island-glossy-black-cockatoos-heatwaves/106273812</link><description>South Australia's population of a unique subspecies of glossy black-cockatoos is heavily dependent on artificial nesting boxes. That could pose a problem during extreme heat conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92c894ea4f73cd62977ed5ac13ed4426</guid></item><item><title>Mother shares concerns about treatment at Toowoomba Hospital amid culture review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/mothers-raise-concerns-about-treatment-at-toowoomba-hospital/106049878</link><description>A confrontation caught on body-worn security footage in the halls of the Toowoomba Hospital maternity unit highlights concerns raised by local mothers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a112f801e8fcf10c351770673c3ebca7</guid></item><item><title>Grandmother removed from Toowoomba birth suite by security</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/grandmother-removed-from-toowoomba-birth-suite-by-security/106301414</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82f83e6cb6359c2e1b990d90449f47f9</guid></item><item><title>Man allegedly pretended to fire on people near bridge where Bondi terror attack occurred</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/man-charged-over-alleged-offensive-acts-at-bondi-beach-bridge/106307032</link><description>A man accused of mimicking firing on people near the pedestrian bridge where the Bondi terror attack occurred has been denied bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc69ac43a7239cdacca1fd936c6894a1</guid></item><item><title>Parramatta Eels veteran Josh Addo-Carr urges young teammates to step up after Zac Lomax depature</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/eels-josh-addo-carr-urges-backs-to-step-up-post-zac-lomax/106307096</link><description>Parramatta's next generation of outside backs must step up if they are to fill the void left by Zac Lomax, his ex-teammate Josh Addo-Carr has said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea4e92a9e372c42cef9125691653f930</guid></item><item><title>'Ironic' and 'lazy' AI-generated images shared on Queensland government department social media accounts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/fisheries-queensland-ai-images-social-media/106287728</link><description>A Queensland government department has urged social media users not to trust AI through the use of an AI-generated image.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efa4fbc893136c3c4c2bcc42e263c7db</guid></item><item><title>Pauline Hanson returns to Senate seat after seven-day suspension — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/federal-politics-live/106305974</link><description>One Nation Leader Pauline Hanson has returned to her seat in the Senate after she was suspended for seven sitting days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3c0cae8506b4df580cead12886e3518</guid></item><item><title>What are data centres and what do they mean for regional Victoria?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/inside-data-centre-computers-ai-information-storage-servers/105904128</link><description>With the announcement of two new facilities outside of Melbourne, could regional Victoria become a hotspot for data centres?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f298636a4109a23d53086ea1d6b5745</guid></item><item><title>Authorities say Appelbee family's rescue highlights unexpected dangers in WA's South West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/geographe-bay-water-safety-austin-appelbee/106306336</link><description>Marine Rescue workers tasked with monitoring WA's Geographe Bay say last week's astonishing rescue of a Perth family highlights the dangers facing tourists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13e4bb920220ee89906831f1827453fb</guid></item><item><title>Police launch investigation into sudden death in Toowoomba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/police-launch-investigation-into-sudden-death-in-toowoomba/106307100</link><description>Police have closed part of Bell Street and the Toowoomba bus terminal car park on Chronicle Lane in Toowoomba's CBD as part of the investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b8806170d7bec631fc6c26704d033eb</guid></item><item><title>What is the difference between a tropical low and cyclone in northern Australia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/meteorologist-explains-tropical-low-cyclone-difference-australia/106299336</link><description>Tropical lows are weaker than tropical cyclones, but a meteorologist explains they can still cause significant damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03da663f1e95f8663d18a36c3196f2a2</guid></item><item><title>Central Queensland conservation group wants to see more transparency on coal mine water releases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/call-for-more-information-on-coal-mine-water-release/106288312</link><description>There were 55 water releases from the region's coal mines in the month of January into the largest catchment draining to the Great Barrier Reef.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ff8693894a0a260e74954e81d5136b2</guid></item><item><title>Homeless Whitsunday boaties begin long rebuild after Tropical Cyclone Koji carnage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/homeless-sailors-tropical-cyclone-koji-aftermath/106304140</link><description>Around a dozen boats recovered by Marine Safety Queensland were part-time or permanent liveaboard boats, with boaties in the Whitsundays facing a long journey to find a new permanent home on or off the water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbed372baa692d7226e9b5fc59f9157c</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump, gold, interest rates and AI data centres to dominate company reporting season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/donald-trump-gold-interest-rates-ai-reporting-season/106306266</link><description>Australia's mining sector is expected to lead the earnings charge for this reporting season, boosted by signs of a stabilisation in the Chinese economy and a turbo-charged commodities market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56354f78af37bcda67f3e92d68cb1d7b</guid></item><item><title>NRL rookie Sebastian Su'a poised for breakout year after injury-plagued 2025 season with Dolphins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/nrl-rookie-sebastian-su-a-poised-for-breakout-year/106307552</link><description>The work ethic of a former Test fast bowler and the mentoring of an elite prop are inspiring Dolphins rookie Sebastian Su'a's NRL quest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5c998e776a7dca4626b0951980d5bc8</guid></item><item><title>Sydney man, 19, charged over alleged threats to kill Israeli president</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/sydney-teen-charged-threats-to-israel-president-isaac-herzog/106307538</link><description>Darcy Tinning was arrested by AFP officers on Wednesday and charged with making a threat to kill an "internationally protected person".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">710d51ed300bc62b14c2402ac4cb7ddd</guid></item><item><title>Worker's death at Tanami gold mine in Central Australia under investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/nt-tanami-mine-newmont-confirms-worker-death-tragic-incident/106307980</link><description>A 47-year-old worker has died following an incident at the Tanami gold mine in remote Central Australia, with police and NT WorkSafe investigating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1662970481b3a89b3a77c8d22c4b591</guid></item><item><title>New resource connects people with organisations on front lines of bushfire relief effort</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/resource-connecting-people-with-frontline-bushfire-relief-orgs/106273490</link><description>A new online resource aims to make it easier for people to contribute to bushfire relief efforts across Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd36f19dbab5f9df4c883c9b96a27f9f</guid></item><item><title>Police executing drug raid find deadly snakes, crocodile in alleged makeshift zoo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/police-discover-snakes-crocodile-during-kempsey-drug-raid/106307800</link><description>More than 50 reptiles, including a 1.3-metre crocodile, have been seized after police discovered an alleged makeshift zoo during a drug raid on the NSW Mid North Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">192a2b9248295d31e2166b2cd7d961e9</guid></item><item><title>Australians in Japan say ski fields are safe after spate of deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/australians-in-japan-say-ski-fields-are-safe/106307558</link><description>Australians working in Japan's ski fields say while the sport has unpredictable risks, there are ways to be prepared.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39a03324b4a4d2e1f6d635af5d43a345</guid></item><item><title>Queensland man charged after police allege 23,000 files of child abuse seized</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/qld-man-charged-with-online-child-abuse-related-offences/106307910</link><description>A Queensland man has been charged with 596 child abuse-related offences after he allegedly "groomed, coerced and threatened" hundreds of young people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e4a567f2ea302cdcfe0c2e38d52e2c3</guid></item><item><title>Two people in custody after alleged Huon Valley home invasion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/two-people-in-custody-after-alleged-huon-valley-home-invasion/106308590</link><description>Police take two people into custody in relation to an alleged early morning home invasion and firearms theft in the Huon Valley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa75d62edb1dff75376f7c6b0aa63ac6</guid></item><item><title>State of Origin 2027 in New Zealand hailed as a boost for rugby league by Kiwi great</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/state-of-origin-2027-in-new-zealand-boost-says-kiwi/106308612</link><description>The NRL's reported landmark move to host a State of Origin match in New Zealand is hailed as "sensational" by Kiwi legend Gary Freeman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">159d849e4617ffdb86ae3e8b97588b9a</guid></item><item><title>Gus disappearance declared major crime, suspect identified</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/police-update-on-missing-boy-gus-lamont/106307630</link><description>South Australian police have declared the disappearance of Gus Lamont a major crime and say a person who has lived at his outback property is now considered a suspect, but have stressed that the boy's parents are not under investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">341261f73a5b122ba7492151167fa9ae</guid></item><item><title>Invasion Day bomb declared terror act, as accused's 'pro-white ideology' probed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/perth-invasion-day-rally-attempted-bombing-terrorist-act/106303806</link><description>The attempted bombing of an Invasion Day rally in Perth's CBD last week is declared a terrorist attack by authorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bc486c32a0f3eb6459afa4f7641f5a9</guid></item><item><title>Strict caps on bottled water extraction urged for World Heritage-listed Springbrook</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/water-extraction-caps-at-world-heritage-springbrook/106304388</link><description>A long-awaited study warns that the extraction of bottled water from the World Heritage-listed Springbrook area poses a potential risk to the ancient Gondwana rainforests and should be strictly limited.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19d076e599ae81db17a9effaa24af962</guid></item><item><title>Private health insurers take aim at rising specialists fees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/private-health-insurers-take-aim-at-rising-specialists-fees/106308202</link><description>A survey of 4,000 patients finds more than half had an unexpected cost when under a specialist's care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3b29ee24b3af0599b1188251d3a6096</guid></item><item><title>AFL integrity unit looking into why police visited Melbourne Demons player Steven May</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/afl-integrity-unit-looking-into-why-police-visited-steven-may/106309028</link><description>Melbourne veteran Steven May is being investigated by the AFL integrity unit, as the premiership defender stays away from Demons training.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c42c8d49e23a155f085f14d82937f7e5</guid></item><item><title>ACTU pushing 'above-inflation' wage increase in 2026 as real paypackets decline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/actu-pushing-above-inflation-wage-increase-in-2026/106308042</link><description>Australia's biggest employers are under pressure to give their workers pay increases above 4 per cent this year, as real wages go backwards and the union movement ramps up pressure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1561858751d3b34e812d34954a75a67f</guid></item><item><title>Families respond after Westfield Bondi Junction stabbing inquest findings released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/families-react-westfield-bondi-junction-stabbing-inquest/106308886</link><description>Loved ones of victims Ashlee Good and Jade Young have fought back tears responding to findings from the high-profile inquest into the Westfield Bondi Junction stabbing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">971eff173ebca3c3a31f9914d604ef48</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie reads Art of War, Pauline Hanson returns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/andrew-hastie-pauline-hanson-clive-palmer-art-of-war/106294690</link><description>The calamity unfolding in the dissolved Coalition provided a convenient distraction for the government, which should have had a worse week amid an interest rate hike.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f8f4cd69aef50acb18d65e06bf186c0</guid></item><item><title>Mother of autistic children shares experience in wake of suspected double murder-suicide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/kalgoorlie-mother-with-two-autistic-children-jo-russell/106306344</link><description>A mother of two autistic children living in regional Western Australia has shared her experience of navigating bureaucracy while caring for children with complex needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2466f5262b39215d9077d95960b80a1</guid></item><item><title>Lockhart River Mayor Wayne William Butcher pleads guilty to Cairns bail breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/lockhart-river-mayor-wayne-william-butcher-bail-breach/106309858</link><description>A Far North Queensland mayor has pleaded guilty to two counts of breaching his bail conditions after he was found drinking tea in a casino with a person he must avoid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d25d211015b67c4f5a1d5efb7ea9fda9</guid></item><item><title>Old Spirit ferries up sale with new berth 'on track' for October launch, TT-Line says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/spirit-of-tasmania-oct-launch-date-on-track-tt-line/106307332</link><description>Ferry operator TT-Line is confident its two new Spirit of Tasmania vessels will begin operating by October — but it says there is a "risk" its existing ships might not be sold by then.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96626d61393ecd333e4ca7e74aa0b968</guid></item><item><title>More than 200 Daly River residents evacuated amid flood threat, with most staying at Darwin's Foskey Pavilion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/daly-river-flood-evacuees-arrive-in-darwin-foskey-pavilion/106308854</link><description>Hundreds of Daly River residents have been evacuated to Darwin ahead of expected major flooding, with Foskey Pavilion set up to accommodate most of the evacuees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">662060972dbfdad2598c5c5fca2c50eb</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne public housing tower residents win injunction against eviction notices ahead of High Court bid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/melbourne-housing-tower-injunction-against-eviction/106309622</link><description>Homes Victoria will be temporarily halted from evicting remaining residents at three Melbourne public housing towers in Flemington and North Melbourne, after an injunction was issued in Victoria's Court of Appeal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac97e2ca66d531e0cd8f886fcab92deb</guid></item><item><title>Bunnings wins fight to use AI facial recognition tech to combat store crime, opening door for other retailers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/bunnings-wins-ai-facial-recognition-tech-fight/106309308</link><description>Bunnings was reasonably entitled to use AI facial recognition technology to combat crime and staff abuse in its stores, the Administrative Review Tribunal finds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11a50582c492ed335c2d3ebadc4e8d41</guid></item><item><title>Murray-Darling Basin Authority hands down discussion paper ahead of first review in 14 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/murray-darling-basin-authority-plan-review-under-way/106307966</link><description>The Murray-Darling Basin Authority says the basin plan has delivered real benefits, but climate change, disconnected floodplains and poor water quality mean things still need to change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40ca47d8c527baec96da95cd77b458be</guid></item><item><title>NSW government contacts Newcastle Writers Festival about author Randa Abdel-Fattah's inclusion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/nsw-government-newcastle-writers-festival-randa-abdel-fattah/106310270</link><description>The NSW government makes contact with the board of next month's Newcastle Writers Festival about the inclusion of Palestinian-Australian author Randa Abdel-Fattah, the ABC understands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f89720cdcf51ab246cbcc55ed24f0196</guid></item><item><title>Albanese, Ley condemn alleged act of terror targeting Indigenous protesters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/albanese-ley-condemn-alleged-invasion-rally-terror-act/106309170</link><description>The prime minister and opposition leader have both condemned the alleged attempted bombing of an Invasion Day rally more than a week ago, after police revealed it was being prosecuted as a terror incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5627852046870a17972ecd39ceb5004e</guid></item><item><title>Democrat victory in Republican stronghold could spell trouble for Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/texas-special-runoff-election-results/106308914</link><description>The US has been gripped by cold weather in recent weeks, but pundits say it is in Texas where hell has truly frozen over. A blue wave just swept a GOP stronghold, and Republicans are very worried.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e651758ff0d99631704edb4c046d58f8</guid></item><item><title>Gus Lamont disappearance from Oak Park Station near Yunta: What has happened so far</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/timeline-of-gus-lamont-oak-park-disappearance/106309554</link><description>It is now more than four months since Gus Lamont went missing from his family's home in South Australia's outback, with the case being declared a major crime on Thursday. Here's what has happened so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c458d64bdef26badd7b278d4e3d5058</guid></item><item><title>How capital gains tax changes could impact you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/how-capital-gains-tax-changes-could-impact-you/106309066</link><description>According to a well-sourced leak, changes to capital gains tax discounts could form the centrepiece of the next federal budget in May. And while the government has downplayed the idea, it has not been ruled out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">566800855cbc95596fa22fe075eeef0e</guid></item><item><title>Union urges Sanjeev Gupta to sell Tahmoor mine as $350m offer revealed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/union-pressure-on-gupta-tahmoor-mine-sale/106309462</link><description>The Mining and Energy Union says a firm $350 million offer is on the table to restart Tahmoor Colliery, warning delays risk the mine's future and hundreds of jobs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc17aa194e049037a72616045ef64b12</guid></item><item><title>Man convicted of grooming one girl and raping another at Canberra Reptile Zoo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/man-convicted-sexual-assault-girls-canberra-reptile-zoo/106310784</link><description>A 26-year-old man has been convicted in the ACT Supreme Court of sexually assaulting two girls at Canberra Reptile Zoo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33ab35ad4d2b0b48e7630e638b33075e</guid></item><item><title>Coroner recommends Ambulance Victoria guideline review following nut allergy death of Max McKenzie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/anaphylaxis-death-nut-allergy-max-mckenzie-box-hill-hospital/106307284</link><description>The coroner could not definitively rule that the anaphylaxis death of 15-year-old Max McKenzie was preventable, despite identifying delays in the teen's medical treatment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7fb96224de8dfd3ac5b2522e7071ec1</guid></item><item><title>Thursday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106309854</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ac2a52ba0b6ad6ce9ccec04590edbb7</guid></item><item><title>Alleged attempted murder victim gives evidence in Shaun Michael Dunk trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/alleged-attempted-murder-victim-gives-evidence-shaun-dunk-trial/106307666</link><description>A woman who was stabbed multiple times in an alleged attack which killed her colleague at an Adelaide real estate office tells a court of her “fight for life”. Warning: This story contains content some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">833bc109e15f857ad157f430abc773b2</guid></item><item><title>Nationals issue Ley with reunion counteroffer as deadline looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/nationals-issue-ley-with-reunion-counteroffer/106311354</link><description>The minor party has given the opposition leader terms that one Nationals MP said they did "not expect" would be acceptable in what has been described as a bid to push out her self-imposed deadline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ad11d81c208265b1abb07a42b719062</guid></item><item><title>Victoria and Queensland lose 17 wickets on day one of MCG Sheffield Shield game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/mcg-sheffield-shield-queensland-victoria-17-wickets-day-one/106311360</link><description>After the two-day Ashes Test raised eyebrows over the MCG pitch, Queensland and Victoria are on track for another swift finish after 17 wickets on day one of their Sheffield Shield clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ed4a66d2d73a61e60062f1dd0187e85</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Junction inquest saw recommendation for supported housing for homeless, some are already benefitting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/bondi-junction-stabbing-inquest-habilis-mental-health-housing/106309484</link><description>An inquest into the Bondi Junction stabbing has recommended that the NSW government support long-term accommodation for homeless people experiencing mental health issues. It's a model that is already finding success.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a81fc4ebb5907745acfeae2e974efbeb</guid></item><item><title>Porsches, Maserati allegedly stolen from Melbourne homes during overnight crime spree</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/luxury-cars-stolen-melbourne-victoria-police/106311510</link><description>Four young men are charged after allegedly stealing three luxury vehicles from homes across Melbourne on Thursday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17e9e07691648c70fb20f7e7cf67d7a2</guid></item><item><title>NT politicians walk out of parliament to protest administrator's appointment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/politicians-protest-administrator-appointment-with-walkout/106309768</link><description>Seven members of the Northern Territory parliament have walked out of Question Time over the appointment of the next administrator, David Connolly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96fb1365a8bd12bcf9d3d83f46b89cba</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds defeat Jamaica in first netball Test match in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/diamonds-defeat-jamaica-in-adelaide/106311692</link><description>The Diamonds made a flying start with the initial six goals in a comprehensive 72-41 victory at the Adelaide Entertainment Centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be741f4d1fb677fd340efe1016d77511</guid></item><item><title>Russian captain of cargo ship Solong jailed over fatal North Sea collision</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/north-sea-collision-captain-jailed/106311942</link><description>A judge describes Vladimir Motin as "an accident waiting to happen" as he hands the Russian national a six-year jail term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87a1a23caacdafe5b4045a3c3b2ae840</guid></item><item><title>New study reveals how stressful footy fandom can be</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/study-reveals-how-stressful-footy-fandom-is/106310960</link><description>A new study reveals how much high-stakes sporting events can get the heart pumping by strapping trackers to over 200 German football fans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c31f01f9ec961ff01d3df42c41faafef</guid></item><item><title>Valentino Guseli gets snowboard big air wildcard, leaps into final at Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/val-guseli-snowboard-big-air-milano-cortina-winter-olympics/106312046</link><description>Valentino Guseli only found out he had been added to the big air field a couple of hours before the competition start after a rival's injury, but still found a way to make it to the final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84ec8404886766b47120ef6c552e418d</guid></item><item><title>Epstein files reveal the men who looked away after women had spoken up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/jeffrey-epstein-files-allegations-melinda-gates/106308164</link><description>The millions of pages of documents related to the late convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein have shone a light on how many influential men were ready to disregard the experiences of countless women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40d57aedebb5b5169d68dfe86d5517cc</guid></item><item><title>Positive spin from Liberal leader as retiring MP Sam Groth forces Nepean by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/member-for-nepean-sam-groth-resignation-analysis/106309684</link><description>When retiring first-term Liberal Sam Groth told his leader he was quitting politics, forcing a by-election, Jess Wilson didn't try to talk him out of it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d064ed909c98a4fe8b1620483b07061</guid></item><item><title>Today in history, February 6: The Manchester United team that perished in the Munich air disaster of 1958</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/manchester-united-munich-air-disaster-1958/106183032</link><description>On a snowy February afternoon in 1958, the football team that many were calling the greatest that Britain had ever produced stopped to refuel at Munich Airport. The plane would never take off, and the Flowers of Manchester would take years to bloom again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd269141d3e84cd66d24a4d4ebf71ed8</guid></item><item><title>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese signs security treaty with Indonesia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/pm-to-sign-security-treaty-with-indonesia/106311374</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has travelled to Jakarta to sign the treaty, which the Australian government calls the "biggest step" the countries have taken together in 30 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">542b9e5f54b180e31559e9247cbd743e</guid></item><item><title>Former attorney-general Mark Dreyfus warned anti-corruption chief to 'manage' or 'avoid' conflicts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/mark-dreyfus-warned-anti-corruption-chief-to-avoid-conflicts/106311478</link><description>A letter from Mark Dreyfus to Paul Brereton provides new insight into the expectations set for the inaugural chief of the anti-corruption watchdog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e67d41ae94005c162be09aa4254b2e2</guid></item><item><title>Effect of capital gains tax changes on housing affordability likely depends on design</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/would-higher-property-taxes-mean-lower-house-prices/106311582</link><description>Labor has not ruled out changes to the capital gains tax discount but wants any tax changes to improve housing affordability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8837e3812457a3afcc82335b9e69139a</guid></item><item><title>Jim Chalmers's appetite for economic reform is about to be tested</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/jim-chalmers-inflation-interest-rates-economy-federal-budget/106294832</link><description>Jim Chalmers could face his biggest test yet as treasurer over the next few months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a3a90492a5e83271ed0e7dfbd2089e3</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: When does it start, how to watch and who is competing in which sports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/winter-olympics-milano-cortina-2026-when-where/106188146</link><description>Australia is tipped for enormous success over the next couple of weeks so now might be a good time to clue yourself up. Here's everything you need to know about the 2026 Winter Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a93b24614f2e1ae879ffc8503e731c6</guid></item><item><title>The questions dogging the search for Gus Lamont after latest police update</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/gus-lamont-update-leaves-more-questions-than-answers/106311214</link><description>Police declared the disappearance of Gus Lamont a major crime due to "a number of inconsistencies and discrepancies" emerging during the four-month investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1798830495f9ff4dfc031d74279bc716</guid></item><item><title>An ex-jihadi and terror experts agree on one thing about extremism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/bondi-terror-attack-radicalisation-islamic-state-group/106300484</link><description>As police probe what led to the deadliest terror attack on Australian soil in December, radicalisation researchers and a former Islamic State group supporter have shed light on how people are recruited.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5cd14c9f76f47554b7f5454f0088c8a</guid></item><item><title>World Anti-Doping Agency bosses 'will look at' claims of penis enlargement in ski jumping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/wada-will-investigate-ski-jumper-penis-enlargement-allegations/106311706</link><description>The World Anti-Doping Agency will investigate bizarre claims in German newspaper Bild that ski jumpers are injecting substances into their penises to aid aerodynamics — and other stories from the Winter Olympics a day out from the opening ceremony.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84586ef0f66b1f30261a833dd26efe85</guid></item><item><title>US hopes to challenge China's critical minerals dominance with new trading bloc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/us-pitches-new-critical-minerals-trading-bloc/106309202</link><description>The US is urging dozens of countries to follow Australia's lead and sign on to a plan to stop relying on China for the critical minerals used in modern technology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4c34d4de059770202fdc288ddc3883b</guid></item><item><title>After the ICE shooting of Renee Nicole Good in Minneapolis, a week of chaos unfolds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/renee-nicole-good-minneapolis-ice-shooting-timeline/106283054</link><description>Renee Good and her wife moved to Minneapolis "to make a better life" with their six-year-old son. But just over two minutes into an encounter with ICE agents she was fatally shot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e825dd4bb27569e03b8e78c060ecdeb</guid></item><item><title>What Israel's President Isaac Herzog has said about Gaza, and why he won't be arrested in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/herzog-will-be-aware-controversy-wont-be-arrested-in-australia/106311734</link><description>When Israel's president lands in Australia this weekend, he can expect an official red carpet treatment. But he will be all too aware of the controversy his visit is generating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ffdecd9e59cf515e239536238754ac7</guid></item><item><title>ATO debt continues to drive record level of calls to small business financial helpline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/debts-to-ato-drive-record-level-of-financial-helpline-calls/106308516</link><description>Financial counsellors say small businesses struggling to pay debts owed to the tax office are driving calls to Australia's Small Business Debt Helpline higher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5e7106c0d32cd232b4538e4271760e1</guid></item><item><title>Karnivool's new album In Verses was worth the 13-year wait, bagpipes and all</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/karnivool-unpacks-album-in-verses-bagpipes-mental-health/106307988</link><description>They're one of Australia's most revered heavy acts. And arguably the most patient. Karnivool unpack the 13-year journey to their new album, In Verses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6bdc3938421e42eb84f1f18d410adb7</guid></item><item><title>Late NSW tradie Brett Mckay connected with thousands by sharing cancer battle online</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/brett-mckay-legacy-after-sharing-cancer-battle-via-social-media/106295230</link><description>When NSW tradie Brett Mckay started sharing videos of his cancer journey with his mates on social media, he did not expect thousands of strangers to come along for the ride.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b28afc999a5809b20a0a7c420ae28ce2</guid></item><item><title>ASX suffers worst day in almost a year in 'panic' sell-off — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/asx-markets-business-news-friday-6-february-live-updates/106312232</link><description>Nearly $70 billion has been wiped off the Australian share market in its worst trading session since the "Liberation Day" sell-off in April 2025. See how the day unfolded and read insights from our business reporters on the ABC News markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95d2e163f643de9fc3d6f43e274be5d4</guid></item><item><title>Nationals counter Ley's offer with two-week frontbench exile — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/federal-politics-live/106310298</link><description>The Nationals have proposed spending another two weeks in exile from the frontbench rather than address the Liberals' non-negotiable conditions for a Coalition reunion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6336bed62f747957f082b887d6fdb45f</guid></item><item><title>Georgia Voll helps Royal Challengers Bengaluru win Indian Women's Premier League</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/royal-challengers-bengaluru-win-indian-women-premier-league/106312236</link><description>Royal Challengers Bengaluru pulled off the biggest successful chase in the Women's Premier League to win their second title in the Indian franchise-based T20 league.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e308434821166760b39b511e513be5cf</guid></item><item><title>NT treasurer Bill Yan says ballooning $11.7bn debt worries him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/nt-paying-millions-a-day-to-keep-afloat-bill-yan-stateline/106309650</link><description>The NT Treasurer Bill Yan outlines his plans for the NT's financial future, saying private investment will be key to turning the debt around.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">053e01f868ba1a3e41ebb5d1c7728840</guid></item><item><title>Fisheries Minister Jackie Jarvis defends controversial Perth and WA demersal fishing ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/wa-fisheries-minister-jackie-jarvis-defends-demersal-fish-ban/106306094</link><description>A "judgement call" about a permanent commercial fishing ban for demersal species went further than the advice handed to her, WA's Fisheries Minister Jackie Jarvis says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df7ef0deccac81a9af72a209aa445804</guid></item><item><title>WA Premier Roger Cook writes letter to 13yo hero swimmer Austin Appelbee</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/wa-premier-writes-letter-to-13yo-hero-swimmer-austin-appelbee/106311516</link><description>Premier Roger Cook writes to the 13-year-old, who made international headlines after swimming 4 kilometres in rough seas to raise the alarm and save his family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f53f88274bd50f3bd2024fb2f1e946fb</guid></item><item><title>Pharmacy apologises after customers given wrong medicines, scripts in Broome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/pharmacy-customers-detail-wrong-medicines-and-scripts-in-broome/106308810</link><description>More than a dozen customers have come forward over concerns two Broome chemists have handed out the wrong medications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f538e97e2b860296b05ed825dc97371</guid></item><item><title>NSW chief justice criticises Tony Abbott's comments on Sydney Harbour Bridge protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/judge-andrew-bell-criticises-tony-abbott-gaza-protest-comments/106308690</link><description>The former prime minister said it should not be for judges to decide when a political protest was justified, which are remarks NSW's top judge called "regrettable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98ab6cec7508f3de2ac09cc3f44222b3</guid></item><item><title>Tristan Peter Ryan faces court after allegedly threatening Prime Minister Anthony Albanese on social media</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/qld-man-beenleigh-court-allegedly-threatening-politicians/106312368</link><description>The court heard the posts included phrases such as "I want your head on a block Albo" and "I want permission to claim your head".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5e2767dac1662f2799f1039aa304fe9</guid></item><item><title>Magnetic fields, psychedelics and ketamine helping to treat the brain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/mental-health-facility-offers-ketamine-psilocybin-treatments/106090572</link><description>A Queensland not-for-profit mental health clinic that delivers novel therapies such as ketamine and psilocybin is expanding its services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">777a273bd12425d8facfba3249d6e2a9</guid></item><item><title>Prosecutors abandon drug trafficking case against Tony Mokbel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/tony-mokbel-drug-trafficking-charges-abandoned/106312416</link><description>Prosecutors have abandoned a drug trafficking case against underworld figure Tony Mokbel following his release from prison last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba15edf1879c688d4930ef676d0b552f</guid></item><item><title>Man and woman charged over alleged domestic violence murder in Goulburn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/charges-laid-over-alleged-domestic-violence-murder/106312402</link><description>Two people in their 40s have been charged over the alleged domestic violence murder of a 48-year-old woman in Goulburn earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a88dc9103a4ea76dc55ca1b2ce04005</guid></item><item><title>Demersal fishing reforms drive fish and chip price rise on WA's south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/fish-and-chip-prices-increase-wa-demersal-fishing-ban/106296470</link><description>The two-time winner of Australia's Best Takeaway Fish and Chips says it has been forced to increase prices considerably following Western Australia's demersal fishing reforms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd1a023e56ad7e334fe96734f82e30a1</guid></item><item><title>Two people charged over domestic violence murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/two-people-charged-over-domestic-violence-murder/106312740</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eef7ad5d95f899d2d1b8a5232869bb52</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Jewish leader wants stronger crackdown on symbols, flags, and slogans in wake of Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/qld-jewish-board-of-deputies-bondi-attack-antisemitism/106310388</link><description>Queensland Jewish Board of Deputies president Jason Steinberg has called on the state government to ramp up anti-hate laws in the wake of last year's Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">657fe1e021667e15565d5bcf8e958757</guid></item><item><title>Louvre releases photos of squashed crown abandoned by jewel heist gang</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/louvre-heist-empress-eugenie-crown-to-be-restored/106312526</link><description>The thieves who robbed the famed Paris museum last October dropped the diamond and emerald-studded crown as they escaped, leaving it crushed and broken.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80c91de186b4aa4f509ce7c72582cf12</guid></item><item><title>Beyond the Songs Inside: After the applause</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/beyond-the-songs-inside-documentary/106032528</link><description>Creative prison programs are celebrated for their ability to heal and transform incarcerated people. But are they enough to break the cycle?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">522012622427958b8365731ca8a4abfe</guid></item><item><title>Questions raised over $93 million investment in WA school with 30 per cent attendance rate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/roebourne-school-low-attendance-lands-93-million-rebuild/106232702</link><description>By the end of 2026 the WA government and Woodside will have spent over $93 million on Roebourne District High School and its 141 enrolled students. But last year only one in four upper school students attended.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cdd919ebf3696cf88d426b1371b09e7</guid></item><item><title>Man shot dead by police after suspected domestic-related stabbing on NSW Mid North Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/forster-fatal-shooting-stabbing-critical-incident/106313028</link><description>Police say a man shot dead by an officer was armed with a knife and chainsaw when he stabbed a woman during an earlier assault in Tuncurry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dc46f966645a6620d1b34cd8edf7b8e</guid></item><item><title>Grandmother removed from Toowoomba birth suite by security</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/grandmother-removed-from-toowoomba-birth-suite-by-security/106312824</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7707483e20eab63b8f53e40475883021</guid></item><item><title>Plenty of barramundi expected to be caught this year after Queensland's wild weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/fishers-hopeful-wild-weather-will-mean-plenty-of-barramundi/106299924</link><description>Commercial fishers are hopeful for an abundance of barramundi after heavy rainfall from ex-Tropical Cyclone Koji on the east coast and ongoing flooding in the Gulf of Carpentaria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9e1f3269c5f4e9ebc2e6800496974a1</guid></item><item><title>NSW Liberal leader Kellie Sloane talks Chris Minns, polls, slogan bans and Bondi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/nsw-liberals-kellie-sloane-talks-minns-polls-slogans-and-bondi/106310818</link><description>The leader of the NSW opposition says the trait behind Premier Chris Minns's popularity is also his greatest weakness, declaring the Coalition is "absolutely in the game" to win next year's state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">799edd3b53920580ddc28a03d66a91d5</guid></item><item><title>French authorities sink tonnes of cocaine bound for Australia, then release suspects</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/french-authorities-sink-five-tonnes-of-cocaine/106307438</link><description>French authorities intercept a ship carrying five tonnes of cocaine bound for Australia, before releasing the vessel and its crew.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9429ea7a44b7fd6eb152b561ab54a17</guid></item><item><title>Victoria Police wrap up five-day search for Dezi Freeman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/victoria-police-wrap-up-five-day-search-for-dezi-freeman/106312492</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">980e52b8e755e4714aea6a625fb5f178</guid></item><item><title>No sign of Dezi Freeman as latest search ends in Mount Buffalo National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/latest-dezi-freeman-manhunt-ends-at-mount-buffalo/106312280</link><description>Detectives say they will not give up on finding Victorian fugitive Dezi Freeman, accused of killing two police officers and injuring a third.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">160ebf8795092502f79fbbe808695189</guid></item><item><title>Terrorist act declaration for Invasion Day attempted bombing shows WA has changed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/wa-will-never-be-the-same-after-invasion-day-terror-act-charged/106311080</link><description>It will take time and significant effort to repair relationships with the Indigenous community amid the fallout from last week's attempted bombing in the Perth CBD — but other growing rifts in society will be even harder to mend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23f6e3d28b465ad95a9a20c73b8a09a8</guid></item><item><title>How sport was both healing and isolating in the aftermath of a violent sexual assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/blathnaid-raleigh-sports-role-in-sexual-assault-aftermath/106308960</link><description>Sport was both healing and isolating in the aftermath of a violent sexual assault for Irishwoman Bláthnaid Raleigh.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb52898cf37b9984cba0ea4038941668</guid></item><item><title>Parton confirms serious Greens–Liberals talks to bring down ACT Labor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/act-parton-confirms-serious-greens-liberals-coalition-talks/106313852</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5865694e87535cb6ad47b28036117399</guid></item><item><title>Gus Lamont's grandparents 'absolutely devastated' by major crime declaration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/gus-lamont-grandparents-release-statement/106314122</link><description>The grandparents of missing four-year-old boy Gus Lamont say the family has "cooperated fully with the investigation and want nothing more than to find Gus and reunite him with his mum and dad".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61b66feeae95a94497e72683ac842ff0</guid></item><item><title>Australia's surging expectations at the Winter Olympics come thanks to Geoff Henke's strident advocacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/winter-olympics-success-for-australia-geoff-henke-revolution/106302018</link><description>Australia is hoping Milano Cortina 2026 will be its most successful Winter Olympics in history. The reason for Australia's winter sports surge has its roots in a 70-year-old snubbing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">864e05b9f59b0989d860aae75009df3d</guid></item><item><title>The easiest way to clean your microwave and a common mistake to avoid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/what-is-the-best-way-to-clean-a-microwave/106307346</link><description>When was the last time you cleaned your microwave? According to experts, it's actually a lot simpler than cleaning other appliances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b708e459302ab8131d3d781a896a62ad</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Mitchell expected to form into category two system in WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/tropical-cyclone-mitchell-forecast-pilbara-kimberley/106310802</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says Tropical Cyclone Mitchell has a high chance of forming into a category two system, bringing destructive winds and heavy rain to northern WA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee400f88b198bb7c1d1db47c86f20493</guid></item><item><title>Brodie Jake Dewar faces upgraded charge of manslaughter after Labor identity Tim Picton's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/charge-upgraded-to-manslaughter-for-tim-picton-alleged-attacker/106313060</link><description>The man accused of a one-punch attack on former Labor strategist Tim Picton, who died in hospital last month, has his charge upgraded to manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61de2fdf6803039343685d247b1ee662</guid></item><item><title>Premier Chris Minns says Newcastle Writers Festival 'crazy' to invite author Randa Abdel-Fattah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/randa-abdel-fattah-author-to-attend-newcastle-writers-festival/106312828</link><description>The festival's director said Dr Abdel-Fattah was invited in August last year and denied the state government pressured her to remove the writer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6e1886c2439b2a6c3591dab671487e5</guid></item><item><title>WA author Craig Silvey has child exploitation bail conditions altered after complaining of media attention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/craig-silvey-court-appearance-bail-conditions-altered/106312848</link><description>WA children's author Craig Silvey gets his bail conditions altered by a Perth court after complaining of "significant media attention" since being charged with child exploitation offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">863da9d2b143ceee4249717f0ee1f2da</guid></item><item><title>Police to resume searching for Celine Cremer items at Waratah after bones discovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/police-to-resume-searching-celine-cremer-waratah-tasmania/106314944</link><description>Tasmania Police will again head into thick bushland to continue searching for more items in the area where Belgian tourist Celine Cremer vanished in 2023 — after the shock discovery of bones last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc62a6cfa45051ba56cce33aab397cae</guid></item><item><title>Handful of residents remain in Daly River amid impending major flooding, as hundreds evacuated to Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/nt-daly-river-flood-handful-of-residents-stay-after-evacuation/106313380</link><description>Some long-term residents have decided to stay behind in Daly River to help amid impending major flooding, after more than 200 people were evacuated to Darwin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2206b76eb8bd7df0127affd68712616</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's free influenza vaccine program to return this year with nasal spray for children aged two to five</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/free-flu-vaccine-program-with-nasal-spray-for-children/106314974</link><description>The program — which will run from March to September — will provide free flu vaccinations, including a nasal spray option for children aged two to five years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6535ffc1b447b733a2730a130f983211</guid></item><item><title>RecipeTin Eats' Nagi Maehashi is normalising taking time off for pets. Here's why that matters.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/recipetineats-nagi-maehashi-time-off-work-care-for-dog-dozer/106313752</link><description>Experts say our pets have become such an important part of our lives that it's important to take a step back from responsibilities, if possible, when they are sick or dying.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9cbd7b56d7377cd2c066ce8db744bca</guid></item><item><title>Man faces court charged with possessing extremist material after phone search at Brisbane Airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/extremist-material-charge-after-phone-search-brisbane-airport/106315576</link><description>Police allege a 25-year-old man intercepted at Brisbane International Airport had violent extremist material on his phone, after an investigation into an alleged Nazi flag delivery to the man.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">507bf1b576bc371496a5d69577c3b4b6</guid></item><item><title>Bullock says government spending not sole factor pushing inflation higher as political fight heats up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/rba-governor-refuses-to-blame-government-for-rising-inflation/106313266</link><description>RBA governor Michele Bullock has refused to blame the Albanese government for rising inflation, as a political fight breaks out in the wake of the bank's rate hike.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c98b12981d05c59ed145353062642772</guid></item><item><title>Josh Hazlewood out of T20 World Cup with injury in another blow to Australia's hopes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/josh-hazlewood-out-of-t20-world-cup-injury-australia/106315684</link><description>Josh Hazlewood is ruled out of Australia's T20 World Cup campaign as he continues to recover from the injuries which kept him from playing in the summer's Ashes series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc2eaa2ecdfd92d77e913bc4aef7b367</guid></item><item><title>Patrol boats out of action in Cairns shipyards as foreign fishers reach Australian shores</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/patrol-boats-out-of-water-amid-illegal-foreign-fishing-influx/106309428</link><description>A "continuous" influx of illegal foreign fishing boats in Queensland waters coincides with at least two of the nation's fleet of patrol boats being out of commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4161f0b872e22c9609c84a3991e94649</guid></item><item><title>Why it took police nine days to declare the Invasion Day attempted bomb attack in Perth terrorism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/process-to-declare-invasion-day-alleged-attack-terrorism-/106314916</link><description>When a homemade fragment bomb was allegedly thrown into a crowd on January 26, it took nine days for it to be declared an act of terrorism. The WA police commissioner explains why, as Indigenous leaders raise concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3aa7ffedfadafcc72701809222cd8964</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Snook, The Newsreader and Bring Her Back triumph at AACTA Awards — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/aacta-awards-2026-live-blog-winners-sarah-snook-celeste-barber/106295178</link><description>Australia's answer to the Oscars — the AACTAs — lit up the Gold Coast tonight, with horror Bring Her Back and The Narrow Road to the Deep North dominating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">473742d5b25ca33648f2c7c0647748d5</guid></item><item><title>Student allegedly raped by Hobart teacher in 1980s disclosed concerns, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/hobart-matriculation-college-student-alleged-rape-trial/106314120</link><description>A student who was allegedly raped by a Hobart teacher in the 1980s was told to focus on her studies after raising concerns with the teacher's behaviour, a court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">699c796ee3d839d6dceb2b50fb9f7c92</guid></item><item><title>Accused murderer Shaun Michael Dunk told police he wanted to kill 'a few people', court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/shaun-michael-dunk-murder-trial-police-interview/106315738</link><description>A recorded police interview reveals that a man accused of killing a woman at a real estate business in Adelaide was not satisfied with his alleged murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51f8e90094cc16ff3b586f8adca7dbbc</guid></item><item><title>Friday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106316284</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">442d545004b23100d0c522b6883e3f48</guid></item><item><title>Pentagon reportedly asked to probe SpaceX for potential Chinese ownership seen as a 'national security threat'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/pentagon-asked-to-probe-spacex-chinese-ownership/106311868</link><description>Chinese investment in Elon Musk's company SpaceX has been cited as a "national security threat", according to senators Elizabeth Warren and Andy Kim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a14c66ba0a91388f5002547f0fc8165b</guid></item><item><title>Evidence concludes in inquest into psychiatric patient's death at Alice Springs Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/kumanjayi-brogus-inquest-nt-alice-springs-hospital-death/106309452</link><description>A coronial inquest has heard that the death of a 34-year-old mother who was repeatedly sedated during a schizophrenic episode was "entirely preventable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e37e11908baa219401597f522da46fe7</guid></item><item><title>AACTA 2026 winners list: Gory horror wins best film, Jacob Elordi drama dominates TV</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/aactas-winners-list-jacob-elordi-key-moments/106315590</link><description>Directors Danny and Michael Philippou clean up at the 2026 AACTA awards, taking home 10 statues for their chilling horror film Bring Her Back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">180771fbc8035cfdbeeb3540d53fab91</guid></item><item><title>TC Mitchell set to become severe category 3 system off WA's Pilbara coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/wa-pilbara-warnings-cyclone-mitchell/106314534</link><description>Residents along WA's Pilbara coast have been warned to prepare to shelter as Cyclone Mitchell builds into a severe category 3 system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b97a227aadadcc4688c45e3310259768</guid></item><item><title>Daisy Thomas, competing without an ACL, suffers heavy crash at Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/daisy-thomas-acl-milano-cortina-2026-winter-olympics/106316542</link><description>Australian freestyle skier Daisy Thomas, who is competing at the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games without an ACL, suffers a heavy fall in slopestyle training and has withdrawn from the event to focus on big air.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f025e657abeae9134b373e8a2e58473</guid></item><item><title>US accuses China of secret nuclear testing as Washington calls for Beijing to be part of new arms deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/us-accuses-china-of-secret-nuclear-testing/106316826</link><description>The claim comes as the US calls for China to be involved in a new deal limiting the use of nuclear weapons, after the New START deal expired this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cb9e860548f8785bbe0b55a630e419e</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump shares, then deletes, then refuses to apologise for posting video depicting Obamas as monkeys</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/trump-posts-video-showing-obamas-as-monkeys-on-truth-social/106316714</link><description>The video was part of a late-night posting spree centred on debunked conspiracy theories linked to the 2020 US election, which the president has falsely claimed was stolen from him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b6db1856379b704580e52cac6e9c085</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's invitation to Herzog is a shift in his approach to Israel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/isaac-herzog-visit-australia/106294858</link><description>Unravelling the threads of antisemitism and anti-Israeli sentiment will require both more political courage and more community tolerance than we have seen to date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0a6a89c96284aff250024f0220ea9d0</guid></item><item><title>Budget reform is back as Labor shapes second term agenda</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/interest-rate-hikes-capital-gains-tax-federal-budget/106294868</link><description>As the opposition and government wrestled in the hay barn over who's to blame for this week's Reserve Bank interest rate increase, there's a much bigger story unfolding in the wings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dc0206816713526b054a2235c2c6cbb</guid></item><item><title>'Another world is possible': Calls for unity at Winter Olympics opening</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/winter-olympics-opening-ceremony-live-blog/106305458</link><description>The 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics are here, launched in an historic opening ceremony held in a number of Italian locations simultaneously.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0991b17313ac249b3564bdd43d3536aa</guid></item><item><title>Former ambassador Ian Kemish writes about Europe's 'forgotten' war in debut novel Two Islands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/ian-kemish-ambassador-book-two-islands-balkan-war/106309626</link><description>Former ambassador Ian Kemish draws on his 25-year diplomatic career in his debut novel, Two Islands, set against the backdrop of the Balkan War.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05ef96597ffb663c7a85cc4469dd35e3</guid></item><item><title>ABC 50/50 quiz: This week we're testing your knowledge of Gladiator, James Bond and your right to party</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/abc-5050-quiz-february-7/106303852</link><description>Every question has only two options: One is right and the other is wrong. You have an even chance of guessing correctly each time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54e87959e3395ec901d768bcd65118c1</guid></item><item><title>British PM Sir Keir Starmer pressured to resign amid fallout of Peter Mandelson's ties to Jeffrey Epstein</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/starmer-uk-pm-mandelson-epstein-files-calls-to-resign/106315470</link><description>Sir Keir Starmer led Labour to a landslide election victory two years ago, but in the past week, things have unravelled for the British prime minister. What went wrong?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">872ae7d2ee39997680208325d4ab5caa</guid></item><item><title>Elders say truth-telling 'critical' to combatting racism after alleged terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/perth-first-nations-elders-call-for-truth-healing-and-justice/106314644</link><description>For Noongar Elders, the alleged attack on Boorloo/Perth is viewed against the background of a long history of violence. They are calling for a truth-telling commission to heal deep scars and help to combat racism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5a4e6692d897a27ad96d0fecbf58894</guid></item><item><title>ICC T20 World Cup: Everything you need to know and who to support as a neutral cricket fan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/cricket-t20-world-cup-ultimate-guide-who-to-support/106307782</link><description>As another T20 World Cup sneaks up on us, here's everything you need to know about the tournament, including a guide on how to pick which team to support, depending on your needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">244273c35ff46c6ce067b4171a530bce</guid></item><item><title>Inside the 'textbook' search for Gus Lamont</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/police-search-for-gus-lamont-explained/106312846</link><description>A retired police officer who helped pioneer search guidelines used during the investigation into the disappearance of Gus Lamont, praises the efforts to find the missing boy and expresses support for the detectives' conclusions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a73e5fd0ac7db7d7191779204b63cb8d</guid></item><item><title>Vaibhav Sooryavanshi, India's 14-year-old batting prodigy, breaks records in Under-19 World Cup final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/vaibhav-sooryavanshi-india-14yo-world-cup-final/106316944</link><description>The 14-year-old prodigy Vaibhav Sooryavanshi breaks Alyssa Healy's record with the highest score ever in a World Cup final to power India to the global under-19 crown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9a291c39d2bac1693c6f902371b6cd0</guid></item><item><title>Weather sees nationwide soaking as tropical humidity reaches south-east Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/rainy-weather-for-most-australia-due-to-tropical-humidity/106314658</link><description>Almost every corner of Australia will pick up rain during the next seven days, including heavy falls and pockets of flooding in multiple states.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7969504c93bd1af8ab23366660a7793</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide Festival leader Julian Hobba reflects on Writers' Week controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/sa-adelaide-festival-director-says-writers-week-saga-preventable/106306654</link><description>As Adelaide Writers' Week went up in flames, Julian Hobba contemplated resigning as Adelaide Festival's executive director. He now says "we needed to trust the judgement" of the literary event's former leader, Louise Adler.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6512b46457dc635dd9be1ece4907ad35</guid></item><item><title>Collision sport Run Nation Championship in Sydney sells 5,000 tickets despite head injury concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/run-nation-championship-sydney-injury-concern/106309620</link><description>The Run Nation Championship will see two athletes run at each other, in a sport criticised for its head injury risks. Organisers argue the championship has been professionalised, and will grow to be as big as boxing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23e3635bb32c11200b36934e253da646</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Shincheonji members accuse church of pressure to make large donations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/ex-shincheonji-members-allege-financial-abuse-church-cult/106247460</link><description>Former members of Christian fringe group Shincheonji have alleged financial abuse by the religious organisation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">754433eee6987a58871ddf8249f97fc4</guid></item><item><title>Golden bandicoot numbers triple at Newhaven Wildlife Sanctuary in Central Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/golden-bandicoot-population-triples-newhaven-wildlife-sanctuary/106280368</link><description>A population of threatened golden bandicoots is booming at Newhaven Wildlife Sanctuary, north-west of Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">127ab3e60e9dc2ca6cffb951c58e803e</guid></item><item><title>Meringandan collector sells vintage tractors, trucks, machines on Queensland farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/meringandan-collector-sells-vintage-tractors-trucks-machines-qld/106305032</link><description>As the last man standing, 78-year-old cattleman Mervyn has parted with his collection of tractors and utes, pledging his estate to charity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">467219dc24b07990a0bbb37f1d3c6d41</guid></item><item><title>Epstein files reaffirm even a conviction doesn't taint 'good bloke' status</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/jeffrey-epstein-good-character-reference/106307992</link><description>The rich and powerful were all too happy to stay connected to Jeffrey Epstein until it became the less convenient option.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ccb9e603f7a0840f1ddee0df072a838</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man who murdered ex-wife in kitchen believed he had been badly treated, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/act-man-faces-court-for-murdering-ex-wife-in-their-home/106315142</link><description>Disturbing new details emerge about the 2023 stabbing death of a woman in her Bruce home as her former partner faces sentencing for her murder in the ACT Supreme Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12b5a2540a02a7cc87777374c8869d52</guid></item><item><title>How a cheating Brisbane socialite orchestrated her high-flying husband’s 1953 murder in a Hamilton mansion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/brisbane-murder-plot-roy-ferguson-1953/106263782</link><description>The brutal killing of a high-flying hotelier in his Brisbane mansion led to decades of rumour, myth and speculation about what unfolded on that fateful night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e9eb1fddb231085c977504bd352a4e3</guid></item><item><title>PFAS foam was used to extinguish a tanker crash just off the M1 Motorway at Ourimbah, on December 8, 2000.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/tanker-crash-just-off-the-m1-motorway-at-ourimbah/106303218</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">341aa7e2b3523d4ec7b91c5164453751</guid></item><item><title>‘Absolutely horrified’: Community left in the dark about PFAS contamination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/pfas-contamination-investigation-ourimbah-creek-catchment-nsw/106037472</link><description>For 25 years this waterway was polluted with toxic "forever chemicals". It was only disconnected from a major drinking supply 18 months ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8f44774d8f3802eb99d4f9f000c87ef</guid></item><item><title>Leo Howard's family pays tribute after three men died in light plane crash near Goolwa South</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/three-men-died-in-light-plane-crash-off-sa-coast/106316980</link><description>One of three people who died in a light plane crash south of Adelaide has been identified as an experienced pilot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dfcf45ccd0ecee92f936a26fe8aa6f0</guid></item><item><title>Australian athletes to watch at the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/aussies-to-watch-milano-cortina-winter-olympic-games-2026/106273742</link><description>Australia is taking its strongest ever team to the Winter Olympics in 2026, with a number of genuine medal chances. Here's a handful of the stars you need to pay attention to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bd59a489c46987c65b9466b27e8d05c</guid></item><item><title>Easy homemade granola that will last you weeks - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/easy-chunky-granola-with-nuts-and-seeds/105442842</link><description>When it comes to batch cooking, don't forget breakfast. This granola can make mornings easier and will last weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a385d3e380c821e791d0def365c56e1</guid></item><item><title>Iran's mysterious Pickaxe Mountain a 'candidate' for new nuclear activities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/iran-nuclear-sites-program-us-strikes-pickaxe-mountain-uranium/106288446</link><description>Since the US bombed Iran's key nuclear sites last year, analysts say work has increased at a secret underground facility that could be used to restart Tehran's nuclear program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8373cfa69a2a2fbf89f948ec7353e78</guid></item><item><title>Nancy Guthrie may have been abducted in a 41-minute window, authorities say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/nancy-guthrie-potentially-abducted-in-41-minute-window/106313064</link><description>Nancy Guthrie was last seen alive when a relative dropped her outside her Tucson home after a family games night. The 84-year-old grandmother has now been missing for a week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa5ac9bb51cacf8178ae332625490dbc</guid></item><item><title>Wodonga Hume Freeway bushfire February 1</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/wodonga-hume-freeway-bushfire-february-1/106307704</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c80ef376ef1e96d0788cdaa2ba4379da</guid></item><item><title>Dashcam footage shows beginnings of spotfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/dashcam-footage-shows-beginnings-of-spotfires/106315864</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">659c010abc3a4026982abf5fe24efc94</guid></item><item><title>Fires in Mudgegonga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/fires-in-mudgegonga/106315930</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cde1c51dd9a80e8ea72807af0e2ce7f5</guid></item><item><title>Lithium-ion battery fires prompt new waste collection program in North Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/lithium-ion-battery-fires-on-increase-waste-collection/106300480</link><description>Authorities say crews responded to 260 lithium-ion battery fires in Queensland last year. A new waste collection program in the state's north aims to prevent them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78470d7337ebbc93d592be39f2203e8b</guid></item><item><title>What is the AIN at the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics? Why Russian and Belarusian athletes are allowed to compete in Italy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/russia-belars-winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-ain/106306898</link><description>The Winter Olympics of Milano Cortina 2026 is another where Russian and Belarusian athletes will be largely absent, although there are a handful competing as individual neutral athletes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b156810fb69debab515ba1c4d4cfceb</guid></item><item><title>Trump endorses Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi ahead of Japan's election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/trump-endorses-japan-pm-takaichi-ahead-of-sunday-election/106317102</link><description>One of Sanae Takaichi's first engagements after she was elevated to prime minister in October was to host Donald Trump in Tokyo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f8f972cb70cce67dc98a1070d0a9d46</guid></item><item><title>Nine-year-old world record deadlift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/nine-year-old-world-record-deadlift/106314846</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd226f4275ac3be2fac8723c9d6c97b5</guid></item><item><title>Nine-year-old Jackson Mackay deadlifts into the record books</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/nine-year-old-jackson-mackay-deadlifting-world-record/106275110</link><description>In January, the Sunshine Coast boy claimed a world record with an 80-kilogram deadlift, beating the previous record of 72 kilograms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f184e4d0d1a8304ea96ede306853553</guid></item><item><title>Family from Netherlands calls for change after 27yo dies of suspected heatstroke in remote WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/tiffani-phelps-de-wildt-suspected-heat-death-remote-australia/106301164</link><description>Tiffani Phelps de Wildt died after collapsing on a remote station in WA's north. Her family says, had they known the risks, they would have tried to stop her from going out in the heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0267267dea2a216fb1a6ff830706a4a</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 opening ceremony quick hits: Mariah Carey and Valentino Rossi ignite an historic evening as Snoop Dogg makes an appearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/winter-olympics-2026-opening-ceremony-quick-hits/106308482</link><description>Athletes parade across Italy, Mariah Carey ignites a historic evening, and 'Coach Snoop' makes an appearance at the curling. Here are the quick hits from the Milano Cortina Winter Olympics opening ceremony.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f58563c217d154493971876cd3e5b89</guid></item><item><title>A 2026 Winter Olympics opening ceremony message of harmony and peace, rammed into a world of division</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/winter-olympics-2026-opening-ceremony-chilly-global-outlook/106316092</link><description>As the Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics Opening ceremony pleads a message of peace, the world outside the Olympic bubble burns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55c5f67fe73425a4675fe57a1c27a807</guid></item><item><title>Why 13yo Austin Appelbee's story of survival resonated so strongly across the globe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/austin-appelbee-quindalup-rescue-global-phenomenon/106306482</link><description>The remarkable story of Austin Appelbee's marathon swim for help went around the world, so why did it spark such an emotional reaction?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df0506ffba50ac7075d62dfa75270cd6</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Mitchell tracker map: When will it hit Pilbara coast in WA?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/cyclone-mitchell-map-tracker-pilbara-wa/106317220</link><description>Track the path of Tropical Cyclone Mitchell and monitor wind speeds as the system approaches the Pilbara coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16f9cd90b76f66e898eb6bb581e1cd7c</guid></item><item><title>Living School's innovative learning model prompts Victorian family to move to Lismore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/lismore-living-school-innovative-approach-to-education/106272794</link><description>A family from Torquay, Victoria, was so impressed by a school's progressive approach that they relocated to Lismore, 1,500 kilometres away in New South Wales, to enrol their children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ad3e533a9f1b89e55a6ce959ac2c6e2</guid></item><item><title>Woman was asleep when car crashed into house in Perth suburb of Rivervale, killing her</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/woman-dies-after-car-crashes-into-house-in-rivervale/106317240</link><description>A woman who had been in Perth to visit family was asleep when a car crashed into an inner-city home, killing her, late on Friday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">836a35326bd5475141d0ed2e13946e33</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 1, Saturday, February 7</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-day-one/106287722</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46c776b730057ca497c0c6b947cce9df</guid></item><item><title>Fifth-generation Gunnedah butcher retires, ending 150-year Etheridge family legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/fifth-generation-butcher-ends-150-year-etheridge-family-legacy/106307698</link><description>Gunnedah butcher Bernard Etheridge has hung up the knives, marking the end of an era for the Etheridge family, which has worked in the meat industry for more than 150 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">520b66345908f8f5c1227f9957ae63a8</guid></item><item><title>Accused militant in deadly 2012 Benghazi attack on US compound taken into custody in United States</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/libyan-zubayar-al-bakoush-arrested-extradited-america/106317146</link><description>Zubayar Al-Bakoush, 58, has been wanted by the United States for more than a decade for his alleged role in the attack, which killed four Americans, including the US ambassador to Libya.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da4c915a8eb2989c66aa09d8ca9da2bc</guid></item><item><title>Police given additional powers as NSW premier calls for calm during Israeli presidential visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/chris-minns-calls-for-calm-president-herzog-visit/106317374</link><description>NSW Premier Chris Minns has told demonstrators planning to protest Israel President Isaac Herzog's visit to Sydney that there should be "no clashes or violence".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b38f18d294a6f2e1ed544f65fa82f9a</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's rare backdown on racist Obama post shows even the 'Teflon president' has limits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/donald-trump-backdown-over-racist-obama-post-analysis/106317296</link><description>Donald Trump has, until now, thrived in controversy. But the US president has now done something that a year ago would have been unthinkable: deleted a social media post.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1854b7e1faef6f3ef56a208033608fc</guid></item><item><title>The Mark of Cain lead singer on a lifetime masking the truth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/the-mark-of-cain-lead-singer-josie-scott-transgender/106315830</link><description>The lead singer of legendary Adelaide rockers The Mark of Cain this week announced she was transgender, but it comes after nearly 60 years of hiding the truth from everyone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f38fc9591c45b6185b51090540bed25</guid></item><item><title>US prosecutors seek 46-month sentence for conspiracy theorist linked to Wieambilla killers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/wieambilla-shooting-daniel-day-sentencing/106317202</link><description>US prosecutors are seeking a sentence of almost four years for a conspiracy theorist linked to the trio behind the Wieambilla shooting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecaaafab7f7a654e969eb656226771fd</guid></item><item><title>Pregnant women in WA's Kimberley face big distances to hospital and high rates of heart condition, diabetes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/pregnant-women-kimberley-high-rates-heart-condition-and-diabetes/105995596</link><description>Pregnant women in WA's Kimberley experience high rates of preventable health conditions, hours of travel to receive basic care and limited support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a989455c0a62c3be3f08588519da209</guid></item><item><title>Thailand election stakes are high as progressives mount new challenge against establishment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/thailand-election-stakes-high-as-progressives-mount-challenge/106312802</link><description>As Thailand prepares to head to the polls, voters remain wary that in their version of democracy, the party they vote for is not always the one that takes power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0569a9a2b0e10f4a080427f63b37d5b2</guid></item><item><title>What you need to know about skiing in Japan and how to keep yourself safe on the slopes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/how-to-keep-safe-skiing-and-snowboarding-in-japan/106310604</link><description>Australians flock to Japan each year to take advantage of its unique and plentiful snow, but it's not just the travel costs that are mounting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17215f0a9c755ba21ee9e86b1e92d22c</guid></item><item><title>Collectors snap up Royal Australian Mint's Queen Elizabeth II coins, despite criticism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/queen-elizabeth-ii-commemorative-coins-royal-australian-mint/106317232</link><description>The portrait of Queen Elizabeth on two coins released by the Royal Australian Mint has drawn criticism, despite proving popular with collectors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc74caa9fdd653a711ef645f3b3a0056</guid></item><item><title>Luigi Mangione speaks out against prospect of back-to-back trials over Brian Thompson's killing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/luigi-mangione-speaks-out-against-dual-state-and-federal-trials/106317270</link><description>Accused killer has spoken out in court against the prospect of back-to-back trials over the shooting of UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson, telling a judge "it's the same trial twice".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">390fec098a01b2229cd8a97c02e0ad2d</guid></item><item><title>Report finds two thirds of tip-offs about children in harm in NSW not investigated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/nsw-children-in-harm-tips-not-investigated-report-says/106317466</link><description>In one uninvestigated case a man was convicted of sexually abusing a minor a year after an uninvestigated report was made to the department.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e806c6bf8e8256cb88d3c5e711a111b6</guid></item><item><title>Mayor of flood-hit Daly region accuses governments of inaction over long-term planning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/nt-long-term-flood-planning-victoria-daly-river-mayor/106317292</link><description>The Northern Territory and federal governments are being accused of failing to plan long term to protect Indigenous communities in the Victoria Daly region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86a569a8f6ddd8608406b0f482e4a898</guid></item><item><title>Latest Epstein files documents reveal links to multiple monarchies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/epstein-files-rock-global-monarchies/106316380</link><description>The latest release of the so-called Epstein files has revealed the convicted child sex offender was in contact with members of — and people close to — monarchies across Europe and the Middle East.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96f0f632ab3802486dbc61abcadd585b</guid></item><item><title>What our teeth reveal about the growing gap between rich and poor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/teeth-reveal-growing-gap-rich-poor/106314470</link><description>Teeth are one of the most visible markers of poverty: structural circumstances that are individually borne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e2a46b225f27cf30eb053acaf6146e0</guid></item><item><title>Jewish leader condemns graffiti attack on Andrew Hastie's office in Mandurah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/police-investigate-graffiti-attack-on-andrew-hasties-office/106317500</link><description>Police are investigating a derogatory slur spray-painted on federal MP Andrew Hastie's electorate office in Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cddac1220b4982a6e1e99f41f0b1f5f2</guid></item><item><title>Why Wests Tigers hopeful Pat Herbert jumped off an excavator and into an NRL pre-season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/pat-herbert-nrl-wests-tigers-train-and-trial/106317620</link><description>After three years away from first grade, Pat Herbert was ready to get on with the rest of his life but a call from Wests Tigers got him off the job site and into an NRL pre-season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">916a7b8e20ff292d6a9e4fe1704fad62</guid></item><item><title>Colorado funeral home owner sentenced over nearly 200 counts of corpse abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/colorado-funeral-home-owner-sentenced-over-corpse-abuse/106317582</link><description>A funeral home owner who stashed 189 decomposing bodies in a building over four years and gave grieving families fake ashes has been sentenced to 40 years in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1ed1d9518b6ba4db182caf8b5e83261</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of Queensland kids 'put at risk' after IT system failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/queensland-child-safety-system-report/106317554</link><description>Queensland's child safety minister says she was not briefed about issues with a botched IT system that potentially put kids at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">593b17f4800c3de163a8a685c74b54e6</guid></item><item><title>Daly River to hit major flood level on Sunday night, damage to homes expected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/nt-daly-river-major-flood-update-damage-evacuation/106317688</link><description>Almost 300 people from Daly River have been evacuated to Darwin, with just a handful of residents staying behind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40c7391489924e4c95d3971aa7147bfc</guid></item><item><title>CCTV footage shows the moment the car crashed into a home in Rivervale.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/cctv-footage-of-car-crashing-into-rivervale-home/106317792</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3356569a7be7e5189e8097956030c1e</guid></item><item><title>Karratha residents warned to prepare for 200km/h winds as Tropical Cyclone Mitchell intensifies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/tropical-cyclone-mitchell-karratha-pilbara-dangerous-winds/106317724</link><description>While avoiding a direct hit, Karratha is still expected to feel the force of the category three cyclone as it tracks along the Pilbara coast tonight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcbcdfe98a2e5e0d8736fcde1ee1600a</guid></item><item><title>Live: Nightmare start for Gu after crash in opening run of slopestyle qualifiers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/winter-olympics-day-one-live-blog-updates-guseli/106317886</link><description>Two-time gold medallist Eileen Gu is in action in the women's slopestyle qualifiers before Valentino Guseli competes in the final round of the Big Air. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bcc9d97fc427e3a730c60850a929116</guid></item></channel></rss>