<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 10:26:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Darkwaves research allows scientists to measure impact of 'underwater blackouts' on marine life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/darkwaves-research-scientists-measure-impact-on-marine-life/106314712</link><description>For the first time a group of international scientists have measured the impact of what happens to marine life when the lights go out underwater.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70eaaa35d2df02cbcf1d34ac0e2a4c3b</guid></item><item><title>Backyard pods won't fix the housing crisis but they signal a shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/backyard-pods-wont-fix-the-housing-crisis/106314472</link><description>Australia's biggest hardware retailer has started selling tiny homes. Are backyard pods the answer to a national housing crisis?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dd2b8a3992ec554b10d8b236bba7c64</guid></item><item><title>Search ends for 'very loved' Gold Coast fisherman Ash Haigh after almost five days lost at sea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/search-ends-loved-gold-coast-fisherman-ash-haigh/106321162</link><description>Queensland Police has suspended the cross-border search for missing Gold Coast fisherman Ash Haigh after an extensive air and sea operation found no signs of life, with his sister describing him as a "very loved" family man.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b728597ddaf78153709b4ea9a825a3a8</guid></item><item><title>Iran sentences Nobel Peace Prize winner Narges Mohammadi to six more years in prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/nobel-peace-laureate-narges-mohammadi-sentenced-iran/106314130</link><description>Women's rights activist Narges Mohammadi is sentenced to a further six years in jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a361ee5a20a3e359c2b25fbca523621</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 3, Monday, February 9</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-holly-harris-jason-chan/106307460</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b8f3992831865843a3ea28399b9cf1f</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Lindsey Vonn hailed as 'idol' by downhill rivals after Milano Cortina crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/winter-olympics-rivals-pay-credit-to-lindsey-vonn/106320254</link><description>Lindsey Vonn's 2026 Winter Olympic Games ended in disaster, but her teammates and rivals have heaped praise on the three-time Olympic medallist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d1e30943c1086fc7cce481c2af84273</guid></item><item><title>Jon Kudelka, Walkley-winning Tasmanian cartoonist, dies from brain cancer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/jon-kudelka-tasmanian-cartoonist-dies/106321714</link><description>Award-winning Tasmanian cartoonist Jon Kudelka dies after being diagnosed with brain cancer in 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b64794da6dd1ff79a97006ebfd7d1f1b</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong media mogul Jimmy Lai sentenced to 20 years in landmark case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/hong-kong-media-mogul-jimmy-lai-sentenced-to-20-years-jail/106321070</link><description>Jimmy Lai, one of Hong Kong's most outspoken critics of China, has learned his fate after being sentenced this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03525059e67690dbcf8a35c0db81456f</guid></item><item><title>Independent inquiry launched into NACC chief's handling of defence ties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/independent-inquiry-launched-into-nacc-chief-defence-ties/106320954</link><description>The body responsible for holding the federal integrity watchdog to account will formally investigate it for agency maladministration and its chief, Paul Brereton, for officer misconduct.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9eb72c36c774cffcae6b73bcb70d699</guid></item><item><title>Rain brings relief and road closures after record heatwave in South Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/rain-brings-relief-and-road-closures-in-outback-sa/106321082</link><description>High rainfall in north-eastern South Australia brings some relief for pastoralists after record-breaking heat, with a reprieve expected for metropolitan Adelaide this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8abb8433aa6e8a46aaa308bd29d9653</guid></item><item><title>Five simple, tasty vegetarian recipes that are perfect for meat-free Mondays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/five-simple-tasty-vegetarian-recipes-for-meat-free-monday/106309846</link><description>Looking to add some more vegetarian dishes to your weekly rotation? We have you covered with these five recipes that are perfect for meat-free Mondays.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8ccc6ae83e7b914cda93001f414be5d</guid></item><item><title>SpaceX to build 'self-growing city' on Moon, Elon Musk says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/spacex-building-lunar-self-gowing-city-moon-elon-musk/106322472</link><description>Billionaire chief executive says the company will shift its focus from Mars and the project could be achieved within 10 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60090cd3e2417da1cd2217d495e8de23</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos captain Adam Reynolds announces retirement at end of NRL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/brisbane-broncos-captain-adam-reynolds-announces-nrl-retirement/106322932</link><description>Adam Reynolds will finish his stellar career at the end of the season after fulfilling his Broncos mission to perfection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">169322d9299a44e0989b53593be68e74</guid></item><item><title>Families of Laos methanol poisoning victims say they've been left in the dark on investigations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/laos-methanol-poisoining-bianca-jones-holly-morton-bowles/106321336</link><description>The families of Bianca Jones and Holly Morton-Bowles say they have been left in the dark following the 2024 poisoning deaths of their daughters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2580145a0bf20f8945a54bc153c8c054</guid></item><item><title>Sanae Takaichi's stomping victory will have profound consequences for Australia and the Asia-Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/japanese-pm-sanae-takaichi-s-election-victory/106323082</link><description>A stomping victory by the ruling coalition government of Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi has opened the way for a major geo-strategic realignment in the Asia-Pacific region, with big implications for Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65ca2c9fe328e0e0981fb58f90e534b5</guid></item><item><title>ASIO was told about Bondi shooter's terrorist links years before attack, former spy claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/bondi-shooting-spy-claims-told-asio-terror-links-four-corners/106306092</link><description>The former undercover agent spied on the Akrams when he infiltrated a Sydney IS terror cell for Australia's intelligence agency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38e7d75b35ff2d3c4a5b6be5b9bb9d73</guid></item><item><title>'Massive' Indonesian ghost barge washes up on tiny Torres Strait island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/mystery-indonesian-ghost-barge-washed-up-in-torres-strait/106323116</link><description>The barge drifted into Australian waters from Indonesia after breaking from its moorings during bad weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08b39ef063e5e2f00075ab3cf9dbea37</guid></item><item><title>Aussies Coady and Stalker miss the medals in big air final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/winter-olympics-day-two-live-blog-updates/106322542</link><description>Australian's Tess Coady and Mela Stalker miss the podium in the snowboard big air final, while Holly Harris and Jason Chan become the first Aussies in 12 years to represent the country in ice dancing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ab5c808eefcaa38bad83f2aee6e5fb7</guid></item><item><title>Coalition reunited again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/coalition-reunited-again/106323374</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62e222383403c789b07fc80e8fe99a11</guid></item><item><title>William and Kate 'deeply concerned' about Epstein files as Andrew faces fresh scrutiny</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/prince-william-kate-epstein-deeply-concerned-statement/106323984</link><description>The Prince and Princess of Wales say their thoughts remain focused on the victims of the late sex offender Jeffrey Epstein, in their first statement on the issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d612c2a641317f685b27655f77ed980a</guid></item><item><title>Queensland health minister orders review of Toowoomba Hospital maternity unit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/toowoomba-hospital-maternity-unit-audit/106323798</link><description>Announcement comes after a woman reveals her support person was prevented from entering the birth suite while she was in labour by Toowoomba Hospital security.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99b063ed21a492a5f313bd8e1046e624</guid></item><item><title>Maritime safety regulator investigating Carnival cruise ship after whistleblower concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/amsa-investigating-carnival-cruise-ship-exploitation-claims/106323754</link><description>The maritime union says crew members of a major Carnival cruise ship allege they are being made to sleep in crowded rooms, lack access to safe free drinking water, and that some are earning as little as $2.50 an hour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aac8562047e40499a73214ddcb3bb039</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Tropical Cyclone Mitchell expected to batter the Gascoyne region as it moves inland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/tropical-cyclone-mitchell-has-crossed-the-wa-north-west-coast/106322566</link><description>The system is expected to bring strong winds and heavy rain as it moves inland through the Gascoyne region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16fcc5ddef3af39a7f8a479648d4aaa0</guid></item><item><title>Scottish Labour leader calls for UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer to quit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/scottish-labour-leader-calls-for-starmer-to-resign/106324396</link><description>Keir Starmer is facing calls to resign after damaging revelations about the man he picked to represent the UK in Washington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e65648acd6fbd0990a4a439c0fd4709</guid></item><item><title>US seizes tanker in Indian Ocean that fled Caribbean blockade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/us-seizes-tanker-in-indian-ocean-that-fled-caribbean-blockade/106324658</link><description>The Pentagon says the vessel was operating in breach of Donald Trump's orders on sanctioned ships in the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba8cb7c1e896319cb0ac6e5a847c3d01</guid></item><item><title>What happens when a medal is shared at the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/2026-winter-olympics-shared-silver-alpine-mens-team-combined/106324230</link><description>In the men's team combined Alpine skiing event at the 2026 Winter Olympics, the Swiss and Austrian teams tied for silver. So what happens to the bronze medal? And when there was a tie for bronze in the men's ski jumping, was there a spare bronze?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23ca44a0a4bf6ec3bbf545f329db23e6</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian cartoonist Jon Kudelka and the art of cutting through political spin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/jon-kudelka-tasmanian-cartoonist-illustrator-obituary/106322196</link><description>Hailed as an artist who "knew the power of comedy in holding truth to power", Jon Kudelka once described himself as "like a monkey with an automatic rifle".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57fe9e141789e47e0247d8471e7bb6b6</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos captain Adam Reynolds holds hope of Payne Haas contract backflip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/adam-reynolds-on-payne-haas-contract-broncos-rabbitohs/106324748</link><description>Brisbane prop Payne Haas is set to arrive in England for the World Club Challenge where his teammates will try to convince him not to honour his deal with South Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26ae11679cc83fdf4ab466c033c7a4f6</guid></item><item><title>More people say they'll vote One Nation. What are they voting for?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/one-nation-policy-platforms-pauline-hanson/106296838</link><description>One Nation questions if man-made climate change is real, wants to wind back access to abortion care and plans to pay the HECS debts of doctors working in the regions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed4bdf450e353d8bca00c742667777f</guid></item><item><title>Roblox on notice after 'disturbing' reports of child grooming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/government-puts-roblox-on-notice-reports-of-child-grooming/100020788</link><description>The government puts popular social gaming site Roblox on notice following media reports of children being approached and groomed by predators on the platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17bbfe956fe95675bddb65bf1b70eaed</guid></item><item><title>Painkillers and HRT therapies among drugs not being subsidised under PBS</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/everyday-medicines-not-funded-under-the-pbs/106209526</link><description>Painkillers, HRT therapies and incontinence medicines are among the drugs that will not benefit from the new maximum $25 script price.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0be6f797e20a595543aed32d3067fce7</guid></item><item><title>St Kilda star Max King injured again, Port ruckman Ivan Soldo out for season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/st-kilda-star-max-king-injured-again-port-ruckman-season-over/106324794</link><description>Max King has suffered another injury, further frustrating the St Kilda key forward's bid for an AFL return.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43a7cb7b674656d6ef9e220abeeb6274</guid></item><item><title>Cheryl Grimmer's family fights for new charges against suspect</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/cheryl-grimmer-nsw-parliament-debate-jeremy-buckingham/106321818</link><description>NSW Parliament will again debate the 1970 disappearance of toddler Cheryl Grimmer, following claims her family's pleas for fresh charges against a suspect who confessed to murdering her when he was a teenager have been ignored.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a621721b38ed6d61fcdd406868faa2a</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan reverses cricket T20 World Cup boycott and will face India in Sri Lanka</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/pakistan-reverses-world-cup-boycott-to-face-india-t20-world-cup/106324864</link><description>Pakistan has ‍agreed to play India ​in the ⁠T20 World Cup match scheduled to take ‌place in Colombo this ‍Sunday, February 15.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d7762f897f18cee09e2bbfe5253973e</guid></item><item><title>Former ATSIC head Geoff Clark was jailed but his community says legal issues persist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/framlingham-aboriginal-trust-shares-court-fallout-geoff-clark/106305592</link><description>Former ATSIC leader Geoff Clark was jailed in 2024, yet some members of his community say legal issues linger on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec0abba8310f5f8dfa22011b1c737b70</guid></item><item><title>Native title holders take appeal over one of Australia's largest groundwater licences to High Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nt-high-court-singleton-station-aboriginal-groundwater-rights/106322626</link><description>The cultural value of water will be front and centre in the High Court in Canberra today as a group of native title holders from Central Australia fight to assert cultural rights over an aquifer under their lands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d334f651d8d34fed9db2b05f2f04adba</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor faces pressure to challenge for Liberal leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/angus-taylor-pressure-to-challenge-for-liberal-leadership/106324000</link><description>Liberal leadership aspirant Angus Taylor is facing pressure from conservative supporters to challenge Sussan Ley this week and end the damaging speculation paralysing the party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d731de86ca9190f9aeabd2e20ffd4bc0</guid></item><item><title>Ghislaine Maxwell will only talk if Donald Trump grants clemency, lawyer says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/ghislaine-maxwell-will-only-talk-if-trump-grants-clemency/106324720</link><description>The jailed accomplice of sex predator Jeffrey Epstein refuses to answer questions for the US Congress — but her lawyer says she will cooperate if granted clemency by the president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">204920be92b87248239c7364a66b65c0</guid></item><item><title>Margot Robbie and Jacob Elordi sizzle, but Wuthering Heights isn't quite the full Brontë</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/wuthering-heights-movie-review-emerald-fennell-jacob-elordi/106321718</link><description>The two Queensland "bogans" put on a show, but Emerald Fennell's Wuthering Heights is more wish fulfilment than a meaningful adaptation of the classic novel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41b2ef0ef990ef2113fe88e9541e3117</guid></item><item><title>States urged to sign National Water Agreement even though users unaware what's in final version</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/waters-users-in-dark-on-water-policy-ready-for-signing/106314610</link><description>As the country's state governments and territories consider signing a new national water policy that seeks to address climate change and elevate First Nations knowledge, the agricultural industry fears it has been overlooked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f8c01ea5477b908bab868e3c766d92b</guid></item><item><title>Swifts Creek faces tough task of reinventing itself amid job losses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/swifts-creek-future-as-logging-industry-closes/105904130</link><description>Job losses mean Swifts Creek in Victoria's High Country is facing an identity crisis, but it is not the only small town undergoing a transformation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1780877bb9a821ea5202114aac7047b9</guid></item><item><title>Jake and Chris Waterman relishing prospect of AFL Origin as Perth prepares for Victorian invasion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/jake-waterman-chris-waterman-relishing-state-of-origin/106323028</link><description>WA's last State of Origin captain Chris Waterman is relishing the prospect of the concept's reboot — and can't wait to see his son Jake donning the famous black swan for the clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4e7c9262ce711480d0a666d35fb1e5a</guid></item><item><title>Turtles discovered in Dumaresq Dam could be dumped pets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/turtles-discovered-in-dumaresq-dam-could-be-dumped-pets/106304016</link><description>The unexpected discovery of four turtle species in a dam near Armidale has left researchers wondering if people have been dumping unwanted pets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3644822f63b6c74afb1a388ba0882f6d</guid></item><item><title>Savannah Guthrie makes latest video plea as missing mother's ransom deadline nears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/savannah-guthrie-makes-new-video-plea-over-missing-mother/106325066</link><description>US TV host Savannah Guthrie says her family is at its "hour of desperation" in the search for their kidnapped mother, but makes no mention of a possible ransom in a new video.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d7b80629fdda5092a47af99f45d7a10</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce taps into rural anger as One Nation eyes Coalition seats at the Victorian election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/barnaby-joyce-one-nation-eyeing-victorian-election-seats/106322072</link><description>The right-wing party's prized recruit, Barnaby Joyce, made a key appearance deep in National Party territory as the 2026 Victorian election campaign began to take shape, Richard Willingham writes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a46ca39f0081cb28359ae1fd139fc030</guid></item><item><title>Catherine O'Hara's cause of death revealed as pulmonary embolism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/catherine-ohara-cause-of-death-announced/106324996</link><description>Award-winning actress Catherine O'Hara died from a pulmonary embolism, according to her death certificate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0db2f6d1caf958e134132f56ca8ef189</guid></item><item><title>Lindsey Vonn set for multiple surgeries but denies torn ACL contributed to Winter Olympic crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/lindsey-vonn-tibia-fracture-multiple-surgeries-winter-olympics/106325232</link><description>American ski great Lindsey Vonn will "require multiple surgeries" after sustaining a tibia fracture, but denies that her previously ruptured ACL was the cause of the crash that ended her Winter Olympic Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ab4072a808dc472c68c186a6da6811b</guid></item><item><title>Border Force launches operation targeting illegal foreign fishing off Queensland coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/border-force-operation-targets-foreign-fishing-queensland-waters/106325290</link><description>Authorities announce a special effort to crack down on illegal foreign fishing boats after intercepting 10 boats in Queensland waters since New Year's Day alone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0edfcd2f222c855ac4118702da6f9305</guid></item><item><title>AI-generated social media posts like a 'snake eating its own tail'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/ai-generated-text-predictive-models-formulaic-social-media/106313944</link><description>The age of AI is here and it's going to be infinitely useful, or so they tell us, unless you're the kind of person who, like me, finds computer-generated stories infinitely boring and an insult to humanity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aec83881dfd13d38b83dd462a4442ff3</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Milano Cortina organisers looking into broken medals after at least four incidents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/winter-olympics-medals-breaking-breezy-johnson-alysa-liu/106325112</link><description>Records are meant to be broken at the Olympics, but in the Milano Cortina Games, it is the medals being dismantled, and organisers are giving it "maximum attention".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da0eeb85cc783bf52dfeec17d907e78e</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach terrorist Sajid Akram voiced support for Islamic State in 2019, former ASIO agent says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/sajid-akram-voiced-support-for-islamic-state-in-2019-ex-spy-says/106321482</link><description>Bondi Beach terrorist Sajid Akram voiced support for the Islamic State group (IS) in 2019 and expressed admiration for a leading Al Qaeda propagandist, according to accounts from two men who moved in the same extremist circles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20f66d766145bf26694aec7669da86aa</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill artist exhibits in Japan after brush with J-pop star Fujii Kaze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/broken-hill-artist-exhibits-in-japan-fujii-kaze-jpop-star/106304746</link><description>When Broken Hill artist Jason McCarthur started receiving emails from Japan about his tote bags, he assumed they were a scam. But pretty soon he had sold out of the bags and it was all thanks to a J-pop star.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c060dce5346c409f34f513e185619ab</guid></item><item><title>International condemnation of new Israeli settlement measures in West Bank grows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/israeli-west-bank-settlement-draws-growing-global-condemnation/106325522</link><description>The United Nations says it is "gravely concerned" over Israeli plans to expand control over the occupied West Bank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">824876180d95cd859030497885dc8632</guid></item><item><title>Licensed program to kill native animals 'weak' and 'outdated' inquiry told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/licences-to-harm-native-animals-inquiry/106320826</link><description>Animal welfare groups are calling for a major overhaul into the system that allows native animals to be killed in NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93d7971e8816215b902c8e022b64e384</guid></item><item><title>NT Child Deaths Review Committee disbanded by government, with concerns it will result in 'serious gaps'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nt-child-deaths-review-committee-disbanded-concerns-serious-gaps/106322560</link><description>The NT Children's Commissioner says the government's decision to scrap a committee tasked with examining all child deaths in the territory leaves "serious gaps".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9b79e206e5a5199f96cc3bb170adf48</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Steven Bradbury clips Jake Paul as Ukrainian pays tribute — quick hits from Milano Cortina day three</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/sport-winter-olympics-qhs-day-three-jake-paul-steven-bradbury/106324398</link><description>Steven Bradbury hits Jake Paul with a drive-by as he celebrates Jutta Leerdam's Olympic gold, while a Sydney-born Kiwi receives a special celebration. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53c571d98ef2321e4d2f32391d047131</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 4, Tuesday, February 10</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-day-4matt-graham-jakara-anthony/106320694</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c39e879c6be4500d56c80aa209f85717</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast's Mona Wiggins celebrates 105th birthday with game of lawn bowls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/gold-coast-mona-wiggins-105-birthday-lawn-bowls/106325762</link><description>Mona Wiggins is showing no signs of slowing down, celebrating her 105th birthday on the bowling green.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f61dc1821573e2ccc4bbc1023166301b</guid></item><item><title>Ghislaine Maxwell was complicit in Jeffrey Epstein's abuse. Now she's pushing for clemency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/ghislaine-maxwell-fed-jeffrey-epstein-abuse-what-happens-now/105610704</link><description>Powerful socialite Ghislaine Maxwell was able to exploit her connections to recruit, groom, and abuse dozens of young girls. Now, she faces a fresh interrogation over her role in Jeffrey Epstein's abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f26e0500fb7cb1b47ab1e939f24d5ab5</guid></item><item><title>Christchurch attacker was pleased when terrorism charge laid, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/christchurch-attacker-was-pleased-when-terrorism-charge-laid/106325142</link><description>A former lawyer for the Australian who murdered 51 people at two New Zealand mosques in 2019 tells a court the shooter "never wanted to defend the terrorism charge".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8d58eeddf70df9910f81aedefca5bb4</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth asks to meet Roblox following reports of child grooming. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/commonwealth-roblox-reports-of-child-grooming/106323242</link><description>Roblox has been called to an urgent meeting with the federal government in the wake of reports that children are being groomed by predators and exposed to sexually explicit material on the popular online gaming platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8186dce135dbe17f29c38ae0b2e5a4fb</guid></item><item><title>Huon Aquaculture confirms antibiotic use in salmon hatchery on River Derwent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/huon-aquaculture-confirms-antibiotic-use-river-derwent-hatchery/106326652</link><description>There are calls for the public to be made aware of antibiotic use in Tasmania's freshwater hatcheries after Huon Aquaculture recently used oxytetracycline to treat diseased salmon without informing downstream users.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d273d5a7b3627b72a6e5120520d92c4a</guid></item><item><title>Exploitation claims have been levelled against cruise ship company Carnival. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/carnival-cruise-exploitation-claims-what-we-know/106325788</link><description>A major cruise ship has been investigated by the maritime safety regulator for claims around poor working conditions. A spokesperson for The Carnival Cruise Line says it has "nothing to hide" and welcomes AMSA's oversight. Here's what we know so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fb766396c9c7d4da6c405ce6634ae51</guid></item><item><title>Baldivis man Jason William Forbes jailed for planning to abduct and abuse child after buying child sex dolls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/perth-man-jailed-over-planned-child-abduction-and-abuse/106326902</link><description>A Perth man who planned to abduct and abuse a child, having scoped out schools and childcare centres and researched restraint methods, is jailed for seven years. Warning: This story contains details that some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">708aa361649907ffe5a33163651eb958</guid></item><item><title>Sydney man avoids jail over 'abhorrent' social media posts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nsw-man-avoids-jail-over-threatening-pm-via-social-media-posts/106326690</link><description>A Sydney man who made "abhorrent" social media posts that promoted sexual violence and threatened the prime minister has been spared time in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17d442d03f2268671f08f95e7ebe2047</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds rally against police response to night of violent protest clashes in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nine-charged-sydney-protest-isaac-herzog-protest/106326288</link><description>Hundreds of protesters have gathered outside a police station in Sydney to criticise the force's response to Monday night's rally against the visit of Israeli President Isaac Herzog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c07cd60e5cebc012e0adb7e616dc9f7f</guid></item><item><title>Mackay MP Nigel Dalton crosses the floor to oppose LNP ban on abortion debate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nigel-dalton-crosses-floor-opposing-lnp-abortion-debate-ban/106327032</link><description>First-term Liberal National Party MP Nigel Dalton votes to overturn a ban on debating abortion — in defiance of his party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c85acc349c94f7e5ef78c2f5a8611f2</guid></item><item><title>Chappell Roan no longer represented by talent agency led by Casey Wasserman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/chappell-roan-no-longer-represented-by-casey-wasserman/106327330</link><description>Pop star Chappell Roan says she is no longer represented by the talent agency led by Los Angeles 2028 Olympics chief Casey Wasserman, who has faced criticism for flirtatious email exchanges with convicted sex trafficker Ghislaine Maxwell more than 20 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfd514ef3d53768e08f6b605a9551524</guid></item><item><title>Grace Tame criticised for leading intifada chants at Sydney protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/grace-tame-criticised-for-sydney-protest-intifada-chant/106326896</link><description>Grace Tame accuses Australia of being "a so-called democracy" that punishes peaceful protesters, before chanting "from Gadigal to Gaza, globalise the intifada!"</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9dc912a9d76603ba103ace6885715f4</guid></item><item><title>Deadline looms for Warren Tredrea to pay Nine's legal costs after failed appeal against unfair dismissal case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/warren-treadrea-deadline-to-pay-legal-costs-to-nine/106326298</link><description>Former footballer Warren Tredrea has an imminent deadline to pay $149,000 to his former employer, Channel Nine, following a failed appeal against an unfair dismissal case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8204048fc3858d5ea8943a955cc6d4ba</guid></item><item><title>Tocumwal arrest over child abuse material.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/tocumwal-arrest-over-child-abuse-material/106325300</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46969e7cbc1d1f9b85ef170990e9cbe5</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after police allegedly find more than 125,000 files of child abuse material</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/child-abuse-material-police-tocumwal-gary-maude/106325362</link><description>A man appears in court after police officers seize a mobile and laptop with allegedly more than 125,000 files of child abuse material.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1937df9d2e4d8ae0dc9b5b60d38a4914</guid></item><item><title>At school, I was my brother's protector. But I needed more support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/support-i-wish-i-had-at-school-while-caring-for-my-brother/106279156</link><description>I was my brother's protector at school, but the education system could have done more to support us both.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8737a14dea75637ab0e525bab21121a9</guid></item><item><title>Trial begins after Geoffrey McLean allegedly murdered and dumped in wheelie bin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/trial-begins-over-alleged-murder-of-geoffrey-mclean/106325614</link><description>Four people, including the victim's former partner, are standing trial in relation to the alleged murder of 55-year-old man Geoffrey McLean, whose remains were found in a wheelie bin in Adelaide's north in 2022. Warning: This story contains details that some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afabcc989f003a7d62876568c6ff8027</guid></item><item><title>Global Athlete accuses IOC of 'kowtowing' to Russia by including AIN athletes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/russian-winter-olympic-athletes-milan-cortina/106327282</link><description>Advocacy group Global Athlete has accused the IOC of enabling Russia by allowing 13 Russian and seven Belarusian athletes to compete at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c9a39c00f74fc512b507557d2b1ac8f</guid></item><item><title>Craig Goodwin's World Cup hopes cop hammer blow after groin injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/craig-goodwin-s-world-cup-hopes-dashed/106327940</link><description>He was one of the Socceroos best in Qatar but now Craig Goodwin will need a minor miracle to make this year's World Cup after the veteran suffered a groin injury for Adelaide United that will sideline him for some time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">832f24e225d388d7831d181361338c99</guid></item><item><title>Dry conditions, heat and high winds combine for another day of high fire danger in Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/victoria-hot-weather-warning/106326392</link><description>Victoria's parched landscape has authorities concerned amid forecasts of another day of heat and gusty winds across the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5ee5fc4f0573fa9ad8061629a612008</guid></item><item><title>Neo-Nazi Thomas Sewell, 13 others face court over alleged Camp Sovereignty protest camp attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/thomas-sewell-neo-nazi-camp-sovereignty-melbourne-court/106326988</link><description>Neo-Nazi leader Thomas Sewell was among more than a dozen people to face a Melbourne court on Tuesday over the alleged attack at Camp Sovereignty near the city's CBD last August.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">114f6696212096c3f23677ac83119e99</guid></item><item><title>Shark filmed in deep Antarctic waters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/shark-filmed-in-deep-antarctic-waters/106321640</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4eb3f0f8027a13b7cb77a572c9acacff</guid></item><item><title>Elvis Presley 'unguarded' in unseen footage used in new Baz Luhrmann film</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/elvis-presley-unguarded-in-unseen-footage-in-baz-luhrmann-film/106327408</link><description>When director Baz Luhrmann and his team uncovered hours of previously unseen Elvis Presley recordings, Luhrmann abandoned his original plans, deciding to "get out of the way" and let Presley tell his own story.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18a8befc1c6399e513d75719298bd33a</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man staged scene and lied to Triple Zero after murdering his partner, court documents reveal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/adam-britt-staged-murder-tiffany-spence-act-supreme-court/106327390</link><description>New details have emerged about the murder of Canberra woman Tiffany Spence, as court documents show her partner staged the scene before calling Triple Zero.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">160376561c043d82e2e0548892ecf6e5</guid></item><item><title>Tahmoor Coal placed into administration as court hears creditor winding-up bid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/tahmoor-coal-mine-placed-into-voluntary-administration/106326534</link><description>Tahmoor Coal has been placed into voluntary administration just as the Supreme Court was set to hear a creditor's winding-up application.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">953d7d3b73b007feb1525c6e38b10dea</guid></item><item><title>Ex-student tells court of pregnancy scare after alleged abuse by Hobart Matriculation College teacher</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/hobart-matriculation-college-former-student-gives-evidence-rape/106326618</link><description>When recounting the first time her former teacher allegedly raped her, the woman told the court he was "like a big monster" on top of her and she "could hardly breathe". The woman is suing both her former teacher and the State of Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffa175ff6b6b2b70b45b9744a5d361fb</guid></item><item><title>Raymond Reddington murder trial hears Sharon Fulton seemed scared in hours before 1986 disappearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/sharon-fulton-murder-trial-raymond-reddington-woman-was-scared/106327376</link><description>A close friend of a woman allegedly murdered by her husband in Perth 40 years ago tells a Perth court she seemed frightened in the hours before her disappearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78ffe88ad62d326c893e3ac20446550a</guid></item><item><title>Grandparents among those injured in Sydney protest against Israeli President Isaac Herzog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/sydney-protesters-injured-at-isaac-herzog-protest-speak-out/106327578</link><description>A Sydney grandmother says she suffered four broken vertebrae after being "violently" pushed to the ground while trying to leave a protest on Monday night. Warning: This story contains images some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60eb786629ff095fd9a4742e988eaefd</guid></item><item><title>Top barrister and charity boss Mark Philip Dennis dead after child abuse arrest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/barrister-mark-dennis-dead-child-abuse-arrest/106328484</link><description>The 60-year-old was found dead at his Leichhardt unit in Sydney's inner west on Monday evening, NSW Police said in a statement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89ae82097c264f14c6bb51a0c601ca54</guid></item><item><title>Cam Bolton fractures neck as training falls rule two Aussies out of Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/winter-olympics-2026-live-milano-cortina-moguls-ice-hockey/106326694</link><description>Australia's Cam Bolton and Misaki Vaughan are ruled out of the Games after training falls, while reigning Olympic gold medallist Jakara Anthony advances to the women's moguls final at the Milano Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf10d0c49b40e45eace54bd9ee12cefa</guid></item><item><title>Australian government puts pressure on Lao authorities over methanol poisoning deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/methanol-poisoning-holly-bowles-bianca-morton-jones-laos/106328530</link><description>The Australian government calls in the Lao ambassador in Canberra, amid criticism of the country's response to a fatal methanol poisoning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc5e186c3bcd06980d9bd00b9b489bd6</guid></item><item><title>Former NT police officer James Kirstenfeldt sentenced on drink driving, weapons offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nt-james-kirstenfeldt-sentenced-drink-driving-weapons-charges/106313314</link><description>A former Northern Territory police officer has been ordered to pay almost $5,000 in fines and undergo supervised treatment for post-traumatic stress disorder after drunkenly crashing his car outside his suburban Darwin home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94f3ae08a6978aeffd227f1b28acd709</guid></item><item><title>Police and protesters clash at Sydney rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/police-and-protesters-clash-at-sydney-rally/106328248</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f55f1c97776896a8ad1d17829bab966</guid></item><item><title>Queensland police commissioner Steve Gollschewski set to retire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/qld-police-commissioner-steve-gollschewski-to-retire/106328730</link><description>Queensland's top cop Steve Gollschewski is set to retire after almost 50 years in the service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed23f80208e7161490469778dd73a42a</guid></item><item><title>Health warnings about ultra-processed foods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/health-warnings-about-ultra-processed-foods/106328288</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52af8963f7db51a368846c06aa60a304</guid></item><item><title>Liberals plot resignations to pave way for leadership challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/liberals-plot-mass-resignation-to-force-leadership-spill-/106328762</link><description>Liberals are bracing for a wave of frontbench resignations as soon as Wednesday to pave the way for Angus Taylor to mount a leadership challenge against Sussan Ley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68227eb101c335608129c57bdf313d7f</guid></item><item><title>WA police investigate possible tobacco wars link to fire at Kelmscott store</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/fire-alleged-linked-to-illicit-tobacco-under-investigation/106325512</link><description>WA Police Commissioner Col Blanch confirms officers from Taskforce Maverick, which investigates crime linked to the illicit tobacco and vape trade, are involved with the investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c193a813072c7da9378b52e50d8e27c3</guid></item><item><title>Celine Cremer search in Arthur River finds more bones and missing backpacker's car key</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/car-key-teeth-found-search-celine-cremer-tasmania/106323260</link><description>Tasmania Police say a car key found in the Arthur River has been "formally verified" as belonging to missing backpacker Celine Cremer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f44f7b3c1d64c6fe98c04e84cabd033d</guid></item><item><title>Police warn against 'false hope' as cold case search bones identified as 'non‑human'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/bones-found-in-yatina-search-not-human/106325728</link><description>Bone fragments found during a private search for evidence relating to the disappearance of two girls in 1973 are "not human remains", according to police, who have issued a public warning against actions that create "false hope".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8578a06110098fdaac062e5d7e5de7e0</guid></item><item><title>Three key moments in police clashes with Sydney protesters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nsw-police-israel-herzog-protest-town-hall-key-moments/106325680</link><description>Competing narratives have emerged from NSW Police and protesters who were at Monday night's demonstration near Sydney's Town Hall. ABC NEWS Verify has gathered footage and spoken to witnesses in an early attempt to examine what happened in detail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55bfcaef3544b431846d0937470d213b</guid></item><item><title>Protesters enter metro station as police converge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/protesters-enter-metro-station-as-police-converge/106327676</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45be7455dd1b8a414a8426333e0823b0</guid></item><item><title>Waterfalls on Uluru, Daly River flooding peaks as rain soaks Central Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nt-weather-rainfall-uluru-daly-river-flooding/106326436</link><description>Heavy rain in Central Australia has sent water cascading down the face of Uluru and filled the usually parched Todd River, while cutting off a number of remote communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">154698806a27d58e8b258474e05ea7dd</guid></item><item><title>Bulk-billing rates rebound on back of government's multi-billion-dollar policy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/bulk-billing-rates-rebound-after-multi-billion-dollar-investment/106327456</link><description>Bulk-billing rates have rebounded in the first clear measure of the impact of the government's multi-billion-dollar pledge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d77c00d7ce459a8883fdcf39108f49f</guid></item><item><title>Rental affordability hits record low as rents rise 2.5 times faster than wages, analysis shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/rental-affordability-rents-rise-faster-than-wages-cotality/106327364</link><description>Tenants now pay an average of 33.4 per cent of their pre-tax income on rent, which is the highest level on record, according to a property research firm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6fc06f379d9dabc4c56af45e59d226cc</guid></item><item><title>The desperate toll of Australia's 2026 Winter Olympic Games injury chaos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/australian-injury-hell-at-2026-winter-olympic-games/106329260</link><description>Games-ending injuries to Cam Bolton and Misaki Vaughan have emphasised the dangers of winter sport as the Australian team copes with issues early in the Milano Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f1a5314017e313b221ef7737afe9b23</guid></item><item><title>Israel tightens grip over West Bank while Herzog visits Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/isaac-herzog-visit-protest-police-west-bank-annexation/106325902</link><description>While Israeli President Isaac Herzog visited Sydney, his government was taking concrete actions in the West Bank designed to "continue to kill the idea of a Palestinian state".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">728001663fca5f0a0371d55a7b3d1249</guid></item><item><title>FBI releases surveillance pictures of masked man at Nancy Guthrie's home on morning she disappeared</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/fbi-release-pictures-of-masked-man-at-nancy-guthries-home/106329322</link><description>FBI director Kash Patel has posted the images on social media, saying they had been recovered after days of work by investigators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">728b1ecdd6098f978fa86fe8a55eede2</guid></item><item><title>Protesters were punched, pushed, and arrested but were NSW Police actions excessive?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/verify-police-use-of-force-town-hall-protest/106328358</link><description>What is reasonable? It's a question being asked by some after footage of clashes in Sydney's CBD, during a rally against Israeli President Isaac Herzog's visit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc032833c827cf116d697c6b10faca22</guid></item><item><title>The Epstein files are shaking Britain, but Donald Trump could still have 3 million reasons to worry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/epstein-files-shake-uk-but-white-house-could-still-be-worried/106324788</link><description>Donald Trump's enemies made no secret of their hopes the documents would contain something explosive enough to bring the president down, but right now the Epstein spotlight is on Britain's politicians and palaces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd62bb34a29f437c14df3ee1992e6c76</guid></item><item><title>Uber quietly agrees to external review after woman sues over guide dog refusals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/uber-agrees-to-review-after-guide-dog-refusal-case/106307858</link><description>Uber quietly agrees to an external review of its Australian operations after settling a Federal Court case brought by a woman refused more than 30 rides while travelling with a guide dog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7dae27423705f7913b0c26f0c1f43a5</guid></item><item><title>Iran's rulers face 'defections and disobedience', but will it be enough to topple the regime?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/amid-us-iran-nuclear-talks-will-defections-spark-regime-change/106323120</link><description>As talks between Washington and Tehran over a nuclear deal continue, fractures within the regime are starting to emerge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec8f5a39abe057d153a273869091cc1d</guid></item><item><title>Jakara Anthony picture perfect, Matt Graham with room to improve at 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games moguls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/jakara-anthony-matt-graham-pressure-moguls-qualifiers/106324214</link><description>Jakara Anthony will do anything aside from thinking about moguls skiing after qualifying number one for Wednesday's 2026 Winter Olympics final, taking to Lego, a puzzle and Grey's Anatomy instead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c5b1f5d3da4862fb201d76474dc2318</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberals face wipeout not seen since state bank election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/sa-liberals-face-wipeout-not-seen-since-state-bank-election/106325582</link><description>Labor faced a humiliating election loss following the state bank collapse in the early 90s. Now, recent polling shows a collapse of another kind could be brewing for the Liberal Party with One Nation hot on its heels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d37b7dfeb9d62359f82edf2221b3e29</guid></item><item><title>How 'capacity constraints' are linked to inflation and your hip pocket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/what-are-capacity-constraints-economic-growth-inflation-rba/106322390</link><description>It may sound boring, but "capacity constraints" are to blame for your higher mortgage repayments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">945ab804992cc48ca6c41e4f4a2a3d57</guid></item><item><title>Food ministers move closer to mandating Health Star Ratings on packaged food</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/move-to-mandate-health-star-ratings-on-food-and-drink/106231700</link><description>The nation's food ministers will this week take a crucial step towards mandating the Health Star Rating scheme on packaged food products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d49aa89b821cfcbaa27037bef0288134</guid></item><item><title>How to reduce loneliness while working remotely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/how-to-reduce-loneliness-while-working-remotely/106286338</link><description>Working remotely can be a lonely experience. Here's what you can do about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07ee38b05fb1af72edee6be374ac35ed</guid></item><item><title>Hume City Council wants action over thousands of tyres dumped in Melbourne's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/illegal-tyre-dumping-and-hume-council-action/106328912</link><description>A council in Melbourne's north wants the federal government to establish a free tyre recycling scheme to stop thousands of tyres being dumped, causing a potential environmental hazard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1abf383c1d01a41e7eb877b26adf62af</guid></item><item><title>Travel quiz, February 11: Which Spanish city hosts a tomato-throwing festival?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/travel-quiz/106251040</link><description>Which European country has no McDonald's? And where's Australia's most western point?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47821408bf3d55cc98b44a62c5659000</guid></item><item><title>Buoyed by global culture juggernauts, the Australian K-pop community has 'exploded' in popularity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/kpop-community-grows-thanks-to-bts-demon-hunters/106325884</link><description>Members of the Australian K-pop community say pop acts and blockbuster films are contributing to the local scene "soaring".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d04497a71176e54746c0307a2d07bd48</guid></item><item><title>Cricket umpire numbers rise since COVID, but regions still in 'dire' need</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/victorian-cricket-umpires-referee-shortage/106313892</link><description>Cricket umpire numbers increase significantly in Victoria, but some regions remain in desperate need.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c25e208a1280b6ca42f95914eb0b617</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor resigns from Liberal frontbench ahead of expected leadership spill — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/federal-politics-estimates-albanese-ley-herzog/106328310</link><description>Angus Taylor has resigned from the shadow frontbench ahead of an expected Liberal leadership spill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9652a4c3a8e2cd737e83d0b30398df6</guid></item><item><title>Australian T20 World Cup squad looks different but do not count it out, Mitch Marsh says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/injury-hit-australia-open-t20-world-cup-campaign-against-ireland/106329438</link><description>Despite a slew of key injuries leaving the Australian team unrecognisable, captain Mitch Marsh is confident about the experience left in the side.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e7e79b7afbfde0a033b919098cc0b12</guid></item><item><title>Limestone Coast hospital's staff shortage in spotlight after former administrator's fall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/limestone-coast-hospital-staff-shortage/106318896</link><description>David Walshaw spent 20 years looking after the Limestone Coast's hospitals, but a fall made him realise the system was failing patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63b01408b05a077885b47352dd28bbdc</guid></item><item><title>ASX 200 rallies as CBA surges, Aussie dollar above 71 US cents — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/asx-markets-business-live-news-february-11/106322798</link><description>The Australian share market has finished strongly after the first "big day" of reporting season with good earnings news for the Commonwealth Bank for the first half of the financial year. Look back on our live blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81edd0aee0be4606cfe44b95d5c351fb</guid></item><item><title>Surgeon Kelvin Kong's life growing up Chinese and Indigenous in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/kelvin-kong-s-growing-up-chinese-and-indigenous-australia/106326388</link><description>Australia's first identified First Nations surgeon, Dr Kelvin Kong spoke about his Malaysian Chinese heritage during the annual Wang Gungwu lecture at Parliament House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3366e9b48200b228bb48ce12f315720</guid></item><item><title>Citizen scientists work on 100-million-year-old ichthyosaur fossil in Winton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/ichthyosaur-winton-australian-age-of-dinosaurs-fossil/106310754</link><description>Participants from across Australia and the world travelled to outback Queensland to clean up the near-complete ichthyosaur fossil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af8a6ea34ab1f32371b167c057d77dd9</guid></item><item><title>Images of alleged tobacco wars kingpin Kazem Hamad released in Iraq</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/images-of-kazem-hamad-released-by-afp/106329460</link><description>Hamad was deported from Australia in 2023 and has been a key person of interest relating to firebombings at Victorian tobacco shops and businesses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e824b5d9e2cfb1c10502ba2cb1ccb7d</guid></item><item><title>US immigration bosses questioned over Donald Trump's ICE crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/ice-customs-border-patrol-heads-questioned-by-congress/106329244</link><description>Democrats level a litany of complaints against the heads of America's immigration agencies during a rare hearing in Washington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e5254a2eb076a02d850dc833ae45c0c</guid></item><item><title>Trump told police chief 'everyone' knew about Epstein, FBI document says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/trump-commerce-chief-claims-no-relationship-with-epstein/106329468</link><description>Donald Trump allegedly told police in 2006 that people in New York knew about Epstein, a newly uncovered FBI interview shows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3c205dcd4860dd580cc592880560660</guid></item><item><title>Five-year-old girl killed in ATV rollover on Queensland's Western Downs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/girl-5-killed-atv-rollover-queensland-property/106329550</link><description>A young girl has died and a boy has been injured after an ATV being driven by a child rolled rolled on a rural property near Chinchilla on Tuesday evening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdda000adf2d614bb5aca14a04fad009</guid></item><item><title>Volunteers say neglect by state's wildlife department caused bushfires on WA's south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/fitzgerald-river-bushfire-dbca-mismanagement/106321810</link><description>Farmers and volunteer firefighters say decades of neglect by WA's Department of Biodiversity, Conservation and Attractions is at the heart of fires that ripped through more than 200,000 hectares of state-managed land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40f45582a4045e521119758ac54edc75</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Stunning cheating admission overshadows medal win as Naumov brings tears with tribute — quick hits from day four</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/sport-quick-hits-winter-olympics-day-four-cheating-nauov-tribute/106329142</link><description>A Norwegian's first-ever medal is overshadowed by a stunning admission to reporters as Maxim Naumov pays tribute to his parents in the most beautiful way. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4ddae6dcef41de86448ed66a84d4881</guid></item><item><title>Western quoll joey born in outback NSW likely to be first in a century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/western-quoll-thrive-outback-nsw-after-taronga-program/106304882</link><description>Once thought to be extinct in NSW, the small, spotted, and highly photogenic western quoll is making a hard-fought comeback to the wild.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1127d8b0dfa1ad403186fda2e24d1f68</guid></item><item><title>Fateful wrong turn, quiet cancer battle possible factors in missing prospector's suspected death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/barry-podmore-inquest-potential-wrong-turn/106328254</link><description>An inquest into Barry Podmore's disappearance in WA's remote Wheatbelt hears the 73-year-old was waging a private battle with cancer and may have become lost in bushland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70fd4d4de62cfa6ad418be560e1027f2</guid></item><item><title>Queensland hospital data shows e-scooter injuries escalate to five per day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/queensland-e-scooter-injuries-escalate-hospital-data-shows/106329602</link><description>New state hospital data shows more than five Queenslanders per day end up in the emergency department with injuries like bone fractures due to e-scooters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">471f0aff695e4a49c8bf9bc9c4fc44b6</guid></item><item><title>What 30 years on the domestic violence front line taught police negotiator Vincent Hurley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/conversations-vince-hurley-domestic-violence-hostage-negotiation/106224980</link><description>Years on the front line of domestic violence surfaced in a frustration-filled moment on national television for Vincent Hurley. He explains what motivates him to keep fighting for change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bbd7954a3ffef22e74026708d401305</guid></item><item><title>Victorian CFMEU branch became 'hateful, greedy rabble' under John Setka, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/vic-cfmeu-report-government-victoria/106329680</link><description>The Victorian government is defending its handling of corruption in the state's construction sector amid accusations in a major corruption report that it was "cowed" by the CFMEU.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25f2d305b24f10007a03a973dde7a0f5</guid></item><item><title>Hand-built high country bridges lost to fires, taking decades of history with them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/historical-high-country-rail-trail-bridges-destroyed-by-fire/106312604</link><description>Volunteers are weighing the future of the High Country Rail Trail after the loss of 12 historic trestle bridges — and decades of work — to bushfires.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84b358786d6ad808955ee6269134044f</guid></item><item><title>Race against bulldozers to save ancient grass trees in WA's South West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/race-to-save-grass-trees-south-west-wa/106323778</link><description>Some of WA's oldest grass trees are being rescued from land clearing and development amid a population and property boom, preserving a unique part of the South West's natural heritage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c035d16240b39fbe758a3a7788f5176</guid></item><item><title>Queensland records first outbreak of Mimosa pigra — giant sensitive tree — in 25 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/giant-sensitive-tree-mimosa-pigra-detected-in-qld/106327380</link><description>A giant sensitive tree infestation has been detected near a lake near Brisbane and authorities say they have "no idea" how it got there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d606b67f355e1baa958386464d8e8d19</guid></item><item><title>Dungeons and Dragons-inspired game breaks down social barriers for neurodivergent kids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/dungeons-and-dragons-inspired-game-for-neurodivergent-kids/106321560</link><description>An Adelaide clinical psychologist creates a simplified version of Dungeons and Dragons to help neurodivergent children and young people learn social skills and develop peer connections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6f190df99526fce8245046efec4cbf7</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos striker Mo Toure scores hat-trick on starting debut in English Championship for Norwich</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/socceroos-striker-mohamed-toure-hat-trick-debut-norwich/106330220</link><description>Mohamed Toure moved to England recently on a $5 million deal and it is already looking like a great decision for the 21-year-old forward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ecfd2aa16103898748a1ab83e8c75e7</guid></item><item><title>High Court finds Catholic Church liable for priest's sexual abuse but halves compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/high-court-catholic-church-liable-priest-sexual-abuse/106329926</link><description>A man who suffered sexual abuse at the hands of a priest in the 1960s has won his High Court battle over liability, but had his compensation nearly halved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">115a801497fb65d312764e99856603d5</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth Bank shares rise after CBA reports increased profits as it lifts home lending volumes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/cba-shares-up-increased-profits-first-half-financial-year/106329968</link><description>CBA's net profit for the first half of the financial year rose 5 per cent to $5.367 billion, beating analyst expectations, on the back of increased lending and deposit volumes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dbf165da5a6dc26e708af53e3360fc9</guid></item><item><title>Milano Cortina 2026 is the most gender-equal Winter Olympics ever, aside from Nordic Combined</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/winter-olympics-2026-milan-cortina-nordic-combined-inequality/105991114</link><description>Nordic Combined is the only sport at any Olympic Games — summer and winter — that does not have an event for women. It's an omission that is putting the entire future of the sport at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1a0f1fcfce4eb1284b220db9b93d2fd</guid></item><item><title>Outgoing Queensland Police Commissioner Steve Gollschewki confident service 'heading in right direction'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/police-commissioner-gollschewski-retires-amid-cancer-diagnosis/106329604</link><description>Police Commissioner Steve Gollschewski has announced his retirement to focus on his family and health after a 46-year career with the service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdc395f5464b0622d6318ea4963cc02d</guid></item><item><title>Perth Festival opens with outdoor music, light sculptures and stories shared via old red telephone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/perth-festival-opens/106328574</link><description>Australia's longest running arts event, the Perth Festival, began on the weekend with Humans of New York-style videos in which locals tell their stories using an old red telephone on a bridge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">471448dd08cd988b876b0d8d841cb742</guid></item><item><title>Flood ruins costly repairs to Savannahlander railway bridge before it is used</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/savannahlander-future-uncertain-etheridge-railway-line-bridge/106327582</link><description>Flooding knocks a heritage-listed bush rail bridge out of alignment only weeks after long-awaited repairs, jeopardising the future of the Savannahlander route.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9297d9a4d890b3802988f3b4beb4481d</guid></item><item><title>Former Gidarjil CEO Kerry Blackman to face trial on five charges of sexual assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/kerry-blackman-to-stand-trial-on-sexual-assault-charges/106327292</link><description>Kerry Blackman will face trial in the Bundaberg District Court in June, charged with five counts of sexual assault.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7deebe3550be4f8148a82c0beb111e66</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 5, Wednesday, February 11</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide/106325628</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4808821c5d5c5ad794f816a30958d89</guid></item><item><title>Foreign Correspondent returns for 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/foreign-correspondent-returns-for-2026/106330242</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e734c6c6a37aaf3cffab1a16eb6fe076</guid></item><item><title>Sophie Ellis-Bextor on why people are obsessed with nostalgic things</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/sophie-ellis-bextor-on-why-people-are-/106325936</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b121321a0264508bb89bb81f075314e</guid></item><item><title>DPP apologises after office 'dropped the ball' over police officer assault case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/sa-police-grant-stevens-concerned-about-police-assault/106329878</link><description>A court decision in which a woman who assaulted a South Australian police officer with a glass bottle was spared jail prompts an extraordinary concession from the Director of Public Prosecutions (DPP).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8f6d35fb3085ec7867365bd29fc6a55</guid></item><item><title>Shootings at school and home in British Columbia leave 10 dead and dozens injured</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/british-columbia-high-school-shooting-multiple-dead/106331278</link><description>The woman turned the weapon on herself after the killings, according to police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">824cf9a23c9f001c9874ced803acf9fe</guid></item><item><title>Missing man Corey Chugg separated from friend while collecting firewood, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/search-for-missing-man-corey-chugg-in-tasmania/106328680</link><description>A 32-year-old man missing in Tasmania's north was collecting firewood with a friend when the pair became separated on Sunday, police have said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e1ef0edf011bcec194b5dfaf7f996fe</guid></item><item><title>Person detained for questioning over disappearance of Nancy Guthrie, Arizona law enforcement says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/nancy-guthrie-person-detained-questioning-kidnapping/106331392</link><description>Law officials in Arizona say a person has been detained for questioning in relation to the disappearance of Nancy Guthrie, the 84-year-old mother of Today show host Savannah.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c03d86c8d87c3051a49958cd259c0fd</guid></item><item><title>Police say there was 'serious, imminent risk' of child kidnapping in Perth by Jason William Forbes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/baldivis-child-kidnapper-jason-william-forbes-update/106327906</link><description>WA Police say "something terrible" could have happened if there was a delay in intercepting a Baldivis man who planned to abduct and sexually abuse a child in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9cb2e1663474710cf734cdb38d48828</guid></item><item><title>Formula 1 2026: New engines and no DRS headline major changes in grand prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/formula-1-2026-new-engines-regulations-sprint-races/106325942</link><description>New engines, new regulations and an 11-team grid are just some of the changes in Formula 1 this season. Get up to speed with what is new in F1 ahead of the Australian Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fce942eea4fa4616a149450aa1c7158</guid></item><item><title>Doongmabulla Springs decision leaves Qld government to weigh appeal or face trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/doongmabulla-springs-qld-government-appeal-or-face-trial/106305714</link><description>Wangan and Jagalingou peoples await the state government's next move after a win in their fight to have alleged damage to a sacred site near a mine in Central Queensland investigated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">409498e1a5333e429fc6fc92646dec77</guid></item><item><title>Two more Chinese nationals accused of foreign interference after allegedly gathering information in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/chinese-nationals-accused-foreign-interference-canberra/106331328</link><description>A task force investigated the alleged covert collection of information about a Canberra Buddhist association.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a1ec680cbea7b7a88f62860b8627475</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia readies up to 8,000 troops for Board of Peace efforts in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/indonesia-to-send-8000-troops-to-gaza-idf-peacekeeping/106330718</link><description>The move makes Indonesia the first country to clearly commit troops to a multinational peacekeeping effort in the war-torn enclave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb09709ab6a43276c0ef5777b42146b8</guid></item><item><title>No body-worn video evidence available for inquest into Krista Kach's death, coroner hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/krista-kach-inquest-no-body-worn-camera-evidence/106330358</link><description>A court hears a NSW inquest will need to rely on eyewitness accounts of the 2023 death of Krista Kach, who was shot with a beanbag round following a 10-hour stand-off with police in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e1eb69fc8206627f42ed509806f3904</guid></item><item><title>What to watch in February, from puppy love to Muppet hijinks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/what-to-watch-the-muppets-scrubs/106325818</link><description>Kermit, Miss Piggy and the rest of the crew are back to celebrate their 50th birthday with a one-off special that has the potential to turn into a whole new series for the beloved characters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09b335d5b372e0742b8c096839af2dff</guid></item><item><title>Dinosaur dig on Victoria's Bass Coast uncovers more than 60 bones and fossils</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/dinosaur-dig-at-inverloch-finds-bones-and-fossils/105904132</link><description>A collection of more than 60 dinosaur bones and fossils are unearthed from rocks at the site of a fossil dig in Victoria's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d67f1ab883871846b55d6387f0f8bd4a</guid></item><item><title>Perth brothers Nezir and Enver Ibrahimovic avoid jail for assault at Scarborough bar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/bouncers-avoid-jail-scarborough-bar-assault/106331266</link><description>Two brothers working as bouncers when they assaulted a man at a Scarborough bar avoid jail after a magistrate recognised the trauma they suffered in the Bosnian war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78455998eac3b4222b694f47d3f06d7a</guid></item><item><title>Mother of teenager allegedly assaulted by NSW Police at Sydney protest to press charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/nsw-police-protest-allegedly-assaulted-teenager-mother-claims/106329674</link><description>The mother of a 16-year-old who alleges he was "pushed, kicked, dragged on the ground" by officers at a Sydney protest against the Israeli president's visit says she wants to press charges against police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30d0c8531d4d566ed060274bb1773187</guid></item><item><title>Cryptosporidium cluster at Waterworld leads to closure of Adelaide Aquatic Centre pools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/adelaide-aquatic-centres-close-after-cluster-of-gastro-cases/106330324</link><description>SA Health is urging people with gastroenteritis symptoms not to visit public swimming pools after eight cases at one swimming centre, including one child who was hospitalised and another who also visited the Adelaide Aquatic Centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">feaa7c2df6769e23acd9a68078708dfc</guid></item><item><title>Axed literary magazine Meanjin is resurrected by Queensland University of Technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/meanjin-magazine-finds-new-home-queensland-university-technology/106331850</link><description>The 85-year-old literary journal Meanjin will return to Brisbane, where it was first published, after it was controversially closed by Melbourne University Press last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8381f55200bc2cef76893ac168c73d93</guid></item><item><title>Telstra to axe up to 650 roles in mass redundancy round, some jobs to be outsourced to India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/telstra-axes-600-roles-in-redundancy-round-outsourcing-to-india/106331708</link><description>Telstra notifies staff of plans to outsource hundreds of jobs to an India-based technology company.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a54d2039d987947db967f7534c2af1d8</guid></item><item><title>Former Carlton legend Peter Dean hospitalised after serious assault in Albury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/former-carlton-legend-suffers-serious-assault-in-albury/106331586</link><description>Former AFL player Peter Dean is recovering in hospital after he sustained serious head and facial injuries in an alleged assault at Albury on the New South Wales Victorian border.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4ceb1d2b4738f0666d773a5bf7a2435</guid></item><item><title>Hobart Cup result under investigation after Elwick course 37 metres short</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/hobart-cup-result-investigation-after-racetrack-too-short/106331290</link><description>The Hobart Cup, the "feature" event in Tasmania's horse racing calendar, is under investigation after the race was run over a distance found later to be 37 metres short of its advertised length.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ca3ca8d95b42b45458bfaf4b0014d2a</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Tropical Cyclone Mitchell brings damage and rain to farmers in WA's south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/strong-winds-wreak-havoc-on-farm-properties-wheatbelt-region/106329960</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says a weather system influenced by ex-Tropical Cyclone Mitchell delivered storms to the Great Southern and central Wheatbelt this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe2f4307942ad8b54d9b5037e79ee1e6</guid></item><item><title>Storms smash WA's Wheatbelt region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/storms-smash-wa-s-wheatbelt-region/106331056</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">519623324f9f4fab52734e78c4afee12</guid></item><item><title>US politician Ro Khanna reveals names of six 'powerful men' scrubbed from Epstein files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/ro-khanna-reveals-names-redacted-from-epstein-files/106331712</link><description>US politician Ro Khanna has publicly named six men whose identities were scrubbed from the Epstein files, including the former boss of Victoria's Secret, who the FBI suspected was a co-conspirator of the sex offender's crimes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5436a5f0bc8f114fceefe16bdeef79e9</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide's own a medal contender for US in women's double luge at Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/winter-olympics-chevonne-forgan-womens-doubles-luge-adelaide/106331288</link><description>The driest state in the driest country of the world might seem the unlikeliest of places for a star in the Winter Olympics sport of luge to emerge, but Chevonne Forgan will be a medal contender tonight — albeit for Team USA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8190dc66c1226686cb38afb044c221c4</guid></item><item><title>Supersized fatberg clogging Sydney sewer blamed for mysterious debris balls on beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/supersized-fatberg-clogging-sydney-sewer-debris-balls/106309658</link><description>The debris balls that have washed up on NSW beaches in recent years are likely to continue as Sydney Water admits a massive fatberg it cannot reach is clogging sewers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e47536114404d9c787ba564b5b869472</guid></item><item><title>How the search for Nancy Guthrie played out as police detain a person for questioning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/nancy-guthrie-timeline-disappearance-fbi-investigation/106330542</link><description>As the frantic search for the mother of a well-known US journalist enters its 12th day, police have more questions than answers. Here's how it unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f460bd6df920530439aac61fcd761aec</guid></item><item><title>Mum of motorcyclist fatally hit by car tells court of 'immeasurable' devastation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/victim-impact-statement-after-motorcyclist-killed-in-crash/106331510</link><description>A grieving mother whose 21-year-old son died after he was struck by a car while riding his motorcycle south of Adelaide tells a court of her devastation and issues a plea to drivers to "check, double check and check again" for bikes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd9c850d55ea31fc30c7fe349201dec0</guid></item><item><title>Ex-student tells court alleged abuse by Matriculation College teacher led to theft and 'warped' relationships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/hobart-matriculation-college-former-student-gives-evidence-rape/106332498</link><description>A woman suing her former teacher has told a court that the alleged abuse impacted her future relationships and "warped" her professional boundaries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa634835bf36571a04b2a810f331b12b</guid></item><item><title>NSW soccer coach Tullio 'Tony' Giacomo Cigana jailed over child abuse material</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/nsw-soccer-coach-jailed-over-child-abuse-material/106332804</link><description>A once well-regarded soccer coach has been handed a 12 month jail sentence for possessing child abuse material, after a Sydney court heard he has been disowned by family members.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46189d96dae7bf43bc8498eec2003538</guid></item><item><title>New video shows the beginning of altercation between police and a protester.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/white-shirted-man-punched-by-police/106332484</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ea61776fd53f613dba5d7dcc9681716</guid></item><item><title>New video sheds light on beginning of altercation between police officers and a Town Hall protester</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/-white-shirt-man-town-hall-protests-punched-new-video/106332094</link><description>A new video filmed by a bystander and shared with ABC NEWS Verify shows the full minute before two police officers began punching a protester, shedding light on the beginning of the altercation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4fecc044fc46d6003450c9200ac8eba</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the mass shooting in Tumbler Ridge, Canada</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/tumbler-ridge-canada-school-shooting-explainer/106331730</link><description>Police confirmed the suspect was a woman but have yet to identify the victims of the mass shooting that left 10 people, including the alleged shooter, dead in the rural town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8e3d7cc9020ede54a38960ebbd3624f</guid></item><item><title>Israeli President Isaac Herzog welcomes 'new beginning' in meeting with Anthony Albanese</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/protesters-rally-as-mps-skip-question-time-for-herzog-visit/106331226</link><description>Israeli President Isaac Herzog meets with the prime minister at Parliament House in Canberra, saying his visit to Australia has been "very emotional".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">579de49026fcdc60f86649be3a4bb35f</guid></item><item><title>Australian dollar reaches '40-year high' against Japan's yen, as cheap holidays fuel tourism surge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/australian-dollar-japanese-yen-currency-exchange-rate-tourism/106332346</link><description>Australia's exchange rate with Japan has grown increasingly favourable to tourists, which have surged to record numbers and topped more than one million visitors in 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7abbc35d9096aae897d046e36ccf9990</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds treated for e-bike injuries in 2025 at Sydney St Vincent Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/ebike-injuries-double-at-sydney-hospital/106332460</link><description>More than 200 people were treated for e-bike related injuries at a single Sydney hospital last year, with one medical professor describing the trend as an "epidemic".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51176d07eca703bb7654923149b12871</guid></item><item><title>RBA deputy governor defends central bank from critics, wonders if Australia is more inflation-prone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/rba-deputy-governor-says-rba-not-criticise-government-policy/106331502</link><description>RBA deputy governor Andrew Hauser says central banks should not criticise normal government spending choices, but he wonders if Australia's economy is more inflation-prone because it is so finely balanced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f806f14f928362b28b219b82a640327b</guid></item><item><title>NT government conducting Sandover Highway speed review after inquest into fatal rollover</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/fatal-rollover-sparks-sandover-highway-speed-review/106332812</link><description>The death of a remote art centre worker in a rollover north-east of Alice Springs leads to a Northern Territory government review of speed limits on an outback highway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2927231b8af83ba18d9fb13a8faf2bb5</guid></item><item><title>Australian fans miss out on World Cup tickets as prices skyrocket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/world-cup-ticket-prices-aussie-fans-miss-out/106332736</link><description>A host of Australian fans will be denied the chance to watch the Socceroos World Cup campaign amid accusations of price gouging by FIFA as tickets to the tournament soar to astronomical prices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cb80105f0eeb0984e8c6d7afad7d449</guid></item><item><title>Labor tries again on super taxes, but yet to secure Greens support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/labor-tries-again-on-super-taxes/106331524</link><description>A second attempt to raise taxes on high super balances has been presented to parliament, but will require the support of the Greens to secure Senate passage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a466ab31df35bf825a2dc9c0feee1d03</guid></item><item><title>US bars Palau senate president and former Marshall Islands mayor over alleged corruption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/us-bars-palau-marshall-islands-officials-for-alleged-corruption/106329288</link><description>A senior Palau politician rejects accusations from the United States Department of State that he accepted bribes from "government, business, and criminal interests from China".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4c5d3311f093881fd48b21aa27d5d56</guid></item><item><title>Austin Appelbee's Triple Zero call to save family swept out to sea at Geographe Bay released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/austin-appelbee-triple-zero-call-released/106333174</link><description>Police release the recording of the Triple Zero call made by 13-year-old Austin Appelbee after his marathon 4 kilometre swim through rough seas to save his family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">080bb848fb9e646a03ddfb0802a198e8</guid></item><item><title>Kane Dallow sentenced to two years in prison on fraud and other charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/tasmanian-man-kane-dallow-jailed-for-28-offences/106227598</link><description>A Tasmanian man who impersonated the Launceston Magistrates Court has been convicted on 28 crimes relating to fraud, forgery and perverting justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a46ce2b2cf467d06b9f88e5ba53d770b</guid></item><item><title>Chinese flotilla sailed to edge of Australia's waters, ADF chief reveals at Senate estimates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/chinese-flotilla-edge-australian-exclusive-economic-zone/106333020</link><description>Under questioning in Senate estimates, the chief of the Australian Defence Force reveals that a Chinese flotilla sailed within seven nautical miles of Australia's 200 nautical mile exclusive economic zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54162e69e9611e52a37af7ad332cce70</guid></item><item><title>NSW Parliament backs Cheryl Grimmer's family after 56-year quest for justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/cheryl-grimmer-parliament-motion-buckingham/106332722</link><description>Decades after three-year-old Cheryl Grimmer vanished from Fairy Meadow Beach, NSW MPs move to support her family's fight for justice, as Jeremy Buckingham directly addressed the alleged perpetrator under parliamentary privilege.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9f2d8b7e5889008ddc973077711f317</guid></item><item><title>Surveillance devices captured accused talking about alleged murder of Geoffrey McLean, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/court-hears-evidence-over-alleged-murder-of-geoffrey-mclean/106333170</link><description>An SA Supreme Court trial hears listening devices captured alleged murderer Mark Murphy admitting to his role in killing Geoffrey McLean in 2022. Warning: This story contains details that some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dee7af032cb8fec1ac1248900b766e93</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor resigns from frontbench ahead of expected leadership challenge to Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/angus-taylor-resigns-from-frontbench-sussan-ley-leadership/106332492</link><description>Angus Taylor says the Liberals are at their weakest point since the party was formed as he announces his resignation from the frontbench.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">719ec35aae82fd4ae16e34d338c37aa1</guid></item><item><title>Parents association fined after allowing alleged sexual offender to keep working at care centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/cranbrook-state-primary-school-parents-association-fined/106333024</link><description>A North Queensland parents association is fined $50,000 for failures in handling allegations of sexual abuse at an after school care service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6337111b808dadf036441dc7b286623c</guid></item><item><title>Live: Anthony looks to defends Olympic crown as James starts medal quest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/winter-olympics-2026-live-jakara-anthony-scotty-james/106329908</link><description>Australia's defending champion Jakara Anthony is preparing for the moguls final, while Scotty James starts his quest to complete his Olympic medal set with a maiden snowboard halfpipe gold. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bde28b9ffb03fa5cbe8c29b66aac219b</guid></item><item><title>Audio of Austin Appelbee's incredible Triple Zero call after marathon swim to save family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/audio-of-austin-appelbee-s-incredible-triple-zero-call-after-mar/106333512</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a07e12a8516d493dc30141c630813b8</guid></item><item><title>Live: Marsh out of Australia's T20 World Cup opener Ireland with testicular bleeding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/cricket-t20-world-cup-australia-ireland-blog-scores-stats/106330266</link><description>Captain Mitch Marsh joins Australia's lengthy injury list as it prepares to take on Ireland in its opening T20 World Cup match in Colombo. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f10653e8e126254d5fa9b92b8b0d7bf</guid></item><item><title>Channel Nine says Warren Tredrea has now paid costs over long-running legal battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/channel-nine-says-warren-tredrea-has-paid-legal-costs/106333410</link><description>Channel Nine has confirmed it has received legal costs from former AFL player and sports presenter Warren Tredrea, who was ordered to pay $149,000 to his ex-employer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f2d55f17d07ae474e5568f1f5fecbde</guid></item><item><title>Is there going to be a Liberal leadership showdown?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/is-there-going-to-be-a-liberal-leader-showdown-/106333560</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffda194d6e76caf03cdfdc9957c0d5c4</guid></item></channel></rss>