<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 04:53:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>WA teenager starts petition for shearing to be in Brisbane 2032 Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/wa-teen-starts-petition-for-shearing-to-be-in-the-olympics/105721670</link><description>We saw break dancing added to the Olympic program for the Paris Games, and now there is a push for shearing to be included for the Brisbane Olympics in 2032.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ce5973b6762c550d39695066a2eff91</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final 2025: Brisbane Lions thump Geelong Cats by 47 points, Will Ashcroft wins Norm Smith Medal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-grand-final-2025-geelong-vs-brisbane-live-blog/105822258</link><description>Brisbane secures its second straight AFL premiership, taking control in the final quarter of an otherwise gripping grand final against Geelong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14ca0c766669a84c1c64d308b07e389c</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Storm Bualoi sweeps through Philippines leaving 10 dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/tropical-storm-bulaoi-philippines-flood-corruption/105823944</link><description>The death toll from a tropical storm that swept across the central Philippines and southern Luzon has risen to 10, as the country's north continued recovering from Super Typhoon Ragasa.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2df415b803d0ecbfbe0362606b7d507</guid></item><item><title>Fortescue offers measles vaccine boosters after Christmas Creek outbreak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/fortescue-measles-vaccine-boosters-christmas-creek-outbreak/105820426</link><description>Iron-ore giant Fortescue says it will offer vaccine boosters after three measles cases were confirmed at its Pilbara mine earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26e09d8753cc469c42fac166c15b08d3</guid></item><item><title>Tourist dies at Tasmania's Cradle Mountain National Park after group becomes 'overwhelmed' by extreme weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/cradle-mountain-walker-dies-extreme-weather/105824188</link><description>A group of tourists who were unprepared for the extreme conditions at Cradle Mountain National Park is rescued, but one member of the group dies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c2bacc1d4008463c044ab40ec94a7ab</guid></item><item><title>Cyclist on a gruelling journey to fight for a better future for people with dementia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/nic-tremaine-cycling-around-australia-dementia-fundraising-trip/105730642</link><description>Nicholas Tremaine is cycling more than 40,000 kilometres to raise $1 million to fight the condition that's befallen his mother and is now Australia's leading cause of death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08add1d8f7252bd94b473e9688d5ae02</guid></item><item><title>Clive Palmer ordered to pay more than $13 million after foreign investor claim dismissed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/clive-palmer-foreign-investor-claim-dismissed/105823966</link><description>The decade-long dispute was related to WA government legislation, which impeded Clive Palmer's ability to extract damages over the Balmoral South Iron Ore Project in the Pilbara.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b97d0fa74d42a0e0aad8a2eb639f05fe</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous teenager teaches Paakantyi language to teachers at Menindee school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/aboriginal-paakantyi-language-teacher-outback-nsw-school/105815440</link><description>Jaz Fusi has been passionate about learning Paakantyi language for most of her life. Now, she teaches it to her local school's teachers and is eager to see other kids do the same.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffc9b2d6c78f4e662e2f96fe4e5bf8a9</guid></item><item><title>WA government facing $400m cost blowout over Peel Health Campus redevelopment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/peel-health-campus-cost-blowout/105824094</link><description>The long-awaited redevelopment of Peel Health Campus is facing a $400 million cost blowout and potential delays, a leaked document reveals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7295950907094099603d65d0a0b06af</guid></item><item><title>All Blacks edge brave Wallabies to retain Bledisloe Cup for 23rd year at Eden Park, Morgan Turinui rants at referee</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/live-updates-all-blacks-vs-wallabies-bledisloe-cup-in-auckland/105816056</link><description>The All Blacks have beaten the Wallabies 33-24 at Eden Park, extending their 39-year and counting winning record against Australia at the Auckland venue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13406db2d00d984b62fdf93c8404b3c6</guid></item><item><title>Relationship experts on the signs that it may be time to call it quits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/signs-it-might-be-time-to-end-a-relationship/105675792</link><description>If you are feeling indifferent about your relationship, have high conflict, or just don't really enjoy their company anymore, it is possible the partnership has reached its end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">499d5b97aa70d0462b93fa23afce5eb8</guid></item><item><title>Snoop Dogg, Baker Boy and Tash Sultana star in AFL grand final entertainment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/snoop-dogg-afl-grand-final-entertainment-mcg/105819406</link><description>The legendary rapper delivered a squeaky clean performance, incorporating local artists and a didgeridoo in a trip through his catalogue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">520a21469afd2968627cca416d5cdb69</guid></item><item><title>Woman, 81, dies after unit fire in Doubleview in Perth's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/woman-hospitalised-after-house-fire-in-doubleview/105824454</link><description>Emergency services found the woman, 81, unresponsive at the scene in Doubleview and took her to hospital, but she couldn't be revived.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efe5ece1968afa40b9bdec4dab0bd7a1</guid></item><item><title>Matt Wright's lawyers reveal five grounds of appeal for Netflix star's guilty verdict, including allegation against judge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/matt-wright-five-grounds-of-appeal-revealed/105824618</link><description>Matt Wright's lawyers have revealed the five grounds they are seeking to appeal their client's guilty verdict on, including an allegation that the judge made an "impermissible comment to the jury".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45adde7e87d9110419b85a7a1e1c1ee1</guid></item><item><title>Lions star Will Ashcroft wins second consecutive Norm Smith Medal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-grandfinal-norm-smith-lons-cats-will-ashcroft/105824400</link><description>Will Ashcroft claims back-to-back Norm Smith Medals after playing a starring role in the Brisbane Lions' grand final win over Geelong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d02e668f13c6768be3d2d3f2232c0931</guid></item><item><title>How the internet reacted to the Brisbane Lions winning the AFL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/internet-reacted-afl-grand-final-brisbane-lions-geelong-cats/105802198</link><description>Brisbane completed an historic back-to-back premiership, beating a wounded Geelong at the MCG, and the internet followed along with every kick.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b68c6dfe98a3f3cc3b923023a51e2931</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane's back-to-back AFL grand final wins suggest we could be back in a 'Lions era'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/brisbane-lions-defeat-geelong-in-grand-final-in-new-era/105824588</link><description>The Lions successfully defended their premiership to go back-to-back, and pose the question: Are we back in a Lions era?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7311d26402f791ca2c79be844c093f2</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final quick hits: Lions' Lachie Neale gamble pays off, Cats' Jeremy Cameron in the wars, and it's Country Road time at the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-grand-final-quick-hits-geelong-cats-brisbane-lions/105821966</link><description>Brisbane's gamble on Lachie Neale's fitness pays off with a team-lifting goal, a brave Jeremy Cameron has a painful day out, and Charlie Cameron's goals provide a Country Road soundtrack at the MCG. Here are the quick hits from the 2025 AFL grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef10be159c2c5da37bc2677e999bc6a9</guid></item><item><title>Two teenagers among three charged after woman injured in alleged carjacking on the Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/woman-suffers-life-threatening-injuries-in-car-theft/105824808</link><description>The woman was injured when she was hit by a vehicle during an alleged car theft while she was unloading groceries at her home on the Gold Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6f5cf82a2835776725b5450a5fa0993</guid></item><item><title>White House releases photo of Donald Trump and Anthony Albanese</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/albanese-trump-photo/105824944</link><description>A photo of a smiling Donald Trump, alongside Anthony Albanese, his fiancée Jodie Haydon and US First Lady Melania Trump, has been released by the White House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff4eec3691a0dfeed959566549f25d32</guid></item><item><title>Chinese presence in the Pacific runs deep and is now reshaped by Beijing's ambitions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/china-pacific-islands-untold-story-chinese-geopolitics-influence/105818894</link><description>China's presence in the Pacific is often viewed in the context of geopolitical tension and rivalry. But Chinese people have been in the region for generations — these are their stories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6598aaeafdf808048e2ae2838622179b</guid></item><item><title>Geelong's strength-in-numbers approach fails its biggest test in AFL grand final loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/afl-grand-final-geelong-cats-brisbane-lions-analysis/105824608</link><description>It is the cruel irony of sport that what is usually the ace up Geelong's sleeve proved to be its downfall in the loss to the Brisbane Lions in the season decider.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1face944653c3d1f368bbbf10b8ded7</guid></item><item><title>As Australia's retirement savings grow into world's second biggest, government to review consumer protections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/as-australian-retirement-savings-grow-greater-regulation-needed/105820684</link><description>Compulsory super has led to higher levels of national savings, but, as the pool of savings grows, many argue that stricter supervision is needed to protect Australians' retirement savings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">727169d9557e7aa1856d8b008f7d6fd7</guid></item><item><title>When it comes to love, more of us are crossing the religious divide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/more-australians-are-marrying-across-the-religious-divide/105779468</link><description>Exclusive data for 5.2 million couples shows nearly one in five marriages are between people of different religions – double the proportion recorded in 1986.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">013dc6d1c3729b713228afd937c045d6</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz Kids: Tom Gleeson's back to put Australia's pint-sized hot shots in their place</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/hard-quiz-kids-weekly-trivia/105773368</link><description>The grump's back to take on the grommets in a new series of Hard Quiz Kids. Don't let the pint-sized know-it-alls show you up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a862981fd7047144319126295a5f472</guid></item><item><title>Guy Sebastian reflects on Titus Day legal case and the lesson he's learned from fans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/guy-sebastian-the-assembly/105671828</link><description>Guy Sebastian opens up about the fan encounter that made him "burst into tears" and a court case with his former manager, Titus Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d1fceb0fd7d9b21cd61a61a6b4f7281</guid></item><item><title>Roosters on cusp of perfect NRLW season after beating Sharks 17-16</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/nrlw-preliminary-final-sydney-roosters-cronulla-sharks/105825564</link><description>Jocelyn Kelleher is relishing the chance to prove her credentials as the Sydney Roosters look to claim back-to-back premierships for the first time in their history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c98d6e82e7da5e596aaac09a0d982f4d</guid></item><item><title>Woppaburra people welcome ancestor's return but face final hurdle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/woppaburra-peoples-fight-to-get-ancestor-home/105788102</link><description>More First Nations remains are being returned to Australia from international institutions, but these Woppaburra men say laying them to rest on country can prove a fresh challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f2752aea82ec37f1fac83229df02a1</guid></item><item><title>England defeats Canada 33-13 in Women's Rugby World Cup final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/rugby-world-cup-final-england-defeats-canada/105825580</link><description>In front of a record crowd of more than 80,000 spectators, England delivers on the biggest stage with a 33-13 defeat of Canada in the tournament decider at Twickenham.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62fcacd86e45554323ddd632300502bc</guid></item><item><title>A small win for beachgoers and gardeners as washed-up sea life turned to compost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/algal-bloom-dead-sea-life-turned-to-compost/105807488</link><description>Dead sea life washed ashore during SA's marine algal bloom has been diverted into commercial compost for farms and gardens, in what has been viewed as a small win amid the large-scale devastation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4b9a8f084b8a14c310d2e1372a86ca2</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's coal royalty regime back in the spotlight after job cuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/qld-coal-mine-royalties-regime-questioned-after-job-cuts/105818488</link><description>Despite a change of government, Queensland's controversial coal royalty scheme remains in place and recent job cuts are prompting renewed discussion about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05fc998cc23e435b2b1e012ba6d8ab22</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane and Geelong fans experience the ecstasy and agony of AFL's biggest game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/afl-grand-final-lions-and-cats-fan-reactions/105824822</link><description>For the second year in a row, Brisbane Lions fans were celebrating in the streets as their team claimed the premiership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6337aba73bc17913cc11052d6f937e4</guid></item><item><title>One man dead, another seriously injured in Morwell incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/morwell-man-dies-another-injured/105825596</link><description>Homicide Squad detectives are investigating the death of a man in Victoria's east in an incident that left another man seriously injured.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79de8270e386a3f0921b72571a11495a</guid></item><item><title>Lions AFL coach Chris Fagan vindicated with Lachie Neale sub call in grand final win over Cats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/afl-grand-final-brisbane-lions-chris-fagan-lachie-neale/105825616</link><description>Brisbane Lions coach Chris Fagan admits he took a punt by naming Lachie Neale as the sub ahead of their stunning win over Geelong in the grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">356d4d2bcf5d986dedc6cb7aff32d029</guid></item><item><title>Feral pigs illegally brought into SA from NSW, DNA testing confirms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/dna-testing-finds-feral-pigs-illegally-brought-into-sa-from-nsw/105806616</link><description>Dozens of pigs were released illegally over several attempts to establish populations for hunting, with a local landscape board warning of the danger a feral population could cause.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1875e7c11aebd493798a84587badd76b</guid></item><item><title>Rod Barwick has international fame as a daffodil breeder, but what matters to him is a love of gardening</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/rod-barwick-daffodil-breeder-glenbrook-bulb-farm/105803774</link><description>Rod Barwick planted his first daffodil bulbs in the 70s. Within a few years, he began breeding daffodils and has since been recognised internationally for his work — but he says enjoying growing plants is the most important part of gardening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca3f901a514528002a7c6ff54fe81d6c</guid></item><item><title>Thirty years ago, Oasis made (What's The Story) Morning Glory? — a Britpop blockbuster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/oasis-morning-glory-30-years-anniversary-review-reunion/105816312</link><description>They'll soon tour Australia, but 30 years ago, Oasis were about to release (What's The Story) Morning Glory? — an enduring British rock classic. Here's how they did it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0332a614c6ebdac441c971670d46b82b</guid></item><item><title>Moment Brisbane Lions win 2025 AFL premiership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/moment-brisbane-lions-win-2025-afl-premiership/105825768</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb7106de6f4f1cb4bf66109d660b5cd7</guid></item><item><title>Ten-year-old mini bull rider from Cape York takes on world's best in Utah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/10-year-old-mini-bull-rider-competes-at-world-finals-in-utah-us/105817314</link><description>In a huge dark hat and shining belt buckle, a 10-year-old from Cape York proves he can mix it with the best at the world finals in Utah.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da9e4e8bec951353c341a9189fe44a20</guid></item><item><title>Dhakiyarr Wirrpanda's family in calls for fresh probe into mystery disappearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/nt-missing-yolngu-man-cold-case-police-killing-confession/105581636</link><description>The family of vanished Yolŋu leader Dhakiyarr Wirrpanda is calling on the Northern Territory coroner to pursue an ABC investigation's lead on his mysterious disappearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66e217a67165888621851fab3aed8814</guid></item><item><title>No subscriptions? No problems! Here are the best movies and TV series you can watch for free</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/where-to-watch-movies-tv-for-free/105809908</link><description>From family favourites to Australia's most controversial soap opera, here's some of the best movies and TV you can watch right now — no fee required!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1dd880d77579b98d0407d4f5c96f4df</guid></item><item><title>Kununurra's Barra Bash barramundi competition underway as restocking solution sought</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/barramundi-stocking-concerns-at-barra-bash-in-kununurra/105815558</link><description>More than 1,000 fishers hope to reel in a winning catch at Lake Kununurra, where a restocking program and ideal conditions have grown record-size barramundi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">923bf257f99baf7de30b4c08ce60dcfd</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese coy on critical minerals offer ahead of meeting with Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/albanese-offer-trump-critical-minerals/105825654</link><description>The prime minister would not say exactly what Australia's critical minerals offer to the United States included — nor whether it was exclusive to the Trump administration, after he discussed the issue with his British counterpart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d440be41b2395718c9785786a4c0dfc</guid></item><item><title>Lions show they're the complete team by beating Cats to claim second straight AFL premiership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/afl-grand-final-lions-cats-analysis/105827470</link><description>With contributors across the board, the Brisbane Lions clinically dismantled Geelong to show last year's premiership victory was no fluke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fe484cf746759bffa0be4bf28fe5c9d</guid></item><item><title>It's OK on the Macleay poster vandalism prompts calls for queer acceptance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/calls-for-queer-visibility-after-vandalism-at-pride-festival/105811572</link><description>A regional queer community says acceptance is improving in regional areas, but vandalism targeting an LGBTQI+ event shows there is still a way to go.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57d4bd6f43f48e213b4f3691a470e868</guid></item><item><title>Selena Gomez marries music producer Benny Blanco in star-studded ceremony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/selena-gomez-announces-marriage-to-benny-blanco/105827466</link><description>Singer, actor and beauty mogul Selena Gomez marries music producer Benny Blanco, with US media reporting Taylor Swift was in attendance at the star-studded affair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97200a44d196247f24b3ee1a047dc883</guid></item><item><title>Astronaut Katherine Bennell-Pegg says studying space will help Australia manage bushfires, floods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/astronaut-katherine-bennell-pegg-study-space-bushfires-floods/105827566</link><description>With Sydney to play host to the world's largest space conference this coming week, Katherine Bennell-Pegg says it is more important than ever to highlight the benefits of growing Australia's space workforce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a22b012cfec7d5326f72f355ce13a7aa</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Kirra Wright claims silver at World Para Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/world-para-athletics-championships-kirra-wright-silver/105827702</link><description>At just 17, Kirra Wright reaches the podium at the world titles after setting a personal best in winning the silver medal in New Delhi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42bba4c45ae83eaf136a7c80e68c26df</guid></item><item><title>The benefits and risks of sleeping next to your dog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/the-benefits-and-risks-of-sleeping-next-to-our-dogs/105774468</link><description>While there are several benefits to keeping our pets close at night, there are a few minor risks to consider.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">932ca557de76cc1cae410a853cede833</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos beat Penrith Panthers to reach NRL grand final as Adam Reynolds kicks game-winning conversion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/nrl-finals-live-updates-brisbane-broncos-penrith-panthers/105780678</link><description>Adam Reynolds nails a sideline conversion with three minutes left to send the Broncos into the NRL grand final and end Penrith's dynasty with a 16-14 win at Lang Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2dae682e54f4bfe7bd10f04e9f859f9</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate death of man at Brisbane shopping centre in early hours of Sunday morning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/brisbane-man-found-dead-at-shopping-centre/105827860</link><description>Police were called to a suburban shopping centre in the early hours of Sunday morning where they declared the man in his 40s dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1f120a042247a986d3d85b34298ac38</guid></item><item><title>Polar bears take over abandoned research station in Russian Arctic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/polar-bears-take-over-abandoned-research-station-russian-arctic/105827636</link><description>A group of polar bears that have taken over an abandoned polar research station off Russia's coast is intimately captured in drone footage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd9190befe49ad2b23306dac25fde98f</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos beat Newcastle Knights to set up NRLW grand final against Sydney Roosters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/brisbane-broncos-beat-knights-to-set-up-nrlw-grand-final/105827872</link><description>Brisbane is back in the NRLW grand final for the first time in five years, setting up the long-awaited clash with the Sydney Roosters after a 30-6 win over Newcastle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67d02df9ba10a85033ed2d183c187b10</guid></item><item><title>St Kilda pulls off record AFLW comeback, Ebony Marinoff, Ally Anderson celebrate milestone games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/st-kilda-stuns-port-with-aflw-comeback/105828018</link><description>St Kilda outscores Port Adelaide 38-0 in the final quarter after trailing by 27 points at three-quarter-time, while Ally Anderson and Ebony Marinoff become the first players to feature in 100 AFLW games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8d47cda8140119afb1ab797fd99be53</guid></item><item><title>Four-year-old boy missing in remote South Australian mid-north since Saturday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/police-searching-for-four-year-old-boy-missing-in-remote-sa/105828250</link><description>The boy was last seen at his family homestead at about 5pm on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9659f294f933266e03db072e8cf90d88</guid></item><item><title>Adam Reynolds and Reece Walsh explain the Broncos' game-winning moment against Penrith Panthers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/adam-reynolds-reece-walsh-nrl-final-game-winning-moment/105828288</link><description>Adam Reynolds took the kicking tee from the Broncos' biggest star in the biggest moment of their season so far, and it paid off in the biggest way possible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">536642d6505adba508e3c36f170c355a</guid></item><item><title>Vietnam evacuates thousands as Typhoon Bualoi approaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/typhoon-bualoi-forces-thousands-to-evacuate-in-vietnam/105828376</link><description>As Typhoon Bualoi approaches Vietnam, thousands of people are seeking safer ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34ba155386d3628844b99b19c8e4efb0</guid></item><item><title>Classified US intelligence warns of China's preparations for Taiwan invasion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/us-intelligence-warns-china-ferries-built-for-taiwan-preparation/105606720</link><description>A classified US intelligence report, seen by the ABC, says vessels have been modified to carry tanks and partake in amphibious operations in what Taiwan considers part of China's "expansionist intentions".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75d1c1d291b29866fa07b6834b7eb3fe</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's 'climate hoax' comments belong to a well-resourced playbook landing on Australia's shores</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/trump-climate-hoax-comments-and-fossil-fuel-lobby/105810870</link><description>US researchers have tracked how dark money funds a tangled web of climate denial think tanks with vested interests in slowing climate action. And Australia is not immune.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">baad7cd0960fc50a010484697cc19237</guid></item><item><title>If China beats the US on fusion energy, its supremacy will be assured</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/fusion-energy-china-united-states-coal/105720436</link><description>China is driving hard to supplant the US in this new military industrial complex, and has already achieved leadership in electric vehicles, batteries, drones and renewable energy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f2ed6434035cb358c677b916343d8b7</guid></item><item><title>Anti-corruption chief Paul Brereton continued defence consulting after declaring he had resigned from role</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/nacc-chief-defence-consulting/105821158</link><description>The head of the national anti-corruption commission told a Senate inquiry he had resigned his role at the defence force's investigative arm. But the ABC has learned he continued consulting for them, and documents proving his resignation could not be identified.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2142fb25ce654eee8a08d853101c7865</guid></item><item><title>Funding deal for research program about Australia's polar security rejected by Tasmanian government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/funding-deal-for-research-into-polar-security-rejected/105817408</link><description>A funding bid to establish a polar security research program has been knocked back, despite the changing geopolitical dynamics in Antarctica and the Southern Ocean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7caffffe60fab33afc201a1dced4018</guid></item><item><title>How Astrid Jorgensen turned a suburban pub choir into a worldwide musical phenomenon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/astrid-jorgensen-pub-choir-phenomenon/105785800</link><description>Astrid Jorgensen has an unusual condition — she finds many human noises unbearable. So how did she end up running the "world's biggest choir"?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c52ac986d15821498768cfce54f56e74</guid></item><item><title>Jewish patients say they feel ongoing fear months after Bankstown Hospital nurses video</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/jewish-community-hold-concern-following-bankstown-nurses-video/105790178</link><description>Some members of Australia's Jewish community say they have experienced ongoing trauma and fear months after a video came to light that included threats to Israeli patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76c4e1c74d2d6684705e8bddc17f4b6d</guid></item><item><title>Family of Melbourne man Kwar Ater searching for answers after his shooting death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/kwar-ater-remembered-after-fatal-melbourne-shooting/105808658</link><description>The 26-year-old was shot dead in Melbourne's CBD earlier this month, leaving his shocked family in search of answers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7da58ed54e19d399a6f3e67cf81bde98</guid></item><item><title>Outback temperatures near 40C as Queensland school holidays continue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/queensland-weather-spring-school-holidays-week-two/105825730</link><description>Clear, bright and sunny skies are expected as the Sunshine State's school holidays continue this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b50fdaed6da57cb2474ee44816c0be0</guid></item><item><title>The deadly legacy of the 'forgotten pandemic' — and why it's drawing comparisons to COVID-19</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/qld-hong-kong-flu-dr-john-gerrard-covid-19-pandemic-vaccines/105774782</link><description>It's been dubbed "the forgotten pandemic" — possibly because it coincided with some of the most momentous events in world history. But Dr John Gerrard argues variants of the H3N2 flu, which led to the Hong Kong flu pandemic, continue to cost lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da8e7bee9c1d98aac2d29d06615ce658</guid></item><item><title>Mark Nawaqanitawase outlines what he misses most about rugby union on Nesian Footy show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/sport-mark-nawaqanitawase-nesian-footy/105822930</link><description>Mark Nawaqanitawase says there are many things he misses about rugby union, but moving to league is the best decision he has made in his life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83953cee38f9bb85258d19c5c2410db2</guid></item><item><title>Grieving family frustrated at lack of licence reform after seven-year coronial inquest wait</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/family-frustrated-licence-reform-coronial-inquest/105822734</link><description>Robert Hall was killed when he was struck by partially blind driver John Charles Robertson on the Horrocks Highway in 2018. His family feel their pleas for licence reforms have been ignored by the state government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">002af794efab261a0061e550c361a41c</guid></item><item><title>These Australians are homeless with a house</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/remote-nt-housing-amid-rising-temperatures-climate-change/105421962</link><description>Many Aboriginal people in Tennant Creek live in overcrowded makeshift shelters with no running water or electricity as they wait up to a decade for a home. But experts say the social housing being built is not safe for today's climate, let alone the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6114aa8701c7c5addd04a9559938ee86</guid></item><item><title>Four dead after gunman opens fire in a Michigan Mormon church service before setting it on fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/michigan-mormon-church-fatal-shooting/105828872</link><description>Hundreds of people were inside The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints in Grand Blanc Township when a 40-year-old man rammed his pick-up truck through the front door, then got out of the vehicle and started shooting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1ca82611da9d7ceda5f81d3deea5660</guid></item><item><title>Southern pygmy perch 'ear bones' provide data to re-establish populations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/fish-ear-bones-could-be-key-to-pygmy-perch-revival/105811482</link><description>Information gleaned from tiny growth rings on "ear bones" of native pygmy perch could be the key to bringing them back from local extinction in the lower Murray.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">649c11322dafbfaa01c2ce68e583e5e7</guid></item><item><title>Two charged with murder over Morwell stabbing incident that left one man dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/vic-morwell-stabbing-murder-charges-laid/105828982</link><description>Homicide detectives have charged two males aged 16 and 19 with murder following the stabbing of an 18-year-old man in Victoria's east on Saturday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63577a879baf44fc9c66794f15e955af</guid></item><item><title>Shellharbour Council proposes tiny home planning pathway in NSW first</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/shellharbour-council-tiny-home-pilot-proposal-development/105811852</link><description>Shellharbour Council approves a plan for a tiny homes planning pathway which it says could be adopted statewide, as owners face uncertainty around legal installation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff8db8dbb4d397dada6c798c4cbe2283</guid></item><item><title>How Astrid Jorgensen started the 'world's biggest pub choir'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/vv-astrid-pub-choir/105820858</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11ca9c1ae053a99b615cfa221aa1a2d6</guid></item><item><title>Government quietly extends Nauru contract, taking the cost to $787m — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/federal-politics-live-blog-september-29/105829016</link><description>The government has quietly extended a contract for the running of asylum seeker services on Nauru until 2027, taking the cost to $787 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3465f48fde355f222f3088b4fb0df59a</guid></item><item><title>New York City Mayor Eric Adams announces he is dropping his re-election bid after unpopular tenure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/eric-adams-drops-re-election-bid/105828948</link><description>Eric Adams announces he is dropping his re-election bid, but says he will "continue to fight for this city" until his term ends on January 1, 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e1a8b654c5ea5d1d7a7ff58bd246fdd</guid></item><item><title>Ivan Cleary says NRL doctor's decision to rule Scott Sorensen out of preliminary final was a 'huge call'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/nrl-broncos-vs-panthers-ivan-cleary-on-scott-sorensen/105829092</link><description>Ivan Cleary says the NRL made a "huge call" in deciding to bench Scott Sorensen after a nasty head clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e1317d4d328348b5aa069d4adbf16b7</guid></item><item><title>Optus investigates outage that led to failed triple-0 calls in Dapto</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/optus-investigates-another-triple-0-outage-in-nsw/105829054</link><description>Embattled telco Optus has apologised for a network outage that led to nine failed triple-0 calls near Wollongong on the NSW south coast over the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80526d53f63f971d4e314371df58583e</guid></item><item><title>Children's author Pamela Allen's work showcased in interactive exhibition at State Library of NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/children-author-illustrator-pamela-allen-exhibition/105816018</link><description>At 91, Pamela Allen has published more than 60 books. This exhibition brings her work off the page and invites children and adults to play as they read.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79ba1502bd70c825488eecfa0f939e60</guid></item><item><title>National campaign against indicator flash as unofficial overtaking signal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/overtaking-signal-from-trucks-raises-road-safety-concerns/105818336</link><description>Road haulage industry leaders are planning a national campaign against using indicators as a signal it is safe to overtake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec43b17ffd8b7717cd672c6b62d5f594</guid></item><item><title>India defeats Pakistan with just two balls to spare in cricket's Asia Cup final, then refuse to claim trophy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/asia-cup-cricket-final-india-downs-pakistan-two-balls-to-spare/105829144</link><description>India defeats Pakistan with just two balls remaining in the Asia Cup final, then refuses to claim the trophy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afd15ee3ed653e96b920ce202b640afe</guid></item><item><title>Victorian emergency relief centres lose federal government funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/emergency-relief-centres-stripped-of-federal-funding-food-cost/105800534</link><description>The Victorian relief service that's fed those in need in the Wimmera for almost 30 years has had its funding slashed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd2acc303fc06e90a792d77f8816c216</guid></item><item><title>WA growers take precautions against mango twig tip dieback disease</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/wa-growers-protect-against-mango-twig-tip-dieback/105811470</link><description>Mango growers in Western Australia's far north are on alert as a mysterious dieback disease decimates crops in the Northern Territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f69d40f7595a9150097e2aeff4c5bcbf</guid></item><item><title>Sailors found with catamaran after extensive search off northern NSW coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/sailors-found-with-catamaran-northern-nsw-coast-search/105829282</link><description>Two men have been rescued with their catamaran after being adrift for two days following an engine failure off the northern NSW coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c26528fdc99ef4b49d09b3b785a9478</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder, attempted sexual assault after alleged attack at Manly West shopping centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/police-man-charged-murder-attempted-sexual-assault-manly-west/105829332</link><description>Police allege the man stabbed a 44-year-old at a suburban Brisbane shopping centre before attempting to sexually assault a woman not known to him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a72b0c1a6dc370e4bcea73c4376e042</guid></item><item><title>Vets warn dog owners as canine ehrlichiosis spreads across northern Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/canine-ehrlichiosis-endemic-spreads-across-northern-australia/105814976</link><description>The rapid spread of canine ehrlichiosis since it was first detected in Australia five years ago "has left a lot of destruction in its wake", a veterinarian says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8e6b345e66a66a94e042d799166c805</guid></item><item><title>The NRL grand final clash between Melbourne and Brisbane is the ultimate clash of footballing styles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/nrl-grand-final-broncos-storm-walsh-munster-clash/105828434</link><description>Neither Melbourne nor Brisbane is approaching perfection ahead of their grand final showdown, but with what they've been through, neither team would want to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">250624bcf063dfe15f4c8e75a31bcbb3</guid></item><item><title>Price of silver nearing record high – 29 September 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/price-of-silver-nearing-record-high/105829558</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f8635f3bfc49f0a01d8e88e8bee8bb0</guid></item><item><title>Death of woman found in Hobart Rivulet not being treated as suspicious</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/tas-hobart-rivulet-death-not-suspicious/105829452</link><description>Police provide an update after a review of CCTV, statements from witnesses, and the results of an autopsy after the discovery of a woman's body on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8d22e62d9408a5f662e881db1dae317</guid></item><item><title>Three people charged with murder of Jayden Selfe in Attadale after body found in bush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/three-people-charged-with-jayden-selfe-murder-in-attadale/105807500</link><description>Three people face a Perth court accused of murdering 33-year-old Jayden Selfe, whose disappearance sparked an extensive investigation and led to the discovery of his body north of the city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03cd3a0177766a1157e2a5340dfc2e15</guid></item><item><title>If you're looking to try out a career change, volunteering can give you a taste</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/volunteering-to-test-a-career-change/105788520</link><description>If you're considering a career change, or want a taste of a new industry, volunteering can be a great option.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8160f86239ba2807fc1b8d35ee83f8df</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says he will tell US military leaders 'we love them' after Pete Hegseth summoned them for a meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/donald-trump-pete-hegseth-us-military-meeting/105829802</link><description>The US president said he will tell military leaders "we love them, they're cherished leaders" during a meeting organised by Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a22fb4128e65a3c7a59aa5e8b1538f09</guid></item><item><title>Cycling great Tadej Pogačar rides away from the field to win men's road race world title in Rwanda</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/pogacar-pedals-to-another-epic-world-cycling-title/105829612</link><description>Tadej Pogačar makes more cycling history with another incredible win in the world championship road race on a brutally tough course in Rwanda.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee6b64a9670ca0fa0891eec61448a68d</guid></item><item><title>Humanity's space ambition to be focus of first Powerhouse Parramatta exhibition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/task-eternal-space-exhibition-to-launch-powerhouse-parramatta/105829116</link><description>Humanity's ambition to explore beyond Earth will feature in the largest exhibition space in the country when Powerhouse Parramatta opens in the city's west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54153ffe9059ead5c032efe725a8e9e6</guid></item><item><title>Rory McIlroy defends wife Erica after 'astonishing' abuse from American Ryder Cup fans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/rory-mcilroy-defends-wife-erica-ryder-cup-abuse/105829570</link><description>Rory McIlroy supports his wife Erica, who was said to be on the receiving end of "astonishing" abuse from American fans during the Ryder Cup in New York.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d7fcf1cc21d22ea7fea1b398e9a7f5f</guid></item><item><title>Investigation begins after Townsville urology patients not given test results, follow-up care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/queensland-health-investigating-townsville-hospital-urology/105829310</link><description>Queensland Health will investigate reports patients did not receive crucial test results from north Queensland's largest public hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">679a4510a52eef9f63713a62046fc045</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast nurse sentenced after stealing patient's bank card</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/gold-coast-nurse-sentenced-for-stealing-from-coma-patient/105829196</link><description>Melelani Crelley was handed 12 months' probation after pleading guilty to fraud and stealing charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6596f48de954220a58ee54eaeea61f27</guid></item><item><title>Bad Bunny to headline Super Bowl Halftime show in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/bad-bunny-to-headline-super-bowl-halftime-show/105830316</link><description>Grammy-winning rapper Bad Bunny is set to headline the Super Bowl half-time show in Northern California next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2ce8791ba83bbac9fb185eb51568e24</guid></item><item><title>Tufi Junior Tauese-Auelua jailed for five years over firebombing of Jordan Shanks' Bondi home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/man-jailed-for-five-years-over-bondi-friendlyjordies-arson/105830364</link><description>Described as "a little boy in a very large body", the man who lit the blaze at the home of the YouTube comedian in 2022 apologised and said he would "rather die" than go back to jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1f43ca56edac53669d0466e7605132d</guid></item><item><title>When is the 2025 NRL grand final? Here's how to watch and everything you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/when-are-the-2025-nrl-and-nrlw-grand-finals/105829220</link><description>The NRL and NRLW grand final teams have been finalised and are getting ready to face-off this weekend. Here's what you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83aee82f83ac81d24eb24f5d884f94e4</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm prop Stefano Utoikamanu labels Brisbane Broncos 'stuck up', Xavier Willison free to play NRL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/nrl-grand-final-melbourne-storm-brisbane-broncos-utoikamanu/105830590</link><description>Melbourne prop Stefano Utoikamanu lights the fuse for an explosive NRL grand final on Sunday, setting his sights on steamrolling "stuck-up" Brisbane opponents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">249ff19ee68f44495059a0506aca76e8</guid></item><item><title>Leisl Smith was killed by James Scott Church, NSW coroner finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/leisl-smith-was-killed-by-james-scott-church-nsw-coroner-finds/105829214</link><description>James Scott Church stood trial in 2022 for the 23-year-old's murder, but died before the verdict was handed down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd37a90df155e5c65bf3557ad54c99f0</guid></item><item><title>Four teenage boys arrested after car chase through Melbourne, pedestrian struck</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/bourke-street-mall-incident-police-pursuit-arrests/105830762</link><description>Police say they've arrested four teenage boys in Melbourne's CBD after chasing them from Doncaster in the city's east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27fa99b6c4ee07d50b1279a05aaad213</guid></item><item><title>Unregulated melatonin products had as much as four times the amount on label, TGA testing shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/tga-safety-concerns-over-melatonin-products/105829782</link><description>The TGA has urged patients to stop using unregulated melatonin products after testing revealed “significant discrepancies” between their actual melatonin amount and what was on the label.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">198d5ab8d2ff8a6e72cbefeb3197ef3e</guid></item><item><title>Death of Port River dolphin prompts calls for stricter boat regulations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/dolphin-death-port-river-sa/105830462</link><description>The "completely preventable" death of a three-year-old dolphin in Adelaide's Port River has prompted new calls for mandatory propeller guards on boats entering the sanctuary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0e18338b2ebf52c030f58a93d721358</guid></item><item><title>Stephen Fleming showed 'grave disrespect' by dumping Annette Brennan's body in bin, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/stephen-fleming-attends-presentence-annette-brennan-manslaughter/105829658</link><description>47-year-old Stephen Fleming, who has pleaded guilty to manslaughter, is accused of ending his new housemate's life last year and stuffing the English teacher's body in a green waste bin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6ea60a644a0a4b2d7360bcaa738d131</guid></item><item><title>National Police Remembrance Day services around Australia pay tribute to fallen officers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/national-police-remembrance-day-services-fallen-officers/105829560</link><description>Three police officers shot dead in the line of duty this year are being honoured as part of National Police Remembrance Day services around Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed20ce542bf062e17fcc30aac01c761c</guid></item><item><title>NRL players, including Brisbane Broncos star Payne Haas, spruik crime-linked fashion line R4W Active</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/nrl-player-payne-haas-fronts-crime-linked-activewear-line-r4w/105828100</link><description>The grand final-bound Origin prop and at least three other NRL players are promoting a clothing brand linked to the Alameddine crime family, fuelling police concern the league has failed to stem the influence of organised crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">013c5a6b057a382fbbed566420a9e84e</guid></item><item><title>Kylie Soanes is an urban ecologist on a mission to prove nature belongs in our cities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/kylie-soanes-urban-nature-conservation-biodiversity/105315332</link><description>Kylie Soanes says urban development should not come at the expense of nature and there's no reason why we should not spot a fairy wren on the way to the bus stop.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a914d2f5b0b9608997ecde0a91c37166</guid></item><item><title>How can we better prepare tourists at Cradle Mountain?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/how-we-can-better-prepare-tourists-for-cradle-mountain-hike/105829334</link><description>Cradle Mountain is one of Tasmania's most popular, and dangerous, tourism destinations. After another tragedy, questions are asked about what more could be done to ensure the safety of visitors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">302f535a72c3b49b49e79a02ae4d6fa9</guid></item><item><title>Larrimah Hotel sold for the second time since Paddy Moriarty's disappearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/larrimah-hotel-sold-again-after-dissappearance-of-paddy-moriarty/105829656</link><description>The Larrimah Hotel is sold again, after capturing the world's attention in podcasts and films about the disappearance of 70-year-old Paddy Moriarty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8b4b29d6e72a4b3c4bb0089716d141b</guid></item><item><title>Youth advocate calls for balance amid knife crackdown, police conduct 1,600 searches at Burnside</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/knife-searches-impact-on-young-people/105830924</link><description>SA Police conducted more than 1,600 metal detector searches at Burnside Village at the weekend, but the state's Guardian for Children and Young People says officials need to "get the balance right" amid a crackdown on knife crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9f06b963a51e8f4f3e76dcb45ce8003</guid></item><item><title>India claim they were denied Asia Cup trophy after win over Pakistan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/india-claims-they-were-denied-asia-cup-trophy-pakistan/105831210</link><description>India T20 skipper Suryakumar Yadav has claimed that his team was denied the chance to lift the 2025 Asia Cup trophy, after it beat Pakistan in the final by five wickets on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b678c1b2c791864e5d3679a316fcc0a</guid></item><item><title>Lismore looks to the future as flood buyback suburbs empty out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/lismore-urban-planning-house-buybacks-2022-flood-recovery/105799094</link><description>A rainforest minutes from the CBD, a food production bowl and riverside walkways are among the big ideas being discussed for Lismore as it continues to recover from the 2022 floods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e184fdd9b89341c132ef1ee0efbbec26</guid></item><item><title>Pedestrians describe police pursuit through Melbourne CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/pedestrians-describe-police-pursuit-through/105831362</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0a998c0e2ce0213e6810d874598dc2e</guid></item><item><title>Queensland coroner to examine cause of fatal house fire in 2017 which killed young boy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/qld-coroner-examining-house-fire/105830424</link><description>In 2017 two boys and their father, who cannot be identified for legal reasons, were badly burnt when their rural property went up in flames.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2004e51fb1f2a324af6cd702585106c</guid></item><item><title>WIM Resource mining employee charged with falsifying document</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/wim-resource-mining-employee-charged-with-falsifying-document/105675812</link><description>Suspended mining company employee Murray Wilson will fight a falsifying documents charge relating to a proposed mineral sands project in north-west Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67b2824f9ffca102ddc3d97dced78d13</guid></item><item><title>Body scanner to be used in ACT courts after significantly reducing prison strip searches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/act-electronic-scanner-expansion-reduce-strip-searches-jail/105830654</link><description>The ACT government will expand the use of electronic body scanners to the courts after their use in Canberra's only prison saw a dramatic drop in the need to strip search prisoners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8593aef0310bd16a46c4fdad86864527</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with performing Nazi salute at the AFL facing two new counts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/nazi-salute-charge-afl-semifinal-gabba-court/105829908</link><description>Tylere Baker-Pearce, 39, was arrested by counterterrorism police outside a Brisbane court on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87fbc67c3b22851008dd4e5af9765dac</guid></item><item><title>At least 13 dead after Typhoon Bualoi makes landfall in Vietnam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/apn-bualoi-vietnam-landfall/105831514</link><description>At least 13 people have died after heavy rain and strong winds from the former Typhoon Bualoi flooded roads, knocked off roofs in central Vietnam, state media reported, with residents describing it as "one of the strongest".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a633befcd32cf7b9b0648dcd1307f2e</guid></item><item><title>Climate change is hitting the Northern Territory harder than most places in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/climate-change-is-hitting-the-northern-territory/105831790</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">100fae9c1f74752eff6db46423f457d5</guid></item><item><title>Man found guilty of murder, two others of manslaughter in David Jenkins trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/verdict-murder-trial-of-david-wayne-jenkins/105816040</link><description>Luke Anthony Shaw, Paul William Shaw and Patrick Kenneth Dolbey were charged with the murder of David Wayne Jenkins, who was stabbed 11 times in October 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f07e01556336f49bccd6423c4f8448c</guid></item><item><title>Noemie Fox leads Aussies to kick off ICF Slalom World Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/noemie-fox-leads-aussies-to-kick-off-slalom-world-titles/105832024</link><description>Noemie Fox has just missed out on a dream start to the ICF Slalom World Championships, finishing fifth in the kayak cross time trials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e3ac00f6bdb3a68d08e0c2eb45d1592</guid></item><item><title>Crime scene declared after two people found dead at Kenmore Hills property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/qld-kenmore-death-two-people-police-investigate/105832174</link><description>A crime scene has been declared at Kenmore Hills after two people were found dead at a property just after midday on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a78aeb9b8f7383f34948d1082844dd37</guid></item><item><title>Will Ashcroft named best AFL finals player to win Gary Ayres Award to add to Brisbane Lions accolades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/will-ashcroft-named-best-afl-finals-player-brisbane-lions/105832244</link><description>Brisbane Lions midfield star Will Ashcroft has added the AFL coaches' award for player of the finals to his growing list of accolades in the wake of his team's 47-point victory over the Geelong Cats on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">468af182ae004fc8c704109b4dcae10a</guid></item><item><title>James Tedesco is named best NRL player by his peers for the fourth time despite Roosters falling short in NRL finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/james-tedesco-is-named-best-nrl-player-by-his-peers/105832318</link><description>The 32-year-old fullback joins Johnathan Thurston as the only four-time winner of the players' champion award, after the Sydney Roosters star was voted the NRL's best player of 2025 by his peers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1edf57f7450acb2b1112ffb830a7d4c</guid></item><item><title>Albanese invites Emirati retail giant Lulu Hypermarket to take on Coles and Woolworths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/albanese-invites-lulu-hypermarket-to-take-on-coles-woolworths/105832238</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has invited Emirati 'hypermarket' chain LuLu Group to set up shop on Australia's shores and take on supermarket giants Coles and Woolworths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dff2e97321eaa2a6005ab80c58f514cb</guid></item><item><title>Caboolture Hospital to review medical scans amid concerns about outpatient service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/caboolture-hospital-patient-scan-review-metro-north-health/105831662</link><description>A clinical team is reviewing the medical imaging results of up to 9,000 patients at Caboolture Hospital amid concerns about how results were communicated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce29051247b7daa71dd24ef941f4d60b</guid></item><item><title>Monday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105832402</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e0efb10200a7cc4ba119bbef3e530ea</guid></item><item><title>Rick Morton's book about Robodebt, Mean Streak, among Prime Minister's Literary Award winners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/prime-ministers-literary-awards-rick-morton-mean-streak-robodebt/105808038</link><description>Journalist Rick Morton didn't want to write a book about Robodebt. Now that book, Mean Streak, has won the Prime Minister's Literary Award for non-fiction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5222686c405207b893f11605f1d249b6</guid></item><item><title>Federal budget deficit lower than forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/federal-budget-deficit-lower-than-forecast/105832494</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">137940a3e5122e9dd450ce55f08c2843</guid></item><item><title>Four teens arrested in Melbourne CBD after police pursuit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/four-teens-arrested-in-melbourne-cbd-after-police/105831944</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2236776dd2f4af63672264e89460c03c</guid></item><item><title>US to impose 100pc tariff on movies made outside the country, Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/us-to-impose-100-tariff-on-movies-made-outside-the-country/105832688</link><description>US President Donald Trump initially threatened to impose such levies earlier in May but offered few details, leading to confusion among entertainment industry executives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c6b83ec49a52515805a0e1a9b788860</guid></item><item><title>Private equity consortium offers to buy Electronic Arts for $80 billion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/consortium-buys-electronic-arts-for-55-billion-dollars/105832746</link><description>A consortium of private equity companies, including one backed by Donald Trump's son-in-law, Jared Kushner, is offering to take the video game giant private.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a06eae9e8baf8c4fc089531baf0884ed</guid></item><item><title>Inside Iran, a paranoid regime hunts for traitors and spies after its war with Israel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/iran-hunts-spies-and-traitors-after-israeli-spy-infiltration/105822466</link><description>For 12 days in June, the world watched as Iran and Israel traded blows. What came next was a brutal purge of spies and traitors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bd8ed2cd2c6a2db151383f80c45b3bf</guid></item><item><title>Will the Reserve Bank cut interest rates today? Only if hell freezes over</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/reserve-bank-set-to-keep-interest-rates-on-hold-at-sept-meeting/105830776</link><description>With markets pricing next to no chance of an interest rate cut today, what are the chances of another RBA move before year's end?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7391188e4fe7f994864ec7dc5831b5d4</guid></item><item><title>What could Thriving Kids, the NDIS alternative for some children, look like?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/thriving-kids-autism-developmental-delay-design/105793852</link><description>Despite the government wanting its Thriving Kids program for children with "mild to moderate" developmental delay and autism to start next year, the system is yet to be designed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11b6c263c5db7a26886a74772271eb7d</guid></item><item><title>Benjamin Netanyahu agrees to Donald Trump's 20-point Gaza peace plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/israel-gaza-peace-plan-white-house-announcement/105832816</link><description>Israel has agreed to a US proposal to end its war on Gaza, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and US President Donald Trump announce after holding talks at the White House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7a1f4e181a9cb0ff116cb25c804daf0</guid></item><item><title>Clock is ticking for Optus boss as triple-0 disaster escalates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/optus-triple-zero-disaster-means-clock-ticking-for-ceo-rue/105832282</link><description>Analysts say the Optus CEO should "leave quietly" now or risk a more public exit once the reviews into the company's recent outages are complete.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d065263a83281a11837869d86cf3d983</guid></item><item><title>Consultancy bill to review 'struggling' submarine agency blows out to $12.1 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/submarine-agency-consultant-review-blows-out-aukus/105831752</link><description>The agency responsible for delivering AUKUS has spent five times what it first planned for consultants to review its operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf24c34870572f0d84606c9ed22dfb92</guid></item><item><title>Pro-EU party wins majority in Moldova election in setback for Russia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/pro-eu-party-wins-majority-in-moldova-election/105832904</link><description>Moscow is accused of attempting to sway the election in favour of a pro-Russian party, but a majority of voters backed the pro-EU Party of Action and Solidarity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96ceb7f4e8448574865973b7d1624d57</guid></item><item><title>Calvary St Luke's Hospital surgeries transferred after micro tears found in the floor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/calvary-st-lukes-hospital-micro-tears-in-floor-launceston/105832280</link><description>The shutdown of Calvary St Luke's Hospital will affect 40 planned surgeries this week, with 22 of those reallocated to nearby St Vincent's Hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e5a2a76e795eadb0cfe0ed7e9a6adce</guid></item><item><title>Tom Ballard's new show searches for the line between funny and offensive while pushing the comedy envelope</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/tom-ballard-jks-a-comedy-melbourne-fringe-festival/105829986</link><description>Comedian Tom Ballard is swapping a stand-up stage for a dramatic one as his new stage show asks, how do you remember a divisive figure?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8deace55743245b36e5fd8f6ad090d8</guid></item><item><title>Hawthorn Hawks AFLW lose Emily Bates to injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/hawthorn-hawks-aflw-lose-emily-bates-to-injury/105832440</link><description>Top-four aspirants Hawthorn are set to lose Emily Bates for the run towards the finals after the star midfielder suffered a shoulder injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c55507c927534eed7b21f75ffeef1b11</guid></item><item><title>Robot for lunar and Earth construction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/robot-for-lunar-and-earth-construction/105831312</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c57ebbbeb8787aacaa657e1323defd81</guid></item><item><title>Australian homes could soon be built by spider-like robot called Charlotte</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/robot-backed-nsw-government-could-be-used-to-build-homes/105831202</link><description>Developers of a speedy, "spider-like" robot named Charlotte believe it could be building homes on Earth within years, and eventually further lunar exploration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da44e9233a44c61287572d5db4f5cb5c</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government writes off up to $4 million worth of COVID-19 fines years after they were issued</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/queensland-government-writes-off-covid-fines/105829608</link><description>The government has confirmed Queensland's state-run debt collection agency has now "finalised" all debts related to COVID fines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6041290208a40933a25acd204d0f629</guid></item><item><title>Teenage boys charged over car chase through Melbourne into Bourke Street Mall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/police-charges-four-teenage-boys-car-chase-bourke-street-mall/105831884</link><description>Police have charged two 16 and 17-year-old boys in relation to a dangerous incident involving an allegedly stolen car being driven into the pedestrian-only Bourke Street Mall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">877d9e2a6596c8c24ed8504b113ca23c</guid></item><item><title>Trump outlines plan for 'eternal peace' in the Middle East</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/trump-outlines-plan-for-eternal-peace-in-the/105833154</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bab01e7f8c95e0f3cf16e28f3d96238b</guid></item><item><title>'Huge change' to Australia's health system as registered nurses set to prescribe medication</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/registered-nurses-prescribing-medicine/105831424</link><description>Qualified registered nurses will soon be able to write prescriptions for medications, in a bid to ease pressure on a stressed public healthcare system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">964c1de9e42f333dca6628564d4d8ca1</guid></item><item><title>First Nations Australians launch class action against Work for the Dole scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/indigenous-class-action-against-commonwealth-work-for-the-dole/105831704</link><description>A class action on behalf of Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander people alleges a Commonwealth Work for the Dole scheme was tougher on remote participants than on jobseekers in cities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5362bf7775d5763f4aee198270866f7b</guid></item><item><title>Looming crisis for older Australian women who will retire into poverty if no urgent action taken, new report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/super-crisis-for-women-who-retire-in-poverty-new-report-says/105830680</link><description>Women's super balances are disproportionately impacted by events later in life, in addition to childcare duties, which could mean serious financial problems, research from Super Members Council (SMC) has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f10e93e0fbfcfdb37654ad8d0c08828</guid></item><item><title>Rescue founders outraged as kitten Pierre dumped within hours of adoption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/adopted-cat-pierre-dumped-owners-urged-to-desex-pets/105832316</link><description>Just 12 hours after he was adopted, eight-month-old kitten Pierre was found in his carrier in the middle of the road, drenched after an overnight storm. Rescuers are urging owners to de-sex their cats, to help prevent other animals from enduring a similar ordeal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03bfb1c1b88e01087bd8ae2e9cb3bd22</guid></item><item><title>Federal environment minister knew of rock art fears before granting Woodside North West Shelf extension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/murray-watt-murujuga-rock-art-woodside-extension/105831128</link><description>The federal environment minister was advised pollution from Woodside's Karratha Gas Plant may be causing irreversible changes to ancient rock art, before granting the company a 40-year extension with strict conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fe1024f68585a39e20b2ea2ecd5747f</guid></item><item><title>Will Skelton to return for Wallabies against All Blacks in second Bledisloe Cup Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/will-skelton-to-return-for-wallabies-against-all-blacks/105832340</link><description>Lock Will Skelton is set to return for the Wallabies ahead of the final round of the Rugby Championship against the All Blacks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8f1ba1dc3e0cf1c5ce16e0e8a5b29b9</guid></item><item><title>Alice the dachshund saved after becoming stuck down rabbit hole for six hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/dachshund-stuck-in-rabbit-hole-in-yulara-nt-saved-by-locals/105829968</link><description>A dachshund named Alice, who found herself stuck down a rabbit hole under a demountable building in Central Australia, has been rescued after a six-hour effort by a group of locals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5e05f6d6901f912afd78b40cad188e2</guid></item><item><title>Matthew McConaughey and America Ferrera highlight the unsung heroes of deadly wildfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/matthew-mcconaughey-and-america-ferrera-highlight/105833216</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be50194906b0a14a438bba5eb62e681b</guid></item><item><title>Agnes Water hospital plans in limbo as council rejects development approval extension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/qld-council-rejects-development-approval-extension-for-hospital/105777972</link><description>Hundreds of homes targeting the over-50s market are in staged construction on Queensland's central coast, but a council will not grant an extension for hospital plans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d62736af3ea526b34da4abe8d2252a1d</guid></item><item><title>Netanyahu vows to 'finish the job' if Hamas rejects Trump's peace plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/netanyahu-vows-to-finish-the-job-if-hamas-rejects-plan/105833264</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94e5510b2dce9573bb53005beef3f369</guid></item><item><title>Search continues for missing four-year-old boy Gus on property near Yunta</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/search-for-missing-boy-gus-at-yunta-grazing-property/105831280</link><description>Police are continuing to search for a four-year-old boy who vanished while playing in sand at his family's isolated sheep grazing property near Yunta in a remote part of South Australia's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78db8ffd422d6e1038415dd9ead44e8e</guid></item><item><title>Detectives release CCTV of car being set alight in Burwood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/detectives-release-cctv-of-car-being-set-alight/105833294</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">317101cd6370b69800b401ad07c63d9a</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: Albanese urges 'all parties' to engage with Trump's Gaza plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/federal-politics-live-blog-september-30/105830872</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese welcomes US President Donald Trump's proposal to end Israel's war on Gaza. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24852d6afe8469b05fdca4276f04c928</guid></item><item><title>What is Donald Trump's peace plan for Gaza?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/what-is-donald-trump-peace-plan-for-gaza/105832748</link><description>US President Donald Trump has pitched a 20-point peace plan for Gaza, after meeting with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35d5e8dbb083b3be541952e63f593457</guid></item><item><title>Mitch Brown hits out at Bailey Smith and Patrick Dangerfield over 'homophobic' social media post from Geelong Mad Monday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/geelong-cats-mad-monday-mitch-brown-hits-out-at-smith/105833250</link><description>Mitch Brown, the first AFL player to reveal he is bisexual, hits out at Bailey Smith and Patrick Dangerfield over a social media post from Mad Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33be92e1e52ee7e5f5e0402c86508d43</guid></item><item><title>Moorambilla Voices choir</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/moorambilla-voices-choir/105818062</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">add312269c80e50e7e2da25cc3b21755</guid></item><item><title>Moorambilla Voices bush choir marks 20 years as former student credits it with saving his life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/moorambilla-voices-bush-choir-celebrates-20th-anniversary/105816166</link><description>Justin Welsh says joining the Moorambilla Voices children's choir helped steer him away from the challenges that face many young men in small country towns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae8aa2b2778f105a3563ecc9408d680e</guid></item><item><title>Australian-made Apollo laser shoots down drone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/australian-made-apollo-laser-shoots-down-drone/105811390</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b2b284b1823eb3fa62389df2cfb9f88</guid></item><item><title>NATO embraces new Australian-made Star Wars-style lasers to counter Russian drones</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/australian-lasers-nato-russian-drones/105810770</link><description>A Canberra-made laser is about to become NATO's newest frontline defence against enemy drones, in a deal experts say could transform the future of warfare.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f0ce2e04baff0097dd262685aac7932</guid></item><item><title>RBA live updates: Reserve Bank keeps interest rates on hold but potential future moves closely watched</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/rba-interest-rates-asx-markets-business-live-news-29-sept/105831264</link><description>The RBA keeps the cash rate steady, with all eyes now turning to the final two meetings of the year. Follow the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1586079bce949bf1d6b30c9934c9d44f</guid></item><item><title>Green carab beetles release tear gas smell in Geraldton while escaping heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/green-carab-beetle-stinks-up-geraldton/105822588</link><description>Often mistaken for a stink bug or Christmas beetle, this iridescent insect has descended on Geraldton with a tear gas-like odour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">045c1f089ddea8fd1940801a7784e8c2</guid></item><item><title>Taliban imposes communication shutdown in Afghanistan after severing fibre optic connections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/afghanistan-taliban-imposes-communication-shutdown/105833300</link><description>Taliban authorities in Afghanistan have imposed a nationwide shutdown of communications, weeks after they began severing fibre optic connections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa47ca3794742304b50f8bf884b4e0e8</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's former top bureaucrat Mike Kaiser paid almost $400,000 in 'termination benefits'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/queensland-bureaucrats-paid-termination-benefits/105833188</link><description>New figures released in the department's annual report reveal Mike Kaiser was paid "termination benefits" of $397,000 in the last financial year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72a252e53dbc318d862278629afc8c7b</guid></item><item><title>YouTube to pay Trump $33.46m following January 6 Capitol riots ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/youtube-settles-with-donald-trump-in-capitol-riot-ban/105833406</link><description>Donald Trump sued parent company Alphabet and other social media companies after the platforms suspended his accounts in 2021.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d1bb644c6003414da83fd1b747251c4</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar's President Andry Rajoelina dissolves government following deadly youth-led protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/madagascan-government-dissolved/105833316</link><description>Youth-led protests over water and power cuts in Madagascar lasted three days and were the largest the island had seen in years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed2c399b5e24fe8142e7b45a076967f0</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police release CCTV footage of drive-by shooting at Sydney home linked to drug dealers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/nsw-police-release-cctv-footage-of-concord-home-shooting/105833244</link><description>Police have released footage showing the moment a gunman fired on a suburban Sydney home in July, with investigations into the matter continuing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da2cab533c5c372fbeddaafb964aeb66</guid></item><item><title>A tip cat and a depot duck become invaluable workmates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/tip-cat-depot-duck-animals-pets-at-work-boost-morale/105808500</link><description>A playful tabby kitten and a ravenous Muscovy duck routinely amuse council staff in their respective workplaces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">215a6d7409ee4f682c0e24316a009438</guid></item><item><title>Broncos second-rower Jordan Riki opens up about his quest for redemption in the 2025 NRL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/nrl-grand-final-2025-jordan-riki-seeks-nrl-redemption/105833446</link><description>After suffering a heartbreaking loss in the 2023 NRL grand final, Jordan Riki says redemption is fuelling Brisbane's journey to the 2025 title.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">096b8067c54230c1c72019b7bba59ada</guid></item><item><title>Advocate calls out Kimberley's 'astronomical' fruit and vegetable prices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/fruit-and-vegetable-prices-remain-high-in-kimberley/105749056</link><description>The cost-of-living crisis means fresh produce is more expensive for all Australians, but residents in some remote WA towns are paying up to triple for some items compared to city prices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3ba3304ab4fe137c5b06a174ba68886</guid></item><item><title>Alcoa confirms permanent shutdown of Kwinana alumina refinery, south of Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/alcoa-announces-permanent-closure-of-kwinana-aluminium-refinery/105833688</link><description>US aluminium giant Alcoa says there is no "sustainable" path to restarting its aluminium refinery in Perth after phasing out production at the facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff0a486a49f7c9c30fd13173b631f2cc</guid></item><item><title>Southern Cross Media and Seven West Media announce merger, Kerry Stokes to step down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/southern-cross-austereo-and-seven-west-media-merge/105833848</link><description>Media magnate Kerry Stokes will stand down as chair of Seven West Media after the company announced plans to merge with Southern Cross Media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f614c97b8fbac30496e1c32a4483ab96</guid></item><item><title>Man's body found after fire destroys East Lismore house in northern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/man-dies-in-east-lismore-house-fire-northern-nsw/105833494</link><description>A man has died in a house fire that caused a structural collapse in East Lismore, NSW. Investigators are trying to determine the cause of the blaze.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d20cc362c1421d955acbbdd11c23b244</guid></item><item><title>Glenn Maxwell out of NZ T20 International series after breaking arm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/australias-glenn-maxwell-out-of-nz-t20-series-with-broken-arm/105833900</link><description>A brutal run of injuries continues for one of Australia's top white-ball cricketers, who is out of the T20 series against New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31c6d853231af79177e49fef323ce41b</guid></item><item><title>Kane Cornes labels Geelong's Mad Monday antics 'disrespectful' and 'embarrassing'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/afl-community-react-to-geelongs-disrespectful-mad-monday/105834040</link><description>Kane Cornes labels Geelong's Mad Monday antics "disrespectful" and "embarrassing", after a slew of social media posts raises eyebrows across the AFL community, including one referencing his Seven colleague Caroline Wilson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e256b45f537f9f1f094c29befffe0edf</guid></item><item><title>Female teacher accused of abusing Sydney boys' school student</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/nsw-sydney-teacher-charges-with-sexual-abuse/105833822</link><description>Police will allege the 24-year-old engaged in an "inappropriate relationship" with a 15-year-old boy in her care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44f3c3d1d41304adddf9dd3d5bfb8bd7</guid></item><item><title>Trump's peace plan shows Netanyahu has outmanoeuvred yet another American president</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/netanyahu-has-outmanoeuvred-yet-another-american-president/105833774</link><description>For all US President Donald Trump's boasts about ending wars and being a worthy candidate for a Nobel Peace Prize, he has failed to end the war in Gaza and build a sustainable future for both Israelis and Palestinians. At least for now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e4ef8c9191cf6f9517189aeae2286b1</guid></item><item><title>Police charge nine people over violent robberies in south-east Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/gympie-police-charge-nine-people-with-114-offences-armed-robbery/105833914</link><description>Detectives lay more than 100 charges following investigations into a series of alleged shootings, burglaries and violent robberies across south-east Queensland since July.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28e7c4f3b0770bb852df6b0b1eebc05c</guid></item><item><title>Why Bad Bunny is a controversial choice to headline Super Bowl half-time show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/why-bad-bunny-is-a-controversial-choice-for-super-bowl/105834094</link><description>Grammy-award winning rapper and singer Bad Bunny receives mixed reactions to the news he will headline the 2026 Super Bowl half-time show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f773b39eed99469859ef72baf7b22b5</guid></item><item><title>Police investigating deaths of mother and daughter at Kenmore Hills house listed on Airbnb</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/qld-police-investigating-death-mother-and-daughter-kenmore-hills/105833308</link><description>Police are investigating the sudden deaths of a mother and daughter whose bodies were found at a property in Kenmore Hills in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdb2e63bd212d8534f0611786f4dc53c</guid></item><item><title>Government instructs Optus to bring in 'external party' to review systems</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/optus-anika-wells-meet-about-triple-0-outages/105833276</link><description>Communications Minister Anika Wells has instructed Optus to bring in an "independent and external party" during a meeting with the heads of the embattled telco and its Singaporean parent company, Singtel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffa091d24bdee9c5e49daa67768fabb7</guid></item><item><title>James Tedesco pulls out of Kangaroos selection for Ashes to be best man at brother's wedding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/james-tedesco-pulls-out-of-kangaroos-selection-for-ashes/105834776</link><description>Former Kangaroos captain James Tedesco has informed the Australian Rugby League that he will not be available for the upcoming Ashes series in England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6b6d926d657bec8f2eec549072bfb50</guid></item><item><title>James Turner wins first gold medal for Australia at World Para Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/james-turner-gold-medal-world-para-athletics-championships/105834992</link><description>Paralympic champion James Turner wins Australia's first gold medal of the World Para Athletics Championships, saluting in the 400m T36 event in Delhi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8961ceea19af23e6792dc83d35ce6d61</guid></item><item><title>NSW government loses music festival strip search case as woman awarded $93,000 in damages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/nsw-government-loses-landmark-police-strip-search-festival-case/105833654</link><description>A Sydney woman subjected to an unlawful strip search at a music festival has been awarded $93,000 in damages, in a judgement that could see thousands of others also receive compensation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8731061ec317f2a8c3879d4163384bc7</guid></item><item><title>Lily Ridgeway found not guilty of Raymond Terrace manslaughter of Jason Adams</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/lily-ridgeway-not-guilty-manslaughter-jason-adams/105820526</link><description>Lily Ridgeway, 27, has been found not guilty of manslaughter over the 2020 death of Jason Adams in the NSW Hunter Valley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12bbe9e6705ff5c489b0b9f36a66e077</guid></item><item><title>How Brisbane's culture of empowerment has allowed its youngsters to be fearless on the AFL's biggest stage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/afl-brisbane-lions-empowerment-youngsters-grand-final/105833746</link><description>Brisbane's youngest players rise to the occasion on the biggest stage, led by its 21-year-old Norm Smith medallist Will Ashcroft. Here's how the two-time premiers allow their kids to thrive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c817f23b0eba7b31b09a29d4859ec37</guid></item><item><title>Donald Day Jr, US conspiracy theorist connected to Wieambilla killers, agrees to watered-down plea deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/donald-day-jr-wieambilla-attack-plea-deal-conspiracy-theorist/105833978</link><description>Donald Day Jr had been in regular online contact with Gareth, Nathaniel and Stacey Train before they shot two police officers and a neighbour in December 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb497afdc963221378344678fdc78218</guid></item><item><title>New Spirit of Tasmania vessels need hull upgrades in case of 'extreme' weather, TT-Line says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/tas-spirit-of-tasmania-hull-upgrade-needed/105833990</link><description>The new Bass Strait ferries have both been completed but new works are needed after an issue with the vessels' hull specifications was detected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49e5e91f617d0c86340eb3fb5eedbd93</guid></item><item><title>Werribee man found not guilty of deliberately setting neighbour on fire over loud music dispute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/michael-gauci-not-guilty-setting-fire-to-werribee-neighbour/105835026</link><description>Michael Gauci, who was accused of setting a neighbour on fire after arguing over loud music, has been found not guilty of attempted murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40b7d260b7a3655bcb8b930cd3700648</guid></item><item><title>RBA leaves interest rates on hold in September</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/rba-leaves-interest-rates-on-hold-in-september/105835342</link><description>The Reserve Bank leaves interest rates on hold at 3.6 per cent, having cut them at its previous meeting in August.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb931fecca858bfc78f61f8553caa441</guid></item><item><title>Calls for investigation after thousands of scans may not have been reviewed by doctors at Caboolture Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/qld-caboolture-hospital-thousands-scans-not-reviewed-review/105834958</link><description>Queensland's premier has called for an independent investigation into the problem, affecting up to 9,000 patients at Caboolture Hospital dating back to April 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e660e5b728d6683b4b992947bd86277c</guid></item></channel></rss>