<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 13:58:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>State government urged to reject Comiskey Group's Coochin Fields music festival site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/qld-regs-coalition-opposes-coochin-creek-development/105875640</link><description>A coalition of Sunshine Coast community groups is calling on the state government to scrap a major music festival development because of ecological concerns raised by the State Assessment and Referrals Agency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0539c64bdbb5c4af23a9fcf63d332535</guid></item><item><title>Elderly man hit by truck at Canberra tip dies later in hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/canberra-man-killed-by-truck-at-tip-dies-later-in-hospital/105878718</link><description>ACT police say the man was hit by the truck and knocked into the rubbish collection area, suffering fatal injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfe3c4d1dbf5c5d5304e88fc5f3650ba</guid></item><item><title>Protecting rock art from wasp nests in Central Australia's Trephina Gorge with chopsticks and brushes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/rock-art-cleaning-at-trephina-gorge/105867252</link><description>Rock art has significant cultural importance to traditional owners, and is a highlight for visitors who make the hike to see it. These Ltyentye Apurte Rangers are working to help keep them protected from wasp nests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e32adeeb4bd3293608b4c2b5f2f9468a</guid></item><item><title>FBI 'seizes and destroys' website linked to hackers threatening to release Qantas customers' data</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/article-qantas-data-breach-website-seizure/105879120</link><description>The seizure comes less than 24 hours before a deadline set by the hackers for around 40 global firms to pay a ransom to prevent the release of sensitive information is due to end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a8c7ec78afba1c7dcd39ff71f28b500</guid></item><item><title>Hoop pine may set record as Australia's tallest rainforest tree</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/hoop-pine-discovery-might-be-tallest-rainforest-tree/105876058</link><description>Researchers mapping millions of trees as part of a climate change study think they have found Australia's tallest rainforest tree.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5b9000e787551f9b2e1e6206dd33c0d</guid></item><item><title>Coalition frontbencher tries to reframe immigration policy debate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/paul-scarr-reframes-immigration-policy-debate/105878470</link><description>Shadow Immigration Minister Paul Scarr has called for a "measured and considered" debate over migration levels after incendiary comments by members of the party's right flank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">009be0aa615f933c89b4f08de8b7d5ef</guid></item><item><title>SA government 'cautiously optimistic' about toxic algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/sa-government-cautiously-optimistic-about-toxic-algal-bloom-/105879314</link><description>SA government officials say there are some positive signs around the toxic algal bloom crisis as it continues to affect the state's metropolitan beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff7f4f2252b7d9c923a41ed25ffcc4d9</guid></item><item><title>Latest finance news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/latest-finance-news/105879480</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83b3f6cc6c027d4ba22acdae17f46292</guid></item><item><title>Western Bulldogs extend Essendon's losing streak with 57 point thrashing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/western-bulldogs-thrash-essendon/105879214</link><description>The Western Bulldogs have kept their faint AFLW finals hopes alive with a commanding 57 point drubbing of Essendon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac92bfe6e1f2c52e8561d9563d00cbb4</guid></item><item><title>International Criminal Court rejects Rodrigo Duterte's bid for release from detention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/icc-rejects-rodrigo-duterte-bid-to-be-released-from-detention/105879846</link><description>Former Philippine President Rodrigo Duterte must remain behind bars while awaiting trial, judges at the ICC have ruled, saying he might use his freedom to interfere with the legal process and suggesting he was a flight risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ec05a77bae27bbba4cacc40494c16dd</guid></item><item><title>Liberals find brief lull in internal hostilities for a passable week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/coalition-andrew-hastie-tony-pasin-anika-wells-chris-bowen/105858494</link><description>If there was some internal call within the Liberals to show some discipline after the last few weeks, it worked at a basic level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98db697ba6641fa4f18bac1f61add805</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump to impose new 100 per cent tariffs on China after Beijing restricts rare earths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/trump-new-china-massive-tariffs-threat/105880136</link><description>The US President takes to Truth Social to say he sees "no reason" to meet Xi Jinping after Beijing's "hostile" move to restrict rare-earth exports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c593e331aa58e6e28231bfbe40174ca6</guid></item><item><title>Memories from the rubble</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/verify-tracking-the-destruction-of-a-neighbourhood-in-gaza/105814932</link><description>When 25-year-old Nour imagines herself back home in Gaza City, she remembers the things that made her smile. Now that's all gone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef31548e58d9f19f9724991b39be12c6</guid></item><item><title>Older borrowers taking out later-in-life loans risk post-retirement mortgage pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/housing-prices-older-borrowers-risk-mortgage-debt-in-retirement/105867244</link><description>Property analysts, brokers and banks report more borrowers are taking on big housing debts in their late 40s and 50s and, potentially, a retirement still saddled with mortgage repayments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cea624f58afd0c1f6bdfb886c7aaa758</guid></item><item><title>Japan's decorated trucks face 'extinction' but fans and truckies are trying to bring them back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/japan-culture-of-dekotora-decorated-trucks-under-threat/105862672</link><description>The dekotora, large decorated trucks covered in colour and bright lights, were once a common sight across Japan. Now they are fighting for survival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eb195808234a2a8b67b318263d22ece</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump deserves credit for stopping the war on Gaza, but his key claim is overblown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/donald-trump-gaza-ceasefire-plan-lyons-analysis/105880080</link><description>In the tragic arc of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, Donald Trump may have closed the latest — and most violent — chapter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35343a2a556ecc6c9cc2d961d8d4a821</guid></item><item><title>Queensland heating up with weekend thunderstorms forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/hot-conditions-and-thunderstorms-forecast-for-qld/105876568</link><description>The weather bureau says much of the state can expect above average temperatures with possibly severe thunderstorms in the south-east today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd2bd926a0f251fc64594556239145cf</guid></item><item><title>Chaotic weather outlook raises prospects of summer bushfires across eastern states</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/chaotic-australia-weather-outlook-a-forecasting-nightmare/105878032</link><description>An atmospheric "tug of war" for control of Australia's weather is taking place this spring, and it is a forecasting nightmare.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b71072a2e473fdafe1fcd7f320252c0</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste workers part of PALM scheme helping to fill NT workforce gaps</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/palm-scheme-workers-timor-leste-nt-workforce-shortages/105876688</link><description>The Northern Territory struggles to find workers for low- and semi-skilled jobs, but with increasing numbers of foreign workers arriving under the Pacific Australia Labour Mobility (PALM) scheme, that may be changing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2c6d5a6c01ae7f403bd6befbcc0d5bb</guid></item><item><title>NT police defend taking five days to appeal for information in alleged DV murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/nt-police-defend-initial-nonsuspicious-label-in-alleged-dv-death/105877858</link><description>Northern Territory police have defended taking five days to appeal for information about a woman’s death in Darwin’s northern suburbs last month, since alleged to be a domestic violence-related murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">343ec3b2b0363e2c050b071fc94f4538</guid></item><item><title>Alameddine crime network suspected in murder of UFC fighter Suman Mokhtarian</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/gunned-down-sydney-ufc-fighter-suman-mokhtaria-alameddine-links/105879342</link><description>Police had intelligence that Sydney's Alameddine organised crime network wanted a former UFC fighter dead more than 18 months before his shooting murder this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f204ff3bc4b1ce27c00eca55cb4de20</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur loses 6-4, 6-4 to Daniil Medvedev in Shanghai quarterfinals to miss out on career milestone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/de-minaur-bows-out-to-medvedev-in-shanghai/105880016</link><description>Alex de Minaur is eliminated from the Shanghai Masters, going down 6-4, 6-4 to former world number one Danil Medvedev in the quarterfinals, denying the 26-year-old Australian a chance of his 300th tour win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d00438342ad763a6953e65f8b5283119</guid></item><item><title>Rockbank man charged with murder over the death of woman at Epping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/rockbank-man-charged-with-murder-after-womans-death-epping/105880244</link><description>A 50-year-old man faces court charged with murder after the death of a 44-year-old woman in Epping on Thursday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f854561e09dcbd87bdb467eff3f1f23</guid></item><item><title>Concord Hospital's Ebola practice run-through tests department's emergency response plans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/hazmat-ebola-emergency-practice-exercise-at-sydney-hospital/105877344</link><description>A high-stakes mission was undertaken at Concord Hospital this week — an exercise to test how multiple government agencies would react to any future infectious diseases outbreak.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae1003d959fd5041db58be9e5f30a1fe</guid></item><item><title>Fashion's misogyny problem might end up in your wardrobe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/fashion-gender-equality-dior-chanel-misogyny/105858400</link><description>Men sit at the top of the world's fashion houses while women designers get torn apart online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35cb2c216556832c5dcdb317d8f6718a</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous elder Alby Clarke remembered for ultramarathon and cycling feats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/indigenous-elder-alby-clarke-endurance-athlete-remembered/105827808</link><description>An Indigenous elder well-known for his sporting achievements, including using long-distance running and cycling to advocate for Aboriginal reconciliation and health, is remembered by loved ones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">571dd2ed6d993a3e06e1bc1389cb6c92</guid></item><item><title>Art courier Laurie Burgess grows his collection as he travels Australia delivering to galleries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/laurie-burgess-art-courier-delivery-driver-collector/105878528</link><description>Laurie Burgess has dedicated two decades to transporting artwork across the country, and has developed an appreciation and knowledge of the Australian art world few could rival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3379fa8a63412be8885047e73fac3f8</guid></item><item><title>Hotel owner mocks Wollongong Council's palm tree art after renovation refusal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/illawarra-hotel-renovation-refusal-protest-mocks-palm-tree-art/105870512</link><description>A Wollongong hotel owner goes to unusual heights to mock a controversial piece of public art and protest against a council decision to knock back a development application.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b1031ea2e23cee5d58514f5c7757b2a</guid></item><item><title>Crispy pita bread, warm chickpeas and garlic yoghurt is an easy dinner - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/fattet-hummus-crispy-pita-bread-warm-chickpeas-yoghurt-sauce/105774760</link><description>This popular vegetarian Lebanese dish with crispy pita bread, warm chickpeas and a garlicky tahini yoghurt sauce is ready in 30 minutes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5fb42664c5b17dc7aa90f429712af7f</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos beat 2026 FIFA World Cup co-hosts Canada 1-0 with Nestory Irankunda scoring only goal in Montreal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/socceroos-vs-canada-internatonal-friendly-live-blog/105880362</link><description>Nestory Irankunda's late strike has given the Socceroos a 1-0 victory over FIFA 2026 World Cup co-hosts Canada in in Montreal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beb7355019e2604569237fb868f651b4</guid></item><item><title>Soccer the name of the game in Borroloola, even reigning over Australian Rules Football</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/borroloola-strikers-remote-aboriginal-womens-soccer-team-revived/105874590</link><description>Aussie Rules football is life for many in remote NT Aboriginal communities but in Borroloola, barefoot young women and girls dream of following their hero into soccer's A-League.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbd37b3db762ecdab8799d372f09e535</guid></item><item><title>Mount Burr Swamp thriving after rehabilitation from farmland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/mount-burr-swamp-revival-wetlands-conservation/105869900</link><description>The Mount Burr Swamp in South Australia is brimming with water, giving conservationists hope its success can be a blueprint for the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e20e0fc5376bd3364f7296a6c0e9c3c</guid></item><item><title>Watchdog says Synergy not the only energy company overcharging amid $40m bungle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/synergy-billing-mistake-could-affect-other-companies/105879468</link><description>A $40 million overcharging bungle by WA's largest energy retailer was a result of serious governance failures and other businesses may have also fallen foul according to the state's economic watchdog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89094235c0602560ac4d9fb70e033767</guid></item><item><title>Machete brawl between groups spills into shopping centre in Melbourne's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/vic-broadmeadows-machete-brawl/105880438</link><description>Investigators say a brawl between two groups armed with machetes spilled into a shopping centre in Broadmeadows on Friday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5dab909acd080dba0340e61fed2aa5d</guid></item><item><title>Kimberley woman part of Seven Sisters project makes submission to UN in fight for justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/irene-davey-seeks-justice-with-un-for-daughter-kimberley/105870006</link><description>It has been close to three decades since Irene Davey's daughter disappeared, now she is taking her case to the United Nations in an attempt to finally get justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">157d801424833657379f8a718b6fc70c</guid></item><item><title>Only four people in Australia have been diagnosed with rare genetic disease CHOPS</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/rare-genetic-disorder-chops-syndrome/105648828</link><description>Fourteen-year-old Isla Steed has unique challenges as one of just four people in Australia diagnosed with CHOPS syndrome.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eebec15926b1d18c6a3efe3b4cef5a61</guid></item><item><title>Sydney FC's Amelia Cassar likened to Matildas World Cup heroes ahead of A-League Women season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/alw-sydney-fc-recruit-amelia-cassar-likened-to-matildas-stars/105880668</link><description>At 17, Amelia Cassar is likened to some of Australia's World Cup heroes, as she embarks on her first season with the Sky Blues in the A-League Women competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">520e9770ff315b1b3d2a8cbba1880f38</guid></item><item><title>Defunct NDIS provider given record $2.2 million penalty after Queensland man fatally hit by car</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/qld-ndis-penalty-two-million-death-participant-federal-court/105880582</link><description>Proceedings began against the now-defunct provider following the death of a Queensland participant in 2023. The penalty is the highest civil sanction imposed on an NDIS provider to date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6acb3225c56ca35a28372adb3d37a9f0</guid></item><item><title>National Rugby League award for Karratha Kangaroos named best community club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/karratha-nrl-community-club-award/105620432</link><description>WA may traditionally be an AFL state but a club in the Pilbara has been named among the nation's best in another footy code.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b809a8c9f2b25b721e97ba288e56b42</guid></item><item><title>'Brilliant time capsule' of historical street images returns to Bendigo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/allan-doney-photographic-collection-returns-to-bendigo/105867172</link><description>A collection of photographs taken by an amateur photographer in a regional Victorian city in the 1950s, 60s and 70s has been returned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">827179a8b6679bc401bc821dbe6910f8</guid></item><item><title>Roaring jet boats to return to Victoria for first time in 15 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/jet-boats-find-home-in-elmore-victoria/105865604</link><description>From tractors to jet boats at Elmore, as Victoria prepares to host Australian series jet boat event in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bd1a38cda11cf4c394fc5acf0033196</guid></item><item><title>Israel announces list of Palestinian prisoners to be released, but one key name is absent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/israel-announces-250-palestinian-prisoners-to-be-released/105880378</link><description>Israel's Ministry of Justice provides the names of prisoners it will release in exchange for Israeli hostages, but Hamas says no agreement has been reached.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">057adbbf0cd2e62eda8543f65fbc9bd0</guid></item><item><title>Trump allies at odds as US moves forward with Qatari military training facility 'on the sacred soil of America'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/us-qatar-military-training-facility-idaho/105880722</link><description>The US military is moving forward with plans to build a dedicated facility in Idaho to train pilots from Qatar. But not everyone is happy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">226b076a0d46540239264bdbf91a8727</guid></item><item><title>Genomic medicine could be huge but 5 million Australians may miss out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/genomic-medicine-could-be-huge-but-5-million/105878606</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ed6e2fb9d4d9d0324e237a7c8b62bfe</guid></item><item><title>Genomic medicine researchers work to fix 'European bias' in DNA databases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/diverse-communities-needed-for-national-dna-project/105865644</link><description>Researchers are trying to fix the "Western bias" contained in many DNA databases with a new national project targeting multicultural communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c6b641519f66ec459f59a401ceae20d</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne closes in on remarkable winning record, Brisbane downs Port</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/aflw-crows-eagles-cats-giants-hawks-suns-lions-kangaroos-tigers/105881094</link><description>The Kangaroos extend their extraordinary AFLW winning streak with a 36-point thumping of the Tigers, while the Lions stay in touching distance of the league's top four with victory over Port.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c0d11a9c91e626275ddd1a919085b2e</guid></item><item><title>Hackers release Qantas customers' data on dark web</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/hackers-release-qantas-customers-data-on-dark-web/105881266</link><description>Hackers have released personal data from Qantas customers onto the dark web, following a cyber attack in July.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89f0546c7b3bb23647757cb38ea11506</guid></item><item><title>Former US President Joe Biden undergoing radiation therapy for cancer, spokesperson says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/joe-biden-radiation-therapy-for-cancer/105881476</link><description>The spokesperson added the radiation treatment is expected to continue for five weeks and is a new stage in his level of care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d799ae80234a2e4df342c09a033526e7</guid></item><item><title>Trump's frustration with Modi over Russia ties misses the memo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/india-united-states-russia-modi-trump-putin/105830580</link><description>Regardless of its historical defence ties to Russia, or its economic reliance on the United States, India is politically non-monogamous.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5ce563ddba7d51b1b5b81df3ce64d8e</guid></item><item><title>How did a mother and daughter at the centre of a suspected murder-suicide 'slip through the cracks'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/queensland-tiffany-wilkes-suspected-murder-suicide-clementine/105874684</link><description>The suspected murder-suicide of a mother and her daughter has raised serious questions about whether there were missed opportunities to intervene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">685fed94a266c8c69def78ef7fb17984</guid></item><item><title>A new supermarket has been invited to Australia. Here's what that might mean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/australia-supermarkets-uae-lulu/105862384</link><description>Last month, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese invited Emirati hypermarket chain LuLu Group to compete with Coles and Woolworths for market share. But some retail experts say entry into Australia's supermarket sector isn't so simple.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5530ab19189c8c30a7193932fff28eb</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government's BetStop scheme not working, former gambler says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/betstop-scheme-not-working-former-gambler-says/105878872</link><description>Diehard Richmond fan "Tiger Shaun" says he's watched on in horror as gambling advertising and sponsorships have come to dominate football — and become a constant reminder of the addiction he has struggled with.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6b9cac18f3f5518da8b3cd291770331</guid></item><item><title>Jared Kushner, Trump's son-in-law, was a key player in the Israel-Hamas peace deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/jared-kushner-a-key-player-in-the-israel-hamas-peace-deal/105876736</link><description>Jared Kushner was a familiar face sitting beside Israel’s PM as a first-phase peace agreement was finalised. According to senior US officials, it was because he was a key player in closing the deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47123b86788c992ca0ca1a3375c9a521</guid></item><item><title>Women express disappointment with some Chinese matchmaking platforms in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/women-disappointed-with-some-chinese-matchmaking-platforms-/105844094</link><description>Chinese Australian women are paying thousands of dollars to find love on matchmaking platforms in Australia, but behind the glossy promotions lies a different reality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de33ea3b1474e557375d1f80e4808280</guid></item><item><title>Platypus vanish from river where Charles Darwin pondered evolution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/platypus-vanish-from-charles-darwin-evolution-river/105752248</link><description>Almost 190 years on, in the place where Charles Darwin first spotted a platypus, the egg-laying mammal seems to have disappeared.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c8747945cd98a902fc15be69eaa2b36</guid></item><item><title>Cost blowout fears cloud $3.2b Women's and Children's Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/cost-blowout-fears-womens-and-childrens-hospital/105874396</link><description>The Malinauskas government has become well-versed in the language of cost blowouts, and the $3.2 billion Women's and Children's Hospital is another chance for it to flex its vocabulary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9b04e9ea7523146654258bde9dae142</guid></item><item><title>In one of Australia's fastest-shrinking regions, towns are fighting to remain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/yarriambiack-warracknabeal-victoria-town-population-shrink/105774946</link><description>In the Yarriambiack Shire, 350 kilometres from Melbourne in Victoria's rural north-west, virtually all of the towns are shrinking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13fe880a8b293197899b32ff61524a1d</guid></item><item><title>Diane Keaton, star of Annie Hall, The Godfather films dies at 79</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/diane-keaton-dies/105881842</link><description>The unexpected news of Keaton's passing has been met with shock around the world, with stars remembering their time with the actor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">880393f1a8884001569183fb7e30b624</guid></item><item><title>Koori Formal an incentive for Mid North Coast students to finish high school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/koori-formal-motivates-students-to-finish-high-school/105758224</link><description>The longest-running year 12 formal for First Nations people in New South Wales proves to be an incentive for students to complete their HSC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5457a819c0978a19e0fdcb577672cd0d</guid></item><item><title>Buyers priced out of market and left in limbo claim developer is exploiting sunset clauses to cancel contracts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/queensland-buyers-call-for-tighter-sunset-clause-legislation/105827656</link><description>Buyers who bought off-the-plan at a Gold Coast housing development years ago weren't just purchasing a home — they were purchasing a dream. Now, the developer is trying to cancel their contracts, but they don't want to accept that lying down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ff4603f3a806b4835203f98d8f982f6</guid></item><item><title>Brandon Starcevich 'good to go' after trade to West Coast despite concussion concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/starcevich-good-to-go-at-west-coast-concussion-concerns/105881284</link><description>West Coast recruit Brandon Starcevich says he has no concerns over his history of concussions after completing a trade to the Eagles from premier Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5459b8a3b694e98ebc45576e5a61e82</guid></item><item><title>Nick Offerman from Parks and Recreation stars as sovereign citizen Jerry Kane in new movie Sovereign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/nick-offerman-sovereign-citizen-jerry-kane-christian-swegal/105867130</link><description>In Sovereign, Nick Offerman stars as real-life radical-right sovereign citizen Jerry Kane, who, with his son, killed two cops in Arkansas in 2010, drawing parallels to Australian fugitive Dezi Freeman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f83d47504974cf5d7dcf916a63e8e8</guid></item><item><title>Benjamin Netanyahu booed as Steve Witkoff speaks ahead of return of hostages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/netanyahu-booed-steve-witkoff-gaza-israel-ceasefire/105881584</link><description>Thousands of Israelis have gathered in Hostages Square in Tel Aviv, where US envoy Steve Witkoff spoke to the crowd in anticipation of the release of the remaining hostages in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">834ca4b7e6bf4f98a9e0415e2b761690</guid></item><item><title>Alyssa Healy backs Australia's batters to fire against India despite stuttering start to World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/alyssa-healy-backs-australias-batters-to-fire-india-world-cup/105881892</link><description>Ahead of a crucial match against World Cup host India, Australia's captain Alyssa Healy says she has faith her side's top order can turn around its recent batting struggles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ca940a6ad8f7318299ae41819020fb6</guid></item><item><title>West Coast Council's vehicle fleet left unregistered for a week after 'administrative error'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/west-coast-councils-fleet-of-vehicles-unregistered-for-week/105878164</link><description>Tasmania's West Coast Council has blamed an "administrative error" for a week-long lapse in the registration for its entire fleet of vehicles, compromising insurance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeef7d3ebe41a78cf42f59c21e055f69</guid></item><item><title>Gregory Porter on turning personal pain into powerful music</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/gregory-porter-interview-australia-mister-holland-no-love-dying/105866372</link><description>From the pain of racism to the joy of love, Gregory Porter's voice carries it all with power and purpose.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a61497653a2cd8967d2930635faab18</guid></item><item><title>Spring rains sow seeds of hope among Limestone Coast farmers after months of drought</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/south-east-emerges-from-drought-and-price-slump/105848144</link><description>After months of dust and dry skies, farmers on South Australia's Limestone Coast have welcomed early spring rain and a promising season ahead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2051346c282334589fac6a762170c40e</guid></item><item><title>Three teenagers charged after alleged stabbing of father and son in Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/three-teenagers-charged-stabbing-melbourne-southbank/105881880</link><description>The men were allegedly attacked on the Yarra Promenade overnight. Police arrested five teenagers and have charged three of them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecfea06173ada53fdc54ddd5008d5a61</guid></item><item><title>Bathurst 1000 results: Matt Payne and Garth Tander win at Mount Panorama, Cooper Murray taken out late</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/live-updates-bathurst-1000-supercars/105865890</link><description>Matt Payne and Garth Tander have won a remarkable edition of the Bathurst 1000 featuring seven safety cars at a rain-soaked Mount Panorama.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cf91c2a3824e89a05e10bdb9f643282</guid></item><item><title>Mango the muster cat draws attention to western Queensland's ongoing recovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/mango-the-muster-cat-draws-attention-to-western-qld-recovery/105783150</link><description>Raised alongside working dogs, Mango isn't your average feline and comes complete with his own Facebook page, loyal followers and fan mail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63b26a87a12960a7f43cb484f5d058c7</guid></item><item><title>The NT has changed the way it responds to domestic violence. Here's what that means.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/domestic-violence-response-nt-co-responder-model/105862072</link><description>The NT has Australia's highest rates of domestic and family violence, with an intimate partner homicide rate seven times the national average.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07816eca6f1c61f284cb6e5bd7fd185f</guid></item><item><title>Two arrested after Ian Watkins, disgraced former Lostprophets singer, killed in UK prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/two-arrested-ian-watkins-lostprophets-singer-killed-in-uk-prison/105882008</link><description>British police have arrested two men on suspicion of murder after Ian Watkins, the disgraced former Welsh rock band Lostprophets singer who was serving a 35-year jail sentence for child sex offences, was killed in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">223e07d6ac712b874d9d5ff2a114ff36</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous community Bidyadanga hosts From the Desert to the Seaside music festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/bidyadanga-music-festival-from-the-desert-to-the-seaside/105879698</link><description>From the Desert to the Seaside arts and music festival brings Western Australia's largest remote community of Bidyadanga together.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bd7b22727457c514f2c9772ca9393b8</guid></item><item><title>Roads in WA's East Pilbara need millions of dollars in repairs eight months after Cyclone Zelia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/road-cyclone-damage-repairs-pilbara/105857014</link><description>Australia's largest shire says it needs state and federal support to repair roads damaged during a cyclone, which provide a "lifeline" to remote communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d923148ba64c43bdcc00574fb481443</guid></item><item><title>Kelpies for Kids fundraiser at Perth Royal Show raises nearly $50k for sick children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/kelpies-for-kids-runs-for-second-year-raising-money-for-children/105862942</link><description>A working dog auction at the Perth Royal Show raises nearly $50,000 for charity Telethon to support sick children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">181b1baf4cc31df1c53d52860f37c8fe</guid></item><item><title>From The Godfather to The First Wives Club — here are Diane Keaton's best films</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/diane-keaton-movies-woody-allen-where-to-watch/105882070</link><description>With a career beginning in the late 1970s, Diane Keaton would star in more than 100 films and earn several Oscar nods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14d0a28df6e1de7e26d3c91ac4faf413</guid></item><item><title>Record beach patrols in South Australia this summer as life savers help battle algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/sa-life-savers-summer-beach-patrol-algal-bloom/105882102</link><description>A record number of beaches in SA are set to have Surf Life Saving patrols seven days a week this summer, as the state grapples with its toxic algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f070b8801a8bfee9819fde617335d087</guid></item><item><title>Tennessee military munitions plant explosion death toll reduced as community mourns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/tennessee-military-munitions-plant-explosion-death-toll-reduced/105882158</link><description>Authorities in the US say 16 people died in a massive explosion at a Tennessee munitions facility that has left a shocked community in mourning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c462b3a9d478f95023770bd769a2230</guid></item><item><title>Police search for man who disappeared during camping trip with wife in Victoria's east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/vic-missing-camper-troy-milne-sale/105882390</link><description>Police are appealing to the public for help in locating a man who left to pick up supplies while camping with his wife in Gippsland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f4f698753fa2532b5dc1e4ddde87d54</guid></item><item><title>At least 41 dead in Mexico's Veracruz region after landslides, floods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/dozens-dead-in-mexico-veracruz-after-landslides-floods/105882420</link><description>Authorities have attributed the deadly downpours to Tropical Storm Priscilla, formerly a hurricane, and Tropical Storm Raymond, both off the western coast of Mexico.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">849ea547c18416e2aa0d551a85bfe9f1</guid></item><item><title>Afghan Taliban forces attack Pakistani border posts as 'retaliation' for Kabul air strikes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/afghanistan-taliban-pakistan-border-fight-air-strike/105882450</link><description>Afghan Taliban forces say they have captured Pakistani border posts, while Pakistani security officials say their military is responding "with full force" to the attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d678035ddccbdb622c7446a6f1d07e9e</guid></item><item><title>Teenager flown to Townsville after shark attack off Thursday Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/shark-attack-thursday-island-torres-strait-teenager-airlifted/105882608</link><description>The 14-year-old is in a critical condition in Townsville University Hospital after a shark attack in the Torres Strait Islands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5da45e0d1dd0729067a30c037543da8</guid></item><item><title>China accuses US of 'double standards' over new tariffs threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/china-responds-to-us-tariff-threat/105882356</link><description>Donald Trump says he will impose extra levies in response to what he called "extraordinarily aggressive" new Chinese export curbs on rare-earth minerals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47e859acbd6ffddc89eb03d8b3a76cf1</guid></item><item><title>How long can you safely store and reheat leftovers?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/how-long-can-you-safely-store-leftover-food/105844878</link><description>Experts share their tips on how to best store cooked food to save money and avoid food waste.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce0d4f73a17f91c0b31eb05a75824b09</guid></item><item><title>Dockers stun Demons in 5-point AFLW upset, Swans snap losing streak, Saints down Magpies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/aflw-swans-blues-saints-magpies-demons-dockers/105882626</link><description>Fremantle keeps its faint AFLW finals hopes alive with a five-point nail-biter against Melbourne, Sydney arrests a massive form slump against Carlton, while St Kilda notches its fifth consecutive win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df3573f2cc285db9b9466558e3598502</guid></item><item><title>Why the Gaza ceasefire could collapse over coming days</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/why-the-gaza-ceasefire-deal-might-collapse/105880872</link><description>There is any number of ways the ceasefire could fall over — perhaps within days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e18514bb800ce6837a2e1588c9a2da4</guid></item><item><title>PM's XIII hammer Orchids 50-0 in Port Moresby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/pms-xiii-orchids-png/105882744</link><description>In their annual clash, the Prime Minister's XIII outclass the Orchids 50-0 in Port Moresby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8613c3f1ac993b642b76ac402d167fb4</guid></item><item><title>Australia could be left behind on renewables – 12 October 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/as-the-world-shifts-away-from-fossil-fuels,/105882858</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcdc037acd4e65b4d364c1b8b9c3d38d</guid></item><item><title>Record-breaking Melbourne Marathon Festival as 50,000 runners hit the road</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/record-breaking-numbers-for-melbourne-marathon-2025/105881966</link><description>Melbourne's Jack Rayner won the men's marathon for the second year in a row with a time of 2 hours, 15 minutes and 2 seconds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdcdedd29e83e0274fd3058187812027</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Diamonds defeat South Africa's Proteas 65-42 in third netball Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/netball-test-australia-diamonds-defeat-south-africa-proteas/105882776</link><description>Australia warms up for the eagerly anticipated Constellation Cup with a convincing 65-42 victory over South Africa in the third and final Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f1ff5a0a480446ef675b46afe105c3f</guid></item><item><title>Ethan Strange stars as PM's XIII defeat Papua New Guinea 28-10</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/strange-stars-pms-xiii-down-png/105882870</link><description>Ethan Strange underlines his case for Kangaroos selection and Trai Fuller scores four tries in the Prime Minister's XIII 28-10 defeat of Papua New Guinea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eed2497e30235bd850a45f4d7782c62</guid></item><item><title>Bathurst 1000 quick hits: Chaz Mostert drinks beer with fans, Erebus owner protests, and drama on Mount Panorama</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/bathurst-1000-quick-hits-chaz-mostert-beer-erebus-trophy-protest/105882090</link><description>Wild weather and hard racing were combined with bold and colourful personalities to create a truly memorable day of Supercars racing. Here are the quick hits from the 2025 Bathurst 1000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56dcf83a7f85000c36d8a88c92eb8787</guid></item><item><title>Australia beats India by three wickets in Women's World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/australia-beats-india-by-three-wickets-in-womens-world-cup/105882054</link><description>Skipper Alyssa Healy scores a super ton and Ellyse Perry sees Australia home in a world-record women's ODI chase to beat India by three wickets in a World Cup thriller.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">793b5b7cd7bd870847524ccb5b3a51ca</guid></item><item><title>Government holds firm on not negotiating with hackers in wake of Qantas breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/government-will-not-negotiate-with-hackers-after-qantas-breach/105882936</link><description>The federal government is sticking to its position of not negotiating with cyber criminals, despite hackers releasing personal data from millions of Qantas customers onto the dark web and threatening to target Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5f206d6dfa9993e776c0fc59eca158a</guid></item><item><title>Vacherot becomes lowest-ranked ATP Masters winner after defeating his cousin Rinderknech in Shanghai</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/valentin-vacherot-wins-shanghai-masters-atp-tournament/105883038</link><description>He beat his cousin Arthur Rinderknech 4-6, 6-3, 6-3 on Sunday local time to claim the first title of his career after a stunning run from the qualifying rounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb81965abf5ff6abbfd51d7bc8b541f5</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump accused of profiting from presidency as crypto ventures rake in hundreds of millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/trump-president-wealth-family-business-crypto-four-corners/105876782</link><description>Donald Trump's wealth has skyrocketed since his return to the White House nine months ago, leading to accusations that he is profiting from the presidency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a085f22828b5fca9aac9493ad39f159</guid></item><item><title>Australians join race for fusion energy as AI pressure on electricity sector starts to bite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/the-australians-in-the-race-for-fusion-energy/105882230</link><description>The two great technology revolutions of the modern era — artificial intelligence and renewable energy — are colliding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e55bc7ba701556faca8e00198d03be1</guid></item><item><title>Western Sydney University consultants paid almost $3k a day, leaked documents show, as redundancies loom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/western-sydney-university-consultants-paid-thousands-a-day/105873714</link><description>As Western Sydney University prepares to shed hundreds of staff due to its dire finances, leaked documents reveal it is paying consultants as much as $2,850 a day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b53eac6b9f8be6dc73b9a78e468e290</guid></item><item><title>Russia expresses 'extreme concern' over US providing Tomahawk missiles to Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/russia-expresses-extreme-concern-over-us-tomahawk-missiles/105883082</link><description>Kyiv and the US are openly floating the idea of providing Ukraine with long-range Tomahawk missiles, in a move Russia says would mark "a very dramatic moment".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3276f5d539ed6330fde6aaa1c0c8618</guid></item><item><title>Pakistani military vision shows attacks on Taliban positions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/pakistani-military-vision-shows-attacks-on-taliban/105883528</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">726a672e1e8b8ad11b1da9d968fd8aaa</guid></item><item><title>Pakistani military vision shows aerial views of strikes on Taliban targets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/pakistani-military-vision-shows-aerial-views-of-strikes/105883548</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83e8a655e215d9482663c08560a1293f</guid></item><item><title>Uber drivers refusing rides due to guide dog, handler says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/guide-dog-handlers-call-for-harsher-penalties-for-uber-refusals/105754360</link><description>Sarah Maculans says she was refused rides by four Uber drivers within a week due to her guide dog, Sunny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4767c5abe70ec191abca333f88092f6b</guid></item><item><title>Israel 'ready to receive all of our hostages' from Gaza, Netanyahu's office says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/gaza-hostages-to-be-released/105883378</link><description>The final 20 living Israeli hostages in Gaza are set to be released by Hamas in a matter of hours, with preparations by Israeli defence and medical authorities to receive the captives after more than two years hidden away from the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b9a5eb8243f6852bb6c4f770512b950</guid></item><item><title>Aid convoys enter Gaza during Israel-Hamas ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/aid-convoys-enter-gaza-during-israel-hamas-ceasefire/105883574</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a492d678557b656caaa8a144bed4d723</guid></item><item><title>Koala killed by a car on Appin Road after being hailed a conservation success story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/appin-road-in-sydney-claims-life-rescued-koala-gage/105879322</link><description>Koala deaths on Appin Road are not unusual this time of year, but the fatality of rescued koala Gage is cause for more than the usual frustration and despair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a01be949d5b85d86fa6ff42ba3ea7c6d</guid></item><item><title>Former tennis star Jelena Dokic grapples with complex grief after abusive father Damir's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/jelenadokic-says-abusive-dad-showed-no-remorse/105849988</link><description>Jelena Dokic was abused by her father for years, with no tennis success enough to stop the beatings. She reveals the complex grief of losing a parent who showed no remorse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69cd6af49b40951598418e7e78d42249</guid></item><item><title>Gaza updates live: Donald Trump addresses Israeli Parliament after hostages, Palestinian prisoners freed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/israel-gaza-hamas-ceasefire-live-updates/105882948</link><description>Hamas has handed over all the remaining living Israeli hostages, as a ceasefire with Hamas continues to hold in Gaza. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be02b702b81f90b4f983344fa10ab6ad</guid></item><item><title>Wetland ecosystem welcomed at Tasmanian sheep farm after 20-year restoration effort</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/tasmania-saltmarsh-wetland-restoration-on-merino-sheep-farm/105883488</link><description>A sheep farmer has welcomed the restoration of an internationally significant wetland on his property outside of Hobart. The collaboration of a non-profit organisation with landowners, scientists, the Aboriginal community and governments has allowed the return of a vital ecosystem.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1e6acb760d399a693f75e216ea48417</guid></item><item><title>Social media ban will further isolate regional and rural youth, LGBTIQA+ advocates say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/social-media-ban-will-isolate-regional-queer-teens-more/105829530</link><description>LGBTIQA+ advocates are concerned the social media ban will have a significant impact on queer youth in regional and remote areas of Australia. They say there are not enough offline, physical supports for these teens to access when the ban comes into effect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cbc396370d50cfb8a5287d529e393b7</guid></item><item><title>ASX closes down 0.8 per cent, gold hits new record, Treasury Wine Estates tumbles — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/105883026</link><description>The ASX sheds 0.8 per cent following Wall Street's Friday hair-on-fire session while gold continues on its record breaking run.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc3926b7bdeb6ef03007675c20ec8918</guid></item><item><title>Rebecca, the haunting story adapted into a Hitchcock classic, is now a gripping psychological stage play</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/rebecca-melbourne-theatre-company-hitchcock/105863212</link><description>First dismissed as "Gothic romance" when it was published by Daphne du Maurier in 1938, the haunting tale has evolved into a modern thriller about the expectations placed on women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1669144caa73fcb084b2ee6660bce19d</guid></item><item><title>Isolated storms forecast for Queensland after weekend hail storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/isolated-storms-forecast-for-queensland-this-week/105882378</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology is also predicting a return to regular spring temperatures after a spell of warmer days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78ba8aa6dcb095d740cbead406d25d9e</guid></item><item><title>Michael Pratt, George Cross recipient and former Victorian police officer, dies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/michael-pratt-victorian-police-officer-george-cross-recipient/105883558</link><description>Former Victoria Police officer Michael Pratt has been remembered for his bravery when he confronted three armed bank robbers in Melbourne in 1978.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">387d0a1122baa4ab5a5052fc5f8da703</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar's President Andry Rajoelina says student protesters are attempting a coup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/madagascar-president-claims-coup-attempt-underway/105883466</link><description>Troops from an elite unit of the country's military are urging fellow soldiers to disobey orders and back student protesters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f041025445012537603be910fd6490a</guid></item><item><title>WA lawyers write to attorney-general calling for in-person court hearings to return to remote Balgo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/kimberley-based-lawyers-struggling-to-support-balgo-residents/105866646</link><description>With in-person court hearings suspended and video links cancelled, lawyers are struggling to ensure access to justice for the remote community of Balgo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08e509522e73a26e49192e99129f2347</guid></item><item><title>'We are going to have a good time': Trump heads to Middle East</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/we-are-going-to-have-a-good-time-trump-heads-to-mid-east/105883718</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">274f7712adfab2b0d1b7c51ba07665d6</guid></item><item><title>Climate Integrity says 'distorted research' behind government policy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/climate-integrity-accc-to-investigate-gas-lobby-ey-modelling/105866988</link><description>Advocacy group Climate Integrity has accused the gas industry of using "distorted research", produced by the accounting firm EY, to influence the Australian government's Future Gas Strategy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28322136f22de6e61de34a7e4e872c4b</guid></item><item><title>Brad Pettitt questions WA Labor's commitment to increasing Perth's tree canopy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/brad-pettitt-questions-wa-labors-commitment-to/105879012</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74296c695f705429cfd19d9d6685f4d5</guid></item><item><title>Fresh doubts over WA Labor election commitments to boost Perth’s tree canopy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/wa-tree-canopy-election-promise-walked-back/105865416</link><description>The WA government is facing renewed questions over its plans to boost Perth's tree cover, with experts saying current funding will not come close to delivering on Labor's election promises.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">755ddb616df68a32d5fd28309f6717e9</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, day six recap: Zach Merrett, Charlie Curnow and Christian Petracca remain in limbo seeking moves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/afl-trade-period-day-six-live-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca/105883736</link><description>Zach Merrett is one of a number of former All-Australians currently in limbo as West Coast continues to wheel and deal after another wooden spoon and Port Adelaide secures a midfielder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b30b12b2a3a7724532b5ba22d8a1df3b</guid></item><item><title>Mount Magnet Shire councillor Ian Black suspended after no apology for defamatory notice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/mount-magnet-shire-deputy-suspended-after-defamatory-notice/105880958</link><description>Mount Magnet Shire deputy president Ian Black is suspended after failing to apologise for posting a defamatory notice about staff to a public noticeboard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56ad1f0b0ee68c823f21a856debc307a</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Minjee Lee finishes third at LPGA Shanghai, behind winner Jeeno Thitikul</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/minjee-lee-finishes-third-in-epic-lpga-shanghai/105883722</link><description>Thai world number one Jeeno Thitikul wins the LPGA Shanghai tournament on the fifth play-off hole, with Australian superstar Minjee Lee settling for third.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98cfc762883593126e34eacce9a9c23f</guid></item><item><title>Committee formally recommends NT government adopt voluntary assisted dying</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/nt-government-voluntary-assisted-dying-report-recommendation/105515296</link><description>On the verandah of their Darwin home, Judy Dent held her husband's hand as he became the first person in the world to die through legally accessible voluntary assisted dying. That world-first would not be possible in the Northern Territory today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3da225f565d839bdf449bf4b26951d4</guid></item><item><title>Lidia Thorpe threatens to 'burn down Parliament House' over Palestine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/lidia-thorpe-threatens-to-burn-down-parliament/105884070</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99f363be50ece9b52ed6fd4c4972f332</guid></item><item><title>Rabin Medical Center deputy director explains recovery plan for returned Israeli hostages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/rabin-medical-center-deputy-director-explains-rehab-plan/105884082</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c23d37454033682278e6815373b4e440</guid></item><item><title>Australian cricket captain Pat Cummins says he is 'probably unlikely' to play in first Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/pat-cummins-unlikely-to-play-first-ashes-test/105883832</link><description>Pat Cummins all but rules himself out of the first Ashes Test, saying he is still a way short of completing his condensed recovery schedule from a back injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b1d8292aabc1b91a7c4ac0cc55cdb3a</guid></item><item><title>Diane Keaton's death shocked many. US media says family kept her sudden decline private</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/diane-keaton-cause-of-death-private-health-decline/105883902</link><description>The actor's cause of death has not been made public, but with US media reporting her family chose to keep her health decline private.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b575d070be7336c702ea5c37aec3f74</guid></item><item><title>Teenagers charged after Hawthorn home owner detains alleged 15-year-old intruder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/teenagers-charged-alleged-hawthorn-melbourne-home-invasion/105883852</link><description>Police have charged two boys, aged 14 and 15, over two alleged early morning break-ins in Melbourne — one of which allegedly saw a man chase and restrain a teenager.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c6fea3b6545310ecc43e0b872b18d5b</guid></item><item><title>Fox Resources collapses, but fight against coal exploration in Bundaberg food bowl continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/fox-resources-collapse-bundaberg-coal-mine-exploration/105884008</link><description>Exploration company Fox Resources has gone into administration, but the community that successfully fought off its mining advances vows to keep fighting to cancel the tenement altogether.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bfdc45a674d8408b12424221c8e22b2</guid></item><item><title>World's biggest light installation to illuminate landscapes of Albany, WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/biggest-light-installation-ever-on-earth-planned-for-albany/105866412</link><description>A light installation, projected onto King George Sound in Albany, will be the largest ever created.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0c3fad2d619ba1d36ef0034dc9d4ec0</guid></item><item><title>Israeli settlers say Gaza peace plan prevents them claiming more land</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/israeli-settlers-say-gaza-peace-plan-prevents-them/105884648</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c37746503a45664a601b407260d84511</guid></item><item><title>Treasurer announces rework of stalled superannuation tax increase plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/treasurer-announces-rework-of-stalled-super-tax-increase/105884568</link><description>The government has bowed to pressure on its superannuation tax policy, one of the few revenue-raising measures it had promised, two years on from when it was first announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6423e004d64ee9090f2694aa27bcd949</guid></item><item><title>Travel and dining vouchers on offer in SA's algal bloom summer plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/summer-algal-vouchers-south-australia/105883636</link><description>Some travellers to South Australia's coast over summer will be able to access $500 accommodation vouchers and $50 cashback on their meal, under a state and federal government plan to stimulate tourism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c47d767109a71d2102d3268c1f6df24</guid></item><item><title>Video games could fall under the social media ban, researchers say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/video-games-could-fall-under-social-media-ban-researchers-say/105859842</link><description>Online video games are excluded from the social media ban, but digital media researchers say the definitions are too broadly defined and games could yet be included.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b0b6fa140b851f58a53917e93936fe0</guid></item><item><title>Eugowra flood inquest told official information was not accurate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/eugowra-flood-inquest-hears-official-information-was-inaccurate/105876674</link><description>A coronial inquest is told residents and emergency responders got inaccurate information from the Bureau of Meteorology (BOM) and Water NSW during a devastating flood that claimed two lives in the NSW town of Eugowra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cc7439df585114af7440bc0a3a659e8</guid></item><item><title>Teenager charged with torture, deprivation of liberty after alleged assault of 15-year-old boy at New Chum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/qld-teenager-faces-torture-assault-charges-new-chum/105884810</link><description>The 17-year-old allegedly forced another boy into the boot of a car before assaulting him with a hammer and knife west of Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2c094fc76a91d3c797a14eded8c75d1</guid></item><item><title>Premier Roger Cook opposes federal government plan to reduce skilled migration into WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/wa-premier-roger-cook-rejects-bid-to-cut-skilled-migrant-places/105884344</link><description>A federal government plan to slash skilled migration into Western Australia by about 30 per cent would stunt economic growth and slow the construction of homes amid a housing shortage, the state's premier says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f72eafef2ad5e2001664285f3ac47214</guid></item><item><title>Carter Gordon rushed back into Wallabies squad after quitting NRL's Titans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/rugby-australia-queensland-reds-carter-gordon-quits-nrl-titans/105884978</link><description>The Wallabies waste no time in welcoming back fly half Carter Gordon to rugby union, less than two hours after it was announced he was leaving the NRL.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3aa32c62a9f0aa84542aa4fe59849c01</guid></item><item><title>How to tell if your Qantas personal data has hit the dark web and what you can do if it has</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/qantas-cyber-hack-has-my-data-been-leaked-what-should-i-do/105884604</link><description>Hackers have released Qantas customer data onto the dark web. Here's what experts say to look out for if you think your personal data may be caught up in the leak and what actions you can take.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0686253e2a0f07a77f7a19d16ef3924b</guid></item><item><title>Pink Elephants report highlights care gaps for rural women experiencing miscarriages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/pink-elephants-miscarriage-report-care-gaps-remote-rural-women/105869210</link><description>Pregnancy loss is a lottery determined by location, according to a report that has sparked calls for the federal government improve care for women who experience miscarriage in regional and rural communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd359295e0f7d58eb51fd7c2a78c928d</guid></item><item><title>GrainCorp settles class action over noise and odour pollution in Numurkah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/graincorp-settles-class-action-over-pollution-in-numurkah/105884138</link><description>The class action was brought by a northern Victorian man who alleged that noise and odour pollution from a GrainCorp factory affected his health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4b7709cd3095f489f46b33d3cdcb673</guid></item><item><title>Peter Damjanovic pleads guilty to Tiffany Woodley's murder in Bedford home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/peter-damjanovic-pleads-guilty-to-bedford-tiffany-woodley-murder/105884738</link><description>Peter Damjanovic changes his plea at the last minute and pleads guilty to murdering his former partner Tiffany Woodley at her home in Bedford two years ago. WARNING: Indigenous readers are advised this story contains photos of someone who has died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27ba88199b3ea947698defbfa9cc5a78</guid></item><item><title>Patients of a Mortdale dentist practice urged to get tested for blood-borne viruses including HIV</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/blood-borne-virus-risk-to-patients-of-mortdale-dentist/105885230</link><description>Safuan Hasic, also known as Steven Hasic, has been barred from practising after breaching infection control standards at his Mortdale dentistry practice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b15b2836f126265f7a5c59c923e63cae</guid></item><item><title>Victoria Police announces plan to slim down executive team, divert more officers to front line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/mike-bush-crime-plan-victoria-police-restructure/105884478</link><description>Victoria Police will slim down its executive team and divert more officers to the front line under reforms aimed at reducing crime in the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e5ea13ad3860beeff687da23a25e08b</guid></item><item><title>What to do if your mortgage payments haven't gone down despite an RBA rate cut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/how-to-lower-mortgage-repayments-after-rba-interest-rate-cut/105844258</link><description>You might assume home loan repayments will automatically reduce when an interest rate cut is passed on, but this isn’t always the case. Here's how to check.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9321ceed8438c8f5233f33dc1bbcc97</guid></item><item><title>Israelis gather in Hostage Square ahead of hostage release</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/israelis-gather-in-hostage-square-ahead-of-hostage/105885492</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9db2cc122e3575d82a435b2c099eb850</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian MP Craig Garland temporarily disqualified from driving over drug driving charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/mp-craig-garland-sentenced-for-drug-driving-charge/105773362</link><description>Independent MP Craig Garland applied in court for a restricted license, saying it would be a "terrible situation" if he wasn't able to attend parliamentary sitting weeks in Hobart due to the ban after being found guilty of drug driving.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c66d699bcd04007a1aae088275012df</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew told Jeffrey Epstein 'we'll play some more soon' over email, UK media reports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/prince-andrew-jeffrey-epstein-email-leak/105884256</link><description>Prince Andrew's relationship with convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein is back in the spotlight after UK media published an email between the pair over the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa57513fab1198a6b6372cd6e846912a</guid></item><item><title>Police resume search for missing boy Gus in South Australia's outback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/police-resume-search-for-gus-in-outback-sa/105885476</link><description>SA Police and ADF personnel will resume their search for missing four-year-old Gus in South Australia's mid-north tomorrow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db3ba9f1c54dc2d88ede63bfafdde0b9</guid></item><item><title>Israeli military releases video of reception area for hostages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/israeli-military-releases-video-of-reception-area/105885582</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a4692af0e06201820a12ff6e7a1cbd7</guid></item><item><title>Here's how Labor's revised super proposal would work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/labor-super-tax-changes-explained/105885434</link><description>Every prominent criticism of the tax has been addressed, with the result that it will apply to fewer people and raise less money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e8eac54b40c708087b8083935640a86</guid></item><item><title>Major review of medical scans at Caboolture Hospital to include 3,500 more patients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/caboolture-hospital-medical-scan-review-broadened/105884950</link><description>Thousands more patients have been caught up in a bungle involving medical scans not being reviewed by doctors at a major south-east Queensland hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8bef54c1a408a99f99190c88af1abba</guid></item><item><title>Coronial inquest begins into death of Energy Queensland meter reader Kane Minion mauled by dog at Logan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/qld-worker-dog-attack-coronial-inquest-kane-minion/105883884</link><description>Kane Minion was killed by dogs on a south-east Queensland property in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efa856002e5e5adb45bd45047e6a47b1</guid></item><item><title>WA Liberals handed 78 recommendations to improve following 2025 state election campaign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/wa-liberals-2025-state-election-campaign-review/105874758</link><description>The WA Liberals are told they need more women and a better candidate vetting process in a post-election review audit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b710a4301f8a908c1fcaffdc66068698</guid></item><item><title>Family of teen attacked by shark off Thursday Island grateful for support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/thursday-island-shark-victims-family-releases-statement/105885506</link><description>The 14-year-old is in a critical but stable condition after emergency surgery at Townsville University Hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a599043dbb6d6c6dfae6892af9ad4f53</guid></item><item><title>Pheobe Bishop accused Kieren Daniel Mittelheuser misses court due to medical episode</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/pheobe-bishop-accused-kieren-daniel-mittelheuser-misses-court/105884432</link><description>A medical episode has prevented Kieren Daniel Mittelheuser from appearing in court to face charges of accessory after the fact to murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01df134fd6e5027db2b7c483ec14d8f9</guid></item><item><title>Trump says Netanyahu was "right guy at right time" for Gaza deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/trump-says-netanyahu-was-right-guy-at-right-time/105885748</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db23f0a5c074faa2c47ac9d11317a68e</guid></item><item><title>Jesse Southwell signs with Broncos amid fears of lopsided NRLW competition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/nrlw-jesse-southwell-signs-with-broncos-after-leaving-knights/105885604</link><description>NSW State of Origin halfback Jesse Southwell's two-year deal with the Brisbane Broncos may add to the debate about the NRLW's competitiveness since it expanded to 12 teams.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abe905c2182f063b37016dc4e7f38ab5</guid></item><item><title>Lidia Thorpe's 'burn down Parliament House' remark faces AFP probe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/afp-investigating-lidia-thorpe-burn-down-parliament-house/105885602</link><description>The Australian Federal Police has issued a rare statement confirming it is investigating whether independent senator Lidia Thorpe broke any laws by saying she was prepared to "burn down Parliament House" in support of Palestinians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2fccb71564f1bd7edfc068317149745</guid></item><item><title>Jason Thomas King pleads not guilty to murdering landlord Susan Walker on the Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/jason-thomas-king-pleads-not-guilty-to-murdering-landlord/105885548</link><description>Jason Thomas King is charged with 74-year-old Susan Walker's murder, and pleaded not guilty at the beginning of a Supreme Court trial in Brisbane on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7698ff5a772eef758d0bfa5979b9ee48</guid></item><item><title>Former teacher Rodney Neville Watkins guilty of sexually abusing boys in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/teacher-rodney-neville-watkins-sex-abuse-trial-verdict/105874798</link><description>A former teacher is found guilty of sexually abusing primary school-aged boys in Perth, and one on Rottnest Island, in the 1970s in 1980s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">699b38068724bae2768d7a3807fbfbae</guid></item><item><title>Hamas releases all remaining Israeli hostages in Gaza, IDF confirms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/hamas-releases-all-remaining-israeli-hostages-in-gaza/105885332</link><description>Israel says Hamas has handed over all 20 living hostages in the first phase of the Israel-Gaza ceasefire agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1da4a5a9ff5c0b24b017021965f0b640</guid></item><item><title>Dolphin calf rescued after spending weeks tangled in fishing line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/dolphin-calf-rescued-from-fishing-line-at-forster/105884112</link><description>Marine rescuers issue an urgent plea for people to responsibly dispose of fishing gear after freeing a dolphin calf from a fishing line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90d0d7d157b2b4ce3c86f1c7a19eb88c</guid></item><item><title>Dolphin calf rescued after weeks entangled in fishing line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/dolphin-calf-rescued-after-weeks-entangled-in/105885136</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51fdb7f8edd659af9c6dfb59eb4fd000</guid></item><item><title>Shire of Coolgardie avoids suspension following 'serious concern' over financial management</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/shire-of-coolgardie-avoids-suspension-after-show-cause-notice/105884860</link><description>A debt-laden shire in WA's Goldfields has avoided being suspended over mismanagement allegations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16e5e2b6e5725473f69cc02f3d0213ae</guid></item><item><title>Student who died in Bendigo after being hit by truck remembered as being 'smart and dedicated'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/thom-hosking-remembered-as-glue-of-family-bendigo-crash/105885680</link><description>The family of Thom Hosking are remembering him as a "smart and dedicated student" full of potential.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db15ecb4af424b27835ec48955d7d187</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Diamonds mindful they need to lift against New Zealand's Silver Ferns in Constellation Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/constellation-cup-australia-new-zealand-diamonds-silver-ferns/105885876</link><description>Despite the comfortable series win over South Africa, Australia is mindful it will need to step up a gear in the Constellation Cup against New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5fb5d579d17d83c75a2e69cee809c80</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of Israelis gather at Hostages Square</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/thousands-of-israelis-gather-at-hostages-square,/105886086</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f850a0bac366588a46b981577479166c</guid></item><item><title>Tatiana Dokhotaru told triple-0 her ex-partner was 'trying to kill' her before alleged murder, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/danny-zayat-trial-for-alleged-murder-tatiana-dokhotaru-liverpool/105885166</link><description>Danny Zayat has pleaded not guilty over the alleged murder of his former partner Tatiana Dokhotaru on May 26, 2023, in a high-rise complex in Sydney's south-west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97587d3d724a31ef37090e00aaebbacd</guid></item><item><title>Court hears of 'irreparable damage' inflicted by former Canberra academic awaiting sentencing for rape</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/victim-irreparable-damage-inflicted-by-convicted-rapist-canberra/105884230</link><description>Prosecutors have called for the man to be jailed for a significant period of time after he was found guilty of raping two women by an ACT Supreme Court jury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e73a6eedd6c7c07d93b6a9510cb21e11</guid></item><item><title>Convoy of Red Cross buses drive through devastated Gaza cityscape</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/convoy-of-red-cross-buses-drive-through-devastated/105886166</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e4a8f198fb10cee7f84442e510ad9a6</guid></item><item><title>Woodside North West Shelf gas project extension challenged in Federal Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/federal-court-appeals-over-woodside-north-west-shelf-extension/105884752</link><description>Two separate appeals are launched in the Federal Court in a bid to overturn Environment Minister Murray Watt's approval of Woodside's gas hub extension on the North West Shelf.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">342bee27bf9dff6d11dddd935c41d8df</guid></item><item><title>SA Premier says algal bloom is not 'toxic', despite word appearing in official government advice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/algal-bloom-not-toxic-sa-premier-says/105884118</link><description>South Australia's Premier has questioned the use of the word "toxic" to describe the state's ongoing algal bloom, despite the word being used in government advice and by scientists researching it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0743c8445b475273de4ae2bd594c0830</guid></item><item><title>John Torney's mother gives evidence in his manslaughter committal hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/john-torney-committal-hearing-emma-bates/105883888</link><description>John Torney's committal hearing begins as his mother tells the court she was the one who called police to check on the woman before her body was found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27f97cc7b1bc58b7979769f5ce683c9f</guid></item><item><title>Red Cross vehicles carrying hostages leave Gaza City</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/red-cross-vehicles-carrying-hostages-leave-gaza/105886272</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7abe747fbd04a6b6c29d3d125b6ca2d4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump touches down in Israel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/donald-trump-touches-down-in-israel/105886378</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2da0fd6431100f72b5e26c2aefa69995</guid></item><item><title>Coronial inquest into death in custody of Dictor Dongrin begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/dictor-dongrin-coronial-inquest/105881152</link><description>A coronial inquest has heard that a 29-year-old man was left for 21 hours without physical observation despite telling staff he had a history of suffering seizures while withdrawing from alcohol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8a0dcfc06d0a8b925f8dddcae2cfd13</guid></item><item><title>Who's in and who's out in Sussan Ley's new shadow cabinet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/shadow-cabinet-reshuffle-federal-politics-ley-hastie-duniam/105886202</link><description>The changes follow two high-profile departures from shadow cabinet within a month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04f8fd366d0a2f3ed19841529ba4629a</guid></item><item><title>CCTV footage shows Stephanie Wynne's car being stolen from her driveway.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/cctv-footage-of-stephanie-wynne-s-car-being-stolen-/105886128</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8b30afdec36fc116a72eaced52329fa</guid></item><item><title>Inside Victoria's escalating crime wave, where a car is reported stolen to insurers every 44 minutes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/victoria-carjacking-rises-as-families-left-on-edge/105885482</link><description>A rise in car theft and carjackings in this state has also seen parents left terrorised as cars are taken with their children inside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1d8b1d3339f8fa66e6e20ad33fdcab3</guid></item><item><title>Money wiped from alleged vandals' bill over Bendigo artefact damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/bendigo-dragon-museum-alleged-vandals-damage-bill-reduced/105885912</link><description>Lawyers for a couple accused of vandalising significant artefacts say the damage caused by sprinkling vegetable oil was unintentional and part of a "blessing".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55d7778c273f3b330ec42c4727ff697b</guid></item><item><title>ACT family violence victims 'waiting 3 or 4 days' for help, inquiry hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/act-family-violence/105886158</link><description>A levy meant to improve support for victims of family violence in the ACT has come under scrutiny in an inquiry, which has heard concerns about how funds are managed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0953fe9b1b0c85e2488c739e87e4df7b</guid></item><item><title>New eyewitness testimony attempts to shed more light on mysterious death of Mark Haines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/mark-haines-inquest-returns-for-fifth-week-of-hearings/105134566</link><description>How Mark Haines's body came to be found on train tracks outside of Tamworth has remained a mystery for 37 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0254cc5f1992da32e9ae401f0ebbfed7</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump writes a message upon arrival at Israel's Knesset</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/donald-trump-writes-a-message-upon-arrival-at/105886564</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b98ce558df901aa34da9e041a08f54b3</guid></item><item><title>Frustration mounts among Qantas customers as personal data released on dark web</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/frustration-mounts-among-qantas-customers-over-data-breach/105885312</link><description>The airline's customers voice their concerns and disappointment after cybercriminals release their personal data on the dark web.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b231e8012746670f061284735b7d6e0</guid></item><item><title>Families of Israeli hostages prepare to be reunited with their loved ones</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/families-of-israeli-hostages-prepare-to-be/105886614</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d55e8a434f5bffabf15e1e0ef6096349</guid></item><item><title>Victoria is in the grip of a car theft crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/victoria-is-in-the-grip-of-a-car-theft-crisis/105886626</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c8d1572c5790bacdcf9f046246b9f89</guid></item><item><title>Government overhauls its proposed superannuation changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/government-overhauls-its-proposed-superannuation/105886646</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7832422b564ea7c9e914c9d44a5a76f6</guid></item><item><title>Family of hit and run victim call for justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/family-of-hit-and-run-victim-call-for-justice/105886666</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">023224101da80413f1e83fd4566ab93f</guid></item><item><title>Former hostage Alon Ohel is received by the IDF representatives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/former-hostage-alon-ohel-is-received-by-the-idf/105886676</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9b974a6ff8210b47a8cf7552878c5cc</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian prisoners return to West Bank</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/palestinian-prisoners-return-to-west-bank/105886688</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edc1c510491d57e93a9f4e3d2901fcc6</guid></item><item><title>Mackay cane train derailment 01</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/mackay-cane-train-derailment-01/105886672</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6357c2ad5dfa953132561e35537ea0e</guid></item><item><title>Mackay cane train driver critically injured after locomotive collides with truck</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/mackay-train-driver-critically-injured-in-derailment/105886630</link><description>A Mackay cane train driver suffers critical injuries after colliding with a truck at a level crossing in north Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e715961bfc48c2b10101c6c56345b3e</guid></item><item><title>Israeli Knesset greets Donald Trump with standing ovation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/israeli-knesset-greets-donald-trump-with-standing/105886700</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bfffb3b35f2e8af404061c39f16a163</guid></item><item><title>Former Israeli hostage Omri Miran reunites with his wife</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/israeli-hostage-omri-miran-reunites-with-his-wife/105886704</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">751adeef4268226e4a315eb479cbaf4e</guid></item><item><title>Queensland council loses $2 million in alleged international fraud incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/queensland-council-alleged-victim-international-fraud/105886682</link><description>Noosa Council alleges it was targeted by "international criminal gangs" in December last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a81b0adf1072bdc643391700c8d3dc7</guid></item><item><title>Released Israeli hostages wave at crowds as they arrive at hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/released-israeli-hostages-arrive-at-hospital/105886776</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">818105ab787786e2c78fa5d4f2be0c23</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian President Abbas arrives in Egypt ahead of Gaza peace summit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/palestinian-president-abbas-arrives-in-egypt-ahead/105886770</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a51b4c519004b388277a2f9b5b8f1eb</guid></item><item><title>Members of Knesset removed after heckling Trump during address</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/heckler-removed-during-trumps-address-to-knesset/105886818</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4961a52dc7802f4b58f9e3f08e125136</guid></item><item><title>Israeli hostages reunite with their loved ones</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/israeli-hostages-reunite-with-their-loved-ones/105886836</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02d664b5e02fdd144286753ad07b004f</guid></item></channel></rss>