<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 03:12:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>'Rogue' tour guides threaten Gold Coast glow-worm population</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/illegal-tour-guides-threaten-gold-coast-glow-worms/106299890</link><description>Last year two operators were fined for running glow-worm cave tours in the Springbrook and Tamborine national parks without the required permits.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f2cfeee4d953e332e303330f7a82147</guid></item><item><title>Australia knocked out of under-19 Cricket World Cup by England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/australia-knocked-out-of-under-19-cricket-world-cup-by-england/106302650</link><description>Ollie Peake's hobbling and defiant captain's knock of 100 has proved too little too late to rescue Australia as their reign as under-19 World Cup champions was ended by England in a compelling semifinal in Zimbabwe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80e061901ed74c831535e7098735692e</guid></item><item><title>'Bloodbath' at Washington Post as massive layoffs announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/washington-post-layoffs/106307024</link><description>The Jeff Bezos-owned paper, which famously brought down US President Richard Nixon, will drastically cut back in size and lay off workers in all its departments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8394731a7449ead8a495e63eba201e42</guid></item><item><title>Strict caps on bottled water extraction urged for World Heritage-listed Springbrook</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/water-extraction-caps-at-world-heritage-springbrook/106304388</link><description>A long-awaited study warns that the extraction of bottled water from the World Heritage-listed Springbrook area poses a potential risk to the ancient Gondwana rainforests and should be strictly limited.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19d076e599ae81db17a9effaa24af962</guid></item><item><title>What Israel's President Isaac Herzog has said about Gaza, and why he won't be arrested in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/herzog-will-be-aware-controversy-wont-be-arrested-in-australia/106311734</link><description>When Israel's president lands in Australia this weekend, he can expect an official red carpet treatment. But he will be all too aware of the controversy his visit is generating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ffdecd9e59cf515e239536238754ac7</guid></item><item><title>Georgia Voll helps Royal Challengers Bengaluru win Indian Women's Premier League</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/royal-challengers-bengaluru-win-indian-women-premier-league/106312236</link><description>Royal Challengers Bengaluru pulled off the biggest successful chase in the Women's Premier League to win their second title in the Indian franchise-based T20 league.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e308434821166760b39b511e513be5cf</guid></item><item><title>Beyond the Songs Inside: After the applause</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/beyond-the-songs-inside-documentary/106032528</link><description>Creative prison programs are celebrated for their ability to heal and transform incarcerated people. But are they enough to break the cycle?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">522012622427958b8365731ca8a4abfe</guid></item><item><title>Josh Hazlewood out of T20 World Cup with injury in another blow to Australia's hopes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/josh-hazlewood-out-of-t20-world-cup-injury-australia/106315684</link><description>Josh Hazlewood is ruled out of Australia's T20 World Cup campaign as he continues to recover from the injuries which kept him from playing in the summer's Ashes series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc2eaa2ecdfd92d77e913bc4aef7b367</guid></item><item><title>Three people die, three others including child injured in car crash south of Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/qld-logan-triple-fatal-crash-yarrabilba/106319000</link><description>Two cars collided on Waterford Tamborine Road in Yarrabilba yesterday afternoon, leaving three people dead and three others with serious injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">443c9497bff34f194f67a833965686d9</guid></item><item><title>Rain brings relief and road closures after record heatwave in South Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/rain-brings-relief-and-road-closures-in-outback-sa/106321082</link><description>High rainfall in north-eastern South Australia brings some relief for pastoralists after record-breaking heat, with a reprieve expected for metropolitan Adelaide this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8abb8433aa6e8a46aaa308bd29d9653</guid></item><item><title>ASIO was told about Bondi shooter's terrorist links years before attack, former spy claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/bondi-shooting-spy-claims-told-asio-terror-links-four-corners/106306092</link><description>The former undercover agent spied on the Akrams when he infiltrated a Sydney IS terror cell for Australia's intelligence agency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38e7d75b35ff2d3c4a5b6be5b9bb9d73</guid></item><item><title>'Massive' Indonesian ghost barge washes up on tiny Torres Strait island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/mystery-indonesian-ghost-barge-washed-up-in-torres-strait/106323116</link><description>The barge drifted into Australian waters from Indonesia after breaking from its moorings during bad weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08b39ef063e5e2f00075ab3cf9dbea37</guid></item><item><title>More people say they'll vote One Nation. What are they voting for?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/one-nation-policy-platforms-pauline-hanson/106296838</link><description>One Nation questions if man-made climate change is real, wants to wind back access to abortion care and plans to pay the HECS debts of doctors working in the regions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed4bdf450e353d8bca00c742667777f</guid></item><item><title>Former ATSIC head Geoff Clark was jailed but his community says legal issues persist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/framlingham-aboriginal-trust-shares-court-fallout-geoff-clark/106305592</link><description>Former ATSIC leader Geoff Clark was jailed in 2024, yet some members of his community say legal issues linger on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec0abba8310f5f8dfa22011b1c737b70</guid></item><item><title>Licensed program to kill native animals 'weak' and 'outdated' inquiry told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/licences-to-harm-native-animals-inquiry/106320826</link><description>Animal welfare groups are calling for a major overhaul into the system that allows native animals to be killed in NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93d7971e8816215b902c8e022b64e384</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth asks to meet Roblox following reports of child grooming. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/commonwealth-roblox-reports-of-child-grooming/106323242</link><description>Roblox has been called to an urgent meeting with the federal government in the wake of reports that children are being groomed by predators and exposed to sexually explicit material on the popular online gaming platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8186dce135dbe17f29c38ae0b2e5a4fb</guid></item><item><title>Elvis Presley 'unguarded' in unseen footage used in new Baz Luhrmann film</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/elvis-presley-unguarded-in-unseen-footage-in-baz-luhrmann-film/106327408</link><description>When director Baz Luhrmann and his team uncovered hours of previously unseen Elvis Presley recordings, Luhrmann abandoned his original plans, deciding to "get out of the way" and let Presley tell his own story.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18a8befc1c6399e513d75719298bd33a</guid></item><item><title>Iran's rulers face 'defections and disobedience', but will it be enough to topple the regime?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/amid-us-iran-nuclear-talks-will-defections-spark-regime-change/106323120</link><description>As talks between Washington and Tehran over a nuclear deal continue, fractures within the regime are starting to emerge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec8f5a39abe057d153a273869091cc1d</guid></item><item><title>Australian T20 World Cup squad looks different but do not count it out, Mitch Marsh says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/injury-hit-australia-open-t20-world-cup-campaign-against-ireland/106329438</link><description>Despite a slew of key injuries leaving the Australian team unrecognisable, captain Mitch Marsh is confident about the experience left in the side.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e7e79b7afbfde0a033b919098cc0b12</guid></item><item><title>Surgeon Kelvin Kong's life growing up Chinese and Indigenous in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/kelvin-kong-s-growing-up-chinese-and-indigenous-australia/106326388</link><description>Australia's first identified First Nations surgeon, Dr Kelvin Kong spoke about his Malaysian Chinese heritage during the annual Wang Gungwu lecture at Parliament House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3366e9b48200b228bb48ce12f315720</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos striker Mo Toure scores hat-trick on starting debut in English Championship for Norwich</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/socceroos-striker-mohamed-toure-hat-trick-debut-norwich/106330220</link><description>Mohamed Toure moved to England recently on a $5 million deal and it is already looking like a great decision for the 21-year-old forward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ecfd2aa16103898748a1ab83e8c75e7</guid></item><item><title>Doongmabulla Springs decision leaves Qld government to weigh appeal or face trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/doongmabulla-springs-qld-government-appeal-or-face-trial/106305714</link><description>Wangan and Jagalingou peoples await the state government's next move after a win in their fight to have alleged damage to a sacred site near a mine in Central Queensland investigated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">409498e1a5333e429fc6fc92646dec77</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia readies up to 8,000 troops for Board of Peace efforts in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/indonesia-to-send-8000-troops-to-gaza-idf-peacekeeping/106330718</link><description>The move makes Indonesia the first country to clearly commit troops to a multinational peacekeeping effort in the war-torn enclave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb09709ab6a43276c0ef5777b42146b8</guid></item><item><title>Axed literary magazine Meanjin is resurrected by Queensland University of Technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/meanjin-magazine-finds-new-home-queensland-university-technology/106331850</link><description>The 85-year-old literary journal Meanjin will return to Brisbane, where it was first published, after it was controversially closed by Melbourne University Press last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8381f55200bc2cef76893ac168c73d93</guid></item><item><title>Australia cruises to victory over Ireland in T20 World Cup opener</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/cricket-t20-world-cup-australia-ireland-blog-scores-stats/106330266</link><description>Australia beats Ireland by 67 runs to win its first game at the T20 World Cup, after captain Mitch Marsh was a late out due to testicular bleeding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f10653e8e126254d5fa9b92b8b0d7bf</guid></item><item><title>Transparency concerns as Bougainville's Panguna mine that sparked civil war on path to reopen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/bougainville-signs-secretive-deal-to-reopen-panguna-mine/106331778</link><description>The Autonomous Bougainville Government signs a secretive deal to reopen the huge Panguna gold and copper mine that sparked a catastrophic civil war three decades ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7a5ff00e0503cc102c30c6e22dae858</guid></item><item><title>South Africa beats Afghanistan at Twenty20 World Cup after two super overs at Narendra Modi Stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/south-africa-afghanistan-t20-world-cup-double-super-over/106334290</link><description>South Africa wins the most dramatic T20 World Cup group stage clash with Afghanistan, featuring two super overs and countless twists of fortune.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb1593268b4f75b9895b6ade64f0c231</guid></item><item><title>Former Tottenham manager Ange Postecoglou says Spurs 'not a big club' in wake of Thomas Frank sacking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/former-tottenham-manager-ange-postecoglou-on-club-issues/106339490</link><description>Tottenham Hotspur are "not a big club" because of their policy in the transfer market, former manager Ange Postecoglou has said in the wake of the London club's sacking of head coach Thomas Frank on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ce56a4955c12cf141f86e6540834b3a</guid></item><item><title>Albany Woollen Mills' 101 years celebrated via shared love of blankets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/albany-woollen-mill-in-albany-celebrates-101-years/106322356</link><description>Established in 1925, Western Australia's first and only woollen mill transformed raw wool into fabric and blankets, becoming a cornerstone of Albany's industry before closing in 2002.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebfd4b3313c5a634d2a8d4ee911573eb</guid></item><item><title>What to know about the Year of the Horse and Lunar New Year celebrations in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/how-lunar-new-year-of-the-horse-is-celebrated-in-australia/106295942</link><description>The Year of the Horse is here and 2026 is a rare "Red Horse" year. Find out what it means, which zodiac animal you are, and how Lunar New Year is celebrated across Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3a175856e4652c5d58d63f6eaaa7e9b</guid></item><item><title>Ley didn't define herself by her gender but women might relate to her workplace woes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/liberal-party-women-sussan-ley-leadership-spill/106340280</link><description>The issue for the Liberal Party is not simply the toppling of a female leader. It's also about what happened to that leader while she was in the job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">596c3a295f267e6667ca697953519fbd</guid></item><item><title>From Japan to Israel, elections are reshaping global politics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/elections-japan-israel-ukraine-global-politics-trump/106337028</link><description>At a time when so much of the global conversation is about the rapid decline of democracy, it is striking what a huge impact elections are having on world events just now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bcebe10dbbdf738fed5ebfaac390428</guid></item><item><title>Easy, tasty and nutritious recipes for sharing this Ramadan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/easy-tasty-and-nutritious-recipes-for-sharing-this-ramadan/106331120</link><description>Looking for easy, nutritious Ramadan recipes? These options will help you prepare for and break your fast well.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb9d0165cd75c38640ee10f031f1d403</guid></item><item><title>Innovative cattle loading ramp puts animal welfare at centre of design</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/wide-cattle-loading-ramp-reduces-transport-stress/106305408</link><description>A retired truck driver has developed a wide, steel, cattle-loading ramp that allows animals to walk side by side, mimicking natural herd behaviour and reducing noise, agitation and the risk of injury during transport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae83b1c62371e347cfe86622f6a1efe5</guid></item><item><title>Easy ways to help protect your hair from chlorine and saltwater damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/how-to-avoid-chlorine-and-saltwater-hair-damage-when-swimming/106334202</link><description>Regular beach days or laps at the local pool can leave our hair looking and feeling quite different.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ed59e0b1894ab058082b567c448eb32</guid></item><item><title>NT film industry on national stage as Kangaroo, Top End Bub and Journey Home win AACTA Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/nt-film-industry-on-national-stage-at-aacta-awards-movies/106345258</link><description>The NT's small but mighty presence is shining on the global stage 40 years after Crocodile Dundee rocketed its film industry into the stratosphere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6b91e7462a835a8868e55cdd28f79a5</guid></item><item><title>Statues of Amy Sherwin, Australia's first opera star, unveiled at Hobart's Hadley's Hotel in bid to cement legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/peter-schipperheyn-statues-of-amy-sherwin-opera-star-unveiled/106344982</link><description>An effort to bring new recognition to a Tasmanian opera star who became world famous, but who died poor, culminates in the unveiling of two statues of her in Hobart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0073ccc352d93326f0623615a91690e2</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous side overturns 14-0 deficit to down Maori in women's All Stars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/womens-all-stars-indigenous-maori-jada-taylor/106347124</link><description>The Indigenous team overturns a 14-0 deficit to score a rousing comeback win over the Maori in the Women's All Stars clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f14485169561b894f2afb767bb7402d</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous and Māori All Stars play out dramatic 16-all draw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/nrl-all-stars-mens-indigenous-maori-result/106347244</link><description>It went down to the final seconds, but the Indigenous and Maori NRL All Stars could not be separated with both sides left to rue missed chances after a 16-all draw.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d01cc349479a0292d97ba58d32f2571c</guid></item><item><title>City of Melbourne quiet on plan for Southbank's 'ugly' red stairs, long after design competition announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/city-of-melbourne-southbank-red-stair-replacement-plan-stalls/106274362</link><description>A Melbourne council unveiled a lucrative competition to replace Southbank's much-derided red stairs. But a year after it was due to start, the plan appears to have gone nowhere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">074f26e344537a0ab6c98a25242c702d</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: The anxiety and joy of dual moguls bronze for Matt Graham, leader and captain of the Australian team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/matt-graham-bronze-leader-moguls-duals-winter-olympics/106347650</link><description>Matt Graham's brilliant bronze in the dual moguls, and the incredible response from his teammates, proved to everyone that he is the true leader of this Winter Olympic squad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cba69d73cf10c866f2189e3ff247f598</guid></item><item><title>Chalmers mocks Taylor's proposal for bipartisan budget savings taskforce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/coalition-proposes-bipartisan-budget-taskforce/106348078</link><description>Angus Taylor wrote to the prime minister pitching the plan just days after being elected leader of the Liberal Party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2e1b7a17f7bbb632412e2760a78b3ec</guid></item><item><title>Israeli air strikes target Gaza Palestinians just days before Board of Peace meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/israeli-air-strikes-days-before-board-of-peace-meeting/106348162</link><description>US President Donald Trump says the first meeting of his newly created Board of Peace will take place on Thursday, with over $7 billion to be pledged for reconstruction and humanitarian efforts in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88fa2f84ef68dfaf1b37d3f11b53b0d6</guid></item><item><title>New tobacco laws proposed by WA government to target stores selling illegal cigarettes, vapes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/new-wa-tobacco-legislation-to-target-illegal-cigarettes-vapes/106348588</link><description>Western Australia could soon have some of the nation's toughest illegal tobacco penalties, including fines of up to $21 million and hefty prison terms for possessing commercial quantities of illicit products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d104e6ddf23aa26a18c6b0d065092530</guid></item><item><title>Senior Liberals deny involvement in draft policy to ban migrants from Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/ley-draft-migration-policy-australian-values-statement/106348870</link><description>A leaked copy of the Liberal Party's migration policy prepared before Sussan Ley was ousted included plans to "elevate" the current non-binding Australian values statement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afcbb687b8d26ea4579377278e93aa57</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor bets on migration politics amid global rightward shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/migration-social-cohesion-language-support-division-policy/106348608</link><description>If migration is treated primarily as a cultural fault line, rather than an economic system embedded in national growth, the debate will remain loud. The structural reform will remain unfinished.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86414a7a131a25b45dbc0a43798c1c16</guid></item><item><title>Robert Duvall, star of The Godfather and Apocalypse Now, dies at 95</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/robert-duvall-star-of-godfather-and-apocalypse-now-dies-at-95/106352132</link><description>Oscar winner Robert Duvall, known for films such as The Godfather and Apocalypse Now, has died at the age of 95.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c557714626458849acf4e2f9e4b0c251</guid></item><item><title>How to decide what type of car insurance is best for you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/how-do-i-know-what-car-insurance-is-best-for-me-/106260688</link><description>Choosing the right car insurance option can feel daunting, but it's the kind of task that it pays to get right. So, how can you decide which type is most suitable for you?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19c1a606228973fe803d3604b38ad3b1</guid></item><item><title>Results show high levels of lead contamination in dust around Hobart, as EPA flags further tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/nyrstar-lead-pollution-epa-tests-hobart/106339682</link><description>High levels of lead contamination have been found in dust samples taken from suburban locations close to Nyrstar's Hobart zinc smelter, documents obtained by the ABC show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df4c929be90ce6716c442950274a84e2</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate hike worries? Here's some good news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/why-the-reserve-bank-interest-rate-hike-may-be-a-one-off/106350914</link><description>Fresh warnings of further rate rises have been enough to send shivers up the collective spine of new homeowners, but if there's any comfort to be had, it's this: Don't believe a word of the forecasts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67fb51f52c86bc4d83c2be7c7d52564e</guid></item><item><title>Anti-slavery commissioner calls for tougher laws amid forced labour concerns for Ansell and Kmart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/anti-slavery-commissioner-tough-laws-dumping-ground-kmart-ansell/106349728</link><description>Australia's anti-slavery commissioner calls for tough new laws forcing companies to take slavery in their supply chains seriously, as Ansell and Kmart face scrutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">304d8b8d78c81209b940b9f107989101</guid></item><item><title>News quiz: Year of the Horse traditions, zodiac facts and festive customs across Asia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/lunar-new-year-of-the-horse-quiz-china-south-korea-vietnam-asia/106348886</link><description>How much do you know about the Year of the Horse and unique Lunar New Year traditions in Asian countries? Put your knowledge to the test with these 10 questions and see if you're a true Lunar New Year expert!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">664780860b8f5a75f0169a583ee380ca</guid></item><item><title>Irish rugby to investigate racial abuse towards Test debutant Edwin Edogbo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/ireland-rugby-test-debut-edwin-edogbo-racial-abuse/106352164</link><description>The Irish Rugby Football Union has said it will launch an investigation after turning comments off a social media post that congratulated the country's newest Test debutant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">261d685409d12066905edfb9104ada79</guid></item><item><title>Mould, asbestos, collapsed ceilings plague some South Australian schools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/sa-schools-in-need-of-repair/106334244</link><description>Almost two years after a state government report revealed 35 per cent of all buildings within the Department for Education's portfolio were past their design life, many schools are still plagued with issues including mould, asbestos and rotting windows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fabb2b4476c5886be92e1dda09f3283</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the ISIS-linked families in Syria who want to return to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/who-are-isis-linked-australian-families-in-syria-al-roj-camp/106352074</link><description>Australia has made limited progress in clearing a passage for the Australian women and their children, citing safety issues in and around the camps, and security concerns back home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b94dd1490b366423951626bba907299</guid></item><item><title>Pod Save America and why Australians remain obssessed with US politics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/pod-save-america-why-australians-are-obssessed-with-us-politics/106327878</link><description>Huge crowds have flocked to live shows for the popular and influential Pod Save America podcast, suggesting Australia's obsession with US politics isn't going away anytime soon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29fd6077abedec21a6c24a6198c4c894</guid></item><item><title>Albanese says Australian government will not help ISIS-linked families leave Syria or return home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/anthony-albanese-on-isis-families-trying-to-leave-syria/106352492</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese insists the federal government will not repatriate the Australian families with links to Islamic State fighters who remain in Syria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faa866e3881f2d6646422dcbe7b56295</guid></item><item><title>Plains-wanderer recorded for first time on outback Queensland cattle station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/rare-plains-wanderer-bird-recorded-on-cattle-station/106350256</link><description>A project with dozens of monitoring sites across the Queensland property confirms the presence of the critically endangered plains-wanderer by analysing bird calls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fb6753c73ebbb858ac8b4791fe49656</guid></item><item><title>Former ACT commissioner Vanessa Turnbull-Roberts accuses public servant of sexual assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/vanessa-turnbull-roberts-alleges-sexual-assault/106352482</link><description>Vanessa Turnbull-Roberts says she stepped down as the ACT's first Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander children and young people commissioner to prioritise her safety after being subjected to sexual harassment and sexual assault by a public servant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d6b858d730eb0ebaae68c60183f36f5</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor reveals shadow ministry, elevating Andrew Hastie and Jacinta Nampijinpa Price</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/angus-taylor-preparing-to-unveil-shadow-ministry/106354092</link><description>The new Liberal leader announces his shadow ministry, elevating prominent right-faction supporters including West Australian MP Andrew Hastie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">989975fa7a8805821e114a08b60c7715</guid></item><item><title>Kyneton women's football players greenlit to join Central Victorian Football League</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/kyneton-womens-football-riddell-update-central-league/106354024</link><description>A long-running saga in country women's football is set to close as a central Victorian team that had been left without a competition will now be allowed to play in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54f16d5c55e8c9bba00d01c3d6d165d3</guid></item><item><title>French Polynesia drug haul hits $2.4 billion in a month as third shipment intercepted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/french-polynesia-third-drug-shipment-cocaine/106352864</link><description>French authorities seized a 2.4-tonne drug shipment near French Polynesia during a joint operation with the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8b05b9703fd79abe25cc2318a523413</guid></item><item><title>Addin Fonua-Blake and Briton Nikora embrace chance to play State of Origin following eligibility changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/addin-fonua-blake-briton-nikora-state-of-origin/106355576</link><description>Cronulla duo Briton Nikora and Addin Fonua-Blake have both praised the rule changes that will give the pair a chance at State of Origin football they thought had long passed them by.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ec581ac1f034662bed78ff674c00b7</guid></item><item><title>Jesse Jackson, civil rights leader and US presidential hopeful, dead at 84</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/civil-rghts-leader-jesse-jackson-dies-age-84/106356528</link><description>The two-time Democratic presidential hopeful remembered for powerful speeches died peacefully surrounded by loved ones, his family said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bef1e4b64b56ce290b7d00444b297818</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump to decide on sending weapons to Taiwan 'soon' despite warnings from China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/donald-trump-make-call-on-taiwan-weapons-deal-soon/106356662</link><description>Despite China's President Xi Jinping warning the US not to send weapons to Taiwan, Donald Trump says he will make a decision soon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35e54c9ae2cb4338e28fe081a4d776d3</guid></item><item><title>Richard Roxburgh, Damon Herriman and Toby Schmitz star in 'wickedly funny' play Art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/art-the-play-richard-roxburgh-damon-herriman-toby-schmitz/106051888</link><description>In the 1994 French play Art, Serge spends 160,000 euros on an all-white painting, horrifying his friend Marc. It might just wreck their decades-long friendship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf94795c60e3d3af64640f380e98e6b3</guid></item><item><title>Millionaire Gary Stevenson's dire warning for Australian property market losing the 'fair go'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/economist-gary-stevenson-warns-australia-losing-the-fair-go/106342536</link><description>British economist Gary Stevenson is on a speaking tour, warning Australia will follow the path of the UK with "poverty exploding" unless politicians deal with inequality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f588e11282bda2e3e28ac0a5b4d7af5d</guid></item><item><title>HungryPanda riders say Chinese police intimidating families in China over Sydney protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/hungrypanda-riders-chinese-police-threats-sydney-australia/106353996</link><description>Riders embroiled in a dispute over pay and conditions with food delivery company HungryPanda in Sydney say Chinese police have asserted pressure back home to stop them protesting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00b78e0a081535d928622de443de63b8</guid></item><item><title>Hindmarsh Island bridge dispute told through Ngarrindjeri women's art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/ngarrindjeri-women-retell-hindmarsh-island-bridge-story/106282804</link><description>In the 1990s, a group of Indigenous women were accused of fabricating claims of sacred sites to stop the construction of a bridge south of Adelaide. It was a decision that has impacted a community for decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c8df9f180475c2f0cfe199f0433a284</guid></item><item><title>Telstra accused of environmental breaches in culturally-significant area in SA national park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/telstra-investigated-environmental-breach-south-australia-site/106349226</link><description>Sources say the actions will likely affect Aboriginal communities and that the investigation was not shared with the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b5f492e4ab694c6050d7c2fadc97f21</guid></item><item><title>Iran announces temporary closure of Strait of Hormuz during US nuclear talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/iran-announces-closure-of-hormuz-strait-amid-us-nuclear-talks/106356970</link><description>Iran says it temporarily closed the Strait of Hormuz — a vital international shipping route — as it entered a new round of talks with the US over its nuclear capabilities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">811f56dfe4adc1e2398db88c571e6b4b</guid></item><item><title>Pauline Hanson issues partial apology for suggesting there are no 'good' Muslims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/pauline-hanson-partially-apologises-for-muslim-remarks/106357130</link><description>The One Nation leader qualified her earlier remarks, which had been met with condemnation, while reiterating calls for tougher vetting processes for Muslim migrants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef8666bfdfbfd0c8dffd9a0c82b5b3cd</guid></item><item><title>Foo Fighters announce 2026 Australian stadium tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/foo-fighters-to-tour-australia-2026-dave-grohl-special-guests/106357718</link><description>American rock superstars Foo Fighters will return to Australia for a run of stadium shows before the year is out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a1855fdd5149c72de22208ce0af24ae</guid></item><item><title>Real Madrid star Vinícius Júnior says Benfica's Gianluca Prestianni racially abused him in Champions League match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/champions-league-racism-vinicius-junior-real-madrid-benfica/106357730</link><description>Real Madrid forward Vinícius Júnior accuses an opponent of racially abusing him during a Champions League game against Benfica, leading to the game being halted for nearly 10 minutes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">659589228e0656b84af72920641782c0</guid></item><item><title>Housing to play part in future of both old and new ABC sites in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/housing-plans-for-new-and-old-abc-adelaide-sites/106357376</link><description>The ABC's managing director says its current Adelaide bureau could be redeveloped in a similar way to an apartment building nearby, while the premier says affordable apartments will still be included on the new CBD site.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">016a01cde2182b1aeb6e120fc901d875</guid></item><item><title>Is it ever a good idea to stay together for the kids?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/should-you-ever-stay-together-for-the-kids/106281890</link><description>When a relationships breaks down, sometimes we think staying in the familiar discomfort is less scary — and even protective — for our kids. But is it ever a good idea to stay in an unhappy relationship for the sake of the children?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbe4bbc74caa9ba1918949fae6630fe1</guid></item><item><title>Chalmers suggests ex-RBA governor's spending critique is due to personal vendetta</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/chalmers-dismisses-criticism-from-philip-lowe/106359398</link><description>Treasurer Jim Chalmers says Philip Lowe was critical of the government over spending because it did not re-appoint him as RBA governor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4578c9f616d6026ee0f378a69efa25e</guid></item><item><title>Mazda, Nissan, Hyundai and Subaru face multi-million-dollar penalties under NVES</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/new-vehicle-efficiency-standard-results-mazda-nissan-penalties/106358770</link><description>Major car brands are staring down the barrel of multi-million-dollar penalties for exceeding their emissions, the first results of the federal government's climate laws for new vehicles have revealed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45198840bd21329442d531c79bcbff0d</guid></item><item><title>Glove found near Nancy Guthrie's home fails to produce DNA match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/glove-found-near-nancy-guthrie-s-home-fails-to-produce-dna-match/106359296</link><description>The glove resembled a pair worn by an armed man in a ski mask seen in video footage shortly before she was abducted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab853563a7fa8ce16c63ba12962c8784</guid></item><item><title>Alcoa hit with record fine for unlawfully clearing WA jarrah forests for bauxite mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/alcoa-fined-for-clearing-jarrah-forest-for-bauxite-mine/106359988</link><description>US mining giant Alcoa is forced to pay $55 million after unlawfully clearing parts of a Western Australian native forest to mine bauxite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f74bb47c6f321183a916fc154005c8ee</guid></item><item><title>Former Coles manager admits 'human error' over Shapes 'Down Down' pricing in federal court showdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/coles-accc-discounts-federal-court/106358474</link><description>A former Coles manager has given evidence in the federal court on day three of a bombshell case between the consumer watchdog and supermarket giant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fac3387b11a41f3cb04ca5d82d1e043</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Macarthur FC captain Ulises Dávila fined $11k over A-League card fixing saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/ex-a-league-captain-ulises-d%C3%A1vila-fined-over-betting-scandal/106358086</link><description>Former Macarthur FC captain Ulises Dávila avoids jail time over his involvement in a card fixing scandal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d649323fcbad3f77ec947285f3251da</guid></item><item><title>Navy chief's speech disrupted, bomb squad called after rocks thrown through glass door at Canberra hotel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/rocks-thrown-defence-industry-conference-hyatt-canberra/106357386</link><description>Officers are looking for two men who fled on bikes after rocks smashed a glass door, halting a defence industry event in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e12c9133d30ce455cfcf6db31deb63d2</guid></item><item><title>Blue Bush Floodway enjoyed by all.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/blue-bush-floodway-enjoyed-by-all/106360146</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbd2f162df0e8fed005d6a35a8340a73</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106359046</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">077e4b34cad227fccef803151960b1af</guid></item><item><title>Queensland man accused of offering $730 to adopt and abuse overseas children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/qld-man-refused-bail-over-alleged-child-sex-procurement-plot/106360740</link><description>A Queensland man accused of offering to pay more than $700 to adopt children overseas so he could have sex with them is refused bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0adc407b09567e623482d48b0cf6af66</guid></item><item><title>Tackling 'blatant' fake discounting, restoring consumer trust among ACCC's priorities for 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/accc-outlines-priorities-for-2026-including-fake-discounting/106359994</link><description>ACCC chair Gina Cass-Gottlieb outlines the consumer watchdog's priorities for 2026, including targeting "blatant" fake discounting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2937ff2740ca14e3dac8a4082576d74e</guid></item><item><title>Mary Fowler named in Matildas Women's Asian Cup squad, Sam Kerr to captain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/matildas-womens-asian-cup-squad-mary-fowler-return-sam-kerr/106358720</link><description>Considered the Matildas' X-factor, Mary Fowler has been named in the Women's Asian Cup squad, just 10 months after sustaining an ACL injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94e1148a75a920a6b5eef99a0cdf14d1</guid></item><item><title>Quiz: Which books are these literary quotes from?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/famous-book-quotes-quiz/106321984</link><description>Are you happiest with your nose in a book? Did you spend summer reading at the beach? This quiz is for you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93263cc459c19ed242af066f07f52020</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, February 19: Britpop, beats and a lust for life on Trainspotting's deathless soundtrack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/trainspotting-soundtrack-30th-anniversary-danny-boyle-britpop/106354570</link><description>Most films are lucky to get just one needle-drop moment embedded in the Zeitgeist. Trainspotting boasted several.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ab3fc2c71c82699927e06d1a58d6cf7</guid></item><item><title>Government spending is creeping up and threatening Australia’s 'low-debt' status</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/government-spending-threatening-australias-low-debt-status/105579046</link><description>Australia will cease to be a low-debt country and be more vulnerable in a future crisis without a combination of spending restraint and tax reform, a new report has warned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13ac01b1668865c59fb5bf518f92a919</guid></item><item><title>Senate committee features climate disinformation, the Atlas Network, and Dr Karl's clash with One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/climate-disinformation-senate-committee-dr-karl-atlas-network/106350002</link><description>The scourge of AI-slopaganda, viral disinformation campaigns and online attacks against individuals and institutions is going to get far worse before it gets better, if the latest public hearings on the topic are any indication.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc806ab7e06e7cc45d048d4f225dbed0</guid></item><item><title>Danielle Scott's Winter Olympic silver ends years of pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/danielle-scott-aerials-silver-medal-2026-winter-olympics/106361322</link><description>In this most tension-filled Winter Olympic sport, it's no wonder tears are a by-product of both success and failure. Thankfully for Dani Scott, this time she was crying tears of pure joy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e5d5a3ecb08453f6f6bb9cdeaccc263</guid></item><item><title>No plans to ban more phrases under hate speech laws, Queensland premier says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/queensland-antisemitism-phrase-ban/106358470</link><description>Religious groups and unions have expressed their concern about a Queensland government move to ban the use of certain phrases as part of an antisemitism crackdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc96734c24b685997f1d82c1818883de</guid></item><item><title>Fiji's former prime minister Frank Bainimarama charged with inciting mutiny</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/former-fiji-prime-minister-bainimarama-arrested-charged-mutiny/106360516</link><description>Long-serving Fiji prime minister Frank Bainimarama and a former police commissioner will face court on Tuesday on charges of mutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfb056a8d72b38a8175534edc2ea18aa</guid></item><item><title>Man who died in Bruce Highway crash remembered as 'kindest bloke'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/car-suspected-of-following-truck-on-bruce-highway-found/106361554</link><description>Mr Roberts died in a head-on collision with a truck on the Bruce Highway at Burpengary on Tuesday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84dff16312a7d9a0423a47b71f90d021</guid></item><item><title>From crime heists to a BDSM love story, here's what's in cinemas this month</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/what-to-watch-movies-february-pillion-crime-101/106352928</link><description>Australians will also finally be able to catch Sirât and The Voice of Hind Rajab, two movies that will be vying for Best International Film at the Academy Awards next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8040a86763a5a4d748d6c02c57f6603a</guid></item><item><title>How exclusion orders could ban Australian citizens from returning home indefinitely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/australian-citizens-banned-returning-overseas-exclusion-orders/106361634</link><description>One of the Australian women being held in a Syrian refugee camp has been barred from returning home after being given a temporary exclusion order — but the ban may not be as temporary as the name implies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b69ea4e5ccbec5d9f3ed7794e281795c</guid></item><item><title>SA secures Australian MotoGP, world-first street circuit announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/sa-secures-motogp-world-first-street-circuit-announced/106361722</link><description>The South Australian government has confirmed the Australian MotoGP will move to Adelaide from 2027, bringing with it huge economic benefits, but the opposition and Greens say the state has other priorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a957e6c008c2cd348424eaa2acecad49</guid></item><item><title>Unemployment rate remains at 4.1pc in January, leading to talk of another rate rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/unemployment-rate-australia-january-2026-steady/106362428</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate remained at 4.1 per cent in January, with 17,800 more employed people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3deb22f01e8aa72f8fccc75f74faf25b</guid></item><item><title>The heartwarming tribute to injured aerials star Laura Peel at the Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/heartwarming-aerials-tribute-laura-peel/106361392</link><description>This Winter Olympics aerials competition saw plenty of Aussies achieve lifetime goals, but they never forgot the one person who was missing — injured champion Laura Peel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">837dd8955b1207595385711ea5af7ba8</guid></item><item><title>In her memoir, Gisèle Pelicot reveals the secret love behind France's most infamous rape trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/secret-boyfriend-who-stood-beside-gis%C3%A8le-pelicot/106357080</link><description>The world knows Gisèle Pelicot as the woman who waived anonymity during France's most infamous rape trial. But in her new memoir she reveals an unexpected story — the boyfriend she kept hidden and the love that helped her face an open courtroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f0faacac57b0eb7bcc67090ad05c423</guid></item><item><title>Dimboola gift shop firebombed days after police find illegal cigarettes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/dimboola-gift-shop-fire-police-investigate-tobacco-wars/106362692</link><description>The small west Victorian town of Dimboola is the latest regional centre to be affected by the state's illicit cigarette trade and tobacco wars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60161459fe1122b86570b3f99dd5ee80</guid></item><item><title>Rugby fans furious over 2027 Rugby World Cup ticket website crashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/rugby-world-cup-tickets-website-crash/106363344</link><description>Rugby fans from around the world are furious after failing to get tickets to the 2027 Men's World Cup due technical glitches and website crashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4827688c1be1b5c4bd7a18a7c04671b5</guid></item><item><title>Hanson digs her heels in, Taylor goes on tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/pauline-hanson-barnaby-joyce-angus-taylor-anthony-albanese/106349216</link><description>This week, the new opposition leader revealed his shadow cabinet while Pauline Hanson spun through a cycle she knows well.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ea3a4f2179a8b0064925ee07ccfca6c</guid></item><item><title>Vegetable scraps to be turned into bioenergy by Scenic Rim farm as part of $291 million project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/qld-kalfresh-bioenergy-scenic-rim/106363982</link><description>A new $291 million project set to turn farm scraps to energy has begun construction in Queensland's Scenic Rim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db61a8e13ba17ab198287e56aca27dc2</guid></item><item><title>Police arrest 16yo over stabbing of teen at Geelong shopping centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/geelong-shopping-mall-stabbing/106365416</link><description>A 16-year-old boy has been arrested following a suspected stabbing at a Geelong shopping centre that left another teen in a critical condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cd13547a7c5a690d71c004d6eaed927</guid></item><item><title>Coles manager moved product onto 'Down Down' promotion days after price hike to be more competitive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/coles-accc-federal-court-dog-food-down-down-pricing/106358664</link><description>A second Coles manager has been grilled in the federal court over whether rushing a product onto a "Down Down" promotion could have broken internal guidelines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41ca3a7b1fd4851df375d2220574fd44</guid></item><item><title>South Korea's ex-president Yoon Suk Yeol sentenced to life in prison over insurrection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/south-korea-president-yoon-suk-yeol-sentenced-insurrection-guilt/106363456</link><description>Former South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol is sentenced to life in prison on charges of rebellion for his attempt to put the country under military rule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8145bfdf54ebbed599a2b489a9edabf6</guid></item><item><title>Gas explosion kills 16 after apartment building partially collapses in southern Pakistan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/gas-explosion-kills-16-apartment-building-collapses-pakistan/106365612</link><description>Women and children are among 16 people killed after a gas explosion ripped through an apartment building in Pakistan on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bac5b7cbd5dc5905b6f47c64562d41d5</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/thursday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/106364470</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4c5b51e530a659b7487c6517551d5d1</guid></item><item><title>Former prince returns home as police investigation continues — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-epstein-police/106365802</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor has returned to his Sandringham home after being arrested and questioned on suspicion of misconduct in public office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5fc074cadfc2697a563fee6e91b29af</guid></item><item><title>What we know about ex-prince Andrew's arrest on suspicion of misconduct in public office</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/what-we-know-about-former-prince-andrew-arrest/106365894</link><description>Police are searching two addresses in the UK, including Royal Lodge on the Windsor Estate where the former prince lived until last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8039d5e6abc316002657b559e90ee456</guid></item><item><title>Ally Hickman showed her grit at 2026 Winter Olympics after heavy fall on second run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/ally-hickman-crash-snowboard-slopestyle-2026-winter-olympics/106366350</link><description>In a Winter Olympics beset by both glory and injury, Ally Hickman's heavy fall in the snowboard slopestyle could have turned a happy day into another disappointing one. Instead, the young Aussie showed her grit to get back up and go again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a129ccb67369e26da08c0952f439ed6</guid></item><item><title>Former premier joins community calls for speed reduction at 'dangerous' fatal intersection in Newham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/community-calls-for-speed-reduction-newham-intersection-victoria/106364280</link><description>A community in central Victoria is calling for a 20 kph speed limit reduction at a "terribly dangerous" intersection after four major accidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d28bf645384eca294d072c5b45849511</guid></item><item><title>Sisters Lisa and Rachael Maza reunite on stage for the world premiere of Black Light</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/lisa-rachael-maza-sisters-black-light-malthouse-theatre/106357630</link><description>The former head of Indigenous theatre company Ilbijerri teams up with her sister Lisa for the world premiere of Black Light, which tells the story of three generations of Blak women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1799e84905988608fb42c35ca34a445</guid></item><item><title>Georgia Voll top scores as Australia beats India in second Twenty20 by 19 runs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/georgia-voll-following-alyssa-healy-footsteps-in-india-t20/106366526</link><description>The retirement of Alyssa Healy leaves a big hole at the top of the order, but Georgia Voll looks capable of stepping in after a career-best outing in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74487880f457828fe8e726b872f23c9d</guid></item><item><title>As electric car prices fall, will affordability win over drivers?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/cart-electric-vehicles-becoming-more-affordable/106348534</link><description>The price tag of EVs has been a barrier to uptake. As cheaper models hit the market, will more drivers go electric?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8e8609bc047b4700deb6c7a5c8c5aa4</guid></item><item><title>Voters divided as Barnaby Joyce considers contesting New England for One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/new-england-divided-over-barnaby-joyce/106353714</link><description>One Nation MP Barnaby Joyce says he might recontest his seat of New England as a candidate for One Nation if the party needs him to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8216e2cb0110f0bcd4db9bab70757914</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's arrest could end monarchy's 'never complain, never explain' mentality</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrest-a-problem-for-monarchy/106365934</link><description>British royals have lived by the adage "never complain, never explain", but these days, many of their subjects are demanding answers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69ce80bb0d80419516702662a1c32494</guid></item><item><title>Can Angus Taylor get beyond slogans to craft a sound immigration policy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/angus-taylor-immigration-pauline-hanson/106349268</link><description>The rifts in Australia's social cohesion can be seen in the blow-up over the so-called ISIS brides and their children, who want to come to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81483ff7c63fdba169c22b024c766cea</guid></item><item><title>Car driving Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor leaves UK police station.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-released-after-being-in-custody/106366694</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5d1b414c5b63a2abd8afd19a7fb4208</guid></item><item><title>Amyl and the Sniffers singer in escalating legal battle with photographer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/amy-taylor-amyl-and-the-sniffers-court-cases-copyright/106361084</link><description>What began as a photo shoot with champagne, ice cream and humorous glamour shots of Amy Taylor, singer from punk band Amyl and the Sniffers, has escalated into a legal fight over copyright, the US Constitution and an application for a restraining order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2eecb7daec40c63d6dec04c319e48120</guid></item><item><title>Coalition willing to help stop passports for IS-linked women— as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/federal-politics-live-albanese-taylor-labor-coalition/106363700</link><description>Angus Taylor says the Coalition is willing to help the government strengthen legislation so women with ties to Islamic State are not issued Australian passports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e73f6a4c21f2ed041db318fdf5bfddfe</guid></item><item><title>Major US fund's credit squeeze could 'blow up' — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-friday-20-february/106366740</link><description>Shares in US asset manager Blue Owl have fallen sharply after it announced it was having challenges meeting investors' cash demands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8cfa058595f0f84f2b91273acd73f15</guid></item><item><title>Federal authorities target black flights and drug importation in Far North Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/afp-queensland-police-target-organised-crime-far-north/106366728</link><description>A joint police taskforce has been launched in Far North Queensland to target the importation of illicit drugs, forced labour and sexual servitude.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad129b09fc9d0b15be5f175dc0beddec</guid></item><item><title>Ingham abuzz as recovering sugar town prepares to host Tones And I concert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/ingham-buzzing-ahead-of-tones-and-i-concert/106357352</link><description>A dedicated community campaign results in the Australian singer performing a one-off, almost sold-out show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54a2843af718594604b8837c663e03da</guid></item><item><title>Sam Altman and Dario Amodei refuse to hold hands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/sam-altman-and-dario-amodei-refuse-to-hold-hands/106366810</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28360275abe5f689dc70a72962b98b0f</guid></item><item><title>Bangarra Dance Theatre wins Golden Lion at international dance festival Venice Danza 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/bangarra-dance-theatre-golden-lion-venice-biennale/106366904</link><description>Indigenous dance company Bangarra Dance Theatre has become the first company and first First Nations performers to receive the Golden Lion at Venice Danza, the international festival of contemporary dance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1e2f7d948461775c920779a3628e602</guid></item><item><title>Canadian skier Cassie Sharpe's horrific crash in the halfpipe reminds us of Winter Olympics dangers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/cassie-sharpe-canadian-freeski-halfpipe-crash/106366818</link><description>As Cassie Sharpe lay motionless on the base of the Livigno halfpipe, the excruciating tension reminded us all that winter Olympians are only ever seconds from disaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca8a04bde9604f081e69e3f402a12a68</guid></item><item><title>Fiji, Palau and Tuvalu set to show world leaders climate change impact ahead of COP31</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/pacific-nations-set-to-host-world-leaders-on-climate-change/106366110</link><description>Fiji, Palau and Tuvalu look set to host world leaders and climate change ministers in the lead-up to COP31 in a bid to encourage larger countries to accelerate cuts to emissions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efb0153cc3ad4a4f839fc3664ed151a9</guid></item><item><title>Is it OK to feed Australia's wild birds?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/is-it-ok-to-feed-australias-wild-birds/106349168</link><description>Many of us love interacting with and feeding wild birds, but experts say giving them the wrong types of food can do more harm than good.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eec910366a2f5aeb070b335682010295</guid></item><item><title>Eric Dane, star of Grey's Anatomy and Euphoria, dies aged 53</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/eric-dane-star-of-greys-anatomy-and-euphoria-dies/106188556</link><description>The star was best known for his role as Dr Mark Sloan in long-running medical drama Grey's Anatomy, and as the patriarch of the Jacobs family in teen hit Euphoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38f5c65f82f5e42103bcfbd84e4e18ea</guid></item><item><title>The Board of Peace meant to rebuild Gaza may well end up as another monument to Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/donald-trump-gaza-board-of-peace-speech-leaves-questions/106367958</link><description>Unless the Board of Peace begins to focus and genuinely tries to make the world a better place, this may well prove to be yet another monument to Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19b5df8e6b47a6791635a631e37275ff</guid></item><item><title>Eileen Gu says JD Vance is 'sweet' for saying she should be competing for US at 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/eileen-gu-jd-vance-us-china-row/106367168</link><description>Eileen Gu says she is flattered that JD Vance thinks she should be competing for the US, but feels his comments are driven by an anti-China bias from Washington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d89980fb1e4f346814c87b1cd907a8d</guid></item><item><title>What to watch, read and listen to this weekend: Eternity, "Wuthering Heights" and new Meg Mac</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/what-to-watch-read-and-listen-to-this-weekend/106348892</link><description>From a cursed vagina to a classic retold, there's plenty of culture to dig into this weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de104c63d006fce83127b9a4e083d6bd</guid></item><item><title>Kyra Wheatley ready to ride the chaos and speed of ski cross at Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/kyra-wheatley-ski-cross-speed-chaos-winter-olympics/106366406</link><description>The speed and chaos of ski cross is what attracted Kyra Wheatley to the sport, and to realise a dream 12 years in the making of competing at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1a4056e5ff034ff263b9864448b4429</guid></item><item><title>Scientists model best-case and worst-case climate scenarios for Antarctica</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/antarctica-faces-devastating-impacts-under-climate-change/106354182</link><description>Scientists say parts of Antarctica face "devastating" and "irreversible" impacts from climate change unless urgent action is taken to limit greenhouse gas emissions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f426dd0a1878420ce756c07766ef447c</guid></item><item><title>Glider pilot creates aviation history in Central Australia flying 1,266 kilometres</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/glider-pilot-makes-history-central-australia/106364374</link><description>A Queensland pilot has made aviation history in Central Australia, flying more than 1,200 kilometres without an engine in a record-breaking glider flight launched from Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3a3e44b629b032cc34ddda0931e8d1e</guid></item><item><title>Ellyse Perry's evolution cements greatness as Australian cricket milestone looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/ellyse-perry-australia-cricket-350-matches/106369982</link><description>Cricket superstar Ellyse Perry will become the first woman to play 350 matches for Australia across all formats on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">588cdbd7c7f7eac8850144d63f6e89e7</guid></item><item><title>Cockroaches peer out of a communications access hole in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/cockroaches-peer-out-of-a-communications-access-hole-in-adelaide/106370192</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e08605d17a90fbae10b53943eaeaeaeb</guid></item><item><title>Police receive 'reports of crime' in relation to Pauline Hanson interview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/police-investigation-pauline-hanson-afp-one-nation-muslim/106370420</link><description>One Nation senator Pauline Hanson accuses the government of trying to put her "back in jail", after police received reports of a crime in relation to the senator's inflammatory comments about Muslims during a media interview.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">185dd63416cc7c6d747e0e5e37316352</guid></item><item><title>Norway sets Winter Olympics record with 17th gold medal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/winter-olympics-milano-cortina-day-14-live-updates/106369192</link><description>Norway breaks its own record for the most gold medals won by a nation at a single Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e17b4999cf1076ac0d1642f69ec78c68</guid></item><item><title>Australia blows Oman away to end T20 World Cup campaign with a bang</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/t20-world-cup-australia-vs-oman-live-blog/106371016</link><description>Australia has flogged Oman, chasing down 105 in less than 10 overs to end a disappointing World Cup campaign on a high. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48a66d916c759b65504e92b5f344bd88</guid></item><item><title>Man whose girlfriend froze to death after he left her mountain convicted of manslaughter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/austria-manslaughter-after-woman-froze-to-death-on-mountain/106371008</link><description>A man who left his girlfriend to freeze to death on an Austrian mountain has been handed a five-month suspended sentence for manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">effae5ababb3ac61ba124a96f11fe003</guid></item><item><title>Jeffrey Epstein's estate agrees to pay up to $US35 million to settle class action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/epstein-estate-agrees-to-pay-up-to-us-35m-to-settle-class-action/106371194</link><description>Jeffrey Epstein's estate has agreed to pay as much as $US35 million to resolve a class action lawsuit, according to a court filing on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">883c1ed664dc93038eba1c101323e85d</guid></item><item><title>Trump vows to resurrect global tariffs after Supreme Court strikes them down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/supreme-court-rules-against-donald-trumps-tariffs/106371286</link><description>The US president says he is "absolutely ashamed" of members of the court who struck down his global tariffs after finding he lacked the authority to implement them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c00aabed63715023fee1232c77fe8c38</guid></item><item><title>UK government to consider removing Andrew from succession line, as royal protection police face grilling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/royal-protection-police-to-be-grilled-over-mountbatten-windsor/106371406</link><description>The UK government is to look at removing Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor from the line of succession, an official says, as royal protection police face a grilling on "anything they saw or heard".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3493cf1504035f8670aff82102e21ef1</guid></item><item><title>Putin is betting Ukraine and the West run out of resources first</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/russia-ukraine-four-year-war-vladimir-putin/106349238</link><description>Russian President Vladimir Putin is betting that the West and Ukraine will run out of resources first.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11d7efa9b8e3b49ad2d1ac3d15d64f51</guid></item><item><title>Should Labor do its own refresh after Angus Taylor's Liberal 'rebrand'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/angus-taylor-shadow-cabinet-albanese-government/106337018</link><description>In the past few days, in a series of largely ignored milestones overshadowed by news of Angus Taylor's new frontbench, Albanese overtook Scott Morrison and John Curtin to become the 12th-longest serving prime minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">070d46246d34302a081ac085940a13ec</guid></item><item><title>ABC 50/50 quiz: This week we're testing your knowledge of Ninja Turtles, Netflix and nagging pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/abc-5050-quiz-feb-21/106362470</link><description>Every question has only two options: One is right and the other is wrong. You have an even chance of guessing correctly each time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75de69d84e56309d413d4f77423b7583</guid></item><item><title>Andy Griffiths, author of the Treehouse books, named new Australian Children's Laureate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/andy-griffiths-author-australian-childrens-laureate/106331360</link><description>Famous for writing stories about toilets and tree houses, the bestselling kids' author is taking on a new challenge on the national stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4faf4f52c970006ea1d74e0f15c753b</guid></item><item><title>15 of your modern dating stories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/modern-dating-love-stories/106353870</link><description>From awkward introductions over a can of soft drink to life-changing lunches, here are some of the stories ABC readers told us about their modern dating experiences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c55dadf4fb8488606f2bcf115acc933</guid></item><item><title>The town that turned its back on a rape victim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/balmoral-home-town-boys-rape-divides-football-farming-town/106145646</link><description>A local footy star and his mate are convicted of raping their friend. In the tiny town of Balmoral, where the footy club reigns, the town makes it clear whose story they believe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcced53be78cf23e4251d66c753ae52d</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's future uncertain under monarch willing to let 'the law take its course'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/andrew-arrest-will-go-down-in-history-books/106367696</link><description>Like so many of the elite caught in Epstein's web, Andrew believed he would escape scrutiny for his behaviour. But it is precisely because of his name and position that his alleged wrongdoing has now delivered him into the hands of the law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">876a05a2e2317a3aa1a9f28c7c53ce70</guid></item><item><title>Why Pacific Islands are rapidly de-flagging Russia's fleet of 'shadow tankers'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/pacific-islands-flags-of-convenience-shadow-vessels/106357172</link><description>Pacific Islands are rapidly de-flagging vessels on their shipping registries after gaining international attention for their role in Russia's "shadow fleet".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f072b9260e3417979d4a703c003d41e0</guid></item><item><title>Landholders fear large-scale battery project will impact Mount Gambier housing developments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/mount-gambier-residents-oppose-blanche-battery-over-housing/106352934</link><description>Landholders call for a proposed 500-megawatt battery energy storage project to be moved amid concerns it will impact on housing developments in South Australia's second largest city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07de98d6be338d20a09b260236ad8580</guid></item><item><title>Nathan Cleary facing two-match suspension over high hit in Panthers' trial loss to Wests Tigers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/nrl-cleary-facing-ban-panthers-lose-tigers-trials-match/106371458</link><description>Nathan Cleary can accept a two-match suspension with an early plea after his high hit on Wests Tigers star Heamasi Makasini.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0688e0c927d67a68c51d9c5a5808dcf7</guid></item><item><title>Eileen Gu calls Australian teen Indra Brown 'the real deal' ahead of 2026 Winter Olympics freeski halfpipe final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/indra-brown-real-deal-eileen-gu-freeski-olympic-final/106371022</link><description>Australian teen Indra Brown's spectacular rise to Winter Olympic medal contender has been stunning to watch, but defending freeski champion Eileen Gu says it's not a surprise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df8afe984e1d68b689fa106cae234001</guid></item><item><title>At Melbourne's Mission to Seafarers, a small team keeps an invisible global workforce afloat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/melbourne-mission-to-seafarers-global-maritime-workforce/106305250</link><description>In a 109-year-old building wedged between mirrored high-rises in Melbourne's CBD, a volunteer team supports a little-known workforce that spends months at a time at sea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e44f3fdcd48ad5e31a22c51f2c67d041</guid></item><item><title>Scientists recommend succulents to protect buildings from bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/succulents-garden-for-fire-protection-bushfire-research/106362920</link><description>As bushfires become more frequent, scientists say garden beds can be a line of defence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a01f9938a43dfe2dc6ef2ca35e27e0a</guid></item><item><title>The art and origins of the courtroom sketch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/the-art-and-origins-of-the-courtroom-sketch/105817718</link><description>They're a small and curious cohort in a line of work rapidly evolving. Welcome to the world of courtroom artists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5051373d22a373be7ac83c73f3f9a4bb</guid></item><item><title>Peregrine falcon drone could save Australian fruit and almond orchards from hungry birds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/robird-peregrine-falcon-drone-to-scare-birds-from-crops/106105572</link><description>A new falcon drone wards off peckish birds that have been destroying valuable fruit crops.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ad160c79a85d52dff1c43c429b91f7d</guid></item><item><title>Peter Malinauskas is heading for a landslide win in SA. How crushing a victory will it be?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/sa-election-lots-to-learn-despite-predicted-labor-landslide/106363808</link><description>Even if it's a Labor landslide, we'll learn a lot from next month's South Australian election, writes Casey Briggs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2475f1de36b7f53be3206611dfb848d</guid></item><item><title>Manchester United owner Jim Ratcliffe avoids sanctions after saying UK has been 'colonised' by immigrants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/football-man-united-owner-not-charged-colonised-call-ratcliffe/106371480</link><description>Jim Ratcliffe is reminded of his responsibilities as a participant in English football but is not handed any penalties from FA after his controversial call.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69bf802509648780c979dcba937fb0a8</guid></item><item><title>Inquiry into Queensland child safety hears child had 22 foster carers by age 13</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/qld-child-safety-commission-of-inquiry-continues-toowoomba/106367756</link><description>Details of a child's tumultuous journey to adulthood under the stewardship of Queensland's Department of Child Safety have been laid bare in a Toowoomba inquiry this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0f721ec8b30964186c7b603e07e1df3</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's arrest shows money talks louder than women's testimony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrest-jeffrey-epstein/106349250</link><description>Why is an email about the trade trip apparently more compelling than the detailed and painful evidence of a woman?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c126708b2400a064fec41430e0ad12c1</guid></item><item><title>Man and 15yo boy charged over shooting of former NRL player Matt Utai</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/nsw-two-charged-shooting-nrl-player-matt-utai-greenacre/106371512</link><description>Police allege a 25-year-old man was responsible for the shooting of former NRL player Matt Utai, while a 15-year-old drove the getaway car.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82625733d6500d322cd94c0445cb3979</guid></item><item><title>Campbell Newman argues new Queensland hate speech laws going down 'dangerous path'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/campbell-newman-criticises-hate-speech-laws-free-speech/106368924</link><description>The new laws will allow the government to ban phrases it deems problematic by regulation once the legislation passes state parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68ff5ad00c6a07b420d4ed9629204d0b</guid></item><item><title>Farmer's hands-off approach creates unusual lamb with distinct flavour chefs say is like nothing else in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/braidwood-farmer-new-lamb-cooked-local-restaurant-expat-chefs/106358970</link><description>When Frank was forced to sell the sheep he'd been farming for more than 20 years, something had to change. His "experiment" is helping expats feel at home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">193e31303ed2bfa342879871031db171</guid></item><item><title>After 60 years, there are fears Myer may walk away from Launceston's CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/concerns-myer-may-leave-launceston-shopping-strip/106367746</link><description>Community and business leaders say the possible departure of retailer Myer would leave a "giant hole" in the heart of the city's shopping district.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c928733eebf54cd5eadca8fc44e69d7</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Lindsey Vonn goes 'bionic' as the curling war of words continues — day 14 quick hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/winter-olympics-day-14-quick-hits-curling-barb-lindsey-vonn/106370974</link><description>Swedish curler Oskar Eriksson hits Canadian nemesis Marc Kennedy with his most devastating barb yet as Lindsey Vonn shares an update on her recovery. Here are the quick hits from day 14 at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e305a380a102e8649ea935e7dd6ce29</guid></item><item><title>Queensland woman wakes from coma after contracting meningitis and septic shock on ski holiday to Japan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/queensland-woman-coma-meningitis-septic-shock-in-japan/106367880</link><description>When 24-year-old Anna Gallo woke up shivering in a Tokyo hotel, she thought it was food poisoning. Hours later, she was in a coma fighting for her life against a disease she thought she was vaccinated against.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df154e4e3de16e61796b2871c5c9fe9b</guid></item><item><title>Cattle tick outbreak raises questions over Queensland's biosecurity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/tick-outbreak-raises-questions-over-queenslands-biosecurity/106367970</link><description>Queensland is known for its hardline biosecurity stance against foreign pests, but farmers say a recent cattle tick outbreak has exposed systemic weaknesses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11798db4c4a29dca21b6773386e53cb7</guid></item><item><title>Americans fearing death of democracy see a glimmer of hope in the Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/supreme-court-tariff-decision-confirms-democracy-isnt-dead/106371496</link><description>Until now, Donald Trump has been one of the most unstoppable presidents ever. But the Supreme Court's tariffs decision proves there are limits to his power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d596259cf551d1d1afc79b3621e90f2d</guid></item><item><title>North-west Queensland on high alert as deluge continues and rivers rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/large-parts-of-queensland-on-high-alert-as-heavy-rain-continues/106367672</link><description>Flooding is likely to become more widespread in northern and western Queensland over the next few days, with further heavy rainfall and road closures expected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b0a1461ea9964b523d17ba2f1d2a90d</guid></item><item><title>Daly River flood evacuees to return home after more than two weeks in Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/nt-daly-river-evacuees-returning-home-after-flood-emergency/106368994</link><description>After spending more than a fortnight sleeping at a Darwin evacuation centre 220 kilometres away from their flooded community, bus loads of Daly River locals are set to return home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2098d8f0591a5fe0f965b8e16635f308</guid></item><item><title>Woman found dead after a house fire near Newcastle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/fatal-house-fire/106371508</link><description>Police are investigating the cause of a fatal house fire at Port Stephens, north of Newcastle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93a18486fb3125c6c471e4baf3829e88</guid></item><item><title>Bayern Munich coach Vincent Kompany says José Mourinho made 'huge mistake' attacking Vinícius Júnior's character after alleged racist insult</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/football-kompany-criticises-mourinho-over-vini-jr-racism-call/106371656</link><description>Bayern Munich manager Vincent Kompany dissects the racism row involving Real Madrid and Brazil star Viní Jr with a passionate 12-minute speech.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">612aa3df4ab705ac95b277d2f9bcadb5</guid></item><item><title>Lavender growers say watered-down oil imports are pricing them out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/lavender-oil-imports-pricing-local-growers-out/106308156</link><description>Despite an Australian lavender industry dating back to the 1850s, you're more than likely using an imported and "watered-down" product, local growers say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e706f0f5677eaf283fac61a73d10ba9e</guid></item><item><title>Herby potato salad with green beans and tuna - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/herby-potatoes-with-green-beans-and-tuna/106252480</link><description>Turn a potato salad into a tasty meal with pantry staples and fresh greens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bf3639cafb3b89fadd2f76dbfd84322</guid></item><item><title>Crocodile attack in WA's Kimberley region prompts calls for more awareness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/man-survives-crocodile-attack-in-far-north-wa/106367776</link><description>A man's close call with a saltwater crocodile in Western Australia's far north has prompted calls for more awareness in remote parts of the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b34143f81b684e0e3799213bbbdbcd89</guid></item><item><title>Opposition does its best to land blows on WA government in parliament's first week back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/wa-parliament-week-one-analysis-basil-zempilas-roger-cook/106365878</link><description>Housing, health and household stress — that's what WA's opposition leader says he's focused on in 2026 as he and his party face an uphill battle against the state government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56f1332a78e625f94d5312f5b9b52fd4</guid></item><item><title>Why economists hate low unemployment for inflation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/why-economists-hate-low-unemployment-for-inflation/106367852</link><description>The theory goes that if you have just the right amount of workers on the unemployment scrap heap, you can keep inflation in check. The problem is that no-one knows exactly what the magic unemployment rate is.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43e029d93818ef09b173d99095546fef</guid></item><item><title>Two teenage boys killed in fatal car crash at Crabtree, in Tasmania's Huon Valley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/double-teen-fatality-in-southern-tasmania-crash/106371746</link><description>Two teenage boys have died in a single vehicle crash in Tasmania's Huon valley overnight, with three others taken to hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04a217818d8de71afce27b22293179fd</guid></item><item><title>Women and children in Syrian camp "will end up in Australia" | Insiders On Background</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/insiders-on-background-abul-rizvi/106370578</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">429933e5b0b8244f26a5c83a2eef8995</guid></item><item><title>Potential release of carp control virus into waterways delayed until 2028</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/national-carp-control-plan-decade-delay-carp-herpes-virus/106348408</link><description>Release of a virus to control carp in Australian waterways has been delayed until 2028, a decade after it was initially slated for release.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dbde53e8280f083aef35066d7c03374</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with hate crime after allegedly ramming Brisbane synagogue with ute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/brisbane-synagogue-rammed-man-charged-hate-crime/106371834</link><description>It's alleged the 32-year-old rammed a ute into the gates of the Brisbane Synagogue on Margaret Street on Friday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">560aa622bfc80adf305756789d41b300</guid></item><item><title>Teagan Micah forced out of Matildas' Asian Cup campaign as concussion issues continue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/matildas-teagan-micah-out-of-asian-cup-concussion/106371804</link><description>Teagan Micah's horror run with concussions continues as she reveals she will miss the Matildas' upcoming Asian Cup campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbcf7ae7402006cdd468aa9c66f144ee</guid></item><item><title>How Reuters captured that photo of former Prince Andrew leaving custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/how-reuters-captured-the-photo-of-former-prince-andrew-leavi/106371770</link><description>The image, taken by Reuters photographer Phil Noble, went viral when it was published on Thursday. He says capturing the moment came down to a tip-off and more than a little luck.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23d31204491246cc184daea89e905d39</guid></item><item><title>Balinese women find shared culture and community in WA's Pilbara</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/balinese-indonesian-women-in-fifo-mining-town/106190742</link><description>The Pilbara is known for spinifex and mining, but has also become a melting pot of cultures from across the globe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">897c042e4f513ac1f82e6b02921636b5</guid></item><item><title>I had a miscarriage over the summer. It was nothing like I expected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/miscarriage-loss-grief/106308830</link><description>My understanding of miscarriage was built on a handful of Hollywood representations and snatches of stories I'd read. Outside of this, I had few reference points.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a18951e43e4efa639be7b2845bc9d57e</guid></item><item><title>A 'return to craft' for the NT's award-winning young artists showcased at this year's Exit Art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/nt-exit-art-exhibition-return-to-crafting-darwin-gallery-museum/106368426</link><description>Almost a dozen high school-aged artists have received awards as part of a prestigious Northern Territory showcase, with a number of finalists exhibiting self-portraits.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ed4262d4757e1158f4f7f9fb3c9f716</guid></item><item><title>Concerns over death of iconic salmon gums in WA's Great Western Woodlands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/concerns-over-tree-deaths-great-western-woodlands/106355300</link><description>Kalgoorlie horticulturalist Phil Stanley says he is struggling to get authorities to take the deaths of more than 100 salmon gums near the mining city seriously.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cef65ddf1756cc101cb4a0d10888de3f</guid></item><item><title>Anna Murdoch-Mann, author and ex-wife of Rupert Murdoch, dies aged 81</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/anna-murdoch-mann-dies-aged-81/106371640</link><description>The author, journalist and philanthropist was Rupert Murdoch's "active partner" in his media empire News Corp over their 31-year marriage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4277353646eb61bcf0bb37d726dbda4</guid></item><item><title>Displaced on the dial by changes to Perth's FM spectrum, Kalamunda community radio is undeterred</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/kalamunda-community-move-down-the-dial/106358500</link><description>Kalamunda Community Radio has been providing a local radio service on 102.5FM to the Perth Hills for more than 25 years, but has now had to move frequency as the ABC switches its Perth radio services to FM.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35daf39c9f69b3c3582dd0627cacab2a</guid></item><item><title>Adam Zampa says claims Australia does not care about T20 cricket 'totally false' after World Cup flop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/cricket-zampa-defends-australia-t20-prep-world-cup-exit/106371894</link><description>Adam Zampa hits back at claims that Australia does not care about T20 cricket after a disappointing World Cup campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47ff9ce19c56b6ba685a684eb3b125df</guid></item><item><title>How a window opened for IS-linked Australians to leave Syria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/how-a-window-opened-for-is-linked-australians-to-leave-syria/106368348</link><description>After holding a large swathe of autonomous territory that included two detention camps, Kurdish-led forces are now reluctantly handing over control to Syrian government forces, following their successful military offensive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79af036f525934cd4e37d746768f51d7</guid></item><item><title>The shamans and designer handbags before Yoon Suk Yeol's insurrection conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/the-scandalous-downfall-of-yoon-suk-yeol/106358072</link><description>Former South Korean president Yoon Suk Yeol's sentence for insurrection comes after a tumultuous era of shamanism, Chanel bags and conspiracy theories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c392edec639f36481f4ec7269ef84031</guid></item><item><title>How a Belgian techno producer with some old synthesisers has reimagined Terminator 2</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/terminator-2-new-score-hear-my-eyes-mess/106369562</link><description>Terminator 2: Judgment Day is getting the live score treatment, but not in the way you might expect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">689c4da252c634c2c4554ed5d31bba80</guid></item></channel></rss>