<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 21:55:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Forgotten tracks from the 2005 Hottest 100 you need to hear again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/forgotten-songs-from-2005-hottest-100-bloodhound-gang/106146344</link><description>We've dug out some standout tracks from the Hottest 100 of 2005 that you need to hear again. Relive the mid-2000s music that defined an era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc09e85614dc423c888ef09906b13089</guid></item><item><title>Bourke artist Jenny Greentree's career sprouted during millennium drought</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/drought-sparked-back-o-bourke-art-gallery-jenny-greentree/106175110</link><description>Jenny and Steve Greentree's young family faced losing everything in the millennium drought. Twenty years on, their thriving art gallery has helped to put Bourke on the map.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d286846e2dad00a047b8c1f2b22adfb</guid></item><item><title>Why Abbey Barrett's mum wants more federal government funding for brain cancer research</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/brain-cancer-abbey-barrett-family-campaigning-for-funding/106231668</link><description>Abbey was "joy on two legs" and now she is gone, another lost to brain cancer. Somehow her family must carry on, as the fight continues for more funding to bring this horror disease to an end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ec9d9719847601eb996db80054f8f03</guid></item><item><title>Flash flooding, heavy rainfall and gusty weather keeps SES busy on NSW coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/flooding-heavy-rainfall-severe-weather-nsw-coast/106241644</link><description>The State Emergency Service responds to more than 2,300 incidents and 25 flood rescues, most of which involve people driving through floodwaters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">682c9a58e4ded3172424c5883c33001a</guid></item><item><title>Torres Strait Islanders commemorate the legacy of 1936 pearl industry maritime strike</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/torres-strait-islanders-commemorate-1936-maritime-strike/106185202</link><description>Fed up with restrictions over what they earned and where they could go, pearl boat workers embarked on nine months of industrial action that would change the face of their communities forever. Ninety years on, their legacy is still felt across the Torres Strait.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bbdd6f0c5d68b167bcdb5801855febc</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026 live: Venus Williams knocked out by Olga Danilovic, Zeynep Sönmez helps ball kid after fall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/australian-open-2026-live-updates-sabalenka-alcaraz-berrettini/106238282</link><description>It was a busy day at Melbourne Park but it was the night session that saw both the men's and women's world number ones progressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4c6da1c1e570acfa84f69ab5872ca93</guid></item><item><title>Plans for Kununurra Aboriginal short stay accommodation abandoned despite dire need</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/kununurra-aboriginal-short-stay-accommodation-axed/106228666</link><description>Leaders in Kununurra say the Cook Government's decision to dump plans for Aboriginal short stay accommodation in town could be putting more people at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c06dd6e462f4e217c665a9750f5b47d4</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's animal populations suffer as state is ravaged by bushfires, extreme heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/victoria-wildlife-animals-suffering-bushfires-heatwave/106219826</link><description>From animal shelters to "entire generations" of bat colonies, heartbreaking stories of the significant loss of animal life are beginning to emerge in the wake of Victoria's disastrous bushfires and severe heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">246fa1e142bbfb8793f30a1c3d549ee0</guid></item><item><title>Status of hate laws remains uncertain as politicians converge on Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/status-of-hate-laws-uncertain-ahead-of-parliamentary-sitting/106242028</link><description>A special sitting to respond to the Bondi terror attack will begin in Canberra on Monday, but the government is no closer to landing changes to hate laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">255e439147fc4cb47e4707425c861a98</guid></item><item><title>NBA great Allen Iverson meets hundreds of fans in Australia, including NBL star Bryce Cotton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/nba-great-allen-iverson-meets-hundreds-of-australian-fans/106241020</link><description>NBA great Allen Iverson left hundreds of fans star struck at a meet-and-greet event in Perth, none more so than one of the best NBL players of all time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b373847c5a5d4039376decd597e93c92</guid></item><item><title>WA government announces Department of Health taskforce to crack down on illicit tobacco trade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/wa-tobacco-wars-police-to-recruit-retired-officers/106242124</link><description>A taskforce will be assembled to combat Western Australia's illicit tobacco market, with plans to pull retired and current police officers into the Department of Health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08dff102ed11f6d8820fe8684e6738e7</guid></item><item><title>Pasa Faho to screen at Sydney Opera House after creating a bit of buzz</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/pasa-faho-to-screen-at-sydney-opera-house/106219252</link><description>Pasa Faho is the story of a shoe salesman who struggles to save his small business and pass on his values to his son.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72a5355a25ce77e7fc6326115bb7b45b</guid></item><item><title>World's first legally binding treaty to protect oceans and marine life takes effect</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/high-seas-treaty-marine-protection-in-effect/106241974</link><description>The High Seas Treaty will govern about two-thirds of the planet's oceans including vast areas beyond any country's borders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">689da612d25cd88f659134fa3cc9f955</guid></item><item><title>RBA cash rate 2026: cuts or hikes coming?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/rba-cash-rate-2026-cuts-or-hikes-coming-/106242308</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff3b744611586db97731db23e9b1b989</guid></item><item><title>Talia Gibson moves through to Australian Open second round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/australian-open-talia-gibson-wins-first-round-melbourne-park/106242036</link><description>Talia Gibson prides herself on her aggressive on-court approach, which was on full display in her convincing first-round victory at Melbourne Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43668a5df364b7db43c9c951d67baef6</guid></item><item><title>Darwin gathers for Geektacular cosplay event celebrating geek culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/geektacular-nt-darwin-is-geek-culture-cool-nerd-community/106241848</link><description>Has a surge in the popularity of hit shows like Stranger Things led to an uptick in geekiness, changing how we feel about nerd culture? The ABC attended Darwin's Geektacular event to find out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95b123f4e86653bc014839e025f23438</guid></item><item><title>Why Alex de Minaur will lean into his 'selfish' side for the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/alex-de-minaur-australian-open-draw-first-round/106242496</link><description>As the nation's great hope for the Australian Open, Alex de Minaur is ready to unleash his selfish side in an effort to secure his first grand slam title.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b153f752f5b400fa206021a2a3f8dbf</guid></item><item><title>Boy, 12, in critical condition after being bitten by a large shark at Sydney Harbour beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/shark-attack-boy-suffers-critical-injuries-vaucluse-east-sydney/106242502</link><description>Emergency services were called to Hermitage Foreshore Walk near Shark Beach at Vaucluse about 4:20pm on Sunday afternoon following reports of a boy being bitten by a shark.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d4a045dd3eae0df5ada21ab4b2d9396</guid></item><item><title>Writers' Week letter shows premier backed removal of Randa Abdel-Fattah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/premier-letter-on-randa-abdel-fatah-at-writers-week-released/106241792</link><description>South Australia's premier told the Adelaide Festival board it would open itself to "accusations of hypocrisy" and "legitimate public ridicule" if it did not cancel the appearance of Randa Abdel-Fattah from Writers' Week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83b2891c320c941cac6481cb385e83d8</guid></item><item><title>Crews respond to Rose Bay shark attack.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/crews-respond-to-rose-bay-shark-attack/106242592</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">822ae7c10cb62a4c9ed5b345d9ebd531</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of WA fishers congregate to protest against ban on demersal fishing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/wa-fishing-ban-protest-dozens-gather-ozone-park/104760976</link><description>Around 200 disgruntled fishers have journeyed through the streets of Perth to protest against the state government's decision to ban demersal fishing, as the WA Premier Roger Cook confirmed he planned to meet with the industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0833f292c27266d407a9d8a7702f3963</guid></item><item><title>Tourists warned to avoid Fitzgerald River National Park as firefighters work to contain bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/bushfire-fitzgerald-national-park-wa-south-coast/106242528</link><description>Tourists are warned to avoid Fitzgerald River National Park, 500 kilometres south-east of Perth, as a bushfire burning in the park is still at Watch and Act level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef9467493e120eb78c12824747110bdb</guid></item><item><title>Body found among wreckage of Indonesian plane that lost contact mid-flight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/body-found-among-wreckage-of-plane-in-indonesia/106242700</link><description>A body has been found among the wreckage of an Indonesian plane that lost contact mid-flight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db885b01bccd5ca18317d0cde9a36a3e</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka advances to Australian Open second round at Melbourne Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/australian-open-aryna-sabalenka-first-round-melbourne-park/106242750</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka again proves she is compulsive viewing, as she moves through to the second round with a straight-sets win at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67e6df23b1e21ab03fae823a5e8f1746</guid></item><item><title>Venus Williams lost in the first round. But she still gave fans an emotional evening</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/venus-williams-first-round-loss-in-emotional-return/106242736</link><description>Undisputed great of the sport Venus Williams was welcomed back to Melbourne Park with multiple standing ovations but bowed out in the first round to Serbian Olga Danilovic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2896ce50a37c4ece236ddfb91dd87fd3</guid></item><item><title>Trump asks Australia, Albanese to join Gaza 'Board of Peace'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australia-asked-to-join-trump-s-gaza-board-of-peace-/106242966</link><description>The US president is pushing for the board to preserve a fragile ceasefire between Hamas and Israel and progress the peace deal to the next phase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed5574cc0854e1096521ee6bea0d0b2</guid></item><item><title>Unregulated fishing keeps Seahorse World locked out of traditional Chinese medicine market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/unregulated-seahorse-trade-hampers-beauty-point-seahorse-world/106225110</link><description>A seahorse farm in Tasmania thought it was onto a sure thing; exporting dried seahorses to the Chinese market — it turned out not to be as easy as hoped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e8e27a55b03ef0979521c99d06b70a2</guid></item><item><title>What psychologists have to say about the seven types of rest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/what-are-the-seven-types-of-rest/106076824</link><description>Have you ever found yourself still exhausted and deflated after an eight-hour sleep? Perhaps sleep isn't the reset you need.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">072209ca692c4f26d317f79697d0defa</guid></item><item><title>AI platforms like Grok are an ethical, social and economic nightmare — and we're starting to wake up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/ai-grok-ethical-social-and-economic-nightmare/106242320</link><description>As 2025 began, I thought humanity's biggest problem was climate change. In 2026, AI is more pressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0956e00f7c9111bf96801d7da3854c5</guid></item><item><title>Tribunal bans senior nurse for trying to take patient's medication, altering hospital records</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/modbury-nurse-banned-stealing-patients-adhd-medication/106229238</link><description>A senior public hospital nurse has been prohibited from working for four years for attempting to steal medication from a patient and manipulating a co-worker's Facebook account in an attempt to cover it up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a458cc28e2befbbf188f607c29e61cab</guid></item><item><title>Frustrated fans, Zverev confused and a ball kid collapses — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australian-open-2026-quick-hits/106242092</link><description>Fans were left queuing for hours after play started, Alexander Zverev got confused by a gate and Maria Sakkari smashed an insane shot. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8de558ff26a80cd67bd1bee03b1b19e0</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith amuses and delights, Sam Curran fires as the Sydney Sixers lock in BBL finals berth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/steve-smith-sam-curran-fire-sixers-to-bbl-finals/106242754</link><description>Steve Smith oscillates between the ridiculous and the sublime as the Sydney Sixers get the better of the Brisbane Heat in a do-or-die clash at the Gabba.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1ef7e0ae732c5419057160e3a03d756</guid></item><item><title>Calls for an industry-standard heat policy to be implemented on worksites as summers get hotter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/calls-for-industry-standard-heat-policy-on-worksites/106234134</link><description>It has been 13 years since Jenny Newport's son died from extreme heat while on a worksite in Queensland. She believes not much has changed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60f002407b15690de7b318b7c9777c52</guid></item><item><title>The highly detailed, invisible work that goes into 'near real-time' bushfire mapping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/near-real-time-fire-mapping-victoria-vicemergency/106229148</link><description>As the devastating fires in Victoria spread earlier this month, people at home could see how they were moving across the state — not just in videos on the news and social media, but on an interactive map.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">469e416c8b8bc080ac586637f311738e</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: MPs deliver emotional speeches as parliament addresses Bondi condolence motion — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/federal-politics-live-blog-jan-19/106243354</link><description>Parliament has returned ahead of schedule to honour the victims of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e846b82d23935ed7d5bcc7708fd2aecf</guid></item><item><title>ASX closes lower as Trump trade jitters renewed, China annual economic growth hits target — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/106242752</link><description>ASX closed lower as Trump trade jitters renewed. China's GDP came in line with expectations but other data is mixed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0794a627b2f9aec538d9e0388539831b</guid></item><item><title>Meals you can get kids on board with</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/fun-and-easy-recipes-kids-can-help-with/106116250</link><description>We’ve put together four recipes that are fun and easy enough for kids to help with.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60feacb4ce01787344636e59ad880e34</guid></item><item><title>Three performers talk about bringing their clown shows to Perth Fringe World</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/perth-fringe-world-festival-clowning-comedy/106134970</link><description>Three performers at Perth Fringe World talk about why the magic of clowning is getting adults to let down their walls and embrace their inner child.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c3258a63e2472d4f0d5955909eb9d5f</guid></item><item><title>Shark attack at Sydney Harbour beach leaves boy in intensive care with critical injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/nsw-sydney-harbour-shark-attack-boy-update-beach/106243340</link><description>Police say the boy was pulled aboard a vessel by water police officers "within minutes" of the Triple Zero call being made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">601ce151705bbedc4941c852971a37ec</guid></item><item><title>Charles Darwin University researchers investigate whether old tyres can strengthen roads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/nt-cdu-recycled-rubber-tyres-stronger-roads-heat-waste/106204858</link><description>Roads buckle under the pressure of the Northern Territory's harsh climate, but a group of researchers think repurposing discarded materials may be the solution — not only helping the environment, but government budgets too.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">313dc4fe7c3b7f9dddeda018717ab128</guid></item><item><title>Boundary Road level crossing upgrade stalls indefinitely as Transport and Main Road reneges on construction date</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/no-end-in-sight-for-derelict-government-eyesore-boundary-road/106219474</link><description>The Queensland government evicted shopkeepers in Coopers Plains to make way for construction that was due to begin in mid-2025 but is yet to happen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">041d5fd00bd0acc3ff2a5a4d906c5328</guid></item><item><title>Tooperang bushfire started by vehicle, CFS believes, as multiple structures lost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/tooperang-fire-rips-through-grass-and-scrub-near-mount-compass/106243392</link><description>A bushfire that has ripped through more than 600 hectares, destroying at least two family homes, is believed to have been started by an "accidental ignition" from a vehicle, the Country Fire Service says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffa572abe13984fd61b50488e392ecf9</guid></item><item><title>Conservationists alarmed by plan to remove rare bird habitat in Sydney's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/conservationists-alarmed-riverstone-wetland-replacement/106227536</link><description>A set of ponds built for a since-shuttered abattoir in Sydney's north-west has become a habitat for rare migratory birds from Alaska and Antarctica.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e97bf8d3994084dbcbcf0225e73b07c4</guid></item><item><title>Two people seriously injured in shooting at Huntfield Heights, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/two-injured-in-shooting-in-adelaide-southern-suburbs/106243568</link><description>Two people have been seriously injured in a shooting at a home in Adelaide's southern suburbs, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53f9a0827c06f656a37b0657ae838015</guid></item><item><title>Cross-cultural sharing is at the heart of Townsville's community garden</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/multiculturalism-thrives-in-townsville-community-garden/106171508</link><description>In the heart of north Queensland, Ukrainians, Fijians, Zimbabweans and Koreans gather in the dirt to help each other grow vegetables.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">747778fb8e47c03a41a45f71a8a4227f</guid></item><item><title>Violent crime spreading to regional towns as WA waits for strengthened tobacco laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/illegal-tobacco-vapes-violent-crime-in-regional-towns/106207292</link><description>Community leaders have called on the West Australian government to take concrete action as violence and crime associated with the illegal tobacco trade spreads to the state's Wheatbelt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7e3842f3ba51094b5b8f8d6f013ec4c</guid></item><item><title>Explosives discovery in Kalgoorlie reno sparks memories of time when gelignite was sold in shops</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/old-explosives-found-in-kalgoorlie-bring-back-gelignite-memories/106240594</link><description>A recent gelignite discovery during a Kalgoorlie renovation has brought back memories of a time when explosives were "freely available" in the mining city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64d37227f41c3e3ac11f2ee1b1eb2dce</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026 live: Djokovic 'excited' to be a centurion as he wins 100th match at Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australian-open-2026-live-alex-de-minaur-novak-djokovic/106243798</link><description>The 10-time champion joined Roger Federer at that milestone after he defeated Pedro Martinez in straight sets on day two.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b57b9ccbcf4cbb0da12d29ad9bb65e74</guid></item><item><title>Senegal storms off field in penalty protest, before returning to beat Morocco in mad AFCON final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/senegal-protests-then-wins-afcon-final-morocco/106243788</link><description>Senegal's players storm off the pitch in furious protest of a refereeing decision late in the Africa Cup of Nations final, but then return to score an extra-time winner against Morocco.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">610d9d94eb36d431cac87390846e0a05</guid></item><item><title>Oxfam wants tougher tax on billionaires as wealth grows 'by half a million dollars a day'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/income-inequality-oxfam-report-calls-to-tax-billionaires/106236612</link><description>Oxfam Australia is calling on the federal government to tax the super-rich to help tackle growing inequality, as billionaires grow their wealth by more than half a million a day on average.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4724ee211a3150b0e7fdb71b1aa50dff</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate death of Canadian hostel worker on K'gari (Fraser Island)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/police-investigating-death-of-woman-on-kgari-fraser-island/106244106</link><description>Police say the woman was working at a backpacker's hostel and went for an early morning swim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f409dea814fdda70230765a9e94b1ae4</guid></item><item><title>Adam Walton reveals what it's like to play Carlos Alcaraz at Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australian-open-adam-walton-carlos-alcaraz-first-round/106244122</link><description>As first-round opponents go, they do not come any tougher than Carlos Alcaraz, as Australia's Adam Walton found out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4124a2c909f8f8034f2ae8a1edd2c277</guid></item><item><title>Bondi victim Matilda's parents doubt hate laws will prevent future violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/matilda-parents-bondi-beach-hate-speech-laws/106241800</link><description>In their first wide-ranging interview, the parents of 10-year-old Matilda, the youngest victim of the Bondi attack, say the federal government's hate laws offer little reassurance that another terror attack will be prevented.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">405f80b4737eaa53d8bbde13d0a4d3d0</guid></item><item><title>Randa Abdel-Fattah's lawyer serves second concerns notice to SA premier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/randa-abdel-fattahs-lawyer-serves-second-concerns-notice/106244418</link><description>Palestinian Australian author Randa Abdel-Fattah says her lawyer has served a second concerns notice for defamation on South Australian Premier Peter Malinauskas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5070a5a415b4ba1efc660416513153cb</guid></item><item><title>Homes lost as Tooperang fire rips through scrub south of Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/homes-lost-as-tooperang-fire-rips-through-scrub/106244226</link><description>Devastated residents of a bushfire ground south of Adelaide are starting to count the cost of the damage, with at least two reporting their homes have been lost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">217b426f97e2049e2d28418425bce959</guid></item><item><title>Labor identity Tim Picton dies three weeks after alleged Northbridge assault, family confirms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/tim-picton-dies-three-weeks-after-nightclub-assault/106244678</link><description>Former Labor strategist Tim Picton dies in hospital, weeks after he was allegedly assaulted outside a Perth nightclub.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d9df645f784d9937ec88dc8a71dd414</guid></item><item><title>Deadly Chile wildfires trigger state of catastrophe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/deadly-chile-wildfires-trigger-state-of-catastrophe/106244428</link><description>Wildfires raging across central and southern Chile have left at least 18 people dead, scorched thousands of hectares of forest and destroyed hundreds of homes, local authorities say, as the South American country swelters under a heat wave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">519c96d7060e5a77953b867e9d438bb0</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open fans wait hours to enter Melbourne Park as Craig Tiley admits surprise over record crowds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/tennis-craig-tiley-surprised-australian-open-crowds-wait-times/106244434</link><description>Thousands of fans are forced to wait in queues for hours, even as Australian Open boss Craig Tiley promised extra resources to aid entry into Melbourne Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e1e9771e052990b4a23a911f74f1c67</guid></item><item><title>Four arrested as Queensland Police seize guns, kilos of drugs in Townsville</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/townsville-police-arrest-guns-drugs-trafficking/106244526</link><description>Police find 100kg cannabis, 8kg of methamphetamine and 1kg of cocaine as well as illegal firearms hidden in bush at a Townsville property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecd99c93b49491f432b2888450905a34</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith focuses on reclaiming Australian T20 spot for Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/steve-smith-t20-world-cup-olympics/106244980</link><description>Steve Smith has lit up the Big Bash since returning to the Sydney Sixers, but concedes the ship has sailed for him to play in next month's T20 World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">840498619d37e7667d0ac59def0a7633</guid></item><item><title>Young Sydney surfer uninjured after shark bites board at Dee Why Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/nsw-young-surfer-second-sydney-beach-shark-encounter/106245088</link><description>Surf Life Saving NSW confirms a boy is unharmed after an encounter with a shark at Dee Why Beach just before lunchtime on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d27f26f3f0945b4bf3612f160d05785d</guid></item><item><title>Roger Allers, co-director of The Lion King, dies aged 76</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/co-director-of-lion-king-roger-allers-dies/106244066</link><description>Roger Allers was known for working on various Disney films including The Lion King, The Little Mermaid and Aladdin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a0ef8a277b8d386b9b932a2c9c5d992</guid></item><item><title>Elphinstone Engineering director sentenced for interfering with Aboriginal relics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/graeme-elphinstone-allegations-interfere-with-aboriginal-sites/106243968</link><description>Graeme Elphinstone, the founder and director of Elphinstone Engineering, avoids conviction and is fined $12,000 for interfering with Aboriginal relics on his land on Tasmania's east coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ad5307c820eb3687e361788dd9c66bf</guid></item><item><title>Queensland teenager creates app allowing people to learn to code without internet access</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/neth-dharmasiri-on-coding/106239316</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2974b7ce001edf8f63ca9f2cdfccc54d</guid></item><item><title>Storm Hunter wins at Australian Open after thinking her career was over</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australian-open-storm-hunter-reaches-second-round/106244620</link><description>A ruptured Achilles tendon threatened to send Storm Hunter into retirement, but her perseverance pays off with a first-round victory in Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fa04a6d2e7099ffe2cd1b1e136b11dc</guid></item><item><title>Petition asks Alice Springs Public Library to extend opening hours amid outback heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/nt-petition-alice-springs-public-library-weekend-opening-hours/106244058</link><description>In one of Australia's hottest towns, the library is an important air-conditioned public space offering a no-cost respite from burning summer temperatures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48234b555f036ba2f92ff1804e8371f6</guid></item><item><title>Bondi survivor Ya'akov Tetleroyd lost his father and nearly his arm in Bondi Beach terrorism event. He forgives the gunmen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/bondi-terror-survivor-yaakov-tetleroyd-speaks-naveed-akram/106238196</link><description>Ya'akov Tetleroyd's father died in the Bondi Beach shootings. He nearly lost his arm as a result of being shot, yet he told 7.30 in an exclusive interview that he forgives the gunmen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">036a2c4738ac88afd5123eda6fe48589</guid></item><item><title>WA is losing the tobacco wars as gangs target vape stores and cheap cigarettes flood market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/wa-losing-the-fight-to-control-illegal-cigarettes/106242556</link><description>Burnt out storefronts in Perth and regional cities are testament to the government's inability to control the illegal tobacco trade — and it's not clear when things will change, writes Keane Bourke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">280b53748e89776c07bee7fd574bc253</guid></item><item><title>What has caused a 'smack' of jellyfish to wash up on Melbourne's south-eastern beaches?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/lions-mane-jellyfish-melbourne-port-phillip-bay/106244362</link><description>Visitors to Melbourne's south-eastern beaches over the weekend were surprised to see an influx of crimson jellyfish bobbing in the water. One expert says a "perfect storm" of factors has brought them to the coastline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e313ec9d19ef5439121c1957e9127cd9</guid></item><item><title>Weekend deluge causes flooding in far-north WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/weekend-deluge-causes-flooding-in-far-north-wa/106246064</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f57d668cd54ac57ee76274d8260c3d64</guid></item><item><title>Nicolas Cage shrine amid weird pranks at Mount Gambier deputy mayor's home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/mount-gambier-deputy-mayor-celebrity-letterbox-mystery/106245108</link><description>A Nicolas Cage-themed shrine is the latest of a series of celebrity-themed pranks that Mount Gambier's deputy mayor says have befallen his home in recent weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">613d4d6f79a342e68fef76235e90f105</guid></item><item><title>Monday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106245916</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bfd8c1fab3cd958260d324a03f7b0f3</guid></item><item><title>Teenage boy dies of injuries at bottom of cliff near Jerrabomberra Waterhole</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/act-teenager-dies-at-jerrabomberra-waterhole-bottom-of-cliff/106246244</link><description>A member of the public tried to perform CPR on a teenage boy suffering serious injuries at the bottom of a cliff near Canberra, but he died at the scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e11e9a0e318dcb3d76efc7eef5c7678</guid></item><item><title>Man critical after being bitten by a shark at North Steyne Beach in third incident in two days</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/shark-attack-north-steyne-beach-nsw/106246378</link><description>A man in his 20s is in a critical condition after he sustained leg injuries in another shark attack at a Sydney beach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01ac466828db525eeb0257f91ad7b0b0</guid></item><item><title>Man faces court after 2kg of meth seized in Katherine roadside drug bust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/katherine-drug-bust-meth-allegedly-bound-for-darwin/106245962</link><description>A 22-year-old man has faced court after police allegedly found 2 kilograms of methamphetamine, along with large quantities of other drugs, during a traffic stop in Katherine last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98effadd199406586f274ffc8312e87e</guid></item><item><title>Helicopter at North Steyne Beach after shark attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/helicopter-at-north-steyne-beach-after-shark-attack/106246484</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">593dba8cca07aa1b05943aea09a7b2b3</guid></item><item><title>What is it like to live and work in the Antarctic?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/living-and-working-in-the-antarctic/106246052</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d13273f34a29dd8e349e41e8e456cd05</guid></item><item><title>Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi to dissolve parliament and call snap election for February 8</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/japan-prime-minister-calls-snap-general-election/106246400</link><description>Japanese Prime Minister ⁠Sanae Takaichi will ​dissolve parliament ‌on ‌Friday ‌and call a snap ​election for February 8 ⁠to seek voter backing ‌for her ​spending ​plans and ‍other ⁠policies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6762019ff9f76327ee529684d85c451</guid></item><item><title>Victim Tanya urges alleged Mullewa shooter Kenneth Giles to come home safe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/mullewa-shooting-victim-makes-public-statement/106246464</link><description>In her first statement since she was shot through the hand on January 7, Tanya says she wants Kenneth Giles to know she wants him to return home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d217f22671f03c4ca8f601a436780f7b</guid></item><item><title>Philippines star Alexandra Eala sends Australian Open crowds into a frenzy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australian-open-alexandra-eala-philippines-melbourne-park/106246520</link><description>Alexandra Eala, ranked 49 in the world, attracts a crowd that virtually brought the Australian Open to a standstill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed8e4fa5d5e748dd1e7b20e436cc5910</guid></item><item><title>Man critical after being bitten by a shark in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/man-critical-after-being-bitten-by-a-shark-in-sydney/106246594</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e136a9efd0474d1502b11b3ec4dc15a</guid></item><item><title>Deadly Pakistan shopping plaza fire death toll rises to 23</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/deadly-pakistan-shopping-plaza-fire-death-toll-rises/106246696</link><description>Pakistani firefighters began pulling bodies from the smouldering remains of a sprawling Karachi shopping mall on Monday where dozens of people remain missing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e150196ed19b2ece558297a16bcff946</guid></item><item><title>Italian fashion designer Valentino dies aged 93 in Rome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/italian-fashion-designer-valentino-dies-aged-93-in-rome/106247130</link><description>The fashion icon's creations were adored by Hollywood stars, royals and first ladies for his fail-safe red carpet designs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46af3ffb2731ac5d3650837108493b36</guid></item><item><title>EPA asks Victorians to check water quality before swimming in Port Phillip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/port-phillip-bay-water-quality-summer-beach-reports-epa/106158836</link><description>Victoria's Environment Protection Authority says people wanting to cool off at bay beaches this summer should stay across its regular pollution updates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea04c727cb0b034491d7cd8c93a10cc6</guid></item><item><title>Oak Tasmania issued $1.1m penalty over hundreds of NDIS compliance failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/tas-ndis-provider-1-1m-penalty-for-breaches/106246414</link><description>Oak Tasmania admits to 474 compliance and reporting failures, as well as breaches that resulted in the hospitalisation of multiple NDIS clients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9e88e8b1c262ca731e0c1c273ec6e75</guid></item><item><title>How lifting gave me back the power to feel good at sport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/how-powerlifting-gave-me-back-the-power-to-feel-good-at-sport/106234088</link><description>As a child, Julie "wasn't one of the sporty kids". A safe gym environment and then a supportive powerlifting community helped her realise that wasn't actually true.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2abbef65f571e75069d3d1abdc6f375</guid></item><item><title>Labor 'really close' to deal with Liberals on hate speech laws, Tony Burke says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/labor-coalition-hate-laws-deal-deadline-looms/106244300</link><description>Liberal MPs gathered to discuss the draft laws at a party room meeting in Canberra on Monday evening after Opposition Leader Sussan Ley and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese met to hash out an agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a2526f58a5d9b6415bdab9d0bbe190d</guid></item><item><title>China ramps up crackdown on Christians amid global political pressures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/china-ramps-up-crackdown-on-underground-christian-churches/106228908</link><description>Dozens of church leaders and members have been arrested in China in recent months, which advocates say is indicative of intensifying persecution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c54c22a63990022797415619510f9303</guid></item><item><title>China's population declines for a fourth straight year amid record low birthrates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/china-population-decline-fourth-straight-year/106245406</link><description>National data shows that in 2025, China's population shrank by 3.39 million people, as experts warn the trend is likely to continue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5e802e05f3c7a95834eb029793b0ed4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump heading to Davos as bond market vigilantes plot against him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/donald-trump-us-federal-reserve-powell-interest-rates/106245010</link><description>There are signs Donald Trump's bold strategy to artificially lower interest rates could backfire, as a level of disquiet emerges on money markets, particularly in bonds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65e936bbb965d193d01d5df138ff1bd8</guid></item><item><title>Shark expert says it's a 'terrible idea' to swim in Sydney Harbour after heavy rain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/sydney-harbour-shark-risk-not-clear-sewage-attracts-fish/106245214</link><description>A public policy shark expert says sewage leaking into the harbour after heavy rainfall is attracting bait fish followed by sharks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">196c8da596d94bf6c88caf312ec27dc2</guid></item><item><title>First Nations employee asked by supervisor about eating ants takes transport department to court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/sa-transport-department-federal-court-case/106231982</link><description>A First Nations employee at South Australia's Department for Infrastructure and Transport (DIT) has claimed she was sexually harassed by her supervisor and racially discriminated against when asked about eating ants before a cultural training session, court documents reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7374c2347019e1b32db9a67988ee3efb</guid></item><item><title>In Iran, Elon Musk's Starlink helped citizens get messages beyond the 'digital prison'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/in-iran-starlink-helped-citizens-break-out-of-the-digital-prison/106244360</link><description>In Iran, Starlink has provided a line to the outside world, but now there are fears about such vital technology being in the hands of one company.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbf024ef38c524a39f1172af74e69250</guid></item><item><title>New Trump tariffs on European allies could push EU to use 'trade bazooka'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/trump-tariffs-european-allies-trade-bazooka/106243894</link><description>Following the Trump administration's recent tariff threat on European allies, some experts warn it may push Europe closer to China, and potentially see the European Union use its anti-coercion instrument, also known as a "trade bazooka", in response.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfd83a0c8c002868f5bb1a1d952c2109</guid></item><item><title>Victorian bushfires squeeze beekeeper access to high-quality trees for bees ahead of winter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/victoria-bushfires-beekeeper-access-restrictions/106243830</link><description>Apiarists in Victoria are wondering how they will keep their bees fed during winter after bushfires two years in a row render certain areas inaccessible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53ba80cd946bb3fbcb843855ca6d35a4</guid></item><item><title>Dissecting Donald Trump's Greenland message to Norway's PM, line by line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/donald-trump-greenland-message-analysed-line-by-line/106246964</link><description>A text message from the US president to Norway's prime minister has fanned the flames of the geopolitical dumpster fire engulfing Greenland. We've analysed Donald Trump's claims to see if they stack up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81dd92b61485bb709c037d07f0241a9b</guid></item><item><title>Women's captain departs football club after men's offensive Silly Saturday costumes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/box-hill-north-fc-womens-captain-leaves-club-after-men-behaviour/106190266</link><description>A women's senior football captain has stepped away from her local club after photos of the senior men's leadership team were posted online during their "Silly Saturday" post-season celebrations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ffb103fdb7886c68801e2562aeef8ca</guid></item><item><title>Stan Wawrinka's impressive win, a wheelchair exit and Alja Tomljanović tells off her dad — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/australian-open-2026-quick-hits/106243998</link><description>One player had to be wheeled off the courts in a wheelchair, while Alja Tomljanović was wishing her dad would be quiet in the crowd. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5d4a55ec566caaa313f28eb7c9913b7</guid></item><item><title>Ipswich residents frustrated as nickel waste stored near homes without council approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/ipswich-residents-nickelwaste-dumped-nearhomes-council-approval/106244714</link><description>The dumping of the waste is the latest in a series of similar events for Ipswich, the city which some now call "Australia's waste capital".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">098856adadd618e6d5f95435a562ca83</guid></item><item><title>Shellharbour mayor's quick thinking during call may have saved deputy's life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/shellharbour-councillor-kellie-marsh-aneurysm-emergency/106245410</link><description>A mayor's split-second decision to answer a phone call instead of heading into the surf may well have saved the life of his deputy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d92c75f46d2dd5048aa680d5e3e2bc68</guid></item><item><title>Flooding impacts low-lying areas in Rockhampton, as residents prepare for Fitzroy River's peak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/rockhampton-prepares-for-flooding-as-fitzroy-river-rises/106243980</link><description>Flooding on the Fitzroy River will be less severe than originally predicted, however about 280 properties could still be impacted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46307e6ceb28c50848a1e3fe59e9e7c9</guid></item><item><title>Foo Fighters are playing their only Australian show in Launceston on Saturday, here's what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/foo-fighters-launceston-concert-what-you-need-to-know/106243618</link><description>Tasmania's "biggest ever concert" is heating up Launceston this weekend, and whether you have tickets or not, there are a few things you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">756623b97549184033b8460854e8b087</guid></item><item><title>Alexei Popyrin shattered as Australian Open campaign ends in first round following thriller against Alexandre Muller</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/tennis-aus-open-popyrin-shattered-muller-defeat/106247208</link><description>Alexei Popyrin concedes he will look inwards once again to think about his career after a crushing loss sent him out of the Australian Open in the first round.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f28d48e2dc361558508277915e9e9d5c</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: PM defends action on antisemitism in QT as debate kicks off in Senate — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/federal-politics-live-blog-jan-20/106245678</link><description>The prime minister defends the government's action on antisemitism in the first Question Time of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce2a21bbf58cf609b34b039baf956196</guid></item><item><title>Man found dead in back of car near Corowa hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/dead-body-found-car-corowa-hospital/106247200</link><description>A police investigation is underway after a man was found dead inside a car near a hospital on the NSW–Victoria border.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffbe1c57c1a4bb08978725b53ff36d04</guid></item><item><title>'Promising' results for AI fish passage aiming to help stop another Menindee mass fish kill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/ai-fish-passage-fishnet-darling-river-trial-mass-fish-kill-nsw/106221776</link><description>The $6.5 million Menindee fish passage trial is now in year two and results are "promising", but not everyone is buoyed by confidence in the project's ability to prevent another mass fish kill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">189c0bfe4dba5512db02a22c6a101b9f</guid></item><item><title>ASX trades down, BHP shares slide, IMF calls out Australia's 'drawn-out' inflation — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-tuesday-20-january/106247268</link><description>The ASX trades down on Tuesday. The International Monetary Fund says Australia, alongside Norway, is projected to see persistent above-target inflation. Follow the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9583dd3a472f2001cb9f12c33d757786</guid></item><item><title>Front lines in 'ghost net' war expand to Australia's north with $25m funding boost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/ghost-nets-funding-remote-nt-blue-mud-bay-indonesia-fishing/106244780</link><description>A $25 million funding injection will help expand the Top End's war on ghost nets, as ranger groups shift focus to the heavily fished seas to Australia's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">486f3c79d2cb26ac2906752d5be6b54c</guid></item><item><title>WA Opposition Leader Basil Zempilas seizes on fishing, tobacco to challenge government's dominance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/basil-zempilas-fishing-ban-tobacco-challenge-state-government/106246436</link><description>While many West Australians were competing for parking spots at beaches on their holidays, Basil Zempilas latched onto two hot topics on which to challenge the government — the demersal fishing ban and WA's illicit tobacco trade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e3968683f38c8c701336ac2ede5ca0d</guid></item><item><title>Attempted murder charges laid, firearm recovered after Huntfield Heights shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/attempted-murder-charges-over-huntfield-heights-shooting/106247230</link><description>A man and a woman are expected to face court after each was charged with two counts of attempted murder over a shooting at a Huntfield Heights home that left two people in hospital, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">728ff3de3a647b50be77716cf4db2799</guid></item><item><title>Pilbara water sources drying up as blistering heatwave continues in Karratha</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/harding-dam-karratha-low-water-storage-levels-heatwave/106237810</link><description>Water sources are depleting in the Pilbara as the arid region endures a summer with little rainfall and temperatures close to 50C.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42ae93a704d37666b5838230f66f76df</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane suffers vaccine shortages after wall collapses at Toll Group distribution centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/brisbane-hit-by-vaccine-shortages/106247402</link><description>Brisbane parents are being turned away from GP clinics due to a shortage of childhood vaccines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95c7e8806a61ca804b73a3bea4054c5a</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026: Naomi Osaka sends a fashion statement, Dane Sweeny and James Duckworth progress</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/australian-open-2026-live-updates-jannik-sinner-naomi-osaka/106247690</link><description>Seeing Naomi Osaka don a jellyfish-inspired outfit was one highlight of day three of the tournament, however two plucky Australians — Dane Sweeny and James Duckworth also put on a show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0df00c26a62e3ee2d269780de89c116</guid></item><item><title>Eraring coal-fired power station to stay open until 2029</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/eraring-coal-fired-power-station-to-stay-open-until-2029/106247568</link><description>The operator of Australia's largest coal-fired power station is to extend the life of its plant in the NSW Hunter Valley for another two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa4566311697a925b7bfb77a6bef8f96</guid></item><item><title>How a lion crushed a Datsun with newlyweds inside in 1970s Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/lion-crushed-datsun-newlyweds-adelaide-bullens-safari-park/106245924</link><description>The pair had made an on-the-spot decision on the way home from their honeymoon to visit a drive-through safari park where lions roamed free — and their little brown Datsun came out worse for wear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43ee7f7f3d6b74a70e1cd8189e8b25db</guid></item><item><title>Mile Jedinak joins Socceroos coaching staff ahead of FIFA World Cup as Australia reveals warm-up opponents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/mile-jedinak-joins-socceroos-coaching-staff-fifa-world-cup/106247740</link><description>The former Australian captain is back in the fold for another World Cup, except this time he will be on the sidelines as one of the team's coaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81fdcba14bb2153f890de445e389887c</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged with attempted murder after child allegedly stabbed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/child-with-knife-wounds-flown-to-melbourne-for-treatment/106248002</link><description>Police are investigating after a child presented to the Launceston General Hospital with serious injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a596a4f476857f12bbadc0a70f6d9bc</guid></item><item><title>Surfer bitten by shark at Point Plomer on NSW Mid North Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/nsw-surfer-bitten-by-shark-at-point-plomer/106247202</link><description>The 39-year-old man was surfing at Point Plomer, near Crescent Head, this morning when the shark bit through his board.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb653505bc6e2a92572d8c8cb09c6e0f</guid></item><item><title>Jessica Pegula reveals what goes on inside the Australian Open locker room</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/australian-open-melbourne-park-jessica-pegula-locker-room/106247748</link><description>According to Jessica Pegula, sometimes it is best to stay out of your opponent's way when you are sharing the same locker room.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a1c583886473dd9b6f5188701bb226f</guid></item><item><title>Increase in suspicious fires puts emergency services under pressure in WA's South West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/south-west-wa-suspicious-fires-arson-increase/106224380</link><description>A growing number of suspicious fires left police and firefighters under significant pressure over the Christmas period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d791a57fff1587aacc6ed5ba010c0fb7</guid></item><item><title>Labor's hate laws pass despite a divided Coalition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/hate-laws-poised-to-pass-after-labor-liberal-deal/106248432</link><description>The federal government has passed new laws targeting hate groups with support from the Liberals, while the Nationals voted against it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b34a07a73e9a13ce0ed28c59db72ba8d</guid></item><item><title>Canadian 19-year-old found dead on K'gari (Fraser Island) identified as Piper James</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/increased-ranger-patrols-woman-found-dead-on-kgari-fraser-island/106247890</link><description>The woman was found surrounded by dingoes after going for an early-morning swim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dacce30c93163641174c887bd95d813</guid></item><item><title>Why could Donald Trump's Board of Peace be a threat to the United Nations?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/what-is-donald-trump-s-board-of-peace/106247750</link><description>Donald Trump appears to be trying to build his own international peacekeeping body, which he calls the "Board of Peace". Here's why experts think it might attempt to rival the UN.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5b33664544fb9cc37564486eeb34924</guid></item><item><title>Police arrest man over death of Maffra jeweller Steve Curtis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/maffra-death-investigation-homicide-squad/106247384</link><description>A 45-year-old man has been arrested following the death of a 63-year-old man in the Gippsland town of Maffra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e35864efde16cf45eb55cc09727ebd2</guid></item><item><title>Brain cancer survivor who finished year 12 hoping medication can get PBS listing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/brain-cancer-survivor-hoping-medication-can-get-pbs-listing/106163562</link><description>Just over a year ago Sienna was shocked to discover she had a rare brain cancer. She's taking a new drug to slow its growth, but it's come at great cost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21adf0d155fecef77dd6873776191137</guid></item><item><title>Man, 29, charged with bushland murder of Matthew O'Brien</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/police-nowra-suspicious-murder-man-charged/106205866</link><description>Police have charged a 29-year-old man after the alleged murder of a 60-year-old man, who was found with serious head injuries on a fire trail in Nowra in December 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1717537b3d9e2a3f71c8e00e16ab753a</guid></item><item><title>French media releases new security footage of thieves in Louvre heist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/new-security-footage-of-louvre-heist-released/106248086</link><description>The security footage shows the thieves smashing the glass on the display cases where the jewellery was kept.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9556ee4895b887312e1e10433709e155</guid></item><item><title>Gilmour Space receives federal funding boost for homegrown rockets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/gilmour-space-funding-boost-for-homegrown-rockets/106247624</link><description>The company hailed the launch of its first Australian designed and manufactured rocket a success, despite it being airborne for just 14 seconds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ef86a9d002caca346cff368daa291fc</guid></item><item><title>Writers' Week replacement likened to 'thought bubble', but backer says it is 'happening regardless'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/adelaide-council-votes-on-writers-week-alternative/106247520</link><description>Adelaide City Council commits to supporting, but not funding, a replacement event to fill the void left by Writers' Week, as the lord mayor describes the proposal as "not much more" than a "thought bubble".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03b47a20c6ad1ec840fbc6a6d97cd5de</guid></item><item><title>UN representative says Iran's death toll is rising and there could be investigations into 'crimes against humanity'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/united-nations-iran-deaths-investigation-crimes-against-humanity/106238634</link><description>An independent fact-finding mission should investigate potential crimes against humanity committed by the Islamic Republic of Iran, according a UN-appointed representative.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9eb9554dc290945551a0d9273835ced</guid></item><item><title>Brooklyn Beckham has cut ties with his famous parents. What can we learn from it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/brooklyn-beckham-statement-cuts-ties-with-family/106247778</link><description>Celebrity family rifts are not new. Experts weigh in on how they can spark negative feelings about our own family dynamics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b2cd51e90201aa458b1662acb5a3c4c</guid></item><item><title>Four shark attacks in 48 hours on NSW beaches. What do we know about them?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/nsw-what-we-know-about-the-shark-attacks/106248186</link><description>Four shark attacks are documented within 48 hours at beaches across New South Wales, lifting the anxieties of swimmers and surfers who are considering a dip in the ocean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdd09d7f88d80c01ef397e46b5b0f25f</guid></item><item><title>One Nation's ambitious plan raises stakes for major parties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/pauline-hanson-one-nation-polling-state-election-mainstream/106244024</link><description>While she's made no secret of her desire to eventually unseat Anthony Albanese, the One Nation leader's immediate electoral strategy is to gain ground at upcoming state elections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9378de660f955ea3ba520a0ae352651f</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese pays tribute to Tim Picton in parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/anthony-albanese-tim-picton-tribute-parliament/106248850</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">815bd620806de5ee13098374c96a6344</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police commissioner extends Sydney protest restrictions with 'significantly limited' scope</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/nsw-police-update-on-public-assembly-restriction-declaration-law/106248964</link><description>NSW Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon has announced restrictions on protests in parts of the state will be extended.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97b157a8e4854c3a779102cd09f55e8f</guid></item><item><title>Three federal politicians demand incoming NT administrator David Connolly apologise for 'offensive' posts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/nt-administrator-david-connolly-criticised-by-labor-politicians/106248300</link><description>Past social media posts made by incoming Northern Territory administrator David Connolly have been labelled "reprehensible" by three federal politicians, who are also demanding he apologise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5197dd5fd318bec2e8fec957cce707e5</guid></item><item><title>Maya Joint vows to 'come back stronger' after early Australian Open exit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/australian-open-maya-joint-loses-first-round/106249028</link><description>Maya Joint's first Australian Open appearance as a seed did not go according to plan, following a straight-sets defeat on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d1cfb70cdfd67e0e62683a684a60cf7</guid></item><item><title>Hackers disrupt Iranian state TV to support exiled crown prince</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/iran-state-tv-hacked-support-exiled-pahlavi/106248974</link><description>Hackers break into Iranian state television satellite transmissions to air footage supporting the country's exiled former prince and calling on security forces to lay down their weapons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2d6af2341a8b6d36468dc784a517900</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic penguin breeding cycles changing rapidly in response to climate change, study shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/antarctic-penguin-breeding-cycles-changing-climate-change/106247472</link><description>Penguins in parts of Antarctica are breeding up to two weeks earlier than a decade ago, likely in response to climate change, according to a long-term study.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">195f7747bf8736cce5a600570b4a107c</guid></item><item><title>Surf webcam captures moment of shark attack at North Steyne beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/surf-webcam-captures-moment-of-shark-attack/106249880</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3383f67b3bfc1661108740bd4f07b134</guid></item><item><title>Valentino's legacy as 'one of the last true titans' of Italian fashion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/valentino-remembered-as-titan-of-fashion-industry-after-death/106247774</link><description>"Valentino red", now synonymous with the Italian designer, was introduced to the world in 1959. But it wasn't until years later he commanded true global attention — and with an entirely different dress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">650b53dff8ce0884258262001076422b</guid></item><item><title>Aussie Dylan Joyce's punt blocked for a touchdown as Indiana down Miami in college football title game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/dylan-joyce-punter-miami-indiana-college-title-game/106249630</link><description>A few months ago, Indiana had the worst record in college football history, and while the Sooners have completed one of the greatest rises in American sports to win the national championship against Miami, it came following a tough moment for an Australian import.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2149ae4285c6910a968f99f276b5563b</guid></item><item><title>Blue Mountains council closes Lincoln's Rock lookout after safety concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/popular-lookout-lincolns-rock-in-blue-mountains-closed/106245326</link><description>A council will shut an iconic Blue Mountains cliff after being overrun with tourists, sparking serious safety and environmental concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ada72b20a8c3f9c6a85fe9134a0fc19f</guid></item><item><title>Prime minister, WA premier pay tribute to former Labor political strategist Tim Picton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/tim-picton-death-tributes-continue-police-minister-sends-message/106248466</link><description>The death of Labor identity Tim Picton rocks his former political colleagues, prompting warnings from WA's police minister about the devastating consequences of one-punch assaults.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84736ea419e0f2b89d15dd485f1e46a2</guid></item><item><title>Hawthorn's Will Day to miss first half of the AFL season with shoulder injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/will-day-hawthorn-shoulder-injury-return-afl/106250104</link><description>Hawthorn star Will Day is set for a lengthy stint on the sidelines after dislocating his right shoulder during pre-season training and undergoing surgery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d307d6fe71f40e6d700287b246f166</guid></item><item><title>Sydney NDIS provider director accused of $3.6m fraud as cash seized at home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/ndis-provider-director-allegedly-defrauded-millions-from-claims/106249802</link><description>Australian Federal Police allege Billal Chami submitted claims for supports and services never provided to participants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df504b690a294a5a80851df23bf1f1ff</guid></item><item><title>CCTV of kitten dumping in Adelaide's north-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/cctv-of-kitten-dumping-in-adelaide-s-north-east/106250206</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a12459f3ea305052690e39c57ca7bc71</guid></item><item><title>Thousands in Albany told to switch to LPG bottles as gas supplier ATCO decommissions network</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/albany-gas-network-to-be-decommissioned/106246382</link><description>The Albany mayor says the city has been blindsided by a decision to decommission the local gas network and transition thousands of customers onto bottled LPG gas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f1c800231c6ac81005eafc6625d1958</guid></item><item><title>Midnight Oil founder and drummer Rob Hirst dies aged 70</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/midnight-oil-drummer-rob-hirst-dies/106249816</link><description>Rob Hirst was diagnosed with pancreatic cancer in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b535d98e30538a1047c5fa6e1db1103a</guid></item><item><title>Do Woolworths shoppers want Google AI adding items to buy? We'll soon find out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/woolworths-google-ai-items-shopping-groceries/106243642</link><description>Without scrutiny, agent-led shopping risks quietly reconfiguring consumer behaviour in ways that are difficult to detect — and even harder to reverse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e87faa771f8a6692e3910d20b01de1f</guid></item><item><title>Is there a 'normal' amount of sex couples should be having?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/defining-a-healthy-and-fulfilling-sex-life/106100374</link><description>Whether it's TV shows or what our friends say, we pick up an idea of "normal" sex frequency from lots of places. But experts say how often you're having sex doesn't tell you much about whether it's satisfying or enjoyable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d933f11a6d491d896029179c92bdd34a</guid></item><item><title>Helen Manuell changed careers in her 50s from bridal design to sustainable fashion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/helen-manuell-fashion-designer-bridal-knitwear-rmit/106231758</link><description>Helen Manuell changed career paths in her 50s, swapping bridal couture for award-winning sustainable fashion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e16e712493ce4cb02d37d38df466c8c</guid></item><item><title>Maggot-infested meal halts work at $1 billion hydro project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/maggot-meal-halts-work-at-1-billion-dollar-hydro-project/106248782</link><description>An investigation into a maggot-infested meal halts work on a key pumped hydro project in North Queensland, with more than 100 workers flown out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b40fe65ed30e5a5b4dd8904eac05d5b4</guid></item><item><title>Queensland health services report financial black hole of almost $1 billion as population booms and ages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/qld-health-blowout-hospital-report/106249992</link><description>The combined deficit of Queensland's health department and 16 hospital and health services in 2024-25 was the worst ever reported in the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3746f384ecbd30edd186f8342ee71689</guid></item><item><title>WA environmental regulator recommends controversial Valhalla gas project go-ahead in Kimberley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/epa-recommends-kimberley-valhalla-exploration-program/106249136</link><description>Traditional owners and environmental groups are calling on the premier and environment minister to reject a controversial proposal to explore gas wells in the Kimberley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">683106aca3d30f27f33ee8e89400d1ee</guid></item><item><title>WA government calls for unity on firearm reforms as Liberal-led states reject national gun buyback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/wa-government-calls-for-unity-on-national-gun-buyback/106248706</link><description>The state government responsible for the Australia's toughest gun laws calls for unity on national reform, as the path forward splinters along party lines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0030b578d133022842e75741ad8e1891</guid></item><item><title>Hobart Hurricanes lose captain Nathan Ellis and Test batsman Jake Weatherald for Big Bash knockout final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/two-big-names-to-miss-bbl-knockout-final/106250756</link><description>Hobart's quest for back-to-back Big Bash titles has copped two major blows with captain Nathan Ellis and Test player Jake Weatherald to miss the Hurricanes' knockout final against Melbourne Renegades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b67761843ab9ed0f2e8dd6d75d499e78</guid></item><item><title>Macron warns of Trump's 'new colonialism' as US president leaks Greenland texts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/trump-shares-texts-from-macron-offering-g7-meeting-after-davos/106250724</link><description>US President Donald Trump has shared a private message purportedly from his French counterpart Emmanuel Macron ahead of a global economic forum in Davos, Switzerland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59956ca8dbf96db0c1b943f3ce007000</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106250606</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b179e9dbc02bc38323324d62e839d0c7</guid></item><item><title>Shooting by ICE agents in Minnesota incites national US protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/shooting-by-ice-agents-in-minnesota-incites-national-us-protests/106250340</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01a9fa2297e01249d676f26d03b97ef0</guid></item><item><title>Israeli authorities begin demolishing former UNRWA compound in East Jerusalem</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/israel-demolish-united-nations-headquarters-jerusalem/106250826</link><description>The UN has labelled Israel's move to bulldoze a former UNRWA headquarters a "serious violation of international law".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f43bc8ddc10b9406d601670f5dec8bf</guid></item><item><title>Farmers Federation slams WA's heritage laws 'a complete mess' and questions enforcement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/wa-heritage-laws-wafarmers-federation-tony-maddox/106248572</link><description>There are calls for the state government to revisit the state's Aboriginal heritage laws, which WA farmers say could result in media outlets being fined thousands of dollars for publishing images of culturally protected heritage sites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ace3e524c4018e818db338a1f8c0d71d</guid></item><item><title>'Large bull camels weighing hundreds of kilos' move into NT communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/feral-camels-central-australia-remote-communities-damage/106248412</link><description>Hundreds of large bull camels descend on remote communities in Central Australia, causing damage to infrastructure in their search for water and prompting calls for federal assistance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43d75c5a1a874b826f57496ac88ef705</guid></item><item><title>Sam Watson wins Tour Down Under prologue, Jay Vine finishes fourth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/sam-watson-tour-down-under-prologue/106250080</link><description>British rider Sam Watson claimed a blisteringly quick Tour Down Under prologue time-trial victory, but Jay Vine took significant time out of his rivals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cca457f29cf44973a50c9e12485cf089</guid></item><item><title>Dame Marie Bashir, the first female governor of NSW, dies aged 95</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/dame-marie-bashir-the-first-female-nsw-governor-dies/106251006</link><description>NSW Premier Chris Minns says a state funeral will be held for the veteran public servant, who he describes as "an extraordinary Australian".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d45edad039d595addb9c09ed06d80e5e</guid></item><item><title>UK backs plan for China's new embassy in London at Royal Mint Court, despite spy fears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/chinese-embassy-in-london-approved-by-uk-government/106251004</link><description>The new embassy will sit in the city's Royal Mint Court alongside London's famous financial hub, despite experts and human rights groups raising concerns about foreign interference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e4e8511161243507bfe43ef3dc5c285</guid></item><item><title>California Governor Gavin Newsom warns US allies against 'rolling over' to Trump amid Greenland crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/newsom-mocks-european-leaders-greenland/106251248</link><description>As European leaders struggle to come up with ways to ease the US president's ambition for a take over of Greenland, a prominent Democrat is accusing them of "rolling over".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c329ff341053c9d7904a28a94d92f51</guid></item><item><title>Baby killer Lucy Letby to face no further criminal charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/lucy-letby-to-face-no-further-criminal-charges/106251330</link><description>The UK's Crown Prosecution Service says it considered the offences of murder or attempted murder in relation to the deaths of nine babies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85b230bf61be118577d731c9fc2899bf</guid></item><item><title>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un fires vice premier over factory modernisation plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/kim-jong-un-fires-vice-premier-over-north-korea-factory-plan/106251318</link><description>The North Korean leader blamed Yang Sun Ho for "confusion" and cost blow-outs at a factory project in the country's north-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9321a014b0f2876383cdc059e28aca14</guid></item><item><title>Marius Borg Hoiby, son of Norwegian Crown Princess Mette-Marit, charged with a serious drug offence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/marius-borg-hoiby-charged-with-new-drugs-offences/106251350</link><description>Marius Borg Høiby faces six new charges including an alleged "serious narcotics offence" in addition to sexual assault charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52fa885acfb387ac4933a280320a5b44</guid></item><item><title>David Beckham breaks silence after son Brooklyn cuts ties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/david-beckham-brooklyn-davos-children-make-mistakes/106251360</link><description>The soccer superstar tells broadcasters at the World Economic Forum that "children are allowed to make mistakes" in his first public comments since his son's allegations went public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eea9ba1d2b7ca4efca871fee6767d24b</guid></item><item><title>From small cuttings to large pots, household plants are being stolen in great numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/plant-theft-greenery-being-stolen-garden-items-data/106092428</link><description>Data shows more than 2,000 items were reported stolen from gardens over a year in one state alone. So what can plant owners do to protect their beloved greenery from theft?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c928230238105d96554ef20638daf04c</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, January 21: The first time the Williams sisters faced off in a Grand Slam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/first-time-venus-serena-williams-face-off-grand-slam-1998/106200228</link><description>On this day in 1998, Venus and Serena Williams faced off for the first time at a Grand Slam tournament, starting an iconic sibling rivalry that would last two decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e3c726e7b71f131c95ac512dde4ff6b</guid></item><item><title>ABC 50/50 quiz: This week we're testing your knowledge of the Beatles, Lost, champagne and floating planets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/abc-50-50-quiz-january-20/106245872</link><description>Every question has only two options: One is right and the other is wrong. You have an even chance of guessing correctly each time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62a81928179bebc2b4b24bb3b8e93a72</guid></item><item><title>Home buyer says scheme does not work after setbacks buying old and building new</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/myhome-home-ownership-scheme-setbacks/106171584</link><description>Erin Bell's efforts to both buy a house and build a new one through a government scheme were repeatedly challenged — once because she had disclosed a new boyfriend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f65e498ebae764bae79b51a699f2cb9f</guid></item><item><title>Inside the program teaching US ICE agents to 'Defend the Homeland'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/ice-us-agent-training-program-to-defend-the-homeland/106231394</link><description>For the thousands of "patriots" who've applied, a position with ICE is a source of pride. Experts, elected officials and activists say otherwise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">169293b8022843b9c673ffd9e9fdcbbc</guid></item><item><title>The Amazon effect: Gen Z now expect same-day or next-day goods deliveries or else</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/amazon-effect-gen-z-expect-deliveries/106137160</link><description>Small retailers are scrambling to keep up with deliveries as research shows Australian shoppers are expecting the same ultra-fast delivery they get from retail giants like Amazon. But some entrepreneurs have more than a few tricks up their sleeves to satisfy gen Z.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c41c48aed166c1984ec2c9a4989947b</guid></item><item><title>Jewish leaders call for vilification offence to be revisited as Coalition splits over watered-down hate laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/jewish-groups-react-hate-law-reform-passes-senate/106248826</link><description>Labor's watered-down hate law reform has passed the Senate with the support of the Liberal Party but not the Nationals, who opposed the legislation due to freedom of speech concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fad11d06343d02b870639866f7eed592</guid></item><item><title>The trends and records to watch in triple j's 2025 Hottest 100</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/hottest-100-records-trends-preview/106194682</link><description>Here's what might go down when triple j unveils the Hottest 100 of 2025 this Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dcfd6df0cc240a6a84c9d241cc075dd</guid></item><item><title>Victorian fires set to send premiums higher in areas where insurance already unaffordable for some</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/insurers-say-premiums-will-rise-after-victorian-fires/106244640</link><description>Neighbours living on the same fire-ravaged street in regional Victoria are facing vastly different recoveries due to insurance differences, and recent disasters may push premiums further out of reach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8eba5d08ece1cd8b797fd8bef1bca4f4</guid></item><item><title>China's air force has technology that rivals the US's and it could be pivotal in any conflict over Taiwan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/chinese-air-force-rivals-us-taiwan-conflict/106212470</link><description>Certain capabilities of China's air force now seriously challenge those of the US and other Western countries, with experts saying that it could tip the balance of any war over Taiwan in Beijing's favour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14ab6258dffc6b2d55045bc2846c68fd</guid></item><item><title>Samoa's prime minister proposes ban on non-Christian faiths after vowing 'God-centred' leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/samoa-prime-minister-religion-restrictions/106225328</link><description>Samoa's prime minister has thrown the future of its religious minorities into doubt after flagging potential restrictions on non-Christian faiths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebae72323b0b85847169eb6d895b9309</guid></item><item><title>Death of Tim Picton puts spotlight on Australia's 'one-punch' laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/tim-picton-death-one-punch-law-national-state-breakdown/106245498</link><description>The death of Labor identity Tim Picton more than three weeks after he was allegedly assaulted outside a Perth nightclub has shocked Australia's political and business worlds and put the nation's one-punch laws under the microscope.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbdb1d300d1e36c3d586f70d5414bce8</guid></item><item><title>First Nations people will protest this January 26, a legacy dating back 88 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/why-first-nations-peoples-protest-on-jan-26/106248728</link><description>Invasion Day rallies will go ahead on Monday after being exempted from NSW protest bans. Here's the story of how they started in the first place.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">099647a352d14be82852c414e0e38460</guid></item><item><title>Austrian study shows a cow using tools for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/austrian-study-shows-a-cow-using-tools-for-the-first-time/106249324</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e93ee64327f2f7b329361f0c4b81d487</guid></item><item><title>Scientific study documents Austrian cow using a tool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/scientific-study-documents-austrian-cow-using-tool/106247598</link><description>A pet cow in Austria has been filmed picking up a tool and scratching herself. An Australian hobby farmer says she is not that surprised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea86ccea34accc0a1ccb2c65d9691ef0</guid></item><item><title>Highest number of January shark attacks in NSW for a decade, according to national database</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/shark-attack-numbers-in-nsw-australian-shark-incident-database/106249078</link><description>Shark populations are declining worldwide but NSW has already recorded the highest number of January attacks in a decade. A marine biologist says there are reasons sharks and people are coming into contact more often.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30165a0269e2829de2cb29bdc11444a0</guid></item><item><title>Queensland teenagers create coding app to bridge digital divide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/qld-teenagers-create-coding-app-code-lab-sri-lanka-students/106225842</link><description>Young coding whizzes Neth Dharmasiri and Chinmay Lal believe learning the language behind computer software shouldn't depend on where you were born.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3629ca2497c48acad1816ae6ba32176c</guid></item><item><title>Insurance industry hoping to break a major barrier to expanding cultural burning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/cultural-burning-insurance-breakthrough/106214712</link><description>Insurance has been a major stumbling block to the scaling up of cultural burning, but a breakthrough could be on the way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70b301662ea2f423238a1d5c9e30bd2f</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump, the madman theory, and why even Australia is not safe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/donald-trump-greenland-threat-madman-theory-analysis/106251358</link><description>One year into Trump's second term, something has become clear: even those who leave the Oval Office with a deal, beware. It might not be worth the paper it's written on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17a15eeef7276e5175a8d9725cbfee47</guid></item><item><title>Mitchell Starc shoulder injury concerns Sydney Sixers after BBL qualifier loss to Perth Scorchers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/sixers-sweat-on-starc-injury-after-bitter-scorchers-blow/106251462</link><description>The Sydney Sixers are thrust into a do-or-die final on Friday after losing to Perth, and star quick Mitch Starc is no guarantee to play.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eefe7c22daed676aa248b269f9e31aae</guid></item><item><title>'Riches to rags story' highlights challenges for homeless on the Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/gold-coast-socialite-homeless-housing-crisis-qld/106237724</link><description>Bethany Turner is among those struggling to find safety and stability while living on the street since the local council began issuing move-on directions to people sleeping rough in public spaces last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27a2abf59a47cd7c6aa17ed145f2f360</guid></item><item><title>Naomi Osaka brings fashion to RLA and Monfils says goodbye — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/australian-open-2026-quick-hits/106248012</link><description>Naomi Osaka took to Rod Laver Arena in a white, flowy jellyfish fashion piece on day three as Gael Monfils waved goodbye to Melbourne Park. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ad648002c1830c934b1b9a8e22a3c1b</guid></item><item><title>Dane Sweeny's Australian Open first-round win over Gaël Monfils built on sacrifice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/australian-open-dane-sweeny-gael-monfils-first-round/106250838</link><description>When Dane Sweeny triumphantly fell to the ground following his defeat of Gaël Monfils at the Australian Open, it was not just a celebration for himself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b0c1a0569a4c42adff52c8869a7aac0</guid></item><item><title>Markets live: 'Sell America' trade in full swing as Trump's Greenland threats send Wall Street and US dollar lower</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/asx-markets-business-live-news-jan-21/106251484</link><description>The Australian share market is set to fall for a third straight day as Wall Street tumbled to a one-month low on worsening relations between the US and Europe. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7ffaaa5709d871e705eec87c84bd2e3</guid></item><item><title>Canegrowers celebrates 100 years of fighting for fairness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/canegrowers-100-year-anniversary/106250648</link><description>Australia's sugarcane industry looks back on a century of representation as peak body Canegrowers turns 100.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d577715ca993aecd95ab753297f6b75</guid></item><item><title>Father of Piper James, found dead surrounded by dingoes on K'gari, 'shattered' by loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/kgari-dingoes-and-death-of-piper-james/106251528</link><description>Canadian Piper James was found on K'gari (Fraser Island) surrounded by a pack of dingoes on Monday morning after telling friends she was going for an early morning swim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efdd2902e34ed5279d20f59d66213d10</guid></item><item><title>Perth Fringe World to feature over 3,000 performers across venues in Northbridge, CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/perth-fringe-world-to-feature-over-3000-performers/106248818</link><description>This year's Perth Fringe World is about more than just racy burlesque shows, spicy cabaret and acrobatic performances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9272b2c44bd3bb74d2fc5018ab0043a4</guid></item><item><title>Future for three Nationals in doubt after defying shadow cabinet on hate speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/nationals-ministries-doubt-coalition-split-hate-speech/106251594</link><description>The future of three senior Nationals who voted against the Coalition's official position on hate speech reforms is in doubt, as both camps mull whether the trio must resign for breaching cabinet solidarity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe681e902b030d99c1bea78cce0b26e2</guid></item><item><title>At least 15 injured after commuter train derails near Barcelona</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/commuter-train-derails-near-barcelona-after-wall-collapse/106251708</link><description>At least 15 people are injured after a containment wall fell onto a train track near the Spanish city of Barcelona, the country's Civil Guard says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e932850efc859db7d5d9da9b61c3373</guid></item></channel></rss>