<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 03:58:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Critics question how $13 billion US–Australia critical minerals deal will benefit WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/what-us-australia-critical-minerals-deal-means-for-wa/105917058</link><description>Western Australia's slice of the critical minerals deal is being heralded as a huge win, but critics are asking how much US aluminium giant Alcoa's boon will benefit Western Australians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d90983fb0f88dbee5bbbe13b312db584</guid></item><item><title>Pilbara communities disconnected from culture, health services due to road damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/remote-aboriginal-communities-isolated-by-road-damage-pilbara/105877672</link><description>Indigenous elders and advocates fear worsening roads in the Pilbara, which are littered with the rusted skeletons of abandoned cars, are isolating remote residents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">786999b61ea8130c215920754d41f52d</guid></item><item><title>Temperatures soar in NSW as cyclone-strength winds batter Victoria and SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/nsw-victoria-sa-wild-weather-hits-state/105917928</link><description>Temperatures are soaring in NSW, while Victorian and South Australian residents are bracing for powerful wind gusts on a day of wild weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bd5aa7b045791c41cd2c9ae88498b37</guid></item><item><title>Victoria Police Chief Commissioner apologises for using Air Wing helicopter to fly to Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/vic-police-commissioner-helicopter-flight-tasmania-apology/105919448</link><description>The chief commissioner of Victoria Police says the use of a police helicopter for a work trip to Tasmania "creates a poor impression".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32718b9a38003dd9ad007b28a05cef38</guid></item><item><title>After learning to walk and talk again, Laura is walking 50km in October to raise money for the RFDS</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/seatbelt-warning-wa-road-crash-rfds-fundraiser/105915366</link><description>After surviving a car crash and a stroke, Laura McKenney was told she may never walk again. Now, she's trekking 50-kilometres to raise money for the service that saved her life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61447439023bae1f51729f2a394f2067</guid></item><item><title>Acting electoral commissioner labels WA council elections successful despite concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/acting-electoral-commissioner-discusses-wa-council-elections/105915918</link><description>The acting head of WA's Electoral Commission is lauding the recent local council poll as a success, despite reports of missing ballot papers and low voter turnout.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce6f55bcaf5403e43b53955128c85371</guid></item><item><title>Expert tips for used-car buyers to spot 'widespread' odometer tampering</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/tips-to-protect-used-car-buyers-from-widespread-odometer-fraud/105911276</link><description>Odometer fraud is "widespread" in the second-hand car industry, but experts say there are warning signs to look for when buying a used car.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c86e77f5f698004a03a397fb0794f07a</guid></item><item><title>Australian flower growers want shoppers to know where their blooms originate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/tasmanian-flower-growers-call-for-country-of-origin-labelling/105901208</link><description>About half of Australia's cut flowers are imported, but there is no requirement to add a label informing consumers of their origin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b13c4c6f8d6bbc45bb31fd9df948937</guid></item><item><title>Donald rare earth mine given major project status by Australian government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/donald-mineral-sands-mine-given-major-project-status/105917530</link><description>The federal government grants major project status to a joint Australian-US mine in regional Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">764adf75e9997cd64369c8f4b49126c1</guid></item><item><title>Inquest probes death in custody of Phillip Walton at Casino Police Station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/phillip-walton-casino-death-in-custody-coronial-inquiry/105915614</link><description>A senior police officer defends the actions of officers during the violent arrest of a man who later died in custody at Casino Police Station in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">497deedb8899b75e15642838af05b82f</guid></item><item><title>Blind baby wombat Gundy adapts to new home at wildlife sanctuary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/wildlife-carers-help-blind-baby-wombat-adapt-to-a-new-home/105903660</link><description>Gundy the wombat suffered vision loss after his mother was killed by a car while he was in her pouch. Wildlife carers are finding creative ways to give him a new chance at life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30aff38c624cd2a105c8aefca99a7d19</guid></item><item><title>Regional cultural icon Anita's Theatre celebrates 100 years of entertainment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/anita-theatre-in-wollongong-celebrates-100-years/105894492</link><description>After starting life as a movie theatre and later a roller-skating rink, it was the bold vision of a Wollongong property developer that turned the 100-year-old Anita's Theatre in Thirroul into a cultural icon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cba77c18d64e232ecd33457ee613fe8</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley backtracks on call for Kevin Rudd to be sacked as US ambassador</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/sussan-ley-walks-back-kevin-rudd-ambassador-sacked/105920516</link><description>After a Liberal colleague calls Sussan Ley's claim that Kevin Rudd cannot remain US ambassador "churlish", the opposition leader walks back from her call.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a29d28518177d0ad8987efade870b0fa</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Island's red crab migration underway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/christmas-island-red-crab-migration-underway/105920342</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b4573733fb09a3d65277a164ebdb94b</guid></item><item><title>INTERPOL issues worldwide alert for 'priceless royal jewels' stolen from the Louvre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/interpol-alert-priceless-royal-jewels-stolen-from-louvre/105920580</link><description>INTERPOL has circulated a "special edition poster" alerting police worldwide to "priceless" stolen Louvre jewels, which French authorities have valued at $157 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36e0c6977f2d06c8ffe15d9264a1078f</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after running over dog, crashing caravan with children inside</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/man-charged-allegedly-stealing-caravan-children-inside/105919982</link><description>A 59-year-old man is taken to hospital under police guard after crashing an allegedly stolen caravan. A family's dog was run over during the incident in the Gold Coast hinterland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f8532a5458eeb18dc12fa15b0a33e03</guid></item><item><title>Rock climbers' celebrations crushed as government confirms Grampians, Arapiles bans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/rock-climbing-bans-remain-arapiles-grampians-despite-speculation/105915428</link><description>The Victorian government clarifies rock climbing bans remain in place in the Grampians and other sites after a message spread online that the bans "were off".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">076cda4bef57d812542ec60186d391d5</guid></item><item><title>Red crabs make their annual march on Christmas Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/red-crabs-make-their-annual-march-on-christmas-island/105920982</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e280c0b4f77bb665c61957afb63ff865</guid></item><item><title>Man charged in Melbourne after police seize dozens of Labubu dolls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/man-arrested-alleged-stolen-labubu-dolls-in-melbourne/105920204</link><description>Police seize Labubu dolls found during a search at a property in Melbourne's west. The dolls, worth an estimated $9,000, were allegedly stolen from a CBD shopping centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6a9be9d1dcf86b3e4860408535870b5</guid></item><item><title>Red crabs make their annual march on Christmas Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/red-crabs-make-their-annual-march-on-christmas-island/105921010</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">488fcc4e29eb8888bda1fb017efd95de</guid></item><item><title>Mysterious military shipwreck appears on Target Beach in Jervis Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/shipwreck-appears-on-jervis-bay-beach/105920008</link><description>Remnants of a shipwreck in Jervis Bay have maritime archaeologists puzzled and wondering what else could be nearby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdacdbc973b4fbefde59c8b5eb42afbe</guid></item><item><title>Lidia Thorpe refers NT attorney-general to corruption watchdog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/senator-lidia-thorpe-refers-nt-attorney-general-to-icac/105917560</link><description>Senator Lidia Thorpe refers Northern Territory's attorney-general to the corruption watchdog after allegations of government interference in the NT Supreme Court's media activities that were later deemed "a misunderstanding".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d8d75816f1da3913d38e857502c284c</guid></item><item><title>Hot weather records broken across parts of Sydney and NSW, with damaging winds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/hot-weather-in-sydney-nsw-fire-bans-and-warnings-wednesday/105920786</link><description>Maximum October temperature records were broken in western parts of the city, where it hit about 40C in Penrith and Bankstown after a hot night in NSW's west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d6fb40b80db5272d50137efc04132b3</guid></item><item><title>'Climate trigger' formally ruled out of environment laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/climate-trigger-formally-ruled-out-of-environment-laws/105919546</link><description>A "climate trigger" that could be used to block coal and gas projects has been formally excluded from the government's overhaul of Australia's environment laws, minister Murray Watt confirms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c1a2a6fff2c15f94e5a6155f42263f4</guid></item><item><title>Chris Scott says Geelong's recruitment of Bailey Smith is an 'outrageous success'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/afl-chris-scott-bailey-smith-success-state-of-origin-injuries/105921548</link><description>Geelong and Victoria coach Chris Scott gets on the offensive about his star midfielder Bailey Smith while urging fans and pundits not to over-react when State of Origin returns next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97880ee57a333d67f13dad4b5fc36756</guid></item><item><title>Donald Day Jr, US conspiracy theorist connected to Wieambilla killers, formally enters plea deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/qld-donald-day-premier-reacts-to-plea-deal/105921610</link><description>Queensland Premier David Crisafulli says the crime "rocked the state", and the news would "hurt" the families of those murdered at Wieambilla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d40c4064b9808b8f8f732625637eee7</guid></item><item><title>Two dead as severe weather across Victoria downs trees, cuts power and postpones Geelong Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/severe-weather-sweeps-victoria-wreaking-havoc/105921826</link><description>Two men have died in rough waters at Frankston as part of the state recorded wind gusts up to 130 kilometres per hour during a severe weather system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fa4c5cf099aa95ead69a7a5ae2d35d6</guid></item><item><title>I moved from Brisbane to the outback at 18 to work on sheep stations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/moving-from-brisbane-to-outback-for-work-art-cooper/105897704</link><description>Art Cooper was almost a year into a panel-beating apprenticeship in Brisbane when he realised it wasn't the career for him, so he packed his belongings and drove 1,300 kilometres to the outback to work as a rouseabout on sheep stations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c8030fef45a6e51f108e10eb0fb223f</guid></item><item><title>South Australian MP Nick McBride charged with further counts of assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/nick-mcbride-further-charges-assault-south-australia/105919754</link><description>Member for MacKillop Nick McBride is facing another three counts of assault dating back to January and September of 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b7d41eef605976bf06febf0e7d78d03</guid></item><item><title>Investigation into Townsville Hospital urology care finds more impacted patients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/urology-healthcare-investigation-townsville/105920928</link><description>Tim Nicholls says an investigation, launched in September, identified that 11 patients were adversely affected, but that number had since more than doubled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b36eab5bf095a5b19b4c9f980b2bea45</guid></item><item><title>Our homes are full of hidden microplastics that could be harming our health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/hidden-microplastics-at-home-and-impact-on-health/105917972</link><description>Microplastics are everywhere, including our bodies and brains, and the exposure risk may be highest within our own homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18690c64251c79c309a9913425622790</guid></item><item><title>Canberra boy's parents detail impact of former childcare worker Muhammad Ali's sexual abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/canberra-childcare-worker-to-be-sentenced-for-child-sexual-abuse/105920350</link><description>Former childcare worker Muhammad Ali, 31, will be sentenced for the 2022 abuse of the boy on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5412d425d889c27b72cffc65c295e44f</guid></item><item><title>Woman injured in army truck collision north-west of Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/emergency-services-respond-army-truck-crash-in-brisbane/105922574</link><description>Emergency services respond to a truck rollover after a crash north-west of Brisbane on Wednesday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dab780379df65ed8a69b41864aeff1ef</guid></item><item><title>Tonga rugby league team meets with king ahead of Test match against Samoa in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/tonga-rugby-league-team-meet-with-king-ahead-of-test-match/105922598</link><description>Lunch with the king of Tonga and quality time spent with his subjects have Jason Taumalolo primed to deliver a blockbusting display against Samoa.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21063f91b8d11d8f74f0efc9bbbab8a1</guid></item><item><title>OpenAI launches Atlas web browser to compete with Google's Chrome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/openai-launches-atlas-web-browser-to-compete-with-google/105922212</link><description>The owner of ChatGPT, OpenAI, launches its own web browser, Atlas, as more people rely on artificial intelligence to answer questions on the internet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">035912db61d38708493abbbf17238c35</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police officer charged with 'more serious' offence over Hannah Thomas arrest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/nsw-police-officer-new-charge-hannah-thomas-sydney-protest/105922410</link><description>The police officer charged with allegedly assaulting former Greens candidate Hannah Thomas is now facing an additional, more serious, offence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14ea47661fb1bfe2edfbc5f4b0f27197</guid></item><item><title>Op shop purchase of The Hobbit could be worth tens of thousands if verified as first edition Tolkien</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/tasmanian-woman-op-shop-selling-jrr-tolkien-the-hobbit/105921072</link><description>A woman who bought a copy of The Hobbit from an op shop in the 1990s says even then she suspected it could be worth a considerable amount — experts now say she could be sitting on a first edition copy, worth tens of thousands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2919bb95ee3eac24182e5b967591143</guid></item><item><title>Man flown to hospital, five others injured in road crash in Oakford, in Perth's south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/children-injured-in-oakford-crash-in-perth-south/105922760</link><description>Six people are taken to hospital, including a baby and a critically injured man, after three cars collide in the southern Perth suburb of Oakford.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa9499acc29d5b871543326da649d9c1</guid></item><item><title>Australian official to join Trump-led Gaza peace taskforce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/australian-official-to-join-trump-gaza-peace-taskforce/105922746</link><description>The official will participate in planning and coordination efforts related to humanitarian and security challenges in implementing the ceasefire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bf7e27f33fc38ba0ad4ea10301b45a7</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105921882</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e6279cd8f29139973fe425cd355b58b</guid></item><item><title>Mate Stipinovich, Aristides Avlontis, Karl Whitburn jailed for bungled Albany drug smuggling attempt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/drug-smugglers-who-clung-to-esky-off-albany-sentenced/105920248</link><description>Three men forced to cling to an esky to survive in wild seas off Albany as they tried to import hundreds of kilograms of cocaine into Western Australia are described by a judge as "Keystone criminals" at their sentencing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3a907b92905039815d6a864be91a54d</guid></item><item><title>How worried should we be about microplastics in our homes?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/how-worried-should-we-be-about-microplastics-in-our-homes/105923098</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44869c3e630bb673ba45455441770045</guid></item><item><title>What the critical minerals deal means for Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/what-the-critical-minerals-deal-means-for-australia/105923100</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d668b79151e7614c59596991073b90bd</guid></item><item><title>Dominic Raab says Australia's critical minerals deal with US 'a great step forward'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/dominic-raab-on-australia-s-critical-minerals-deal-with-the-us/105923102</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac56bf4011e907307c8e1b4a94ddbaea</guid></item><item><title>Inquest into deaths of Stanley Obi and Sarah Mudge hears of events during hours before fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/qld-stanley-obi-sarah-mudge-coronial-inquest-logan/105922700</link><description>The mother of a woman who allegedly broke into her former partner’s home and set it alight, before dying in the fire herself, gives evidence at a coronial inquest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c59e1ec53c121be68ac61ea36b5eee8d</guid></item><item><title>Australia continues dominance against England as Sutherland and Gardner put on monster stand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/live-australia-vs-england-women-s-cricket-world-cup-scores-stats/105922176</link><description>Australia is rescued by an incredible stand between Ash Gardner and Annabel Sutherland at the Women's World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">477d5c29ed6fe1e24fd3e3e1d66f84e9</guid></item><item><title>Supreme Court in Brisbane reserves decision on Queensland's puberty blocker freeze after legal challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/queensland-court-reserves-decision-on-puberty-blocker-ban/105923126</link><description>The mother of a trans teenager launched legal action over the state's freeze on puberty blockers earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b89c70a0198a1a471131e89eeb91c10</guid></item><item><title>Delegates discussed 'getting rid' of land council boss during men's meeting, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/jacinta-nampijinpa-price-defamation-case-land-council-meeting/105919748</link><description>A defamation trial over a press release issued by Northern Territory senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price has been derailed by an "unusual and significant" application to have a man barred from the court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af47f07fb7cd4f7ceb6c102d71240f4a</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds dominate Silver Ferns to take 2-0 lead in Constellation Cup series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/diamonds-vs-silver-ferns-second-test-constellation-cup/105922576</link><description>Australia is one win away from regaining the Constellation Cup after dominating New Zealand in the second netball Test match in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be7d38a2f2feab1621ca6ea454baa5cd</guid></item><item><title>AC Milan Serie A game will be played in Perth despite backlash, deputy premier says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/ac-milan-serie-a-perth-game-update/105922940</link><description>The state government is doubling down on its plan to bring European football heavyweights AC Milan to Perth to play a historic Italian league game, despite significant backlash from fans and players.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4af059711217c189b72dab3189cc3a7b</guid></item><item><title>Serbian president labels shooting and fire outside parliament building a 'terrorist act'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-22/serbian-shots-fired-and-fire-ignited-outside-belgrade-parliament/105923266</link><description>One person has been detained and at least one person injured after a shooting and a fire broke out outside of Serbia's parliament in Belgrade, in an incident that President Aleksandar Vučić has called a terrorist act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e409138657ffa02353bf062ea77546c</guid></item><item><title>Trump seems relaxed about Taiwan and analysts are concerned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/donald-trump-anthony-albanese-china-taiwan/105919780</link><description>There was something Donald Trump said that alarmed strategic analysts. And it had nothing to do with disliking Kevin Rudd.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b09727993adc1f99b586851208f3b20d</guid></item><item><title>Luna Park machete brawl accused free on bail after alleged St Kilda attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/vic-st-kilda-luna-park-machete-brawl-accused-free-on-bail/105920760</link><description>Three men charged over a machete brawl outside Melbourne's Luna Park have been freed on bail, despite police urging magistrates to keep the trio locked up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">597d4cc833e7c6a2a0ff34753fc30d43</guid></item><item><title>The move to break China's iron grip on world's supply of critical minerals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/australia-us-join-china-in-race-to-bottom-on-rare-earth-prices/105921278</link><description>America dominates the global financial system. The Middle East controls energy. And China, during the past 40 years, has created a vice-like grip on the mining, refining and production of global metals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d4352ba09b87fc1dd1206a1a824d91a</guid></item><item><title>As Europe proposes a ban on all PFAS, some researchers say Australia should do the same</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/calls-to-ban-entire-pfas-class-in-australia/105787430</link><description>As the European Union proposes a ban on the entire PFAS chemical class, some researchers say Australia should do the same.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e04ed432a807d5c6fca30c5667ca447</guid></item><item><title>Where Matildas coach Joe Montemurro wants to take the team and women's football</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/matildas-coach-joe-montemurro-vision-australian-womens-football/105912590</link><description>Matildas coach Joe Montemurro has no shortage of ideas or passion for how to reshape women's football in Australia, and it's a contrast from his predecessor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd1cec1f5763be070ccdf86a5517ae73</guid></item><item><title>Keeping Tasmania's radar network operating a labour of love for BOM's Brendan Hanigan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/tasmania-bom-weather-radar-network-brendan-hanigan/105912464</link><description>Songs about radars strike a chord — personally and professionally — with Brendan Hanigan. He is tasked with leading the team that keeps Tasmania's weather radars in good working order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc082d84e0df7fa8df3fce80488937ec</guid></item><item><title>Seafood has undeserved reputation as source of microplastic exposure, scientists say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/seafood-unfair-microplastics-reputation-puts-off-consumers/105912838</link><description>There are microplastics in almost everything, so why does seafood get such a bad reputation? Scientists say it is down to disproportionate research and media attention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8567870a03b1df65e2a20ba21bc314a2</guid></item><item><title>'Localised extinction' risk for seagrass in Botany Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/localised-extinction-risk-for-seagrass-in-gamay-botany-bay/105903236</link><description>It is estimated half of the local seagrass habitat in Gamay (Botany Bay) has already been lost. Researchers and Aboriginal rangers are replanting seagrass fragments and using biochar to restore the area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecdd76f0fa0000dab7a916d234e1a86e</guid></item><item><title>Amid a small investor rush on precious metals, have the gold and silver bubbles popped?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/gold-price-silver-price-fall-after-record-runs/105919932</link><description>Precious metal prices have been pushing record highs and, as queues lengthened outside bullion traders, gold and silver prices suddenly fell back. But positive signs remain, analysts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85df381e3c773d3666ff2d41e431258c</guid></item><item><title>Why mpox cases in Australia in 2025 are a fraction of what they were last year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/nsw-mpox-cases-australia-2025-scientists/105842962</link><description>Mpox transmission surged between July to September last year, but there have been far fewer cases recorded in 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88dbfb4e2d3e282dfa8c1c7b16bf4dc2</guid></item><item><title>After 37 years, mystery still surrounds the death of Mark Haines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/mark-haines-death-still-surrounded-by-mystery/105902802</link><description>Some key questions about the death of Indigenous teenager Mark Haines are still unanswered after a coronial inquest spanning five weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">baad175ed7981a98ee6ddb26820019e5</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri confident in F1 championship battle against Lando Norris and Max Verstappen in Mexico</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/oscar-piastri-f1-championship-max-verstappen-lando-norris-mexico/105917790</link><description>This year may be the first time in F1 that Oscar Piastri has been under the cosh of a title fight, but it is not the first time he has been in a three-way fight for a championship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ebaf21cbbf4bb580ca4d8a0c8c713f3</guid></item><item><title>Russia jails teen musicians for viral anti-Kremlin song performance amid censorship crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/russia-jails-musicians-banned-anti-kremlin-song-viral/105919236</link><description>An ongoing censorship crackdown in Russia sees a teenage band jailed after a performance of an anti-Kremlin song went viral, but the protest keeps growing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78c1b9719c8d25ebaf254bbe05a71cd1</guid></item><item><title>Brazen crime and protest clashes have made Melbourne's CBD less safe, traders say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/brazen-crime-heated-protests-make-city-unsafe-traders-say/105913296</link><description>Business owners say recent incidents — including a random daylight stabbing and clashes between protesters and police — are deterring customers from the heart of the Victorian capital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdea6b2a0483f121ef68654757cb9b9e</guid></item><item><title>How a climate adaptation 'shortfall' is being felt in northern Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/northern-australia-struggles-to-adapt-to-climate-change/105841310</link><description>Shaded and green spaces can be hard to find in northern towns and cities where summer temperatures regularly surpass 40 degrees Celsius.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7d3002a3bc79b18ecd9a182e49c7a99</guid></item><item><title>Designer Amy Lawrance's new collection Total Recall is a mix of medieval and sci-fi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/amy-lawrance-fashion-designer-total-recall/105905406</link><description>Award-winning fashion designer Amy Lawrance blends 90s sci-fi with the medieval in her new collection, Total Recall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea78787d197aa80e9e98691d3fe5a513</guid></item><item><title>Masses of NT prison rehabilitation sessions cancelled as prisoner numbers surge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/majority-of-nt-prison-rehab-programs-cancelled-overcrowding/105916564</link><description>As the Northern Territory prison population continues to reach all-time highs, data reveals a majority of the NT's rehab program are being cancelled more often than they are being delivered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70fee00a47f2a73f47e0da6b21b749c7</guid></item><item><title>Claims foster care payments have been cut spark concern for kids with complex needs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/foster-care-payments-claims-of-cuts/105915512</link><description>Foster carers in Victoria say sudden allowance reductions for children with complex needs have left them feeling "undervalued and confused".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">290f7f0f209c4f37ad30fb2ca338f5ad</guid></item><item><title>South Energy plans 100-megawatt battery project for Victoria's Macedon Ranges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/macedon-battery-site-proposal-south-energy-in-fire-zone/105920150</link><description>A proposed energy storage facility in Macedon could power thousands of homes — but not everyone is convinced it is being built in the right place.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57367107a833ee15f4bd22b1939535df</guid></item><item><title>'Daughter's promise' inspires Darkinyung dictionary to revive sleepy language</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/daughters-promise-inspires-darkinyung-dictionary-revive-language/105536842</link><description>With the help of a linguist and her community, Aunty Bronwyn Chambers has revitalised a sleepy language.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a24bd8d4af7b8738937f7d3ae67a569</guid></item><item><title>Parts of NSW and Victoria 'absolutely battered' by howling winds, storm damage in Greater Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/damaging-winds-damage-sydney-and-nsw-amid-wild-weather/105923502</link><description>Howling winds overnight will lead to extensive clean-up work today in NSW's south-east and parts of Victoria, with October heat records also broken in Western Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">736a6689acf417333720c384ceaa765a</guid></item><item><title>Mount Stirling Resort financial deficit prompts review of winter operations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/mount-stirling-winter-operations-under-review-financial-deficit/105921394</link><description>The managing body of Victoria's six alpine resorts says it is reviewing winter operations at its Mount Stirling resort, which has been "operating at a financial deficit" for some time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">defbb82f65c793e59b689c95ccbcb355</guid></item><item><title>KAPCO deal with NT abattoir to supply communities with affordable Kimberley beef</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/kapco-branded-beef-for-sale-in-kimberley-communities/105890452</link><description>A cattle company in Western Australia's Kimberley has struck a deal with a Northern Territory abattoir to get local beef to consumers in remote communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25fe008938e380014edc09ae37eac45c</guid></item><item><title>Waroona weighs up planned gallium refinery funded by US-Australia critical minerals deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/waroona-weighs-up-gallium-refinery-from-critical-minerals-deal/105923056</link><description>Locals in the WA community of Waroona are welcoming a US-Australia deal set to build a new rare earth refinery south of Perth, but others warn the project will further entrench mining interests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a68b7d21b8bbd286c5a1420e728a78b4</guid></item><item><title>Australia's first fluorite mine faces 'deep opposition' from Kimberley traditional owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/tivan-speewah-fluorite-project-opposited-by-traditional-owners/105920700</link><description>Traditional owners have raised cultural and environmental concerns about a proposed fluorite mine in Western Australia's remote Kimberley region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efdb89f0ff517cf2828ffb7c1c2afd25</guid></item><item><title>Forced adoption redress scheme to offer compensation for impacted Tasmanians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/tasmania-forced-adoptions-redress-scheme/105923474</link><description>More than 13 years after the Tasmanian state government delivered an apology to mothers impacted by the historical practice of forced adoptions, a redress scheme will offer compensation to those affected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9e233d73a03968984e5e44b24557626</guid></item><item><title>Louvre chief blames CCTV gaps for $150m jewellery heist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/louvre-director-acknowledges-failure-after-jewellery-heist/105923584</link><description>The Louvre chief says she repeatedly raised concerns about CCTV coverage at the museum, only for her fears to come "horribly true".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99315f3e0a3e5504191af2333fe36547</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's hobby gold-diggers under threat from law giving veto power to miners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/law-change-locks-queensland-gold-fossickers-out-of-state-land/105917922</link><description>Gold prospectors are being locked out of some fossicking areas by a new law that allows mining companies with pending leases to say no.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85a7b5aaba311b4d1d00b68e1673a4ee</guid></item><item><title>More Australian-grown coffee to become available as industry grows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/australian-coffee-industry-grows-as-new-varieties-available/105921496</link><description>The Australian coffee industry is growing as new varieties become available and local demand increases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6c87086f9f3d9ec9979146c33619d97</guid></item><item><title>Frankston drowning victims were inexperienced surfer and friend who tried to rescue him, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/frankston-drowning-victims-yet-to-be-identifed/105923626</link><description>Police say two men who drowned on Wednesday were a British national who was surfing in extreme conditions and his friend who came to his aid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec3497c2ab41d5c6cb203ecb66c9ece6</guid></item><item><title>Criticism over rodenticide review delays as study finds poison in northern quolls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/apvma-delays-rodenticide-review-despite-quoll-concern/105891008</link><description>Rat bait poison has been found in threatened northern quoll populations as an overdue report into their use by the federal pesticides regulator is again delayed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49bba0b00d15e090d19a9695528b4cb4</guid></item><item><title>Mapping rare earth supplies and the challenges of turning these minerals into magnets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/rare-earths-reserves-global-critical-minerals-australia-china-us/105913262</link><description>Unlike the name suggests, rare earths are not very rare at all. The critical minerals are found in abundance in many countries, but being big on reserves may not mean big business.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ddfebc841ee6318f2335037eafb611f</guid></item><item><title>Australia wins double bronze at UCI Track World Championships, team pursuit men to race for gold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/australia-sprint-teams-win-bronze-uci-track-world-championships/105924084</link><description>Australia's two team pursuit squads both claimed bronze medals on day one of the UCI Track World Championships in Santiago, while the Olympic champion team pursuit squad will race for gold on day two.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f6ca636ffd63dedbb1d1698a6d45066</guid></item><item><title>US hits Russia's biggest oil firms with sanctions over Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/us-announces-sanctions-against-russias-two-biggest-oil-firms/105923888</link><description>The White House makes a sharp move to pressure Moscow to secure peace in Ukraine just one day after a summit between US President Donald Trump and Russian President Vladimir Putin falls apart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5148d7b66a9ed5008e197f1624fa3d7</guid></item><item><title>Funky animal hairdos and a smoking duck among 2025 Comedy Wildlife Photo Awards finalists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/comedy-wildlife-photo-awards-2025-finalists/105924038</link><description>The 40 shortlisted images pair talented nature photography with humour that often relies on capturing a moment at just the right time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cf991d1c5656f5992afd5e37bae6bf3</guid></item><item><title>State of Origin battleground experience a bonus for Kangaroos against England in Ashes trilogy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/state-of-origin-a-bonus-for-kangaroos-against-england/105924964</link><description>The Ashes clash with England is a three-Test contest and Origin rivals Nathan Cleary and Harry Grant believe experience in the state head-to-head could be telling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a024e0af020d527eca0fb362a4822126</guid></item><item><title>Two teenage boys stabbed, one with a screwdriver, during alleged daylight brawl in Broadmeadows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/broadmeadows-station-brawl-screwdriver-machete-stabbings/105925064</link><description>Two teenage boys were hospitalised with stab wounds after an alleged brawl between two groups armed with a screwdriver and possibly a machete at a train station in Broadmeadows on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b3aae3e8bb739a159250f2870888544</guid></item><item><title>Queensland coach Johan Botha baffles Cricketers' Association with stance on injured players being paid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/cricket-johan-botha-injured-players-payment-aca-response/105925350</link><description>Australian Cricketers' Association boss Paul Marsh will seek clarification from Queensland coach Johan Botha over his comments regarding player payments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b24fae5c54211515b378c57e9505f03</guid></item><item><title>Cheryl Grimmer confession read in NSW Parliament under privilege</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/cheryl-grimmer-confession-read-in-nsw-parliament/105923732</link><description>A NSW MP invokes parliamentary privilege to name the man who confessed as a teenager to killing three-year-old Cheryl Grimmer, and reads aloud a long-suppressed confession.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4b215bc52fbac35c6b9f6914216c032</guid></item><item><title>Jack Bowd pleads not guilty to Newell Highway crash that killed four people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/newell-highway-fatal-crash-driver-jack-bowd-pleads-not-guilty/105842498</link><description>A 23-year-old pleads not guilty to dangerous driving and drink driving charges after a crash that claimed the lives of two friends and a husband and wife last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4df2a7a2674f7ead4af00da2819e1709</guid></item><item><title>Coles to appear at Kumanjayi White coronial inquest after Alice Springs death in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/nt-kumanjayi-white-coronial-update-family-speaks-outside-court/105923958</link><description>Supermarket giant Coles is among the parties expected to take part in a coronial inquest into the death in custody of a young Aboriginal man inside its Alice Springs shop earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57cae39432a2f9acece58217a2dd16a8</guid></item><item><title>Australia's institutions are what make us freaking amazing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/justin-wolfers-boyer-lecture-australia-democracy/105922196</link><description>The world changes, yet Australia keeps being great. Our institutions permit us to be nimble, and we adapt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dffb7d7a76e996bb90c250cc8fedf101</guid></item><item><title>Australia beats India in second ODI in Adelaide to clinch three-game series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/australia-india-second-odi-adelaide-oval-live-scorecentre/105925988</link><description>Australia completes a two-wicket win over India, clinching the three-game ODI series as Cooper Connolly and Mitch Owen combine to lead Australia's run chase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09d9e7a380edc4e84fbbde426a78ef4e</guid></item><item><title>Backlash over Bureau of Meteorology's 'confusing' new website</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/bureau-of-meteorology-bom-new-website-changes-outrage/105924016</link><description>As wild weather wreaked havoc across the country, the Bureau of Meteorology launched a new website.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcd7a595a8a85c57ad7276d0adf530fc</guid></item><item><title>Stop-work action to affect Tasmanian public schools and health services next week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/stop-work-action-tasmanian-shools-health-services/105925826</link><description>Unions are unhappy with the state government's latest public sector pay offer and are planning stop-work actions next week. Schools and health services for non-urgent patients could be affected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fb024e94793b276871b16cb272ba02e</guid></item><item><title>What a film reviewer who is also a twin thinks of Twinless</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/what-a-film-reviewer-who-is-also-a-twin-thinks-of-twinless/105924720</link><description>Montearo Brown is a TV and film reviewer who blogs under the name Sprite Lee. He also happens to be a twin. So, what does he think of the movie Twinless?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c65c6c04a99379cf1c85bdc15c57082b</guid></item><item><title>Group of juveniles accused of chasing Kununurra police in stolen cars, with video posted online</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/video-police-car-stolen-vehicles-kununurra/105924600</link><description>A video of an erratically driven vehicle chasing a police car in Kununurra has been posted on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ecb115a52256b8be486ebe6cfa6b7ec</guid></item><item><title>Police pursuit Kununurra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/police-pursuit-kununurra/105925774</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea060374cc97fea062773dbce5422978</guid></item><item><title>North Queensland health authorities issue warning over flying foxes after more exposures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/flying-fox-health-concern/105915766</link><description>An increase in people being injured by bats sparks a health warning over the deadly Australian bat lyssavirus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96a3d651d9acbfdda2b14ae456ad0dea</guid></item><item><title>Coalition sours over proposed reform to 'broken' environment laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/coalition-sours-over-proposed-environment-laws-epbc/105923700</link><description>Optimism that a deal can be found to amend Australia's environment laws fades, as the Coalition raises concerns over details just days after parts of the legislation were shared with stakeholders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f9b159125f963e87d883b00d5340b6b</guid></item><item><title>Artificial nests trial underway to save Queensland's endangered palm cockatoo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/artificial-nest-trial-for-cape-york-palm-cockatoo/105925758</link><description>Few birds have nesting requirements as finicky as Australia's largest parrot, the palm cockatoo, which is facing its own housing crisis due to a shortage of breeding habitat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38b5c14841513d18a26729b5408f5edd</guid></item><item><title>Central Land Council boss testifies against senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price in Federal Court defamation trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/nt-senator-jacinta-nampijinpa-price-sued-over-defamation-claims/105923738</link><description>Central Land Council chief executive Lesley Turner — who is suing Jacinta Nampijinpa Price for defamation — testifies in Federal Court, and denies being "embarrassed" by the senator pointing out alleged "failures" of the council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">847c001aa784b1748eea85fc42770bc4</guid></item><item><title>Why have protesters clashed with police in Dublin?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/dublin-protests-asylum-hotel-violence/105923890</link><description>The head of the Irish police service condemns what he has called "thuggery" by "a mob intent on violence".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">101a139b9e9a08d7dc6cde10a7f8f14f</guid></item><item><title>Hanson rubbishes Joyce leadership speculation, Albanese gets two thumbs up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/barnaby-joyce-pauline-hanson-anthony-albanese-donald-trump/105920314</link><description>This week in politics Barnaby Joyce became a "free agent" and the PM's meeting with Donald Trump got two thumbs up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5df28780e3e41d8abdf5ffa75fe6fe1b</guid></item><item><title>Ways to reduce pollen and dust at home this allergy and hayfever season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/ways-to-reduce-dust-pollen-in-your-home-allergy-hayfever-season/105887900</link><description>Hayfever symptoms can be debilitating. Experts give their tips and tricks on helping reduce allergens in the home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a6f1e49281635efb970909e28a519f0</guid></item><item><title>Promised police beat to tackle Burleigh 'thugs' but acting mayor questions limited hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/police-beat-promised-to-tackle-burleigh-thugs/105924090</link><description>The state government says a promised police beat in Burleigh Heads will be operating by the end of the year, but the acting mayor has questioned why it won't be open at night or on weekends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ff0ea97a3295f24236cbfae6630b7d3</guid></item><item><title>The US military released a video of a strike on an alleged drug vessel in the Pacific.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/us-military-releases-video-of-strike-on-drug-vessel-in-pacific/105926086</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94ac7d5da1ec04c21d2f304cd778adfb</guid></item><item><title>Trump administration conducts military strikes on suspected drug-courier boats in the Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/trump-conducts-military-strikes-on-drug-boats-in-pacific/105925884</link><description>The Trump administration has expanded its target area in its 'narco-trafficking' offensive, conducting two military strikes in the Pacific and bringing the death toll from its attacks to at least 37.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a46a9a6b02e2bf8cfd638137aff833b5</guid></item><item><title>Former Canberra childcare worker Muhammad Ali sentenced for sexually abusing boy in his care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/act-former-childcare-worker-muhammad-ali-jail-sexual-abuse-boy/105925990</link><description>Muhammad Ali, 31, who is already behind bars for a similar incident, has been sentenced to two years in jail for indecently touching a boy in his care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6e9646d46c7bc52e6d3db6116b2354a</guid></item><item><title>Two senior Optus executives depart as scrutiny over recent major triple-0 outage continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/two-senior-optus-executives-depart-as-scrutiny-continues/105927132</link><description>Optus confirms two of its senior executives will step down as it continues to face scrutiny over a recent major triple-0 outage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30218f8ef2001ee3fc1eac7f976e7275</guid></item><item><title>Spotted-tail quoll discovered at Coffs Harbour marina amid rewilding effort</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/vulnerable-spotted-tail-quoll-spotted-at-coffs-harbour-marina/105923582</link><description>An unusual sighting of a spotted-tailed quoll at a boat marina has surprised residents and prompted parks and wildlife experts to monitor the usually forest-dwelling creature.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edd21e50d75559e5fae100d7ea055ae3</guid></item><item><title>Sport has a role to play in addressing harmful gender stereotypes, says Carlton defender</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/harriet-cordner-on-carlton-respects-and-violence-against-women/105923910</link><description>Carlton defender Harriet Cordner says sport has a key role to play in challenging gendered stereotypes in society, particularly given its reach within communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d204662d618f48e535520e14f7eff3a</guid></item><item><title>Private email chain released by NT government amid political interference claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/emails-revealed-between-nt-top-judge-and-department/105926238</link><description>The NT attorney-general's department has taken the extraordinary step of releasing private emails between a top judge and bureaucrats, to try and address allegations of interference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f5a59e1c60fbb6b40ad7cbb13ba40c8</guid></item><item><title>Inquest finds fisherman died after being dragged overboard by shark near Newcastle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/fisherman-paul-barning-dragged-overboard-by-hark-inquest-finds/105926506</link><description>An inquest finds a Sydney fisherman likely drowned after being pulled overboard by a large Mako shark during a game fishing competition near Newcastle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0e1dc02dd8b8f2550ca37546a157088</guid></item><item><title>Temporary commercial and recreational fishing restrictions announced amid ongoing algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/fishing-restrictions-announced-amid-ongoing-algal-bloom/105926488</link><description>The SA government is placing temporary restrictions on fishing in the Gulf St Vincent and Spencer Gulf as results from fish stock monitoring show declining numbers of some species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf20fc4355e416dc49bd319eea97e9b3</guid></item><item><title>Torranzino wins Geelong Cup, giving trainer Paul Preusker a Melbourne Cup runner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/torranzino-wins-geelong-cup-earns-melbourne-cup-place/105926372</link><description>The Geelong Cup is run and won, with King Charles III's horse Gilded Water beaten at the finish to miss out on a spot in this year's Melbourne Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70cd139492e3ba83f7c344dbf62fc6f9</guid></item><item><title>High speed camera captures how venomous snakes bite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/snake-bite-camera-colubridae/105926354</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c64d98557d75c7464c1bd86149b88f11</guid></item><item><title>High speed camera captures how venomous snakes bite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/snake-bite-camera-3/105926212</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">608eec0bd7426e48ade3e4539f05f467</guid></item><item><title>High speed camera captures how venomous snakes bite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/viper-strike-high-speed-camera/105913278</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5221b3a3cef0e11c8f94fbe4d678b328</guid></item><item><title>High speed camera captures how venomous snakes bite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/elapid-snake-high-speed-camera/105913286</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8985fd9490ff9803e28a1a862fe8cf44</guid></item><item><title>Business Correspondent David Taylor explains Optus' management structure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/david-taylor-optus-executives-step-down/105927562</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33499d08788ad403adfa817e071004f6</guid></item><item><title>Homicide investigation underway after Queensland police find man dead on southern Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/homicide-investigation-coolangatta/105927508</link><description>Queensland police say it is believed the two men are known to each other and there is no threat to the community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4089e76e5071e7971f473ec4009540ae</guid></item><item><title>Coronial investigation into Solomone Taufe'ulungaki's death lays bare tragic reality of Victorian knife crime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/victoria-coronial-findings-solomone-taufeulungaki-youth-crime/105926518</link><description>The data is included in the findings into the death of 15-year-old Solomone Taufe'ulungaki, who died after being chased by a gang who thought he was a member of a rival group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">376c7fb0b2ec8217b6f0d17f00a7570d</guid></item><item><title>Phillip Mark Walton's family tell inquest of their heartbreak about his death in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/walton-inquest-day-4/105926812</link><description>The family of a man who died in police custody in northern New South Wales say they thought he had overcome his problems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07288cf36f87b9d44e29cc8e9b3fa714</guid></item><item><title>South West paramedic sentenced for stealing fentanyl, replacing vials with saline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/south-west-paramedic-sentenced-fentanyl-theft/105925616</link><description>A paramedic has been sentenced for stealing vials of an opioid used for pain relief, refilling them with saline and returning them into circulation in WA ambulances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">752259b2c0432ecb8ea7593a03ef065a</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man found guilty of raping 16-year-old girl as co-accused has charge dismissed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/act-man-guilty-raping-teen-girl-co-accused-charge-dismissed/105927648</link><description>Canberra man Josh Fenwick, 29, is found guilty of raping a 16-year-old girl he took home from Civic with her friend after a night out drinking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d543cfc18bd528119d1f3140073f669</guid></item><item><title>Australian runner Phil Gore wins Backyard Ultra World Championship after five gruelling days of running</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/phil-gore-wins-backyard-ultra-world-championship/105757780</link><description>Ultra-athlete Phil Gore is Australia's newest world champion after five days of near-continuous running in Bell Buckle, Tennessee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bb9eef60c49ccbdafd3c5d3001f3054</guid></item><item><title>King Charles becomes first British monarch to pray with pope in five centuries in service at Sistine Chapel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/king-charles-pope-leo-historic-religious-service/105925462</link><description>King Charles and Pope Leo have become the first British monarch and pontiff to pray together at a church service in at least five centuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2d5ca5615ce41207adde952909ef55a</guid></item><item><title>Former British soldier found not guilty of 1972 Bloody Sunday murder charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/bloody-sunday-1972-massacre-british-soldier-found-not-guilty/105928006</link><description>The only British soldier ever charged in the 1972 Bloody Sunday massacre is found not guilty of all counts of murder and attempted murder, in a ruling handed down in a Northern Ireland court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">020db12c1a608425a856c20804b9c59b</guid></item><item><title>Chinese Communist Party body replaces 11 members amid corruption purge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-23/chinese-communist-party-replaces-11-members-at-key-congress/105927988</link><description>The personnel turnover is the highest since 2017 and shows Xi's determination to crack down on corruption, say analysts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0713d89fed50edcc77631eac414c2bd1</guid></item><item><title>Armed with Snapchat and a photo, detectives set about identifying a sexual predator</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/how-snapchat-led-detectives-to-a-sexual-predator/105927598</link><description>Police did not know his name but they did have his Snapchat handle. From there, detectives pieced together a case that would reveal the true identity of sex offender 'Alec'.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a33d16db0483801e5a843b88913d592</guid></item><item><title>King Charles and Pope Leo pray together in Vatican's Sistine Chapel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/king-charles-and-pope-leo-pray-together-in-vatican/105928592</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f52e2c0fc8575ca2fcce17d8ec63854f</guid></item><item><title>Vodafone customer unable to ring triple-0 with Samsung phone says telco failed to help her fix problem</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/vodafone-customer-service-samsung-triple-0/105922288</link><description>A Vodafone customer who was repeatedly unable to ring triple-0 says the major telco failed to help her fix the problem for months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb45f4a15310e3076db7e65e77dc8aa5</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne crime prevention program provides mentoring for multicultural youth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/youth-crime-melbourne-centre-for-multicultural-youth-mentoring/105922620</link><description>Lueth Akue turned to crime during a childhood plagued by hardship. He is using his experience to help young offenders turn their lives around in Australia's "crime capital".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9b9568cadf6cfa0b86a159d9d6ca3f8</guid></item><item><title>Coalition's climate strategy could learn from the proverb about a dog returning to its vomit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/liberals-coalition-proverb-dog-vomit-climate-policy/105919794</link><description>The Liberals have faced an existential crisis over climate and energy twice in recent memory. The damage must live in the memory of today's parliamentarians, who face the prospect of another episode.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b4261ed35e4f4a9c014387726b12a75</guid></item><item><title>The Dish still helping unravel secrets of the cosmos 25 years after film's release</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/dish-movie-25th-anniversary-australia-role-in-moon-landing/105915320</link><description>The film The Dish helped reintroduce a new generation of Australians to the critical role the Parkes Observatory played in the Moon landing. Twenty-five years after its release, the film has had a lasting impact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d3e939b63051b8f008dee345b8474d8</guid></item><item><title>How to tell if a book is valuable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/what-makes-some-books-so-valuable/105924004</link><description>There are many factors that can determine the monetary value of a book, so what can make an edition worth tens of thousands of dollars?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">180abc4ea316320cff098bcae2fc6f5c</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's trade moves with China put South-East Asian countries in the crossfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/us-china-trade-shift-hits-south-east-asian-nations/105924246</link><description>As US President Donald Trump visits South-East Asia amid global trade tensions, Indonesian exporters worry the region could bear the brunt of his protectionist policies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ff0cb1575f3309d3297bacec596d92a</guid></item><item><title>Women push for flexible construction jobs amid building delays in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/nsw-women-builders-flexible-construction-jobs-delays/105921604</link><description>Experts say unlocking flexible hours, gender diversity and migrant workers could help Australia meet its housing targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebafd488245f8c16ee8d73adf614cb0c</guid></item><item><title>Australia is all in on AUKUS. In Donald Trump's America, it's more complicated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/us-aukus-commitment-welcomed-but-questions-remain/105928396</link><description>In Washington on Monday, Anthony Albanese made something clear once again: Australia is all-in on the trilateral defence pact. Clarifying what US powerbrokers think remains a multi-billion-dollar question.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2097e546d99243d4faca7eb0a1113d6</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners handed 900,000ha of Cape York land after 255 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/cape-york-land-returned-to-traditional-owners-native-title/105926650</link><description>A native title claim in the region where Captain James Cook made landfall after his ship crashed into the Great Barrier Reef in 1770 is among one of three to finally be settled by the Federal Court this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">628998917e10c5d82b1709ecf427d004</guid></item><item><title>Three men charged with murder of Bankstown woman Thi Kim Tran</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/three-men-charged-with-bankstown-murder-of-thi-kim-tran/105928608</link><description>Three men have been charged with murder after a Sydney woman was kidnapped and killed over her husband's drug debt earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a975243015b6297bb0cc8036144a60a</guid></item><item><title>Parliamentary privilege used to name Cheryl Grimmer murder confessor, but legal limits remain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/nsw-parliament-privilege-cheryl-grimmer/105927602</link><description>NSW MP Jeremy Buckingham used parliamentary privilege to read a 1971 confession in the Cheryl Grimmer case, bypassing decades of legal silence. Outside parliament, the man's identity remains legally suppressed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36733a4ca15a0296a5011bc639441aec</guid></item><item><title>NSW program helps mothers restore dignity, rebuild lives outside of prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/nsw-women-prison-program-from-now-wagec-mothers-homelessness/105787934</link><description>The program from the Women's and Girls' Emergency Centre helps pregnant women in, or at risk of incarceration find safe accommodation and keep families together.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">130f9d1b4ce2f26b7907dd3236ade820</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government announces pilot program to subsidise apprenticeships, but industry warns more needed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/queensland-apprentices-funding-but-industry-warns-more-needed/105927430</link><description>The Queensland government has announced a pilot program which would subsidies the wages of about 7 per cent of the state's apprentices if taken on by eligible businesses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4fa9b11ae8fcd5c2daa797bbf97ba1e</guid></item><item><title>Markets live updates: ASX and Aussie dollar down, Trump terminates trade talks with Canada</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/asx-markets-business-live-news-oct-24/105928654</link><description>The Australian share market is losing steam in afternoon trade, while the Aussie dollar is also in the red. US President Donald Trump took to social media to declare trade negotiations with Canada over. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d29e8b0481f79711586321434a587e57</guid></item><item><title>Sydney 2000 Paralympics changed everything for the Paralympic movement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/sydney-paralympics-changed-everything-elizabeth-wright/105872756</link><description>Sydney 2000 was a turning point — not just for me, but for the entire Paralympic movement, writes silver medallist Elizabeth Wright.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">092136bc1972dc772bb30f1718b69b4c</guid></item><item><title>ABC news quiz: A jewel heist, an awkward Trump moment and a mysterious burning object in the outback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/abc-new-quiz-october-24-donald-trump-louvre-theft-prince-andrew/105922120</link><description>How closely were you following the news this week? Test yourself to find out!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c98b5aec7b57b223d6eb29ed7816a8a</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Labor's environment protection bill 'unreasonable', Sussan Ley says — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/federal-politics-live-blog-oct-24/105928628</link><description>Opposition leader Sussan Ley says the federal government's proposed environmental protection laws are "completely unreasonable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50c30ee6c3b274d9ece8ede11a368c5d</guid></item><item><title>NBA head coach Chauncey Billups, player Terry Rozier arrested over sports betting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/basketball-billups-rozier-arrested-nba-betting-poker-schemes/105928658</link><description>Portland coach Chauncey Billups and Miami Heat guard Terry Rozier are among more than 30 people arrested in two cases alleging sprawling criminal schemes to rake in millions by rigging sports bets and poker games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c1adda1a7bfd5e98d96964fe5622c73</guid></item><item><title>Innovators rethink bike seat design to combat cycling saddle pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/innovative-bike-seat-designs-to-combat-cycling-saddle-pain/105898628</link><description>"Saddle soreness" is a common complaint among cyclists. These innovators are looking at creative ways to prevent it by redesigning the bike seat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6022273d98d73660d31032c869b90541</guid></item><item><title>ADHD support groups help women in Geraldton navigate life after diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/adhd-support-groups-for-women-in-geraldton/105920570</link><description>Jessie Carrie could not find the support she needed after being diagnosed with ADHD as an adult, so she started groups to help others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22b713181dd93c35dad55fe09e8d7be2</guid></item><item><title>Mudgee's Regent Theatre bought by residents with big plans for grand revival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/movies-to-mudgee-regent-theatre-bought-by-residents/105926030</link><description>After sitting idle for two decades residents of the NSW town of Mudgee have purchased the iconic Regent Theatre, with plans to return it to its former glory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f751cc691c737c4a8150cf9a7ec5388a</guid></item><item><title>Police allege Melbourne men tried to extort $6.6 million from construction company</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/construction-alleged-extortion-arrests-melbourne/105928724</link><description>Police allege three men falsely claimed to be mediating between a construction company and unions to prevent disruptions at buildings sites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3132ed3d63e108d7dd1227d856d66d8f</guid></item><item><title>Dolphins frolic with sea sponges on heads in unique mating tactic off WA coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/humpback-dolphins-wear-wigs-of-sea-foam-to-attract-mate/105918014</link><description>Scientists observe male humpback dolphins parading sea sponges on their heads to impress females off Western Australia's northern coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4caf78cc79dddb901f74e7fb48aa7634</guid></item><item><title>Women's marathon world record-holder Ruth Chepngetich banned for three years over doping violation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/ruth-chepngetich-banned-for-three-years-over-doping/105928812</link><description>Kenya's Ruth Chepngetich is banned from athletics for three years over a doping violation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78b0adf7f4bb7b275f2c995b59d2b826</guid></item><item><title>New deep cave diving doco features Thai cave rescue hero Richard Harris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/new-deep-cave-diving-doco-features-thai-cave-rescue-hero/105928728</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cfcb8e95e96669786fad904239a5e3d</guid></item><item><title>Australia backs Pacific Islands facing China heat over Taiwan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/pacific-islands-forum-under-pressure-from-china-over-taiwan/105928036</link><description>Beijing reprimanded Pacific Island nation ambassadors for including Taiwan in the regional summit last month, but Australia and New Zealand have lent their support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9de69f4ef09294d85a96827432ef8a87</guid></item><item><title>Fashion Critical reveals her favourite red carpet 'lewks'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/fashion-critical-reveals-her-favourite-red-carpet-lewks-/105923630</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46f8de476d3ef3483a512229f20aa93b</guid></item><item><title>Deadly H5 strain of bird flu suspected on sub-Antarctic Heard Island in the Southern Ocean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/bird-flu-suspected-remote-sub-antarctic-heard-island-nuyina/105928676</link><description>Suspected bird flu has reached Australia's sub-Antarctic Heard Island, with signs of the deadly H5 avian disease observed in elephant seals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">009928e6c16748c0cac1dfa1d8fb29c8</guid></item><item><title>What we know about 'mind-boggling' NBA rigging and poker fraud cases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/nba-rigging-and-poker-fraud-cases-explained/105928536</link><description>The allegations involve NBA luminaries, multiple New York mafia families, millions in cash and even an x-ray poker table that could read cards face down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">baea5497909229f2d0e05e216133bb50</guid></item><item><title>A-League footballers' mental health and substance abuse concerns revealed in PFA report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/a-league-mental-health-concerns-revealed-in-new-report/105927872</link><description>Socceroos hero Andrew Redmayne sheds light on the stresses A-League players face after a report finds footballers are struggling with their mental health, substance abuse and job security issues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dba60209ba077b7518445fa02b5a66e</guid></item><item><title>US imposes more sanctions on Russia as Ukraine war continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/us-imposes-more-sanctions-on-russia-as-ukraine-war-continues/105928768</link><description>The Russian president acknowledged that the move to sanction two oil companies would have "certain consequences", but would not significantly impact the country's economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91e2f52a7f7565fea1f79fcd0a317a98</guid></item><item><title>Man charged over stabbing death on southern Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/man-charged-over-stabbing-death-on-southern-gold-coast/105928840</link><description>A 27-year-old man has faced court on the Gold Coast, charged with murder after allegedly stabbing a man known to him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bda3c665cfbe619d676ea71be58b97e0</guid></item><item><title>India qualifies for Women's World Cup semifinal after double-century partnership from opening pair</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/cricket-smriti-mandhana-india-vs-new-zealand-world-cup-wrap/105928974</link><description>Smriti Mandhana scores her third century of the World Cup as a monster partnership with fellow opener Pratika Rawal delivers India a crucial win against New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fecc1046a1aaf0e7ce8821df9986c7e7</guid></item><item><title>Survivor calls for greater awareness of strokes in young people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/young-stroke-survivor-calls-greater-awareness/105920754</link><description>Despite one in four sufferers being under 65, experts say there is a common misconception that strokes only occur in older people. Mental well-being is key to recovery but is often more difficult for younger stroke survivors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e500e676e885fd882a544785e36d9e8</guid></item><item><title>World Rowing hits back at green light claims for Olympic Games rowing on Fitzroy River</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/world-rowing-canoeing-hits-back-at-brisbane-olympic-venue-claims/105929140</link><description>The world's top rowing and canoeing bodies say they are conducting their own assessments of the Fitzroy River ahead of the 2032 Games despite Queensland politicians insisting events will be held there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">475a995036543379c20e32db7848ebdb</guid></item><item><title>First Nations women share healing stories to pave bright tourism future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/first-nations-cultural-women-tourism-growing-demand-australia/105894586</link><description>A growing number of women are entering the in-demand cultural tourism field in which First Nations guides share treasured knowledge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">651a9c18b262747919d1b4e1ad65533e</guid></item><item><title>Injury status of LeBron James and other NBA stars allegedly used in betting scandal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/nba-betting-scandal-lebron-james-injury-status-used/105929340</link><description>The injury status of the likes of LeBron James and Anthony Davis was allegedly passed on to gamblers in the scandal that has rocked the NBA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91d1f60262f9cd2725fc1cb19e730a48</guid></item><item><title>Cranky crow targets unsuspecting visitors to Queensland's holiday hotspot.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/cranky-crow-targets-unsuspecting-visitors-to-queensland-s-holida/105925460</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2814c0fe5cbdca654169c2630984f46</guid></item><item><title>Cranky crow forces visitors to Noosa's Hastings Street to duck for cover</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/cranky-crow-divebombs-noosa-visitors-prompting-warning/105918290</link><description>Noosa Council has received multiple reports of the crow swooping walkers, which experts say is unusual for the species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33643d00a64e72ebb959cfe74e0f6634</guid></item><item><title>LA's Pacific Palisades fire suspect pleads not guilty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/las-pacific-palisades-fire-suspect-pleads-not-guilty/105929470</link><description>Jonathan Rinderknecht, 29, is charged with "maliciously" starting a fire in January that killed 12 people. If he is convicted he could spend up to 45 years in jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57abb6c4675be8a90d593a0ba7f68231</guid></item><item><title>13-year-old has major surgery after eating 100 magnets bought on Temu</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/boy-swallows-100-magnets-new-zealand/105929338</link><description>Surgeons in New Zealand remove part of the 13-year-old boy's bowel after he obtained banned magnets online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dca4339c08bc185eb2f9cc87f52f48d</guid></item><item><title>Ex-employees accuse Kimberley service station of hygiene breaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/derby-fuels-service-station-food-allegations/105729068</link><description>Steve Pates has worked in kitchens all around Australia, but says what he witnessed at a business in WA's far north was beyond anything he had ever seen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5addf76fa5eb7356b14e448f41abf14f</guid></item><item><title>From phishing to investment cons: How to spot a scam and safeguard your savings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/how-to-talk-to-your-parents-about-scams/105803754</link><description>From phishing to investment cons, scammers are staying "one step ahead" in their efforts to separate us from our savings. Older Australians are often targeted, but there are steps you can take to protect yourself, and those you care about.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09100ec38d619a5592d2adf13c4d427e</guid></item><item><title>Northern Territory, Queensland swelter through heatwaves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/severe-heatwave-warning-qld-nt-nothern-australia/105928886</link><description>Temperatures are set to reach above 40 degrees in some places, with more hospital admissions likely because of heat-related illness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">403e25f2e31c032e4898f6ba873ae739</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroo Nawaqanitawase will earn Wallabies recall in 2027, says Les Kiss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/kangaroo-nawaqanitawase-to-earn-wallabies-recall-2027-says-kiss/105929654</link><description>Wallabies coach-in-waiting Les Kiss is an admirer of Kangaroos debutant Mark Nawaqanitawase, who he says will return to union in 2027 wiser and a better player.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80a870d9bd80cd8a7e8054e329512588</guid></item><item><title>Dezi Freeman search 'far from over' as new taskforce continues investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/dezi-freeman-search-mount-buffalo-national-park/105929524</link><description>Mount Buffalo National Park will open to everyone as Victoria Police's search for Dezi Freeman continues with the creation of a new taskforce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc44dc7c9743d1b95cfd844c476c8be9</guid></item><item><title>Staff in regional ACM newsrooms concerned about rollout of generative AI model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/generative-ai-newsroom-journalism-acm-media-journalists/105860896</link><description>Staff and a union say a generative AI model being tested in Australian Community Media's regional newspapers is misattributing facts and leaving some fearing for their jobs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52b0a8efbd397a63d6b496185d72f575</guid></item><item><title>Australia claims silver in team pursuit at UCI track world championships in Santiago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/australia-team-pursuit-silver-uci-track-world-championships/105929270</link><description>Australia's team pursuit squad and keirin rider Leigh Hoffman have both claimed silver medals on day two of the UCI track world championships in Santiago, Chile.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a318b65fb181e3b901272e28b974b68b</guid></item><item><title>Road crash simulation and morgue tour part of road education in WA's South West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/road-crash-safety-education/105920154</link><description>A simulated road crash and an introduction to the local undertaker are part of a confronting, but what police say is effective, road safety program in WA's south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d669de4f8e46ad0b17feed5355fb9e1d</guid></item><item><title>Police warn wave of kill crew plots break 'no families' gangland code</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/nsw-tran-murder-gangs-code-families-sydney-bankstown/105929560</link><description>The alleged murder of a woman who was stripped naked, bound and gagged before she was killed shows a wider trend that Sydney's "guns for hire" are willing to break gangland code, a senior NSW detective says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b434841ca81ea8b0a89c19a8ea4eeba</guid></item><item><title>Man hit by cane train suffers serious leg injury in far north Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/pedestrian-hit-cane-train-queensland/105929136</link><description>A 30-year-old man is flown to hospital with life-threatening injuries after being struck by a cane train in Tully, south of Cairns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">debd60aa2bb13329c9a6448089aae074</guid></item><item><title>Mount Gibson announces 450 redundancies due to Koolan Island mine closure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/mount-gibson-koolan-island-collapse-closure/105930000</link><description>A rockfall has led to the Koolan Island mine site closing earlier than expected, with 450 jobs to be axed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf5cbcf1950b4018709ddadb3c80ed06</guid></item><item><title>Suspected arson attack on Bega home, weeks after fatal stabbing on same street</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/bega-house-fire-arson-investigations-stabbing-death/105911350</link><description>A fire that destroyed a house on the NSW far south coast is being treated as suspicious, after a man was fatally stabbed on the same street earlier in the month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d371ed2e334ed528ad9afecb1f8aee05</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged with murder, arson over Gladstone house fire in central Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/woman-charged-with-murder-after-fatal-gladstone-house-fire/105930378</link><description>A woman has been charged with murder and arson after a house fire that took the lives of a woman and two young children in Gladstone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51582c9643baa6361572e9efafb2ba42</guid></item><item><title>Louvre thieves descend on crane after robbery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/louvre-thieves-descend-on-crane-after-robbery/105930090</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f300126d928789f032c949bfeb2a619b</guid></item><item><title>Video appears to show Louvre jewel thieves escaping on ladder in broad daylight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/video-appears-to-show-louvre-thieves-escaping/105929650</link><description>Video shared widely on social media appears to show alleged Louvre jewellery thieves escaping on a crane near the Seine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc3ee68a92442faf5873cbe10dff28d3</guid></item><item><title>Bec McGaw reflects on alleged sexual assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/bec-mcgaw-sexual-assault-adf/105926836</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a19e08d04878491d2a4ee12808d06980</guid></item><item><title>Donna Manton says sexual violence does not discriminate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/donna-manton-says-sexual-violence-does-not-discriminate/105930256</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01d9bcfba0d6544a668cc21bb94d5928</guid></item><item><title>Kate says she was broken by a series of incidents, including a threat by her superior.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/kate-adf-class-action-experience/105930344</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4521aa9886b90b6f7379081e15467e7</guid></item><item><title>ADF facing landmark class action over alleged systemic sexual violence, harassment and discrimination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/adf-class-action-alleged-sexual-violence-harassment/105926114</link><description>The class action, which was officially launched in the Federal Court today, will operate on an opt-out basis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23893b0db232e3b277956d060ee2a24d</guid></item><item><title>Rare dinosaur mummies help scientists recreate what the prehistoric creatures may have looked like</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/rare-dinosaur-mummies-wyoming-america-duck-billed/105929888</link><description>The duck-billed dinosaur was only a few years old when it died. Scientists now believe the species had hooves on its feet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2902ec0732a0af00e2fc4f5f4bb38d0</guid></item><item><title>Police launch fresh search in cold case murder of Colleen Walker-Craig</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/fresh-search-for-missing-bowraville-murder-victim-colleen-walker/105928932</link><description>A search is underway on NSW Mid North Coast for the remains of Colleen Walker-Craig, who went missing within months of two other children in Bowraville.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab94d3c6b78437a27a9bdd74b9dc8791</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce's animated response to a question about carp in parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/barnaby-joyce-s-animated-response-to-a-question-about-carp/105930950</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74ec36a03f393b65f800fa7aed202736</guid></item><item><title>From insulting prime ministers to picking fights with celebrities, Barnaby Joyce has never been afraid to carpe diem</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/barnaby-joyce-from-threatening-to-euthanase-johnny-depp-dogs/105908978</link><description>Threatening to euthanase Johnny Depp and Amber Heard's dogs, repeatedly calling out "caaarp" in parliament, that notorious moment on a Canberra footpath, Barnaby Joyce's career has had plenty of colour and movement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ca0e80c58ee09ae5db3624ed42dd657</guid></item><item><title>US faces a reckoning after blurring line between gambling and sport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/american-sports-betting-reckoning-/105929458</link><description>Seven years ago, the United States crossed a line that it once dared to never cross, leading to a string of arrests that threaten to tarnish sports in the country for generations to come.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aee14fa4bd13768c4f4fa7e4d89b53af</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle mother calls for tougher laws after toddler run down by e-bike</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/mother-calls-for-tougher-laws-after-toddler-run-down-by-e-bike/105928636</link><description>More than a year after her 21-month-old child was hit by an e-bike, a Newcastle mother is calling for change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bc69cffa7f162ac54d3c32a7e7ea9d5</guid></item><item><title>Rough sleeping camps found burnt in Launceston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/tasmania-launceston-housing-camps-burnt-homelessness/105929238</link><description>Two homeless camps in Launceston were found burnt, and with the social housing waitlist growing and more people calling for help, advocates say the situation is at breaking point.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0ccc84bf11e8b6bdcb05feb85f54d02</guid></item></channel></rss>