<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 11:31:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Update your ABC News homepage for more local stories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2020-09-03/update-to-abc-news-homepage/12579988</link><description>We've got an ABC News homepage for you. Adjust your settings for the right mix of local and national news.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">146f1699ce6b1b7420a91b6bb80d0309</guid></item><item><title>Behind the Juanita Nielsen mystery is another, forgotten cold case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2021-07-13/behind-juanita-nielsen-mystery-forgotten-aboriginal-death/100283926</link><description>In the shadow of Juanita Nielsen's disappearance lies another suspicious and unsolved death. This is her story. Warning: Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander readers are advised this story contains the name and image of a person who's died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbc17b36905b7521b8cac858e244f041</guid></item><item><title>'Politicised' Administrative Appeals Tribunal abolished, after attorney-general declares its reputation ruined</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2022-12-16/administrative-appeals-tribunal-abolished-by-attorney-general/101781300</link><description>One of the most notoriously politicised bodies in the Commonwealth will be overhauled, as the attorney-general seeks to end political appointments to the Administrative Appeals Tribunal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a85910f1f525f653dcc7de8f440431ae</guid></item><item><title>Barbara Kingsolver returns to Appalachia to tackle opioid crisis, in Dickens-inspired novel Demon Copperhead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2022-12-27/barbara-kingsolver-demon-copperhead-appalachia-opioid-crisis/101792232</link><description>Barbara Kingsolver, author of The Poisonwood Bible, returned to her home turf of Appalachia to tackle one of its most urgent issues — with a little help from David Copperfield.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62dd1dd08c1847e4a1f545d423272405</guid></item><item><title>Spotlight forum: the transition to clean energy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2023-10-26/energy-spotlight/103026768</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">644120ae1bf63ea4ccf5fa3e1bc0916a</guid></item><item><title>More parents are happy with having an only child. Here's why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2023-11-09/why-more-parents-are-happy-with-having-an-only-child/103011388</link><description>Although having one child is becoming a more common family model, concerns only children will be "lonely and spoilt" persist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e29517935b34ed4e56901ad433a4460d</guid></item><item><title>Having an only child means we're better parents for our daughter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2023-11-15/why-we-decided-to-have-just-one-child/103019000</link><description>We realised family is what you make it and that we wanted to do things that might be more possible with just one child.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cc921ddf13d474e7188389a5db5b6cb</guid></item><item><title>Dick Smith says no country has ever been able to run entirely on renewables. Is that correct?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-03-22/fact-check-dick-smith-renewables-entire-country/103617364</link><description>Entrepreneur Dick Smith says no country has ever been able to run on renewables, labelling the idea "impossible". What do the experts say?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2284a3f13a33a1af76fef9c17bbce51</guid></item><item><title>Mark Butler says one in six high school students and one in four people aged 18 to 24 are vaping. Is that correct?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-06-13/fact-check-mark-butler-vaping-rates-students-young-adults/103968776</link><description>Minister for Health and Aged Care Mark Butler says one in six high school students, along with one in four 18–24-year-olds, is vaping. RMIT ABC Fact Check takes a look at the research.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d57ab06dd5f5f69803b80853e7fcf2ca</guid></item><item><title>Fact Check signs off today after 11 years at the ABC. Here's our guide to being your own fact checker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-06-28/fact-check-final-wrap-11-years/104033004</link><description>Eleven years ago, the first formal fact check was published at the ABC. A lot has been fact checked between then and now — here's how to spot a dubious claim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">969fae2908f259f9de2daf75ed84ff66</guid></item><item><title>Call for button battery redesign after new study reveals horrific injuries and fatalities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/button-battery-warning-danger-deaths-lithium-swallow/103986966</link><description>A new study reveals the horrific injuries suffered after swallowing or inserting button batteries but manufacturers aren't prioritising their redesign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46ab5f96ade65908ecf6b7be8673e61f</guid></item><item><title>The US election is about style more than substance. It's why Kamala Harris needs to nail her DNC speech in about eight seconds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/us-election-kamala-harris-dnc-speech-style-substance/104256162</link><description>When the Democrat presidential candidate Kamala Harris delivers her speech to the Democratic National Convention today, style will be almost everything.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bddf8093759d999153dfd749b90e144a</guid></item><item><title>Reserve Bank restructure closer to reality after Treasurer Jim Chalmers offers olive branch to Angus Taylor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/reserve-bank-restructure-closer-to-reality/104260250</link><description>The Reserve Bank of Australia is a step closer to its biggest restructure in three decades after the treasurer offers an assurance to his Coalition counterpart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e920ec5b24583b8f74962ecc7f9c2585</guid></item><item><title>SA government allows Riverlea housing project to continue after discovery of Aboriginal remains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-10-11/riverlea-housing-project-to-continue/104461676</link><description>The SA government gives developers of the Riverlea housing estate in Adelaide's north the green light to continue building, despite the discovery of Indigenous remains at the site last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65d626a6c4d1d9a026afc9dabe1bb41b</guid></item><item><title>Hugo Weaving, Meg Washington on adapting Paul Kelly’s How To Make Gravy into a Christmas movie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-12-01/how-to-make-gravy-movie-paul-kelly-hugo-weaving-interview/104654220</link><description>How do you turn an iconic Aussie song into a movie? In the case of How To Make Gravy, the secret is in the source... material.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bfa331d227c25df3c88016f74881f75</guid></item><item><title>Launceston man dies while competing in Coles Bay Triathlon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-02-08/tasmanian-man-dies-coles-bay-triathlon/104914190</link><description>A Launceston man has died while competing in the swimming leg of the Coles Bay Triathlon, an annual event on Tasmania's east coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4834445d0e22c495c70b01fa76efb2f</guid></item><item><title>Have Your Say: What was the issue, policy or event that decided your vote?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-02-26/federal-election-your-say/104788518</link><description>After a five-week campaign, the results are in with Labor returned to government. Is there a policy or issue that swayed your vote? Have Your Say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">320dfcbec9cd8fe02e449407ce78e618</guid></item><item><title>Voters tell ABC's Your Say they want politicians with a vision, not bickering</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-13/abc-your-say-federal-election-politicians-with-vision/105164874</link><description>Voters tell ABC's Your Say campaign they want courage and vision from politicians, not bickering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">033ddce5ad54070fbce620dc6760d9ba</guid></item><item><title>Push for seniors' dental scheme grows ahead of federal election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-13/aged-care-dental-scheme-australia-federal-election/105149782</link><description>Imagine living in aged care and not having your teeth or dentures properly cleaned and checked each day. That's a risk faced by elderly Australians, prompting calls for the next federal government to boost oral health training and services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36d312d336a36247fd1c01e78814112b</guid></item><item><title>Australians tell ABC's Your Say they are struggling more than ever with housing costs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-15/abc-your-say-federal-election-2025-housing-policies/105175180</link><description>Voters tell ABC's Your Say campaign they are struggling more than ever with housing costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54451646ec8e9f100cc2fe59fc9c08c5</guid></item><item><title>Australia's growing cohort of tenants fear they will rent forever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-16/australias-growing-tenant-cohort-fear-forever-renting/105127148</link><description>Home ownership rates in Australia have been falling for decades, and with rental vacancies at record lows and prices at historic highs, many fear their dream of owning a home may be out of reach. Some experts say rental caps could help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36f35fe439f533ac9522c679c7e37187</guid></item><item><title>Housing advocates seek federal funding election promise for co-op model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-17/housing-cooperative-solution-proposed-for-rental-crisis/105108816</link><description>Advocates admit co-operative housing models are not for everyone but say for the right residents, they offer more security and affordable pricing than traditional rentals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3608b0c1ae56f5a5b36968898f65df5e</guid></item><item><title>Next-generation voters call for better engagement ahead of federal election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-18/federal-election-rural-next-generation-voters/105173450</link><description>Young people in Albury say issues that directly affect them and their communities are not being addressed by major parties for the 2025 election campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ae182892b8c9591cd9ec35e6e57fcb9</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne seat of Calwell highlights Labor woes as Gaza pain galvanises Muslim voters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-20/calwell-labor-backlash-over-gaza-islamophobia/104850500</link><description>Dissatisfaction with the Albanese government's stance on Israel-Palestine among many Arab and Muslim voters threatens to unseat Labor MPs, in some places for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63e7f9854fee5bc20e54ee2f5bd136f4</guid></item><item><title>Cost of living, housing among key concerns in SA marginal seat of Boothby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-21/boothby-cost-of-living-federal-election-2025/105190262</link><description>At this year’s federal election, the South Australian seat of Boothby is one of the state’s two marginal seats. As part of the ABC’s “Your Say” campaign, we spoke to residents in the electorate about their biggest concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dfd66b0605d29b960082ff52f18c170</guid></item><item><title>Energy projects in South West WA threaten votes for major federal parties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-21/energy-projects-south-west-wa-federal-election-labor-liberals/105152524</link><description>Australia's two major parties have tied their federal election fates to controversial energy projects in WA's South West where the issues have polarised voters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8962a53de05f0293b3a104690022111a</guid></item><item><title>Tiwi Islanders eager to have their say as remote voting for the federal election begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-22/early-voting-starts-in-remote-communities-tiwi-islands-aec/105201318</link><description>Voters in the small remote community of Pirlangimpi on the Tiwi Islands, north of Darwin, have become some of the first to cast their votes for the federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0c419fe3ae44debe7edf27241c0e5c1</guid></item><item><title>Mobile coverage is an election issue in regional areas. What's been promised?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-23/telecommunications-mobile-coverage-federal-election-promises/105080674</link><description>For many regional and remote Australians, reliable mobile coverage can be life-saving. They are desperate for both sides of politics to take meaningful action towards eliminating black spots.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ceda72e552d98e5f293d3c037efeefa</guid></item><item><title>Health, climate and community sport: What older voters in the Tasmanian seat of Bass are talking about this election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-29/health-climate-sport-election-older-voters-bass-tasmania/105224138</link><description>The federal seat of Bass is held by a margin of just 1.4 per cent. For these older voters who live in the electorate, health, climate and community sport are the issues that will decide their vote.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a3579db910b5a7ee8e11d2618bf798f</guid></item><item><title>The Catholic Church had always resisted a North American pope. Is Leo XIV the anti-Trump?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-10/is-pope-leo-the-anti-trump-pontiff/105273262</link><description>The election of Pope Leo XIV brings the Catholic Church closer to the United States in a way it has never been before, but with that comes a unique challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18cad5848806a0ba000985f4b9774ba6</guid></item><item><title>The Anglican bishop who took on sexual abuse in the church</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-11/compass-the-anglican-bishop-who-took-on-the-church/105138236</link><description>When Greg Thompson became bishop of Newcastle, he refused to turn a blind eye to the decades-long child sex abuse scandals in the diocese. For him, it was personal. He was himself a sexual abuse survivor. But speaking out came at huge cost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f4bd7d328730e2d28f922edabd33ff9</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese formally invites Pope Leo XIV to Australia in Vatican meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-20/anthony-albanese-formally-invites-pope-leo-xiv-to-australia/105312312</link><description>It is the first time an Australian prime minister has had a private audience with the head of the Catholic Church since 2008.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e58f0be3bb255698971a503ca44faa62</guid></item><item><title>Albanese invites Pope Leo XIV to Australia in Vatican meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-20/albanese-invites-pope-leo-xiv-to-australia-in/105314792</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1751c6431203907ccfe079d827c18a73</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Tony Abbott says he 'deeply regrets' Coalition split — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-21/federal-politics-may-21-coalition-liberal-nationals-labor/105315946</link><description>Former prime minister Tony Abbott says he hopes the Coalition can re-form "as soon as possible".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c817d1c67eda29c1633a0e39645dcbe</guid></item><item><title>David Littleproud under pressure to reconcile with the Liberals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-21/david-littleproud-under-pressure-to-reconcile-with/105320918</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0128e28166c2727cb2399251a182efeb</guid></item><item><title>Coalition gets back together after week-long split</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-28/coalition-gets-back-together-after-week-long-split/105350204</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f71a36f022d3c76ea247259c27e2ff7a</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou praised by Spurs captain Son Heung-min following sacking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-06-08/spurs-sacking-ange-postecoglou-son-heung-min/105390928</link><description>In the wake of Ange Postecoglou's sacking, Tottenham Hotspur captain Son Heung-min describes working with the Australian as an "incredible privilege".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9460c746230ba6952e483d467bdf75d</guid></item><item><title>Reckless crocodile interactions spark calls for tougher penalties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-06-26/crocodile-interactions-spark-calls-for-tougher-penalties/105457366</link><description>A popular croc-spotting site in Far North Queensland will be monitored after multiple reports of illegal interactions with the reptiles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a0da61abce640d90ba2aae8c4fe59ac</guid></item><item><title>North Adelaide's LIV Golf redevelopment to go ahead after controversial laws pass SA parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-06-26/north-adelaide-liv-golf-upgrade-to-go-ahead/105465432</link><description>Laws that allow the South Australian government to redevelop the North Adelaide Golf Course and move the LIV Golf tournament into the city pass parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7004b5a65837ff277c8c17d8b3d382e8</guid></item><item><title>Rangers search for owner of pet snake left on Bundaberg footpath</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-07-01/snake-in-enclosure-left-on-bundaberg-footpath-queensland/105480068</link><description>A dog walker makes an unusual discovery in Queensland that sends wildlife rangers on a "very strange" mission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9231cc1048a424620fcde3b420d5ca1</guid></item><item><title>WA election staff recruitment outsourced after reputation hit by 2021 poll, documents suggest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-07-15/wa-electoral-commission-feared-reputation-documents-suggest/105518826</link><description>A perceived blow to its reputation from the 2021 state election drove the WA Electoral Commission's decision to outsource recruitment for this year's poll, it emerges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94f6d8db85df8d4b86e93c765c4d5152</guid></item><item><title>Wildlife rangers search for Noosa crocodile after potential sighting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-07-22/search-for-noosa-crocodile-after-potential-sighting/105558608</link><description>The search for a crocodile reportedly seen by a fisherman in the Noosa River continues, but authorities say there have been no additional sightings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">268c5e5a37724a1e03e962fb1f05e6a0</guid></item><item><title>Outback astronomers lodge appeal against Hydrostor's $1b energy storage project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-07-24/outback-astronomy-court-actions-against-hydrostor-project/105554294</link><description>A tourism business has lodged an appeal against a decision to approve a nearly billion-dollar energy storage project outside Broken Hill, saying light and noise will impact its business.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75b0ea3081f5560d334a5837de106942</guid></item><item><title>Kaylee McKeown into backstroke final at world swimming titles as Alex Perkins wins bronze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-07-29/world-aquatics-championships-kaylee-mckeown-alexandria-perkins/105584388</link><description>Five-time Olympic gold medallist Kaylee McKeown sets up a showdown with rival Regan Smith, while Australian teammate Alex Perkins climbs the podium in Singapore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68f8561d9ea3f204993eef09638095f4</guid></item><item><title>Kaylee McKeown wins 100m backstroke gold at World Aquatics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-07-30/mckeown-wins-100m-backstroke-at-world-championships/105588694</link><description>Kaylee McKeown unleashes a sensational swim to come from behind and claim the 100m backstroke gold medal at the World Swimming Championships in Singapore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">395a6a1901c52296cc1b764ec6c47cc9</guid></item><item><title>ASX gains 1.2 per cent in broad rally following strong Wall Street session — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-05/asx-markets-business-live-news-august5-2025/105609344</link><description>The local share market closed more than 1.2 per cent higher, with all sectors gaining ground, following a strong rally on Wall Street overnight. Look back on the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a6dfedb27e6ecbcb43336e691376c1c</guid></item><item><title>If the RBA cuts rates this week, expect property prices to rise (again)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-10/if-the-rba-cuts-rates-expect-property-prices-to-rise-again/105632180</link><description>When the RBA cuts rates, it drives property prices higher. What does it mean for housing affordability?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf87af7ec9947f68d427d05b79425f06</guid></item><item><title>Australia is now a 'home owners' welfare state', and income inequality is worse than we think</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-13/australia-is-a-homeowners-welfare-state-making-inequality-worse/105620522</link><description>Australia is now a "home owner's welfare state", leading economists argue, and if the tax treatment of housing were reformed, the nation as a whole would benefit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2c4e07bf026ae12611af5e96e4ceb1b</guid></item><item><title>'Ketamine Queen' agrees to plead guilty to selling drugs that killed Matthew Perry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-19/ketamine-queen-pleads-guilty-to-matthew-perry-drug-death/105670034</link><description>Jasveen Sangha is the fifth and final defendant to be charged with the actor's death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bf64d7118f6ab696d88f71e10227196</guid></item><item><title>Seekers come up short in hunt for meteor seen in central Victorian night sky</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-21/hunt-for-space-rocks-after-victorian-meteor-sighting/105670756</link><description>Researchers have vowed to continue their search for a missing bit of space treasure after a meteor fell to Earth two weeks ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98966d4190de31cd00c8930bdec97fe1</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce's net zero repeal bill to be debated, as Labor presses Coalition over climate divide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-25/barnaby-joyce-net-zero-bill-debate/105690926</link><description>Labor will seek to maximise internal Coalition divisions over whether to scrap its net zero emissions commitment, allowing debate in the chamber today on Barnaby Joyce's bill to repeal climate laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e6caf00d41b6ac2dcab3b57d9c35b19</guid></item><item><title>Australia keeps pumping house prices, while Trump pursues 'state-run capitalism'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-31/australia-keeps-pumping-house-prices-trump-state-run-capitalism/105711838</link><description>President Donald Trump opens the door to "state-run capitalism" in the US, while Australia keeps pumping house prices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b191800d2a4bd82d48bb07bbf964b60</guid></item><item><title>Anti-immigration rallies and counter protests held in cities across the country — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-31/anti-immigration-rally-march-for-australia-august-31/105717552</link><description>Demonstrators gathered in cites across the country as March for Australia rallies call for a reduction in immigration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e42ab0e5162487f73a87de03e243cbb5</guid></item><item><title>Gold price hits record, ASX slips on retail sell-off — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-02/asx-markets-business-live-news-sept-2/105723514</link><description>Local stocks end lower as the retail sector gets hit and Woolworths and Wesfarmers trade ex-dividend. See how the trading day unfolded on the business blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3487bf12138a6f82d540b44c9e957e62</guid></item><item><title>ABC presenters give us their tips for Top 100 books countdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-03/vv-authors-reveal-their-favourite-books/105676710</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13d34c88e23891ada7c19f8319bc34b7</guid></item><item><title>ASX falls, ANZ shares down after mass sackings — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/asx-markets-business-live-news-sept-9-2025/105746990</link><description>ANZ's share price loses ground after announcing mass sackings, ASX slips. Catch up on the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acfc484132838ee521db5d8e551e4475</guid></item><item><title>Haven't started on your tax return and feeling overwhelmed?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/how-to-start-on-tax-return-if-feeling-overwhelmed/105623326</link><description>Despite being something most of us tackle every year, lodging a tax return can easily end up at the bottom of your to-do list.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d4b915e4c4f4debb7dd1fb6ed70afbe</guid></item><item><title>These images show the damage wrought by the shot hole borer on Hyde Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/these-images-show-the-damage-wrought-by-the-shot/105741042</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af481785da688b26e7b4f6dba03dabb5</guid></item><item><title>Trump confirms US military carried out strike on drug boat from Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/trump-confirms-us-military-carried-out-strike/105777688</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac78de1cdb120bc010d65f78e27d2742</guid></item><item><title>How the Collingwood Magpies are righting the ship this AFLW season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/aflw-collingwood-magpies-round-six-hawthorn/105785982</link><description>A year after finishing dead last in the AFLW, the Magpies have started making moves up the ladder thanks to a new approach at both ends of the field.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09dcd2a4338fbef6fc6396c784fa2fe5</guid></item><item><title>Crocodiles on the move in northern Australia as breeding season arrives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/crocodiles-on-the-move-breeding-season-arrives-north-australia/105766898</link><description>It's crocodile breeding season and at one central Queensland farm, the drama is on par with a reality television dating show as keepers try to work out the best pairings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab50329a1039618670babc23784c4980</guid></item><item><title>How to clean out your wardrobe as the seasons change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/how-to-spring-clean-wardobe-clean-out/105780140</link><description>It's the kind of task that can seem overwhelming, but the change of season is the perfect opportunity to review what's in your wardrobe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf9c7f0a36323b3457588962f5d0b0b0</guid></item><item><title>Eleanor Patterson's 'bittersweet' moment of support for young rival at World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/eleanor-patterson-world-championships-support-heartwarming/105762048</link><description>Eleanor Patterson did not come away with a medal at the 2025 World Athletics Championships. But by supporting Angelina Topić through a tough moment, she gained so much more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">826692bb635f6dcf2b35199ab6113385</guid></item><item><title>Australian Jay Vine wins men's time trial silver in the world road cycling championships in Rwanda</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/world-road-cycling-championships-jay-vine-wins-silver/105800504</link><description>Queenslander Jay Vine races to a silver medal in the men's time trial at the world road cycling championships in Rwanda.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55f4e8238bda50010bb62f921851af9d</guid></item><item><title>Moldovan authorities arrest 74 people over alleged Russia-backed election plot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/moldova-election-arrests-russia-backed-plot/105804776</link><description>The widespread raids came ahead of the country's parliamentary elections on Sunday, expected to determine whether the country will pursue closer ties with the European Union.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a647be00ecfc0d387fa0b9a153bf4406</guid></item><item><title>Egyptian activist Alaa Abd el-Fattah released from prison after nearly 12 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/egyptian-activist-alaa-abd-el-fattah-released-from-prison/105805902</link><description>Pro-democracy activist Alaa Abd el-Fattah has been released from prison, following a pardon from the Egyptian president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d429202c47e43999510999e5ea936c5c</guid></item><item><title>Perth grandmother Donna Nelson loses appeal over Japan drug smuggling conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/donna-nelson-loses-japan-drug-smuggling-appeal/105804346</link><description>Convicted drug smuggler and Perth grandmother, Donna Nelson, loses her appeal against her conviction for smuggling two kilograms of methamphetamine into Tokyo Airport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47b528f98203d1300e8e1b40978bdddc</guid></item><item><title>Shellharbour Council proposes tiny home planning pathway in NSW first</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/shellharbour-council-tiny-home-pilot-proposal-development/105811852</link><description>Shellharbour Council approves a plan for a tiny homes planning pathway which it says could be adopted statewide, as owners face uncertainty around legal installation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff8db8dbb4d397dada6c798c4cbe2283</guid></item><item><title>Humanity's space ambition to be focus of first Powerhouse Parramatta exhibition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/task-eternal-space-exhibition-to-launch-powerhouse-parramatta/105829116</link><description>Humanity's ambition to explore beyond Earth will feature in the largest exhibition space in the country when Powerhouse Parramatta opens in the city's west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54153ffe9059ead5c032efe725a8e9e6</guid></item><item><title>NRL players, including Brisbane Broncos star Payne Haas, spruik crime-linked fashion line R4W Active</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/nrl-player-payne-haas-fronts-crime-linked-activewear-line-r4w/105828100</link><description>The grand final-bound Origin prop and at least three other NRL players are promoting a clothing brand linked to the Alameddine crime family, fuelling police concern the league has failed to stem the influence of organised crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">013c5a6b057a382fbbed566420a9e84e</guid></item><item><title>Max Verstappen has never won the F1 Singapore Grand Prix but has a chance as he chases Oscar Piastri and McLaren</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/max-verstappen-f1-singapore-grand-prix-oscar-piastri/105843662</link><description>Max Verstappen has won the previous two grands prix in Formula 1, but this weekend's race in Singapore is the only circuit on the calendar on which he has never triumphed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87e6eaeb3c042f6e16d829282d81e75c</guid></item><item><title>South West Aboriginal Medical Service members expelled after allegedly 'storming' headquarters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/south-west-aboriginal-medical-service-members-expelled/105835570</link><description>The South West Aboriginal Medical Service has expelled several of its members who it has accused of sowing community division.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d58f590226ffd5ec4e623b45427995e</guid></item><item><title>Report into proposed Burswood racetrack finds noise concerns for locals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/burswood-racetrack-noise-concerns-report/105845314</link><description>Noise levels from a controversial motorsport racetrack planned for inner-city Perth are likely to be excessive for residents of nearby apartments and guests at the adjacent Crown entertainment complex, a new report finds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dde0f26a9c584b6ebb95b4b4c84f567</guid></item><item><title>Nine people killed in violent Kashmir protests that took place during internet blackout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/nine-killed-in-violent-anti-government-kashmir-protests/105846508</link><description>The extent of the violence is still becoming clear after days of protests took place amid an internet blackout in the region of Kashmir administered by Pakistan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4241a7a41504a46692c346d92c0a1b6b</guid></item><item><title>Pro-Palestinian protesters told Sydney Opera House 'off-limits' for planned rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/pro-palestine-march-planned-for-sydney-opera-house/105848564</link><description>NSW Police says the location and expected scale of the rally planned by the Palestinian Action Group poses public safety concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75e8ff7e77c0e3b00a8c435b6cb3bb22</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds chasing polished performance against 'confident' Proteas in three-Test series ahead of 2026 Commonwealth Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/netball-test-australia-diamonds-south-africa-proteas/105850266</link><description>The Diamonds are way of South Africa ahead of their three-Test series, which kicks off in Bendigo on Saturday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a3b06b304eb0344892b3505a559ab20</guid></item><item><title>Sean 'Diddy' Combs sentenced to 50 months' prison after offering tearful apologies in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/sean-diddy-combs-sentenced-in-new-york-court/105847246</link><description>A New York judge says the disgraced music mogul's violence, coercion and abuse had devastating consequences on his two former partners, and he was unconvinced that Combs would not reoffend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cf4dfca9ee9f35e74ada3699a88df0e</guid></item><item><title>European Space Agency launches second space antenna in New Norcia, north of Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/space-agency-opens-second-deep-space-antenna-new-norcia/105849820</link><description>A second deep space antenna opened in a tiny monastic town in Western Australia could help unlock the secrets of the universe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">897e2da31ddeaef33af502525555b9b4</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne hands Ashes selectors reminder with Sheffield Shield century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/marnus-labuschagne-sheffield-shield-scores/105857408</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne has hit his first century in red ball cricket for over a year just one month out from the first Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a176bd65e86e8cee22777c8998188414</guid></item><item><title>Trump deploys National Guard in city deeply scarred by military force</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/national-guard-chicago-1968-history/105740956</link><description>The National Guard was deployed to Chicago streets in 1968. It changed the city forever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5de315904cfb310941c0e5754b3c7116</guid></item><item><title>Broncos shares surge 40 per cent after Grand Final win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/broncos-shares-surge-40-after-grand-final-win/105858608</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb9f530fa3b53960f57deb774eadfed4</guid></item><item><title>Team Australia wins back-to-back Motocross of Nations titles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/team-australia-go-back-to-back-in-motocross-of-nations/105856060</link><description>Queensland brothers Jett and Hunter Lawrence help secure Australia's second consecutive Motocross of Nations title in Indiana.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c01890fe6dc96d2122a816cdf583308a</guid></item><item><title>Planning can help save you money this festive season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/preparing-financially-for-christmas-and-holidays/105795388</link><description>Australians estimate Christmas costs them about $800 a year, on average, but planning ahead can reduce the financial burden.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">158e6acd232ffd0c3bea1632ef3d82e3</guid></item><item><title>Players concerned over Shanghai heat as Novak Djokovic collapses on court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/players-concerned-over-shanghai-heat-as-novak-djokovic-col/105864786</link><description>Holger Rune says "there is always a limit" as soaring temperatures and humidity in Shanghai and Wuhan tennis events cause player distress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0a40634d1b457b5752fb7f8a643aea7</guid></item><item><title>Domain rental report for September quarter shows rent for houses stable across combined capital cities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/domain-rental-report-september-quarter-2025/105868398</link><description>Domain's September quarterly report shows house rents across the country's combined capitals have remained stable for five consecutive quarters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4195ce266d53f9e8b7b3108d8b6860ff</guid></item><item><title>Beast of War is the indie shark movie that bit off a lot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/beast-of-war-kiah-roache-turner-mark-coles-smith/105857098</link><description>Mystery Road star Mark Coles Smith and his Beast of War director Kiah Roache-Turner on taking a chomp out of WWII soldiers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c11e53d16ff74618f42da0430ef3787b</guid></item><item><title>Deloitte caught out using AI in report for federal government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/deloitte-caught-out-using-ai-in-report-for-federal/105874634</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73a40e241a39295c35b76e8f87cb1de6</guid></item><item><title>László Krasznahorkai awarded Nobel Prize in Literature for 'visionary' work that 'reaffirms the power of art'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/l%C3%A1szl%C3%B3-krasznahorkai-nobel-prize-in-literature-2025/105874554</link><description>László Krasznahorkai has been awarded the Nobel Prize in Literature, one of the world's most prestigious writing awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcaabf1e799e51426d25d8a82300fd8f</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic advances to Shanghai Masters semifinals, qualifier Valentin Vacherot continues fairytale run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/novak-djokovic-advances-to-semifinals-of-shanghai-masters/105875540</link><description>Fourth seed Novak Djokovic battled past a spirited Zizou Bergs 6-3 7-5 on Thursday to reach the Shanghai Masters semifinals for a 10th time, setting up a clash with surprise package and world number 204 Valentin Vacherot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">745b0675e4a5c74aaa50698faa310769</guid></item><item><title>Brodie Kostecki sets qualifying record to snare Bathurst 1000 provisional pole</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/bathurst-1000-qualifying-brodie-kostecki-sets-record/105879396</link><description>Brodie Kostecki looks a strong chance to become the third driver to claim three consecutive Bathurst 1000 poles after going fastest in Friday's qualifying session.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7507b3e62b65366d3ca4a6fdabe8fb7</guid></item><item><title>Kimberley woman part of Seven Sisters project makes submission to UN in fight for justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/irene-davey-seeks-justice-with-un-for-daughter-kimberley/105870006</link><description>It has been close to three decades since Irene Davey's daughter disappeared. Now she is taking her case to the United Nations in an attempt to finally get justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">157d801424833657379f8a718b6fc70c</guid></item><item><title>Genomic medicine could be huge but 5 million Australians may miss out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/genomic-medicine-could-be-huge-but-5-million/105878606</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ed6e2fb9d4d9d0324e237a7c8b62bfe</guid></item><item><title>Hackers release Qantas customers' data on dark web</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/hackers-release-qantas-customers-data-on-dark-web/105881266</link><description>Hackers have released personal data from Qantas customers onto the dark web, following a cyber attack in July.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89f0546c7b3bb23647757cb38ea11506</guid></item><item><title>What time is the 2025 Bathurst 1000? How can I watch the Supercars at Bathurst?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/what-time-is-the-2025-bathurst-1000-how-can-i-watch-bathurst/105861440</link><description>The 2025 Bathurst 1000 starts on Sunday morning. Here's all you need to know before the 68th running of the iconic endurance race.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32f6b0cbbc3f3ff226077a40bb8c9459</guid></item><item><title>Gregory Porter on turning personal pain into powerful music</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/gregory-porter-interview-australia-mister-holland-no-love-dying/105866372</link><description>From the pain of racism to the joy of love, Gregory Porter's voice carries it all with power and purpose.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a61497653a2cd8967d2930635faab18</guid></item><item><title>Vacherot becomes lowest-ranked ATP Masters winner after defeating his cousin Rinderknech in Shanghai</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/valentin-vacherot-wins-shanghai-masters-atp-tournament/105883038</link><description>He beat his cousin Arthur Rinderknech 4-6, 6-3, 6-3 on Sunday local time to claim the first title of his career after a stunning run from the qualifying rounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb81965abf5ff6abbfd51d7bc8b541f5</guid></item><item><title>Former tennis star Jelena Dokic grapples with complex grief after abusive father Damir's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/jelenadokic-says-abusive-dad-showed-no-remorse/105849988</link><description>Jelena Dokic was abused by her father for years, with no tennis success enough to stop the beatings. She reveals the complex grief of losing a parent who showed no remorse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69cd6af49b40951598418e7e78d42249</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar's President Andry Rajoelina says student protesters are attempting a coup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/madagascar-president-claims-coup-attempt-underway/105883466</link><description>Troops from an elite unit of the country's military are urging fellow soldiers to disobey orders and back student protesters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f041025445012537603be910fd6490a</guid></item><item><title>Climate Integrity says 'distorted research' behind government policy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/climate-integrity-accc-to-investigate-gas-lobby-ey-modelling/105866988</link><description>Advocacy group Climate Integrity has accused the gas industry of using "distorted research", produced by the accounting firm EY, to influence the Australian government's Future Gas Strategy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28322136f22de6e61de34a7e4e872c4b</guid></item><item><title>World's biggest light installation to illuminate landscapes of Albany, WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/biggest-light-installation-ever-on-earth-planned-for-albany/105866412</link><description>A light installation, projected onto King George Sound in Albany, will be the largest ever created.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0c3fad2d619ba1d36ef0034dc9d4ec0</guid></item><item><title>How to tell if your Qantas personal data has hit the dark web and what you can do if it has</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/qantas-cyber-hack-has-my-data-been-leaked-what-should-i-do/105884604</link><description>Hackers have released Qantas customer data onto the dark web. Here's what experts say to look out for if you think your personal data may be caught up in the leak and what actions you can take.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0686253e2a0f07a77f7a19d16ef3924b</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian MP Craig Garland temporarily disqualified from driving over drug driving charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/mp-craig-garland-sentenced-for-drug-driving-charge/105773362</link><description>Independent MP Craig Garland applied in court for a restricted license, saying it would be a "terrible situation" if he wasn't able to attend parliamentary sitting weeks in Hobart due to the ban after being found guilty of drug driving.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c66d699bcd04007a1aae088275012df</guid></item><item><title>Hamas releases all remaining Israeli hostages in Gaza, IDF confirms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/hamas-releases-all-remaining-israeli-hostages-in-gaza/105885332</link><description>Israel says Hamas has handed over all 20 living hostages in the first phase of the Israel-Gaza ceasefire agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1da4a5a9ff5c0b24b017021965f0b640</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Diamonds mindful they need to lift against New Zealand's Silver Ferns in Constellation Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/constellation-cup-australia-new-zealand-diamonds-silver-ferns/105885876</link><description>Despite the comfortable series win over South Africa, Australia is mindful it will need to step up a gear in the Constellation Cup against New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5fb5d579d17d83c75a2e69cee809c80</guid></item><item><title>How to help kids prepare for music exams and competitions and manage performance anxiety</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/music-exam-competition-manage-performance-anxiety/105873254</link><description>Music exams and competitions aren't easy, but our experts have some tips to make the process as stress-free as possible, including managing performance anxiety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ce54e25b952b97ee1ce5b2b5c2b6f1c</guid></item><item><title>Fresh doubts over plans to boost Perth's tree canopy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/fresh-doubts-over-plan-for-perth-tree-canopy/105886692</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eeff764a51281b1a24aecd32b078248f</guid></item><item><title>Six NRL players named in England rugby league Ashes sqaud, Man of Steel winner not selected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/six-nrl-players-named-in-england-rugby-league-ashes-sqaud/105887552</link><description>Six NRL players are in the England rugby league squad for the upcoming Ashes series against Australia, but there's no room for the most consistent player of the Super League season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78de8086dd1c502899a17e878f7658b2</guid></item><item><title>When to share the news of a pregnancy with your employer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/when-to-share-the-news-of-a-pregnancy-with-your-employer/105865350</link><description>Experts on the rules around when you need to inform your employer if you’re planning to take parental leave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdd7ceffb7b18af44c36f8079e6d9e03</guid></item><item><title>Abducted by Hamas, Noa never lost hope she would see her 'soulmate' again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/noa-argamani-avinatan-or-hamas-hostages-freed/105890692</link><description>Noa and Avinatan's abduction from a music festival became an enduring illustration of the horrors endured by Israelis on October 7. Now safely in each other's arms, a chapter has closed on a harrowing two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e795ebb238cdbebca7f0fd0bfe11d9d4</guid></item><item><title>Five takeaways from the ABC's Your Say: The Digital Dilemma forum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/abc-your-say-the-digital-dilemma-key-takeaways/105890184</link><description>An emotional plea to the country, concerns about privacy and how Australia's social media ban will actually work. These are the key takeaways from the ABC's Your Say: The Digital Dilemma forum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de6e80e7d191490fa6fdf7119bf8ab6e</guid></item><item><title>LNP government criticised over new 'jobs for mates' appointment of party powerbroker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/lnp-government-faces-new-jobs-for-mates-controversy/105885154</link><description>Queensland's Crisafulli government is embroiled in a new "jobs for mates" claim after it appointed a Liberal National Party powerbroker to oversee the state's lead agency for disaster recovery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c4a2974cdf74d5e986c5d44d0d027b3</guid></item><item><title>Powerhouse misses opportunity to get Melbourne-bound drums of Sydney's Midnight Oil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/sydneys-powerhouse-missed-out-on-midnight-oil-drums-hirst/105894330</link><description>Midnight Oil are Sydney rock royalty, but the drum kit that stuck with the band for more than 40 years is heading to a Melbourne music museum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77d8f6e30d82e4cfddfe3d8643cf4ad8</guid></item><item><title>When is the F1 US Grand Prix, how can I watch and who is battling for the championship?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/f1-us-grand-prix-what-time-how-to-watch-oscar-piastri/105614112</link><description>Formula 1 returns to the United States, officially marking the final quarter of an epic 2025 championship. Here is what is to come.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53bd31ae325a4d1a91c38ac12e6504cf</guid></item><item><title>How long does it take to acclimatise to a new place when the weather is very different?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/how-to-adjust-different-climates/105887794</link><description>Do our bodies actually acclimatise when moving from one climate to another and can we do anything to smooth the transition?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7b51651bfb1e6f2f7657bf344b2ebee</guid></item><item><title>CO2 emissions reached record high in 2024, World Meteorological Organization report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/co2-emissions-reached-record-high-in-2024-wmo-report-finds/105897180</link><description>The World Meteorological Organization says carbon dioxide levels in the atmosphere are increasing at rates that have tripled since the 1960s, and emissions from human activities and more wildfires have helped fan a "vicious climate cycle."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fe5ddc947f3b56d25680eb47317a921</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar military coup leader Michael Randrianirina 'taking the position of president'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/madagascar-military-leader-appoints-himself-president/105897228</link><description>Colonel Michael Randrianirina led a rebellion by soldiers that ousted President Andry Rajoelina after weeks of youth-led protests against the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1f046f647c3e9115cf381c09119bcda</guid></item><item><title>Australia sees opportunity in China-US rare earths dispute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/trump-albanese-xi-critical-minerals-us-china/105884214</link><description>Trump may have expressed "shock", but his administration is clearly not surprised at China's willingness to flex its dominance on rare earths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa98a5f162d3f58f6ff157adeeba8042</guid></item><item><title>Calvary Health Care questioned over Launceston private hospital's future after infrastructure failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/calvary-health-care-private-hospital-launceston-tasmania/105885816</link><description>Tasmanian healthcare experts are calling for assurances about the future of a private hospital in Launceston in the wake of a costly infrastructure failure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41f8500ececa20b4fc5acfda9bbdbc9e</guid></item><item><title>Nikon Small World photomicroscopy competition's top 15 images of 2025 capture our tiniest signs of life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/nikon-small-world-photomicrography-competition-2025-winners/105880892</link><description>Extreme close-ups of rice weevil, pollen in a spider's web and a geometer moth laying eggs are among this year's Nikon Small World competition entries from thousands of scientists and artists across the globe. Here are the judges' favourites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">422146c134220b9daaeb85e97181786b</guid></item><item><title>Soldier killed in vehicle rollover during army training in north Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/army-soldier-killed-in-vehicle-rollover-while-training/105897572</link><description>The Department of Defence says an Australian soldier has died after a single-vehicle rollover during training at the Australian Army's Townsville Field Training Area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9064921280d2988c8f1986804181b2f4</guid></item><item><title>R360 hits back at Australian Rugby League Commission's threat of 10-year bans for rebel players</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/arlc-nrl-r360-hits-back-at-ban-threats-for-players/105897732</link><description>The boss of R360 says threats of 10-year bans for NRL players who defect to the rebel competition are predictable, as the code war escalates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a507cb97abb406d1566b15b62aa13750</guid></item><item><title>First Nations artists warn against AI 'double colonisation' as Meta uses work for training</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/first-nations-creatives-warn-against-ai-double-colonisation/105889290</link><description>The rapid development of AI is testing the effectiveness of the Copyright Act, with creative and media industries calling for better protections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fc2ae378cfa0f6d485867eb2b770985</guid></item><item><title>Review: After the Hunt has noble ambitions but misses the mark</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/after-the-hunt-julia-roberts-review/105876254</link><description>The ingredients are all here — public scandal, duelling divas and unearthed secrets — but Luca Guadagnino's provocative drama misses the mark.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f67b806ed73e7ac77c9e5486230066b3</guid></item><item><title>Teddy Swims tells SXSW Sydney he uses AI when making music, but warns of its dangers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/teddy-swims-tells-sxsw-sydney-he-uses-ai-in-music/105897908</link><description>Grammy-nominated music artist Teddy Swims says AI is a "beautiful tool" when it comes to composing music. Swims was in conversation at SXSW Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dcc839da82c48def79030a917173b7e</guid></item><item><title>Tasma Walton and Robbie Arnott share $100,000 ARA Historical Novel Prize</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/tasma-walton-robbie-arnott-ara-historical-novel-prize-2025/105886334</link><description>Robbie Arnott's Dusk about twins hunting a puma in Tasmania, and Tasma Walton's I Am Nannertgarrook about an Aboriginal woman kidnapped and sold into slavery, have tied to win the ARA Historical Novel Prize.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36563ad06ad055a6eaead4a3f8596a89</guid></item><item><title>Government unveils a plan to combat South Australian algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/plan-to-combat-sa-algal-bloom/105900918</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb673ff2efdfdb07d4b825046c407370</guid></item><item><title>'Dangerously low' funding to Tasmanian arts sector creating reputational damage, minister warned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/tasmanian-arts-industry-highly-vulnerable-low-funding-investment/105899498</link><description>"Dangerously low" arts sector funding has rendered the Tasmanian industry "highly vulnerable", with funding stagnant since 2016-17, the state government has conceded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a29de7c4d5bc252c9a785dea93220878</guid></item><item><title>Drunken motorcyclist crashes with daughter riding as passenger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/drunken-motorcyclist-crashes-with-daughter-passenger/105898498</link><description>A Mildura father-of-six avoids jail after drunkenly crashing his motorbike while carrying his young daughter as a passenger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b7dbbdb3b9ed775f287c7490a9599c8</guid></item><item><title>Warnings for explicit deepfakes, 'image-based abuse' amid rise of AI technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/sydney-school-students-explicit-ai-images-investigation-police/105901372</link><description>A senior academic has warned a Sydney school caught up in an investigation into digitally altered explicit images of female students is just "another shocking iteration" of gendered violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9bb776a70b24518b0d2a82348f1046f</guid></item><item><title>BHP vs China Inc: What the iron ore dispute says about Australia's present and future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/what-bhp-china-iron-ore-dispute-means-to-australia/105901692</link><description>The resolution of negotiations between Australian mining giant BHP and China's state-backed iron ore buyer China Mineral Resources Group could reshape not just the resources industry, but also international trade flows, global markets, and the relationship between China and the West.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f17745151acc39e0b5f38368c4928c68</guid></item><item><title>From cult web series to cinema: Nirvanna the Band the Show the Movie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/nirvanna-the-band-the-show-the-movie/105898756</link><description>Canada's cult web series heads to the big screen, after creators Matt Johnson and Jay McCarrol were told they could make any movie they liked after their success with BlackBerry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcab9960bf8462cac061bee2cf98745a</guid></item><item><title>How a 15yo autistic boy tinkering in his bedroom triggered WA's biggest ever data breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/joshua-unwittingly-triggered-major-wa-health-data-breach-autism/105455250</link><description>Joshua's "passion project" with a radio scanner led to one of WA's most significant public health data breaches. His story highlights the challenges confronting autistic people caught up in the legal system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13c71de037de480416dd879b9c6eab51</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government seeks private market interest to develop riverside precinct in South Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/qld-riverfront-precinct-south-brisbane-private-sector/105902488</link><description>The government says construction could begin from March 2027 and has suggested the site could feature over 4,000 homes, as well as "event lawns" and promenades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71e510b6fa92de09ab4aec4b9b044d41</guid></item><item><title>'No doubt' Anthony Albanese and Donald Trump will discuss critical minerals: Chalmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/albanese-trump-chalmers-critical-minerals-deal/105903392</link><description>Anthony Albanese will "no doubt" use a meeting with Donald Trump next week to discuss critical minerals, the treasurer says as he dismisses a call for Australia to "decouple" with China over rare earth materials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fe4351ff10e966c7a84c8e260555fa8</guid></item><item><title>Ways to increase safety on a first date and red flags to watch for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/red-flags-on-first-date-safety-tips/105805388</link><description>Both people involved in a date are responsible for creating a safe environment, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f5f2638f6ee24d2f8b7347e8441dce8</guid></item><item><title>Endemic frog and gecko species identified on Dauan Island in Torres Strait</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/frog-gecko-species-found-dauan-torres-strait/105790146</link><description>Two new frog species and a banded-patterned gecko are believed to have sheltered among the boulders of Dauan, in the Torres Strait, for millions of years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02d7af04ef02838cbdfc93bff8ff13f8</guid></item><item><title>Wayne Swan steps down as Labor president urging party to focus on membership boost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/wayne-swan-labor-president-leaves-role-politics/105905064</link><description>Labor party president Wayne Swan will step down next July and has warned the ALP must boost membership if it is to survive into the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75e127f2e28c7f78ce730de287d98398</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew giving up his royal titles and honours after speaking with King Charles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/prince-andrew-to-give-up-royal-titles-and-honours/105907098</link><description>King Charles's brother has come under significant pressure after being linked to the late convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein and his ties to China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b88d507f6b73a3388229f325fd5168e</guid></item><item><title>Creating deepfakes has never been easier, so what should parents do?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/creating-deepfakes-is-easy-what-should-parents-do/105902982</link><description>Some parents may feel distressed and ill-equipped to tackle the issue of image-based abuse and deepfakes. This is what to watch out for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">136e26003e31a95432cd2b1c4b32704d</guid></item><item><title>Video appears to show March for Australia organiser coordinating with Neo-Nazi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/march-for-australia-organiser-coordinates-with-neo-nazi/105902754</link><description>A previously unreported video has emerged appearing to show a key March for Australia organiser coordinating with a Neo-Nazi at the first rally in Sydney in August, ABC NEWS Verify has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc104ef4e2d70260f456bb05e05b9a6c</guid></item><item><title>Administrative Review Tribunal swamped by surging demand, more than 100 members short</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/administrative-review-tribunal-overwhelmed-surging-demand/105893728</link><description>The Administrative Review Tribunal was set up to resolve issues with its predecessor, but has struggled with staffing and long wait times over its first year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fd2f156e95340a969daa8b6003273f1</guid></item><item><title>Education department admits not enough done to stop Dubbo College Delroy aide harming children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/systemic-failure-to-investigate-nsw-dubbo-school-staff/105807290</link><description>The NSW government says it should have taken allegations of wrongdoing by a male school staff member more seriously. That failure left those who reported it so isolated their mental health spiralled and never fully recovered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c22f6955d77c23cb8f7c088405ad508</guid></item><item><title>Benjamin Netanyahu's name prompted boos in Israel but is it a signal he has lost favour?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/benjamin-netanyahu-popularity-in-israel-in-spotlight/105903240</link><description>As the dust settles on the ceasefire and hostage exchange deal, the question arises as to whether the partial resolution could deliver Benjamin Netanyahu a bounce in the polls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3cc3003b8b28e951e730e5aa18bbb1f</guid></item><item><title>Water testing in the Murweh Shire returns negative for dangerous amoeba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/murweh-mayor-charleville-hospital-negative-water-testing-amoeba/105899494</link><description>South-west Queensland residents are questioning the detection of a dangerous amoeba at Queensland Health sites after all follow-up tests were negative.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f732b4b65ef2c9618812d9b472a6ce26</guid></item><item><title>As the Australian op shop turns 100, the legacy of Lady Millie Tallis lives on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/lady-millie-tallis-australian-op-shop-100-year-anniversary/105901846</link><description>One hundred years ago, showgirl-turned-philanthropist Millie Tallis spent weeks preparing for a major second-hand goods fundraiser in Melbourne, giving rise to the Australian op shop.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92ea4c4664694717607b7fd6c4bd9662</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Island wants more tourists but luggage is often left behind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/christmas-island-travellers-luggage-regularly-left-behind/105778992</link><description>On Christmas Island, locals are not surprised if tourists' checked baggage does not arrive with them. Fragile supply chains on the remote Indian Ocean island are a part of life in this unique community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf635fd57a7aedc3288c6869b3851e6d</guid></item><item><title>Hospital in the Home program helping young man with agoraphobia who 'cut himself off from the world'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/hospital-in-the-home-northwest-tasmania-mental-health/105789004</link><description>Tom French's agoraphobia meant he couldn't leave the house to access the mental health care he needed, but a Hospital in the Home program means the care is coming to him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1b964e8ba63ca42e36daf1af0d1b9c8</guid></item><item><title>Greek-inspired lamb kebabs with olive potatoes baked in the oven - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/easy-oven-baked-lamb-kebabs-with-olive-potatoes/105291672</link><description>The lamb is fuss-free and full of flavour. No barbecue needed — the oven takes care of everything.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97732d3bb23552f5f8a4e4e0fa75a14b</guid></item><item><title>Phoebe Litchfield learning from opening partner Alyssa Healy at Women's Cricket World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/phoebe-litchfield-alyssa-healy-womens-cricket-world-cup/105907312</link><description>Alyssa Healy has joined an elite band of women batters with 7,000 international runs, and Australia's captain is giving her brilliant young opening partner something to aim for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a50f38a0dacc4756881494b6edf4d5e</guid></item><item><title>Minister flags compulsory voting in local government elections, 4-year terms amid low voter turnout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/compulsory-voting-flagged-for-wa-local-government-election/105901804</link><description>Voting in council elections could become mandatory in Western Australia if the turnout for this weekend's poll continues to plummet, the local government minister warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90ce7dc5327df5d0b3904814e2638839</guid></item><item><title>Max Verstappen claims sprint pole ahead of Lando Norris and Oscar Piastri at US F1 Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/f1-max-verstappen-lando-norris-oscar-piastri-us-grand-prix/105907488</link><description>Max Verstappen topples McLaren pair Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris to claim pole position for the sprint race at the United States Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0aead0d7f508abc19c76aa70fab17de8</guid></item><item><title>A history of the Israeli settler movement in the Occupied Palestinian Territory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/israeli-settlers-rear-vision/105789284</link><description>Since October 7, tensions have been rising between Palestinians and Israeli settlers in the Occupied Palestinian Territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23198e502573622dd9f58f17a1d48075</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce hasn't quit the Nationals yet but he's got one foot out the door</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/speers-analysis-barnaby-joyce-has-not-quit-the-nationals-yet/105907744</link><description>In declaring he won't be recontesting his lower house seat and letting speculation run that he might jump ship for One Nation, Barnaby Joyce is declaring he's had enough with the Nationals under David Littleproud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f61bd6ea4984b1bc51fdcb3bae580b</guid></item><item><title>Jamie Melham creates Caulfield Cup history after riding Half Yours to victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/caulfield-cup-jamie-melham-makes-history-with-half-yours-win/105907872</link><description>Jamie Melham breaks new ground as the first female jockey to win the Caulfield Cup in its 149-year history, steering favourite Half Yours to victory in the $5 million handicap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">667ff62cf5c5a273ffd2a976a56004c6</guid></item><item><title>Israel identifies remains of 10th hostage handed over by Hamas as 76-year-old Eliyahu Margalit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/israel-10th-hostage-handback-identified-76yo-eliyahu-margalit/105907884</link><description>Eliyahu Margalit's body was found after two bulldozers ploughed up pits in the earth in the city of Khan Younis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1d5a64c472215dfc37dd3ae22ab51a6</guid></item><item><title>Nottingham Forest sack manager Ange Postecoglou immediately after loss to Chelsea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/ange-postecoglou-sacked-nottingham-forest/105908162</link><description>Nottingham Forest sacked the winless manager moments after their 3-0 defeat by Chelsea on Saturday local time, which left the club 17th in the standings and on the brink of slipping into the relegation zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57c551c6fd2ddff4af0d49de00cd0a77</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese is set to sit down with Donald Trump. What can he learn from other world leaders?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/anthony-albanese-sits-down-with-trump-what-can-he-learn/105894690</link><description>As other world leaders have discovered, a visit to Donald Trump's White House can become an unpredictable, if not uncomfortable, encounter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4b6d1356ae3c998aaee4553a3793db7</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew's decision to give up his titles may have been quietly orchestrated by members of his own family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/is-prince-andrews-decision-enough-to-stem-damage-to-monarchy/105907688</link><description>With the swirl of news around Prince Andrew this week, something had to be done; the question was whether he would do it himself or if his brother would be forced to show him the door.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b77456c907ef9b548850123a9b10fa3e</guid></item><item><title>BOM's first long-range summer forecast shows increased chance of extreme heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/bom-summer-weather-forecast-hot-and-dry-with-high-fire-risk/105899594</link><description>Hot nights coupled with high daytime temperatures could see Australia heading into an extremely hot summer, BOM's first long-range forecast indicates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f141a77feebbff9dd877f9c172a7d949</guid></item><item><title>After Ukraine, Finland hopes it won't be Putin's next target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/inside-finlands-preparations-for-russian-invasion/105859992</link><description>Blasted into the bedrock, deep below the streets of Helsinki, these massive bunkers are currently used for recreation. Their primary function, however, is much more sinister: preparing for a Russian invasion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3896c79d12d96bc2c66108ed2320d926</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz Kids: Who says trivia is just for grown-ups? It's time to put your thinking cap on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/hard-quiz-kids-weekly-trivia-tom-gleeson/105894882</link><description>Hard Quiz Kids is here again, and we're gifting you a bunch of straightforward questions. Don't embarrass yourself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eae196e3bd245bc87722d2b719e6f741</guid></item><item><title>China's 'special forces'-style tourists packing big itineraries in small budgets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/china-hong-kong-special-forces-style-travel-sleep-mcdonalds/105902602</link><description>Young Chinese tourists with limited time and money are travelling 'special forces'-style — inspired by the efficiency, endurance, and intensity of military units.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecc8983a388385cd9855eaf49fa6fe2b</guid></item><item><title>Aussie Bird Count brings together students, photographers and nature-lovers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/aussie-bird-count-students-volunteer/105903124</link><description>A primary school teacher is getting her students involved in a volunteer-led bird count, to gather a snapshot of birds across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1902614b6d2d117e4440091bf145ffb</guid></item><item><title>'No Kings' protest crowds gather across the US against Donald Trump's leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/no-kings-protests-across-us-against-donald-trump/105908510</link><description>Organisers say the rallies reflect frustration over the Trump administration's prosecutions of the president's perceived enemies, immigration raids and the sending of troops into US cities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">844c41c111bff92bc93ef28915c54a4f</guid></item><item><title>Julian Assange seeks 20-year jail term for David Morales, the Spaniard who spied on him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/julian-assange-suggested-sentence-for-david-morales/105908048</link><description>His lawyers suggested the jail term for David Morales, accused of discovery and disclosure of secrets, bribery, money laundering and illegal possession of weapons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d09193e99604a479bc0cc7a2da23e6e</guid></item><item><title>Sheffield Shield round two quick hits: Marnus Labuschagne confirms form ahead of Ashes, Scott Boland bullies and spinners offer reminder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/sheffield-shield-summary-marnus-labuschagne/105907142</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne's magical early season form continues with the bat, Scott Boland and a pair of spinners offer a reminder of their skill, while Sam Konstas turns on the flair at round two of the Sheffield Shield.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">054ff0d8e5945ea2d312a9468fd3278e</guid></item><item><title>Iconic house for sale for only second time in 193-year history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/iconic-house-for-sale-for-only-second-time-in-193-year-history/105838914</link><description>Classical musicians Richard and Suzy Miller count their circa-1832 home as one of their greatest creative achievements as they prepare to leave it for someone else to love.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0cb817277090afe4c3ee03c0a1fb2c2</guid></item><item><title>It's been called Canberra's 'forever government' — but ACT Labor's brand is growing tired</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/act-canberra-forever-government-but-labor-brand-growing-tired/105904332</link><description>It's been a year since Canberrans re-elected an ACT Labor government for a seventh consecutive term — but as budget pressures bite, analysts say Labor's stocks are suffering from brand fatigue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ee3cbb31b12feb0dbf9a314f57eeb6d</guid></item><item><title>Mike Hewson creates controversial children's playgrounds. Explore his latest creation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/mike-hewson-takes-kids-four-storeys-underground/105896640</link><description>This designer's "risky playgrounds" are often divisive. His latest is four storeys underground in a former World War II oil tank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5af465a6bbf0383d41c1060eddfa1af6</guid></item><item><title>Social media promotion of raw milk 'misleading and dangerous'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/raw-milk-trend-worries-experts/105636166</link><description>A public health expert says social media content creators are undermining years of scientific research by promoting raw milk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be479a18a9b8b5bd2c9c5515b5b11008</guid></item><item><title>Dodo and iPrimus hack impacts more than 1,600 home internet, email and mobile customers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/dodo-hack-impacts-internet-email-and-mobile-customers/105908674</link><description>More than 1,600 Dodo and iPrimus home internet and mobile customers were impacted by a hack of the telco's email and mobile services, the company confirms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2023f6e78d453f5b1767f6b78873787c</guid></item><item><title>US warns of 'imminent' Hamas attack on Palestinians in Gaza in potential ceasefire breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/hamas-hands-over-two-more-israeli-hostages-remains/105908710</link><description>The United States has received "credible reports" indicating an imminent violation by Hamas of the ceasefire with Israel in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b7efb1dc721bfd6d2e091b751007994</guid></item><item><title>National Disruption Group to be established to crush tobacco black market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/national-distruption-group-tobacco-black-market/105908764</link><description>A new "National Disruption Group" will be convened to stamp out the exploding illicit tobacco market and other "converging" threats, the home affairs minister has announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cc3bdda511d1e9aa7bb583dee35ef1e</guid></item><item><title>Five suspected rat poison cases detected in south-east Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/qld-rat-poisoning-symptoms-reported-to-hospitals/105908798</link><description>Queensland Health is investigating after five people were hospitalised with symptoms of ingesting rat poison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17e5b91d5e833fa2e54a07c383a89f60</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou's Nottingham Forest stint a classic case of wrong place, wrong time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/ange-postecoglou-nottingham-forest-wrong-team-brian-clough/105908712</link><description>Ange Postecolgou was on a hiding to nothing at Nottingham Forest, his sacking the result of terrible recruitment and a knee-jerk appointment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0adc426b55b3caeb01dc1561cdfadbc</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan and Afghanistan agree to immediate ceasefire after peace talks in Doha</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/pakistan-afghanistan-agree-to-immediate-ceasefire-doha-talks/105908852</link><description>A week of fierce border clashes has seen the worst violence between the two countries since the Taliban seized power in Kabul in 2021.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ae3ed5418e4616f7f9a9cc4b9feaba5</guid></item><item><title>'Green bans' saved Sydney's historic buildings and taught economists a lesson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/green-bans-sydney-1970s-unions-nimby-yimby-milton-friedman/105903850</link><description>The "green bans" in the 1970s saved many of Australia's historic buildings and our cities are richer for them. But a famous economist didn't like them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abdb337970b734f91db4e99387b96c1a</guid></item><item><title>Australian Para Triathlon mixed relay team seal silver at World Triathlon Championship Finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/paratriathlon-relay-seal-silver-at-world-championships/105908976</link><description>Australia's para triathlon mixed relay team sealed a successful week by claiming a sensational silver medal on the final morning of the World Triathlon Championship Finals in Wollongong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9b6a331ee8dec8a3f69255dcf628bf3</guid></item><item><title>Anti-immigration rallies and counter protests held across the country with lower numbers — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/march-for-australia-anti-immigration-counter-protest/105908854</link><description>Demonstrators gathered in cities across the country today, with March for Australia rallies sparking counter protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc46a6a077edb7895f0c0b99d9e04d87</guid></item><item><title>Mollie O'Callaghan crushes 200m short course world record as post-Titmus era begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/mollie-o-callaghan-crushes-200m-short-course-world-record/105909080</link><description>Mollie O'Callghan breaks the women's short course 200m freestyle world record on day two of the World Aquatics Swimming World Cup second leg in Illinois.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6231da4c79de0162d4eb6b705e6680d</guid></item><item><title>Trent Dalton's Boy Swallows Universe wins the Top 100 Books countdown — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/top-100-books-of-the-21st-century-radio-national-live-updates/105900036</link><description>Trent Dalton's debut novel Boy Swallows Universe has won Radio National's Top 100 Books of the 21st Century countdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a93d820be1134030d36a0450e5827bd4</guid></item><item><title>Missing bushwalker Daryl Fong's brother thanks crews as search continues in 'dangerous' conditions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/missing-bushwalker-daryl-fong-search-continues-mount-field/105909192</link><description>Rescue crews have faced challenging conditions in the search for Daryl Fong, who has been missing in Tasmania's Mount Field National Park since last Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79317a802b551f057750daca1b564099</guid></item><item><title>How Claire's decision to be 'one and done' was rocked by divorce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/how-claire-feels-about-being-one-and-done-after-divorce/105870074</link><description>After a traumatic birth, followed by mental and physical health challenges, Claire was "one and done". But divorce made her think twice about her decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c4071ab0f2b41bc5ba8af85bdc44b4</guid></item><item><title>Tiger snake slides over passenger's foot during a drive on NSW far south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/tiger-snake-encounter-passenger-narooma-rescue/105909112</link><description>A passenger in a car has the fright of his life when a tiger snake slithers across his feet during a drive on the NSW far south coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2664ddc2ecf35a9e1c24c1ee8681b6ac</guid></item><item><title>North Adelaide golf course safeguards fall short, some Kaurna community members say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/liv-golf-aboriginal-heritage-reaction/105908982</link><description>As the Malinauskas government proceeds with its $50 million North Adelaide golf course upgrade, some Kaurna elders are grappling with the prospect that the redevelopment could uncover Aboriginal remains.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9101d5e10e56032ae087ac48805699a</guid></item><item><title>The story of the 1970 West Gate Bridge disaster features in Melbourne Theatre Company's 2026 season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/melbourne-theatre-company-mtc-2026-season-anne-louise-sarks/105896178</link><description>The people impacted by Australia's worst industrial disaster are at the centre of West Gate by Dennis McIntosh, one of seven new Australian plays coming to Melbourne Theatre Company in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de0ad7e53c23dbee737f8a5d0098d29e</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Reynolds to remain City of Perth Lord Mayor as counting continues in WA local government elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/wa-local-government-election-results-perth-lord-mayor/105905464</link><description>Bruce Reynolds has held onto the title of City of Perth Lord Mayor, while early figures from WA's local government elections show voter turnout is below what authorities hoped for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a54bf02a0f8001516a58239517b18816</guid></item><item><title>Wadeye traditional owners say Yidiyi cultural festival brings community together as 'one family'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/wadeye-nt-yidiyi-festival-2025-brings-community-together/105908796</link><description>Traditional owners of the remote NT Aboriginal community of Wadeye say the community has been brought "together as one family" at this year's Yidiyi cultural festival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d233684dc20b0f2b15cd1d575b533874</guid></item><item><title>More than $6 million of cocaine and methylamphetamine seized during vehicle stop in southern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/highway-patrol-drug-haul-in-hay-nsw-vehicle-stop/105909462</link><description>Highway patrol stopped the black luxury SUV on a major New South Wales highway for a random drug and alcohol test on Friday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0b12cb731bfba08c1331b8020ab344b</guid></item><item><title>Bulldogs keep finals hopes alive with 66-point Suns trouncing, Lions and Tigers pick up wins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/aflw-bombers-lions-magpies-tigers-suns-bulldogs/105909452</link><description>The Western Bulldogs hammer Gold Coast by 66 points to keep their finals flame flickering, while Brisbane returns to the top four with victory over Essendon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">220f543ca713782ae1e2a21e7e2fa7c0</guid></item><item><title>Tensions erupt on Melbourne streets as opposing immigration rallies held across Australian capitals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/tensions-flare-melb-march-for-australia-anti-immigration-rallies/105908634</link><description>Two Victoria Police officers were hospitalised after violent clashes, while protesters were also arrested following scuffles in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0df5800a61965c627856a41a42a4d2f1</guid></item><item><title>Raúl Fernández wins Australian MotoGP as Jack Miller fails to finish</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/australian-motogp-raul-fernandez-wins-phillip-island/105909524</link><description>Raúl Fernández breaks through for his first MotoGP win, but Australian Jack Miller's race ends in agony at Phillip Island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c694a400ab3702b8a4fad7d55703dad</guid></item><item><title>Trent Dalton's Boy Swallows Universe wins Radio National's Top 100 Books of the 21st century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/top-100-books-trent-dalton-boy-swallows-universe/105872764</link><description>The results are in — Trent Dalton's Boy Swallows Universe has won Radio National's inaugural Top 100 Books of the 21st Century.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cef78d8d8b4ac4e460acf0badccc758</guid></item><item><title>Former March for Australia organiser shut down at latest anti-racism rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/march-for-australia-organiser-attends-anti-racism-rally/105909698</link><description>The organiser of the first March for Australia rally in Adelaide has distanced himself from that movement, attending a counter-protest on Sunday and declaring that "racism just has no place in Australia".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e621febcfc496a432f9bd8ab5fd8ff8</guid></item><item><title>Robbers armed with chainsaws steal jewellery from the Louvre Museum in Paris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/louvre-museum-in-paris-robbed/105909826</link><description>The Louvre said it was closing for the day "for exceptional reasons", but was not immediately available for comment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e953ebb539487579a0d2605ae291124</guid></item><item><title>Israel launches attack on Gaza after accusing Hamas of violating ceasefire, Israeli media reports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/israel-launches-air-strikes-on-gaza/105909902</link><description>An Israeli military official said on Sunday local time that Hamas had carried out multiple attacks against Israeli forces inside Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d50407ec9ae20783aa96b653d9624a8</guid></item></channel></rss>