<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 18:59:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EU 'optimistic' about breakthrough in free trade agreement negotiations with Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/australia-europe-free-trade-agreement-optimistic-negotiations/106034206</link><description>A breakthrough in long-stalled negotiations over a free trade deal between Australia and the European Union could come as soon as this weekend, sources have told the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e444a0ca255a016485ab328f707b1428</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106031650</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8e2fdcc5cd594466797ed720c24a798</guid></item><item><title>Tivoli Drive-In closes amid rising operating expenses and low attendance numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/qld-ipswich-tivoli-drive-in-closure/106033632</link><description>Rising expenses and poor weather are to blame for the closure of one of Queensland's last remaining drive-in cinemas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c187aa66aa3e495ef0457680fe61dc99</guid></item><item><title>Prominent neo-Nazi figure Joel Davis arrested in Sydney, group leader says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/nsw-neo-nazi-joel-davis-arrested-sydney-bondi/106034504</link><description>Joel Davis, who spoke at a rally outside NSW parliament earlier this month, was referred to the Australian Federal Police over a message about a Sydney MP.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">361915873f1da26ae2cef12d223efefd</guid></item><item><title>Commissioner for Aboriginal Children and Young People to resign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/ccyp-aboriginal-children-commissioner-resign/106034770</link><description>Commissioner Meena Singh will step down from her role on Friday after three and a half years in the job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43ea058e05ffe69393dc720b45c61768</guid></item><item><title>Coalition would back Labor's environment laws with 'sensible' amendments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/coalition-would-back-labors-environment-laws-with-amendments/106034196</link><description>The opposition has identified seven key areas where change would be required for the Coalition to support Labor's proposed reforms to the Environment Protection and Biodiversity Conservation Act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0726b07c2ced853a3fc984282d99880</guid></item><item><title>The US has a fresh plan to end Russia's war in Ukraine. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/what-is-the-new-ukraine-peace-plan-explained/106034920</link><description>European allies of Kyiv say "peace cannot be capitulation" as details of a new plan to end the Ukraine war emerge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca8c7a5f4d39c564ceaebe640714d156</guid></item><item><title>Trump floats death penalty for Democrats urging military to refuse illegal orders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/trump-floats-death-penalty-for-democrats-military-refuse-orders/106035314</link><description>Six Democratic politicians, all of whom are veterans, are urging members of the military not to obey unlawful orders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ccf85ac83f706c8ff037b6e03e9be2a</guid></item><item><title>How Elon Musk's Cybertruck dreams quickly went pear-shaped</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/today-in-history-november-21-cybertruck/106029340</link><description>Elon Musk hinted at his dream for a battery-electric pick-up truck for years before, finally, on November 21, 2019, Tesla unveiled a prototype for its Cybertruck.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8d304d1f0d001700bede354ae8fb5d6</guid></item><item><title>Our family made an emergency plan. Here’s how it went</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/emergency-plan-natural-disasters-here-is-how/106027454</link><description>I sat down with my family to make an emergency kit and an emergency plan. Here's how we did it and what we spent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73c0e54da54826bd427b79034f96a5ff</guid></item><item><title>US honours Republican titan Dick Cheney, while Donald Trump and JD Vance not invited</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/dick-cheney-funeral-trump-vance/106035422</link><description>Joe Biden, George Bush and every living former vice-president — Kamala Harris, Mike Pence, Al Gore and Dan Quayle — were in attendance, along with generals, foreign dignitaries and Supreme Court justices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cadd8f1ad1b71c816c55d49fc654798</guid></item><item><title>Virgin and Qantas to ban use of portable power banks after string of fires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/airlines-virgin-australia-qantas-ban-power-banks/106033982</link><description>Virgin Australia and Qantas will ban the use of portable power banks from next month following a string of international incidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd7768cb78f9615d22c938dc101aa79b</guid></item><item><title>How much will Tasmanians actually be paying for the stadium proposed for Hobart's Macquarie Point?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/macquarie-point-stadium-hobart-cost-questions/106033990</link><description>There are many questions still to be answered when it comes to how the stadium will be paid for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c5a1c38c81ca672b598e9b700203914</guid></item><item><title>How critical minerals power our daily lives from the moment we wake up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/how-critical-minerals-rare-earths-are-used-in-everyday-life/105980350</link><description>Take a tour around the house and see how everyday life is powered by critical minerals and why we will keep hearing so much about them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45cadb27240800c30df396aa4dbd11b8</guid></item><item><title>Bulk-billing rates flatline, despite billions tipped into Medicare</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/bulk-billing-rates-flatline-medicare-billions/106032104</link><description>Medicare figures quietly published online show bulk-billing has not improved from a year ago, despite billions being tipped into the scheme. As out-of-pocket costs rise, GPs are delivering 10,000 fewer services every day compared to last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbab951050ea668dba6ac2a335732595</guid></item><item><title>The pre-Ashes chatter has been predictable. The cricket will be anything but</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/the-pre-ashes-chatter-has-been-predictable-the-cricket-will-be-a/106018376</link><description>The build-up to this Ashes series has been long and often painful, but will quickly be forgotten when the first bowl is bowled and all hell breaks loose today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bac7a318debdb03545ba27ad44d8f627</guid></item><item><title>Australia's race to rewire the country amid a global transmission boom is not unique</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/transmission-line-projects-faces-massive-challenges/106029214</link><description>Countries across the globe are racing to rewire their electricity systems for a decarbonised future. In Australia, delays are mounting, along with doubts about whether it can meet goals on schedule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11696a7028bbd801d9aebbc02fd63d0c</guid></item><item><title>Alice Guo has been sentenced to life in prison for human trafficking in the Philippines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/alice-guo-sentenced-to-life-in-prison-for-human-trafficking/106035204</link><description>Former mayor Alice Guo has generated headlines for years in the Philippines. Now, her story might have come to an end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed42b75b8b91a94713b80ffa01c96f5b</guid></item><item><title>Inquiry demands 'immediate' supply of clean drinking water for Aboriginal community contaminated by PFAS</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/pfas-senate-report-wreck-bay/106031392</link><description>An elder in an Aboriginal community exposed to PFAS contamination says the town is proof of the health risks of "forever chemicals", as a federal inquiry recommends widespread testing to establish a link.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0a0899dc8843fe90fa548d84bcb2713</guid></item><item><title>Push for national approach to ADHD diagnoses as states forge different paths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/qld-adhd-diagnosis-national-body-needed-ranzcp-says/106033392</link><description>As ADHD diagnoses rise, Australia's peak body for psychiatrists is calling for a national system to monitor and stop potential over-diagnosis of the condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3447e68f9e5e1f4748726a1f78ee2b43</guid></item><item><title>Return of showers and storms as heatwave expands across Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/showers-storms-forecast-as-heatwave-builds-across-qld/106031810</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says storm activity, expected mainly about the southern border area, is not forecast to be as intense as in previous weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99256cda15582e10172cb863f0d77ace</guid></item><item><title>The COP result is a Goldilocks outcome for the Albanese government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/cop-outcome-a-goldilocks-result-for-australia/106034632</link><description>Türkiye is the big winner in the diplomatic stand-off over COP31, but nabbing the most powerful seat at the table while someone else picks up the lunch tab is not a bad result.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cf26563d300886f6f6d0480da10b1a3</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Coalition accuses Chris Bowen of being a 'part-time energy minister' — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/federal-politics-live-nov-21/106032654</link><description>The opposition leader has accused Chris Bowen of being a "part-time energy minister" after he stuck a deal to take up a negotiator role for COP31.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42244d569178680ff5c87fe15e239a53</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy says he is ready to work on US-backed plan to end war in Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/ukraine-ready-to-work-with-us-on-peace-plan/106035582</link><description>The White House says senior Trump administration officials have met Ukrainian officials in the past week to discuss the plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7dd88807391aae9d12f21c793e8e5e0</guid></item><item><title>The smell is so bad in Kalgoorlie-Boulder, residents have given it a name and launched a petition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/kalgoorlie-boulder-odour-continues-to-plague-residents/106023242</link><description>Kalgoorlie-Boulder residents launch a petition to have the city's wastewater treatment plant relocated as they continue to grapple with a smell so bad that some fear it will drive people away.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb27ddf0c2146692ae2b8905828f936f</guid></item><item><title>ASX in the red with DroneShield dropping almost 12 per cent — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/asx-markets-business-news-updates/106035662</link><description>"Wild" Wall Street sell-off triggers a sea of red on ASX. See how the trading day unfolded on our live blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfe50dd4c97a904be968d80ef748b82f</guid></item><item><title>Is Adelaide's stormwater contributing to the toxic algal bloom?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/is-adelaides-stormwater-contributing-to-the-toxic-algal-bloom/106025180</link><description>Adelaide's stormwater network has been discharging high loads of sediment into the Gulf of St Vincent for decades, killing off seagrasses that are a key defence against blooms of the kind wreaking havoc in South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56f3130528b745efa8d1130f1a86814f</guid></item><item><title>Former Stone Roses and Primal Scream bassist Gary 'Mani' Mounfield dies aged 63</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/stone-roses-bassist-gary-mounfield-dies/106035664</link><description>Mounfield was a member of the classic Stone Roses line-up for their 1989 self-titled debut album, which featured hits such as I Wanna Be Adored, She Bangs The Drums, and I Am The Resurrection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4630ed408a25aa9c5e120dc73358602f</guid></item><item><title>Ashes debutant Brendan Doggett becomes fifth Indigenous player to represent Australia in Test cricket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/brendan-doggett-indigenous-australian-test-player-ashes/106023988</link><description>When Brendan Doggett receives his cap today, he joins the sparse ranks of Indigenous Australian Test players.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13a6793390c083ac93e1de32f02022f8</guid></item><item><title>Industrial hemp crop trial gives new hope for Australian industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/australian-hemp-industry-trial-opens-door-more-planting/106021526</link><description>A trial showing industrial hemp can be grown year-round has farmers excited about the crop's "huge" potential.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60cc4dacbc274f690ad78f41cc81b2c4</guid></item><item><title>Rules meant to protect endangered gliders increase risk of localised extinction, scientists say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/environment-groups-decry-greater-glider-survey-results/106017274</link><description>New data points to the "systemic" under-reporting of greater glider dens within areas earmarked for logging in NSW, which scientists say could result in localised extinctions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c61552b4ab799ca6a5be5eb0e7fbee2f</guid></item><item><title>Mary Fowler's racism allegation denied by French football club Montpellier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/football-mary-fowler-racism-allegation-denied-by-monpellier/106035736</link><description>Montpellier responds to racism allegations made by Matildas forward Mary Fowler, who says a teammate gave her bananas as a departing gift in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95d35bc02368a27f9902fe883011efc9</guid></item><item><title>Perth GP gave patient’s confidential medical records to ex-partner despite domestic violence concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/perth-doctor-suspended-for-patient-confidentiality-breach/106034508</link><description>A Perth doctor is suspended after disclosing confidential medical information about a patient and her baby to her estranged husband, despite knowing there was a domestic violence restraining order against him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10c91ed64fff1aa9bf139431611fe1dc</guid></item><item><title>NT Corrections announces new approach to prisoner rehabilitation in shift 'from crisis to reform'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/nt-corrections-announces-new-plan-on-prisoner-rehabilitation/106025510</link><description>The officials who manage the Northern Territory's prison system say a new framework will replace a "fragmented" rehabilitation model that was not based on evidence, as the department moves "from crisis to reform".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4164425feb50f571a204902d42feede</guid></item><item><title>Olympic gold medalist Kyle Chalmers visits Broken Hill for How's Ya Mate mental health program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/kyle-chalmers-visits-broken-hill-for-lifeline-hows-ya-mate/106032250</link><description>Olympic gold medal-winning swimmer Kyle Chalmers is inspiring young and aspiring athletes, and speaking about the importance of mental health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2509bf6a03aac25255df6768cbd5ba46</guid></item><item><title>How Melbourne's journey to the preliminary final was forged in the fires of 2024</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/aflw-melbourne-demons-north-melbourne-kangaroos/106029864</link><description>Melbourne was pushed to its limit during a horror 2024 season but the pain gleamed from that difficult campaign has formed the basis of its return for another preliminary final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">312eadfa6066074ba448c7d29173de53</guid></item><item><title>Coloured sand for sale on eBay Australia removed days after asbestos contamination recall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/coloured-sand-product-for-sale-on-ebay-after-asbestos-recall/106029476</link><description>The online retail platform eBay Australia tells the ABC it uses artificial intelligence to stay informed of product recalls and to flag items that may be subject to a notice so they can be removed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2016b5699e4b79e181d73431c419e8b</guid></item><item><title>Matildas star Ellie Carpenter scores stunner in Chelsea's 1-1 draw with Barcelona</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/ellie-carpenter-scores-for-chelsea-vs-barcelona-champions-league/106035954</link><description>In a player-of-the-match performance, Ellie Carpenter sends Chelsea fans into a frenzy with a brilliant goal against European heavyweights Barcelona.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88ac3c81d4a3e87619160dbb15fef828</guid></item><item><title>NT cattle rustler fined almost $430k for stealing 116 head from neighbouring station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/nt-cattle-rustler-nicolas-kostowski-fined-430k/106032226</link><description>Nicolas Kostowski is ordered to pay hundreds of thousands of dollars in compensation after pleading guilty to stealing 116 cattle from a neighbouring property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0785dae5d1aa37bba26ea11e033d8122</guid></item><item><title>Tobacco retailers in the Riverina and Illawarra issued 90-day bans for illegal sales</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/illegal-tobacco-retailers-issued-90-day-bans-in-nsw/106036030</link><description>Shopfronts were plastered with yellow closure orders this week by the Chief Health Officer, alerting the public to breaches of new laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ed98903a2b8a85fad78114957be03f3</guid></item><item><title>Streaming platform Twitch to be included in under 16s social media ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/twitch-included-in-under-16s-social-media-ban/106036398</link><description>Less than three weeks out from when the ban is due to come into force, the eSafety Commissioner revealed the platform would join the list of age-restricted social media sites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff615635751f2a47946b7c35b49b446d</guid></item><item><title>Green shoots bring hope after bushfires in the Grampians (Gariwerd) National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/grampians-gariwerd-fire-recovery-conservation-climate-change/105997720</link><description>New growth is sprouting in the fire-ravished Grampians (Gariwerd) National Park, but an ecologist fears for the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">149e8962ff35c04bcfeaa0779a60651e</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Ben Stokes takes five-wicket haul as 19 wickets fall on day one of Perth Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/ashes-first-test-day-one-australia-england-perth-stadium/106036896</link><description>England captain Ben Stokes takes five late wickets as both batting line-ups fall to pieces on a frantic first day of the opening Ashes Test in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4fbce9441218f29a85df845829a8f22</guid></item><item><title>Money laundering network helping to fund Russia's war against Ukraine uncovered in the UK, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/uk-discovers-money-laundering-network-funding-russia/106036708</link><description>Britain's National Crime Agency says criminal cash has been funnelled through a bank in Kyrgyzstan, then on to Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">caa8b5de421ce3e81f82353c2dbc77fe</guid></item><item><title>Disco proves a safe space for disability community in regional Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/discobility-in-dalby-gives-space-for-disability-community/106029100</link><description>Sean Pocock says he is still learning after 10 years of providing a space for people with disabilities to dance and socialise in a welcoming environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edd7fffa7c3636eea2ae96ab3520415f</guid></item><item><title>Paul Kelly covers Kylie Minogue in his return to triple j’s Like A Version</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/paul-kelly-covers-kylie-minogue-triple-j-like-a-version/106036408</link><description>Nearly 20 years on from his debut on triple j's long-running covers segment, Paul Kelly and his trusty band take on Australia's queen of pop for their Like A Version comeback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecda913a645bdc41ca44b693c5257919</guid></item><item><title>'Buying the dip has become a dangerous sport' as nervous global share markets dive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/tech-bubble-asx-nasdaq-dow-jones-sell-off-japanese-bonds/106036078</link><description>Global markets are nervous after more than $3.1 trillion was wiped off Wall Street last night in a matter of hours, with Australia's ASX following suit today. So, what's behind the dip, and do analysts expect it to continue?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55df200f7f3cc8e877ef7400577d9f9b</guid></item><item><title>Japan's new PM said the quiet part out loud on Taiwan and unleashed Beijing's fury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/the-china-japan-diplomatic-row/106031582</link><description>China was already wary about Japan's new Prime Minister, Sanae Takaichi, a renowned Beijing hawk, before she weighed in on one of its most sensitive issues: Taiwan. Now it's unleashing economic pain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d997c481c4dbf5f57e30316ee0e92984</guid></item><item><title>Practice for F1 Las Vegas Grand Prix stopped twice, drivers unable to show true pace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/f1-las-vegas-grand-prix-practice-oscar-piastri-lando-norris/106032050</link><description>Oscar Piastri has not been able to show his true pace in Las Vegas, with the second practice session on Friday being cut short for "track maintenance".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75e1367c1f7e3a7282e633955f95a79b</guid></item><item><title>Chadwick Boseman, late star of Marvel's Black Panther, honoured with posthumous star on Hollywood Walk of Fame</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/hollywood-walk-of-fame-star-for-chadwick-boseman/106036630</link><description>Boseman, who played T'Challa in Marvel's Black Panther, died in 2020 at the age of 43 from colon cancer, which had been diagnosed previously.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98053f919bd140521593353dd3d87f15</guid></item><item><title>Planned update to new Bureau of Meteorology website delayed by Tropical Cyclone Fina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/update-to-new-bureau-of-meteorology-website-delayed-cyclone/106036366</link><description>The first major update to the maligned, redesigned Bureau of Meteorology website has been delayed by Cyclone Fina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a68098dc69577d31aeb683af6a51ef2f</guid></item><item><title>Man who caused Melbourne CBD evacuation jailed over 'homemade napalm' bombs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/melbourne-cbd-steven-mauldon-homemade-napalm-jailed/106037452</link><description>A bombmaker who created "homemade napalm" and whose arrest led to evacuations in Melbourne's CBD has been jailed for eight years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d6f2d2d38eede5d5ff299e1611edc93</guid></item><item><title>Republican who called eSafety head a 'zealot' persists with call to testify</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/jim-jordan-calling-esafety-commissioner-testify-congress/106035836</link><description>The powerful chair of a United States congressional committee who called in the head of Australia's internet regulator to testify before US Congress says he does not think foreign governments should be telling America about its "First Amendment liberties".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b6294e113e24a2f30a814df238094e0</guid></item><item><title>Several residents across the Goldfields town heard a large 'bang'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/residents-across-the-goldfields-town-heard-a-large-bang-/106037308</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">114172ab12a99a7cb7576ede7d55b1a3</guid></item><item><title>A bang was heard as a meteor flashed across Kalgoorlie-Boulder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/a-bang-was-heard-as-a-meteor-flashed-across-kalgoorlie-boulder/106036996</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">255668d9fe6ed1e4551f775682b69781</guid></item><item><title>'Big bang' over Kalgoorlie believed to be a meteor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/-big-bang-over-kalgoorlie-believed-to-be-a-meteor/106036316</link><description>A loud bang was heard in Kalgoorlie-Boulder on Thursday evening as a light quickly flashed across the sky.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8376606ba1e5a10bd2d998a1bd087ce6</guid></item><item><title>Pint-sized granny becomes face of Yandaran Hotel and a social media sensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/granny-becomes-face-of-yandaran-hotel-and-social-media-star/106018200</link><description>A pint-sized, pint-pouring granny becomes a social media star and the face of a country pub, as she adjusts from nursing to life behind the bar alongside her daughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4a36b1fb01a341a09e9696b770b1800</guid></item><item><title>Frida Kahlo painting sets new auction record for female artists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/frida-kahlo-painting-auctions-new-york/106037402</link><description>Mexican artist Frida Kahlo has become the most expensive female artist at auction, after her El sueno (la cama) painting sold for $US56 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbcadaae83f4c273f46ea0094d606584</guid></item><item><title>Dozens of birds killed in suspected poisoning attack on the Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/dozens-birds-killed-in-suspected-poisoning-attack-gold-coast/106036640</link><description>Animal rescue group WIRES says its concerned about dogs and children who use the park after more than 30 birds were found dead from a suspected poisoning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a9f4f337c85aa77b1602468b45e6bd0</guid></item><item><title>Star Entertainment $300 million rescue package approved by regulators</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/star-entertainment-us-rescue-deal-approved/106036192</link><description>Under the deal, two US-based companies will own more than half of the embattled casino operator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">058b8b01e17fb296cd8c3a4ce2233152</guid></item><item><title>Varroa mite detected at Salt Creek, South Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/varroa-mite-detected-at-salt-creek-south-australia/106038292</link><description>The deadly bee parasite has been detected in South Australia again — this time in the state's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd88c91f40ac1f74bb86099ffe76d6a6</guid></item><item><title>Murrumbidgee Local Health District to explore providing surgical abortions at Wagga Base Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/mlhd-surgical-abortion-investigation/106036264</link><description>The Murrumbidgee Local Health District is exploring expanding reproductive health services so surgical abortions are available across a quarter of a million people in southern NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16635eefb63a20a2c4a78fe296152295</guid></item><item><title>WA musician Guy Ghouse dies, aged 56, after cancer battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/wa-musician-guy-ghouse-dies/106038466</link><description>Western Australian musician Guy Ghouse dies at the age of 56 after a two year battle with cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">824e49589943507835a27382b32e3b68</guid></item><item><title>Health network boss apologises to Adelaide woman for spine surgery delays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/adelaide-woman-surgery-delayed-several-times/106037320</link><description>An Adelaide woman says her elective surgery has been cancelled four times in the past few months as SA Health data shows nearly 25,000 people are waiting for elective surgeries across the state's public hospitals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de961a220fe541b33b9f887395c3c3f5</guid></item><item><title>Man charged over theft of car with sleeping child inside</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/victoria-police-shepparton-arrest-car-theft-child-inside/106038384</link><description>Victorian police have charged a man over the theft of a vehicle that had a sleeping toddler inside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a754bf473501bf7956e11e4f952223ef</guid></item><item><title>Fuel tanker racing to unload in Darwin ahead of Tropical Cyclone Fina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/fuel-tanker-rushed-to-darwin-port-tropical-cyclone-fina/106038374</link><description>A fuel tanker is racing to unload diesel for the Northern Territory as Cyclone Fina approaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14fc48b7edb81b3f02a9fb25b272d4e9</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide Crows take Brisbane Lions dual-premiership player Callum Ah Chee in pre-season draft</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/crows-land-flag-star-as-players-earn-afl-lifelines/106038614</link><description>Adelaide could not satisfy Brisbane in the AFL trade negotiations for Callum Ah Chee, but finally land the target through the pre-season draft.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">836b4b154e533478ca59115ff76fa111</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106039014</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec7320653531f18520793dca08f3497e</guid></item><item><title>Report finds $200 billion of Chinese credit pumped into Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/aiddata-report-chinese-loans-credit-australia/106033062</link><description>A new study has revealed the scale of China's lending for projects and activities in Australia, with money poured into everything from tollways to supermarkets, wind farms and breweries — but mostly mining projects.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e0eaad8eeb22c51811587ce984c5ff1</guid></item><item><title>WA government commits further $147 million for new youth detention centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/wa-government-commits-147-million-new-wa-youth-detention-centre/106037134</link><description>The WA government pledges a further $147 million to fund the construction of a new youth detention centre in Perth to replace the notorious Unit 18.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5330aa8e3bbd61d6ac277b17c6e7e16a</guid></item><item><title>Mitchell Starc registers career-best figures as England's 'unacceptable' batting style backfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/cricket-mitchell-starc-seven-wickets-england-batting-woes-ashes/106038948</link><description>Mitchell Starc turns it on in the absence of Pat Cummins and Josh Hazlewood, as England's aggressive approach with the bat backfires spectacularly after Ben Stokes won the toss in the first Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bf31ead6371b4accd2ece154ed475cb</guid></item><item><title>Waste from Perth set to be trucked out to York after WA minister approves landfill site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/york-landfill-environment-minister-approved-community-angry/106036564</link><description>The Western Australian environment minister has approved a new landfill site which will hold millions of cubic metres of waste trucked from Perth to a property near York.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb532a63f7a3d2d22067d7eb59e9a4a4</guid></item><item><title>Former Reform UK politician Nathan Gill jailed for taking bribes from pro-Russians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/uk-politician-sentenced-over-10-years-for-pro-russia-bribes/106039806</link><description>Nathan Gill, a hard-right British former politician and one-time ally of Reform UK leader Nigel Farage, pleaded guilty earlier to eight counts of bribery between December 2018 and July 2019.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bd4e0d144cf51f7bd540834ceb2204c</guid></item><item><title>Toy Story turns 30: How Pixar's animated buddy comedy went to infinity and beyond</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/toy-story-celebrates-30th-anniversary/106017068</link><description>Toy Story made history as the world's first computer-animated feature film. As it celebrates 30 years, we look back on the cinematic hit that sparked a technological revolution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3f2f1235e8b1298ef7e8e402535c7b1</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy says Ukraine faces choice of losing dignity or US backing, Trump gives a week for decision</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/volodymyr-zelesnkyy-says-us-peace-plan-difficult-choice-ukraine/106039966</link><description>In a sombre address to Ukraine's citizens, the president vowed he would not betray Ukrainian interests in the US-led peace process.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96603e61743332ef8a2726f1ef7dbe13</guid></item><item><title>Coalition fends off One Nation as another Labor minister takes one for the team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/liberals-sussan-ley-one-nation-coalition-nationls-chris-bowen/106026490</link><description>Labor is trying to keep a low profile while the opposition fends off One Nation and Sussan Ley fights for her job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9f62e1065a506c37be593d430b2ea01</guid></item><item><title>Europe invests in military while Trump spruiks Ukraine 'peace plan'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/donald-trump-saudi-arabia-israel-ukraine-weapons-europe/106026496</link><description>Europe is pouring resources into military production and coordination which will impact its agency as well as that of the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">221132ee5a8cc3652cdbb6a6547afabb</guid></item><item><title>Behind the testimonials selling leg-lengthening surgery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/behind-the-testimonials-selling-leg-lengthening-surgery/105941950</link><description>Videos spruiking limb-lengthening are targeting the insecurities of young men, promising the luxury of height. The bone-breaking surgery comes with huge risks, and some botched procedures are being fixed in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a7b9af2a96dd953ddff5d9b706bf6f1</guid></item><item><title>Australia cops ominous Ashes warning as England responds to Mitchell Starc's excellence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/starc-reaches-new-heights-but-australia-cops-ashes-warning/106037798</link><description>Mitchell Starc's career-best day had Australia on track for a dream Ashes opening, only for England to offer back an ominous warning for the series ahead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3cf7b37c36c599fa3bcdbcd18af89ca</guid></item><item><title>Away from COP30 and treaties, pragmatism sparks clean energy boom in the global south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/the-global-south-drives-the-energy-transition/106022814</link><description>Unshackled from legacy fossil fuel interests, the world’s clean energy future is being forged in the bustling cities of the global south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">916400558363f7adbb5ec1769622adcc</guid></item><item><title>Critically endangered orchid thrives as NSW Mid North Coast cemetery provides habitat refuge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/endangered-plants-thrive-in-cemeteries/105980820</link><description>Australian cemeteries have become a safe haven for flora and fauna affected by urban expansion, including a rare orchid unique to a small patch of the NSW Mid North Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">584d8e5910f911033672eb0cdce785b4</guid></item><item><title>Bumpy's debut album Kanana connects country, language and cultural responsibility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/bumpy-kanana-debut-album-noongar-language-culture-country/106017142</link><description>Connecting language and country with culture and community, Bumpy's beautiful debut album is closing the gap through music.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d59ddf50bbf31d5ad10fad173ce87eda</guid></item><item><title>Wild weekend of weather for Australia includes cyclone, severe storms and record heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/australia-wild-weather-brings-cyclone-storms-record-heatwave/106037818</link><description>Three major weather events are unfolding across Australia this weekend, with the assortment of intense weather set to impact several capitals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4c6f5f4059c5f8da6a8781930221c97</guid></item><item><title>TC Fina tracker map: Where is the tropical cyclone Fina now?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/story-lab-cyclone-fina-path-tracker-map/106032760</link><description>Tropical Cyclone Fina has intensified to a category three system with 100km/h winds recorded at Darwin Airport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af8570c2ea529fcbc515aa17f9cab023</guid></item><item><title>Severe Tropical Cyclone Fina could impact Darwin today with extreme weather conditions. Here's what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/tropical-cyclone-fina-northern-territory-darwin-weather-forecast/106036324</link><description>Severe Tropical Cyclone Fina is approaching north of Darwin today, bringing with it some extreme weather conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a6cd01600f308ae9de0c90e74152140</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Fina updates: Storm intensifies to category three system as it moves away from Darwin— as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/tropical-cyclone-fina-live-blog-saturday-november-22/106038950</link><description>Tropical Cyclone Fina intensifies to a category three system as it moves away from Darwin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cbe8a7bce838c5311fb58dcd8ac02ba</guid></item><item><title>Rare parma wallabies moved to predator-free zones after 50 years in Blue Mountains sanctuary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/rare-parma-wallabies-moved-to-predator-free-zones/106024162</link><description>The parma wallaby was thought to be extinct until Peter Pigott followed up on a rumour that a 19th century governor took a bunch of the mammals to New Zealand proved to be true.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c1cf5ac53ba419affc9469dbe21e4be</guid></item><item><title>Parma Wallabies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/parma-wallabies/106033944</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab8d9945b922fb13c6f8a58ee0ab31b8</guid></item><item><title>English Premier League to introduce spending cap in 2026/27 season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/football-england-premier-league-to-introduce-spending-cap/106040116</link><description>Premier League clubs agree to the establishment of spending caps in England's top flight, beginning in the 2026/27 campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50759ada23a292eca7de0cb4be0b6725</guid></item><item><title>Families of Wieambilla ambush victims say they are 'disappointed' by coronial inquest findings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/qld-wieambilla-findings-family-reactions-disappointed-by-inquest/106038136</link><description>The families of constables Matthew Arnold and Rachel McCrow, who died along with neighbour Alan Dare at the deadly 2022 ambush, had hoped for more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">344045dac841c0f223a7aa03ace96802</guid></item><item><title>First Hike Project helps refugees experience hiking in Australia's bushland for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/first-hike-project-welcome-refugees-/106005500</link><description>A community-led hiking program is introducing migrants to the bush, offering moments of connection, discovery and, for some, a sense of safety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">754bc926cb95778f43be1cf78cb173e1</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump praises Zohran Mamdani after cordial White House meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/zohran-mamdani-donald-trump-meet-white-house/106040052</link><description>The US president and New York's mayor-elect present a united front at a warm and friendly press conference, even as reporters ask about their stark ideological differences and past attacks on one another.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5567d5a1487883d6aabd57350ea43851</guid></item><item><title>Australian doctors visit rare PNG conjoined twins to assess options</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/sydney-doctors-to-try-help-separate-png-conjoined-twins/106039510</link><description>A team of specialised doctors from Sydney has flown to Papua New Guinea to determine whether a rare set of conjoined twins can be surgically separated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">293cb440b96ff9fb5f3c2f3aed2618dc</guid></item><item><title>Fake digital IDs pose new challenge for pubs and clubs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/digital-fake-ids-on-the-rise-queensland/105958526</link><description>Once a one-off occurrence, publicans are now reporting "multiple per week" fake IDs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">012e2e1c8807fc4aceaf3d189bf9d7ae</guid></item><item><title>Italy reaches Davis Cup final after defeating Belgium in Bologna semi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/davis-cup-italy-defeats-belgium-to-reach-final/106040142</link><description>Italy's Flavio Cobolli shows class in comforting his Belgian opponent Zizou Bergs following a dramatic Davis Cup semifinal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c6792c2a01bfad53ff8ba1428f13dd0</guid></item><item><title>16yo one of two people charged after shots fired at home in Bossley Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/bossley-park-shooting-two-charged-sydney-south-west/106040206</link><description>Police were called to a home in Bossley Park on Friday morning after reports of a public place shooting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8436786340e789073378afcac3ca43c</guid></item><item><title>Woman's miscarriage and stillbirth prompt 900km walk to raise awareness and money for cuddle cots</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/miscarriage-and-stillbirth-grief-family-wants-to-support-others/106030842</link><description>Sasha Barton has lived though the grief of losing two babies. She wants others to know they are not alone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba1c4a3b787c5be0e5f969a569980126</guid></item><item><title>Recall notice issued for deli meat products over listeria contamination risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/deli-meats-recalled-over-listeria-cotamination-risk/106040268</link><description>Multiple deli meat products sold in two Australian states have been recalled over fears of possible listeria contamination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">785f2cbcecd84f0f1b034884d876dea4</guid></item><item><title>Port Hedland buyback scheme to end in weeks as more than 100 houses remain unsold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/port-hedland-dust-buyback-scheme-to-close-in-weeks/106032006</link><description>The West Australian government is hailing its buyback scheme for houses coated in dust in Port Hedland as a success. But with more than 100 homes still not sold back, some residents are not making plans to leave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c03f56f4130c09c04df2ea4ff47c88b</guid></item><item><title>WA school leavers warned of sexually transmitted infection increase as celebrations begin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/sexual-health-sti-chlamydia-warning-as-wa-leavers-begins/106036370</link><description>Health authorities warn WA school leavers to be aware of an increase in sexually transmitted infections as they embark on end-of-school celebrations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8626a9efee2a645ad27febb51aa7fef1</guid></item><item><title>Severe heatwave hits parts of Queensland, with more scorching days ahead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/heat-warning-cairns-hinterland-north-west/106040270</link><description>Large parts of Queensland are expected to swelter under extreme and severe heatwave conditions, with temperatures soaring across much of the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5d9d9cadb1342de7f0a3026a61e4ab9</guid></item><item><title>Authorities look to underworld for answers after massive illegal rubbish dump sparks outcry in England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/rubbish-mountain-in-england-sparks-outcry/106025532</link><description>British authorities are scrambling to work out how an estimated 100 tonnes of garbage could be dumped in plane sight, and they're looking to the underworld for answers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af3c043c7db5a9c88ee488cae0ef54a8</guid></item><item><title>An illegal rubbish dump in Oxfordshire has sparked outrage among Brits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/drone-vision-rubbish-pile-oxfordshire/106039012</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63760c9acd10c799f3f0e2ef4f2c11cb</guid></item><item><title>High-profile Republican Marjorie Taylor Greene to resign after fallout with Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/marjorie-taylor-greene-resigns-after-trump-fallout/106040468</link><description>Republican Marjorie Taylor Greene, a longtime ally of Donald Trump who recently had a dramatic falling out with the president, has announced she is resigning from Congress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc12260ef848bfe1e72d8da74a5366fd</guid></item><item><title>WA artist Lori Pensini captures the human toll of drought in the South West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/wa-artist-captures-toll-drought-south-west/106017074</link><description>When dams dried up and livestock struggled, farmer and artist Lori Pensini turned the season into an award-winning painting — revealing the toll of the drought and the strength of her rural community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">222d9581a10c19b2567bf232fdaceb65</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Travis Head scores century, Australia chases 205 to win first Test against England in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/ashes-test-live-australia-england-perth-stadium/106040490</link><description>Travis Head, promoted to open after Usman Khawaja suffered a back injury, scores a magical century in just 69 balls to lead Australia to a famous first-Test victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c6577d24fb713d2827118dcaef01b87</guid></item><item><title>Death toll rises to 41 in central Vietnam flooding, more heavy rain forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/vietnam-floods-death-toll-rises-to-41-more-rain-forecast/106040388</link><description>More than 1.5 metres of rain has fallen in parts of Vietnam and authorities have warned of further floods with heavy rains set to continue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7faa6b4b9b7a60977621d0df4319602a</guid></item><item><title>Boys' netball movement gains pace on Sunshine Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/sunshine-coast-all-boys-netball-competition/105867122</link><description>From regional Queensland to state level, boys' netball is gaining momentum and reshaping the future of the sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6163db43d0ecb3dc1cb9bd8e17a7ebb</guid></item><item><title>'Sorry New Zealand, love you': The record number of Kiwis leaving the country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/kiwi-exodus-record-number-leave-new-zealand/106037238</link><description>Max was earning more as a dishwasher in Australia than as a university-qualified environmental monitoring technician back home in New Zealand. He is among a record number of people leaving the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33b7dc172ace2335a1e938614a93d82f</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Fina moves towards Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/cyclone-fina-moves-towards-darwin-/106040590</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6432e3acf46fb099839bcc8c05837404</guid></item><item><title>RFK Jr says he personally directed CDC's new guidance on vaccines and autism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/rfk-jr-says-he-directed-cdc-on-vaccines-and-autism/106040486</link><description>The change has surprised staff and contradicts the US Health Department's long-held scientific consensus that vaccines don't cause autism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9da80fe50aad05af9cb0fb8595abebcc</guid></item><item><title>Chinese dating show If You Are the One returns to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/nolm-if-you-are-the-one-australia/106036970</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18c307959f9038a9392c9092c0922257</guid></item><item><title>China's hit dating show If You Are the One recruits talent in Australia and faces new challenges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/china-dating-show-if-you-are-the-one-recruits-in-australia/106021564</link><description>Long-running global hit If You Are the One returns to Australia to recruit contestants from a younger generation, many who do not prioritise marriage. Here is why the show is still relevant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">364157543b73787ef524864ff46aa30e</guid></item><item><title>Zoe Terakes reclaims queer love in ancient Greek myths in debut short story collection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/zoe-terakes-book-eros-queer-myths-for-lovers/106017590</link><description>Zoe Terakes, star of Wentworth and Ironheart, has added another string to her bow, publishing a collection of short stories inspired by ancient tales — with a queer twist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80300b1df26488820c836bd47909c683</guid></item><item><title>Lando Norris claims pole position in Las Vegas as Oscar Piastri qualifies in fifth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/f1-las-vegas-piastri-norris-qualifying-positions/106040926</link><description>Lando Norris has stormed into pole position for the Las Vegas Grand Prix with teammate and championship rival Oscar Piastri to start in fifth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4348875f81454c3449d17ffd7211b256</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne move to brink of back-to-back AFLW titles with comeback win over Demons</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/aflw-roos-demons-prelim-grand-final/106040956</link><description>After surviving some nervous moments, North Melbourne have progressed to another grand final courtesy of a narrow prelim win over the Demons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4162b019d0ff4ebbb28ad54c87a8731</guid></item><item><title>Ashes engulfed by fresh DRS controversy as TV umpire gives Jamie Smith out despite RTS 'murmur'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/cricket-drs-controversy-jamie-smith-marnus-snicko/106040940</link><description>The first Ashes Test encounters its first umpiring controversy as England wicketkeeper Jamie Smith is given out in an incident similar to one which Australia's Marnus Labuschagne survived.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b582b4819ced3e29944f6cf63675759</guid></item><item><title>Ashes opener provides major tourism boost as cricket fans take over Perth during thrilling Test match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/ashes-cricket-opener-in-perth-provides-major-tourism-boost/106040412</link><description>As record crowds descend on Perth Stadium for one of the most dramatic starts to an Ashes series in recent history, diehard English fans Nigel and Keith describe their experience as "once-in-a-lifetime".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0474855dd411b14563edf48e05bcf804</guid></item><item><title>Has the election of Kellie Sloane solved the NSW Liberals' 'woman problem'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/two-women-leading-nsw-liberals-did-not-happen-organically/106040852</link><description>Kellie Sloane's election to lead the NSW Liberals was made on "merit", no quotas were involved, and there was barely any discussion on gender, party insiders say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f63cf38558b1cdac826324ee0291a87</guid></item><item><title>Australian motorsport great Allan Moffat dies aged 86</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/motorsport-great-allan-moffat-dies-aged-86/106041046</link><description>The Australian motorsport world is in mourning over the death of racing legend Allan Moffat who has passed away at the age of 86 following a lengthy battle with Alzheimer's.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc88f8ea9f003220c6a0a0fac03594ec</guid></item><item><title>Firefigher extinguishing fire on ship in Los Angeles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/firefigher-extinguishing-a-fire-on-a-ship-in-los-angeles-/106041134</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0344a105ccf36f17d7b5e0a8c47beef</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja and Nathan Lyon injured, Scott Boland back in Ashes wickets — quick hits from day two of Perth Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/ashes-quick-hits-first-test-day-two-australia-england/106040662</link><description>Stuart Broad hangs his head as England is torn apart by Scott Boland again, while Usman Khawaja and Nathan Lyon can't make it through a day in the field. Here are the quick hits from the frantic conclusion of the first Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c98f1f0d415271d03e916e2474a2a9da</guid></item><item><title>Travis Head explodes into Ashes folklore as Australia wins a frenzied and farcical Perth Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/australia-travis-head-explosion-england-tiktok-test/106040806</link><description>The innings of a lifetime from Travis Head may be the resounding memory from an often farcical first Test in Perth, won by Australia and lost by England in spectacular fashion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1987c852283016844875e078750d0030</guid></item><item><title>Travis Head plays 'one of the best innings you'll ever see' to potentially solve Australia's opening headache</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/cricket-travis-head-century-reaction-opening-problem/106041148</link><description>Travis Head awes multiple cricket legends with a stunning century in the first Test against England, offering Australia hope that he may well fill what looked like a gaping hole at the top of the batting order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8adacef24090a40f87e2a64bb59b059</guid></item><item><title>'Feral Senate': How voters keep the government on its toes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/senate-two-party-system-civic-duty-preferential-voting/105970018</link><description>For most of our federation's history, the two-party system has been an efficient organiser of the population. That has all changed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3a51ddf37babb9fe86a96b1b2fd6a23</guid></item><item><title>When child care fails, women leave work: Is gender equality the next victim of the childcare crisis?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/childcare-abuse-crisis-parenting-women-gender-equality/106004596</link><description>What happens to gender equality when the childcare system meant to support working parents becomes a source of fear?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">070d25b6c09deb70d5b5eec6025683ab</guid></item><item><title>The mission to save Gaza's historical artefacts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/the-mission-to-save-gaza-s-historical-artefacts/106036340</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">838db4da3f2bb759a1566df796e062e9</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians scramble to save centuries-old books and manuscripts before they are lost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/race-to-save-ancient-artefacts-in-gaza-before-they-are-lost/105992964</link><description>With a ceasefire in effect in Gaza, a restoration team is painstakingly retrieving historical manuscripts, rare volumes, and archival documents from beneath the rubble of a destroyed mosque.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2aa849837a316d0af13c4707d4a15ca7</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump responds to questions about the prospect of US military action in Mexico</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/donald-trump-responds-to-questions-/106040350</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73ee22bae89f6c53c8b46a4259ee6d45</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says he would be 'proud' to take down Mexico's cartels. Will he send in the US military?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/donald-trump-mexico-drug-cartels/106030748</link><description>Donald Trump believes the US has the right to strike directly at those it accuses of trafficking drugs — even beyond America's borders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e5bee568b0f97294cbe85d7e8f96018</guid></item><item><title>How the internet reacted to Australia winning the first Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/how-the-internet-reacted-to-the-first-ashes-test/106038632</link><description>In the most anticipated Ashes in years, Australia and England opened the series with a topsy-turvy clash in Perth, and the internet went wild.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ad9ea0166edbc7f873195e7654957ec</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies record historic Test loss as France wins 48-33</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/wallabies-vs-france-rugby-union-test-live-blog-updates/106040540</link><description>The Wallabies lose a 10th Test in a calendar year for the first time, as France proves too strong in Saint-Denis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0afbbaaa8e396c7baa19eb427d7deeb3</guid></item><item><title>G20 defies Donald Trump, with leaders jointly signing statement endorsing Paris agreement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/g20-defies-trump-with-leaders-jointly-signing-statement/106041342</link><description>US President Donald Trump was the only G20 member to boycott the summit in South Africa.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c92a98bb8764f7ac0aa742b9081590f9</guid></item><item><title>TC Fina tracker map: Track the cyclone's path</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/story-lab-cyclone-fina-path-tracker-map/106032836</link><description>Tropical Cyclone Fina, which is packing sustained winds of 165 kilometres per hour near its centre, is slowly moving south-west, towards the north-east Kimberley coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">286f0dd5b0159ee09c45e9d4a76eab95</guid></item><item><title>Discovery in desk's nook paints picture of Australia's oldest continuously operating crematorium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/rookwood-crematorium-artefact-find-in-architect-desk-sydney/106016866</link><description>An architect's desk at Australia's oldest continuously operating crematorium housed a trove of artefacts inside a compartment, only to be unearthed 100 years later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18a0cb16a312f34eba9ba1cbb621bbe7</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Fina intensifies to a category four system over water, BOM confirms — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/tropical-cyclone-fina-live-updates-sunday-november-23/106041128</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says Tropical Cyclone Fina is expected to reach category four strength while still in Northern Territory waters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">787ca815823e5ea13964631d84e915b9</guid></item><item><title>Workers deported from Ansell-linked Malaysian factory after abuse allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/ansell-mediceram-human-rights-abuse-allegations/106039160</link><description>Malaysian company MediCeram, which previously made moulds for Australian glove-maker Ansell, has denied claims it abused the rights of its Bangladeshi workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fc622d57c920bc34e74952d52c30a7c</guid></item><item><title>Severe Tropical Cyclone Fina moves towards WA as Darwin surveys the damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/severe-tropical-cyclone-fina-sunday-darwin-surveys-damage/106040870</link><description>Severe Tropical Cyclone Fina was the first cyclone to pass Darwin at a category three since Cyclone Tracy in 1974. Here is the damage it left in its wake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f31667c70164c836fd9dac92eb67e354</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Bree Walker takes third place in Olympic monobob test event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/walker-puts-down-marker-in-olympic-monobob-test-event/106041830</link><description>Australia's Bree Walker has finished third in the monobob test event in Cortina for next year's Winter Olympic Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a48b749d4b44fa4bd4cf7b3b1250e3be</guid></item><item><title>Will teens without accounts be safe on YouTube under social media ban?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/will-teens-without-accounts-be-safe-on-youtube-social-media-ban/106031868</link><description>BTN High tests what YouTube content will be viewable without an account ahead of next month's social media ban, as an academic says the restrictions are unlikely to change what young people are watching.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50698d5676700fee887f04d7b15eb0f4</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Think you'll nail it this week? I do love some misguided confidence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/105951746</link><description>Spent too much time online shopping this week, and not enough time studying fun facts? Let's see.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45c52af5024bd88b843172ebcc4a8b2f</guid></item><item><title>Australian F-35 exports face fresh scrutiny as jets approved for Saudi Arabia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/f-35-fighter-jet-sale-saudi-arabia-uae-australia-weapons-exports/106029218</link><description>The US approval of F-35 sales to Saudi Arabia sparks concerns among human rights groups in Australia, which provides parts and components to build and maintain the fighter jets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">272643e1cc3dce1fad5da58a47bd67e5</guid></item><item><title>David Boon's Test debut came as Australian cricket lurched into crisis against rampant West Indies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/today-in-history-november-23-1984-david-boon-test-debut/105951100</link><description>David Boon is one of Australia's greatest and most-beloved Test cricketers. His debut, at the Gabba on November 23, 1984 was not the most auspicious of starts, though.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0175adadb908fd2c601cef4a28bd695</guid></item><item><title>Experiences of homophobia 'happening every day' in Australia's most progressive city</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/homophobia-every-day-australia-progressive-city-canberra/106038804</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac4793f854c1db3e78e0800f4612514e</guid></item><item><title>Experiences of homophobia 'happening every day' in Australia's most progressive city</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/homophobia-in-canberra-australias-most-progressive-city/106004910</link><description>Luke was only minutes into his first shift at his new workplace when he began hearing his colleagues making homophobic comments. Despite being a resident of Australia's most progressive city, he says he no longer feels safe in public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07565072cbf43ea80cac6e9863aebefe</guid></item><item><title>Water is under pressure in the Great Artesian Basin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/water-is-under-pressure-in-the-great-artesian-basin/106002448</link><description>The Great Artesian Basin covers a fifth of Australia and contains water that has been there for millions of years. Now, decades of extraction are taking their toll and traditional owners are fighting a mining giant for compensation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f93e8b3e6314dd27f4ab4a3e8b246163</guid></item><item><title>From living homeless as a teenager to becoming Toowoomba's motorbike-riding priest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/motorbike-riding-anglican-priest-pauline-harley-toowoomba/106015442</link><description>Pauline Harley did not grow up with religion, far from it. She was homeless for six months as a teenager, which has informed her passion now for social justice in Toowoomba.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0249aa734fd607c50779a712b4a4798</guid></item><item><title>'Hope is the strongest weapon': Afghan women celebrate return to international football</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/hope-strongest-weapon-afghan-women-united-international-football/105993742</link><description>After four years in exile, some of Afghanistan's female footballers have returned to the pitch, giving hope to those still in the country, fighting for basic rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67ce65879a558d6c10b795ea483011f1</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian man's wait for surgery stretches into years as daily pain worsens with no relief within sight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/elective-surgery-tasmania-wait-for-years-timothy-smith/106040548</link><description>Within three months is the recommended time for surgery to remedy the painful health problem Timothy Smith has. But the 60-year-old has been forced to wait for years and still has no idea when he will get relief.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">962bc180bde0b32ad3b40cf43c2dea30</guid></item><item><title>A secret scheme and plans to expel former leaders — here's what we've heard from Queensland's inquiry into the CFMEU</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/qld-cfmeu-commission-of-inquiry-five-key-moments/106035616</link><description>An inquiry has heard violence was the "cancer" in Queensland's CFMEU branch. Here's what we have learned from the first week of public hearings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">668c3deb01be781e130598903902f6b1</guid></item><item><title>As climate change accelerates Launceston's flood risk, some propose putting floodgates on the estuary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/climate-change-flood-risk-launceston-tamar-estuary-floodgates/106004394</link><description>Andrew Lovitt is part of a community group that has spent 15 years investigating a large-scale infrastructure proposal to prevent flooding in Launceston, in northern Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7a83f5b024e830180eda53851f2dc58</guid></item><item><title>Golden Guitars to review stance on AI after 2026 awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/golden-guitar-awards-generative-ai-country-music/106023832</link><description>After a snap decision to ban generative tracks made using Artificial Intelligence for the 2026 Golden Guitar Awards, the Country Music Association of Australia is reviewing whether AI has a place in country music.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67651833aa9dc924741152f3b46a94f9</guid></item><item><title>Person dead and four others rushed to hospital after north Brisbane house fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/brisbane-house-fire-police-declare-crime-scene/106041950</link><description>A person has died and four others have been rushed to hospital after a house fire north of Brisbane, with police declaring a crime scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49bfb6b73551789355f61c34135accd8</guid></item><item><title>Government promises stronger protection for native forests if Greens back environment reforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/labor-greens-deal-on-environment-laws-native-forests/106040766</link><description>The ABC has been told the federal government is willing to ensure native forestry complies with tougher new standards within three years if the Greens back the reforms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b406504f8a8bc14e613f05d39f1f300</guid></item><item><title>Victorian farmer crafts unique spirits from sugar beet and red wheat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/victorian-farmer-unconventional-crops-spirits-alcohol-distilling/103563416</link><description>A Victorian farmer is making unique alcoholic drinks from unconventional crops.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60ab2971dfec0e29a781fcac231b7bdc</guid></item><item><title>England's first Ashes Test capitulation with bat and ball a symptom of 'dumb', brainless batting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/ashes-england-hammered-ben-stokes-batting/106041156</link><description>As England counts the cost of its first Ashes Test defeat, questions over how its world-beating pace attack was rendered so impotent and its high-class batters so comprehensively lost the plot will rumble all the way to Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ffb0de34551bc7bf42ebe72b0618ea4</guid></item><item><title>Extent of damage from Tropical Cyclone Fina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/extent-of-damage-from-tropical-cyclone-fina/106042028</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">092984bbb16c0cb81cb929f635139647</guid></item><item><title>JFK's granddaughter Tatiana Schlossberg reveals terminal cancer diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/jfk-granddaughter-tatiana-schlossberg-cancer-diagnosis/106041994</link><description>Tatiana Schlossberg says the cuts to research made by her cousin RFK Jr, the US Health and Human Services secretary, are disappointing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff63406b1fd607cb085ba37acee6421b</guid></item><item><title>Why is Mount Gambier's Blue Lake so blue?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/why-is-mount-gambier-s-blue-lake-so-blue/106032672</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">918c6e2bdcf0189b031462f4eb820491</guid></item><item><title>Why is the Blue Lake in Mount Gambier so blue?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/why-is-mount-gambier-blue-lake-so-blue/106031572</link><description>Most lakes are kind of blue, but this lake in South Australia stands out for its super-bright colour that attracts tourists from around the country. But just why it is so blue and why it changes colour during the year are not well known.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bcaf22035bd2fd217025ad9de55d64e</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne star on side’s ability to run opposition ‘out to the last siren’</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/alice-oloughlin-north-melbourne-win-over-melbourne-aflw/106041940</link><description>North Melbourne will play in its third consecutive AFLW grand final after weathering an almighty scare from Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c27668d7ad5b1d4f913eab612b73abb</guid></item><item><title>Police rule out schoolies link after Noosa teenage pedestrian killed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/police-rule-out-schoolies-link-after-noosa-pedestrian-killed/106042074</link><description>A 17-year-old boy was struck by a ute about 2am and died at the scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cd345a4f54d671f88ceff24be87080f</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Lions beat Carlton by 35 points to set up third straight AFLW grand final against Kangaroos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/svarc-plug-ruby-dazzles-as-lions-blitz-ends-blues/106042056</link><description>The Brisbane Lions will meet North Melbourne in the AFLW decider for a third straight season after a crushing 35-point preliminary final defeat of Carlton.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b23c002d02dd251928c1da2c16dca6b</guid></item><item><title>How an anti-war blockbuster starring Mel Gibson helped rebirth the Anzac Gallipoli legend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/gallipoli-mel-gibson-anzac-legend/106005722</link><description>By the 80s, the story of the Anzacs at Gallipoli had started to fade from the public consciousness. Then an Australian anti-war filmmaker had an idea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d4f822d85e6cb3952d8475468144ecd</guid></item><item><title>No early Christmas presents for WA when Anthony Albanese journeyed west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/anthony-albanese-wa-visit-saw-no-christmas-presents/106033346</link><description>When the prime minister and his entourage rolled into town on Monday, WA Premier Roger Cook couldn't be blamed for hoping for an early Christmas present, writes state political reporter Keane Bourke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7174d19abafcfb99c3b3dd4d25753074</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine and Europe scramble to respond to US plan to end Russia's war</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/ukraine-europe-scramble-to-respond-to-us-plan-to-end-war/106042072</link><description>Ukraine and its European allies are scrambling to come up with counter-proposals after US President Donald Trump gave Kyiv a tight deadline to approve a deal to end the war that accepts some of Russia's hardline demands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">962224e343051a5df1d5678365c27c0d</guid></item><item><title>Woman sheds light on life with severe pelvic pain as research gaps persist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/pelvic-pain-devastates-lives-amid-vast-research-gaps/106033730</link><description>As the country attempts to close the gaps in pelvic pain research and treatment, Jaali Barton continues to search for help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e8ecdb938196c1df7e06360063f4776</guid></item><item><title>Australia's two-day Ashes Test win to leave Cricket Australia millions short of expected revenue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/two-day-ashes-test-could-cost-cricket-australia-millions/106041938</link><description>Travis Head's stunning take-down of England, leading to a speedy day two finish in Perth, is set to cost Cricket Australia millions in lost ticket revenue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42db2822cc4bd5346d8cdd116b767a99</guid></item><item><title>Treasury should take on Australia's oligopolies, new think tank says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/treasury-should-take-on-oligopolies-policy-institute-australia/106040652</link><description>We need to beef up the Department of Treasury and let it take on Australia's oligopolies, a new think tank says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01c02744a122a95414d94dc247d1243a</guid></item><item><title>Martu rangers capture rare night parrot in WA's Pilbara region.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/martu-rangers-capture-rare-night-parrot-in-wa-s-pilbara-region/106034066</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b21800156c4a741b9f8c24db2648fa27</guid></item><item><title>Critically endangered night parrot captured by Martu rangers in east Pilbara</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/thirsty-night-parrot-pilbara/106029246</link><description>After thousands of hours of recording, the elusive night parrot has been captured on camera drinking from a water hole for the first time, reshaping researchers' understanding of their needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2d81811f2cbdb83f25b0a1eec6f1057</guid></item><item><title>Man suffers life-threatening burns after light plane crash at Raglan in central Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/man-suffers-life-threatening-burns-light-plane-crash-raglan/106042294</link><description>Paramedics are treating a man in his 60s with significant burns to his limbs, face and chest following a light plane crash in central Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e65c854752b07d862ac5ecd112f04378</guid></item><item><title>Israel launches strikes in Gaza ceasefire's latest test as hospitals say dozens killed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/israel-launches-strikes-in-gaza-ceasefire-s-latest-test/106042236</link><description>It is not the first time that Israel has carried out similar waves of strikes after reported attacks on its forces during the ceasefire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06985e96025d1db6193aea8cbc224601</guid></item><item><title>Man who allegedly shot at Canberra police during domestic violence-related arrest found dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/man-shot-at-police-canberra-dv-arrest/106042194</link><description>Police are investigating after a 71-year-old man who allegedly shot at officers during an attempted arrest was later found dead on a property in Canberra's south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d4fb635b5ff822a042c17406134e4d8</guid></item><item><title>Trump, Zelenskyy and European leaders under pressure over peace deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/ukraine-russia-zelenskyy-putin-trump-nato-eu/106042192</link><description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy is under pressure to agree to a peace deal, while US President Donald Trump faces domestic blowback over his foreign policy decisions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4a7975454f1263ccfc241675b9f8658</guid></item><item><title>Brazil's ex-president Jair Bolsonaro arrested over alleged plot to escape</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/brazils-ex-president-bolsonaro-arrested-over-alleged-escape-plot/106042220</link><description>Jair Bolsonaro has been taken into police custody after the country's Supreme Court found he was trying to escape house arrest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c6de39732bb02f2a6af94acbabac242</guid></item><item><title>Storm and wind gusts of 119km/h damage homes, trees, powerlines at Port Pirie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/storm-causes-widespread-damage-at-port-pirie/106042166</link><description>Thousands of residents were faced with outages in the South Australian town of Port Pirie after a severe thunderstorm and hail destroyed roofs as well as bringing down trees and powerlines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0468b7e73c4576b2bd73f7c8fe0a8990</guid></item><item><title>F1 Las Vegas Grand Prix: Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris disqualified, Max Verstappen wins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/f1-las-vegas-grand-prix-oscar-piastri-lando-norris-disqualified/105995102</link><description>Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris have both been disqualified from the Las Vegas Grand Prix, in a stunning post-race moment that has blown the battle for the Formula 1 drivers' championship wide open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6fd104ffb99297d627f46331c85d527</guid></item><item><title>Make a Christmas wreath with flowers from your garden</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/make-your-own-christmas-wreath-with-flowers-from-your-garden/106006876</link><description>Worried you might make a mess, get it wrong or waste your time making a wreath? Read our tips first.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfb834459f70c0113e9a903223f2b896</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies showed promised in 2025 but have stalled two years out from World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/wallabies-progress-stalls-after-promising-signs-in-2025/106042214</link><description>The Wallabies did not turn the corner this year, as many had suggested, as they instead face a daunting challenge to be competitive at the 2027 World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">824c646920e68fd5e2f99ed533b16ec0</guid></item><item><title>How migrant and overseas Christians are helping keep Australian churches alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/christian-migrants-asia-pacific-sustain-australian-churches/105997642</link><description>Without 11 Pacific Islander ministers serving parishes in north Queensland, the region's Anglican church would collapse, according to bishop Keith Joseph.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb86bd5bbe8cccb2bfd413fa8d120b7d</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Fina's destruction in Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/tropical-cyclone-fina-s-destruction-in-darwin-/106042622</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b447a8ff4aa14c993003d595cde035e</guid></item><item><title>Storm causes damage in Port Pirie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/storm-causes-damage-in-port-pirie/106042502</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dadf1285a8c4cded8dece1d9893df68</guid></item><item><title>What is behind Nigeria's latest school kidnappings and church attack?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/explainer-nigeria-latest-school-kidnappings-church/106042464</link><description>More than 300 students have been kidnapped in Nigeria's worst school abduction in 10 years, days after a deadly assault on a church service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">947345b04676ea23f9c6af5d2428b8ab</guid></item><item><title>Trump-style tactics used in Tasmanian government's push for Hobart stadium, rally told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/no-stadium-rally-hobart-macquarie-point-opposition/106040210</link><description>The Tasmanian government has taken a "leaf out of the Trump White House" by "smearing opponents" to the proposed Hobart AFL stadium, according to a rally against the project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">578f451e99bdef99b7c020c50e92a72c</guid></item><item><title>Brazil COP30 deal sidesteps fossil fuels, triples climate finance for developing nations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/cop30-climate-deal-sidesteps-fossil-fuels/106042660</link><description>Denial and division have been highlighted in the COP30 deal that makes no mention of cutting fossil fuels but boosts climate aid for developing nations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5cc72a82efdfdfd6ccc8f43fd61cf1b</guid></item><item><title>Opponents to Hobart's proposed AFL stadium rally in Hobart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/opponents-to-hobart-s-proposed-afl-stadium-rally-in-hobart/106042772</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54a77ae12003d031d6caea223898e9e0</guid></item><item><title>Former federal Liberal candidate Amelia Hamer wins preselection for state seat of Malvern</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/amelia-hamer-wins-preselection-for-malvern/106042776</link><description>Amelia Hamer has been endorsed as the Liberal Party's candidate for the state seat of Malvern at Victoria's 2026 election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e302238c926d762fd123474a9bdc8560</guid></item><item><title>WA government releases business case and images of controversial $217m Burswood racetrack project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/wa-government-releases-images-of-burswood-racetrack-project/106042566</link><description>The deputy premier accuses the Town of Victoria Park of lying to ratepayers over the controversial $217 million entertainment and sporting precinct in Burswood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a7e961be9f631d804104d184430cf6b</guid></item><item><title>Bureau of Meteorology's new boss asked to examine $96.5m bill for website redesign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/bureau-of-meteorology-new-website-cost-blowout-to-96-million/106042202</link><description>Federal Environment Minister Murray Watt has asked the weather agency's new boss to examine how the website's cost and redesign went so wrong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77632c609a2a766464db3db93e3232ff</guid></item><item><title>Draws released for 2026 men's, women's and wheelchair rugby league world cups</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/rlwc-draws-released-2026-mens-womens/106042928</link><description>The draws for next year's rugby league world cups have been confirmed, with a format change on the cards for the men's and women's tournaments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1184e0900d191319d6c4d2b9dbcebb0a</guid></item><item><title>F1 standings after Las Vegas Grand Prix disqualification, Lando Norris leads Oscar Piastri and Max Verstappen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/f1-standings-las-vegas-grand-prix-norris-piastri-verstappen/106042984</link><description>Here is how the drivers' championship is poised with two rounds remaining.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1be7c513c92bc3ec40b1a5afea7b85db</guid></item><item><title>Rental affordability data shows 'dire' situation across Australia — but there are 'green shoots'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/sgs-economics-rental-affordability-index-data-release/106031672</link><description>Data released today shows rental affordability in regional parts of Australia has fallen in the last year, while the situation in most capital cities has not improved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97b02490c80e60ad6d24448d120dbbcd</guid></item><item><title>DOGE no longer exists, White House says, after Musk departure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/doge-no-longer-exists-white-house-says/106043076</link><description>The department, established by Donald Trump and once headed up by Elon Musk, promised to slash billions from the US government but has quietly faded into the background in recent months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0d5af77f52a8b16c7fbbaa3a6fe4351</guid></item><item><title>Israel kills Hezbollah militant in air strike on Beirut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/israel-target-hezbollah/106043238</link><description>Israel has launched an air strike on Lebanon's capital Beirut after intensifying attacks on southern Lebanon in recent weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f5c1f41ab674f67b28c8e571a3fbd35</guid></item><item><title>Trump says Ukrainian leaders have shown 'zero gratitude' for US support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/trump-says-ukraine-zero-gratitude-us-support/106043358</link><description>It comes after the US presented Ukraine with a 28-point peace plan and gave President Volodymyr Zelenskyy a week to accept its terms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53b45af3ff6d7d899b82c2b76c376f93</guid></item><item><title>This week in history quiz, November 24: Step back in time and prove how well you know history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/-this-week-in-history-quiz-november-24/105960088</link><description>CIA assassination plots, the Eureka flag and the Sex Pistols — how well do you know this week in history?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">605a30b7946d7d4f16fa5df0d6c2c1b6</guid></item><item><title>Humanoid robots present an unprecedented dilemma for the economy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/artificial-intelligence-robot-humanoid-workforce-labour-tax-ubi/106034208</link><description>There is now a global race to build humanoids that can walk, talk, reason, lift, carry, fetch, stack and generally operate in a human environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11015f2f3ba4acc558810e73151bbb62</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley faces a fight for her political survival in parliament's final week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/sussan-ley-leadership-liberals-women-angus-taylor-andrew-hastie/105884524</link><description>The optics of rolling the Liberal Party's only woman leader when NSW and Victoria have managed to elevate traditional "small-l liberal" candidates is playing on the minds of some members.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eaee738e013977074c56a612f24dc099</guid></item><item><title>Murray Watt declares 'now or never' for environment laws as parliament stand-off looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/watt-declares-now-or-never-for-environment-laws/106042780</link><description>As politicians converge on Canberra for the last time this year, Labor is determined to pass its environment law reform and insists it will work with either the Coalition or the Greens to do so.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7275f31ad98a6ce8e5713f37f17da866</guid></item></channel></rss>