<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 04:00:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Donald Trump posthumously awards Presidential Medal of Freedom to Charlie Kirk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/donald-trump-charlie-kirk-presidential-medal-of-freedom/105892844</link><description>The public killing of the conservative figure rocked the US. Now Donald Trump has awarded the Presidential Medal of Freedom to Charlie Kirk at a White House ceremony.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9871d0204a8a88f4c9fb8ad7727658f8</guid></item><item><title>Regional Victorian farmers left high and dry as decent spring rain fails to arrive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/farmers-cutting-crops-for-hay-as-decent-spring-rain-doesnt-come/105884166</link><description>Some Victorian farmers are cutting crops for hay as the drought continues to bite in the nation's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">509574dcbec28aaf0b1eb34f8aa69ab5</guid></item><item><title>Illawarrra Academy of Sport holds open testing day for aspiring young athletes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/illawarrra-academy-of-sport-pen-testing-day-young-athletes/105878204</link><description>Young athletes wanting to be the next Emma McKeon or Jessica Hull have been put through high-performance testing to see if they have what it takes to be a professional.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15a018213f26351372e484eeb90ad629</guid></item><item><title>Japan makes history as Brazil records 'unacceptable' 3-2 loss in international friendly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/japan-beats-brazil-in-football-international-friendly/105893036</link><description>For the first time in 14 meetings, Japan defeats Brazil 3-2 in their international friendly at a sold-out Tokyo Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6454207cf8d9709c6caca8495b04511c</guid></item><item><title>Queensland health minister knew of hospital failures before going on leave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/queensland-health-minister-knew-about-caboolture-/105890580</link><description>Queensland's health minister has revealed he knew about failures at Caboolture Hospital involving the death of a patient after delays to medical scan results, before he went on holiday when the issue later became public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12969694309920e5fabdb01232ea2a22</guid></item><item><title>WA's Coolgardie council avoids suspension, with residents expressing frustration and relief over the saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/coolgardie-to-dig-itself-out-of-debt/105881252</link><description>Coolgardie Shire leaders hope to rebuild trust among ratepayers after the local government minister announced the WA state government would not suspend the council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77b218585453033539c537af21793f7f</guid></item><item><title>England thrashes Latvia 5-0 to qualify for World Cup finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/football-england-thrashes-latvia-to-reach-world-cup-finals/105893278</link><description>Unbeaten in its qualifying matches, England reaches next year's World Cup finals following a dominant 5-0 defeat of Latvia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">776384400073f9c24dc5ed3d14d31475</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of Victorians are graduating as paramedics, but have to go interstate for jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/paramedic-student-glut-no-jobs-ambulance-victoria/105874740</link><description>For regional paramedicine graduates, finding a job, let alone one in your hometown, is a challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87a5961a74a7b4d6e63a1037bd6466b2</guid></item><item><title>Gaps in cyberbullying reporting leave parents feeling lost, struggling to find answers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/cyberbullying-reporting-gaps-leave-parents-children-helpless/105864800</link><description>Parents and carers are frustrated by what they say is a lack of support when trying to report several Instagram accounts targeting children under the age of 17 over the school holidays.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86168b6389493c5ee569ccfbc8f2dbdb</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Health issues public health alert as person dies after ingesting rare nitazene</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/second-death-queensland-novel-nitazene-health-alert/105893200</link><description>A second person has died this month after ingesting a synthetic opioid in Queensland, raising concerns about the safety of thousands of teenagers during Schoolies celebrations in coming weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3e5416e73a0037aeae6e9e25a384a6b</guid></item><item><title>Randa Abdel-Fattah reveals how the Israel-Gaza war shaped her new book Discipline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/randa-abdel-fattah-palestinian-author-new-book-discipline/105865540</link><description>Randa Abdel-Fattah explores the experience of Palestinian Australians in Discipline, her first book for adults.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5256627cfb3d5e9fd11c695daf718ec</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos lose 2-1 to USA in international friendly, ending Tony Popovic's unbeaten start</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/live-updates-usa-socceroos-international-friendly-fifa-world-cup/105884330</link><description>The Socceroos suffer defeat for the first time under Tony Popovic, falling to a 2-1 defeat against the USA in Colorado.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ce54438a6647fef94dd054d64e53f08</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump posts video of US strikes on alleged drug trafficking boat off coast of Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/donald-trump-posts-video-of-us-strikes-on-alleged/105893326</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7821ad1026d9a5f2396b0de54e5b73f6</guid></item><item><title>US strike on alleged drug boat off Venezuela kills six, Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/us-strike-on-alleged-drug-boat-off-venezuela-kills-six/105893308</link><description>It is the fifth deadly strike in the Caribbean amid the Trump administration's crackdown on alleged drug traffickers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c1e71f90039f55cf158db7a0c7d28d9</guid></item><item><title>Wildlife Photographer of the Year 2025 winners list: Spiders, frogs and fungi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/wildlife-photographer-of-the-year-2025/105890182</link><description>An Australian photographer who took a unique shot of a skeletoniser caterpillar is among the winners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad80355b3634f5b9a21420c66946ea25</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, deadline day recap: Zach Merrett stuck at Essendon as Charlie Curnow and Christian Petracca find new homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/afl-trade-period-day-live-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca/105893932</link><description>The clock runs out on deadline day of the AFL trade period, with Hawthorn failing to seal a deal for Zach Merrett, while the Swans hand over a raft of picks to clinch a move for Charlie Curnow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1880fba71c2089a10a592d3d6c29bd87</guid></item><item><title>Rockhampton man charged after allegedly stabbing two men at sports club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/man-charged-after-alleged-frenchville-sports-club-stabbings/105893310</link><description>Police allege a 21-year-old man stabbed two men at a Rockhampton sports club and threatened another man in unprovoked attacks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f2bd9d1641e7a8a163dd0a29d84b977</guid></item><item><title>Search continues for missing bushwalker Daryl Fong in Tasmania's Mount Field National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/search-for-hiker-missing-in-mt-field-national-park-continues/105893390</link><description>Tasmania Police Inspector Luke Horne says gale force winds and deep snows are slowing search crews on day three but they still hold out hope.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">390b73e5cb58f0ab0c47066c89188622</guid></item><item><title>The US has dropped out of the top 10 most powerful passports — but where does Australia rank?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/united-states-passport-drops-out-of-top-10-most-powerful/105893408</link><description>The US passport has fallen to 12th place, a five-spot decline from its previous ranking, tying with Malaysia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">210460eb5dcbc50a34d606ea70c1a796</guid></item><item><title>Powerhouse misses opportunity to get Melbourne-bound drums of Sydney's Midnight Oil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/sydneys-powerhouse-missed-out-on-midnight-oil-drums-hirst/105894330</link><description>Midnight Oil are Sydney rock royalty, but the drum kit that stuck with the band for more than 40 years is heading to a Melbourne music museum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77d8f6e30d82e4cfddfe3d8643cf4ad8</guid></item><item><title>CCC investigation into former Townsville mayor Troy Thompson finished, but unreleased</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/former-mayor-troy-thompson-ccc-investigation-finished/105894368</link><description>A crime and corruption investigation into former Townsville mayor Troy Thompson has been finished, weeks away from a by-election he is expected to contest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80c6a9e3495196a82025540b243c8512</guid></item><item><title>Conjoined boys born in PNG bound for Australia for medical treatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/png-conjoined-twins-braun-hospital-medical-treatment-sydney/105888942</link><description>The boys, who are only the second known case of conjoined twins born in PNG, are expected to come to Australia for medical treatment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">602984aa1a6e648bd1700a79bdd0ced0</guid></item><item><title>Australian seamer Megan Schutt looks to delay retirement until 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/full-trophy-cabinet-part-of-schutt-s-cricket-retirement-dream/105894742</link><description>Megan Schutt had once planned to walk away after the ODI Women's World Cup, but the veteran seamer is now considering playing into 2026 for Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f84bc367da9d0232000fcadc14ce9b90</guid></item><item><title>ARLC says NRL players face 10-year ban for joining rebel leagues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/nrl-players-face-10-year-ban-for-joining-rebel-leagues/105894992</link><description>The Australian Rugby League Commission has announced a 10-year ban for any NRL player who agrees to join a football competition it does not recognise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddb37f0928e43c1b5bbf5bd94cff1dfa</guid></item><item><title>Hamas executes 'collaborators and lawbreakers' in graphic scenes in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/abc-news-verify-hamas-executions-gaza-city/105893350</link><description>Masked gunmen have carried out "extrajudicial executions" in the streets of Gaza City as an expert claims the terror group is trying to regain control of the destroyed enclave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">011b7d02b9a4606194657179c44c731f</guid></item><item><title>Hamas fighters execute alleged collaborators in Gaza. ABC NEWS Verify has chosen not to show the executions due to their graphic nature.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/hamas-fighters-execute-alleged-collaborators-in/105893348</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d75241605dfda6cf26081e293c37b7c</guid></item><item><title>Michael J Fox talks about life with Parkinson's disease</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/michael-j-fox-talks-about-death-and-parkinsons-disease/105894044</link><description>The Back to the Future star has been candid about life with the degenerative neurological condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb8da2122b00a39bed22e5f831e89528</guid></item><item><title>How long does it take to acclimatise to a new place when the weather is very different?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/how-to-adjust-different-climates/105887794</link><description>Do our bodies actually acclimatise when moving from one climate to another and can we do anything to smooth the transition?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7b51651bfb1e6f2f7657bf344b2ebee</guid></item><item><title>Police charge two men after raids on alleged safe houses used by South-East Asian drug gang</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/police-seize-drugs-in-raids-on-south-east-asian-drug-gang/105895348</link><description>Investigators are probing links between a haul of drugs seized on Tuesday and the South-East Asian gang allegedly behind a failed hit in Western Sydney last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b2dd9d3f7b882327d1b570132b6d61c</guid></item><item><title>Federal government puts states, territories on notice over failure to close the gap for Indigenous people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/closing-the-gap-proposed-penalties/105894194</link><description>The federal Indigenous minister may impose penalties on states and territories that fail to meet critical targets for the National Agreement on Closing the Gap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db05c3e8b8aaf1109e2ab7a09d9a6061</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says Time magazine cover of himself may be 'worst' in history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/donald-trump-reacts-to-time-magazine-cover/105895214</link><description>Donald Trump made the comments in reference to Time magazine's upcoming November cover story, detailing how his administration "sealed the Gaza ceasefire deal".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76e60a710086e2ae8db0e801f7bc30d1</guid></item><item><title>Australia's baby recession deepens, new ABS data says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/australia-s-baby-recession-deepens-new-abs-data-says/105541086</link><description>The baby recession in Australia is deepening as cost of living pressures make the decision for people to have children less of a choice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c8e24e2ff09a356f53956f037c71227</guid></item><item><title>Magistrate issues arrest warrant after teen refuses to attend court over alleged murders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/arrest-warrant-teen-refused-court-melbourne-murders/105894642</link><description>A teenager in youth custody over the murders of Dau Akueng and Chol Achiek is forcibly arrested by police after he repeatedly refused to attend court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bd5acafab7d1eda9c384d53816d696c</guid></item><item><title>NSW bowler Sean Abbott subbed out of Sheffield Shield game after splitting webbing on hand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/abbott-splits-webbing-on-hand-in-latest-australian-bowling-blow/105895908</link><description>Sean Abbott becomes the latest Test hopeful to suffer an injury, ruled out of NSW's Sheffield Shield match after splitting the webbing on his bowling hand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63204e72e5ad62a8ea02127575bba291</guid></item><item><title>Mother stands trial accused of 'criminally negligent conduct' that resulted in daughter's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/mother-jenni-wilmott-manslaughter-and-criminal-neglect-trial/105894292</link><description>A mother should be held criminally responsible for the death of her 15-year-old daughter, who she allegedly subjected to physical and emotional abuse for a period of five years, a court has heard. Warning: This story includes references to child abuse and self-harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b548a1668d79ca4e5a8322f03015590e</guid></item><item><title>David Pye faces murder trial accused of organising Nick Martin assassination at Kwinana Motorplex</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/david-pye-murder-trial-nick-martin-kwinana-motorplex-killing/105889968</link><description>The man accused of organising the assassination of former Rebels boss Nick Martin believed the bikie had also arranged to have him killed, a Perth court hears.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad56fba6941aeb6e543564f19ae2ea7a</guid></item><item><title>Family of Albanvale murder victim Kylie Sheahan confront her killer Roland Griffiths in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/prosecutors-life-sentence-roland-griffiths-albanvale-fire/105894710</link><description>A lawyer calls for Roland Griffiths to face a life sentence for the murder of his wife, who he doused in petrol and set on fire in Melbourne's north-west in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40b0b528fca67e230df3b96abe480fe1</guid></item><item><title>Three Australian men accused of killing Zivan Radmanovic in Bali could face death penalty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/three-australian-men-could-face-death-penalty-bali/105896428</link><description>Indonesian police allege Zivan Radmanovic was killed when two Australian men stormed the villa, shooting him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4bb686a2307e1685b9fddd02d399650</guid></item><item><title>Boat approaches southern right whales off Albany coast in WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/boat-approaches-southern-right-whale-and-calf-wa/105893974</link><description>The latest close encounter with a protected whale species has renewed calls for the public to give the animals space.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d402bafad752b1c94a1343f0154bcac</guid></item><item><title>Police charge man with Armadale murder after alleged altercation leaves older man dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/homicide-squad-investigates-armadale-death/105896646</link><description>Police charge a 35-year-old man with murder after the death of a 49-year-old man in the Perth suburb of Armadale.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7b9b6705107b6ff5b738b62d81c44fc</guid></item><item><title>Residents in WA's north urged to prepare for cyclone season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/bom-retires-cyclone-outlook-for-northern-wa/105894634</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says it will no longer publish a cyclone outlook for WA's north, saying it was less reliable due to a changing climate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53781b9b19159607ee69607086ea9579</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105896606</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5de03d8a271e83312ef111c5e775f4b8</guid></item><item><title>Police say accused carjacker granted bail days before alleged Melbourne CBD crime spree</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/melbourne-cbd-carjacking-crime-court-little-bourke/105896422</link><description>A court has heard the man accused of committing multiple carjackings with a fake gun on Tuesday had been granted bail two days prior.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcaf2e74fe39a2ed80ce7e5d4da0b2cc</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government apologises for releasing victims of crime data which overstated drop in numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/qld-government-apologises-victim-of-crime-data-incorrect/105896620</link><description>The Queensland government has apologised for releasing data that overstated a drop in the number of victims of crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef67127403637791c97172e47ffa1b51</guid></item><item><title>One of four bodies handed over by Hamas does not match any hostage, Israel says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/body-returned-to-israel-not-a-hostage-israel-says/105897000</link><description>The Israeli military says one of four bodies handed over by Hamas on Tuesday night, local time, is not that of an Israeli hostage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f337f67d18c93c55e85db0501d33d7d5</guid></item><item><title>Benjamin Netanyahu attends court to testify in corruption trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/benjamin-netanyahu-attends-court-to-testify-in-corruption-trial/105897112</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">191cdd59809cd16e8df57ce25a15e615</guid></item><item><title>Former Alice Springs principal Gavin Morris guilty on four counts of aggravated assault against students</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/former-nt-principal-gavin-morris-trial-assault-charges-court/105895336</link><description>Former Yipirinya School principal Gavin Morris has been found guilty of physically assaulting four students, including choking a pupil and dragging students by the ear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99f044f608bfcab8a036f2890956c675</guid></item><item><title>CO2 emissions reached record high in 2024, World Meteorological Organization report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/co2-emissions-reached-record-high-in-2024-wmo-report-finds/105897180</link><description>The World Meteorological Organization says carbon dioxide levels in the atmosphere are increasing at rates that have tripled since the 1960s, and emissions from human activities and more wildfires have helped fan a "vicious climate cycle."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fe5ddc947f3b56d25680eb47317a921</guid></item><item><title>Syria's president Sharaa tells Putin he will respect all past deals with Moscow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/syrian-president-to-honour-past-deals-with-russia/105897210</link><description>Syrian President Ahmed al-Sharaa has told Russian President Vladimir Putin he would honour all past deals struck between his country and Moscow, a pledge suggesting Moscow's two main military bases in Syria are safe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20ceb7fb8dd0ab7c013b89252936bab6</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan and Afghanistan agree to temporary ceasefire after deadly violence along border</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/pakistan-afghanistan-fighting-temporary-ceasefire-conflict/105897208</link><description>A 48-hour ceasefire has been decided between the Pakistan government and the Afghan Taliban regime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c0608cfefe376793ed0f1726baceedd</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar military coup leader Michael Randrianirina 'taking the position of president'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/madagascar-military-leader-appoints-himself-president/105897228</link><description>Colonel Michael Randrianirina led a rebellion by soldiers that ousted President Andry Rajoelina after weeks of youth-led protests against the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1f046f647c3e9115cf381c09119bcda</guid></item><item><title>Australia sees opportunity in China-US rare earths dispute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/trump-albanese-xi-critical-minerals-us-china/105884214</link><description>Trump may have expressed "shock", but his administration is clearly not surprised at China's willingness to flex its dominance on rare earths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa98a5f162d3f58f6ff157adeeba8042</guid></item><item><title>Fresh new faces campaigning to make a difference in Melbourne's north as part of youth council</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/hume-council-youth-elections/105895026</link><description>Melbourne's Hume Council will see the city's first-ever democratically elected youth mayor take office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">495c6511513593a8edc13e076cfdb0e4</guid></item><item><title>Calvary Health Care questioned over Launceston private hospital's future after infrastructure failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/calvary-health-care-private-hospital-launceston-tasmania/105885816</link><description>Tasmanian healthcare experts are calling for assurances about the future of a private hospital in Launceston in the wake of a costly infrastructure failure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41f8500ececa20b4fc5acfda9bbdbc9e</guid></item><item><title>Singapore, 'so dependent on external demand', braces for tariff hit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/singapore-economy-business-fallout-donald-trump-tariffs/105893038</link><description>Businesses in Singapore — one of the most trade-exposed economies in the world — have been watching the fallout from Donald Trump's 'Liberation Day' tariffs with apprehension.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f30cb84dd7e9868667ba93e4670d3a2</guid></item><item><title>'No understanding': The extreme cost of living crisis affecting Australia’s most remote communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/cost-of-living-crisis-aurukun-australia-remote-communities-/105879078</link><description>Being one of Australia’s most remote and disadvantaged communities, Aurukun’s grocery prices are some of the highest in the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b0e33d99ce449a6673d4b6cc201e7ed</guid></item><item><title>Historic Number 12 Squadron returns as Australia expands anti-submarine capability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/poseidon-12-squadron-defence-air-force-australia-us-china/105895342</link><description>The federal government has re-established the Number 12 Squadron in SA at the same time as Australia's anti-submarine capability is expanding with the arrival of new aircraft.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6176d289d3b4affa946abe70f4a0a0c</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period quick hits: Zach Merrett's agent fumes, clubs feud over Callum Ah Chee deal and Charlie Curnow gets his move</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/afl-trade-period-deadline-day-quick-hits-merrett-curnow/105897020</link><description>The AFL trade period's deadline day delivered more drama than ever — with a manager blowing up and a Hawks star suggesting Essendon is 'Alcatraz' on a social media post.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30e7d7c3c3877a4e5422e185ff4a2a02</guid></item><item><title>US wants to make rare earth deals with Australia but without China involved, expert says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/us-is-open-to-make-rare-earth-deals-with-australia/105895128</link><description>As rare earths re-emerge as a central battleground in the US-China trade war, Australian companies are already striking deals to supply America. A policy expert says talks at the White House next week could secure a national agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93a0c2c00f2f1e07783629d538ec8b4e</guid></item><item><title>One student's journey from heart transplant to final exams as HSC begins in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/hsc-exams-begin-nsw-nathan-barbara-shares-his-story/105896454</link><description>Sitting year 12 exams is a big achievement for anyone, but more so for Nathan Barbara having undergone a heart transplant less than a year ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04f234df9186de4f609cfbd4eaf6e457</guid></item><item><title>Fifty years since the Balibo Five murders, families are still seeking justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/balibo-five-murders-50-years-indonesia-australia-timor-leste/105884316</link><description>On the 50th anniversary of the Balibo Five murders, families are still grieving the loss of their loved ones and remain committed to holding those responsible accountable for their actions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1314ae8328046a527aba9120658d2d1d</guid></item><item><title>US vows to 'impose costs on Russia' if Ukraine war continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/us-to-impose-costs-on-russia-if-ukraine-war-continues-power-cuts/105897356</link><description>Ukraine implements emergency power cuts across the country amid a relentless drone assault on the country's power grid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7f6cbc10f55744bc3e72a2978363274</guid></item><item><title>Australians are no fans of Donald Trump, but see no alternative to US alliance, according to poll</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/polls-no-alternative-united-states-ally-trump-negative/105895536</link><description>New polling shows most Australians want to stick with the US alliance, despite holding overwhelmingly negative views towards the Trump administration and harbouring deep worries about the erosion of American democracy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b34e4eb2cc25c472ba249c4f880b3e50</guid></item><item><title>Dead koala found after sighting of the endangered animal halted ACT suburb's construction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/act-dead-koala-found-as-new-suburb-development-on-hold/105896808</link><description>The construction of new homes in Canberra's north remains on hold after a koala was spotted. Now, a dead koala has been found nearby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">662b333c24de695d37cbf543e12d606a</guid></item><item><title>What is Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder and how is it diagnosed? Unpacking questions about ADHD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/what-is-adhd-attention-deficit-hyperactivity-disorder-diagnosis/105843020</link><description>October marks Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) awareness month and the focus this year is on the many faces of the neurological condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">326c4e8c1519f7e7bdd9cf1c15fa5446</guid></item><item><title>Australians Ajla Tomljanović and James Duckworth reach WTA and ATP quarterfinals in Asia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/tennis-alja-tomljanovic-james-duckworth-ningbo-almaty-open/105897556</link><description>Australian duo Ajla Tomljanović and James Duckworth reach the quarterfinals at their respective events in China and Kazakhstan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">336d915e1efab8f376e17988ed3ec4ca</guid></item><item><title>Funeral held for dead Israeli hostage Guy Illouz as two more bodies released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/funeral-for-dead-israeli-hostage-guy-illouz/105892306</link><description>Funerals begin for dead Israelis returned from Gaza in the ceasefire and hostage exchange deal, as the nation receives the remains of two more former captives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8225bf7145b96b2938ea9a624f2675cd</guid></item><item><title>Casterton residents still displaced one year on from 2024 hailstorm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/casterton-storm-anniversary-residents-feeling-damage/105894364</link><description>A year since the freak hailstorm that devastated the Victorian town of Casterton, Kim Jeffrey marked the anniversary the same way she has spent most of 2025 — living in a caravan in her driveway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efd11ff021468bf135d28b2bfd9c4403</guid></item><item><title>Third day of renewed search for missing 4yo Gus wraps up amid extreme heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/search-for-missing-gus-near-yunta-to-continue/105894686</link><description>More than 100 people, including from SA Police, the Australian Defence Force, and the State Emergency Services, have been walking about 20 kilometres per day in hot conditions during the renewed search, police say. The search concluded about midday on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cc1f1a5678d418814e5b57c1fcb4bc6</guid></item><item><title>Bundaberg and Maryborough grapple with anti-social behaviour in town centres</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/queensland-towns-grapple-with-anti-social-behaviour/105890248</link><description>Arriving at their local park for a morning walk, Lili Jacobsen was pulling her pram out of the car when a woman approached her, talking about the devil and demanding money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41ea3f514aee424f129616008b60678b</guid></item><item><title>Nikon Small World photomicroscopy competition's top 15 images of 2025 capture our tiniest signs of life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/nikon-small-world-photomicrography-competition-2025-winners/105880892</link><description>Extreme close-ups of rice weevil, pollen in a spider's web and a geometer moth laying eggs are among this year's Nikon Small World competition entries from thousands of scientists and artists across the globe. Here are the judges' favourites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">422146c134220b9daaeb85e97181786b</guid></item><item><title>Soldier killed in vehicle rollover during army training in north Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/army-soldier-killed-in-vehicle-rollover-while-training/105897572</link><description>The Department of Defence says an Australian soldier has died after a single-vehicle rollover during training at the Australian Army's Townsville Field Training Area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9064921280d2988c8f1986804181b2f4</guid></item><item><title>England saved by rain in Pakistan World Cup match as Australia prepares to face Bangladesh</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/cricket-world-cup-england-pakistan-banadoned-colombo/105897648</link><description>Only a rain downpour against Pakistan prevents England from recording its first defeat of the World Cup, as Australia looks to book its berth in knockout stages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">149a025fb79f05b67378d20a66adf0e4</guid></item><item><title>Cost of 'best practice' on emissions at leaking Darwin gas plant an 'intolerable risk' for Santos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/santos-darwin-lng-emissions-best-practice-intolerable-risk/105819802</link><description>Santos's Darwin gas plant is set for a new lease of life despite a major methane leak. The company told federal officials the risk it could be forced to meet best practice on carbon emissions was "intolerable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4185616f1eb4420fa8e0bb9f51a7a95</guid></item><item><title>Replica of destroyed Juukan Gorge being built five years after Rio Tinto blast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/juukan-gorge-rock-shelter-recreated-models-virtual-reality/105889276</link><description>A full-scale replica of the Juukan Gorge rock shelter, destroyed by mining company Rio Tinto, will be built over the remains of the original in Western Australia's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17d49eeea6ddb3bcb9585027b4d633f3</guid></item><item><title>Inside the plan to rebuild Juukan Gorge rock shelter destroyed by Rio Tinto</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/inside-the-plan-to-rebuild-juukan-gorge-rock/105897086</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">836ec1aeb75c45e97fb5a15b6da4f392</guid></item><item><title>$5 milk and $90 rent increases: The NT's rising cost of living pushing families into housing stress</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/nt-cost-of-living-report-rising-rents-fuel-prices-housing-stress/105895916</link><description>Kerrie Matthews has been forced to sell personal items to afford life-saving diabetes equipment, and with skyrocketing bills she is putting her house on the market and leaving the Northern Territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6003c03876e99fd949a9e637f3665cce</guid></item><item><title>Teen girl allegedly fixated with Bondi and Columbine massacres granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/teenager-granted-bail-after-after-allegedly-taking-knife-school/105887774</link><description>A knife-wielding Victorian teen allegedly fixated by the Columbine school shooting and Bondi Junction attack has been granted bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">806781780e4621828d5311cc03d12762</guid></item><item><title>Prestigious Australian wine labels feeling the pinch as Chinese buy and drink less</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/premium-wine-penfolds-reports-china-sales-slump/105887474</link><description>Cheaper bulk wine has been struggling in the market, but now even prestigious labels like Penfolds are feeling the pinch off the back of changing drinking habits and a reported crackdown on lavish banquets for civil servants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">824a7cb7547f583c912f4b33ffcad31d</guid></item><item><title>R360 hits back at Australian Rugby League Commission's threat of 10-year bans for rebel players</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/arlc-nrl-r360-hits-back-at-ban-threats-for-players/105897732</link><description>The boss of R360 says threats of 10-year bans for NRL players who defect to the rebel competition are predictable, as the code war escalates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a507cb97abb406d1566b15b62aa13750</guid></item><item><title>Pentagon journalists exit en masse over new reporting restrictions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/pentagon-press-corps-leaves-in-protest-over-reporting-rules/105892258</link><description>Journalists working at the Pentagon had been asked to sign a pledge to refrain from reporting information not authorised for release by the US Department of War.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55cc5a0ac437d8e13ddd34e87c58ee4e</guid></item><item><title>Why did Britain's case against two alleged Chinese spies collapse?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/why-did-britains-chinese-spy-cases-collapse/105897212</link><description>The collapse of the case against the men — a former think-tank director and a researcher for a senior MP — prompts some to argue the British government deliberately failed to provide enough evidence against the pair in order to avoid upsetting China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcaf5bf9b104df3541cca14fa206a0c1</guid></item><item><title>Country GP crushed by vintage tractor in Denmark issues safety warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/safety-warning-after-country-gp-crushed-by-heritage-tractor/105885980</link><description>What started as a routine day of chores for a country GP and his son became a life-or-death situation after he was crushed by a vintage tractor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc4c053f90131636fe18b998de8dcf1f</guid></item><item><title>Four-time Olympic champion Ariarne Titmus announces retirement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/swimming-ariarne-titmus-announces-retirement/105898036</link><description>Ariarne Titmus draws the curtain on a decorated career, in which she won eight medals across two Olympic Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b20c3d209eb66b297a235d75ac8ea914</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Auditor-General lays out government's 'slow' and 'burdensome' response to 2022 floods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/auditor-general-lays-out-slow-reponse-to-2022-floods/105895512</link><description>A Victorian Auditor-General's report says state government agencies need to be quicker at providing relief and recovery when responding to natural disasters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b0605c3712edfcb20f02a29fd0c8fc4</guid></item><item><title>Madura Plains sheep station hits the market as wool and lamb prices soar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/historic-madura-plains-for-sale-wa-sheep-station/105894986</link><description>One of Australia's largest sheep stations is listed for sale as wool and lamb prices soar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdf5cb0f5e7c6d4612908253b324ec0b</guid></item><item><title>NSW Supreme Court finds protest law amendments invalid after Palestine Action Group challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/nsw-court-palestine-action-group-protest-law-amendment-challenge/105898160</link><description>The Palestine Action Group has won a NSW Supreme Court challenge against a law that limited protests near places of worship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10a0f52fe7d5082728fa923101f920a5</guid></item><item><title>Rental affordability report reveals dire reality for essential workers priced out of housing market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/essential-workers-priced-out-of-rental-housing-queensland/105893520</link><description>Anglicare has issued a dire warning to policymakers after its latest report found nurses, teachers and paramedics can only afford a tiny fraction of rental properties across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e6d1509d67c1c52c79888f69f295db0</guid></item><item><title>Abattoir worker's long road to recovery after losing part of leg in meat processor accident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/abattoir-worker-speaks-out-after-losing-part-of-leg-in-accident/105865640</link><description>Almost four years after his leg was partially severed in a workplace accident, Dean Spencer's recovery is ongoing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c38a5474c735b4a8a46add9612e9c959</guid></item><item><title>Which team came out the most ahead in the AFL draft period and does free agency need fixing?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/afl-trade-period-2025-which-team-came-out-the-most-ahead/105897898</link><description>It was one of the more chaotic AFL trade periods on record as picks and players moved all over the place — but who came out ahead the most?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4de5f79b4339bc87a72fedad20788ad</guid></item><item><title>Police investigating reports of explicit deepfake images of girls from Sydney school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/police-investigate-sydney-school-image-deepfake/105896812</link><description>The ABC understands a number of families attended Eastwood Police Station on Wednesday evening after growing frustrated that a local high school had failed to act on a complaint.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">913aa7d6ba3fc90880d957db2eaf13db</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill man who ran 27 marathons in 29 days finishes with fractured hip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/broken-hill-man-ran-to-newcastle-with-broken-femur/105866122</link><description>Mitch McKenny is unlikely to run again after spending four weeks running from Broken Hill to Newcastle, including the last 380 kilometres with severe pain in his hip.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de6f9d09fba1260c22272a56efcf4fa3</guid></item><item><title>Calls for federal oversight of Indigenous deaths in custody rejected in the NT</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/nt-parliament-rejects-aboriginal-deaths-in-custody-motion/105895810</link><description>Three decades after the landmark Royal Commission into Aboriginal Deaths in Custody, the Northern Territory parliament rejects a motion proposing the federal government establish an independent oversight body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf403f214ebf0a2f051e0cb3ec8f817b</guid></item><item><title>Australia's unemployment rate jumps to 4.5pc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/australia-unemployment-rate-rises-september-2025/105898244</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate jumped to 4.5 per cent in September, up from 4.3 per cent in August.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">944d983f4c3e591e79c311c6deea0d20</guid></item><item><title>Kingston residents rally to save 130yo oak tree from transmission project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/campaign-to-save-algerian-oak-kingston-western-renewables-link/105885046</link><description>Residents are getting creative in their fight to save a "magnificent" 130-year-old Algerian oak tree from being felled for a controversial transmission line project in western Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f54bb8b9ecab1e3d0af3c172dfd77c73</guid></item><item><title>Female shearer sets world record by shearing 500 merino lambs in one day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/shearer-sets-womens-record-shearing-500-merino-lambs-in-a-day/105897736</link><description>Nikki Lyons's clippers started humming at 6am. Twelve hours later, she was a world record holder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d962c3ee2503118469de3426af4a2f</guid></item><item><title>Remains of missing Victorian woman Lucinda Miller discovered in police search</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/lucinda-miller-items-found-neerim-south-gippsland/105895350</link><description>New information from a member of the local community has led police to human remains in bushland in Victoria's east believed to be missing woman Lucinda Miller.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ff902b644302bf25e73309688f89cf5</guid></item><item><title>Former US Marine Pilot Dan Duggan appears in person at appeal against extradition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/us-marine-pilot-dan-duggan-appears-appeal-extradition/105898850</link><description>US authorities want Dan Duggan extradited from Australia for allegedly training Chinese pilots in South Africa in 2012. An appeal to avoid the extradition has started in the Federal Court today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e24e51691d3df5e1bb5646ddb4181f4a</guid></item><item><title>Ariarne Titmus's retirement ends years of sacrifice and allows her to at last savour her greatness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/ariarne-titmus-retirement-a-career-of-sacrifice-and-greatness/105898280</link><description>Ariarne Titmus has given her life to a dream. As she sets off on her next adventures, she can be in no doubt that her years of sacrifice and devotion were worth it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ace92f301f8bbd380cf4ea10e08f291</guid></item><item><title>Consumer groups, regulator concern as number of Australians accessing super to fix health surges again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/concern-over-accessing-super-for-medical-care-rises/105876384</link><description>Australians were allowed to withdraw $1.37 billion from their superannuation accounts for medical costs last financial year, in another jump from previous years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc6ab38204feeb436342c69f39e8b1a1</guid></item><item><title>Ariarne Titmus labelled a 'living legend' after calling time on decorated swimming career</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/swimming-ariarne-titmus-olympics-teammates-rivals-tribute/105899022</link><description>Olympic teammates and rivals pay tribute to the career of Australian swimming great Ariarne Titmus, who has announced her retirement at the age of 25.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcd8f1c3121e47375a837e4ff51132ea</guid></item><item><title>First Nations artists warn against AI 'double colonisation' as Meta uses work for training</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/first-nations-creatives-warn-against-ai-double-colonisation/105889290</link><description>The rapid development of AI is testing the effectiveness of the Copyright Act, with creative and media industries calling for better protections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fc2ae378cfa0f6d485867eb2b770985</guid></item><item><title>Trump confirms the CIA is conducting covert operations inside Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/trump-confirms-cia-conducting-covert-venezuela-operations/105899100</link><description>Donald Trump says he authorised the CIA operation in part to stop the flow of "drugs coming in from Venezuela".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e085079c4af6fbf7e7281c139d73b6c8</guid></item><item><title>Endangered regent honeyeaters released in Hunter breeding effort</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/critically-endangered-regent-honeyeaters-released-hunter-valley/105897506</link><description>Dozens of regent honeyeaters have been released in woodlands in the NSW Hunter Valley in an effort to boost the critically endangered population.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">383b1b3969cfdfce4abe0f4f51474d27</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne drug trafficker Justin Craig Barnett jailed over foiled canola oil methamphetamine plot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/justin-craig-barnett-sentenced-canola-oil-drug-plot/105898720</link><description>A drug trafficker's dreams of a multi-million dollar payday — and a Lamborghini — collapsed after police uncovered liquid methamphetamine in canola oil bottles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92ccc82051fe3e10e4bfe3a2544597cf</guid></item><item><title>Pets on planes trial launches with first flight from Melbourne to Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/pets-on-plane-trial-launches-melbourne-gold-coast/105897770</link><description>Pets under 8 kilograms can now travel inside the passenger cabin on selected flights between Melbourne and the Gold and Sunshine Coasts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b5ae7ea04c0deb33f2236309eaa3f58</guid></item><item><title>Mother who faked son's cancer diagnosis pleads guilty to 11 charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/mum-who-faked-sons-cancer-diagnosis-pleads-guilty/105899556</link><description>A South Australian woman has pleaded guilty to 11 charges after she faked her six-year-old son's cancer diagnosis in a bid to raise more than $11,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c2e5d37ec4bcc47a6d8f6a555affc95</guid></item><item><title>Hope at last for families as NSW backs inquiry into unsolved murders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/hope-as-nsw-backs-probe-into-unsolved-murders/105898598</link><description>The NSW Parliament has backed an inquiry into decades of unsolved murders and missing persons cases, following a campaign led by Illawarra families.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">967e3ff5e688cbc3cc4d948f1955a838</guid></item><item><title>Assassin who killed Nick Martin at Kwinana Motorplex takes stand in David Pye murder trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/nick-martin-assassin-takes-stand-in-david-pye-murder-trial/105898658</link><description>The man accused of orchestrating the murder of a Perth bikie boss at a suburban speedway did so because of tensions arising from his defection to a rival gang, a court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc6bf7ec9a0285b7ae72294da6659da5</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar's president Andry Rajoelina rose to power off youth discontent and was taken down by it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/madagascar-explainer-andry-rajoelina-president-ousted/105898028</link><description>Former DJ Andry Rajoelina was the world's youngest head of state when he came to power in Madagascar in a 2009 coup. The military and youth movement were pivotal in his rise — and fall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18df5036d8670e01811282249766d2e5</guid></item><item><title>Curators among 45 full-time jobs to be axed in Art Gallery of NSW cuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/curators-among-45-jobs-to-be-axed-at-art-gallery-of-nsw/105892942</link><description>Leaked documents show curators and conservator jobs will go as 45 full-time roles are cut from the Art Gallery of NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cf617a6570a7217321d8d4482b5215b</guid></item><item><title>Review: After the Hunt has noble ambitions but misses the mark</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/after-the-hunt-julia-roberts-review/105876254</link><description>The ingredients are all here — public scandal, duelling divas and unearthed secrets — but Luca Guadagnino's provocative drama misses the mark.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f67b806ed73e7ac77c9e5486230066b3</guid></item><item><title>Albanese dismisses lobby concerns, Chalmers takes one for the team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/anthony-albanese-jim-chalmers-good-oppositions/105884222</link><description>This week, the PM was not wasting any time on "this" issue, and the treasurer took one for the team as Brett Worthington signs off with his final political wrap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8caaca04017f6e10ef0a87a9a892f94f</guid></item><item><title>Coroner expresses 'horror' at lack of infrastructure upgrades after 2022 Eugowra flood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/eugowra-inquest-day-four/105898058</link><description>A coroner has expressed "horror" at the lack of modern river gauge infrastructure around the NSW inland community of Eugowra three years after it was smashed by record-breaking floods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfabe5218f015faa669d4da3b163dd62</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government approves Arrow Energy gas plant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/darling-downs-arrow-energy-gas-plant-approval/105900018</link><description>The Queensland government's recent approval of a major coal seam gas-processing facility three kilometres from a farming family's home has left them feeling "extremely disappointed".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cfb1f65a2244ef0e91ff8d80b92092e</guid></item><item><title>Former Ballarat dentist Ian Lomax suspended after alleged Neo-Nazi ties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/former-ballarat-dentist-suspended-after-alleged-neo-nazi-ties/105876992</link><description>Dental board suspends practitioner, who was allegedly photographed at a Neo-Nazi rally, while it investigates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">318fe292d66345273a778b72f5f069a7</guid></item><item><title>Essendon CEO says Hawthorn AFL trade tactics for Zach Merrett were surprising</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/essendon-ceo-says-hawthorn-afl-trade-tactics-merrett-surprising/105900392</link><description>Essendon chief executive Craig Vozzo says the club was surprised Hawthorn waited until late in the AFL trade period to make an offer for their captain, Zach Merrett.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e96f0a6c62b0d3f1e70f37fd7a66a0b2</guid></item><item><title>The Hobart Clinic rescue hinges on Monday shareholder meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/hobart-clinic-rescue-hinges-on-monday-meeting/105893386</link><description>Despite the offer of a $2 million lifeline to keep a private mental health clinic in Hobart open, last-minute wobbles could yet scupper the rescue bid, as the clinic's shareholders prepare to meet on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bc39e20ce0caab5b58da7fe6590d2ae</guid></item><item><title>Mark Haines inquest hears differing opinions from detectives on teen's mysterious death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/mark-haines-inquest-hears-from-detectives-and-homicide-squad/105887822</link><description>Thirty seven years after his death, police still cannot agree on how 17-year-old Mark Haines came to be found on train tracks near Tamworth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f08356610886575aa5a825b2c6af363e</guid></item><item><title>Siver Ferns coaching saga casts shadow over Constellation Cup opener against Diamonds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/silver-ferns-coaching-saga-diamonds-constellation-cup/105900692</link><description>Imploring New Zealand Netball to reinstate coach Noeline Taurua, Silver Ferns skipper Karin Burger believes her team can put the turmoil aside when they face Australia in the Constellation Cup opener.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1e4ab0f4d9f51f247913a2c29d87c82</guid></item><item><title>Teddy Swims tells SXSW Sydney he uses AI when making music, but warns of its dangers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/teddy-swims-tells-sxsw-sydney-he-uses-ai-in-music/105897908</link><description>Grammy-nominated music artist Teddy Swims says AI is a "beautiful tool" when it comes to composing music. Swims was in conversation at SXSW Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dcc839da82c48def79030a917173b7e</guid></item><item><title>Ariarne Titmus's greatest races, from Olympic golds, world records and surprise silvers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/ariarne-titmus-a-swimming-legend-races/105899372</link><description>The races that made Ariarne Titmus an Australian legend, from her maiden world championships appearance to her perfect Paris farewell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db607ccb521dd952dfad409a01b1c02e</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian and Jewish communities in Australia watch on with caution over Gaza peace plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/palestinian-jewish-people-australia-react-to-gaza-peace-plan/105896464</link><description>Samer Tarazi is one of thousands with strong ties to the Middle East region, watching from afar to see what the US-led peace plan means for the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">404b4d3c975048899e4387620de98f34</guid></item><item><title>Essential workers cannot afford to rent in Western Australia, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/rental-affordability-crisis-for-essential-workers-social-housing/105899042</link><description>A new report shows there are just 16 affordable properties across the state for hospitality and childcare workers. It gets far worse if you live in a regional area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82a46d873a6470d760ba4816c9f6e2e2</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with manslaughter over St James sudden death in Perth's south east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/wa-st-james-sudden-death-investigation/105900760</link><description>Homicide squad detectives charge a 33-year-old man with manslaughter over the sudden death of a 25-year-old man in Perth's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d5a1388158f509c28aca638005b14ff</guid></item><item><title>Diabetes-related condition cause of Emma Bates' death, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/doctor-gives-evidence-in-john-torney-emma-bates-case/105893266</link><description>A medical expert has told a court hearing for a man charged with negligent manslaughter that a 49-year-old woman died from a diabetes-related condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5ae2f81c26d9d8f668485f8ae209b0a</guid></item><item><title>Darling Downs man found guilty of manslaughter of Russell Klein on Christmas Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/callum-anthony-padaric-cook-guilty-of-manslaughter/105895696</link><description>A jury finds Callum Anthony Padaric Cook guilty of the manslaughter of Russell Klein, who died after he was struck by Cook's car outside his home on Christmas Day in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ab4e41b1c61d4eba3870f84b5bbd652</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne improves Ashes Test case with another century for Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/marnus-labuschagne-scores-century-for-queensland-sa/105900926</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne has added to his case for selection in Australia's Test team for the Ashes, making an emphatic case for selection with his fourth century in five innings for Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c8ce13cfc70e71af84960d841aaf47</guid></item><item><title>Diane Keaton's family releases cause of death, urging tributes to homelessness services and animal shelters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/diane-keaton-cause-of-death-released/105898904</link><description>The actor's family says the 79-year-old died of pneumonia, expressing gratitude for the "extraordinary messages of love and support" received following news of her passing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ad4d9062c3fd28201c61a47954bccd0</guid></item><item><title>Release of Virginia Giuffre's memoir renews sex allegations against Prince Andrew</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/virginia-giuffre-book-prince-andrew-allegations-jeffrey-epstein/105898044</link><description>Extracts from Virginia Giuffre's posthumously released memoir have further intensified the recently renewed scrutiny on Prince Andrew.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40e21158edb995f36869ca565b0e2b53</guid></item><item><title>Cohealth's closure of three Melbourne GP clinics to affect 12,500 patients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/melbourne-cohealth-gp-clinics-closing/105897006</link><description>Inner-city Melbourne community health service cohealth will be shuttering its GP services at the end of the year, citing escalating costs and aging infrastructure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">206d1831d09920250b9663ff89ae7f92</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/thursday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/105900826</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39251dff22abd93c574816fddff415b9</guid></item><item><title>National Gallery will host APY artwork exhibition after paintings cleared of improper interference</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/act-apy-indigenous-art-interference-national-gallery-exhibition/105901272</link><description>The National Gallery will host an exhibition of art from the Aṉangu Pitjantjatjara Yankunytjatjara Lands three years after a video appearing to show a non-Aboriginal assistant helping to paint an artwork led to it being postponed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f256cd75d8dd22a070a0b023a2212e2</guid></item><item><title>Tasma Walton and Robbie Arnott share $100,000 ARA Historical Novel Prize</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/tasma-walton-robbie-arnott-ara-historical-novel-prize-2025/105886334</link><description>Robbie Arnott's Dusk about twins hunting a puma in Tasmania, and Tasma Walton's I Am Nannertgarrook about an Aboriginal woman kidnapped and sold into slavery, have tied to win the ARA Historical Novel Prize.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36563ad06ad055a6eaead4a3f8596a89</guid></item><item><title>Rugby Championship scrapped for 2026 due to Test calendar squeeze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/rugby-championship-scrapped-for-2026-test-season/105901714</link><description>The competition will not be played next year but will appear on the global calendar the following three years, including ahead of the 2027 Rugby World Cup, the organisers say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84c38b2c85ed36bf3a8054c41860989d</guid></item><item><title>Alyssa Healy scores second straight century as Australia qualifies for World Cup semis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/womens-world-cup-australia-beats-bangladesh-for-semifinal-berth/105899700</link><description>Australian captain Alyssa Healy scores her second straight century as her side maintains its unbeaten record at the cricket World Cup with a 10-wicket win over Bangladesh.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa8f9519f2a73e65f2eef48c11a9f988</guid></item><item><title>Female shearer sets world record by shearing 500 merino lambs in one day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/female-shearer-sets-world-record-by-shearing-500-merino-lambs-in/105901376</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f540d190f772539d16d4658bec564b0</guid></item><item><title>Government unveils a plan to combat South Australian algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/plan-to-combat-sa-algal-bloom/105900918</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb673ff2efdfdb07d4b825046c407370</guid></item><item><title>French PM Sebastien Lecornu survives no-confidence votes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/french-pm-sebastien-lecornu-survives-no-confidence-votes/105901916</link><description>Despite the reprieve, the motions underscore the fragility of President Emmanuel Macron's administration midway through his final term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef9eb69bc5c812ba483714c1ea1b2bea</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says Narendra Modi has pledged that India will stop buying Russian oil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/donald-trump-says-india-will-stop-buying-russian-oil/105901976</link><description>The US president says his Indian counterpart has made the pledge, as pressure continues to mount over the purchases that fund Moscow's war in Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfa3d657832c0a2a078b14f16d2fc9e8</guid></item><item><title>Israel claims killing Houthi military chief of staff in strikes on rebel group leaders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/israel-claims-killing-houthi-military-chief/105902004</link><description>An Israeli air strike targeting top leaders in Yemen's Houthi rebels in August killed its military's chief of staff, officials say, further escalating the tensions between the group and Israel even as a ceasefire holds in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bae806be897ad5b63d1942e4f84cc100</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump and Vladimir Putin to discuss Ukraine war at Budapest summit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/donald-trump-vladimir-putin-to-meet-again/105902260</link><description>Donald Trump and Vladimir Putin will meet face-to-face in Hungary to discuss ending Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine, the US president announces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87e82ba667b74fbf2ab5298f72f1c729</guid></item><item><title>Calls for Australia to follow England's ban on supermarket junk food specials</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/calls-for-australia-to-follow-england-ban-on-junk-food-specials/105807974</link><description>Research finding supermarkets continue to offer discounts and multi-buy deals on junk food more frequently than healthy food prompts calls for Australia to follow England's lead and ban "buy one, get one free" deals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edbe2cd8f08f8c2fc9c6395f9edf30b7</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian journalist Shadi Abu Sido reunites with his family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/palestinian-journalist-shadi-abu-sido-reunites-with-his-family/105900342</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4444ed700101dc4a34dd62cee2419b5</guid></item><item><title>More Palestinian prisoners allege mistreatment in Israeli prison system after being reunited with their families</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/palestinian-prisoners-allege-mistreatment-in-israel/105895592</link><description>Shadi Abu Sido spent 18 months in Israeli detention believing that his entire family had been killed in Gaza. Then he was reunited with his wife and children in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c31a6cc30147c611bd4bfc23280a0c4</guid></item><item><title>Temperatures across Australia to soar, threatening October records</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/forecast-for-australian-weather-weekend-high-records-october/105901378</link><description>Unseasonable temperatures have lasted along the eastern seaboard for weeks — which has Sydney, and possibly Brisbane, on track to observe their warmest October on record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f4bf36d4491c7073e70092e07ba68cc</guid></item><item><title>Oil leaking from WW2 shipwreck the Rio de Janeiro Maru in Chuuk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/oil-leaking-from-ww2-shipwreck-the-rio-de-janeiro-maru-in-chuuk/105889748</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2be0837ab0fb4ac0467e1f6078adc4e</guid></item><item><title>WWII shipwrecks a 'ticking time bomb' for Federated States of Micronesia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/war-relics-threat-for-federated-states-of-micronesia/105884710</link><description>The Federated States of Micronesia's biggest tourism asset has become one of its largest threats, with as much as 22 million litres of oil from World War II shipwrecks slowly leaking into the ocean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5a5e22c5b7f81e23acf8feb4ae870bd</guid></item><item><title>'Dangerously low' funding to Tasmanian arts sector creating reputational damage, minister warned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/tasmanian-arts-industry-highly-vulnerable-low-funding-investment/105899498</link><description>"Dangerously low" arts sector funding has rendered the Tasmanian industry "highly vulnerable", with funding stagnant since 2016-17, the state government has conceded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a29de7c4d5bc252c9a785dea93220878</guid></item><item><title>Jim Chalmers and Tony Burke are in a long race for prime position</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/jim-chalmers-tony-burke-leadership/105884226</link><description>There is general agreement in Labor that Jim Chalmers is the government's best communicator. But insiders watching this race know Tony Burke is the master tactician.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93f58dc170f3f37c70cca03a69e3a6f5</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: A deported star, a shock retirement and the hottest place on Earth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/abc-weekly-news-quiz-oct-17/105899240</link><description>It's that time of the week again. Test your news knowledge to see how much you remember for the week that was.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcb568d8e78190bb9398f72d37d5bd5c</guid></item><item><title>Expanded search for Gus nears conclusion as missing persons advocate speaks out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/renewed-search-for-missing-boy-gus-continues-in-sa-outback/105900448</link><description>As SA Police and ADF personnel prepare to scour remaining areas in an expanded search zone for four-year-old Gus, a missing persons advocate has spoken out about the emotional impact of such cases on all families who have experienced the disappearance of a loved one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a97a1bed1323118fc2f898d318dc3426</guid></item><item><title>Drunken motorcyclist crashes with daughter riding as passenger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/drunken-motorcyclist-crashes-with-daughter-passenger/105898498</link><description>A Mildura father-of-six avoids jail after drunkenly crashing his motorbike while carrying his young daughter as a passenger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b7dbbdb3b9ed775f287c7490a9599c8</guid></item><item><title>Dog attacks have been making headlines recently. How can they be prevented and who is responsible?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/dog-attacks-who-is-responsible-explainer/105884928</link><description>A behavioural veterinarian says there's not usually one direct cause for dogs attacking, and owner education could help improve the rate of horror incidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">963be610b2b5f839c77cf2252bf5c5a7</guid></item><item><title>Warnings for explicit deepfakes, 'image-based abuse' amid rise of AI technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/sydney-school-students-explicit-ai-images-investigation-police/105901372</link><description>A senior academic has warned a Sydney school caught up in an investigation into digitally altered explicit images of female students is just "another shocking iteration" of gendered violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9bb776a70b24518b0d2a82348f1046f</guid></item><item><title>Live: ASX slips as gold price surges to new record above $US4,300</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/asx-markets-business-live-news-date-year/105902438</link><description>The Australian share market falls after a downbeat session on Wall Street, weighed down by a sell-off across US regional bank stocks. Gold jumped to a new record high, above $US4,300 an ounce, as investors flocked to safe haven assets amid US-China trade tensions. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c45f9ed11d3fac698ab6fe04be5606</guid></item><item><title>BHP vs China Inc: What the iron ore dispute says about Australia's present and future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/what-bhp-china-iron-ore-dispute-means-to-australia/105901692</link><description>The resolution of negotiations between Australian mining giant BHP and China's state-backed iron ore buyer China Mineral Resources Group could reshape not just the resources industry, but also international trade flows, global markets, and the relationship between China and the West.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f17745151acc39e0b5f38368c4928c68</guid></item><item><title>Lucy Derbyshire hunting first Coolangatta Gold win, enters Iron Series as defending champion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/lucy-derbyshire-hunting-first-coolangatta-gold-win-iron-series/105806790</link><description>Lucy Derbyshire enters this year's Iron Series as the defending champion and has set her sights on winning the Coolangatta Gold for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59032c6abfd46454ff5e9b348f7ebe8b</guid></item><item><title>From cult web series to cinema: Nirvanna the Band the Show the Movie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/nirvanna-the-band-the-show-the-movie/105898756</link><description>Canada's cult web series heads to the big screen, after creators Matt Johnson and Jay McCarrol were told they could make any movie they liked after their success with BlackBerry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcab9960bf8462cac061bee2cf98745a</guid></item><item><title>Zach Merrett trade drama a reminder that deals can no longer be judged by amount of first-round picks involved</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/afl-trade-period-analysis-zach-merrett-first-round-pick-value/105898588</link><description>The AFL trade period offered three different test cases on just how much value a first-round pick holds during negotiations. Two stars got their moves, while one was left stranded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28e8bb8d5802a90c22f1d69d1a4727c3</guid></item><item><title>New research shows impact of lead poisoning on ancient humans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/new-research-shows-impact-lead-poisoning-ancient-humans/105899188</link><description>A new study claims lead might be the reason why Homo sapiens came to dominate the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12aa86f8c8828a99bbdb6054ea89c8c1</guid></item><item><title>Minjee Lee and defending champion Hannah Green off to slow start in BMW Ladies Championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/golf-bmw-ladies-championship-minjee-lee-hannah-green/105902436</link><description>Australia's golf aces are left needing to play catch-up as a hometown hero sets the pace to begin the BMW Ladies Championship in South Korea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67729e59f0132de72f0cf0af030fb54e</guid></item><item><title>Dangerous flammable cladding still not removed from dozens of NSW high-rise apartment buildings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/government-yet-to-fix-cladding-on-dozens-of-apartments-re-scheme/105900296</link><description>Dozens of high-rise apartment buildings across the state are still covered in flammable cladding as the NSW government's scheme has failed to fix them on schedule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">900570fd41fc7cafb3f056a176d7d52c</guid></item><item><title>Shocking CCTV footage shows moment bus driver assaulted while driving down Darwin highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/nt-bus-driver-assaulted-cctv-footage-played-in-court/105901292</link><description>Shocking video footage capturing the moment a bus driver was assaulted, and passengers were thrown through the air, has been played in the NT Supreme Court after the attacker pleaded guilty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72512a66b5c068ddcb13f9e41634e0e4</guid></item><item><title>Specialist health services shortfall for women in regional WA leave many struggling for support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/women-missing-out-on-specialist-health-services-in-regional-wa/105866424</link><description>Faced with a lack of specialist women's health services, women in regional WA are researching their own conditions and volunteering to raise awareness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a46a1f1f255a795ba616233f2bb18c5</guid></item><item><title>How a 15yo autistic boy tinkering in his bedroom triggered WA's biggest ever data breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/joshua-unwittingly-triggered-major-wa-health-data-breach-autism/105455250</link><description>Joshua's "passion project" with a radio scanner led to one of WA's most significant public health data breaches. His story highlights the challenges confronting autistic people caught up in the legal system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13c71de037de480416dd879b9c6eab51</guid></item><item><title>Former Trump national security adviser John Bolton indicted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/ex-trump-national-security-adviser-charged-in-probe/105902540</link><description>Donald Trump's former national security adviser John Bolton has been charged with mishandling classified information.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d572b768f51c9023aa7d06f2a1ca468b</guid></item><item><title>Younger candidates out to bring change in WA local government elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/young-candidates-seek-change-in-wa-local-government-elections/105888820</link><description>In the last local government elections in WA, the average age of candidates running for councils was 53 years old — but these young candidates are keen to lower that figure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">612d6039eb66ee2883e4b90a17276dfe</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government seeks private market interest to develop riverside precinct in South Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/qld-riverfront-precinct-south-brisbane-private-sector/105902488</link><description>The government says construction could begin from March 2027 and has suggested the site could feature over 4,000 homes, as well as "event lawns" and promenades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71e510b6fa92de09ab4aec4b9b044d41</guid></item><item><title>NicheLiving customers continue to find defects</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/nicheliving-customers-continue-to-find-defects/105899574</link><description>Nicheliving customer Kathy Ellis thought her three-year nightmare was finally over in July, only to discover defective plumbing work in her new house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c827db340a1c42daeb836818d1a1c034</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says he will meet with Vladimir Putin 'within two weeks or so'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/donald-trump-says-he-will-meet-with-putin-within-two-weeks-/105902626</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3952d5581444934dd2d638c3febb4800</guid></item><item><title>McLaren's 'papaya rules' may be over as Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris battle for the F1 drivers' championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/mclaren-papaya-rules-oscar-piastri-lando-norris-f1/105855110</link><description>"Papaya rules" have dominated Formula 1 for two seasons, but with both McLaren drivers in the heat of a world championship battle, Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris may no longer prioritise what is best for the team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c1dd9f6429245aceb6baaa21e041d3e</guid></item><item><title>Starmer criticises police decision to ban fans of Israel's Maccabi Tel Aviv from Aston Villa match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/football-maccabi-tel-aviv-fans-banned-police-aston-villa/105902590</link><description>Fans of Israel's Maccabi Tel Aviv are banned from attending next month's Europa League match against Aston Villa in Birmingham over "public safety concerns".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">effc61153d88fcce13575af2eb2a3f1c</guid></item><item><title>Woman stabbed in Melbourne's CBD in broad daylight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/woman-stabbed-in-melbourne-s-cbd-in-broad-daylight/105902728</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d3d70526290bba71783eacb1628cb9c</guid></item><item><title>Stabbing attack in Melbourne's CBD more evidence Victoria is nation's crime capital, opposition says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/melbourne-cbd-stabbing-attack-opposition/105902598</link><description>CCTV footage has emerged showing a random stabbing attack in Melbourne's CBD earlier this month. The Victorian opposition says its more evidence of Victoria's standing as the country's 'crime capital.'</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a90a763d98aa94226b4d5deddcd22873</guid></item><item><title>Coronado Curragh fined for death of miner Clark Peadon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/coronado-curragh-fined-for-death-of-worker-clark-peadon/105893210</link><description>The MEU has described the fine as "inadequate" for the loss of someone's life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">302b71db67d68b4b399d0e78f4be1f6f</guid></item><item><title>Ace Frehley, founding member of rock group KISS, dies at 74</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/ace-frehley-guitarist-kiss-dies-aged-74/105902920</link><description>The original lead guitarist of the glam rock band captivated audiences with his elaborate makeup and smoke-filled guitar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70f68f5def708160810eec0ad80e8354</guid></item><item><title>Outback communities reflect on actions taken one year on from power outages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/transgrid-broken-hill-outage-one-year-on/105893212</link><description>In October 2024, thousands of households and businesses in far west NSW were hit by a catastrophic power outage that lasted for weeks, and the fallout continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13ae63395f1d58aa22c7422571e058ce</guid></item><item><title>King Charles commemorates 40th anniversary of Uluru handback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/king-charles-commemorates-40th-anniversary-of-uluru-handback/105902056</link><description>King Charles marked the major milestone in Aboriginal land rights alongside Uluru-Kata Tjuta's traditional owners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7d5382ea3e29445cd53373bb9eda014</guid></item><item><title>Australian swimming star Ariarne Titmus says she lost 'fire in the belly' before shock retirement call</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/swimming-ariarne-titmus-retirement-press-conference/105902788</link><description>Ariarne Titmus has spoken publicly for the first time after abruptly retiring from professional swimming at just 25, revealing the reasons behind her decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce4208efcf5ba5f558acc40ad5edc802</guid></item><item><title>Southern Mallee Council mayor found by ombudsman to have engaged in misconduct</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/southern-mallee-mayor-misconduct-apology/105898854</link><description>The South Australian ombudsman says Southern Mallee Council Mayor Ron Valentine improperly used his position to gain an advantage for himself in the recruitment of a CEO in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">968cba559352190fb4a9912978cceb6f</guid></item><item><title>SA Education Department fined after teen fell from school playground swing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/sa-education-department-fined-playground-swing-fall/105900366</link><description>South Australia's Education Department has been fined $225,000 after a student at a special school fell from a swing which had not had a comprehensive safety inspection for eight years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cdc7ec760bf1e318791fcad162c615f</guid></item><item><title>Defence in talks to support Gaza peace plan but Australia says no request yet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/defence-in-talks-with-us-to-support-gaza-peace-plan/105902742</link><description>Australia's defence force has had discussions with the Unted States to provide support for its Gaza peace plan but the government says no formal request has been made yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd80619b996f35eb17de143a6b7e07dc</guid></item><item><title>Virtual emergency department a lifeline for patients in regional areas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/virtual-emergency-department-option-for-patients-remote-areas/105371852</link><description>A virtual emergency room app created during the pandemic could help bridge healthcare gaps in regional Victoria. But more patients need to dial-in and use the resource.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cce3e05039289d83c6bdbae0a5d4e7b</guid></item><item><title>How wild bird poo testing in northern Australia is helping keep eggs on the shelves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/bird-flu-poo-testing-in-northern-australia-keeps-eggs-on-shelves/105894598</link><description>Hundreds of kilometres from the nearest supermarket, Indigenous rangers in Australia's remote north are working to keep eggs on your breakfast table.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">126bc279f84d1b05bc9d6ac31fa6b513</guid></item><item><title>Five people taken to hospital after chemical leak at Australia Post offices in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/chemical-leak-australia-post-offices-north-queensland/105903264</link><description>Authorities are working to identify the chemical that leaked from a single package at two post offices in Queensland. Four people of the people who were taken to hospital earlier have now been discharged.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e24a3f69a465e0085b9ba95a2817ceb</guid></item><item><title>Indigiearth founder inspires Indigenous women to chase business dreams</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/indigiearth-award-sharon-winsor-australian-cuisine/105899236</link><description>Sharon Winsor is honoured for her pioneering work in native Australian cuisine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9867852928883c2abad3f488c0d1bf3b</guid></item><item><title>Bears kill record number of people in Japan amid scores of attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/record-number-of-bear-attacks-in-japan/105902770</link><description>At least seven people have been killed by bears in the country since April and many more have been injured as the hungry animals venture into human territory to find food.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41b4b93bb120166534952debb22263e8</guid></item><item><title>US dangled threat of Tomahawks for Ukraine, then Russia called to negotiate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/us-tomahawk-long-range-missiles-supply-ukraine-russia-talks/105884192</link><description>US President Donald Trump threatened to send Tomahawk missiles to Ukraine if Russia did not return to peace talks, but analysts say the long-range weapons are not the game-changer they are made out to be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab37297fc9b45cbc08d59856d14f85f4</guid></item><item><title>Renters despair in 'landlord's market' where no-grounds evictions and frequent rent rises are legal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/nt-rental-housing-standards-no-grounds-eviction-rent-rises/105900204</link><description>Renters and experts are calling for change in one of just two Australian jurisdictions where renters can be evicted for no reason and the only place where landlords can raise rents more than once a year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73136c6fb3e9f3567290edd360f36a95</guid></item><item><title>Venezuela says US strike on suspected drug vessel 'extrajudicial executions'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/new-usa-strike-on-venezuelan-drugs-boat-leaves-survivors/105903128</link><description>A US strike against a suspected Venezuelan drug-smuggling vessel has left multiple survivors, as Venezuela's ambassador to the United Nations condemned the strikes as a "series of assassinations".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a3ad366e7e0f7f78fc016c52b612098</guid></item><item><title>King Charles commemorates 40th anniversary of Uluru-Kata Tjuta handover</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/king-charles-commemorates-40th-anniversary/105903854</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c93eec247a1e442de98f772d2428ec4</guid></item><item><title>'No doubt' Anthony Albanese and Donald Trump will discuss critical minerals: Chalmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/albanese-trump-chalmers-critical-minerals-deal/105903392</link><description>Anthony Albanese will "no doubt" use a meeting with Donald Trump next week to discuss critical minerals, the treasurer says as he dismisses a call for Australia to "decouple" with China over rare earth materials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fe4351ff10e966c7a84c8e260555fa8</guid></item><item><title>Hamish McIntyre elected new president of National Farmers' Federation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/hamish-mcintyre-new-president-of-national-farmers-federation/105903736</link><description>Hamish McIntyre is named the new president of Australia's peak farmer representative body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c317e433f02d76c14e44c86f15f08ecd</guid></item><item><title>Police renew appeal for information as 'inconsistencies' identified in 2022 death of toddler in Burpengary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/qld-police-call-for-witnesses-burpengary-toddler-death-2022/105904174</link><description>Detectives are renewing calls for witnesses as they investigate the suspicious death of a 16-month-old boy in Burpengary in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37d9e03fda64f4811d650ec7aaa2a85d</guid></item><item><title>Pacific Championships set to start without Australia as strong Samoa and Tonga teams take on New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/pacific-championships-stars-embrace-their-island-heritage/105903826</link><description>Emerging superpowers Samoa and Tonga will field formidable teams loaded with NRL talent in the third edition of the Pacific Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07fb63cc9e9ec53c5f2664aaf516d600</guid></item><item><title>Missing man Troy Milne found alive in bushland more than two hours from campsite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/missing-man-found-troy-milne-fire-gippsland/105904026</link><description>A man who was missing in Victoria's east for more than a week is recovering in hospital after being found in bushland when he started a fire to draw attention to his location.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c75d2afbeefc32496c0ab94cbb90f22</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill man wins appeal of sentence for animal cruelty offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/broken-hill-man-animal-cruelty-offences-appeal/105903070</link><description>Jet Jai Johnson is released from prison two-and-a-half months into his 14-month sentence after telling a court spending his 21st birthday behind bars was a wake-up call.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ad3f1fe76e5d052feb967d866f79777</guid></item><item><title>WA's insolvent Griffin Coal ramps up operations as taxpayer bailout deadline looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/insolvent-wa-griffin-coal-ramps-up-operations/105901120</link><description>The receiver of a WA coal mine says it is ramping up operations in a final attempt to trade out of insolvency before millions of dollars in taxpayer support dries up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2e888ffc914c66fe0fec7316e9144da</guid></item><item><title>Pet-friendly flights are taking off in Australia. Here's what to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/pet-friendly-flights-what-to-know/105903876</link><description>The first pet-friendly commercial flights have taken off in Australia this week. Here's what you need to know about the new service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4379a2d55c184d75fb0dbc167127d3db</guid></item></channel></rss>