<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 23:43:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Sussan Ley apologises for Jacinta Nampijinpa Price's remarks about Indian migrants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/jacinta-nampijinpa-price-liberals-react-sacking/105760472</link><description>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley apologises for Jacinta Nampijinpa Price's remarks that "hurt" Indian Australians eight days after they were first made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b16a692a5b37ba90b0230552e964581</guid></item><item><title>Heritage protection top priority for Pilbara traditional owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/heritage-protection-top-priority-for-pilbara-traditional-owners/105748362</link><description>The traditional owners of Juukan Gorge have celebrated 10 years of native title determination and shared plans to safeguard heritage sites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2b63dfb64660699087909555e221c07</guid></item><item><title>Environmentalists want new dump site for dredged mud around Magnetic Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/magnetic-island-world-heritage-area-dredged-mud/105739090</link><description>Tourists flock to Magnetic Island to see its unique coral reefs, but locals say underwater visibility is getting worse — and some blame dredging.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">402c451164dd97863a3e4caaa889864c</guid></item><item><title>Freestyle motocross rider Clinton Moore lands 'impossible' world-first 720 trick</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/clinton-moore-lands-world-first-freestyle-motocross-720-trick/105752952</link><description>It's taken more than 15 years and countless failed attempts, but freestyle motocross rider Clinton Moore has landed the "impossible" trick.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b48362b2c83094dcb23e1ca238fbba8d</guid></item><item><title>Australian FMX rider Clinton Moore lands 720 trick</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/australian-fmx-rider-clinton-moore-lands-720-trick/105748934</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b750776abb60a888ae4a0a4f4496216</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese wears the wrong shirt to a Pacific Islands Forum meeting.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/anthony-albanese-wears-the-wrong-shirt-to-a/105761810</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0698d65c7693475092a9c20efd3e420e</guid></item><item><title>Jess Fox announces she will miss Canoe Slalom World Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/jess-fox-announces-she-will-miss-canoe-slalom/105762586</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5dc18bb88857142cc4820e1ddcca090</guid></item><item><title>Zach Merrett's meeting with Hawthorn has given Essendon a chance to become a ruthless football club once again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/afl-zach-merrett-hawthorn-meeting-essendon-culture-analysis/105757688</link><description>Essendon has gone from an AFL powerhouse to a cellar-dweller due to its inability to make tough decisions over the last two decades, and now its captain has offered the club a chance to flip the script.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8384497c62ff7a3ac09bf2775c0e31b4</guid></item><item><title>Canterbury Bulldogs recall Toby Sexton, axe Reed Mahoney for NRL finals against Melbourne Storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/canterbury-bulldogs-axe-reed-mahoney-for-toby-sexton/105762352</link><description>Canterbury coach Cameron Ciraldo has confirmed the bold selection call to axe Reed Mahoney from the qualifying final squad to face Melbourne and recall Toby Sexton.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8299dd0d00e67f343a66f7cde293f42</guid></item><item><title>Is the pink soap scum in my bathroom mould, or something else?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/why-is-the-soap-scum-in-my-bathroom-pink-and-orange-/105721212</link><description>Have you ever noticed a pink or orange-coloured substance in the tile grout or around taps in your bathroom? In most cases, it's one of two things.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9deb3308036c00d500826ba08d50f062</guid></item><item><title>What videos from the scene tell us about Charlie Kirk’s 'political assassination'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/verify-what-we-know-about-the-charlie-kirk-assassination/105761534</link><description>Verified videos taken at the scene of the shooting of high-profile right-wing activist Charlie Kirk show what appears to be a figure on the roof of a nearby building.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24160b081eec81b32cd9932baf801b0b</guid></item><item><title>Measles outbreak declared in Cairns after cases linked to Bali travel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/measles-outbreak-declared-in-cairns/105762482</link><description>Health officials in Cairns publish a list of potential measles exposure sites after a locally acquired case of the illness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f201a5a54f95ccc742a4fb02a779b93</guid></item><item><title>A Nampijinpa Price-sized chink in Ley's armour might have given Labor a campaign edge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/jacinta-nampijinpa-price-sussan-ley-armour-election/105745506</link><description>The Jacinta Nampijinpa Price saga is a chink in Sussan Ley's armour and at the very least has handed Labor damaging material for their 2028 election campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f675f2ca4f69a3fbd020a7e26196ccf0</guid></item><item><title>How Hawthorn and Gold Coast proceed to the AFL preliminary finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/how-hawthorn-and-gold-coast-get-to-prelim-finals/105762028</link><description>Hawthorn and Gold Coast go into their cut-throat semifinals with reasons for some confidence against the Crows and Lions. Cody Atkinson and Sean Lawson look into the factors driving both teams' September runs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bee6f2e0e1aee53ecd326cca279df14</guid></item><item><title>Exhibition of ceramic work by Purple House dialysis patients opens in Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/purple-house-dialysis-patients-ceramics-exhibition-alice-springs/105762128</link><description>Between treatments, Purple House patients have been creating colourful works of ceramic art. The results are now on display in Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b06662e346a171d11fdb5732df22f736</guid></item><item><title>'Bubble curtain' ready to protect cuttlefish as algal bloom persists in SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/algal-bloom-bubble-curtain-ready-as-asthma-advice-defended/105761978</link><description>A "bubble curtain" is set for activation as part of South Australia's fight against the ongoing algal bloom, as the state government defends its handling of health advice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c99d09af36c76bdbcccd8ef52874b9da</guid></item><item><title>Ley's frontbench replacement pick 'being watched really closely' as fallout from migration saga continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/jostling-for-nampijinpa-prices-frontbench-replacement-underway/105762238</link><description>Machinations over who will replace Liberal senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price on the Coalition frontbench are already underway, with the party's right warning it would be "incendiary" if the position was handed to someone from the left.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fcb480f58d90526a3ee3a5fda2ccb3b</guid></item><item><title>All Consuming | Kate Reid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/all-consuming-kate-reid/105763908</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3466116ad88226d6f90355d99b0d918</guid></item><item><title>OECD chief Mathias Cormann urges Australians to keep open mind about nuclear power amid climate target debate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/oecd-mathias-cormann-australia-nuclear-policy-climate-target/105764162</link><description>Secretary-General of the OECD and former Coalition finance minister Mathias Cormann suggests Australians keep an open mind to nuclear power, saying there isn't "anything inherently partisan" about the energy source.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23c894156f3a263a60e49bac027901b9</guid></item><item><title>All the latest finance news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/all-the-latest-finance-news/105764310</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdc15a69f4a3a97e08b06865b7ecc2a4</guid></item><item><title>Senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price appears at Liberal Party fundraiser in Perth, a day after front bench axing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/jacinta-nampijinpa-price-liberal-meeting-perth/105763152</link><description>Senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price attends a Liberal Party fundraiser in Perth, avoiding a sizeable media contingent who had gathered outside the event, a day after being axed from the shadow ministry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61da8a42d32e6ce6374dd17e223e01b8</guid></item><item><title>'Unconscionable' for Ireland to participate in Eurovision 2026 if Israel takes part, says broadcaster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/ireland-threatens-eurovision-boycott-if-isreal-takes-part/105764652</link><description>Irish national broadcaster RTE has said Ireland will not participate in Eurovision 2026 if Israel does, citing the ongoing and appalling loss of lives in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6e6c785f4a9425e849bb6220cf8b39f</guid></item><item><title>Growing group of Labor MPs urge 2035 emissions target above Climate Authority's floor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/labor-mps-urge-2035-target-within-climate-authority-advice/105762592</link><description>A growing cross-factional group within Labor is privately urging for Australia's next major climate target to respect the advice of the Climate Change Authority, which will hand its opinion on a 2035 target to government any day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">366f414d754ce8a4269105ca01955ee0</guid></item><item><title>'Clone' websites catch out Australian customers as online shopping scams become 'alarmingly' common</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/clone-websites-retailers-catch-out-online-shoppers-scam/105736854</link><description>Online shopping scams are now one of the most frequently reported scam types and experts say they are alarmingly common, impersonating well-known brands and being promoted in search engine advertisements.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d6cf1bf94f1b9a65d30881e571ce779</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: A lunar eclipse, the VMAs and a new richest person</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/weekly-news-quiz-vmas-lady-gaga-mariah-carey-lunar-eclipse/105763050</link><description>A lot happened this week. Have you been paying attention?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13fe50b4bed78863a9b92e0af6e36044</guid></item><item><title>Government urged to do more to address 2,500 hospital patients waiting for aged care beds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/federal-government-aged-care-hospital-beds-waitlist/105763730</link><description>States and territories will use a health ministers' meeting today to call on the federal government to do more to address what they say is a critical aged care crisis affecting hospitals around the nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">775dea44832f82b251e46e951ca9014f</guid></item><item><title>Queenslanders pay more than $4.5 million in fines after failing to vote in 2024 state election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/queensland-electoral-commission-voting-fines-state-election/105761396</link><description>Electoral Commission of Queensland data has revealed about 340,000 eligible Queenslanders failed to cast a vote at last year's state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20c10f9744349fd14e99fba7df2e4300</guid></item><item><title>Muslim groups call for rethink of approach to terrorism ahead of Islamophobia report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/muslim-groups-call-for-rethink-of-counter-terrorism-approach/105764246</link><description>Community leaders say the government must consider social and legal reforms to address a spike in Islamophobic incidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68f974fec4e114e80148da8649df2e39</guid></item><item><title>Sydney live music venue embraces grant for soundproofing amid noise complaint concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/nsw-government-grants-soundproofing-sydney-live-music-venues/105748102</link><description>When the Red Rattler theatre in Sydney's inner west installed acoustic foam in the walls behind its stage, it didn't just make the venue soundproof — but future-proof.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ff16aa762f54c42d123cbb2a78c68e5</guid></item><item><title>Toni Jordan spent her childhood at the greyhound track, inspiring her new novel Tenderfoot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/toni-jordan-books-tenderfoot-interview/105754310</link><description>The acclaimed author's father was a greyhound trainer and her mother ran a TAB. Her unconventional childhood inspired her eighth book, Tenderfoot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19370cb777b009a92f1855e8361e9d09</guid></item><item><title>3D-printed guns, internet-ordered drugs on the list for Crime Stoppers in Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/tasmania-crime-stoppers-3d-guns-drugs-tip-offs/105754796</link><description>While they may look strange, even toy-like, 3D-printed weapons can still be deadly — and they are high on the watchlist for police in Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4cd3763ba4465b166d38c248751263b</guid></item><item><title>Northern Territory Corrections Department honours 20th anniversary of Elders Visiting Program in prisons</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/aboriginal-elders-visiting-nt-prisons-program-20th-anniversary/105762476</link><description>A decades-long partnership between Indigenous elders and the Northern Territory’s prison system is helping prisoners reconnect with culture and encouraging them to turn their lives around.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d147bcd5d79a00f7cbb9532900da3288</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia floods death toll rises as Australian woman thanks her dogs for saving her life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/australian-in-bali-survives-indonesian-flash-floods/105764660</link><description>Authorities are still cleaning up following the disaster, which hit two islands in the archipelago amid warnings more rain could fall in affected areas in coming days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebd9f89c26a15ca4e6aaa721ec19f3b5</guid></item><item><title>Netball final scoring error sparks resignation in Wimmera Football Netball League rivalry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/wimmera-netball-scoring-error-sparks-football-controversy/105753726</link><description>A botched score in a western Victorian netball league final has led to a senior official resigning and a police escort at the rival clubs' football match as tensions between the clubs remain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2cee958724691598f5102c88f167506</guid></item><item><title>Islamophobia has been 'persistent' and 'ignored', envoy says — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/federal-politics-live-sept-12/105765250</link><description>A long-awaited report into Islamophobia in Australia has been handed down, with the special envoy finding it has been "persistent" and "ignored".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2ef5426aa13af6f04a2b80bf14d5cab</guid></item><item><title>Kiama by-election could signal voter mood across NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/kiama-by-election-test-for-labor-and-liberals-after-gareth-ward/105761224</link><description>The Kiama by-election this weekend is more than a fight for one seat. It could reveal how voters view the state's major party leaders after scandal and political upheaval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fc47b757caa798d67eb6d84b1a4c0fa</guid></item><item><title>Tarryn Aiken injures knee as Sydney Roosters win NRLW minor premiership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/tarryn-aiken-injures-knee-roosters-win-nrlw-minor-premiership/105765274</link><description>The undefeated Sydney Roosters lock up the minor premiership with another big win despite a slew of injuries, including an apparently serious knee issue for halfback Tarryn Aiken.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3d0ec8cc837f9f4c700dece4e69d2af</guid></item><item><title>ASX higher on US rate cut expectations, but markets underestimating inflation risk — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/asx-markets-business-live-news-sept-12/105765376</link><description>The ASX rises, as do Virgin shares, as the airline reveals the exit pay of its former CEO. Westpac's economics team, led by former RBA assistant governor Luci Ellis, say they think markets are underpricing the risk of a renewed inflation breakout in the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9e5b59041ffdcd6b6304cf4b5301d79</guid></item><item><title>Outback hairdresser a 'hero' to Wilcannia residents longing for a pampering</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/outback-hairdresser-travels-1000kms-to-pamper-remote-residents/105636488</link><description>The "salon" is an op shop and the round-trip commute's a doozy, but Juliann Mutch is happy to go the extra distance to pamper her grateful Wilcannia clientele.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">078b38e392f5ace6b92b8e4e40ed7b88</guid></item><item><title>How Jamal Fogarty learned to be the hero Canberra needed for its premiership charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/jamal-fogarty-canberra-raiders-nrl-finals-broncos/105763708</link><description>Jamal Fogarty has spent a rugby league lifetime waiting to play on a team like the Raiders. Now with the NRL finals approaching, he's ready for his close-up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37ebbb2fb5d1d3bfd53ea39bbcdce144</guid></item><item><title>Voter turnout as low as 10 per cent in NT local elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/nt-local-government-council-elections-see-dip-in-voter-turnout/105760662</link><description>Two out of five of the NT's enrolled voters failed to vote in the jurisdictions recent local government elections, with experts concerned voting fatigue has taken hold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">889f1bd29f1f4d9c6b5541f52d7a7f70</guid></item><item><title>Albany residents call for lower speed limits after van strikes pedestrian at crossing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/improved-pedestrian-safety-calls-driver-charged-albany-crash/105763894</link><description>A crash involving a van and an 81-year-old woman in Albany prompts calls for reduced speed limits from locals and road safety advocates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28cafa4834c5ecfdd772b7a30cc30200</guid></item><item><title>What happens to your data when you trade or recycle your device?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/what-happens-to-data-when-disposing-of-old-devices-in-ewaste/105681804</link><description>A cybercrime expert says trading or recycling electronics may not completely erase personal data and users should adopt a "risk-adjusted strategy" when disposing of devices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a43950c96dbc6efda59bd57a5459809</guid></item><item><title>Netball Australia, players strike revenue-sharing deal in collective player agreement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/netball-australia-players-strike-landmark-revenue-sharing-deal/105765526</link><description>Netball Australia and the players' association strike a landmark revenue-sharing deal as part of a three-year collective player agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04124b57417d9814469f61aa8c909075</guid></item><item><title>Queensland barramundi producer found guilty of environmental breaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/mainstream-aquaculture-queensland-guilty-environment-breaches/105766424</link><description>An aquaculture company "took a gamble" when it stocked a prawn farm in Far North Queensland with barramundi without environmental approval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f4c443ce9a2874a3066358363141f23</guid></item><item><title>Murray Watt stamps final approval of Woodside's North West Shelf extension to 2070</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/woodside-north-west-shelf-decision-murray-watt-pilbara/105758850</link><description>Australia's biggest gas project, Woodside's North West Shelf, has received final approval to extend operations through until 2070.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d18fcc83afaca4bb228cc354760d240</guid></item><item><title>The simple system I use for composting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/simple-system-use-for-composting/105648580</link><description>Koren Helbig has devised an easy and effective method of turning her food waste and plant trimmings into a nutrient-rich compost for her Adelaide/Tarntanya food gardens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79967d2cf242f317c83d0a075a76ca87</guid></item><item><title>Australia to face Belgium in Davis Cup in Sydney with Final 8 spot up for grabs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/nothing-for-granted-aussies-wary-of-belgian-davis-cup-threat/105767498</link><description>Lleyton Hewitt's Australian Davis Cup team is ready for another fierce battle with old foes Belgium as they chase a spot in this year's Final 8 in Italy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25e0a60e31cf0b026f68b6ea2239af89</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne names Geelong assistant Steven King as new senior coach as Nathan Buckley is overlooked</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/afl-steven-king-named-melbourne-demons-coach/105767854</link><description>Melbourne surprises the AFL world by naming Geelong assistant Steven King as its new senior coach despite persistent links with Nathan Buckley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fea7a235f5c0090787551364ca3b7d77</guid></item><item><title>Islamophobia envoy calls for religious discrimination laws, review of approach to counter-terrorism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/islamophobia-envoy-wants-religious-discrimination-laws/105767918</link><description>In a landmark report, newly-appointed Aftab Malik also calls for counter-terrorism laws and approaches to be reviewed, and for national inquiries into Islamophobia and anti-Palestinian racism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc9a9f371e9e7f0d19902747f4cfb1dd</guid></item><item><title>Quote Quiz: Who said it, Lachlan Murdoch or Succession's Kendall Roy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/quiz-who-said-it-lachlan-murdoch-or-kendall-roy/102946532</link><description>As Lachlan Murdoch's ascension to the head of the family business is cemented, can you tell his quotes apart from Succession's self-proclaimed "eldest boy", Kendall Roy?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cddc5ea62e8e2529ae1aade17a00dfd</guid></item><item><title>Artists and users boycotting Spotify over AI use and CEO's military tech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/spotify-boycott-daniel-ek-ai-music-military-tech-fenn-wilson/105765846</link><description>A growing number of artists and users are leaving Spotify. What's changed with the streaming giant? And what comes next?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dce4c940b969890ecfdfb4e37ad98c9</guid></item><item><title>Independent accreditation system for fertility sector to be established as all recommendations of IVF review accepted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/health-ministers-meeting-ivf-rapid-review/105767258</link><description>Federal Health Minister Mark Butler has announced he has accepted all recommendations of a rapid review into the IVF sector at a meeting with state and territory health ministers in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fa1b97ddad00e883abaf6ad33c49ac4</guid></item><item><title>Mop-top virus found in potatoes bought from retail stores in Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/mop-top-virus-found-in-supermarket-potatoes/105767970</link><description>Biosecurity Tasmania is working to trace the origins of the two potatoes, as potato mop-top virus continues to spread through Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b203465ed9e5237115d518e91f8591f</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian government consulting on public homebirth model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/tasmanian-government-consulting-on-public-homebirth-model/105767780</link><description>A proposal by the Tasmanian government to introduce a public homebirth model has been welcomed by those in the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9fdea3108a66149f4d49c462aee9cca</guid></item><item><title>British YouTube creator Yung Filly to travel home to UK on bail for sexual assault charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/youtube-creator-yung-filly-allowed-to-fly-overseas-on-bail/105094220</link><description>British YouTube content creator Yung Filly, who's facing trial in Perth on sex assault charges, is granted permission to travel home to the UK for the first time since he was arrested.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c89f9603e811b96cf1412b9f341613a</guid></item><item><title>Former Geraldton family appeals pet labrador's dangerous dog declaration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/family-appeals-labradors-dangerous-dog-declaration-wa-council/105766142</link><description>A WA family asks the State Administrative Tribunal to overturn the City of Greater Geraldton's ruling that Dozer, their golden labrador, is a dangerous dog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e55a65c5af9b846f557497d2f6ef2701</guid></item><item><title>Judge awards man $450k in damages after ex-premier's police officer son falsified evidence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/man-gets-450k-damages-for-daniel-keneally-fabricating-evidence/105767836</link><description>A Supreme Court judge has awarded NSW man Luke Moore $450,000 in damages after the disgraced police officer son of former senator Kristina Keneally falsified evidence about alleged death threats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11118a489badd08a9a50abbfccbc184e</guid></item><item><title>Developers put $8b Navigator North offshore wind farm on hold amid uncertainty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/navigator-north-offshore-wind-farm-on-hold/105562834</link><description>A Victorian wind farm project that promises to power more than a million homes is put on ice as developers worry the proposal will not meet government timelines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">628864fce9d6062c492a3d555bfb25cd</guid></item><item><title>NRL finals: Melbourne Storm defeat Canterbury Bulldogs 26-18, Stephen Crichton injured</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/nrl-finals-live-updates-melbourne-storm-canterbury-bulldogs/105751872</link><description>Bulldogs coach Cameron Ciraldo feels his side was let down by the refereeing performance in their 26-18 defeat to the Storm in their qualifying final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b35b168c35672017d9e1e7c85773c92</guid></item><item><title>Australian basketballer Tiana Mangakahia dies of cancer aged 30</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/tiana-mangakahia-dies-of-cancer/105768486</link><description>The family of Australian basketballer Tiana Mangakahia has paid tribute to the former Opals and WNBL player, describing her as a "shining light" after her death from cancer at the age of 30.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f153ce2471de0dc5956d6a1f0ff65c07</guid></item><item><title>Hawthorn ends Adelaide's season with rollicking semifinal win, setting up epic Geelong prelim final date</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/afl-adelaide-crows-vs-hawthorn-hawks-semifinal-live-blog/105767748</link><description>After dispensing of the Crows via a 34-point victory, the Hawks are licking their lips ahead of their preliminary final against the annoyingly good" Cats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dae5c2cdc7b85088bd6f6b57bce33018</guid></item><item><title>Gold miners drive ASX higher as bullion price hits new record</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/gold-miners-drive-asx-higher-as-bullion-price-hits/105768800</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c389ec43bef072905fd30ff2eb03f65</guid></item><item><title>Matildas to face England Lionesses in October international window</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/matildas-to-face-england-in-october-international-window/105768734</link><description>The Matildas have announced an international friendly against England this October, the first time they will face the European champions since the semifinal of the 2023 FIFA Women's World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dcbfca402515a25dcb9fa30ae7dbe58</guid></item><item><title>Pacific leaders reaffirm support for Taiwan's right to attend regional forum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/pacific-backs-taiwan-in-regional-forum-despite-chinas-opposition/105768946</link><description>Despite pressure from Beijing, Pacific leaders have backed Taiwan's right to attend the Pacific Islands Forum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be257f4ebf8ffb7425aa8971ff6a5ff8</guid></item><item><title>Armani drama beyond the grave as will instructs heirs to sell or list on stock market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/giorgio-armani-will-sell-company-or-list-on-stock-market/105768872</link><description>Giorgio Armani's will has surprised fashion watchers as it contains instructions to gradually sell off his company to a luxury brand or seek a listing on the stock market, in seeming contrast to his fiercely independent stance throughout his career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53e94498a98d7b4b3828f43dae15498d</guid></item><item><title>Sushila Karki sworn in as Nepal's new prime minister after gen Z protests prompt political change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/sushila-karki-nepals-new-prime-minister-after-gen-z-protests/105769388</link><description>Sushila Karki garnered widespread support from many young Nepalese people who took to the streets in anger over government corruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b14068c37ad26302453e199b0b0960b7</guid></item><item><title>Netanyahu and Putin escalate their wars as Trump looks on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/vladimir-putin-donald-trump-benjamin-netanyahu/105756892</link><description>In the Middle East and in Europe, political leaders are making their own arrangements in the absence of US leadership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8f842a85a5aa2869baa2e7a9502079a</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump and his 'good man' Anthony Albanese share some common ground</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/donald-trump-anthony-albanese-common/105756898</link><description>The MAGA president's grip on the Republican party is near total while Albanese holds a sway over his left-leaning caucus like few of his Labor predecessors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88bb570d5f115243764edac358fd6925</guid></item><item><title>Former minister Greg Hunt works for Brethren company whose owners made millions on COVID contracts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/greg-hunt-plymouth-brethren-liberal-party-four-corners/105767402</link><description>The Sydney-based church has been described by former members and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese as a "cult".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4328a557e1520bd5030668231cb9ac20</guid></item><item><title>North West Shelf extension comes at critical juncture in Australia's climate conversation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/north-west-shelf-extension-part-of-climate-conversation/105766008</link><description>Seven years after it was first mooted, the extension of Australia's biggest gas project could not have landed at a more critical juncture for the nation's climate credentials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9765dc66a42d1f27ca625f703478a49b</guid></item><item><title>Australians watched the moment of Charlie Kirk's assassination on social media with no warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/young-australians-watched-charlie-kirk-murder-social-media/105766060</link><description>Young Australians say they are seeing graphic video of US commentator Charlie Kirk being shot dead pop up in their social media algorithms without warning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9340dfaeb79e8ebb902319c5caea2078</guid></item><item><title>Evidence points to remains found in Vietnam cave being South-East Asia's earliest known homicide victim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/vietnam-remains-earliest-known-homicide-victim-cold-case/105741956</link><description>It was on a sweltering morning in 2018 in a cave in northern Vietnam when Chris Stimpson and his team uncovered what may be the oldest cold case murder in South-East Asia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34f92776d6167c167af22a4b170f6648</guid></item><item><title>Elderly Porepunkah woman left without in-home care as Freeman manhunt continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/alleged-police-killer-manhunt-disrupts-elderly-in-home-care/105761728</link><description>Elderly residents of Porepunkah have had their home nurse visits cancelled as alleged police killer Dezi Freeman remains at large.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">507302c0595171195289e7be5a84ab6f</guid></item><item><title>Journey Home, David Gulpilil shows the film icon's remote homeland 'for the first time'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/new-documentary-journey-home-david-gulpilil-screens-in-darwin/105765450</link><description>Legendary Yolŋu actor David Gulpilil held an ambition throughout his career to share a part of himself and his culture that the world had never seen before. A new documentary does exactly that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d65721a64e5ebe2a1f5e94ea75d0c3b0</guid></item><item><title>Nepal's gen Z protesters are continuing the fight for their future even after picking a new prime minister</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/nepal-gen-z-protesters-on-fight-for-future/105765704</link><description>A calm has fallen on Nepal's streets after days of violence and chaos. But leaders of the gen Z protest movement say the work's not done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b37bb71a46bc744a9f38b66a4eed75af</guid></item><item><title>Female farmers determined to defy NSW dairy industry exodus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/women-future-proofing-dairy-farms/105726594</link><description>As repeated natural disasters and stagnating milk prices see dairy farmers walk away from the industry, these women are looking at smaller changes to help shore up their future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b09d384265f0a5a6006ce26c1589abef</guid></item><item><title>More than a dozen women complain about Brisbane doctor accused of performing 'sexually motivated' checks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/complaints-against-brisbane-doctor-accused-unnecessary-checks/105761406</link><description>Dr Stan Theodoros is facing disciplinary proceedings, lodged by Queensland's health ombudsman, in the Queensland Civil and Administrative Tribunal (QCAT).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">741e87aaa3667ced3bea58af9748de48</guid></item><item><title>A Sydney council's $378k battle against Woolwich marina expansion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/hunters-hill-council-battle-sydney-marina-expansion-kellys-bush/105752296</link><description>Locals have argued if the expansion in Woolwich were to go ahead it "would be like putting a bus station in the middle of a children's playground".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f201212c7510948a067483566c2b06e2</guid></item><item><title>Keio Yoshida tells queer stories differently in their new book, Pride and Prejudices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/keio-yoshida-pride-and-prejudices-queer-lives-and-the-law/105658412</link><description>In their latest book, author and human rights lawyer Keio Yoshida draws on their personal experience and legal expertise to demonstrate the importance of sharing queer stories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">325fafb6f4714080b832c5a0148c1ee0</guid></item><item><title>Yorke Peninsula businesses worry tourists won't return if algal bloom continues over summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/communities-worry-tourists-wont-return-if-algal-bloom-continues/105754016</link><description>After a cold winter, a warm spring is often a welcome time for towns that rely heavily on tourism. But for regional South Australian coastal communities hit hard by the ongoing algal bloom, there's a feeling of concern about what should be a busy period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cd840af551174abcc311d6961bec3ba</guid></item><item><title>Cairns tourism is a roller-coaster from Francis Ford Coppola to crocs and the reef</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/50-years-tourism-promotion-tropical-north-queensland-cairns/105728438</link><description>The Great Barrier Reef and the Daintree Rainforest are must-sees for millions worldwide, but it was once so difficult to get to Cairns that promoters resorted to gimmicks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">736225370f7bd0c68c294577b5f0ba8d</guid></item><item><title>Adrianne Lenker on Big Thief's evolution and the making of Double Infinity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/big-thief-double-infinity-adrianne-lenker-new-album-interview/105754728</link><description>At the peak of their success, Big Thief faced a major emotional rupture that reshaped the group from the inside out. Now, they've returned with their sixth album, shaped by deep creative trust and a renewed commitment to collaboration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c838f7561646302e00adf2a4fa4ff7b4</guid></item><item><title>Black Diamond Cup, the oldest trophy still in use in Australian sport, up for grabs in Newcastle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/black-diamond-cup-oldest-trophy-still-in-use/105757792</link><description>Teams in the Hunter Central Coast AFL play for a trophy that was first contested in 1888 and holds plenty of memories for grand final winners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a44aa5fba65df5067d085c7c531b0f1</guid></item><item><title>Wallaroos primed for Rugby World Cup quarterfinal against Canada</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/rugby-world-cup-australia-wallaroos-canada/105769754</link><description>Considered underdogs against the world number two, the Wallaroos are urged to be bold in their sudden-death encounter in Bristol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00a664df1e40e5f48d4be15d391193dc</guid></item><item><title>What's next for the far-right political movement in Australia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/what-next-for-far-right-john-macgowan/105735032</link><description>Australia's far-right movement has been buoyed by a wave of recent protests against mass immigration, with some saying the rallies were the "biggest thing that's happened in conservative and nationalist politics for a hundred years".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07e149ee4aff2602783cd21b0afe8328</guid></item><item><title>ABC Quote Quiz: Birthday cards, bucket lists and (briefly) Banksy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/abc-quote-quiz-sept-13/105765946</link><description>See if you can work out who said it, and what they were talking about.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a2877e43e9ea593141eb7e2d26494b5</guid></item><item><title>Who is Tyler Robinson, the accused killer of Charlie Kirk?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/tyler-robinson-charlie-kirks-alleged-killer/105769710</link><description>After his father encouraged Tyler Robinson to turn himself in, people close to the 22-year-old provided investigators with crucial insights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeb2177456349534e747aeb65ed554d9</guid></item><item><title>Astronomer Grote Reber's ashes are held in radio telescope locations around the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/pioneering-radio-astronomer-grote-reber-built-first-big-dish/105725764</link><description>Grote Reber helped spark decades of interest in radio astronomy in Tasmania when he decided to call the southern state home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9417f11c5baa5079e22009aea0722381</guid></item><item><title>Nourishing and easy sweet potato and lentil bowls - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/easy-roasted-sweet-potato-and-lentil-bowl/105643934</link><description>This jazzy little bowl is made from simple ingredients. The sweet potato is roasted gently with spices and tinned lentils are roasted until crisp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f14ee49334cef10b8f95233d1889d9e</guid></item><item><title>Recyclers call for end to 30,000 tonnes of mining tyres being buried every year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/tyre-recycling-facility-hopes-process-more-mining-waste/105642522</link><description>Australia's mining industry has been burying enormous, worn out tyres for decades. But a new facility is offering a solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e88f7f8fefbb3e349ddbc89682fdd00e</guid></item><item><title>Suns coach Damien Hardwick praised ahead of historic finals clash against Lions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/afl-suns-lions-damien-hardwick-alastair-lynch/105769862</link><description>Brisbane Lions great Alastair Lynch hails the impact of Damien Hardwick at the Gold Coast Suns as they look to continue their run in the finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">325e308ff45d50af4c7b44030c5cb081</guid></item><item><title>Rare good news for critically endangered east coast grey nurse sharks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/critically-endangered-grey-nurse-shark-numbers-on-the-rise/105765674</link><description>Scientists say increasing numbers of east coast grey nurse sharks is rare good conservation news for the critically endangered species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10548b61892e77ded2ac12afc8405a87</guid></item><item><title>NSW government to roll out capped taxi fares from Sydney Airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/nsw-sydney-airport-to-cap-taxi-fees-in-fare-crackdown/105769768</link><description>A New York-style approach to taxi fees will roll out at Sydney Airport in a bid to put an end to fare rip-offs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2552ed679b01d6ed028827768a374b6</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne's Royal Children's Hospital cancels children in war discussion citing staff safety</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/royal-childrens-hospital-children-in-war-event-cancelled/105768998</link><description>Melbourne's Royal Children's Hospital says a symposium on the effect of war on children has been cancelled due to safety fears, but some doctors say pressure from a group opposing antisemitism is to blame.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fccbb42b0ca2b5ba0a4d9a7fdb9a9816</guid></item><item><title>A journey through 35 years of Canberra's history since the Raiders last won a minor premiership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/the-35-years-since-canberra-raiders-last-won-a-minor-premiership/105768944</link><description>Two weeks ago, the Canberra Raiders won the NRL's 2025 minor premiership by beating the Wests Tigers. It is their first minor premiership since 1990, and a lot has changed since then.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6c07216269a150c362150bb1c36ed05</guid></item><item><title>Bush band tells Aboriginal people's side of the Maralinga nuclear weapon tests story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/bush-band-song-tells-story-of-maralinga-atomic-bomb-tests/105765452</link><description>For Liam Tunkin, making music is about continuing his late father's legacy and sharing a dark part of Australia's history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b898813878aa4745672fc29e28ce560b</guid></item><item><title>Men's shed volunteers craft simple gifts to make young hearts skip with joy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/wagga-mens-shed-skipping-ropes-for-children-in-need-overseas/105739052</link><description>Retired farmer John's foray into woodworking has led to mateship, connections with kids in need around the world — and quite a few skipping rope handles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd8bc83565302e9b62ded0ed0f29564b</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fall to 28-26 defeat against Argentina in The Rugby Championship in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/live-updates-wallabies-vs-argentina-the-rugby-championship/105753320</link><description>The Wallabies have fallen just short of a magical comeback against Argentina, losing 28-26 in a thrilling Rugby Championship Test in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac9963693b81c061d5a7137f7874121c</guid></item><item><title>Erika Kirk makes first public statement after assassination of husband Charlie Kirk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/erika-kirk-pays-tribute-to-late-husband-charlie-kirk/105770008</link><description>Charlie Kirk's widow, Erika, delivers her first public remarks since the fatal shooting of her influencer husband.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a3e797f573f130d4cdaa37fc918652a</guid></item><item><title>Advocates call for action on brain health as AIHW reveals dementia is leading cause of death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/australians-dying-from-dementia-more-than-any-other-cause/105768682</link><description>Advocates warn the number of people with the condition could exceed 1 million without government intervention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b35bf8bb29f6390428b007c4fc10877</guid></item><item><title>Penrith Panthers, Cronulla Sharks win NRL elimination finals against Warriors, Sydney Roosters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/nrl-finals-live-warriors-panthers-sharks-roosters/105770330</link><description>The Sharks are looking to correct the mistakes of the past, as they advance to the semifinals with a 20-10 victory over the Roosters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8453f95a136416a45ec4efe167c5d81f</guid></item><item><title>Supreme Court gives Queensland hospital permission to terminate 12yo girl's pregnancy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/qld-hospital-gets-court-permission-for-abortion-on-12yo-girl/105770196</link><description>A 12-year-old girl in residential care in Queensland should be allowed to have an abortion, a court rules, after a judge found she was not capable of making the decision herself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86cd5589ba9855a3f68a146a74e238ad</guid></item><item><title>NRLW wrap: Brisbane Broncos thrash the Cowboys 50-4, Gold Coast grab last finals spot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/upton-hat-trick-leads-broncos-to-big-nrlw-win-over-cowboys/105770416</link><description>It's a big day for Queensland sides in the NRLW, as the Broncos — led by skipper Tamika Upton — are far too good for the third-placed Cowboys, while the Titans clinch the last finals spot with a win over Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0af6a0f9bdb8ae75a28c6c7e963ce856</guid></item><item><title>AFLW wrap: Collingwood ends Sydney's unbeaten run, Carlton thumps Gold Coast, the Power beats the Demons</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/swans-perfect-start-ends-as-magpies-stun-at-home/105770154</link><description>Collingwood, wooden spooners last season, keep Sydney goalless for more than three quarters at home on Saturday for an upset win, as Port Adelaide beat another unbeaten side in Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">112f93d3f5b081beaf0d54247ad5c93a</guid></item><item><title>WA Health issues measles warning as two more cases linked to Bali travel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/two-more-measles-cases-in-wa-linked-to-bali-travel/105770492</link><description>West Australians planning to visit South-East Asia are being urged to get vaccinated against measles, with two more cases linked with travel to Bali.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1897bbaf4493022b86af465fcc949ac6</guid></item><item><title>Labor win Kiama by-election as voters replace disgraced MP Gareth Ward</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/kiama-byelection-polls-close-votes-counting/105770414</link><description>The NSW Premier said Kiama now has the ear of the government after it claimed victory in the by-election triggered by the resignation of convicted rapist Gareth Ward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f8148eb8e329e6cf74190c6118a0a8f</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane far too good for Gold Coast in QClash semifinal, setting up Collingwood prelim date</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/afl-finals-brisbane-lions-gold-coast-suns-live-blog/105768034</link><description>Bouncing back from a resounding loss to Geelong, the Brisbane Lions comfortably dispense of the Gold Coast Suns to advance to the preliminary finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35fd90e486aa2532889961cd9ae474b8</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government pours $12 billion into expanding AUKUS defence facility near Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/albanese-announces-aukus-12-billion-dollar-defence-spend-perth/105770188</link><description>The Albanese government will spend $12 billion on building a submarine and naval shipbuilding facility south of Perth under AUKUS, as doubts linger over the agreement's future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">420e959c71ffce19abd7eac4b8f6483e</guid></item><item><title>London anti-immigration protesters scuffle with police, who promise 'many more' arrests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/uk-anti-immigration-rally-and-counter-protests/105770802</link><description>The march was organised by far-right activist Tommy Robinson while a counter protest by anti-racism campaigners also took place as the country continues to be dogged by the issue of immigration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">400ded37a12d6921e0e758dc480fc33d</guid></item><item><title>Australia and Papua New Guinea to 'totally integrate' military in defence treaty, minister says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/australia-and-png-defence-treaty-to-integrate-military-forces/105770088</link><description>Australia is set to "totally integrate" its military with Papua New Guinea's forces, PNG's defence minister has said, as the two countries prepare to sign a landmark treaty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20e8d04fdc68355dd6bb0bcbd76a253c</guid></item><item><title>From Formula One to creating the 'world's best' croissant, how baking saved Lune founder Kate Reid's life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/cars-to-croissants-kate-reid-and-the-lune-empire/105750472</link><description>Kate Reid's Lune croissants have been called the world's best. But how did a young woman struggling with a near-fatal eating disorder end up perfecting pastry?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d09b350f758690100795053d1425df1</guid></item><item><title>Children missing out on early intervention for language delays due to shortage of speech pathologists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/australias-speech-pathology-therapy-language-delay/105658306</link><description>One in four children starting school now has a speech or language delay. It can hold back their learning, affect their friendships and harm their mental health. Speech therapists are struggling to find ways to support them all, but one school is leading the way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fd8643f474de3cb897a95d95769fb75</guid></item><item><title>Trump hits out at Florida's 'tough stance' on vaccines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/trump-hits-out-at-floridas-tough-stance-on-vaccines/105767070</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">411cbb4e0109999f07a638bac1bb9e45</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's health chief, RFK Jr, is dividing Republicans on vaccines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/trump-health-chief-rfk-jr-divides-republicans-on-vaccines/105763060</link><description>US Health Secretary Robert F Kennedy Jr's anti-vaccination agenda is gaining ground, but resistance is coming from all sides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">550382bc4a2dad860c2ebd332ba5da22</guid></item><item><title>Understanding the literal bin fires in Europe's 'magical mystery summer' of inaction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/drone-attack-on-poland-shows-europe-is-not-equiped-for-war/105769208</link><description>Moscow's drone incursion into Polish airspace this week may have just laid bare how fruitless Europe's summer of talkfests has been.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ad36c5f8aa76037acc9c47d200ab7bb</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Think you're contestant material? Prove it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/105746846</link><description>It's time to show me your exceptional trivia knowledge. Ha!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03f61e05a2d928ef5dd5a855914f188a</guid></item><item><title>'Bone lady' who helped find Daniel Morcombe still unearthing stories of the dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/life-of-qld-police-forensic-anthropologist-donna-macgregor/105757258</link><description>From the search for Daniel Morcombe to a flaming roadside torso, Queensland's top forensics cop deals with some of the state's worst crimes — when she's not identifying fallen Australians on WWI battlefields.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">756451363a24944c71314b39d4ee9da4</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal artist Emily Kam Kngwarray becomes first Australian with solo exhibition at London's Tate Modern</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/emily-kam-kngwarray-nt-artist-solo-exhibition-tate-modern/105748722</link><description>Emily Kam Kngwarray has been recognised as "one of the world's leading artists" after becoming the first Australian whose work is the subject of a solo exhibition at the Tate Modern Gallery in London.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80742075f005deb3851d847eafa37b21</guid></item><item><title>Wallaroos' Rugby World Cup hopes dashed by dominant Canada in 46-5 loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/rugby-world-cup-wallaroos-canada-quarterfinal/105771382</link><description>The Wallaroos miss the chance to reach the Rugby World Cup semifinals, losing heavily 46-5 to Canada in Bristol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eeea51af32489f3175d1f115a728a37</guid></item><item><title>Perth had its wettest winter in 30 years. Why aren't its dams full?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/perth-dam-remains-low-despite-the-wettest-winter-in-30-years/105767386</link><description>The last time it rained that much in winter, Perth's drinking water dam overflowed. Now it's barely half full. It's telling the story of a water crisis that's not only affecting Australia, but the globe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">520afffe8e8f2b9614549ec3a2399a4d</guid></item><item><title>The Pacific won a stunning climate victory at the International Court of Justice. What's next?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/whats-next-after-pacific-icj-climate-victory/105747794</link><description>Pacific Island nations are weighing up how to use a historic international court ruling in their fight to bring about stronger emissions reductions and climate justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4d5352fd2872714b73915e90a078b57</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk's accused killer Tyler Robinson awaits formal charges in Utah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/tyler-robinson-awaits-formal-charges-over-charlie-kirk-murder/105771364</link><description>Tyler Robinson, jailed on suspicion of fatally shooting right-wing activist Charlie Kirk, faces formal charges in Utah early next week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">388d30366d16f1bf3aebb0058cc923e8</guid></item><item><title>Lord Howe Island detection dog Sebbi retires to Brisbane after years of 'hard work'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/lord-howe-island-sniffer-dog-sebbi-retires-to-brisbane/105762486</link><description>It might be hard to leave the one of the most idyllic places in Australia, but it is not a case of paradise lost for this retiring pest-hunting pooch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee308da8fc9e5d16b127301e912ff08d</guid></item><item><title>World-famous bee sanctuary on Kangaroo Island under threat from Varroa mite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/world-famous-bee-sanctuary-under-threat-from-parasite/105766650</link><description>Beekeepers on Kangaroo Island are demanding that biosecurity measures be boosted to prevent a deadly parasite from wiping out the island's world-famous bee sanctuary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dc81d0494e04695ce39dafec86cab57</guid></item><item><title>'White-hot anger' in the bush as Victorians fight government on multiple fronts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/why-regional-victorians-are-angry-at-state-government/105761034</link><description>Rural residents and local councils are deeply unhappy with new taxes, renewable energy, bad roads and mining companies, accusing the state government of "city centric" policymaking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">975ae86896e7894f15dfe756b7e0f4f9</guid></item><item><title>Inaugural Blue says club has reached a 'turning point' after challenging years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/with-a-few-added-pieces-carlton-have-flown-up-the-ladder-aflw/105770732</link><description>Inaugural Carlton player Gab Pound says the club has reached a turning point after not making the finals since the 2020 COVID-interrupted season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4746581d3adeb6ddbdb1c2e40b060a32</guid></item><item><title>Brick-pit frog recovery another win for green and gold at Sydney Olympics site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/green-and-golden-bell-frogs-thrive-at-sydney-olympics-site/105762124</link><description>Twenty-five years after the Sydney Olympics, an important Homebush planning decision has led to successful conservation efforts for a species born in the green and gold. But a deadly fungus poses a threat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7163e13b015cd649bd1282f9f989c65e</guid></item><item><title>The annual 'hungry ghost' festivities mark Christmas Island's troubled past</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/hungry-ghost-festivities-mark-christmas-island-troubled-past/105747320</link><description>More than a few spirits haunt the remote Indian Ocean territory, according to islanders deeply connected to its fraught and sometimes tragic history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">209c402fa089ebebb9e97e797155b656</guid></item><item><title>'Where to now?' Liberals soul searching after heavy loss in Kiama by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/nsw-kiama-by-election-analysis/105768772</link><description>For a party that had just suffered a heavy defeat, the mood at the Liberals' post-election event was surprisingly upbeat on Saturday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0324f2b1e17e0afe58c8b2fdb2342585</guid></item><item><title>Steeplechaser Tim Van de Velde stops to help struggling rival at World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/world-athletics-championships-steeplechase-tim-van-de-velde/105771466</link><description>Belgium's Tim Van de Velde provides the highlight of the opening night of the World Athletics Championships, helping a fellow competitor cross the finish line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d470e01e604db46cc6545807e9ed2bc</guid></item><item><title>Wombats in Robe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/wombats-in-robe/105762994</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b3220b0971b015745735ee5063bf7e0</guid></item><item><title>Wombat makes home in Robe's main street as numbers increase despite habitat loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/wombats-take-over-robe-south-australia/105763680</link><description>A wombat has made its home in the main street of Robe, evidence of an influx of the animals in the South Australian fishing town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd75f8c80d7887020cad44750ebb3000</guid></item><item><title>The Franklin River rescue was extreme. Here's how medics prepare for the wilderness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/expedition-medicine-frontline-wilderness-rescue-tasmania/105647214</link><description>The Franklin River rescue was an extreme test for the skills of medics. In remote Tasmania, here's how they train for "chaos".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ad6b3276dc3d97f9e83daaf4447dd1e</guid></item><item><title>Police clash with anti-immigration protesters in London</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/police-clash-with-anti-immigration-protesters-in-london/105771538</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f624fc78fd6ee39a07fa2a3279d4573b</guid></item><item><title>Outback nurse transforms remote diabetes care with cans, rocks and bush tucker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/collarenebri-hosts-pilot-diabetes-and-holistic-health-program/105600544</link><description>When Rishoniy Caine arrived in a remote NSW community with one general store and no gym, she knew fixing its diabetes problem would need a different approach to what had already failed the locals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">222ba35951a8a4a1e2c0a8f063f85b5b</guid></item><item><title>The federal press gallery is ceding power to the Albanese government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/australias-press-gallery-problem-with-political-coverage/105762464</link><description>The federal press gallery is ceding power to the Albanese government. It needs to take it back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ab87f4785a2cdb321543f771c1d84de</guid></item><item><title>How to watch the 2025 Primetime Emmys in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/how-to-watch-the-emmys-2025-primetime-awards-los-angeles/105751936</link><description>Your pocket guide to watching the Emmy awards in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec791c67cc32865ea8679b33207acf56</guid></item><item><title>Victorian farmers welcome spring forecast despite long-term climate concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/farming-faces-global-warming-challenges-bom-csiro-forecasts/105698854</link><description>As spring brings a flicker of hope, some farmers cautiously embrace optimism while others face mounting pressures and climate uncertainty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eefc8f08701a2e9f48f36a96143be8ca</guid></item><item><title>Residents in flood-affected communities want more warning technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/flood-hit-residents-call-for-more-automated-river-gauges/105724942</link><description>For generations, farmers and outback communities have relied on the bush telegraph during floods but it has fallen silent in recent years, leaving residents without up-to-date information.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c31e8ba3a792f16088d132fc493aa4e1</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump threatens new sanctions on Russia if NATO suspends all oil purchases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/donald-trump-demands-nato-stop-all-russia-oil-imports/105771434</link><description>US President Donald Trump says he is ready to impose sanctions on Russia, but only if NATO members agree to do the same, as well as set massive tariffs on Russia's main ally, China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d06ea199ed9911761efa00cca6ba9712</guid></item><item><title>All Blacks forced to re-group after 43-10 loss to Springboks in Rugby Championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/all-blacks-regroup-after-springboks-defeat/105771568</link><description>After a demoralising 43-10 loss to the Springboks on home soil, the All Blacks are looking to rebound against the Wallabies in the upcoming Bledisloe Cup Tests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14cb19776ed7e08739a74354c2afa92e</guid></item><item><title>Police scour cave in search for Dezi Freeman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/police-scour-cave-in-search-for-dezi-freeman/105771632</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31f3f48ab8e56b741412c9d44baf7df1</guid></item><item><title>Creamed honey nostalgia helps producers find niche market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/meilbee-honey-producers-adapt-to-new-normal-with-varroa-mite/105666254</link><description>Some New South Wales beekeepers are determined to stay the course in the face of varroa mite, turning to childhood memories for inspiration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b04ab4401117d12b619bbf4390eaafa6</guid></item><item><title>Sharp drop in Gouldian finch sightings sparks worry in WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/gouldian-finch-sightings-drop-northern-wa/105763736</link><description>Numbers of the brightly coloured Gouldian finch appear to be dropping in Western Australia's East Kimberley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6772c4e9c00b75c099803dcbbf782b7</guid></item><item><title>Victoria set to have first new national parks in more than a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/victoria-set-to-have-three-new-national-parks/105762596</link><description>Conservation groups are celebrating proposed legislation for three new national parks in Victoria but not all bush users are happy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d36bb38c879de78daf8fd739801d0718</guid></item><item><title>Albanese announces new AUKUS facility in WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/albanese-announces-new-aukus-facility-in-wa/105771780</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">351395ae5e354677773f0fc914b78d26</guid></item><item><title>Platypuses found dead in illegal fishing traps in regional Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/two-platypuses-found-dead-in-illegal-fishing-traps-in-gippsland/105770064</link><description>Anglers are urged to dispose of illegal fishing nets and stick with safer open-top traps, after two platypuses are found drowned in regional Victorian waterways.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa94e78e7c284c127ba7cfde9ae4e257</guid></item><item><title>Dezi Freeman search at Porepunkah now Australia's largest tactical police deployment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/dezi-freeman-porepunkah-shooting-search-new-zealand-travellers/105771638</link><description>New Zealand police briefly joined the search for alleged police killer Dezi Freeman as travel advice for Victoria's north-east eases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">245ca35d19cd85927d8c2271531369df</guid></item><item><title>'World's biggest' hockey game in York fundraises for cancer research</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/eliza-reynolds-hockey-game-cancer-fundraiser/105763156</link><description>More than 370 people participate in a hockey game lasting more than eight hours in honour of a little girl who died from a rare form of cancer earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6940b0964bbe2ae1724b08b2a97f81f</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley reshuffles frontbench in wake of Jacinta Nampijinpa Price saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/coalition-frontbench-reshuffle-melissa-price-claire-chandler/105771468</link><description>West Australian MP Melissa Price will replace Jacinta Nampijinpa Price as the shadow minister for defence industry and personnel, after the outspoken senator was sacked for refusing to back her leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5afabc2037eaede8864df8e5a67e0e3f</guid></item><item><title>How to give your indoor plants a spring clean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/how-to-spring-clean-indoor-plants/105754044</link><description>As gardens, parks and nature strips start showing signs of spring, our indoor plants might need a little help to jump into the new season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7041345f64a52b3d64fb6ac2ef82f3b</guid></item><item><title>In the midst of destruction in Gaza, these parents found 'paradise' through adoption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/palestinian-couple-adopts-baby-who-survived-israeli-strike/105691626</link><description>A newborn baby was left in a Gaza hospital, the sole survivor of a deadly Israeli strike which killed her family. A couple who had struggled to have children of their own knew they had to provide her with a home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d91dd396d69c59c3b40cbd1f35b154a2</guid></item><item><title>Over 100,000 anti-immigration protesters march through London</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/over-100,000-anti-immigration-protesters-march/105772002</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17773d1eb1ee1d5cfe1fb604f37b3675</guid></item><item><title>Lachie Neale gives himself '50 per cent' chance of improbable grand final appearance after calf injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/afl-brisbane-lions-lachie-neale-50-per-cent-chance-gf/105771982</link><description>Lachie Neale admits medical professionals are not holding out much hope of him recovering from a calf injury in time for the grand final, but he is not giving up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a19957fc35f1ad280cdb57d03a33c7d3</guid></item><item><title>Ben Hunt's Golden Point field goal sends Brisbane Broncos into NRL prelims after downing Canberra Raiders in all-time classic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/nrl-live-updates-finals-canberra-raiders-brisbane-broncos/105767630</link><description>Jamal Fogarty scores a try in Golden Point to send the Raiders to a preliminary final only for it to be disallowed before Ben Hunt delivers a dagger field goal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6df4f99fbc4ba21354c9bf49bf40731</guid></item><item><title>FBI director Kash Patel to face congressional hearing amid missteps on Charlie Kirk assassination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/kash-patel-faces-congressional-hearing/105771606</link><description>Kash Patel faces a clear test of whether he can convince the country that the FBI, under his watch, can avoid compounding its mistakes in a time of political violence and deepening distrust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff3edf3e8615beb76880722256515f03</guid></item><item><title>WA set to get two new public holidays in 2028 in upcoming legislation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/wa-set-to-get-two-new-holidays-in-shake-up-of-public-holidays/105771652</link><description>WA Premier Roger Cook announces plans to change the state's public holidays from 2028, adding Show Day and Easter Saturday to the calendar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">295fa0b064b6ec349ac3a310f7c3f0f0</guid></item><item><title>Terence Crawford beats Canelo Alvarez in Las Vegas to becomes first male to notch three unified division titles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/boxing-terence-crawford-beats-canelo-alvarez-vegas-fight-result/105771950</link><description>Terence Crawford is overcome with emotion after doing something no male boxer has done in the history of the sport, in front of over 70,000 fans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a799e0a0cf3718cd26470a6545a9dbc</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull cruises to 1,500m final at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-2025-in-tokyo-day-2/105772150</link><description>Jess Hull made light work of a rough semifinal to progress in the women's 1,500, but Linden Hall and Torrie Lewis both fell just short of making the final themselves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3251a6322d104d5e8dec69a8eb3f155</guid></item><item><title>AFLW Round 5 Sunday wrap: Kangaroos claim grand final rematch against Lions as Saints and Cats record big wins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/aflw-round-5-sunday-wrap-kangaroos-beat-lions-gf-rematch/105771940</link><description>North Melbourne continues its blistering start to the AFLW season as Geelong and St Kilda also record big wins in Round 5.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cee53d3f18feb5d3f6fa788a7a48b761</guid></item><item><title>Belgians break Australian hearts in Davis Cup classic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/tennis-de-minaur-australia-belgium-davis-cup-wrap/105772264</link><description>Beligum's Raphael Collignon wore down late stand-in Aleksandar Vukic in the deciding rubber to lead Belgium to the quarter-finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48108db3db36157632582610dcc8f4ed</guid></item><item><title>Reece Walsh grabs the Sun to lead Brisbane to an all-time victory over Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/canberra-raiders-brisbane-broncos-nrl-finals-reece-walsh/105767838</link><description>Brisbane and Canberra went to the great beyond in their golden point finals match and it was Reece Walsh who led the Broncos to the promised land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">863df8dd52133df36ae1790ea450fe7c</guid></item><item><title>British boxer and former world champion Ricky Hatton dies at age 46</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/boxer-ricky-hatton-dead-at-age-46/105772360</link><description>The British boxer was a former world champion boxer and had been due to make a comeback in December this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e023553d39179697cc4d8231e8b2bfd</guid></item><item><title>Plymouth Brethren attempted to silence alleged rape victim with a million dollars and a non-disclosure agreement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/exclusive-brethren-plymouth-alleged-abuse-nda-four-corners/105762208</link><description>The controversial church offered to settle with Mick Dover over his allegations of abuse, but only if he signed a non-disclosure agreement and agreed not to disparage them in any way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78d95957cfe6ad02b1a9caec307b2254</guid></item><item><title>Liberal Party immigration fight is a battle over how the party wants to position itself</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/liberals-mass-immigration-debate-protests/105771786</link><description>Immigration has become a new fault line inside the Liberal Party that will erupt again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a99f0ce667959a16433080650b5d2dc</guid></item><item><title>The year Australia is due to blow its carbon budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/australia-carbon-budget-2035-emissions-target/105341080</link><description>Unless Australia lifts its ambitions, its "fair share" of carbon emissions will be spent 14 years early. With the government announcing a 2035 climate target this week, there is intense debate on how high the government should aim — and whether it will be enough to help limit global warming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92c26486065559e6e68fc907f4300c31</guid></item><item><title>The higher Australia's 2035 emissions target, the more necessary a carbon tax will be</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/albanese-government-2035-climate-emissions-target/105771566</link><description>Australia's emissions reduction number is, in short, a laugh-or-cry-o-meter, or perhaps more accurately, a tax-o-meter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5aae41b286ff6b7c3400069e180e67f</guid></item><item><title>GIM Trading accused of defrauding millions from ordinary Australian investors with 'low risk' bonds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/gim-trading-alleged-fraud-investors-bonds/105747410</link><description>A Gold Coast musician approached by a man he knew from a local bar went on to front a trading company, later accused of defrauding millions from ordinary Australian investors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef7a680d03253010b78fa5b88e06a4f0</guid></item><item><title>Dads leaving sex education to mums, report finds, with concerns young boys are missing out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/dads-leaving-sex-education-to-mums-boys-missing-out/105761172</link><description>New report finds mothers do more of the sex education at home, raising concerns that young boys are missing out on key information from their dads.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09373ae607cb293f5028b7499dce7b5a</guid></item><item><title>Family violence survivors waiting years for social housing as demand surges in Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/social-public-housing-wait-times-victoria-family-violence/105655044</link><description>As family violence survivor and mother-of-two, Maya was assessed as a high priority for social housing. Eight years later, she's finally moved into a suitable home in outer-suburban Melbourne, with vulnerable Victorians left waiting for years as the social housing waitlist soars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e74302190404e5284428c6e45ccbce8a</guid></item><item><title>Rideshare drivers bypassing fatigue restrictions amid calls for industry minimum standards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/uber-didi-rideshare-drivers-fatigue-union/105756620</link><description>According to the Transport Workers' Union, some rideshare drivers have reported being on the road for up to 18 hours a day, swapping between multiple apps in order to bypass fatigue restrictions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57ca272bb5fb555b414489cd8648ff0a</guid></item><item><title>Weather to warm up in Queensland, as more rain forecast for the north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/warmer-weather-tipped-for-much-of-queensland-as-spring-sets-in/105771650</link><description>The southern half of Queensland can expect fine weather at least for the first half of the week, while more rain is on the way for the north of the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44a26254dc8a8890086a64f319e0fce8</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic expeditioners join research project to help astronauts on space missions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/antarctic-expeditioners-join-astronaut-research-project/105767136</link><description>Expeditioners at Australia's Antarctic stations are taking part in a research project to better understand the cognitive and physiological impacts of extended deployments — which can include actual "brain shrinkage".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d57ace742d2dab72c8470091d9eea61</guid></item><item><title>SA government error in your favour — collect $1 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/sa-government-erroneously-hands-1-million-to-small-business/105767306</link><description>Political parties usually get in trouble for breaking their election promises. But what happens when they keep a promise that never actually existed?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea597ae377c0e7662d5bf4f001c30c70</guid></item><item><title>Bankruptcy law reform push after paedophile protects assets in superannuation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/paedophiles-using-bankruptcy-loophole-to-avoid-payouts/105765918</link><description>Edan van Haren, a victim of child predator Maurice Van Ryn, says legal loopholes are allowing the confessed paedophile to protect his assets in superannuation to avoid paying compensation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">598df1c8747bfb8132eaed82ca93974e</guid></item><item><title>How Sydney's Olympic legacy continues to unfold, 25 years on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/2000-sydney-olympics-25-year-anniversary-legacy-reflections/105764442</link><description>Largely regarded as one of the most successful modern Olympics, years of work went into ensuring Sydney could fully capitalise on its moment in the spotlight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">917e1ac91bb7370325e50d1950ba2a40</guid></item><item><title>Residents say former Moe Hospital could become public housing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/moe-hospital-newborough-derelict-building-social-housing/105637366</link><description>A retired nurse who worked at Moe Hospital says the closed facility could be used for housing rather than left to further rot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d6259927cc7b3ea15a9fcb2704c8b7c</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk shooting suspect not cooperating with authorities, Utah governor says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/charlie-kirk-shooting-suspect-not-cooperating-with-authorities/105772848</link><description>Investigators are working to piece together why Tyler Robinson allegedly scaled a rooftop at Utah Valley University during an outdoor event and shot Mr Kirk in the neck at long range.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84a96eb58021324ea7568c8d91e90253</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr scores 100th goal for Chelsea in long-awaited WSL return from knee injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/sam-kerr-makes-wsl-chelsea-return-from-torn-acl/105772878</link><description>Matildas star Sam Kerr scores her 100th goal for Chelsea just minutes after returning to the pitch for the Blues for her first game since 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bae5f25a567be7986ec4489f569f5f25</guid></item><item><title>Road repairs after flood delayed by 'excruciating' eligibility criteria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/buloke-shire-flood-funding-pot-holes-delays-unsafe-roads/105733714</link><description>Victorian councils say they are required to provide before-and-after photos of every 100 metres of road in order to be eligible for flood recovery funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d6870a6663a3b8139b0e567866cd586</guid></item><item><title>PAWS Darwin accused of 'unprofessional' conduct over failure to desex animals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/paws-darwin-leaves-pet-owners-out-of-pocket-desexing-service/105719438</link><description>A Darwin animal shelter has been accused of "unprofessional" behaviour after failing to provide desexing services which new owners had already paid for as part of their adoption fee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3656590762062340470798e4c5e00fd2</guid></item><item><title>Nepalese migrants in Australia turning to parents to help with childcare and culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/canberra-nepalese-community-family-tradition-and-culture/105772020</link><description>For many Nepalese families living in Canberra, the arrival of parents from overseas is both a helping hand with raising children and a connection to their homeland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83d7bb8c245d2e5d11433eda0c9b3fd1</guid></item><item><title>Documents reveal unauthorised sediment releases at Blackwater Coal Mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/blackwater-coal-mine-contamination-sediment/105769922</link><description>A report obtained by lobby group Lock The Gate under right-to-information laws reveal a mine in central Queensland was releasing sediment into environmentally sensitive areas for more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c0e5d78e0e78c7d0e25c51e02aed43f</guid></item><item><title>Nepalese migrants turning to parents to help with childcare and culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/nepalese-migrants-turning-to-parents-to-help-with/105772960</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ef1641c480b7de5217f0b243fef7f49</guid></item><item><title>Fortunes change quickly in AFLW as round of upsets shakes up ladder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/round-of-upsets-shakes-up-aflw-ladder-mid-season/105772256</link><description>After a tough start to the year, Geelong sit just outside the top eight and equal on points with the reining grand finalists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a314ed873d6767758eb39088f9f9e0f6</guid></item><item><title>Live updates: ANZ hit with a record $240m fine for 'unconscionable' conduct, ASX set to fall after Wall Street treads water</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-sept-15/105772186</link><description>ANZ has been hit with a massive fine for unconscionable conduct impacting 65,000 customers ranging from the federal government to dead account holders. Follow the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b1ea0b2586714bfb8864773045ae93a</guid></item><item><title>Traditional custodian readies for 'challenge' over North West Shelf gas project extension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/traditional-custodian-fights-north-west-shelf-approval/105770306</link><description>Environment Minister Murray Watt approved the extension of Australia's biggest gas project last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fff78b1c904abb60057a8fd295536c56</guid></item><item><title>Almost 100 students from Green Point Christian College have put Mr Formston's life story into dance.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/almost-100-students-from-green-point-christian-college-have-put-/105762512</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61bea7e7f30f03f4aced2007ca0bc314</guid></item><item><title>Blind, big-wave surfer Matt Formston inspires students' dance performance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/blind-big-wave-surfer-matt-formston-inspires-students/105758670</link><description>Record-breaking surfer and Paralympic cycling gold medallist Matt Formston's feats are brought to life in a dance performance by students in New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7ece4beed1bdd4fb2bc2ae712f13dea</guid></item><item><title>Specialist GPs to diagnose ADHD in WA amid calls for further easing of restrictions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/wa-gps-soon-start-diagnosing-adhd/105759814</link><description>As a select cohort of WA GPs begins to diagnose ADHD in people older than 10, parents of younger children and some medical professionals have expressed concerns about the scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32f743c6d37c23f14438dac29a9eb199</guid></item><item><title>Inside the Australian lab where scientists study bird flu and other emerging disease threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/nate-goes-inside-the-australian-lab-where/105773024</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8a3ae876bad63be662df15d1a3acf96</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: Marles reluctant to outline percentage of GDP spent on defence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/federal-politics-live-blog-sept-15/105772900</link><description>Deputy Prime Minister Richard Marles defends Australia's spending on defence as a percentage of GDP amid pressure for it to be lifted. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca7a459a805e02ad8171e4c3d68d78b9</guid></item><item><title>ANZ faces record $240m penalty for ripping off customers and government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/anz-record-penalty-asic-federal-court/105773084</link><description>ANZ bank agrees to a record penalty with the corporate regulator over its dealings with about 65,000 customers, as well as the federal government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8475aebd937a4522870145c77b4667d8</guid></item><item><title>Reece Walsh headbutt, Pat Carrigan high shot could lead to NRL bans after Broncos beat Raiders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/reece-walsh-headbutt-pat-carrigan-bans-from-broncos-raiders/105772942</link><description>Brisbane's stunning win over the Raiders could be soured if Reece Walsh and Pat Carrigan cop suspensions that would rub them out of the preliminary final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69bc0f4f4df315eed7d8c781e1acb538</guid></item><item><title>Emmys 2025 red carpet: Lisa, Walton Goggins, Megan Stalter and Kathy Bates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/2025-emmys-red-carpet-fashion/105752046</link><description>The stars of the television industry are arriving at the Peacock Theater in Los Angeles. Here are some of the looks we've seen so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85981e3d6d9c2977cda8244d6580248c</guid></item><item><title>WA's expanded container deposit scheme to cost wineries, distilleries millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/container-for-change-wa-wine-expansion-hits-small-business/105763914</link><description>Producers in Western Australia's premier wine region say the state government's expanded bottle recycling scheme is set to cost them millions of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16ff8a6ec9140b73f0af3e85a003dec0</guid></item><item><title>Australia beats India in first of three ODIs before Women's Cricket World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/australia-beats-india-in-odi-world-cup-warm-up/105773182</link><description>Australia's Cricket World Cup preparations are in full swing as three batters score half-centuries in a big run chase in the first of three ODIs against India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a29f09f0be7bd9b554de11bd5f4906d1</guid></item><item><title>Emmy Awards 2025 live: Severance leads nominees on television's biggest night</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/emmy-awards-2025-live-blog-latest-updates/105757172</link><description>It is time for television's biggest night, the Emmy Awards. Workplace thriller Severance leads the pack with 27 nominations, while The Bear and Hacks will duke it out in the comedy categories. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f0dab0d1494400d0b01fc6483c43b32</guid></item><item><title>Port Hinchinbrook marina remains inaccessible despite dredging project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/port-inchinbrook-marina-remains-inaccessible-after-dredging/105739106</link><description>Mud and silt continue to choke the channel connecting the controversial development to the Great Barrier Reef, once again putting industry and conservationists at odds over the fix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08f6ca749e0003ee3df4e1048a1bdfda</guid></item></channel></rss>