<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 19:34:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The pros and cons of the expanded home buyer scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/first-homebuyer-scheme-explainer-income-limits-property-caps/105838164</link><description>The revamped scheme has come into effect, with first home buyers of all income levels now able to purchase a property with only a 5 per cent deposit. Here are all the changes explained.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">164b15e14b7ab8348ed381818b59b1cf</guid></item><item><title>China's K visa scheme has some worrying about jobs in a country already facing challenges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/china-k-visa-draws-fierce-criticism/105840312</link><description>The new visa is designed to attract top global STEM talent but has sparked fierce backlash, with critics warning it could squeeze Chinese nationals out of the graduate job market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83c304642bcc0e464acc5ea89a172ec6</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm and Brisbane Broncos face off in NRL Grand Final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/melbourne-storm-and-brisbane-broncos-face-off-in/105846424</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7c17a506df456fc9c620d5c07d1e268</guid></item><item><title>Former WA Health boss outlines missing pieces of puzzle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/former-wa-health-boss-outlines-missing-pieces-of/105846500</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fed0bc5657b6da20e039ca9c89e5ec2c</guid></item><item><title>AI is creeping into our court system. Will it undermine justice?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/artificial-intelligence-law-robot-legal-judge-jury-ai/105545900</link><description>Artificial intelligence is coming for the law. Are we ready for robots to become judge and jury?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e1797579913bae4cb5a8a9d33306767</guid></item><item><title>Harry Lush is handing out alpine plants to form a large-scale urban climate refuge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/harry-lush-director-of-gondwana-project/105853556</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc052d43324e94b02a9758439e00028f</guid></item><item><title>Calls to ban machetes as elderly Territorians terrorised in their own homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/stateline-nt-calls-ban-machetes-as-elderly-territorians-hurt/105855298</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50227819e4fb3d1211eb8ade2e674398</guid></item><item><title>Homeschool registrations are rising and policy needs to catch up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/australians-homeschooling-registrations-growth-queensland/105857486</link><description>Primary school homeschooling registrations in Queensland grew by 110 per cent from 2021 to 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2da6ac568e30445c88402c2dd8b19cc</guid></item><item><title>Broncos shares surge 40 per cent after Grand Final win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/broncos-shares-surge-40-after-grand-final-win/105858608</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb9f530fa3b53960f57deb774eadfed4</guid></item><item><title>Trio of scientists win Nobel Prize in Medicine for 'discoveries concerning peripheral immune tolerance'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/scientists-win-nobel-prize-medicine-for-immune-system-work/105859742</link><description>The Nobel Prize for Medicine has been given to three scientists for discovering how our immune systems protect us from microbes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9af5df2f41780faee103603c8684e8f8</guid></item><item><title>Expert cautions people using AI as search for missing boy in SA outback scaled back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/gus-missing-boy-facebook-ai-misinformation/105856594</link><description>Users have reported Facebook's AI search has shown incorrect information about four-year-old Gus who remains missing in SA's outback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f85f82b8a98c3c714a1862384b881823</guid></item><item><title>Fresh and fragrant strawberry and cinnamon torte - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/alison-alexander-s-strawberry-and-cinnamon-torte/105849766</link><description>Sweet strawberries pair with a subtle cinnamon spice in this irresistible torte.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f19db1f54abf4889c55a5e00aedebdc8</guid></item><item><title>Planning can help save you money this festive season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/preparing-financially-for-christmas-and-holidays/105795388</link><description>Australians estimate Christmas costs them about $800 a year, on average, but planning ahead can reduce the financial burden.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">158e6acd232ffd0c3bea1632ef3d82e3</guid></item><item><title>What the Health of the Nation report tells us about GP doctors by numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/health-of-the-nation-gp-report-by-numbers/105861118</link><description>These five charts give us a glimpse into what the current state of general practice looks like in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fab4fda08cc0d73f7ca73f5c43a01ec1</guid></item><item><title>Powerlifting champion aged 82 and ready to represent Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/powerlifting-champion-aged-82-and-ready-to/105868692</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e86a029c85c4645e6a5b1179ad310de</guid></item><item><title>Beast of War is the indie shark movie that bit off a lot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/beast-of-war-kiah-roache-turner-mark-coles-smith/105857098</link><description>Mystery Road star Mark Coles Smith and his Beast of War director Kiah Roache-Turner on taking a chomp out of WWII soldiers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c11e53d16ff74618f42da0430ef3787b</guid></item><item><title>Deloitte caught out using AI in report for federal government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/deloitte-caught-out-using-ai-in-report-for-federal/105874634</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73a40e241a39295c35b76e8f87cb1de6</guid></item><item><title>The US sees Pacific Islands as 'tip of the spear', but locals fear becoming China's 'bullseye'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/united-states-military-presence-pacific-guam-palau/105861216</link><description>The United States is spending billions of dollars muscling up across its Pacific Island military outposts, but locals fear their peaceful islands will become a target.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b686686c787aed163ffe21d540cdc7e</guid></item><item><title>Why Alliyah is identifying themselves as a victim-survivor — and the power this act holds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/alliyah-identifying-as-abuse-victim-survivor/105865908</link><description>Alliyah's decision to talk about their abuse was a brave act that exposed the red flags that weren't caught along the way — and they hope it helps others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef3b7c86d2e08ce64793b8a13d322eee</guid></item><item><title>Two dead on private property in Tasmania after tree falls in wild winds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/tasmania-wild-weather-two-dead-in-tree-fall/105875332</link><description>Two people have died after a tree fell on them on a rural property in Tasmania's north-west, during Friday's severe winds and wet weather, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">762b5ecc8c7afc01f1284936da8823ae</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia urges respect for its sovereignty after Australia-PNG defence treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/indonesia-responded-pukpuk-defence-agreement-australia-png/105869738</link><description>The landmark agreement commits both countries to "meet the common danger" in the event of an armed attack on either. With that, questions have been raised about Australia's role if the conflict in West Papua escalates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d73f53cf0f068b144851c0c5f4cd706</guid></item><item><title>Principals' power to ban aggressive parents from school grounds to extend to social media behaviour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/safety-protections-parents-schools-aggressive-parents-review/105875552</link><description>Principals in Victoria already have the power to ban aggressive or violent parents from school grounds, but the state government is looking to apply the power to parents' behaviour on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cfdbdd1cc62140ca01e0eeea675488e</guid></item><item><title>Protecting rock art from wasp nests in Central Australia's Trephina Gorge with chopsticks and brushes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/rock-art-cleaning-at-trephina-gorge/105867252</link><description>Rock art has significant cultural importance to traditional owners, and is a highlight for visitors who make the hike to see it. These Ltyentye Apurte Rangers are working to help keep them protected from wasp nests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e32adeeb4bd3293608b4c2b5f2f9468a</guid></item><item><title>Older borrowers taking out later-in-life loans risk post-retirement mortgage pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/housing-prices-older-borrowers-risk-mortgage-debt-in-retirement/105867244</link><description>Property analysts, brokers and banks report more borrowers are taking on big housing debts in their late 40s and 50s and, potentially, a retirement still saddled with mortgage repayments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cea624f58afd0c1f6bdfb886c7aaa758</guid></item><item><title>Genomic medicine could be huge but 5 million Australians may miss out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/genomic-medicine-could-be-huge-but-5-million/105878606</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ed6e2fb9d4d9d0324e237a7c8b62bfe</guid></item><item><title>Diane Keaton, star of Annie Hall, The Godfather films dies at 79</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/diane-keaton-dies/105881842</link><description>The unexpected news of Keaton's passing has been met with shock around the world, with stars remembering their time with the actor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">880393f1a8884001569183fb7e30b624</guid></item><item><title>Carter Gordon rushed back into Wallabies squad after quitting NRL's Titans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/rugby-australia-queensland-reds-carter-gordon-quits-nrl-titans/105884978</link><description>The Wallabies waste no time in welcoming back fly half Carter Gordon to rugby union, less than two hours after it was announced he was leaving the NRL.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3aa32c62a9f0aa84542aa4fe59849c01</guid></item><item><title>How to tell if your Qantas personal data has hit the dark web and what you can do if it has</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/qantas-cyber-hack-has-my-data-been-leaked-what-should-i-do/105884604</link><description>Hackers have released Qantas customer data onto the dark web. Here's what experts say to look out for if you think your personal data may be caught up in the leak and what actions you can take.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0686253e2a0f07a77f7a19d16ef3924b</guid></item><item><title>What to do if your mortgage payments haven't gone down despite an RBA rate cut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/how-to-lower-mortgage-repayments-after-rba-interest-rate-cut/105844258</link><description>You might assume home loan repayments will automatically reduce when an interest rate cut is passed on, but this isn’t always the case. Here's how to check.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9321ceed8438c8f5233f33dc1bbcc97</guid></item><item><title>Here's how Labor's revised super proposal would work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/labor-super-tax-changes-explained/105885434</link><description>Every prominent criticism of the tax has been addressed, with the result that it will apply to fewer people and raise less money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e8eac54b40c708087b8083935640a86</guid></item><item><title>Hamas releases all remaining Israeli hostages in Gaza, IDF confirms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/hamas-releases-all-remaining-israeli-hostages-in-gaza/105885332</link><description>Israel says Hamas has handed over all 20 living hostages in the first phase of the Israel-Gaza ceasefire agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1da4a5a9ff5c0b24b017021965f0b640</guid></item><item><title>England provides the blueprint for 2029 Women's Rugby World Cup in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/rugby-world-cup-women-england-wallaroos/105874404</link><description>The recently concluded Women's Rugby World Cup in England took the game to new heights. But, as Alicia Lucas writes, Australia needs to take big strides to ensure its hosting of the tournament in 2029 continues to raise the bar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b19337aaae0b20b96cc6cd07fe6cffb7</guid></item><item><title>Why Santos is behind your soaring electricity and mortgage costs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/why-santos-is-behind-your-soaring-electricity-and-mortgage-costs/105885202</link><description>It was a primary force behind Australia’s inflationary surge, it’s forced businesses either to the wall or to shift offshore, undermined national industry policy and resulted in the loss of countless thousands of jobs. And it all hinged on one disastrous decision in an Adelaide boardroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">103585cee22276b5b682cf9cc4c3ec88</guid></item><item><title>How to help kids prepare for music exams and competitions and manage performance anxiety</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/music-exam-competition-manage-performance-anxiety/105873254</link><description>Music exams and competitions aren't easy, but our experts have some tips to make the process as stress-free as possible, including managing performance anxiety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ce54e25b952b97ee1ce5b2b5c2b6f1c</guid></item><item><title>Fresh doubts over plans to boost Perth's tree canopy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/fresh-doubts-over-plan-for-perth-tree-canopy/105886692</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eeff764a51281b1a24aecd32b078248f</guid></item><item><title>The Hobart Clinic offered government funding lifeline to stay open for six months</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/hobart-clinic-offered-funding-lifeline-government/105871126</link><description>A southern Tasmanian private mental health clinic will remain open for at least six months after securing $2 million in government funding while it explores a new business model.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35cc0c7b5d6ca1be32aa4ab4247addc4</guid></item><item><title>Australia hosts hottest place on Earth, but here's why it's not a heatwave yet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/australia-hosts-hottest-place-on-earth/105888248</link><description>Parts of Pilbara and Kimberley surpassed 40 degrees Celsius yesterday but meteorologists say the temperatures will not trigger a heatwave warning yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d5466674485d37a8a2a5d373d647f80</guid></item><item><title>Bridget Archer announces funding for Hobart Clinic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/bridget-archer-announces-funding-for-hobart-clinic/105890098</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb1b30d865a9a239f2642a4dd843222b</guid></item><item><title>WA's flu season exceeds 30,000 cases as authorities blame low vaccination rates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/wa-flu-season-worst-ever-poor-vaccination-rates/105891252</link><description>Western Australia records its worst flu season on record, with more than 30,000 influenza cases reported this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f1f2484096733debed58e21c7b6682</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105891880</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">653774c141b651a45c0a8cb8f098cded</guid></item><item><title>An embarrassing backflip by Chalmers on super or a strategic shift?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/was-chalmers-taught-a-lesson-in-his-fight-over-superannuation/105891400</link><description>After two years of refusing to reshape his superannuation shake-up, the treasurer abandons the idea of taxing unrealised gains while agreeing to index a key tax threshold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81f26bfccf07023bc6ed3051fab482c2</guid></item><item><title>Dying mother loses life insurance after failing to declare UTI tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/dying-mother-loses-life-insurance-after-failing-to/105891944</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3a16fd23e92a2762fe66d3e28645c0c</guid></item><item><title>Illawarrra Academy of Sport holds open testing day for aspiring young athletes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/illawarrra-academy-of-sport-pen-testing-day-young-athletes/105878204</link><description>Young athletes wanting to be the next Emma McKeon or Jessica Hull have been put through high-performance testing to see if they have what it takes to be a professional.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15a018213f26351372e484eeb90ad629</guid></item><item><title>Randa Abdel-Fattah reveals how the Israel-Gaza war shaped her new book Discipline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/randa-abdel-fattah-palestinian-author-new-book-discipline/105865540</link><description>Randa Abdel-Fattah explores the experience of Palestinian Australians in Discipline, her first book for adults.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5256627cfb3d5e9fd11c695daf718ec</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump posts video of US strikes on alleged drug trafficking boat off coast of Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/donald-trump-posts-video-of-us-strikes-on-alleged/105893326</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7821ad1026d9a5f2396b0de54e5b73f6</guid></item><item><title>The US has dropped out of the top 10 most powerful passports — but where does Australia rank?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/united-states-passport-drops-out-of-top-10-most-powerful/105893408</link><description>The US passport has fallen to 12th place, a five-spot decline from its previous ranking, tying with Malaysia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">210460eb5dcbc50a34d606ea70c1a796</guid></item><item><title>Conjoined boys born in PNG bound for Australia for medical treatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/png-conjoined-twins-braun-hospital-medical-treatment-sydney/105888942</link><description>The boys, who are only the second known case of conjoined twins born in PNG, are expected to come to Australia for medical treatment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">602984aa1a6e648bd1700a79bdd0ced0</guid></item><item><title>ARLC says NRL players face 10-year ban for joining rebel leagues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/nrl-players-face-10-year-ban-for-joining-rebel-leagues/105894992</link><description>The Australian Rugby League Commission has announced a 10-year ban for any NRL player who agrees to join a football competition it does not recognise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddb37f0928e43c1b5bbf5bd94cff1dfa</guid></item><item><title>How long does it take to acclimatise to a new place when the weather is very different?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/how-to-adjust-different-climates/105887794</link><description>Do our bodies actually acclimatise when moving from one climate to another and can we do anything to smooth the transition?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7b51651bfb1e6f2f7657bf344b2ebee</guid></item><item><title>Australia's baby recession deepens, new ABS data says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/australia-s-baby-recession-deepens-new-abs-data-says/105541086</link><description>The baby recession in Australia is deepening as cost of living pressures make the decision for people to have children less of a choice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c8e24e2ff09a356f53956f037c71227</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105896606</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5de03d8a271e83312ef111c5e775f4b8</guid></item><item><title>Australia sees opportunity in China-US rare earths dispute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/trump-albanese-xi-critical-minerals-us-china/105884214</link><description>Trump may have expressed "shock", but his administration is clearly not surprised at China's willingness to flex its dominance on rare earths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa98a5f162d3f58f6ff157adeeba8042</guid></item><item><title>US wants to make rare earth deals with Australia but without China involved, expert says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/us-is-open-to-make-rare-earth-deals-with-australia/105895128</link><description>As rare earths re-emerge as a central battleground in the US-China trade war, Australian companies are already striking deals to supply America. A policy expert says talks at the White House next week could secure a national agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93a0c2c00f2f1e07783629d538ec8b4e</guid></item><item><title>One student's journey from heart transplant to final exams as HSC begins in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/hsc-exams-begin-nsw-nathan-barbara-shares-his-story/105896454</link><description>Sitting year 12 exams is a big achievement for anyone, but more so for Nathan Barbara having undergone a heart transplant less than a year ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04f234df9186de4f609cfbd4eaf6e457</guid></item><item><title>Fifty years since the Balibo Five murders, families are still seeking justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/balibo-five-murders-50-years-indonesia-australia-timor-leste/105884316</link><description>On the 50th anniversary of the Balibo Five murders, families are still grieving the loss of their loved ones and remain committed to holding those responsible accountable for their actions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1314ae8328046a527aba9120658d2d1d</guid></item><item><title>What is Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder and how is it diagnosed? Unpacking questions about ADHD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/what-is-adhd-attention-deficit-hyperactivity-disorder-diagnosis/105843020</link><description>October marks Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) awareness month and the focus this year is on the many faces of the neurological condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">326c4e8c1519f7e7bdd9cf1c15fa5446</guid></item><item><title>Australians Ajla Tomljanović and James Duckworth reach WTA and ATP quarterfinals in Asia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/tennis-alja-tomljanovic-james-duckworth-ningbo-almaty-open/105897556</link><description>Australian duo Ajla Tomljanović and James Duckworth reach the quarterfinals at their respective events in China and Kazakhstan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">336d915e1efab8f376e17988ed3ec4ca</guid></item><item><title>Nikon Small World photomicroscopy competition's top 15 images of 2025 capture our tiniest signs of life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/nikon-small-world-photomicrography-competition-2025-winners/105880892</link><description>Extreme close-ups of rice weevil, pollen in a spider's web and a geometer moth laying eggs are among this year's Nikon Small World competition entries from thousands of scientists and artists across the globe. Here are the judges' favourites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">422146c134220b9daaeb85e97181786b</guid></item><item><title>Soldier killed in vehicle rollover during army training in north Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/army-soldier-killed-in-vehicle-rollover-while-training/105897572</link><description>The Department of Defence says an Australian soldier has died after a single-vehicle rollover during training at the Australian Army's Townsville Field Training Area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9064921280d2988c8f1986804181b2f4</guid></item><item><title>Replica of destroyed Juukan Gorge being built five years after Rio Tinto blast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/juukan-gorge-rock-shelter-recreated-models-virtual-reality/105889276</link><description>A full-scale replica of the Juukan Gorge rock shelter, destroyed by mining company Rio Tinto, will be built over the remains of the original in Western Australia's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17d49eeea6ddb3bcb9585027b4d633f3</guid></item><item><title>R360 hits back at Australian Rugby League Commission's threat of 10-year bans for rebel players</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/arlc-nrl-r360-hits-back-at-ban-threats-for-players/105897732</link><description>The boss of R360 says threats of 10-year bans for NRL players who defect to the rebel competition are predictable, as the code war escalates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a507cb97abb406d1566b15b62aa13750</guid></item><item><title>Four-time Olympic champion Ariarne Titmus announces retirement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/swimming-ariarne-titmus-announces-retirement/105898036</link><description>Ariarne Titmus draws the curtain on a decorated career, in which she won eight medals across two Olympic Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b20c3d209eb66b297a235d75ac8ea914</guid></item><item><title>Australia's unemployment rate jumps to 4.5pc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/australia-unemployment-rate-rises-september-2025/105898244</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate jumped to 4.5 per cent in September, up from 4.3 per cent in August.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">944d983f4c3e591e79c311c6deea0d20</guid></item><item><title>Ariarne Titmus's retirement ends years of sacrifice and allows her to at last savour her greatness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/ariarne-titmus-retirement-a-career-of-sacrifice-and-greatness/105898280</link><description>Ariarne Titmus has given her life to a dream. As she sets off on her next adventures, she can be in no doubt that her years of sacrifice and devotion were worth it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ace92f301f8bbd380cf4ea10e08f291</guid></item><item><title>Consumer groups, regulator concern as number of Australians accessing super to fix health surges again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/concern-over-accessing-super-for-medical-care-rises/105876384</link><description>Australians were allowed to withdraw $1.37 billion from their superannuation accounts for medical costs last financial year, in another jump from previous years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc6ab38204feeb436342c69f39e8b1a1</guid></item><item><title>First Nations artists warn against AI 'double colonisation' as Meta uses work for training</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/first-nations-creatives-warn-against-ai-double-colonisation/105889290</link><description>The rapid development of AI is testing the effectiveness of the Copyright Act, with creative and media industries calling for better protections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fc2ae378cfa0f6d485867eb2b770985</guid></item><item><title>Curators among 45 full-time jobs to be axed in Art Gallery of NSW cuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/curators-among-45-jobs-to-be-axed-at-art-gallery-of-nsw/105892942</link><description>Leaked documents show curators and conservator jobs will go as 45 full-time roles are cut from the Art Gallery of NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cf617a6570a7217321d8d4482b5215b</guid></item><item><title>Albanese dismisses lobby concerns, Chalmers takes one for the team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/anthony-albanese-jim-chalmers-good-oppositions/105884222</link><description>This week, the PM was not wasting any time on "this" issue, and the treasurer took one for the team as Brett Worthington signs off with his final political wrap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8caaca04017f6e10ef0a87a9a892f94f</guid></item><item><title>Inquiry into Queensland container refund scheme makes referrals to Crime and Corruption Commission</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/qld-containers-for-change-referred-to-ccc/105899540</link><description>A parliamentary inquiry into the container refund scheme says it received "troubling evidence," including alleged conflicts of interest and unfair contracts, as well as bullying and harassment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dfbae0a619b4f5a916e4644cb466f1f</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/thursday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/105900826</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39251dff22abd93c574816fddff415b9</guid></item><item><title>National Gallery will host APY artwork exhibition after paintings cleared of improper interference</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/act-apy-indigenous-art-interference-national-gallery-exhibition/105901272</link><description>The National Gallery will host an exhibition of art from the Aṉangu Pitjantjatjara Yankunytjatjara Lands three years after a video appearing to show a non-Aboriginal assistant helping to paint an artwork led to it being postponed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f256cd75d8dd22a070a0b023a2212e2</guid></item><item><title>Rugby Championship scrapped for 2026 due to Test calendar squeeze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/rugby-championship-scrapped-for-2026-test-season/105901714</link><description>The competition will not be played next year but will appear on the global calendar the following three years, including ahead of the 2027 Rugby World Cup, the organisers say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84c38b2c85ed36bf3a8054c41860989d</guid></item><item><title>Calls for Australia to follow England's ban on supermarket junk food specials</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/calls-for-australia-to-follow-england-ban-on-junk-food-specials/105807974</link><description>Research finding supermarkets continue to offer discounts and multi-buy deals on junk food more frequently than healthy food prompts calls for Australia to follow England's lead and ban "buy one, get one free" deals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edbe2cd8f08f8c2fc9c6395f9edf30b7</guid></item><item><title>'Dangerously low' funding to Tasmanian arts sector creating reputational damage, minister warned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/tasmanian-arts-industry-highly-vulnerable-low-funding-investment/105899498</link><description>"Dangerously low" arts sector funding has rendered the Tasmanian industry "highly vulnerable", with funding stagnant since 2016-17, the state government has conceded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a29de7c4d5bc252c9a785dea93220878</guid></item><item><title>Jim Chalmers and Tony Burke are in a long race for prime position</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/jim-chalmers-tony-burke-leadership/105884226</link><description>There is general agreement in Labor that Jim Chalmers is the government's best communicator. But insiders watching this race know Tony Burke is the master tactician.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93f58dc170f3f37c70cca03a69e3a6f5</guid></item><item><title>Drunken motorcyclist crashes with daughter riding as passenger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/drunken-motorcyclist-crashes-with-daughter-passenger/105898498</link><description>A Mildura father-of-six avoids jail after drunkenly crashing his motorbike while carrying his young daughter as a passenger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b7dbbdb3b9ed775f287c7490a9599c8</guid></item><item><title>BHP vs China Inc: What the iron ore dispute says about Australia's present and future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/what-bhp-china-iron-ore-dispute-means-to-australia/105901692</link><description>The resolution of negotiations between Australian mining giant BHP and China's state-backed iron ore buyer China Mineral Resources Group could reshape not just the resources industry, but also international trade flows, global markets, and the relationship between China and the West.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f17745151acc39e0b5f38368c4928c68</guid></item><item><title>Zach Merrett trade drama a reminder that deals can no longer be judged by amount of first-round picks involved</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/afl-trade-period-analysis-zach-merrett-first-round-pick-value/105898588</link><description>The AFL trade period offered three different test cases on just how much value a first-round pick holds during negotiations. Two stars got their moves, while one was left stranded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28e8bb8d5802a90c22f1d69d1a4727c3</guid></item><item><title>New research shows impact of lead poisoning on ancient humans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/new-research-shows-impact-lead-poisoning-ancient-humans/105899188</link><description>A new study claims lead might be the reason why Homo sapiens came to dominate the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12aa86f8c8828a99bbdb6054ea89c8c1</guid></item><item><title>Dangerous flammable cladding still not removed from dozens of NSW high-rise apartment buildings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/government-yet-to-fix-cladding-on-dozens-of-apartments-re-scheme/105900296</link><description>Dozens of high-rise apartment buildings across the state are still covered in flammable cladding as the NSW government's scheme has failed to fix them on schedule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">900570fd41fc7cafb3f056a176d7d52c</guid></item><item><title>Specialist health services shortfall for women in regional WA leave many struggling for support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/women-missing-out-on-specialist-health-services-in-regional-wa/105866424</link><description>Faced with a lack of specialist women's health services, women in regional WA are researching their own conditions and volunteering to raise awareness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a46a1f1f255a795ba616233f2bb18c5</guid></item><item><title>How a 15yo autistic boy tinkering in his bedroom triggered WA's biggest ever data breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/joshua-unwittingly-triggered-major-wa-health-data-breach-autism/105455250</link><description>Joshua's "passion project" with a radio scanner led to one of WA's most significant public health data breaches. His story highlights the challenges confronting autistic people caught up in the legal system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13c71de037de480416dd879b9c6eab51</guid></item><item><title>McLaren's 'papaya rules' may be over as Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris battle for the F1 drivers' championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/mclaren-papaya-rules-oscar-piastri-lando-norris-f1/105855110</link><description>"Papaya rules" have dominated Formula 1 for two seasons, but with both McLaren drivers in the heat of a world championship battle, Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris may no longer prioritise what is best for the team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c1dd9f6429245aceb6baaa21e041d3e</guid></item><item><title>SA Education Department fined after teen fell from school playground swing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/sa-education-department-fined-playground-swing-fall/105900366</link><description>South Australia's Education Department has been fined $225,000 after a student at a special school fell from a swing which had not had a comprehensive safety inspection for eight years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cdc7ec760bf1e318791fcad162c615f</guid></item><item><title>Defence in talks to support Gaza peace plan but Australia says no request yet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/defence-in-talks-with-us-to-support-gaza-peace-plan/105902742</link><description>Australia's defence force has had discussions with the Unted States to provide support for its Gaza peace plan but the government says no formal request has been made yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd80619b996f35eb17de143a6b7e07dc</guid></item><item><title>Virtual emergency department a lifeline for patients in regional areas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/virtual-emergency-department-option-for-patients-remote-areas/105371852</link><description>A virtual emergency room app created during the pandemic could help bridge healthcare gaps in regional Victoria. But more patients need to dial-in and use the resource.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cce3e05039289d83c6bdbae0a5d4e7b</guid></item><item><title>Bears kill record number of people in Japan amid scores of attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/record-number-of-bear-attacks-in-japan/105902770</link><description>At least seven people have been killed by bears in the country since April and many more have been injured as the hungry animals venture into human territory to find food.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41b4b93bb120166534952debb22263e8</guid></item><item><title>Venezuela says US strike on suspected drug vessel 'extrajudicial executions'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/new-usa-strike-on-venezuelan-drugs-boat-leaves-survivors/105903128</link><description>A US strike against a suspected Venezuelan drug-smuggling vessel has left multiple survivors, as Venezuela's ambassador to the United Nations condemned the strikes as a "series of assassinations".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a3ad366e7e0f7f78fc016c52b612098</guid></item><item><title>'No doubt' Anthony Albanese and Donald Trump will discuss critical minerals: Chalmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/albanese-trump-chalmers-critical-minerals-deal/105903392</link><description>Anthony Albanese will "no doubt" use a meeting with Donald Trump next week to discuss critical minerals, the treasurer says as he dismisses a call for Australia to "decouple" with China over rare earth materials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fe4351ff10e966c7a84c8e260555fa8</guid></item><item><title>Pacific Championships set to start without Australia as strong Samoa and Tonga teams take on New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/pacific-championships-stars-embrace-their-island-heritage/105903826</link><description>Emerging superpowers Samoa and Tonga will field formidable teams loaded with NRL talent in the third edition of the Pacific Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07fb63cc9e9ec53c5f2664aaf516d600</guid></item><item><title>Ways to increase safety on a first date and red flags to watch for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/red-flags-on-first-date-safety-tips/105805388</link><description>Both people involved in a date are responsible for creating a safe environment, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f5f2638f6ee24d2f8b7347e8441dce8</guid></item><item><title>Wayne Swan steps down as Labor president urging party to focus on membership boost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/wayne-swan-labor-president-leaves-role-politics/105905064</link><description>Labor party president Wayne Swan will step down next July and has warned the ALP must boost membership if it is to survive into the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75e127f2e28c7f78ce730de287d98398</guid></item><item><title>Wittenoom asbestos contamination prompts legal threat from Banjima traditional owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/wittenoom-asbestos-litigation-documentary/105886444</link><description>After decades of disconnection, the traditional owners of Wittenoom say they are prepared to take legal action to ensure the area is properly remediated so they can return to country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">713ee52afb0c4689f99c025841f00428</guid></item><item><title>Strict conditions imposed on future LIV Golf site at North Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/strict-conditions-on-north-adelaide-golf-course-redevelopment/105905844</link><description>South Australia's Aboriginal affairs minister has imposed 31 strict conditions on the government's planned redevelopment of the North Adelaide golf course.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc6d01343d110faca4bb8653ade74cc5</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's Trump meeting comes amid global geopolitical circus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/gaza-ceasefire-deal-donald-trump-anthony-albanese-trade-tariff/105884238</link><description>All signs suggest Anthony Albanese will be sticking with Plan A in his meeting with the US president on Tuesday, rather than becoming a prop for the bigger global circus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7369e04e283103228bfcf69dddc12dd2</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew giving up his royal titles and honours after speaking with King Charles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/prince-andrew-to-give-up-royal-titles-and-honours/105907098</link><description>King Charles's brother has come under significant pressure after being linked to the late convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein and his ties to China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b88d507f6b73a3388229f325fd5168e</guid></item><item><title>Administrative Review Tribunal swamped by surging demand, more than 100 members short</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/administrative-review-tribunal-overwhelmed-surging-demand/105893728</link><description>The Administrative Review Tribunal was set up to resolve issues with its predecessor, but has struggled with staffing and long wait times over its first year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fd2f156e95340a969daa8b6003273f1</guid></item><item><title>Education department admits not enough done to stop Dubbo College Delroy aide harming children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/systemic-failure-to-investigate-nsw-dubbo-school-staff/105807290</link><description>The NSW government says it should have taken allegations of wrongdoing by a male school staff member more seriously. That failure left those who reported it so isolated their mental health spiralled and never fully recovered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c22f6955d77c23cb8f7c088405ad508</guid></item><item><title>Wall Street sell-off could mean hip-pocket relief for millions of Australians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/insurance-companies-caught-in-global-sector-sell-off/105906164</link><description>Australia's big insurance companies were sold off heavily on the share market on Friday after a wave of anxiety hit the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e35eee1242809cb384df7776dc560ebc</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's family reportedly made hundreds of millions from crypto after White House return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/how-trump-family-profits-from-cryptocurrencies/105445400</link><description>US President Donald Trump and his family have reportedly amassed hundreds of millions of dollars from cryptocurrencies. Here is what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d405316e27218a44724818a9f9ff772a</guid></item><item><title>Young people with chronic pain feel 'unheard', misunderstood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/young-people-living-with-chronic-pain/105898314</link><description>Chronic pain affects one in five Australian children. Two young people who experience it want more people to understand their conditions and better support for all children in pain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">946486ae5287caf11084ac18ee24e69e</guid></item><item><title>James Duckworth returns to ATP Tour semifinal four years after his last</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/james-duckworth-atp-tour-astana-open-semi-final/105907190</link><description>Four years since he last reached an ATP tournament semifinal in Kazakhstan, Australian James Duckworth is back in the last four at the Almaty Open</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dceb858841c1c847c349b2a7432508b3</guid></item><item><title>Hospital in the Home program helping young man with agoraphobia who 'cut himself off from the world'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/hospital-in-the-home-northwest-tasmania-mental-health/105789004</link><description>Tom French's agoraphobia meant he couldn't leave the house to access the mental health care he needed, but a Hospital in the Home program means the care is coming to him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1b964e8ba63ca42e36daf1af0d1b9c8</guid></item><item><title>From a Springsteen biopic to a doggy horror: here are the movies out in October</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/october-movie-wrap-what-to-watch/105893300</link><description>From the highly anticipated Bruce Springsteen biopic to a horror movie from the viewpoint of the family pup, here are the films filling up cinemas in October.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f217a9477d3de1211d4744ae2ba19bd8</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne's record-setting AFLW winning streak is clear in the numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/north-melbourne-setting-aflw-standards/105905842</link><description>Having developed the program layer by layer since joining the AFLW in 2019, North Melbourne's disciplined, professional style of footy is forcing the rest of the league to rise to their level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3f69ec228f1094f89b081dd9d305cb5</guid></item><item><title>Minister flags compulsory voting in local government elections, 4-year terms amid low voter turnout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/compulsory-voting-flagged-for-wa-local-government-election/105901804</link><description>Voting in council elections could become mandatory in Western Australia if the turnout for this weekend's poll continues to plummet, the local government minister warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90ce7dc5327df5d0b3904814e2638839</guid></item><item><title>Gungahlin United Football Club to fold after losing NPL licence, leaving 2,000 grassroots players club-less</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/gungahlin-united-fc-fold-capital-football-licence-revoke/105907530</link><description>Just last year, the club won the league, and a former president was jailed for stealing $20k. Now they are going to fold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b94409bd3e5cff77f2199cae368e6fbf</guid></item><item><title>Who is Prince Andrew? Why is he giving up his royal title?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/why-prince-andrew-gives-up-royal-titles-duke-of-york/105907380</link><description>The third-born child of Queen Elizabeth II will still be referred to as a prince and is expected to continue living in his Windsor mansion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08536e709980d0a36f65e1774362c22d</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce hasn't quit the Nationals yet but he's got one foot out the door</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/speers-analysis-barnaby-joyce-has-not-quit-the-nationals-yet/105907744</link><description>In declaring he won't be recontesting his lower house seat and letting speculation run that he might jump ship for One Nation, Barnaby Joyce is declaring he's had enough with the Nationals under David Littleproud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f61bd6ea4984b1bc51fdcb3bae580b</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos defeat Crows by 40 points to move closer to winning record as Saints, Dockers and Demons notch victories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/aflw-demons-swans-kangaroos-crows-giants-dockers-blues-saints/105907762</link><description>North Melbourne moves one victory away from equalling the all-time VFL/AFL and AFLW winning record with a 40-point drubbing of Adelaide as St Kilda moves closer to a maiden finals appearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3036c640f5f12f4b89b3526d94476ea</guid></item><item><title>NT chief minister claims tough-on-crime approach has led to 'significant' crime drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/nt-chief-minister-claims-tough-on-crime-led-to-crime-drop/105906588</link><description>NT Chief Minister Lia Finocchiaro says the Country Liberal Party's tough-on-crime approach "is working". But after two teens broke into a play centre and left a trail of destruction, operator Steve Mason is not convinced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ceb1811e211ef03f608859e94141ede6</guid></item><item><title>Chinese Communist Party's Central Committee set for major shake-up at plenum meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/xi-inner-circle-major-shakeup-ccp-meeting-beijing/105885472</link><description>A key meeting of the Chinese Communist Party Central Committee is expected to include a major shake-up of President Xi Jinping's inner circle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41655c3a7bf399a2c8c3669a0f55d79b</guid></item><item><title>Collingwood cult hero Mason Cox not offered new contract for 2026 AFL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/mason-cox-leaves-collingwood-magpies/105907852</link><description>Mason Cox, the first American to become an AFL regular, confirms he will not be with the Magpies in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faaa19652e592fb7fd468bdd25c33d4d</guid></item><item><title>Nottingham Forest sack manager Ange Postecoglou immediately after loss to Chelsea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/ange-postecoglou-sacked-nottingham-forest/105908162</link><description>Nottingham Forest sacked the winless manager moments after their 3-0 defeat by Chelsea on Saturday local time, which left the club 17th in the standings and on the brink of slipping into the relegation zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57c551c6fd2ddff4af0d49de00cd0a77</guid></item><item><title>China's economic slowdown has become its diplomatic weapon in the Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/china-economy-pacific-australia-united-states/105884758</link><description>For Australia and the US, the Pacific is no longer a comfortable backyard — it's a battleground of credibility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2b0e48dd4fde1249a89b421640ef595</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew's decision to give up his titles may have been quietly orchestrated by members of his own family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/is-prince-andrews-decision-enough-to-stem-damage-to-monarchy/105907688</link><description>With the swirl of news around Prince Andrew this week, something had to be done; the question was whether he would do it himself or if his brother would be forced to show him the door.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b77456c907ef9b548850123a9b10fa3e</guid></item><item><title>Native mussel restoration project supported by Victor Harbor community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/mussel-bed-rebuilding-at-encounter-bay-after-algal-bloom/105887684</link><description>Victor Harbor was one of the first areas affected by SA's harmful algal bloom. Now its citizens are funding and supporting research into rebuilding native mussel populations as it looks to the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5482853b2341d466e8d2331ff929036a</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz Kids: Who says trivia is just for grown-ups? It's time to put your thinking cap on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/hard-quiz-kids-weekly-trivia-tom-gleeson/105894882</link><description>Hard Quiz Kids is here again, and we're gifting you a bunch of straightforward questions. Don't embarrass yourself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eae196e3bd245bc87722d2b719e6f741</guid></item><item><title>After Ukraine, Finland hopes it won't be Putin's next target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/inside-finlands-preparations-for-russian-invasion/105859992</link><description>Blasted into the bedrock, deep below the streets of Helsinki, these massive bunkers are currently used for recreation. Their primary function, however, is much more sinister: preparing for a Russian invasion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3896c79d12d96bc2c66108ed2320d926</guid></item><item><title>China's 'special forces'-style tourists packing big itineraries in small budgets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/china-hong-kong-special-forces-style-travel-sleep-mcdonalds/105902602</link><description>Young Chinese tourists with limited time and money are travelling 'special forces'-style — inspired by the efficiency, endurance, and intensity of military units.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecc8983a388385cd9855eaf49fa6fe2b</guid></item><item><title>How Mother Teresa helped Steve Waugh channel his 'power' for children in need</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/steve-waugh-on-meeting-mother-teresa/105671818</link><description>When Steve Waugh retired from cricket, he knew he wanted to use his influence to make a difference. It was meeting Mother Teresa that made him realise his new path.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f532c8e947e73fb6c25eb280850294d</guid></item><item><title>Cheap energy driven by rooftop solar means larger solar farms could be unviable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/cheap-solar-household-energy-pushing-solar-farms-out-of-market/105898336</link><description>Australia's renewable energy push has resulted in a surge in household solar power. But what does that mean for private solar farms?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36014b920dd1bc4459bb64a96d7ea4d1</guid></item><item><title>Iconic house for sale for only second time in 193-year history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/iconic-house-for-sale-for-only-second-time-in-193-year-history/105838914</link><description>Classical musicians Richard and Suzy Miller count their circa-1832 home as one of their greatest creative achievements as they prepare to leave it for someone else to love.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0cb817277090afe4c3ee03c0a1fb2c2</guid></item><item><title>James Duckworth falls at Almaty Open semi-final stage against Daniil Medvedev</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/james-duckworth-falls-almati-open-semi-final-daniil-medvedev/105908658</link><description>Australian seed-slayer James Duckworth has finally met his match in Almaty, where Daniil Medvedev dug deep to beat him in three sets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0d127a1f537ae19f3d552f01bce600f</guid></item><item><title>It's been called Canberra's 'forever government' — but ACT Labor's brand is growing tired</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/act-canberra-forever-government-but-labor-brand-growing-tired/105904332</link><description>It's been a year since Canberrans re-elected an ACT Labor government for a seventh consecutive term — but as budget pressures bite, analysts say Labor's stocks are suffering from brand fatigue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ee3cbb31b12feb0dbf9a314f57eeb6d</guid></item><item><title>Social media promotion of raw milk 'misleading and dangerous'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/raw-milk-trend-worries-experts/105636166</link><description>A public health expert says social media content creators are undermining years of scientific research by promoting raw milk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be479a18a9b8b5bd2c9c5515b5b11008</guid></item><item><title>Dodo and iPrimus hack impacts more than 1,600 home internet, email and mobile customers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/dodo-hack-impacts-internet-email-and-mobile-customers/105908674</link><description>More than 1,600 Dodo and iPrimus home internet and mobile customers were impacted by a hack of the telco's email and mobile services, the company confirms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2023f6e78d453f5b1767f6b78873787c</guid></item><item><title>GPs with extra skills who want to work in Tasmania say there are no suitable jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/rural-generalists-tasmanian-health-service-say-no-suitable-jobs/105907346</link><description>Rural generalists are GPs with training in emergency care and one other advanced skill area. While Tasmania has a training program for rural generalists, doctors say their skills are not properly recognised by the Tasmanian Health Service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa38354b32d3f313d4fb620c7e2db87f</guid></item><item><title>Nationals leader wants Barnaby Joyce to 'stay', amid rumour of One Nation defection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/nationals-littleproud-barnaby-joyce-stay-party-one-nation/105908722</link><description>Announcing he would not re-contest his seat of New England for the Nationals, Barnaby Joyce cited an irreparable breakdown with his party leader David Littleproud. Mr Littleproud says he still wants Mr Joyce to stay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9848481613384650c56cadeda692b7be</guid></item><item><title>National Disruption Group to be established to crush tobacco black market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/national-distruption-group-tobacco-black-market/105908764</link><description>A new "National Disruption Group" will be convened to stamp out the exploding illicit tobacco market and other "converging" threats, the home affairs minister has announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cc3bdda511d1e9aa7bb583dee35ef1e</guid></item><item><title>Five suspected rat poison cases detected in south-east Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/qld-rat-poisoning-symptoms-reported-to-hospitals/105908798</link><description>Queensland Health is investigating after five people were hospitalised with symptoms of ingesting rat poison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17e5b91d5e833fa2e54a07c383a89f60</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou's Nottingham Forest stint a classic case of wrong place, wrong time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/ange-postecoglou-nottingham-forest-wrong-team-brian-clough/105908712</link><description>Ange Postecoglou was on a hiding to nothing at Nottingham Forest, his sacking the result of terrible recruitment and a knee-jerk appointment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0adc426b55b3caeb01dc1561cdfadbc</guid></item><item><title>'Green bans' saved Sydney's historic buildings and taught economists a lesson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/green-bans-sydney-1970s-unions-nimby-yimby-milton-friedman/105903850</link><description>The "green bans" in the 1970s saved many of Australia's historic buildings and our cities are richer for them. But a famous economist didn't like them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abdb337970b734f91db4e99387b96c1a</guid></item><item><title>Trent Dalton's Boy Swallows Universe wins the Top 100 Books countdown — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/top-100-books-of-the-21st-century-radio-national-live-updates/105900036</link><description>Trent Dalton's debut novel Boy Swallows Universe has won Radio National's Top 100 Books of the 21st Century countdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a93d820be1134030d36a0450e5827bd4</guid></item><item><title>How Claire's decision to be 'one and done' was rocked by divorce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/how-claire-feels-about-being-one-and-done-after-divorce/105870074</link><description>After a traumatic birth, followed by mental and physical health challenges, Claire was "one and done". But divorce made her think twice about her decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c4071ab0f2b41bc5ba8af85bdc44b4</guid></item><item><title>The story of the 1970 West Gate Bridge disaster features in Melbourne Theatre Company's 2026 season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/melbourne-theatre-company-mtc-2026-season-anne-louise-sarks/105896178</link><description>The people impacted by Australia's worst industrial disaster are at the centre of West Gate by Dennis McIntosh, one of seven new Australian plays coming to Melbourne Theatre Company in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de0ad7e53c23dbee737f8a5d0098d29e</guid></item><item><title>Bulldogs keep finals hopes alive with 66-point Suns trouncing, Lions and Tigers pick up wins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/aflw-bombers-lions-magpies-tigers-suns-bulldogs/105909452</link><description>The Western Bulldogs hammer Gold Coast by 66 points to keep their finals flame flickering, while Brisbane returns to the top four with victory over Essendon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">220f543ca713782ae1e2a21e7e2fa7c0</guid></item><item><title>Possible space junk found near Western Australian mine site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/wa-space-debris-reentry-investigation/105909612</link><description>Suspected space debris is believed to have crashed near a WA mine site, with the Australian Transport Safety Bureau confirming the object was not from a commercial aircraft.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07160fd72846f9d8cf600d6423dfba11</guid></item><item><title>Australia cruises to seven-wicket victory over India in rain-shortened ODI</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/odi-australia-defeats-india-by-seven-wickets-perth/105909904</link><description>Surviving a series of rain delays in Perth, Australia records a seven-wicket win over India in the first of three men's ODI matches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bfda650a8c1f1f7cac905e46ef4fbd7</guid></item><item><title>F1 United States Grand Prix: Oscar Piastri's championship lead trimmed, Max Verstappen beats Lando Norris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/f1-live-united-states-grand-prix-oscar-piastri-lando-norris/105894158</link><description>Max Verstappen has dominated from pole position to claim his fifth grand prix win of the season, as Oscar Piastri's lead of the Formula 1 drivers' championship was trimmed for the fourth consecutive weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bcdd6bd358bd86dd0f6bfeea97ab54e</guid></item><item><title>If AI and crypto aren't bubbles, we could be in big trouble</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/ai-crypto-bubbles-speculative-mania/105884508</link><description>Speculative manias where the first investors win because there isn't a bust are rare occurrences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">283c30df2984a269ddf09fef3456e7d6</guid></item><item><title>Reused signature among string of issues as home owner left with unfinished build</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/reused-signature-among-string-of-failures-on-home-build/105792444</link><description>When Matthew Mapley questioned why the bank had paid his builder for unfinished works, it said it had his written authority — except he hadn't signed it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">145bbaf8d8739f0ee1789f78d179e3e6</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce says One Nation 'not barking mad' on net zero, but will not reveal if he will defect</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/nationals-no-mass-defection-barnaby-joyce-one-nation/105909238</link><description>Barnaby Joyce says that, "unlike others", One Nation's approach to climate change is not "barking mad". But the Nationals MP says he remains with his party — for now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba1192292768a0257d6e65e047ca10d2</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese's meeting with Donald Trump could hardly be timed better</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/albanese-trump-meeting-timing-critical-minerals/105909072</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is about to set foot inside the gilded cage of the Oval Office — and the timing could hardly be better.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d20e6cfd5af8252e5277f8c4a4af005</guid></item><item><title>Over a dozen unis are using AI to catch AI — and getting it wrong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/universities-using-ai-to-detect-students-cheating/105905804</link><description>At least a dozen Australian universities are using AI to detect AI. But they're not always catching cheats. Instead, they're wrongly accusing students of academic misconduct.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5ac54c938944764d045af8b0b3883b9</guid></item><item><title>20 per cent HECS cut does not address 'underlying problems', uni students and graduates say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/20-per-cent-off-australian-hecs-debt-but-underlying-problems/105888952</link><description>A 20 per cent reduction on HECS debt is a welcomed relief for some 3 million Australians with a student loan. But those who paid their HECS early or are yet to rack up a debt will miss out on the support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b09ab14b2ad609ce96fc07e9706db7c3</guid></item><item><title>Teenager who died by suicide sent final message to Gold Coast health service, but it went unanswered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/neve-wright-gold-coast-health-service-death-calls-investigation/105902752</link><description>The ABC has uncovered the case as part of an examination of Gold Coast Hospital and Health Service's treatment of mental health patients and their suicides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80b94bbccc9715cedfe4fc21a97e430c</guid></item><item><title>Rabbit populations boom in parts of Australia as ideal conditions see pests return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/rabbit-populations-on-rise-in-southern-australia-after-rain/105903702</link><description>A resurgence of rabbit populations following recent rainfall is driving experts to urge for increased control measures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f0b63e3021992436e68289f3f87b2a2</guid></item><item><title>Daniil Medvedev wins Almaty Open, Elena Rybakina closes in on WTA Finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/atp-wta-tours-daniil-medvedev-elena-rybakina-win/105910582</link><description>Daniil Medvedev claims his first ATP Tour tournament win since 2023, while Elena Rybakina's push to reach the WTA Finals gathers momentum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d27928b89915e24efb9812cfeeed4e7</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Chinese aircraft releases flares near Australian military plane — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/federal-politics-live-blog-october-20/105910558</link><description>Defence Minister Richard Marles says a Chinese military jet has released flares "very close" to an RAAF plane surveilling the South China Sea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72bc8103d4f91ae0296dacb6042cd595</guid></item><item><title>ASX closes higher supported by banks while gold stocks sold off, China's economy continues to slow — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-october-20/105909396</link><description>The ASX gained 0.4 per cent as investors rotated out of miners and gold and into banks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5928ef0e0c4f7a369dea8bcc22702546</guid></item><item><title>All the numbers behind Radio National's Top 100 Books of the 21st century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/top-100-books-radio-national-trent-dalton-numbers/105876550</link><description>The winner for the Top 100 Books has been announced. What do the votes behind it say about us?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eceddbdf78c0567b7386f67a77686872</guid></item><item><title>Healthscope under fire over proposal to farm millions in employees' tax benefits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/healthscope-proposal-for-workers-tax-benefits-under-fire/105894910</link><description>In-receivership hospital group Healthscope is taking radical steps to stay alive, converting to a charity and proposing to take up to 90 per cent of a benefit intended to reduce workers' taxable income.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54fe6626e9683e97ff7c755dc0f3b158</guid></item><item><title>Israel says ceasefire and aid to resume after airstrikes kill 26 in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/israel-says-gaza-ceasefire-and-aid-to-resume/105910598</link><description>Israel says it has resumed enforcement of the Gaza ceasefire plan after it was "violated" by Hamas following a wave of Israeli strikes that killed 26 people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b15241284c0d7f497581843777ebda8</guid></item><item><title>Multiple sclerosis support group tries to fill gaps as Northern Territory services dwindle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/multiple-sclerosis-support-group-tries-fill-nt-service-gaps/105839144</link><description>Being diagnosed with multiple sclerosis can often be an isolating experience, and even more so for those in Darwin who lack access to on-the-ground supports. Despite these barriers, a group of local women have created a support group to help fill the service gap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14749aee6ee20b3feba95efcd80cf469</guid></item><item><title>Drone footage reveals Gaza City's destruction as people return home during ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/drone-footage-reveals-gaza-city-destruction/105906708</link><description>One week into the ceasefire in Gaza, Palestinians are returning to destroyed homes and trying to find shelter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3949b76fa29fedb2ce2ac2c7ac488821</guid></item><item><title>England records four-run Women's World Cup win over India to join Australia in semifinals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/cricket-world-cup-england-defeats-india-to-reach-semifinals/105910632</link><description>England secures its Women's World Cup semifinal spot with a tense four-run win over tournament co-host India at Indor's Holkar Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca127f26cc1b519429233a14a7576b44</guid></item><item><title>India backs Virat Kohli to rebound after ODI duck against Australia in Perth series opener</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/cricket-odi-india-australia-virat-kohli-duck/105910756</link><description>Virat Kohli failed to score in the opening men's ODI in Perth. However, his India teammates expect their ex-skipper to quickly recapture his best form.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bc80acf1d0f546076475e758c726a92</guid></item><item><title>Holiday from Hospital virtual reality to transport patients to Australia's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/holiday-from-hospital-virtual-reality-program/105904452</link><description>A leukaemia survivor designs a VR program that will help patients travel to some of Australia's iconic locations from their hospital beds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86e927a78d6931f5a5bc765a1bd0349f</guid></item><item><title>Richmond is starting to play good footy. But in AFLW's short season there's no time left to build momentum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/richmond-aflw-short-season-limits-chance-to-build-momentum/105910676</link><description>After a 0-7 start to the season, Richmond are starting to notch wins on the board. But it's too late for much momentum to build in the short women's season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">069e771beb7b5a18b4ca2823e445cde9</guid></item><item><title>F1 standings: Oscar Piastri says too early for McLaren to prioritise drivers as Max Verstappen continues charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/f1-championship-standings-2025-piastri-verstappen-norris/105910856</link><description>Formula 1 championship leader Oscar Piastri says McLaren does not need to prioritise one driver over the other, as four-time world champion Max Verstappen continues to narrow the deficit to both.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6b6dbcdc3ff000bf792dec04e4a387f</guid></item><item><title>Warning over rare but deadly virus after bat bites Pilbara woman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/pilbara-bat-bite-lyssavirus-treatment/105903464</link><description>A Pilbara resident says an attempt to save a small bat stuck in her house has resulted in painful treatment for a deadly virus that can be passed onto humans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7649b3e7c5d127072e9734a5e6389db2</guid></item><item><title>Melt Festival is giving queer artists a space to be themselves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/melt-at-pip-queer-arts-festival-stand-up-comedy/105876434</link><description>Brisbane's Melt Festival has rapidly expanded in the past decade, inviting numerous venues into the celebration of queer artistry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82f95541593c2dd6615f166a0fa29834</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr backed by Matildas coach Joe Montemurro to make impact in friendlies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/matildas-sam-kerr-joe-montemurro-wales-england-friendlies/105911490</link><description>Sam Kerr will return to the Matildas fold off the back of limited minutes at Chelsea, but coach Joe Montemurro is confident she will shine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55b775730bad08a65eaa25450f51842f</guid></item><item><title>Limp Bizkit bandmates pay tribute to bassist Sam Rivers after death at 48</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/limp-bizkit-bandmates-pay-tribute-to-bassist-sam-rivers/105911436</link><description>Fred Durst takes to social media to say he has shed "gallons of tears" since finding out about the death of his "truly wonderful" bandmate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1d63bc89303f861e3b31723c1277a98</guid></item><item><title>Australian Olympic champion Kaylee McKeown breaks world short course record</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/swimming-kaylee-mckeown-breaks-world-short-course-record/105912014</link><description>Australia's five-time Olympic gold medallist Kaylee McKeown sets a world short course record in the women's 200 metres backstroke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">402b6aa0b6c8c60ddfcda2c6439f5872</guid></item><item><title>Black Swans rowing crew from WA records win at Head of the Charles Regatta in Boston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/black-swans-rowing-crew-posts-win-at-head-of-the-charles-regatta/105912280</link><description>A group of West Australian former high-level rowers are still in shock after claiming a win at the world's biggest and most famous rowing event — The Head of the Charles Regatta in Boston.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c9029515cc34eb9eab3a0a5e60e4e01</guid></item><item><title>Samoa down to 17 fit players after Pacific Championships loss to New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/samoa-to-call-in-replacements-after-brutal-kiwi-defeat/105912418</link><description>Samoa's brutal loss to New Zealand leaves them needing to call fresh troops into their squad, with the Pacific powerhouse down to just 17 fit players.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b4e1cb8410d3d6e41561f33c4befb1e</guid></item><item><title>Central Land Council CEO Lesley Turner sues senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price over defamation claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/nt-clc-lesley-turner-sues-senator-jacinta-nampijinpa-price-court/105911056</link><description>A seven-day Federal Court defamation case, alleging senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price "trampled" the reputation of an NT land council leader, has begun in Darwin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8420ac7f16d0a99cba30c47990ca4485</guid></item><item><title>Has Australia just killed its cultural cringe?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/books-100-cultural-cringe-australian-literature/105911414</link><description>How wonderful for Australian writers to receive this recognition from the very people who consume their work, as part of ABC Radio National's Top 100 Books countdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6955af048b4c6e6460e149afd7da2d97</guid></item><item><title>Election campaign donation laws would have blocked $8m in Climate 200 funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/climate-200-donations-millions-blocked-election-reforms/105910960</link><description>Climate 200 would have been blocked from making $8.34 million in donations to independent candidates if new election donation laws were in place at the 2025 poll.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a105858ce5aba7b87125fcecf773b3e4</guid></item><item><title>New England voters divided by Barnaby Joyce's flirtation with One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/barnaby-joyce-future-uncertain-as-new-england-voters-react/105910950</link><description>Support for the politician remains strong in his electorate despite his apparent flirtation with One Nation, a party enjoying a surge in popularity in the seat of New England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5fd341f9bae412bf8bef068aa17b4f9</guid></item><item><title>Bonza's financial backer 777 Partners co-founder charged with fraud</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/bonza-us-financier-charged-500-million-alleged-fraud/105910734</link><description>The FBI investigation resulted in 777 Partners co-founder Joshua Wander being charged with stealing US$500 million from lenders and investors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e392cffcb519df7c5888daa3070bb23a</guid></item><item><title>Patients at centre of suspected rat poisoning cluster in south-east Queensland are all from Logan. This is what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/south-east-qld-rat-poison-cluster-from-same-city-logan/105912822</link><description>South-east Queensland authorities are continuing to investigate the source of the cluster, with contact tracing underway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70d8c5b4606af35b4f66793f5f9df39a</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew is no longer the Duke of York but will likely remain a prince. Here's why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/how-does-being-stripped-of-a-royal-title-work/105911378</link><description>The second son of the late Queen Elizabeth II will no longer be called the Duke of York, but he still remains a prince and in the line of succession, despite calls for his remaining title to be stripped. Here's why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcc480b17f85a98ca2b072bb33bf703f</guid></item><item><title>Temporary bans on fishing popular species floated to address dwindling populations off WA coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/wa-fishing-bans-floated-address-species-shortages/105913198</link><description>A temporary ban on fishing iconic species, including WA dhufish and pink snapper, could be on the table as the state government scrambles for solutions to WA's at-risk fish populations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57ce6ad300f7bec9a9eaa714428b06db</guid></item><item><title>Mitch Marsh dismisses suggestion he should open for Australia in the first Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/six-beers-deep-marsh-s-ashes-plan-is-not-about-opening/105912940</link><description>Michael Vaughan wants Mitch Marsh opening the batting for Australia in the Ashes but it would require a serious leap of faith from Test selectors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84ef3c8bde1f51f97c40040a93279935</guid></item><item><title>Fast and easy dinners for busy weeknights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/fast-easy-low-effort-dinners-busy-weeknights/105731730</link><description>Make life easier with some of our simplest dinner recipes, including a 15-minute creamy pasta and air-fryer salmon fillets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca82c101073b2325f491bf70e520a749</guid></item><item><title>Voter turnout dips again at 2025 WA Local Government elections amid calls for mandatory voting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/wa-council-elections-turnout-results/105911966</link><description>The number of West Australians who voted at the weekend's local government elections is slightly down on previous years, following calls for participation to become mandatory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">504f2098aa38fa7e3529412db62fa9b2</guid></item><item><title>Chinese fighter jet released flares 'very close' to Australian aircraft</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/chinese-fighter-jet-released-flares-close-to-australian-aircraft/105913308</link><description>Defence Minister Richard Marles says the incident was "unsafe and unprofessional" and the government has made representations to China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d5d4ce46fc1b59552abe10865158072</guid></item><item><title>Work begins on UNSW's billion-dollar Canberra campus in the 'education capital'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/work-begins-on-unsw-camberra-campus-expansion/105911670</link><description>Once complete, the new UNSW campus will be an education hub for thousands of students and staff, and is expected to provide a much-needed injection to the city's economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2bcb88310b1f23f8d036712ff2ef416</guid></item><item><title>ACT Chief Minister Andrew Barr says it has been a 'challenging first year' in minority government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/act-chief-minister-andrew-barr-one-year-in-minority-government/105912376</link><description>The ACT's chief minister brushes off criticism that his government is "tired", but acknowledges the 12 months since the election have been "difficult" for the territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc10b94fa7ea07f36073003ea1fef5b2</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanians buffeted by spring winds, but conditions not unusual, BOM says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/tasmanians-buffeted-by-spring-winds-conditions-not-unusual/105912682</link><description>Springtime typically means gardens come to life and the winter chill eases — for Tasmanians, it also means whatever isn't nailed down might get blown away.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6eaa5247e8e932d2697776dbceea8aa</guid></item><item><title>John Simmons was convicted of fraud but no one stopped him being a military advocate who ripped off vulnerable veterans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/military-advocates-scamming-vulnerable-veterans/105895360</link><description>A convicted "fraudster" has been able to represent vulnerable veterans, scamming them in the process.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70c17c42fa3605238095524dfa9bb2f4</guid></item><item><title>The moment authorities move a piece of space junk that crashed in Western Australia.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/space-junk-removal/105913574</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72a4417dd8cbbba89ec350034e6936d5</guid></item><item><title>Scott Pendlebury launches legal action against former financial adviser over alleged secret withdrawals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/afl-collingwood-scott-pendlebury-sues-financial-adviser/105913420</link><description>The Collingwood player alleges Jason Sourasis, who helmed A-League club Western United before its collapse, misappropriated more than $2 million over a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6ecd6960b929b61007c9f264fb6ae95</guid></item><item><title>Inquest finds death of Mount Barker man waiting for ambulance 'potentially' preventable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/coroner-finds-death-of-john-kennedy-potentially-preventable/105910896</link><description>The cardiac arrest death of a man who waited more than 20 minutes for an ambulance could have been "potentially" prevented if a paramedic had not interfered with the dispatch process and had help arrived sooner, a South Australian coroner has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee1d0e0a27105e5d015c0ea287fb1521</guid></item><item><title>Amazon cloud unit AWS experiences major global outage disrupting hundreds of platforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/amazon-aws-experiencing-online-outage/105913856</link><description>Amazon's cloud unit AWS has experienced a major global services outage that also disrupted hundreds of other platforms, including Robinhood, Snapchat, Roblox and Perplexity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f69822d7088a0b7e47296f3179cb8d7f</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine accuses Russia of detaining scientist ahead of Antarctic conference in Hobart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/ukraine-accuses-russia-of-detaining-scientist-antarctic-hobart/105912586</link><description>A diplomatic row has broken out at an international conservation conference in Hobart after Ukraine accused Russia of detaining one of its scientists for alleged security threats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d362443d4d5959aa919960ff002394b</guid></item><item><title>Amazon says outage issue is 'fully mitigated' as sites return to normal— as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/amazon-cloud-systems-outage-as-it-happened/105913922</link><description>Amazon's cloud unit AWS experienced an outage that also disrupted several other global platforms, affecting customers worldwide — as it happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ea7be8e00d10a46b4cd78fbd190c92</guid></item><item><title>Coroner probes death of Alice Springs psychiatric patient who was repeatedly sedated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/nt-kumanjayi-brogus-inquest-psychiatric-patient-sedation/105912198</link><description>NT Coroner Elisabeth Armitage is investigating the death of a 33-year-old Alice Springs mother of three who was unable to be revived after repeated medical sedations in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f45eb3e7586382d4b06686c776d0362c</guid></item><item><title>Colombia recalls ambassador to the US after Trump announces tariffs increase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/colombia-recalls-us-ambassador-after-trump-tariff-increase/105914158</link><description>The Colombian foreign ministry said Daniel García-Peña had returned to Bogotá from Washington DC after Donald Trump also announced the US would slash financial assistance to the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c468d4e382a5141ea746dd893c70464</guid></item><item><title>Trump, Albanese sign minerals deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/trump-albanese-sign-minerals-deal/105914572</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1160bf31f63b0ed3608b24ab33bf5533</guid></item><item><title>Trump affirms support for AUKUS deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/trump-affirms-support-for-aukus-deal-/105914592</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">538107ab9d730342bb5fa7e9f2da5c97</guid></item><item><title>Australians turning to ChatGPT and other AI for financial advice warned to tread with caution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/using-ai-chatgpt-for-financial-advice/105882042</link><description>When Georgina Doll was looking to buy a home, generative artificial intelligence was one of the sources she turned to for advice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31dfe56a757dbf400518a430139816b9</guid></item><item><title>How bankers have learned to operate outside the rules in the murky world of private credit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/could-private-credit-spark-the-next-financial-market-meltdown/105912494</link><description>In recent months, there's been a growing focus on private credit, the alter ego of private equity, and the potential it may have to destabilise the system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b5102a83b080e9d88cf1e8ee42917d5</guid></item><item><title>Trump praises Australia and takes swipe at Rudd during White House meeting with Albanese</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/donald-trump-and-anthony-albanese-meet-in-washington/105914030</link><description>Donald Trump lavishes praise on Australia and Anthony Albanese during the pair's landmark meeting in Washington, but takes a swipe at a former prime minister in the room.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7300b47ce981f4e235c6ae1fd3ef2a90</guid></item><item><title>'Accidental' homeschooling on the rise, as families say schools are not coping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/accidental-homeschooling-on-the-rise/105912808</link><description>Homeschooling rates are rising rapidly, with families claiming schools aren't coping with bullying or neurodiversity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">398a4a3c482508648c94ad55376d70d4</guid></item><item><title>Weapons maker Saab 'directly linked' to human rights harm over missile at Lake Hart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/saab-linked-to-human-rights-harm-over-woomera-missile/105911274</link><description>Traditional owners win a decision against a multinational weapons manufacturer after finding one of the company's missiles at a heritage site in the remote South Australian outback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">944f17d9574ffd98ced64a4f0b26e76f</guid></item><item><title>New analysis of building activity data shows house construction has sped up for first time since pandemic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-21/construction-data-shows-quicker-timeframes-since-pandemic/105913360</link><description>Analysis of the latest Australian Bureau of Statistics data on building activity shows good signs for the first time since the pandemic. But, experts warn there is more to be done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bf9b9c18d22cdbf5ea03b6e7f3ce1f3</guid></item></channel></rss>