<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 06:59:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Labor is celebrating a successful year but tough budget choices lie ahead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/albanese-government-budget-repair-tax-reform-inflation-figures/106045644</link><description>The level of the prime minister's reform appetite has been discussed and debated since roughly 9pm on election night in May, when Labor's massive win became clear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc7d249f5a1fc31d045262e25487f88b</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos player Ash Riddell has entire school behind her ahead of Saturday's AFLW grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/aflw-grand-final-roos-brisbane-lions-ash-riddell/106055592</link><description>Roos star — and grade 6 teacher — Ash Riddell has an entire school behind her ahead of this Saturday's AFLW grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa1af0827399d6e8529afc6864dad710</guid></item><item><title>Australian music quiz: Test your knowledge of iconic Aussie acts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/australian-music-quiz-ausmusic-t-shirt-day/106024778</link><description>Celebrate Ausmusic T-Shirt Day with our Australian music trivia quiz. How well do you know your local legends?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04461578279a0e63af53eaac4a8c26ea</guid></item><item><title>Fire engulfs high-rise apartment buildings in Hong Kong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/fire-engulfs-high-rise-apartment-buildings-in-hong-kong/106057854</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6975391cd2aeff64d658407b3d156cd9</guid></item><item><title>Black Friday puts 'social pressure' on shoppers as more Australians rack up credit card debt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/black-friday-sales-pressure-pushing-families-into-debt/106050862</link><description>With millions of Australians tipped to spend record amounts this Black Friday, the value of personal credit and charge-card balances accruing interest has hit its highest level since 2021.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed20bcd7ecc0d1ee384e872f40037a8d</guid></item><item><title>London Broncos rugby league hopes buoyed by Brisbane icon Darren Lockyer and players from PNG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/london-broncos-rugby-league-hopes-buoyed-by-brisbane-icon-darren/106054530</link><description>The London Broncos might be the only rugby league club in Britain to have experienced relegation before a season even began — and Darren Lockyer, through the help of PNG Players, is hoping to bring them back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adb18a1d230194d5cd653be6a57035e1</guid></item><item><title>Rockliff's premiership tied to proposed stadium, but his is not the first to push a contentious project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/hobart-stadium-contentious-projects-not-new-for-tasmania/106031950</link><description>With the vote to decide the fate of the Hobart stadium a week away, Premier Jeremy Rockliff's political legacy is in the balance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f16a9e5fe18b1bb157e39386de502c9</guid></item><item><title>NSW deputy coroner to decide if teen's death was caused by meat allergy from tick bites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/nsw-central-coast-mammalian-meat-allergy-ticks-inquest/106050534</link><description>Jeremy Webb died aged 16 after eating sausages while camping in the Central Coast. Growing up, he was bitten by ticks outdoors multiple times.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cb275094f2c8b4ced3fb753f939f33f</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Premier David Crisafulli faces a political test on his home turf in Hinchinbrook by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/crisafulli-kap-hitchinbrook-by-election-north-queensland/106054982</link><description>If the electorate were to vote strongly against the government, it would sting first-term leader David Crisafulli and be spun as a rejection of the LNP's agenda, writes Alex Brewster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f61dcf4492645631956393c9afaccc0</guid></item><item><title>Here is what we know about Hong Kong's Tai Po fire and the role of bamboo scaffolding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/what-we-know-about-hong-kong-tai-po-fire-bamboo-scaffolding/106057774</link><description>The blaze in Tai Po that engulfed multiple high-rise apartment blocks is still burning, and authorities say it likely began in bamboo scaffolding that encased the buildings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3c70703dd65c0158e4a972c10588d22</guid></item><item><title>Death toll rises to 55 as Hong Kong blaze continues to burn, three arrested</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/hong-kong-apartments-kills-dozens-hundreds-missing/106057928</link><description>A massive high-rise apartment fire in Hong Kong's Tai Po district has killed at least 55 people and left hundreds more missing, with firefighters continuing to battle the blaze — as it happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4944c844f04d7dc04528ed1c46887f17</guid></item><item><title>Mother calls for new age limits after 8yo son killed in e-motorcycle crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/mother-calls-for-change-zeke-hondow-killed-emotorbike-crash/106038102</link><description>Kloe Weedon's son Zeke William Hondow, a schoolboy with a sharp wit and even sharper haircuts, was farewelled at a funeral last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">609e2e2d976d22162c79d00f932c38c8</guid></item><item><title>Two National Guard members shot near White House in Washington DC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/national-guard-members-shot-in-washington-dc/106057960</link><description>Authorities say the soldiers were ambushed by a lone gunman while on patrol in Washington, DC, as part of a Trump-ordered crime crackdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a60895cc50de27a7ee9cc8fb206623c5</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Barnaby Joyce quits the Nationals, Labor grilled on power prices in final Question Time of the year — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/federal-politics-live-november-27/106056740</link><description>Former deputy prime minister Barnaby Joyce quits the Nationals. Meanwhile, Labor is grilled on power prices in the final Question Time of 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">541194ba788a7849af6314ab76d415d3</guid></item><item><title>Kotoni Staggs will continue to represent Kangaroos if Kevin Walters remains coach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/rugby-league-kotoni-staggs-kangaroos-kevin-walters-coach/106057948</link><description>Kotoni Staggs must decide between representing Australia or Tonga at the international level, and says there is one key factor that will tip his decision either way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a3a520cd5ff15f4a4e022fd413d25b9</guid></item><item><title>TagEnergy Naracoorte big battery project raises concerns about take-up of agricultural land</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/tagenergy-naracoorte-big-battery-project-concerns-farm-land-sa/106053784</link><description>One of Australia's largest battery energy storage systems would be built on farmland in South Australia's south-east in a proposal that the developer says will lower electricity costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfc3956b34d7f4fc2985968c6a79a0c9</guid></item><item><title>Queensland potato farmers help fill supply gap as southern drought causes national shortage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/queensland-potatoes-in-high-demand-due-to-potato-shortage/106053778</link><description>Potato growers in Queensland's far north are suddenly in hot demand as drought-stricken paddocks in the country's south fail to deliver.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab54a48adc81583eac2c8289c34cc05a</guid></item><item><title>Department of Transport and Main Roads orders shutdown of North Ipswich Free Shop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/tmr-orders-shutdown-of-unauthorised-street-charity/106056444</link><description>Queensland's transport department has threatened to penalise residents who set up street-side charity cupboards without filling in the requisite paperwork.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5f68b265064320596ea9b346d00604d</guid></item><item><title>Labor strikes deal with Greens to end environmental reform stalemate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/labor-strikes-greens-deal-to-end-environmental-stalemate/106054928</link><description>The years-long stalemate over reforms to environmental laws is set to clear in the final week of the parliamentary year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">457287247a78f8861b98c2a2a62e1428</guid></item><item><title>Varroa mite detected in bee hives at Sellicks Hill and Taratap</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/varroa-mite-detected-at-sellicks-hill-and-taratap/106057922</link><description>Beekeepers are being urged to monitor their hives more frequently after further detections of the deadly bee parasite varroa mite in South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7eb6178921afeda19d18f99d63e45b70</guid></item><item><title>Man throwing item over fence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/man-throwing-item-over-fence/106055784</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afc43fd69b8878df07f8e99634932057</guid></item><item><title>Matt Renshaw calls under-fire Usman Khawaja one of Australia's best-ever cricketers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/cricket-matt-renshaw-backs-usman-khawaja-amid-test-battle/106058068</link><description>Matt Renshaw is gunning for a spot in Australia's Test side, but does not want it to come at the expense of Australia's veteran opener Usman Khawaja just yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21256bb8c842b636950f520ea8d75c36</guid></item><item><title>Industry's power woes continue in mining city of Kalgoorlie as peak demand looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/power-woes-for-kalgoorlie-on-edge-of-grid-rear-head-again/106051784</link><description>The WA government has taken the first steps towards fulfilling its election promise of a $150-million, 50-megawatt vanadium flow battery for Kalgoorlie-Boulder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdd6e0c0236d7df04a0de4741a90efe4</guid></item><item><title>National Guard troops being treated after they were shot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/eyewitness-show-national-guard-troops-being-treated/106058346</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e941ff58ba9ff9cf882779101579d5ce</guid></item><item><title>Ballarat Gold Mine operators charged over 2024 rockfall that killed miner Kurt Hourigan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/ballarat-gold-mine-collapse-charges/106031668</link><description>The operators of Ballarat Gold Mine have been charged over a rockfall that killed 37-year-old miner Kurt Hourigan and seriously injured a 21-year-old workmate in March 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">010111803eafbfddbe1540944f1ad016</guid></item><item><title>Floods leave at least 50 dead across Thailand, Indonesia and Malaysia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/floods-hit-south-east-asia-killing-at-least-50-people/106057902</link><description>The Thai city of Hat Yai received its heaviest rainfall in 300 years, while mudslides killed dozens on the Indonesian island of Sumatra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55ac0bd33d6d24697793ea836bc613fb</guid></item><item><title>Banking regulator APRA to impose home loan caps amid housing boom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/banking-regulator-apra-imposes-home-loan-caps/106058604</link><description>The banking regulator will impose restrictions on home loans from early next year to limit the number of "high-risk" large loans being issued to customers, which could have flow on effects in the housing market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e618ae3926dd5a073f3c4e646719968</guid></item><item><title>Isolation risks of Australia's social media ban for regional, rural and remote boarding school students</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/social-media-ban-regional-remote-students-boarding-school/106044168</link><description>Regional and remote students are being encouraged to learn old-school ways to stay in contact as social media bans for those under 16 come into effect over the summer holidays.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f44945bd63b42506de530681b3681dc9</guid></item><item><title>Eight-year-old boy injured in reported stabbing at Berwick school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/police-investigating-reported-school-stabbing-berwick-melbourne/106058974</link><description>An eight-year-old boy has been treated for non-life-threatening injuries after a reported stabbing at a school in Melbourne's south-east on Thursday morning, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">316e315328561c7f94077cdf6c9d7a6a</guid></item><item><title>Hotter than average summer forecast as fire authorities warn of 'highly flammable' conditions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/summer-bushfire-outlook-2025-afac-bom/106056420</link><description>An increased risk of bushfire is expected for parts of the country this summer, with most areas expecting hotter than normal temperatures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35de51530d6e65def2fe73a47d7fc215</guid></item><item><title>Labor and Greens agree on extra ABC funding for kids' programs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/labor-and-greens-agree-on-extra-abc-kids-funding/106058638</link><description>A deal between the federal government and the minor party will see an extra $50 million go to the public broadcaster to facilitate passage of a bill to impose local content requirements on streaming platforms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c824131213857592fc38200c1446b5d9</guid></item><item><title>White wine grape oversupply 'another kick in the guts' for growers already in crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/white-wine-oversupply-set-to-deepen-grower-crisis/106049916</link><description>The wine grape industry has written to the SA government pleading for help as it reaches breaking point after indicative pricing for the next vintage is released showing growers could face losses of up to $270 per tonne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">151dd7784ca8f537f4b48874b3828488</guid></item><item><title>Search for Samantha Murphy in state park could continue beyond Thursday as police seek 'closure'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/latest-samantha-murphy-search-in-state-park-near-ballarat/106058858</link><description>Police say a search of an area of state park near Ballarat for missing woman Samantha Murphy may continue beyond Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">315a1a2774100b342bbea412b52964dc</guid></item><item><title>Government projected to badly miss 2035 climate target, fall shy of 2030</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/climate-target-2035-badly-miss-projection/106059034</link><description>The Environment Department projects Australia is expected to fall well short of its commitment to cut emissions by 62 to 70 per cent by 2035 — though the minister notes that is before accounting for a number of recent commitments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2eebb6d19b55247b0bd317df371ca0e8</guid></item><item><title>ICC rates Perth pitch 'very good' despite two-day finish, putting spotlight on England's poor batting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/icc-rates-perth-stadium-cricket-pitch-very-good-two-day-finish/106071812</link><description>Suggestions the pitch at Perth Stadium was not up to scratch for the first Ashes Test have been well and truly put to bed as the ICC hands down its assessment of the playing surface.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34684565fdadc4fb9024644dcc6d6a51</guid></item><item><title>A new war looms one year on from the Israel-Lebanon ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/new-war-looms-israel-hezbollah-ceasefire/106054010</link><description>One year after Israel and Hezbollah agreed to a ceasefire, the IDF is bombing Beirut again. And Israel has promised its latest strike will not be the last unless Lebanon's government does more to disarm Hezbollah.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7f4b0f925d96470a8b995f7e62579af</guid></item><item><title>Coroner releases findings into murder of Lilie James at Sydney school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/nsw-lilie-james-murder-sydney-coronial-inquest-findings/106055226</link><description>A NSW coroner has urged young people to consider their use of location-sharing technology after the "senseless" murder of Lilie James at the hands of her ex-boyfriend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fce86aa8cf89453a7bb4d17ab58df194</guid></item><item><title>Motherly love produces sweet jujube crop for grower near regional Victorian city of Mildura</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/motherly-love-produces-sweet-jujube-crop-mildura/106033130</link><description>Jujubes are a relatively unknown fruit for most Australians, but the sweet fruit has strong domestic demand for those looking for a taste of home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">baaea74624af0abd3a70790f1c1a8bcb</guid></item><item><title>Why housing, renewables and mining projects may speed up under new environment laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/how-new-epbc-environment-laws-may-speed-up-housing-renewables/106051844</link><description>Major housing, renewables and mining projects often get bogged down for years by Australia's aging environment laws. Now a deal to rewrite them could change that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74282892f23e8416aff1ac1dfeb6e18e</guid></item><item><title>Future of Tasmania's foresty industry uncertain as Labor, Greens agree on environmental reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/native-logging-industry-reacts-labor-greens-environmental-reform/106058926</link><description>The government has struck a deal with the Greens to overhaul Australia environmental laws, sparking concerns for the future of Tasmania's native logging industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e8d9edbe73058dca32b4efe24c1ef73</guid></item><item><title>Bali governor demands demolition of glass lift at Kelingking Beach in Nusa Penida</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/bali-governor-demands-demolition-of-kelingking-beach-glass-lift/106071962</link><description>A controversial glass elevator at one of Bali's most picturesque beaches will have to be dismantled, with authorities citing planning violations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92b6991ba8d42977b7801376bf6c6188</guid></item><item><title>Roger Cook declares he has 'industrial FOMO' as Law Society slams powerful development laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/premier-roger-cook-says-he-has-industrial-fomo/106072428</link><description>Roger Cook declares he has "industrial FOMO" and wants to take every opportunity to bring big projects to the state, as WA's peak legal body slams proposed new laws aimed at fast-tracking development.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e88ef60ee797b1e699e35742c01b480</guid></item><item><title>WA Premier Roger Cook says he has "industrial fomo"</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/vertical-roger-cook-industrial-fomo/106072992</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3907684179431c31f35634c3a523922f</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Health imposes three month closures on illegal tobacco stores after statewide raids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/queensland-health-shuts-down-tobacco-stores-across-state/106054716</link><description>Dozens of stores across every corner of the state have been closed for three months as officers exercise new powers passed in Queensland's parliament last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4ef6a2c8e5e629d96de4e9b6dd2f3a4</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong inferno puts spotlight on risks of bamboo scaffolding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/hong-kong-inferno-puts-spotlight-on-risky-bamboo-scaffolding/106058820</link><description>Hong Kong's deadliest fire in three decades draws attention to its risky use of flammable bamboo scaffolding and mesh for building work, in a tradition dating back centuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47eb71c180cb2095a2970244e7a4e145</guid></item><item><title>Head of Queensland child safety inquiry flags subpoena as department accused of ignoring law</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/child-inquiry-legal-priorities-care-department-queensland/106071834</link><description>The head of Queensland's child safety inquiry says he "might need to subpoena" files from the department after hearing it was often "not" following its own legislation around preferred permanency options for children in care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1c3fe438c94c263bede033ddac7acef</guid></item><item><title>From harried mums to high-stakes magic here are November's best movies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/november-movie-wrap-what-to-watch/106044854</link><description>November saw the return of two beloved franchises; magic-filled Now You See Me and action classic Predator — but can either live up to their predecessors?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bb4ee3da5f8691e532198a7fd6f9ed4</guid></item><item><title>United States says it has stopped processing all immigration requests from Afghan nationals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/us-immigration-stops-afghanistan-applications/106073890</link><description>The decision comes hours after US President Donald Trump said he was confident the suspect behind the shooting of two National Guard soldiers in Washington was from Afghanistan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94f55ec54347170d813acc90c4beda9e</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce quits Nationals, will sit as independent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/barnaby-joyce-quits-nationals/106073080</link><description>The former leader and deputy prime minister has confirmed his long-awaited political move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad80d64fab33e97131a94af09ce91139</guid></item><item><title>Muhammad Abdur Rehman Mirza jailed over murder of Helen Marsuk after body found in a South Fremantle harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/muhammad-mirza-jailed-over-murder-of-helen-marsuk/106058954</link><description>A Perth man who stabbed a woman multiple times in a "ferocious attack" before her body was found in a South Fremantle harbour has been sentenced to 20 years in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0596f2dfa0728320bca460e47023e67</guid></item><item><title>Artificial reefs to be installed in Queensland's Great Sandy Marine Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/artificial-reefs-for-queenslands-great-sandy-marine-park/106072706</link><description>Claims new artificial reefs being installed in a protected marine park could damage a vulnerable natural coral reef are disputed by Queensland's environment minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adb041adf0a56dd405c9a5b94647401c</guid></item><item><title>Live grenade, firearms, sledgehammer seized by police after Sydney shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/live-grenade-sledgehammer-firearms-seized-police-sydney-shooting/106073960</link><description>The NSW Police bomb disposal unit and Australian Defence Force attended to safely remove the grenade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0165e566eed68cdcd24319a7e8ec447</guid></item><item><title>How families tracked victims and survivors in real time during Hong Kong's Tai Po tower fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/how-families-tracked-hong-kong-fatal-fire-in-real-time-online/106073204</link><description>When a fatal fire tore through seven high-rise towers in Hong Kong's Tai Po district, thousands of families were glued to a single webpage that offered updates far more quickly than official government briefings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e2290560386f7b6709730cbd29a277f</guid></item><item><title>Joyce exits, Turnbull returns as Ghosts of Christmas Past haunt parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/pauline-hanson-barnaby-joyce-malcolm-turnbull-environmental-deal/106045622</link><description>In the end, it turns out not even a Wagyu steak from Gina Rinehart's cattle company cooked on a sandwich press was enough to lock in Barnaby Joyce's defection to One Nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c5b7ab2901acdb567b6d8b309e7f264</guid></item><item><title>James Anderson expects England to pick same side for second Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/anderson-expects-england-to-pick-same-side-for-second-ashes-test/106074560</link><description>England are unlikely to tinker with their side for the second Ashes Test against Australia starting in Brisbane next week despite being thumped in the opening match, former fast bowler James Anderson has said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">630bd12ba3bd647c27bb2bd361ffa514</guid></item><item><title>Guide to listening: Christmas music highlights on ABC Classic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/guide-to-listening-2025-christmas-music-highlights-abc-classic/106056366</link><description>ABC Classic's Christmas music selection has everyone covered, whether you're a fan of choirs, orchestras, Christmas movies, operas, musicals or video games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a169c3871c0fb81038141d3622f746a</guid></item><item><title>Dead fish, foam seen on metro beaches despite overall low Karenia algal levels</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/foam-and-dead-fish-seen-on-adelaide-beaches/106058862</link><description>Authorities say metropolitan testing shows Karenia algal levels remain low compared with last month, despite thick foam and fish deaths seen on some beaches in recent days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5642130694d61a2e34e5915ea6b79ecf</guid></item><item><title>With a deal on Australia's environmental laws, Murray Watt has cemented his reputation as a 'fixer'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/environmental-laws-deal-watt-a-fixer-greens-negotiations/106073524</link><description>In his deal with the Greens, Environment Minister Murray Watt has just scraped off one of the biggest barnacles clinging to parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">804e194f7bdde600f65fda9cfda2ac70</guid></item><item><title>Woman sentenced over Willetton hit-and-run crash that injured schoolgirl Alexis Lloyd</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/perth-hit-and-run-driver-tahira-shaheen-sentenced/106074546</link><description>A 49-year-old L-plater who kept driving after hitting a 12-year-old as she walked to school in suburban Perth, causing serious injuries, is jailed for 16 months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ece4d8bc641987441319504bb45a62b</guid></item><item><title>Neuropsychologist in 'emphatic' disagreement over whether alleged murderer had substantial mental impairment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/brendan-kantilla-murder-trial-nt-supreme-court-neuropsychologist/106073702</link><description>A neuropsychologist tells the court an NT man accused of murdering an international student was not suffering from a substantial mental impairment at the time of the alleged crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bde41a5b3ead7c1c7c08d7599b187ea</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106075062</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b37aa8afb73f4cf1a95b7336a26a230c</guid></item><item><title>NT rams through changes to Banned Drinker Register amid parliamentary debate on scrutiny</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/nt-parliament-banned-drinking-order-changes-on-urgency-bdo-bdr/106056090</link><description>In the final hours of parliament for the year, the government has extended the time a person issued with a Banned Drinker Order is prevented from drinking alcohol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d9fdcacf79bdc27fe03cadca73109bc</guid></item><item><title>Iran condemns Australia's listing of IRGC as sponsor of terrorism as 'offensive and unjustified'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/iran-condemns-australia-listing-irgc-as-sponsor-of-terrorism/106075808</link><description>The Iranian Government has condemned Australia's formal listing of its Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) as a state sponsor of terrorism as "offensive and unjustified", accusing the Albanese government of doing Israel's bidding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a7648f1d89e94aa9069b6dd0a4f8d8c</guid></item><item><title>Troops critically injured in Washington shooting named as FBI launches terror probe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/national-guard-troops-critical-dc-shooting-lakanwal/106075898</link><description>Authorities identify the two National Guard members shot just blocks from the White House, as the FBI carries out searches of two properties on the US west coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3306015607d4d84545f785167cd7faea</guid></item><item><title>The ABC's explosive childcare investigations began with an email</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/four-corners-childcare-safety-investigation-profit-abuse/106054128</link><description>This story is about something deeper than policy or profit. It's about the trust parents place in childcare every morning when they hand over their children, believing they will be safe — only to find they're not.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">565a54873d41f4884181dcefb55e2629</guid></item><item><title>Student paramedic wins battle with Ambulance Victoria over beard policy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/ambulance-victoria-mask-beards-ppe/106072778</link><description>A student paramedic who accused Ambulance Victoria of discrimination on the grounds of race and religion is "ecstatic" to have won his battle to allow cultural beards on the job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8603b192af88be50f617e729e0a3400a</guid></item><item><title>Patrick Lee Brown sentenced to three years in prison over 'inexcusable' Tasmanian car chases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/patrick-lee-brown-sentenced-police-chases-launceston-hobart/106074964</link><description>During sentencing, a Supreme Court Justice told Patrick Lee Brown he "completely disregarded the safety of anyone else" during two different police pursuits, including one in a stolen rental truck with blown-out tyres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f2d03e954f98247d476033a91f412b9</guid></item><item><title>Macquarie Point stadium planning panel tells parliament of ongoing concerns a week from crucial vote</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/stadium-expert-planning-panel-presents-tasmania-upper-house/106074672</link><description>An expert planning panel has defended their scathing assessment of Hobart's proposed Macquarie Point stadium while speaking to the politicians who will ultimately decide the project's fate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54d1b89e512468f2010ccb2e2c36f11d</guid></item><item><title>Frozen rewrote the Disney princess narrative — and 12 years later, it's still relevant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/frozen-movie-elsa-anna-disney-princess-narrative/106028062</link><description>It wasn't just a box office success — Frozen introduced a new type of Disney princess: one who was strong, flawed and uninterested in romance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a85819a41d9e434e1858a6a2f98a85c8</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong residents devastated by mega blaze engulfing blocks of flats in Tai Po district</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/hong-kong-fire-tai-po-district-devastates-local-residents/106058690</link><description>Locals are in shock after fire destroyed apartment blocks home to thousands of people, as questions remain about the suitability of building materials and a lack of fire alarms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e120ab685c2b233ab8699cf50790bf4</guid></item><item><title>Social media ban implementation will 'vary' across platforms, eSafety commissioner warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/social-media-ban-implementation-to-vary-across-platforms/106075376</link><description>Not all Australians aged under 16 will "magically disappear overnight" from social media, the nation's online safety regulator says, amid a legal challenge to pause the start of the federal government's ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4031126c5650441d0b4cced144d50d67</guid></item><item><title>Maduro sings Lennon's 'Imagine' during a rally with supporters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/maduro-sings-lennon-s-imagine-during-a-rally-with-supporters/106056320</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87d3d2420b03ff23df27551a932ea6b8</guid></item><item><title>Calls for states to change alcohol laws ahead of women’s ministers meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/alcohol-delivery-violence-against-women-children-ministers/106075170</link><description>A major review into preventing violence against women and children called for changes to immediate alcohol home delivery</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75de4bdd1d698ed274797ef8f19599cc</guid></item><item><title>How to spot a scam during Black Friday and Cyber Monday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/how-to-stay-vigilant-for-black-friday-cyber-monday-scams/106020794</link><description>As scammers look to exploit sales during Black Friday and Cyber Monday, we explain what you need to know to avoid being duped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">603e861eec95b5b55d7aa539d56feb59</guid></item><item><title>Second storm of the year pushes tiny town of Nevertire to its limit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/storm-damage-onslaught-batters-rural-town-nevertire/106072008</link><description>A storm that hit a tiny rural NSW town, damaging one in 10 homes, is psychologically draining for residents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ee59ac88a5c7a76bc45eea502bcb1eb</guid></item><item><title>Perth Scorchers defeat Melbourne Renegades by four wickets in WBBL clash at Junction Oval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/perth-scorchers-defeat-melbourne-renegades-four-wickets-wbbl/106076168</link><description>Perth have survived a dramatic collapse to beat the Melbourne Renegades by four wickets, denying the Renegades a share of top spot on the WBBL ladder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">806f5cf45451ad7a88e7ea9dbbb0fec6</guid></item><item><title>Greens out-step flat-footed Liberals on crucial environmental deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/labor-greens-deal-murray-watt-liberals-bowen-chalmers/106045646</link><description>The environmental deal is a major win for a government whose critics on the left are calling for it to be more reformist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbd419f5416a826abe1d7016a6c2b855</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri dismisses helping McLaren teammate Lando Norris win F1 drivers' championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/oscar-piastri-will-not-help-lando-norris-win-f1-title-in-qatar/106076210</link><description>Oscar Piastri says McLaren raised the prospect of the Australian helping his teammate Lando Norris win the Formula 1 world championship, but it was rejected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3ec980521382ffb12e9d33768384b86</guid></item><item><title>Infrastructure installed to probe Coorong storm surges and groundwater impacts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/coorong-murray-research-for-future-erosion-rising-sea-levels-sa/106013728</link><description>Infrastructure to monitor the impact of rising sea levels and storm surges on the Coorong in South Australia has been installed along the thin strip of coastline between Goolwa Beach and the lagoons of the Ramsar-listed wetland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d8134b101b12c53dff3475c445f3957</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne protesters throw fruit, rocks, glass at police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/melbourne-protesters-throw-fruit-rock-glass-at-police/106076318</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dc88592d63b4c5f785ce3bbc7c9fffd</guid></item><item><title>Cool weather sets cherry crops 'weeks' behind schedule in lead-up to Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/cold-weather-cherry-delay-crops-fruit-victoria/106059072</link><description>The latest casualty in a year of delayed crops is the cherry, with cold weather in some growing regions setting the festive favourite "weeks" behind schedule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3612aa2f5f80c3dc5098162be5c662b1</guid></item><item><title>US futures markets halted as CME data centre overheats — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-28-november/106074700</link><description>Derivates trading operator CME Group says trading in its markets has been halted due to a cooling issue at data centres. Global financial markets watch futures closely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ae0c62e2e60633eaddc29868f23f37f</guid></item><item><title>Indian cricket star Deepti Sharma fetches highest WPL price, Australia captain Alyssa Healy unsold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/wpl-cricket-record-auction-price-alyssa-healy-unsold/106076270</link><description>All-rounder Deepti Sharma fetched the highest price at the Women's Premier League (WPL) auction, while Australia captain Alyssa Healy, one of the marquee players up for grabs, went unsold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f71128bee52e51ebbd4cda7fbc61351</guid></item><item><title>How a breakdown in the search for a boat named Margaret led to adventure on the Birdsville Track</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/inland-barge-reconnects-outback/106045962</link><description>The ABC's Landline crew discovers extreme kindness with a can-do attitude after a mechanical breakdown in South Australia's outback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3900ff291da27d0cba5eb67d9f84795e</guid></item><item><title>Trump says US must re-examine Biden era immigrants from Afghan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/trump-says-us-must-re-examine-biden-era-immigrants-from-afghan/106076436</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81ab4e8ec577f66aa2f9170b3d83b067</guid></item><item><title>United States to begin reviewing all asylum cases approved under Joe Biden's presidency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/us-to-review-all-asylum-cases-under-biden/106076322</link><description>US Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) says it has begun "a full-scale, rigorous re-examination of every Green Card for every alien from every country of concern".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d5b5129d35a1d8e0f8954109f0262ce</guid></item><item><title>Former WA police officer Kaine Burgess relives the night his patrol car was rammed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/retired-police-officer-shares-harrowing-story/106011590</link><description>More than two years on from a serious crash that saw him medically retired, a former police officer says he can still hear the screech of tyres before the deafening bang of a car slamming into his police wagon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ee39cf3b5fdb5213f314ddcdd462d23</guid></item><item><title>'Brumby Bill' protecting heritage value of wild horses to be scrapped in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/nsw-upper-house-vote-scrap-brumby-bill/105916360</link><description>A widely criticised bill recognising the heritage value of wild horses in Kosciuszko National Park will be scrapped in a move celebrated by the Invasive Species Council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">218f14fa35313423c0ae0caa3984a13b</guid></item><item><title>Estella brings strength and resilience to her family as she navigates life with disability in remote NT</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/estella-jones-tennant-creek-fighting-spirit-sam-cameron-idpwd/106024834</link><description>Nineteen-year-old Estella Jones lives with a disability in her hometown of Tennant Creek, where she loves baking brownies, singing karaoke and spending time with good friends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a69782b87662c716e55f95068ba1a663</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners in WA's north challenge state over fast-tracking mining exploration approvals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/wa-challenged-over-fast-tracking-mining-exploration-approvals/106055862</link><description>Traditional owners in WA's north launch legal action against the state government claiming it is fast-tracking mining and exploration projects using "expedited procedure" approvals at cultural expense.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1acd9b4007bcc42af41bfabb5e31199e</guid></item><item><title>Inquest concludes into death of SA boatie Tony Higgins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/inquest-into-death-of-anthony-higgins-ends/106074014</link><description>A coroner has found Anthony Higgins, who went missing in 2020 sparking the largest and most expensive marine search in South Australian waters, died two weeks later when he went missing again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61223a88fc3bf783740e8e43e1bf7a69</guid></item><item><title>Common antidepressant helps reduce some men's domestic violence, ReINVEST trial finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/reinvest-clinical-trial-anti-depressant-reduce-domestic-violence/105999382</link><description>The findings are significant not just because of how much the trial reduced domestic violence, but because only a few years ago it drew fierce criticism from women's advocates and politicians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5ae82aa88fb1df7aebdb637f7dac70e</guid></item><item><title>Benedict Bryant found guilty of dangerous driving causing the death of Jai Kalani Wright</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/nsw-benedict-bryant-verdict-jai-wright-death/106075564</link><description>Benedict Bryant had pleaded not guilty to dangerous driving occasioning death over the crash in inner Sydney in February 2022, which killed Jai Wright.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7851b2e4abcbdfd81ad9a630d7761b1f</guid></item><item><title>Suspect in Washington DC shooting to face murder charge after soldier Sarah Beckstrom dies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/national-guard-member-shot-washington-dc-dies/106077076</link><description>Sarah Beckstrom, 20, has died in hospital after an ambush shooting near the White House on Wednesday. A male soldier who was also shot, Andrew Wolfe, is fighting for his life, the president says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a041c390c0306157b5291a220d28033</guid></item><item><title>Christmas prawns could be more expensive as wild-caught Australian seafood stocks drop off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/prawns-mackerel-crabs-barramundi-christmas-seafood-prices-high/106058324</link><description>Wild-caught Aussie prawn fishers are reporting a tough catch season. Here's what you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38c830975e652eab6b006f6847ad8e55</guid></item><item><title>Award-winning regional pharmacist says relationship with patients is 'unique'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/pharmacist-award-ouyen-regional-communities-rural-healthcare/105999812</link><description>A north-west Victorian pharmacist is being celebrated for his contribution to his local community after winning an award for going the "extra mile".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11825fa9764b4ae42f7505f1fb4240e6</guid></item><item><title>Super Netball could grow to 10 teams as Netball Australia invites licence bids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/super-netball-could-grow-to-10-teams-by-2027/106077068</link><description>Super Netball could have two additional teams by 2027, with Netball Australia calling for expressions of interest to expand the competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f51d1aadcd45af0382e9a8ea5524b8e</guid></item><item><title>What time is the 2025 AFLW grand final? All you need to know as Brisbane and North Melbourne clash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/aflw-grand-final-2025-what-time-does-the-game-start/106049752</link><description>Wondering what time the AFLW grand final starts and how you can watch it live? We've got you covered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c52c36fdd58c5fcf88e25fe664fef0a</guid></item><item><title>Rare West Australian seaweed scrapbooks provide glimpse into history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/wa-seaweed-scrapbooks-glimpse-into-history/106052420</link><description>The State Library of WA is running an appeal to save a set of seaweed scrapbooks made nearly 100 years ago by a renowned Kalgoorlie-born naturalist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf4174762be5bbe41b633305d0598ec1</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong building fire prompts serious questions about construction safety</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/hong-kong-fires-prompt-questions-about-construction-safety/106074568</link><description>Just months ago, Hong Kong leaders were dismissing calls for a total ban on bamboo scaffolding on construction sites. Now they are facing one of the region's worst building-fire catastrophes, and anger is growing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c1eb75c0809317b5e5c2b262e0cf8c6</guid></item><item><title>Why the banking regulator is targeting property investors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/why-the-banking-regulator-is-targeting-property-investors/106074360</link><description>It's been called a bubble for more than 15 years but the great Aussie housing price boom has barely skipped a beat, as regulators eye the threat of risky loans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ca5ec2b583890693afd566c1fef922f</guid></item><item><title>Victorian regulator imposes conditions on Monash IVF after embryo bungles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/monash-ivf-victorian-health-regulator-conditions/106077192</link><description>Monash IVF has been ordered to be more rigorous when checking the biological origin of embryos to avoid more mix-ups, in order to stay registered in Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">533e38b17ff79f4b0fa25b439eeb33a4</guid></item><item><title>Jane Edmanson hangs up her Gardening Australia hat, reflects on labour of love behind show's success</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/jane-edmanson-gardening-australia-retires/106027658</link><description>As Gardening Australia's longest-serving presenter, Jane Edmanson says farewell and shares the secrets behind the success of Australia’s favourite gardening program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">281e322ce0bc8aaface52c810fbad18a</guid></item><item><title>Berkeley River Lodge caretakers survived 'apocalyptic' Cyclone Fina in underground bunker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/resort-caretakers-survive-cyclone-fina-in-underground-bunker/106077598</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ac0a638981477382a839c62467dab91</guid></item><item><title>Crime scenes declared in Mackay as search continues for Wayne Pedro Morseu</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/suspicious-disappearance-wayne-pedro-morseu/106077476</link><description>Wayne Pedro Morseu was reported missing on November 10, with police now upgrading his disappearance to suspicious.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0450dd9c855f793a17e6942da2790745</guid></item><item><title>F1 Qatar start time, how to watch grand prix, and drivers' championship standings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/f1-qatar-grand-prix-start-time-how-to-watch-driver-standings/105995172</link><description>Lando Norris has match point heading into the penultimate weekend of the Formula 1 season, with the British driver having one hand on a maiden drivers' championship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cf99e225205d22e6b2cdd4aec07317d</guid></item><item><title>Doctors and nurses claim ramping protocol gives ambulance patients priority access to ED, but paramedics disagree</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/tasmania-ambulance-ramping-protocol-emergency-department-nurse/106018196</link><description>Medical experts fear sick or injured Tasmanians who make their own way to emergency departments wait longer than others, due to pressures to fast-track ambulance patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2cbf4fa3c30c15c90451339cafc4607</guid></item><item><title>Dairy 'disrupter' wins science award for inventing spreadable butter in 1970s</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/farmer-who-invented-spreadable-butter-in-70s-wins-science-award/106058726</link><description>An 86-year-old farmer claims this year's Dairy Science Award for inventing spreadable butter, by mixing oils with cultured cream at a time when it was illegal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57efc9add8623d8b897b7403389e53a3</guid></item><item><title>Large police operation underway in Blacktown after man shot dead, two arrested</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/nsw-shooting-blacktown-western-sydney-police-operation/106078118</link><description>A man aged in his 20s has died after being shot multiple times near a police station in Western Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbded38203d1dadfef9c009192e04211</guid></item><item><title>Third renewable energy company discovers asbestos in wind farm turbine lifts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/call-for-border-force-review-asbestos-in-imported-products/106076286</link><description>An anti-asbestos advocate wants a review of import supply chains after a third renewable energy company confirmed the discovery of asbestos in wind farm turbine lifts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d7f9c928f6c8b8a0952caa7dd643ca8</guid></item><item><title>Australia names unchanged squad for second Ashes Test, with captain Pat Cummins still out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/pat-cummins-australia-second-ashes-test-england/106076408</link><description>Australia will go into the second Ashes Test against England in Brisbane next week with an unchanged line-up, meaning there is no place for captain Pat Cummins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">998b1e72e6fbe80fcf0b62145af7bc54</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's education department and RSB Travel charged over child's attempt to drink engine coolant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/education-department-bus-company-engine-coolant-charges/106077516</link><description>Tasmania's education department and a bus company have both appeared in court after a child with a disability was allegedly left unattended on a bus with access to a bottle of engine coolant in a plastic water bottle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a384e06dbe017543ba08056058f5cb2f</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Travel Management embroiled in overcharging scandal potentially worth more than $100 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/corporate-travel-management-overcharging-scandal-100-million/106077806</link><description>Corporate Travel Management helps arrange travel bookings for clients ranging from Wesfarmers to the Australian government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b6d5e0f6a21ec3ecdc711385bed0e1a</guid></item><item><title>Whadjuk Aboriginal Corporation to oversee Rottnest Island cultural services</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/whadjuk-aboriginal-corporation-rottnest-cultural-services-/106078776</link><description>A strife-torn Aboriginal corporation crucial to heritage approvals across Perth wins a contract to oversee cultural services on Rottnest Island, Wadjemup, one of Western Australia's premier tourism destinations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1ba915a0f3aa07e41791c03b661320f</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos coach Darren Crocker opens up on difficult Mia King selection call ahead of AFLW grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/aflw-grand-final-darren-crocker-mia-king-kangaroos-selection/106078850</link><description>North Melbourne coach Darren Crocker says telling Mia King she isn't going to play in the AFLW grand final is "one of the harder conversations" he's had to have.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13aae557b26efb85a64e42a9c4739658</guid></item><item><title>Victims' families of Westfield Bondi Junction attack grateful for inquest but want 'reforms'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/bondi-westfield-stabbing-victims-families-want-reform-inquest/106076576</link><description>A lawyer representing one of the bereaved families took aim at the owner and operator of Westfield, saying they were "extremely disappointed".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0403311f0e2782dcdcf3c2a15bebebe1</guid></item><item><title>A crystal Fabergé egg is expected to sell for more than $40 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/crystal-faberg%C3%A9-egg-expected-to-sell-for-more-than-40-million/106078696</link><description>A rare crystal and diamond Fabergé egg is heading to auction with a price estimate of more than $40 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6099723b7ff7cfb11af19db108b58054</guid></item><item><title>'Rare' cyclone in Indonesia among wild weather in South-East Asia that has killed hundreds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/rare-cyclone-south-east-asia-floods-disaster/106076572</link><description>The death toll is expected to continue rising after a week of record-breaking rain, flash flooding and a "rare" tropical cyclone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24dfcfea06d025032f1301a64b95d0e1</guid></item><item><title>Toyah Cordingley's accused killer '3.7 billion times more likely than not' to have contributed to DNA sample near burial site, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/toyah-cordingly-rajwinder-singh-murder-trial-cairns-dna-testing/106078870</link><description>The former nurse accused of the 2018 murder of Toyah Cordingley was 3.7 billion times more likely than not to have contributed to a DNA sample found on a stick where she was buried, his trial has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b210174034d9ee393eacc220d012cd63</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says America will pause all migration from 'Third World countries'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/donald-trump-migration-pause-from-third-world-countries-to-us/106079562</link><description>US President Donald Trump says his administration will work to permanently pause migration from all "Third World Countries" to allow the American system to fully recover.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79e0ad16bb4c35dc14bd5434c068e1df</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian government criticised for not signing up to federal Help to Buy home ownership scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/tasmanian-government-federal-housing-scheme/106079386</link><description>Tasmania is the only state or territory that is not joining the federal government's Help to Buy home ownership scheme, which aims to reduce the time it takes home buyers to save for a deposit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f76be8be6cc3bea21d5898416d4c47a9</guid></item><item><title>Preparing my garden for time away in summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/preparing-my-garden-for-time-away-in-summer/106051574</link><description>Leaving my garden in the heat of summer can feel worrying but some simple planning means it misses me less than I miss it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56b35dd6decc39572e5296aff34ea254</guid></item><item><title>Police believe stabbing at Elizabeth City Centre was not a random attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/police-believe-stabbing-at-elizabeth-city-centre-not-random/106079818</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dce233839c709fd80a55d5b1b6e841a5</guid></item><item><title>Struggling AFLW teams GWS, Collingwood and Gold Coast receive extra picks or list spots from league</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/aflw-have-nots-receive-league-boost-on-grand-final-eve/106079622</link><description>Three of the AFLW's worst-performing clubs will receive boosts to their lists, with the help announced the day before the grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">087d6c70c437791857888893255fa45d</guid></item><item><title>Lotterywest cancels licences of seven stores across Perth found to be selling illegal tobacco or vapes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/lotterywest-cancels-licences-over-illegal-tobacco-/106079700</link><description>Seven stores across Perth found to be selling illegal tobacco and vapes have their lotteries licences terminated, as attempts to disrupt the illicit and growing trade continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">deaa16d974f977f92fc4244b10fe4aeb</guid></item><item><title>Boy won't face charges after Melbourne primary school stabbing, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/no-charges-over-melbourne-primary-school-stabbing/106080018</link><description>Police say a boy who allegedly stabbed a child at a Berwick primary school will not face charges as he is under the age of criminal responsibility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f93f3f14d73885bdb2435df2a87f02fa</guid></item><item><title>Perth hacker Michael Clapsis jailed after setting up fake Qantas Wi-Fi, stealing sex videos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/perth-michael-clapis-guilty-airport-data-theft-sex-videos/105442798</link><description>A Perth hacker who copied intimate images and sex videos from women's personal online accounts and set up fake Wi-Fi on Qantas flights is sentenced to more than seven years in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">137224c08606535454faf495212728d1</guid></item><item><title>Kyra Cooney-Cross scores stunning long range goal as Matildas down New Zealand 5-0</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/kyra-cooney-cross-goal-matildas-defeat-new-zealand/106074508</link><description>A spectacular long range effort from Kyra Cooney-Cross has helped the Matildas to a dominant 5-0 win over New Zealand in Australia's penultimate game before hosting the Asian Cup in March.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ed492f5f89ed6ab1feddf18b1b73bf8</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong's aging towers face urgent questions after city's deadliest blaze in decades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/behind-hong-kong-s-skyline-thousands-of-old-towers-fire-risks/106079352</link><description>Hong Kong's worst fire in decades exposed long-standing weaknesses in its aging residential blocks. The question haunting the city is whether the disaster could happen again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e527e3cdb4fb8aec5ae2e15796f2ecc</guid></item><item><title>One of seven Rosenberg's goannas from ACT reserve is missing from home for second time in two years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/act-rosenbergs-goanna-rum-missing-ainslie-majura-conservation/106080004</link><description>One of a handful of Rosenberg’s goannas living in the ACT’s hill reserves has once again wandered off, prompting calls from a local conservation organisation for help bringing him back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d236e04ccb909529cfe855fa2a4af683</guid></item><item><title>Brodie Kostecki wins Supercars grand final sprint race as Chad Mostert narrows gap to leader Broc Feeney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/kostecki-wins-as-mostert-closes-in-on-supercars-crown/106080514</link><description>Brodie Kostecki prevails in wet and wild conditions to win the opening Supercars grand final race, as Chaz Mostert closes in on the championship lead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a600518a7d11ed23c8999092c6e4bf7b</guid></item><item><title>Wala Kooral-bi juvenile justice facility opens in northern WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/wala-kooral-bi-juvenile-justice-facility-opens-in-northern-wa/106057316</link><description>An on-country youth diversion facility has been built in the state's far north, offering a culturally grounded alternative to traditional youth justice programs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">142d8035e60293b2bfd4ea512b3d855f</guid></item><item><title>Confidence remains in WA iron ore industry despite forecast royalty drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/wa-iron-ore-royalties-forecast-down/106077818</link><description>Western Australia has long prospered off its hefty irone ore mining royalties, but new figures reveal that revenue may drop by billions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b59e6502bce4249b5b139e3efa48f011</guid></item><item><title>ICC rejects plea to release Philippine ex-president Rodrigo Duterte</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/icc-rejects-plea-to-release-philippine-ex-president-duterte/106080850</link><description>The judge says it is "necessary" for the 80-year-old to remain in detention as the conditions proposed by his lawyers do not meet the conditions for parole.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69d31e21ba06deee8c154d6e2ab9059b</guid></item><item><title>Eight arrested and 128 people dead as alarm faults confirmed in Hong Kong fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/eight-people-arrested-over-deadly-hong-kong-fire-tai-po-district/106080926</link><description>The arrests come as the probe into what caused the deadly blaze that killed at least 128 people continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce9a1003dd5cc3333427e62260e00d1c</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy's chief of staff Andriy Yermak quits as anti-corruption probe widens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/andrii-yermak-zelenskyy-aide-home-office-raided/106080910</link><description>It come as Kyiv battles to persuade US officials to defend Ukraine's interests in peace agreement talks with Russia expected to take place in the coming days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5d4e479539240306c2c980146ac385d</guid></item><item><title>Imran Khan's son and political allies concerned about his health amid block on prison visits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/imran-khan-son-kasim-khan-calls-for-proof-his-father-is-alive/106081236</link><description>The family and political allies of Pakistan's former prime minister say they've not been allowed to visit him in prison for weeks but authorities say he is well.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d540ded1863177c7fec3ea7b841e6670</guid></item><item><title>Putin may laugh but Europe is taking Russian aggression seriously</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/ukraine-russia-vladimir-putin-donald-trump-european-war/106045656</link><description>Something has now been unleashed in Europe which is going to be hard to put back in the bottle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fc1c906afe2cafc664654bab4a6685b</guid></item><item><title>Albanese knows the power dynamic between Labor and mining interests has shifted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/anthony-albanese-mining-labor-greens-deal-environment/106045658</link><description>There has been a shift in the power dynamic between Labor and the mining industry. This week's environmental law reform is its embodiment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f47fba9a6d450b1c3228007e52bf0c6</guid></item><item><title>Growing concern filler doesn't break down even with hyaluronidase dissolver</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/side-effects-of-cosmetic-filler-dissolver-hyaluronidase/106050856</link><description>As more people turn towards cosmetic injectable "journeys", Lana is sounding the alarm about the risks of developing long-term side effects.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">252d91cb5f41b989c74e7ac62d70ee8a</guid></item><item><title>John 'Wacka' Williams labels Barnaby Joyce's resignation an 'act of treason'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/barnaby-joyce-resignation-voter-reaction/106077566</link><description>The MP's resignation from the Nationals surprised no one, but drew ire from members of the party. Those on the ground in his electorate have a more mixed view.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">405b5edf3c1f4ee76d755bb3f5b3be01</guid></item><item><title>Director Peter Weir on capturing the mood for Picnic at Hanging Rock</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/director-peter-weir-on-filming-picnic-at-hanging-rock/106074136</link><description>Renowned Australian director Peter Weir gives a rare behind-the-scenes insight into what made Picnic at Hanging Rock such a memorable and enduring film.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a0a3a9f7a11c445ebf09909341a28d0</guid></item><item><title>Cape Barren Island was returned for Aboriginal self-governance 20 years ago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/cape-barren-island-20-years-after-land-return/105916324</link><description>Twenty years ago, Cape Barren Island was handed back to its traditional owners. Today's children are proof of the life-changing power of that act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1e8123e16da228977e990ee9aa39db7</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong tower residents had safety complaints more than 12 months before deadly fires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/hong-kong-tower-fire-alarms-failed-safety-concerns-flagged/106080022</link><description>Many of the people who managed to escape the Wang Fuk Court fires in Hong Kong believe the disaster could have been prevented, saying they had flagged safety concerns more than a year ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ae6220382bd183f602e5d1bab1fffd7</guid></item><item><title>Hottest spring on record for Australia's east coast as dangerous weekend storms return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/sydney-brisbane-on-track-hottest-spring-weather-storms-return/106081426</link><description>An ongoing heatwave along Australia's eastern seaboard will fuel further extreme weather this weekend, and its longevity is now breaking long standing records.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f7721e772d99b6af67f5041ab734fbe</guid></item><item><title>Normalisation of location sharing, tech-facilitated abuse in spotlight after Lilie James inquest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/nsw-lilie-james-murder-location-sharing-dv-tech-abuse/106072984</link><description>Experts on gendered violence have warned against the proliferation of everyday location sharing tools to control victim-survivors after NSW's top coroner found Paul Thijssen used them to track Lilie James before her murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e22e4fc827d54f6212352558e70a7129</guid></item><item><title>King Gizzard &amp; the Lizard Wizard on quitting Spotify, orchestras, raves, and world domination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/king-gizzard-on-leaving-spotify-orchestras-raves/106058570</link><description>Their rock, rave and orchestral music attracts a cult global following. But the prolific, chaotic King Gizzard &amp; the Lizard Wizard are just "at peace with failing".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fee298a5f31019c8e735f977dd540e6</guid></item><item><title>ABC News - Trusted Source of Latest News &amp; Headlines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2011-07-26/sport-top-stories/2799958</link><description>ABC News - Trusted Source of Latest News &amp; Headlines</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef0d2998edda1e27d100a251175b38b4</guid></item><item><title>R360 launch postponed from 2026 to 2028, after players withdraw due to threats of NRL bans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/r360-postponed-until-2028-after-nrl-ban-threat/106081400</link><description>Threats of long bans for prospective R360 players prompted "a handful" of them to withdraw from the rebel league, which now says it will launch in 2028 instead of next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f9056cd6a82d72eef6485c9c07cdf99</guid></item><item><title>Crowdy Bay shark attack highlights need for first aid devices, drone surveillance on remote beaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/shark-attack-highlights-need-for-remote-first-aid-and-drones/106077444</link><description>A makeshift tourniquet may have made the difference between a shark attack on the NSW Mid North Coast this week claiming one life not two. The attack has put a spotlight on how fatalities may be prevented.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b66b310d8becee41e4ab954e7df6286c</guid></item><item><title>Australia's emissions have dropped, but we've got our work cut out to reach targets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/record-drop-in-australias-emissions/106074296</link><description>Australia's emissions had the biggest drop ever this year outside the artificial kink in the curve during COVID-19 shutdowns, but there's still a lot of work to do.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7549e00e7dd7bc370cfc65bcedc0f0ba</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder after public place shooting in Blacktown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/man-charged-murder-after-man-fatally-shot-in-blacktown/106080772</link><description>A 28-year-old man died after suffering gunshot wounds to his neck, chest and leg in Blacktown on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">571382cdebf8c8726c61fe9dce847452</guid></item><item><title>Waukaringa mine ruins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/waukaringa-mine-ruins/106075580</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e20f80c2cb94c1f65eff431c39a78dfb</guid></item><item><title>Landscape around Yunta in outback SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/landscape-around-yunta-in-outback-sa/106075520</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">620dacb5ce6fa85351a0006df0af44a7</guid></item><item><title>Gus has been gone for 63 days, and searches of mines, dams and scrub have yielded no clues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/the-search-for-gus-lamont-has-included-dams-mines-and-scrub/106055504</link><description>The disappearance of Gus Lamont is one of those events that have a seismic impact on public consciousness: they distress, disturb, upset and unsettle. This week six mine shafts were searched, providing no further clues in the case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b62919d1d99b64b2df9b85158a7245c5</guid></item><item><title>Google's global data hub plan for Christmas Island gets mixed reviews from locals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/google-data-centre-stokes-uncertainty-on-christmas-island/105984092</link><description>Google's plans for a data hub could drag this remote island from a digitally starved past into an AI-powered future. But are the locals ready?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d18f6a9a2d826a770ae8e4af6f53d68b</guid></item><item><title>Trolls stole Dr Juliet Turner's joy and in doing so took their own</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/misogyny-educated-women-manosphere-juliet-turner/106045666</link><description>The saddest aspect of all this that a generation of boys may feel compelled to suppress the ordinary the joy of celebrating another's success.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3b6c544f1770a658d82fc7ad5e282ac</guid></item><item><title>Adoption support service warns against increasing adoption in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/service-warns-against-increasing-adoption-in-queensland/106074614</link><description>Queensland should overhaul "outdated" adoption laws that sever children's legal ties to their families, while ensuring adoption remains a last resort, a peak support service tells a commission of inquiry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">837f8739ea4d39173b45a9bfd38ebb06</guid></item><item><title>Queensland report on puberty blockers might not see the light of day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/queensland-puberty-blocker-hormone-therapies-review/106077108</link><description>A Queensland government-ordered report on the use of puberty blockers and hormone therapies in the treatment of transgender adolescents is due on Sunday but might never be publicly released.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d91fdb74b4a85dd1ede150fd2d4445a6</guid></item><item><title>Unsettled weekend ahead in south-east Queensland, with 'pretty much nowhere' without chance of thunderstorms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/more-storms-ahead-for-queensland-possible-hail-flash-floods/106078390</link><description>A wet weekend is forecast for Australia's sunshine state, with meteorologists warning that "pretty much nowhere in Queensland" is without a chance of thunderstorms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a0fb687524ab6bf4e774b76d15bc712</guid></item><item><title>World-first tournament hopes to 'break down barriers' between the golf and disability communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/queensland-golf-disability-charity-world-first-tournament-pga/106075338</link><description>People with intellectual disabilities will have roles in planning, promoting, preparing, and supporting professionals at a charity golf tournament that is the first of its kind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad28868bc3e87eb99dac4917ac4d964d</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Thunder miss out on WBBL win as Adelaide Strikers clash ended early by rain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/wbbl-thunder-strikers-game-called-off-in-rain/106081446</link><description>After rain falls for most of the Sydney Thunder's innings, umpires decide to call off their WBBL clash against the Strikers with Phoebe Litchfield one swing away from ending the game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99a82cac35ddfb1d3680e1d37e2e0c6d</guid></item><item><title>Former premier Peter Gutwein says Hobart AFL stadium has been 'poorly' sold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/former-premier-peter-gutwein-hobart-afl-stadium-poorly-sold/106079926</link><description>Peter Gutwein initiated the push for a stadium in Hobart, but he has had to watch the drama unfold from the sidelines. He says rejecting the proposal would be the biggest "lost opportunity" in the state's history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d17e00abf2f08909b0d3296cd540598</guid></item><item><title>What would it be like to visit Hobart's proposed Macquarie Point stadium?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/hobart-stadium-design-macquarie-point-spectator-experience/106054654</link><description>From potential gridlock to an "immersive" viewing experience, let's set aside the politics — just for a moment — and look at what planning documents tell us about the building at the heart of Tasmania's fiery stadium debate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7091033d2c6379cd7e19e030424554ee</guid></item><item><title>About 90 Jetstar flights cancelled due to global recall of Airbus A320 planes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/jetstar-flights-grounded-delayed-due-to-airbus-a320-recall/106081408</link><description>About 90 Jetstar flights have been cancelled across Australia today due to a global recall of Airbus A320 planes for urgent software repairs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e49f058098a40deeb8a96f3caf5f71a6</guid></item><item><title>Think you're ready to own a home? Here are the costs that experts want you to consider</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/the-up-front-and-ongoing-costs-of-home-ownership/105984188</link><description>We asked three financial experts about the up-front and ongoing costs of buying a home and for their tips on how to prepare for home ownership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a044e362104441aa527db1d121dcea86</guid></item><item><title>Cricket Australia set to speak with Usman Khawaja after he labelled Perth Ashes Test pitch a 'piece of shit'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/usman-khawaja-pillories-perth-ashes-test-pitch/106081416</link><description>Usman Khawaja may face a sanction for labelling the first Ashes Test surface a "piece of shit", with Cricket Australia understood to be disappointed by the remarks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62c5c47efcba08e3a71df02e352a8f9e</guid></item><item><title>Survivors of forced adoption in South Australia call for greater recognition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/forced-adoption-survivors-call-for-greater-recognition/105946656</link><description>Decades on from Australia's forced adoption era, just two states have set up a redress scheme for the mothers who were harmed. Survivors are calling for South Australia to take similar action — warning time is running out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">883276d36b1aa0a38c589ceb338c5a55</guid></item><item><title>After suffering 'terrifying' postpartum rage, this mother wants others to know they're not alone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/mother-comes-to-terms-with-terrifying-postpartum-rage/106072456</link><description>When Ali Gossage gave birth a second time, she did not experience the constant joys of motherhood. Instead, she was sometimes filled with "terrifying" anger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d749279af4a3906951170031a067264</guid></item><item><title>What must the government prioritise in the new year? | Insiders On Background</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/economic-report-card-insiders-on-background-/106079830</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">053eb94a8d9f352fdee2b46570e99793</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Airport terminal fire under investigation after evacuation of Qantas domestic terminal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/melbourne-airport-fire-evacuation-investigation/106081444</link><description>A fire that forced the evacuation of Melbourne's Qantas domestic terminal on Friday night continues to be investigated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7842effb7970063a8123e6d16509d33</guid></item><item><title>Severe Tropical Cyclone Fina damage exposes need for new Royal Darwin Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/nt-cyclone-fina-damage-royal-darwin-hospital-need-rdh-analysis/106074054</link><description>A new Royal Darwin Hospital would cost more than $1 billion to build, and likely take a decade or more to deliver. So who has the political bravery to commit?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37551ba9b57d2f519ca4ea062b5a9376</guid></item><item><title>Central Queensland success at Commonwealth coastal rowing in Barbados amid Olympic push</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/central-qld-coastal-rowing-gold-amid-olympic-push/106056042</link><description>Though she only tried the sport for the first time this year, the 18-year-old nursing student was one of several Australians taking home gold after competing in coastal rowing in Barbados, ahead of the sport's 2028 Olympic debut.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0a74d68a4ed43d7deab2a1a17881b7c</guid></item><item><title>Who's thriving and who's barely surviving in Australia, the Land of the Parrots?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/parrots-of-australia-a-spotters-guide/106056012</link><description>Australia is the land of the parrot — few places in the world have such a dazzling array of colourful and clever members of the psittacine family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4344c3353cd2f3bf141b8ec4ca2378d0</guid></item><item><title>Crowds grow at Melbourne Airport after Jetstar flights are grounded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/crowds-grow-at-melbourne-airport-/106081616</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1d12c0080e45b2944363b7dd5074653</guid></item><item><title>Jetstar flight cancellations causes travel chaos for passengers at airports across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/vic-jetstar-travel-chaos/106081606</link><description>The cancellation of Jetstar flights due to an issue with Airbus A320 planes has left passengers stranded across Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f288cd807799adb73b68763b5971c050</guid></item><item><title>'Naughty Boy' pelican draws in visitors and locals in coastal tourist town of Kalbarri</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/naughty-boy-pelican-delights-tourists-kalbarri/106073082</link><description>Locals say this cheeky pelican has a personality unlike any bird they have ever seen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59a37b02c238ac01526a5608d9d1e8f3</guid></item><item><title>Australia's peak music exam body under fire amid claims of 'slipping standards'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/claims-standards-slipping-at-ameb-as-regions-revolt/106074654</link><description>It is held up as the "gold standard" of music testing in the country, but there are claims the Australian Music Examinations Board is letting down talented students.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbe3a51c36b4d2bc06add40728c47ad6</guid></item><item><title>South-East Asia flood deaths rise as Cyclone Ditwah hits Sri Lanka, heads towards southern India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/south-east-asia-flood-deaths-rise-cyclone-ditwah-hit-sri-lanka/106081562</link><description>Parts of South-East Asia have been hit with record levels of rain as a cyclone hits Sri Lanka, causing floods and landslides, as the system heads towards India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aac070a6e624988081f4ca440d27d6e4</guid></item><item><title>Snowy Mountains farmers call for support in managing spread of invasive weed African lovegrass</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/african-lovegrass-weed-chokes-out-native-grass-snowy-mountains/106006854</link><description>To the untrained eye, African lovegrass is just another plant in the NSW Snowy Mountains. But this golden plant is a deceptive invasive weed that is choking out the landscape, causing some farmers to leave the land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97336bfbd9984ec7e511ae69aa52d050</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri fastest qualifier for Qatar F1 sprint race, with championship leader Lando Norris third</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/oscar-piastri-pole-position-for-qatar-f1-sprint/106081654</link><description>Oscar Piastri returns to form by qualifying fastest for the F1 sprint in Qatar, as he launches an unlikely bid to catch McLaren teammate and world championship leader Lando Norris.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4c968437af1a688da3df1481b00bf56</guid></item><item><title>Police seize more than $8m in assets after alleged illicit tobacco raids in the NT</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/afp-nt-qld-tobacco-raids-8-million-dollar-assets-seizure/106081638</link><description>Police have seized about $8.4 million in assets, including two cars and a jet ski, and almost 1 million cigarettes, following an operation targeting the NT's illicit tobacco trade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c6957203f64aa81778a9e1449c06437</guid></item><item><title>Conservationists worldwide scrambling for alternative funding after USAID cuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/conservationists-scrambling-for-funding-after-usaid-cuts/106053490</link><description>Citizen science and AI have never been more important to the environment after White House cuts to USAID are felt beneath the waves, a new report says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02a67830f4b18930900eb775f8ab34b6</guid></item><item><title>The Wiggles issue statement after appearing in Keli Holiday Ecstasy video</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/wiggles-issue-statement-after-keli-holiday-ecstasy-video/106081670</link><description>A spokesperson for the group says the band "does not condone" the use of drugs after a since-deleted video promoting Keli Holiday's single, Ecstasy, appeared on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88bf00aa8f0697112dd1631b533873f9</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne teen who died after nut allergy 'let down' by health system, family says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/max-mckenzie-nut-allergy-coronial-inquest/106022338</link><description>Four years after a 15-year-old boy died due to a nut allergy, a Victorian coroner is examining if the death was preventable and whether paramedics and doctors at the Box Hill Hospital provided appropriate care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea1a2581536020cb7f1dd793ff06ac66</guid></item><item><title>Girl Guides still going strong in Western Australia after 110 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/girl-guides-western-australia-celebrating-110-years/106001684</link><description>The uniforms and pledge may have had a revamp, but the learning, friendships and camping trips at Girl Guides are just as relevant for a new generation more than a century after the organisation first began.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ad840e69b1c4ba52c321ee835f8df16</guid></item><item><title>Mother 'devastated' by police decision to drop murder charges in Kaiden Morgan-Johnston stabbing case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/kaiden-morgan-stabbing-murder-charges-dropped-morwell/105904144</link><description>A 19-year-old man has been released from custody after police withdrew charges against him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60a40bc9505bca95a18024f89547d985</guid></item><item><title>Five boys injured after jumping castle flies into air in Sydney's west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/nsw-jumping-castle-flips-in-sydneys-west/106081798</link><description>Emergency services were called to a property in Bradfield following reports a jumping castle had flown into the air with people onboard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0a20489e78bb14cf5ecc2879df7e588</guid></item><item><title>RBA could hike interest rates in early 2026 as banks rewrite forecasts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/rba-interest-rate-hike-possible-within-months/106077098</link><description>Hotter-than-expected inflation figures have caught most economists and policy makers off guard. The ongoing price pressures in the economy open the door for an RBA interest rate hike in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d82eb1838ac69bb8ea36fe67f738a8cc</guid></item><item><title>Skyhooks guitarist Bob Starkie dies aged 73 after a battle with cancer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/skyhooks-guitarist-bob-starkie-dies/106081862</link><description>A statement released on Skyhooks' official Facebook page announced his passing this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9887f7f9c22df27c6c83a6df9ee2dbf</guid></item><item><title>Parramatta River gets new swimming spot at Gladesville's Bedlam Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/bedlam-bay-beach-becomes-sydneys-newest-swimming-spot/106073282</link><description>While new swimming areas have opened along the river in recent years, an election promise to open a Western Sydney location has stalled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a976fe127fd6d0c30492d4cea8889487</guid></item><item><title>Planning to bite into a sweet, juicy mango? Here's what to know about your favourite summer treat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/australian-mango-varieties-and-origins/106072138</link><description>What's the difference between a big R2E2, a delicate Honey Gold, and an iconic Kensington Pride? Find out before biting into a mango this season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70ee88f5621fa0e89efe9a8c714443d7</guid></item><item><title>Victorian coroner determines Mount Buller hiker missing since 2019 is dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/niels-becker-coroner-finding-mount-buller-inquest-missing-hiker-/106081758</link><description>A Coroner has determined that Niels Gunther Becker, 39, who went missing at Mount Buller in 2019 is dead but that no third party was involved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">472d867bb5bccf18ea322810f522a39f</guid></item><item><title>Terminated Bedford staff in limbo, with millions of dollars owed in entitlements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/bedford-staff-in-limbo-millions-owed-in-entitlements/106080712</link><description>Former Bedford staff have said they are owed millions of dollars in entitlements after they were made redundant when the disability employment provider entered voluntary administration earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfe87f0fcb8a8a391861ebdeb706d658</guid></item><item><title>Colin Friels takes on his final stage role in King Lear at Belvoir in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/colin-friels-king-lear-water-rats-monkey-grip-malcolm/106051868</link><description>Colin Friels, the award-winning actor known for Malcolm and Water Rats, reflects on his 50-year career on stage and screen as he approaches what might be his final role.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">967f29bede3ba2e25f22d270ea5f4fba</guid></item><item><title>US halts all asylum claims following the shooting of two National Guard members in Washington DC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/us-halts-all-asylum-claims-after-national-guards-shooting/106081774</link><description>Less than 24 hours after the shooting, Trump officials began ordering widespread reviews of immigration policies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6ca5d3708d013392675c37ab077e950</guid></item><item><title>No-bake chocolate and strawberry cake is the ultimate make-ahead dessert - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/no-bake-chocolate-biscuit-and-strawberry-cream-cake/105543504</link><description>Icebox cakes are retro no-bake desserts made by layering store-bought biscuits and whipped cream. A no-fuss option for summer celebrations, this one can be assembled in 10 minutes and made well ahead of time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa595533c02a1f792c1bf40a7fb5ef05</guid></item><item><title>Best books out in November, featuring Margaret Atwood's memoir and The Mushroom Tapes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/best-books-november-margaret-atwood-memoir-mushroom-tapes/106018540</link><description>Wondering what to read next? This month's best books include a novel that brings to life Britain's only named wind and a new book by the author of The Handmaid's Tale.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9716753e1b04846ee97e8f09ff9b42a</guid></item><item><title>England captain Ben Stokes dismisses 'arrogant' label amid criticism of Ashes Test loss to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/ashes-cricket-england-australia-ben-stokes-arrogant-label/106082046</link><description>Captain Ben Stokes responds to England's critics in the wake of the defeat to Australia in the first Test, maintaining his squad will not step back from its aggressive approach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cadb1c10356060c35802d310ab0fa02f</guid></item><item><title>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese marries Jodie Haydon at The Lodge in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-29/anthony-albanese-jodie-haydon-wedding-prime-minister-married/106080434</link><description>Anthony Albanese has married partner Jodie Haydon at his official Canberra residence in a private ceremony on Saturday, after details of the wedding were kept top secret.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f951cdd57ae649a668fbbb63b9787d7e</guid></item></channel></rss>