<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 03:47:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>WWII shipwrecks a 'ticking time bomb' for Federated States of Micronesia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/war-relics-threat-for-federated-states-of-micronesia/105884710</link><description>The Federated States of Micronesia's biggest tourism asset has become one of its largest threats, with as much as 22 million litres of oil from World War II shipwrecks slowly leaking into the ocean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5a5e22c5b7f81e23acf8feb4ae870bd</guid></item><item><title>Oil leaking from WW2 shipwreck the Rio de Janeiro Maru in Chuuk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/oil-leaking-from-ww2-shipwreck-the-rio-de-janeiro-maru-in-chuuk/105889748</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2be0837ab0fb4ac0467e1f6078adc4e</guid></item><item><title>'Dangerously low' funding to Tasmanian arts sector creating reputational damage, minister warned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/tasmanian-arts-industry-highly-vulnerable-low-funding-investment/105899498</link><description>"Dangerously low" arts sector funding has rendered the Tasmanian industry "highly vulnerable", with funding stagnant since 2016-17, the state government has conceded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a29de7c4d5bc252c9a785dea93220878</guid></item><item><title>Jim Chalmers and Tony Burke are in a long race for prime position</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/jim-chalmers-tony-burke-leadership/105884226</link><description>There is general agreement in Labor that Jim Chalmers is the government's best communicator. But insiders watching this race know Tony Burke is the master tactician.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93f58dc170f3f37c70cca03a69e3a6f5</guid></item><item><title>Drunken motorcyclist crashes with daughter riding as passenger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/drunken-motorcyclist-crashes-with-daughter-passenger/105898498</link><description>A Mildura father-of-six avoids jail after drunkenly crashing his motorbike while carrying his young daughter as a passenger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b7dbbdb3b9ed775f287c7490a9599c8</guid></item><item><title>BHP vs China Inc: What the iron ore dispute says about Australia's present and future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/what-bhp-china-iron-ore-dispute-means-to-australia/105901692</link><description>The resolution of negotiations between Australian mining giant BHP and China's state-backed iron ore buyer China Mineral Resources Group could reshape not just the resources industry, but also international trade flows, global markets, and the relationship between China and the West.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f17745151acc39e0b5f38368c4928c68</guid></item><item><title>From cult web series to cinema: Nirvanna the Band the Show the Movie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/nirvanna-the-band-the-show-the-movie/105898756</link><description>Canada's cult web series heads to the big screen, after creators Matt Johnson and Jay McCarrol were told they could make any movie they liked after their success with BlackBerry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcab9960bf8462cac061bee2cf98745a</guid></item><item><title>Zach Merrett trade drama a reminder that deals can no longer be judged by amount of first-round picks involved</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/afl-trade-period-analysis-zach-merrett-first-round-pick-value/105898588</link><description>The AFL trade period offered three different test cases on just how much value a first-round pick holds during negotiations. Two stars got their moves, while one was left stranded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28e8bb8d5802a90c22f1d69d1a4727c3</guid></item><item><title>New research shows impact of lead poisoning on ancient humans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/new-research-shows-impact-lead-poisoning-ancient-humans/105899188</link><description>A new study claims lead might be the reason why Homo sapiens came to dominate the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12aa86f8c8828a99bbdb6054ea89c8c1</guid></item><item><title>Dangerous flammable cladding still not removed from dozens of NSW high-rise apartment buildings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/government-yet-to-fix-cladding-on-dozens-of-apartments-re-scheme/105900296</link><description>Dozens of high-rise apartment buildings across the state are still covered in flammable cladding as the NSW government's scheme has failed to fix them on schedule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">900570fd41fc7cafb3f056a176d7d52c</guid></item><item><title>Shocking CCTV footage shows moment bus driver assaulted while driving down Darwin highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/nt-bus-driver-assaulted-cctv-footage-played-in-court/105901292</link><description>Shocking video footage capturing the moment a bus driver was assaulted, and passengers were thrown through the air, has been played in the NT Supreme Court after the attacker pleaded guilty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72512a66b5c068ddcb13f9e41634e0e4</guid></item><item><title>Specialist health services shortfall for women in regional WA leave many struggling for support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/women-missing-out-on-specialist-health-services-in-regional-wa/105866424</link><description>Faced with a lack of specialist women's health services, women in regional WA are researching their own conditions and volunteering to raise awareness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a46a1f1f255a795ba616233f2bb18c5</guid></item><item><title>How a 15yo autistic boy tinkering in his bedroom triggered WA's biggest ever data breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/joshua-unwittingly-triggered-major-wa-health-data-breach-autism/105455250</link><description>Joshua's "passion project" with a radio scanner led to one of WA's most significant public health data breaches. His story highlights the challenges confronting autistic people caught up in the legal system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13c71de037de480416dd879b9c6eab51</guid></item><item><title>Younger candidates out to bring change in WA local government elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/young-candidates-seek-change-in-wa-local-government-elections/105888820</link><description>In the last local government elections in WA, the average age of candidates running for councils was 53 years old — but these young candidates are keen to lower that figure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">612d6039eb66ee2883e4b90a17276dfe</guid></item><item><title>McLaren's 'papaya rules' may be over as Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris battle for the F1 drivers' championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/mclaren-papaya-rules-oscar-piastri-lando-norris-f1/105855110</link><description>"Papaya rules" have dominated Formula 1 for two seasons, but with both McLaren drivers in the heat of a world championship battle, Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris may no longer prioritise what is best for the team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c1dd9f6429245aceb6baaa21e041d3e</guid></item><item><title>Starmer criticises police decision to ban fans of Israel's Maccabi Tel Aviv from Aston Villa match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/football-maccabi-tel-aviv-fans-banned-police-aston-villa/105902590</link><description>Fans of Israel's Maccabi Tel Aviv are banned from attending next month's Europa League match against Aston Villa in Birmingham over "public safety concerns".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">effc61153d88fcce13575af2eb2a3f1c</guid></item><item><title>Coronado Curragh fined for death of miner Clark Peadon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/coronado-curragh-fined-for-death-of-worker-clark-peadon/105893210</link><description>The MEU has described the fine as "inadequate" for the loss of someone's life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">302b71db67d68b4b399d0e78f4be1f6f</guid></item><item><title>Ace Frehley, founding member of rock group KISS, dies at 74</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/ace-frehley-guitarist-kiss-dies-aged-74/105902920</link><description>The original lead guitarist of the glam rock band captivated audiences with his elaborate makeup and smoke-filled guitar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70f68f5def708160810eec0ad80e8354</guid></item><item><title>King Charles marks land rights milestone in first visit to London's Australia House</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/king-charles-commemorates-40th-anniversary-of-uluru-handback/105902056</link><description>King Charles marked the major milestone in Aboriginal land rights alongside Uluru-Kata Tjuta's traditional owners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7d5382ea3e29445cd53373bb9eda014</guid></item><item><title>Australian swimming star Ariarne Titmus says she lost 'fire in the belly' before shock retirement call</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/swimming-ariarne-titmus-retirement-press-conference/105902788</link><description>Ariarne Titmus has spoken publicly for the first time after abruptly retiring from professional swimming at just 25, revealing the reasons behind her decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce4208efcf5ba5f558acc40ad5edc802</guid></item><item><title>Southern Mallee Council mayor found by ombudsman to have engaged in misconduct</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/southern-mallee-mayor-misconduct-apology/105898854</link><description>The South Australian ombudsman says Southern Mallee Council Mayor Ron Valentine improperly used his position to gain an advantage for himself in the recruitment of a CEO in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">968cba559352190fb4a9912978cceb6f</guid></item><item><title>SA Education Department fined after teen fell from school playground swing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/sa-education-department-fined-playground-swing-fall/105900366</link><description>South Australia's Education Department has been fined $225,000 after a student at a special school fell from a swing which had not had a comprehensive safety inspection for eight years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cdc7ec760bf1e318791fcad162c615f</guid></item><item><title>Defence in talks to support Gaza peace plan but Australia says no request yet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/defence-in-talks-with-us-to-support-gaza-peace-plan/105902742</link><description>Australia's defence force has had discussions with the Unted States to provide support for its Gaza peace plan but the government says no formal request has been made yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd80619b996f35eb17de143a6b7e07dc</guid></item><item><title>Virtual emergency department a lifeline for patients in regional areas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/virtual-emergency-department-option-for-patients-remote-areas/105371852</link><description>A virtual emergency room app created during the pandemic could help bridge healthcare gaps in regional Victoria. But more patients need to dial-in and use the resource.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cce3e05039289d83c6bdbae0a5d4e7b</guid></item><item><title>How wild bird poo testing in northern Australia is helping keep eggs on the shelves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/bird-flu-poo-testing-in-northern-australia-keeps-eggs-on-shelves/105894598</link><description>Hundreds of kilometres from the nearest supermarket, Indigenous rangers in Australia's remote north are working to keep eggs on your breakfast table.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">126bc279f84d1b05bc9d6ac31fa6b513</guid></item><item><title>Indigiearth founder inspires Indigenous women to chase business dreams</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/indigiearth-award-sharon-winsor-australian-cuisine/105899236</link><description>Sharon Winsor is honoured for her pioneering work in native Australian cuisine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9867852928883c2abad3f488c0d1bf3b</guid></item><item><title>Bears kill record number of people in Japan amid scores of attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/record-number-of-bear-attacks-in-japan/105902770</link><description>At least seven people have been killed by bears in the country since April and many more have been injured as the hungry animals venture into human territory to find food.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41b4b93bb120166534952debb22263e8</guid></item><item><title>'No doubt' Anthony Albanese and Donald Trump will discuss critical minerals: Chalmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/albanese-trump-chalmers-critical-minerals-deal/105903392</link><description>Anthony Albanese will "no doubt" use a meeting with Donald Trump next week to discuss critical minerals, the treasurer says as he dismisses a call for Australia to "decouple" with China over rare earth materials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fe4351ff10e966c7a84c8e260555fa8</guid></item><item><title>Hamish McIntyre elected new president of National Farmers' Federation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/hamish-mcintyre-new-president-of-national-farmers-federation/105903736</link><description>Hamish McIntyre is named the new president of Australia's peak farmer representative body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c317e433f02d76c14e44c86f15f08ecd</guid></item><item><title>Pacific Championships set to start without Australia as strong Samoa and Tonga teams take on New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/pacific-championships-stars-embrace-their-island-heritage/105903826</link><description>Emerging superpowers Samoa and Tonga will field formidable teams loaded with NRL talent in the third edition of the Pacific Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07fb63cc9e9ec53c5f2664aaf516d600</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill man wins appeal of sentence for animal cruelty offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/broken-hill-man-animal-cruelty-offences-appeal/105903070</link><description>Jet Jai Johnson is released from prison two-and-a-half months into his 14-month sentence after telling a court spending his 21st birthday behind bars was a wake-up call.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ad3f1fe76e5d052feb967d866f79777</guid></item><item><title>WA's insolvent Griffin Coal ramps up operations as taxpayer bailout deadline looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/insolvent-wa-griffin-coal-ramps-up-operations/105901120</link><description>The receiver of a WA coal mine says it is ramping up operations in a final attempt to trade out of insolvency before millions of dollars in taxpayer support dries up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2e888ffc914c66fe0fec7316e9144da</guid></item><item><title>Pet-friendly flights are taking off in Australia. Here's what to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/pet-friendly-flights-what-to-know/105903876</link><description>The first pet-friendly commercial flights have taken off in Australia this week. Here's what you need to know about the new service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4379a2d55c184d75fb0dbc167127d3db</guid></item><item><title>Victims of former Hobart teacher Keith Athol Bates-Willie read impact statements of abuse to court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/keith-bates-willie-supreme-court-victim-impact-statements/105902600</link><description>After former teacher Keith Athol Bates-Willie was found guilty of assault against Hobart schoolboys, 10 complainants read out in court their victim impact statements as sentencing begins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b66a194144d3bc9a4d6c49ad44b75493</guid></item><item><title>Cameron Green ruled out of Australia vs India ODI series, Marnus Labuschagne called into squad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/cameron-green-ruled-out-of-australia-vs-india-odi-series/105904798</link><description>Cameron Green has been ruled out of Australia's ODI series against India, just over a month out from the start of the Ashes series against England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfecd41bffae6db1aa484dbde8addcc6</guid></item><item><title>Family of murdered Darwin man Tony Rowe describe 'massive hole' of father's absence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/family-murdered-darwin-man-tony-rowe-by-timothy-hunt-impact/105904050</link><description>Family members of Tony Rowe — who was murdered on the outskirts of Darwin in 2022 — have read emotional victim impact statements to the court ahead of killer Timothy Hunt's sentencing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8adc5da1876325d1a54d3a1b9c74771e</guid></item><item><title>Australia Test batter Nic Maddinson reveals testicular cancer diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/australia-test-batter-nic-maddinson-testicular-cancer-diagnosis/105905220</link><description>Former Australia batter Nic Maddinson has revealed he underwent chemotherapy for testicular cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7f603e8cc45b625885d16071d38bc7a</guid></item><item><title>David Pye on bail after being refused anxiety drugs in custody, Nick Martin trial hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/david-pye-trial-told-of-nick-martin-killer-iraq-terror-link-/105903116</link><description>An accused murderer and bikie gang member on trial in WA's Supreme Court amid heightened security is granted bail because he is unable to get access to anti-anxiety medication behind bars, it is revealed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d458f503d4b0f4c89690a3b91078a89e</guid></item><item><title>Accused killer Jason Thomas King takes stand in Molendinar landlord Susan Walker's murder trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/jason-thomas-king-murder-trial-landlord-continues/105904754</link><description>Jason Thomas King has pleaded not guilty to the murder of his landlord Susan Walker on the Gold Coast in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">561483c094963904fd07393e184bed8f</guid></item><item><title>Endemic frog and gecko species identified on Dauan Island in Torres Strait</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/frog-gecko-species-found-dauan-torres-strait/105790146</link><description>Two new frog species and a banded-patterned gecko are believed to have sheltered among the boulders of Dauan, in the Torres Strait, for millions of years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02d7af04ef02838cbdfc93bff8ff13f8</guid></item><item><title>Inquest hears of grief, trauma from families of Eugowra locals after record-breaking 2022 flood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/eugowra-inquest-day-five/105902498</link><description>Families speak of loss, trauma on final day of the coronial inquest into the deaths of Les Vugec and Diane Smith.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dcae5aba593220ee08189da0bc90ff1</guid></item><item><title>After three trials Hunter Valley man jailed for covering up Carly McBride's 2014 murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/james-cunneen-sentenced-for-murder-cover-up/105462274</link><description>Hunter Valley man James Anthony Cunneen has been sentenced to six years jail for covering up a murder after helping his friend to dump a woman's body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b74dbad40fbab690ff260ffadfa040df</guid></item><item><title>NT DPP confirms it will not appeal sentence for Alice Springs baby assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/man-sentenced-over-alice-springs-baby-assault-no-dpp-appeal/105904314</link><description>The NT Director of Public Prosecutions has confirmed it will not appeal the non-custodial sentence handed to a young man who fractured the skull of a nine-week-old baby in Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c925ab8c4fe58507e765dc17837dd6b</guid></item><item><title>Video released of moments leading up to strip search that breached Aboriginal woman's human rights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/julianne-williams-strip-search-canberra-jail-video-release-court/105905888</link><description>The ACT Supreme Court has made public confronting video showing the moments leading up to a strip search that violated an Aboriginal woman’s human rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdcb7325932b405b24aab30e15587062</guid></item><item><title>Three teens charged over Wakeley church attack on bishop hit with violent extremist material charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/wakeley-church-stabbing-teens-face-extremism-material-charges/105905428</link><description>Three of the five young people charged in relation to the alleged stabbing of a Bishop at a church in Sydney's west last year have been charged with additional offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c73ef4a1ef617bb06598d16d3f448ae5</guid></item><item><title>Wayne Swan steps down as Labor president urging party to focus on membership boost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/wayne-swan-labor-president-leaves-role-politics/105905064</link><description>Labor party president Wayne Swan will step down next July and has warned the ALP must boost membership if it is to survive into the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75e127f2e28c7f78ce730de287d98398</guid></item><item><title>Wittenoom asbestos contamination prompts legal threat from Banjima traditional owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/wittenoom-asbestos-litigation-documentary/105886444</link><description>After decades of disconnection, the traditional owners of Wittenoom say they are prepared to take legal action to ensure the area is properly remediated so they can return to country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">713ee52afb0c4689f99c025841f00428</guid></item><item><title>Friday the pelican captured and washed after three-week chase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/friday-the-pelican-captured-and-washed-after-three-week-chase/105906028</link><description>Friday the pelican evaded capture for weeks. But a long-overdue bath is for her own good.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08e29ab2dd99920f8f64165e8034ff2b</guid></item><item><title>Strict conditions imposed on future LIV Golf site at North Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/strict-conditions-on-north-adelaide-golf-course-redevelopment/105905844</link><description>South Australia's Aboriginal affairs minister has imposed 31 strict conditions on the government's planned redevelopment of the North Adelaide golf course.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc6d01343d110faca4bb8653ade74cc5</guid></item><item><title>Chinese national charged with foreign interference granted bail despite concerns she could flee country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/act-chinese-national-charged-foreign-interference-granted-bail/105906106</link><description>A woman accused of covertly gathering information for the Chinese government has been granted bail in Canberra, despite police warning she could try to flee the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f8a82b873c67ac845e029c6fb5fd2f1</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/friday-finance-with-david-chau/105906178</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6b775f25a05cb343702a02cf5d8de47</guid></item><item><title>Scott Boland bowls Victoria to Sheffield Shield victory over NSW, ahead of Ashes against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/scott-boland-bowls-victoria-to-sheffield-shield-victory-over-nsw/105905076</link><description>Scott Boland has produced a man-of-the-match performance, bowling Victoria to a 38-run win over New South Wales in their Sheffield Shield clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">729329d9bae119b36c0706d109492cf3</guid></item><item><title>Family of woman murdered by co-worker at National Zoo tell court of their 'constant grief'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/act-family-murdered-woman-tshewang-choden-zoo-court-grief/105905924</link><description>Jude Wijesinghe previously pleaded guilty to stabbing his co-worker Tshewang Choden to death in the kitchen area of the National Zoo and Aquarium in Canberra, where they both worked, in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fd47b1c9bc2ac77c75ae045dd46cfe3</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar military leader Michael Randrianirina sworn in as president after coup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/madagascar-new-president-sworn-in-after-military-coup/105906334</link><description>An army colonel who seized power in a military coup has been sworn in as Madagascar's new leader, after a sudden power grab that ousted the president and sent him fleeing from the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96dcc3f3b1832b7f3704ff8662f60934</guid></item><item><title>Inquest recommends road safety reforms after cyclist killed by partially blind driver</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/robert-hall-inquest-findings-handed-down/105903390</link><description>A coroner has recommended changes to national driving fitness standards following the death of cyclist Robert Hill who was hit and killed by a partially blind driver on a country highway seven years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58795b8a47c2e0572a629a78ac6f936c</guid></item><item><title>Australia Diamonds defeat New Zealand Silver Ferns 69-52 in game one of Constellation Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/australia-diamonds-defeat-new-zealand-silver-ferns-69-52/105905070</link><description>Australia has stormed to a commanding win in the first Test of the Constellation Cup series, defeating New Zealand 69-52.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f36860ee433d3f4861c1144ddc36164e</guid></item><item><title>AFLW Round 10: Port Adelaide Power defeat Hawthorn Hawks, West Coast Eagles down Geelong Cats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/aflw-round-10-power-hawks-eagles-cats/105906400</link><description>Port Adelaide defeats Hawthorn to record its fourth win of the AFLW season, while West Coast moves closer to a maiden finals appearance with victory over Geelong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae0cbd52bca8dc6756cd2ffe42c3b8bd</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide United defeats Sydney FC 2-1, Brisbane downs Macarthur on A-League Men opening night</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/aleagues-men-adelaide-sydney-brisbane-macarthur/105906556</link><description>Adelaide United begins its season with a 2-1 win over Sydney, while Brisbane coach Michael Valkanis sees son Dimitri sent off in the Roar's 1-0 defeat of Macarthur.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82bb437ece317276dd69493b6848e7ad</guid></item><item><title>Russia convicts 15 captured Ukrainian soldiers on terrorism charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/russia-convicts-15-captured-ukrainian-soldiers/105906652</link><description>Fifteen captured Ukrainian soldiers from the Aidar battalion have been sentenced in a Russian court to up to 21 years in a penal colony.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b7ddec1dccff7c0b1c93ead771afa46</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's Trump meeting comes amid global geopolitical circus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/gaza-ceasefire-deal-donald-trump-anthony-albanese-trade-tariff/105884238</link><description>All signs suggest Anthony Albanese will be sticking with Plan A in his meeting with the US president on Tuesday, rather than becoming a prop for the bigger global circus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7369e04e283103228bfcf69dddc12dd2</guid></item><item><title>Creating deepfakes has never been easier, so what should parents do?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/creating-deepfakes-is-easy-what-should-parents-do/105902982</link><description>Some parents may feel distressed and ill-equipped to tackle the issue of image-based abuse and deepfakes. This is what to watch out for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">136e26003e31a95432cd2b1c4b32704d</guid></item><item><title>Video appears to show March for Australia organiser coordinating with Neo-Nazi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/march-for-australia-organiser-coordinates-with-neo-nazi/105902754</link><description>A previously unreported video has emerged appearing to show a key March for Australia organiser coordinating with a Neo-Nazi at the first rally in Sydney in August, ABC NEWS Verify has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc104ef4e2d70260f456bb05e05b9a6c</guid></item><item><title>Administrative Review Tribunal swamped by surging demand, more than 100 members short</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/administrative-review-tribunal-overwhelmed-surging-demand/105893728</link><description>The Administrative Review Tribunal was set up to resolve issues with its predecessor, but has struggled with staffing and long wait times over its first year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fd2f156e95340a969daa8b6003273f1</guid></item><item><title>Education department admits not enough done to stop Dubbo College Delroy aide harming children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/systemic-failure-to-investigate-nsw-dubbo-school-staff/105807290</link><description>The NSW government says it should have taken allegations of wrongdoing by a male school staff member more seriously. That failure left those who reported it so isolated their mental health spiralled and never fully recovered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c22f6955d77c23cb8f7c088405ad508</guid></item><item><title>Wall Street sell-off could mean hip-pocket relief for millions of Australians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/insurance-companies-caught-in-global-sector-sell-off/105906164</link><description>Australia's big insurance companies were sold off heavily on the share market on Friday after a wave of anxiety hit the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e35eee1242809cb384df7776dc560ebc</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's family reportedly made hundreds of millions from crypto after White House return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/how-trump-family-profits-from-cryptocurrencies/105445400</link><description>US President Donald Trump and his family have reportedly amassed hundreds of millions of dollars from cryptocurrencies. Here is what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d405316e27218a44724818a9f9ff772a</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou defends record as pressure builds at Nottingham Forest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/ange-postecoglou-launches-passionate-defence-of-record/105907112</link><description>Amid growing pressure of his poor start at Nottingham Forest, Ange Postecoglou delivers a five-minute defence of his record as a manager.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1863ae28c5532d8ed98a6a975abd634</guid></item><item><title>Fire authorities warn of 'above average' fire season as NSW starts to warm up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/nsw-above-average-fire-season-bushfire-risk-weather/105900120</link><description>Fire authorities warn of above average fire season in NSW despite previous modelling showing a wet summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52eaca3898c563789480ae66f0c7a43f</guid></item><item><title>Water testing in the Murweh Shire returns negative for dangerous amoeba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/murweh-mayor-charleville-hospital-negative-water-testing-amoeba/105899494</link><description>South-west Queensland residents are questioning the detection of a dangerous amoeba at Queensland Health sites after all follow-up tests were negative.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f732b4b65ef2c9618812d9b472a6ce26</guid></item><item><title>Is the transfer of Australia's best young soccer players a good thing?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/soccer-a-league-player-transfers/105893566</link><description>Are A-League soccer fans right to be frustrated when its best young players are sold off, or should they accept it is a 'selling' league?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0e06963459d7a95465fff2d57464f52</guid></item><item><title>Young people with chronic pain feel 'unheard', misunderstood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/young-people-living-with-chronic-pain/105898314</link><description>Chronic pain affects one in five Australian children. Two young people who experience it want more people to understand their conditions and better support for all children in pain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">946486ae5287caf11084ac18ee24e69e</guid></item><item><title>Lack of housing in remote NT community Borroloola forcing families off country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/borroloola-housing-lack-forcing-families-leave-country/105895586</link><description>Remote NT residents are calling on the government to fund new housing in the Gulf community of Borroloola, fearing limited access to appropriate homes has forced families to move off country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df22bcf01f5fa2c70abd461d204c6d03</guid></item><item><title>James Duckworth returns to ATP Tour semifinal four years after his last</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/james-duckworth-atp-tour-astana-open-semi-final/105907190</link><description>Four years since he last reached an ATP tournament semifinal in Kazakhstan, Australian James Duckworth is back in the last four at the Almaty Open</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dceb858841c1c847c349b2a7432508b3</guid></item><item><title>AI tech takes on one of NSW's deadliest rock fishing spots</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/ai-camera-trial-rock-fishing-safety-nsw/105902900</link><description>Surf Life Saving NSW is testing artificial intelligence cameras at Kiama Blowhole to detect when fishers are swept into the water and alert rescuers within seconds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">151eddbf0d62e8e7f4aeb5cec27a435d</guid></item><item><title>Hospital in the Home program helping young man with agoraphobia who 'cut himself off from the world'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/hospital-in-the-home-northwest-tasmania-mental-health/105789004</link><description>Tom French's agoraphobia meant he couldn't leave the house to access the mental health care he needed, but a Hospital in the Home program means the care is coming to him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1b964e8ba63ca42e36daf1af0d1b9c8</guid></item><item><title>The face of Brisbane is changing — but should thousands of homes be developed in a flood zone?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/visy-montague-road-riverfront-precinct-thousands-of-homes-floods/105904030</link><description>Plans to build a riverfront precinct in a flood-prone area of Brisbane have urban planners and locals wary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d506b00fbc8d45eff04ef30c465454e6</guid></item><item><title>Tool's Maynard James Keenan on touring Australia, making wine and martial arts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/tool-australia-tour-2025-maynard-james-keenan-interview/105865706</link><description>The alt-metal band's frontman is a world-class multi-tasker. He tells us how he balances it all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">501350518724f7dcac6393cd0c095da6</guid></item><item><title>Western Australia starts harvesting what could be a record-breaking grain crop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/western-australia-harvest-record-grain-crop-expected/105900332</link><description>Farmers in Western Australia have begun harvesting a grain crop that could set a new record. It is a different story on the other side of the Nullabor though.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a84a87f36461e65b587de7b1fd2f66c6</guid></item><item><title>Greek-inspired lamb kebabs with olive potatoes baked in the oven - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/easy-oven-baked-lamb-kebabs-with-olive-potatoes/105291672</link><description>The lamb is fuss-free and full of flavour. No barbecue needed — the oven takes care of everything.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97732d3bb23552f5f8a4e4e0fa75a14b</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne's record-setting AFLW winning streak is clear in the numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/north-melbourne-setting-aflw-standards/105905842</link><description>Having developed the program layer by layer since joining the AFLW in 2019, North Melbourne's disciplined, professional style of footy is forcing the rest of the league to rise to their level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3f69ec228f1094f89b081dd9d305cb5</guid></item><item><title>Cool weather prescribed burn on WA's south coast should be expanded, environmental group says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/call-to-expand-cool-weather-burns-to-protect-the-environment/105896512</link><description>The success of a small, autumn prescribed burn on WA's south coast has prompted calls to replace the regular program to reduce environmental damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">164585befee231bbcfbedee418ccc7bd</guid></item><item><title>NT's top judge tells government not to interfere with court independence, in leaked email</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/nt-judge-accuses-government-of-interfering-with-court-operations/105904858</link><description>A leaked email shows the Northern Territory's highest-ranking judge wrote to a government department asking it not to interfere with the Supreme Court's independence. A courts spokesperson has since said the email was the result of a misunderstanding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69ad31302102fadb90b3e422f9c25327</guid></item><item><title>Phoebe Litchfield learning from opening partner Alyssa Healy at Women's Cricket World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/phoebe-litchfield-alyssa-healy-womens-cricket-world-cup/105907312</link><description>Alyssa Healy has joined an elite band of women batters with 7,000 international runs, and Australia's captain is giving her brilliant young opening partner something to aim for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a50f38a0dacc4756881494b6edf4d5e</guid></item><item><title>Minister flags compulsory voting in local government elections, 4-year terms amid low voter turnout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/compulsory-voting-flagged-for-wa-local-government-election/105901804</link><description>Voting in council elections could become mandatory in Western Australia if the turnout for this weekend's poll continues to plummet, the local government minister warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90ce7dc5327df5d0b3904814e2638839</guid></item><item><title>Black Swans rowing crew from WA set sights on Head of The Charles Regatta in Boston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/black-swans-rowers-take-on-head-of-the-charles-regatta/105840934</link><description>Former Olympic medallists and a founding member of a platinum-selling band form part of a veteran crew from WA who have set their sights on the world's biggest and most famous rowing race.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7890e76f907f31fe1fe9d3e1d7e724a</guid></item><item><title>Heavy horsemen keep farming traditions alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/heavy-horsemen-keep-farming-traditions-alive/105887988</link><description>Aleks Berzins is farming the land in the same way his grandfather did, using draught horses for jobs now widely done by machines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f47d3bf2b7c8199053c352b6aaf54536</guid></item><item><title>Gulgong woman changes career to honour murder victim Michelle Bright</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/michelle-bright-murder-leads-abby-honeysett-on-forensic-career/105866588</link><description>The murder of Michelle Bright altered Abby-Lee Honeysett's childhood in Gulgong, New South Wales and guided her towards a career in forensic medicine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b220bc940fcd8f7c374cc9f9976a5291</guid></item><item><title>Max Verstappen claims sprint pole ahead of Lando Norris and Oscar Piastri at US F1 Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/f1-max-verstappen-lando-norris-oscar-piastri-us-grand-prix/105907488</link><description>Max Verstappen topples McLaren pair Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris to claim pole position for the sprint race at the United States Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0aead0d7f508abc19c76aa70fab17de8</guid></item><item><title>Coroner finds snakebite death of 11yo Tristian Frahm preventable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/coroner-finds-snakebite-death-of-tristian-frahm-preventable/105907556</link><description>The death of an 11-year-old Queensland boy from a snakebite may have been prevented had he received early medical attention, according to the findings of an inquest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7845efcc529ff7078aaecea2c035d784</guid></item><item><title>Gungahlin United Football Club to fold after losing NPL licence, leaving 2,000 grassroots players club-less</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/gungahlin-united-fc-fold-capital-football-licence-revoke/105907530</link><description>Just last year, the club won the league, and a former president was jailed for stealing $20k. Now they are going to fold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b94409bd3e5cff77f2199cae368e6fbf</guid></item><item><title>Who is Prince Andrew? Why is he giving up his royal title?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/why-prince-andrew-gives-up-royal-titles-duke-of-york/105907380</link><description>The third-born child of Queen Elizabeth II will still be referred to as a prince and is expected to continue living in his Windsor mansion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08536e709980d0a36f65e1774362c22d</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce hasn't quit the Nationals yet but he's got one foot out the door</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/speers-analysis-barnaby-joyce-has-not-quit-the-nationals-yet/105907744</link><description>In declaring he won't be recontesting his lower house seat and letting speculation run that he might jump ship for One Nation, Barnaby Joyce is declaring he's had enough with the Nationals under David Littleproud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f61bd6ea4984b1bc51fdcb3bae580b</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos defeat Crows by 40 points to move closer to winning record as Saints, Dockers and Demons notch victories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/aflw-demons-swans-kangaroos-crows-giants-dockers-blues-saints/105907762</link><description>North Melbourne moves one victory away from equalling the all-time VFL/AFL and AFLW winning record with a 40-point drubbing of Adelaide as St Kilda moves closer to a maiden finals appearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3036c640f5f12f4b89b3526d94476ea</guid></item><item><title>NT chief minister claims tough-on-crime approach has led to 'significant' crime drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/nt-chief-minister-claims-tough-on-crime-led-to-crime-drop/105906588</link><description>NT Chief Minister Lia Finocchiaro says the Country Liberal Party's tough-on-crime approach "is working". But after two teens broke into a play centre and left a trail of destruction, operator Steve Mason is not convinced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ceb1811e211ef03f608859e94141ede6</guid></item><item><title>Chinese Communist Party's Central Committee set for major shake-up at plenum meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/xi-inner-circle-major-shakeup-ccp-meeting-beijing/105885472</link><description>A key meeting of the Chinese Communist Party Central Committee is expected to include a major shake-up of President Xi Jinping's inner circle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41655c3a7bf399a2c8c3669a0f55d79b</guid></item><item><title>Collingwood cult hero Mason Cox not offered new contract for 2026 AFL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/mason-cox-leaves-collingwood-magpies/105907852</link><description>Mason Cox, the first American to become an AFL regular, confirms he will not be with the Magpies in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faaa19652e592fb7fd468bdd25c33d4d</guid></item><item><title>Contact us about ABC's Deep Time project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/deep-time-abc-indigenous-history-contact/105834498</link><description>Do you have a story to share with the ABC's Deep Time project?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba17e42746e20113c5ca22b369962617</guid></item><item><title>Nottingham Forest sack manager Ange Postecoglou immediately after loss to Chelsea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/ange-postecoglou-sacked-nottingham-forest/105908162</link><description>Nottingham Forest sacked the winless manager moments after their 3-0 defeat by Chelsea on Saturday local time, which left the club 17th in the standings and on the brink of slipping into the relegation zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57c551c6fd2ddff4af0d49de00cd0a77</guid></item><item><title>China's economic slowdown has become its diplomatic weapon in the Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/china-economy-pacific-australia-united-states/105884758</link><description>For Australia and the US, the Pacific is no longer a comfortable backyard — it's a battleground of credibility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2b0e48dd4fde1249a89b421640ef595</guid></item><item><title>The deep Indigenous history of Australia deserves to be up in lights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/deep-time-indigenous-history-65000-years/105693082</link><description>We've flipped the script to put Indigenous Australians back at the centre of telling their own stories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1b24be62527f979869b9fe019461e17</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew's decision to give up his titles may have been quietly orchestrated by members of his own family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/is-prince-andrews-decision-enough-to-stem-damage-to-monarchy/105907688</link><description>With the swirl of news around Prince Andrew this week, something had to be done; the question was whether he would do it himself or if his brother would be forced to show him the door.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b77456c907ef9b548850123a9b10fa3e</guid></item><item><title>BOM's first long-range summer forecast shows increased chance of extreme heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/bom-summer-weather-forecast-hot-and-dry-with-high-fire-risk/105899594</link><description>Hot nights coupled with high daytime temperatures could see Australia heading into an extremely hot summer, BOM's first long-range forecast indicates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f141a77feebbff9dd877f9c172a7d949</guid></item><item><title>Native mussel restoration project supported by Victor Harbor community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/mussel-bed-rebuilding-at-encounter-bay-after-algal-bloom/105887684</link><description>Victor Harbor was one of the first areas affected by SA's harmful algal bloom. Now its citizens are funding and supporting research into rebuilding native mussel populations as it looks to the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5482853b2341d466e8d2331ff929036a</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz Kids: Who says trivia is just for grown-ups? It's time to put your thinking cap on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/hard-quiz-kids-weekly-trivia-tom-gleeson/105894882</link><description>Hard Quiz Kids is here again, and we're gifting you a bunch of straightforward questions. Don't embarrass yourself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eae196e3bd245bc87722d2b719e6f741</guid></item><item><title>China's 'special forces'-style tourists packing big itineraries in small budgets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/china-hong-kong-special-forces-style-travel-sleep-mcdonalds/105902602</link><description>Young Chinese tourists with limited time and money are travelling 'special forces'-style — inspired by the efficiency, endurance, and intensity of military units.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecc8983a388385cd9855eaf49fa6fe2b</guid></item><item><title>How Mother Teresa helped Steve Waugh channel his 'power' for children in need</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/steve-waugh-on-meeting-mother-teresa/105671818</link><description>When Steve Waugh retired from cricket, he knew he wanted to use his influence to make a difference. It was meeting Mother Teresa that made him realise his new path.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f532c8e947e73fb6c25eb280850294d</guid></item><item><title>Lando Norris and Oscar Piastri crash in Formula 1 US Grand Prix sprint race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/lando-norris-and-oscar-piastri-collide-in-formula-1-us-sprint/105908518</link><description>Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris have once again made contact with each other in a Formula 1 race, this time taking each other out at the sprint race of the US Grand Prix, just two weeks after their collision in Singapore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0f825561d6966341b8a99ea5341d7a1</guid></item><item><title>Gellung Warl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/gellung-warl/105887694</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf0fe968e72376f9816a5efb2bcd3919</guid></item><item><title>Nyerna Yoorrook Telkuna</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/nyerna-yoorrook-telkuna/105887680</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93e42589db4490a6e86b296e2255f3d6</guid></item><item><title>Nginma Ngainga Wara</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/nginma-ngainga-wara/105887688</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83c32e5e94f6c2ec9f717181d30f1691</guid></item><item><title>Aussie Bird Count brings together students, photographers and nature-lovers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/aussie-bird-count-students-volunteer/105903124</link><description>A primary school teacher is getting her students involved in a volunteer-led bird count, to gather a snapshot of birds across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1902614b6d2d117e4440091bf145ffb</guid></item><item><title>'No Kings' protest crowds gather across the US against Donald Trump's leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/no-kings-protests-across-us-against-donald-trump/105908510</link><description>Organisers say the rallies reflect frustration over the Trump administration's prosecutions of the president's perceived enemies, immigration raids and the sending of troops into US cities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">844c41c111bff92bc93ef28915c54a4f</guid></item><item><title>Cheap energy driven by rooftop solar means larger solar farms could be unviable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/cheap-solar-household-energy-pushing-solar-farms-out-of-market/105898336</link><description>Australia's renewable energy push has resulted in a surge in household solar power. But what does that mean for private solar farms?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36014b920dd1bc4459bb64a96d7ea4d1</guid></item><item><title>Julian Assange seeks 20-year jail term for David Morales, the Spaniard who spied on him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/julian-assange-suggested-sentence-for-david-morales/105908048</link><description>His lawyers suggested the jail term for David Morales, accused of discovery and disclosure of secrets, bribery, money laundering and illegal possession of weapons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d09193e99604a479bc0cc7a2da23e6e</guid></item><item><title>Sheffield Shield round two quick hits: Marnus Labuschagne confirms form ahead of Ashes, Scott Boland bullies and spinners offer reminder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/sheffield-shield-summary-marnus-labuschagne/105907142</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne's magical early season form continues with the bat, Scott Boland and a pair of spinners offer a reminder of their skill, while Sam Konstas turns on the flair at round two of the Sheffield Shield.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">054ff0d8e5945ea2d312a9468fd3278e</guid></item><item><title>Iconic house for sale for only second time in 193-year history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/iconic-house-for-sale-for-only-second-time-in-193-year-history/105838914</link><description>Classical musicians Richard and Suzy Miller count their circa-1832 home as one of their greatest creative achievements as they prepare to leave it for someone else to love.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0cb817277090afe4c3ee03c0a1fb2c2</guid></item><item><title>James Duckworth falls at Almaty Open semi-final stage against Daniil Medvedev</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/james-duckworth-falls-almati-open-semi-final-daniil-medvedev/105908658</link><description>Australian seed-slayer James Duckworth has finally met his match in Almaty, where Daniil Medvedev dug deep to beat him in three sets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0d127a1f537ae19f3d552f01bce600f</guid></item><item><title>North Queensland by-election to provide snapshot of state's politics a year on from LNP victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/qld-hinchinbrook-by-election-analysis/105902784</link><description>The looming by-election in Hinchinbrook will not have a significant impact on the makeup of Queensland parliament, but it will give insight into the state of play of politics a year after the LNP swept to power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">172765f854cdca401a9862668704f49f</guid></item><item><title>Flood mapping is different between councils, but one resident is calling for change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/qld-flood-mapping-local-council-development-ban-petition/105885362</link><description>Ben Parkinson is proud of the five acres he calls home in south-east Queensland, but what is missing is the ability to develop his land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7ccf073b5939120e126c4119a081064</guid></item><item><title>It's been called Canberra's 'forever government' — but ACT Labor's brand is growing tired</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/act-canberra-forever-government-but-labor-brand-growing-tired/105904332</link><description>It's been a year since Canberrans re-elected an ACT Labor government for a seventh consecutive term — but as budget pressures bite, analysts say Labor's stocks are suffering from brand fatigue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ee3cbb31b12feb0dbf9a314f57eeb6d</guid></item><item><title>Social media promotion of raw milk 'misleading and dangerous'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/raw-milk-trend-worries-experts/105636166</link><description>A public health expert says social media content creators are undermining years of scientific research by promoting raw milk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be479a18a9b8b5bd2c9c5515b5b11008</guid></item><item><title>Dodo and iPrimus hack impacts more than 1,600 home internet, email and mobile customers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/dodo-hack-impacts-internet-email-and-mobile-customers/105908674</link><description>More than 1,600 Dodo and iPrimus home internet and mobile customers were impacted by a hack of the telco's email and mobile services, the company confirms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2023f6e78d453f5b1767f6b78873787c</guid></item><item><title>GPs with extra skills who want to work in Tasmania say there are no suitable jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/rural-generalists-tasmanian-health-service-say-no-suitable-jobs/105907346</link><description>Rural generalists are GPs with training in emergency care and one other advanced skill area. While Tasmania has a training program for rural generalists, doctors say their skills are not properly recognised by the Tasmanian Health Service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa38354b32d3f313d4fb620c7e2db87f</guid></item><item><title>International chefs share signature flavours as part of Lambassador program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/international-lambassadors-arrive-in-australia-for-lamb-lessons/105903950</link><description>A delegation of international chefs from 11 countries have landed in Australia to gain a deeper understanding of locally produced Australian lamb.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71e07198c67015e99c324d0292653818</guid></item><item><title>Nationals leader wants Barnaby Joyce to 'stay', amid rumour of One Nation defection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/nationals-littleproud-barnaby-joyce-stay-party-one-nation/105908722</link><description>Announcing he would not re-contest his seat of New England for the Nationals, Barnaby Joyce cited an irreparable breakdown with his party leader David Littleproud. Mr Littleproud says he still wants Mr Joyce to stay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9848481613384650c56cadeda692b7be</guid></item><item><title>National Disruption Group to be established to crush tobacco black market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/national-distruption-group-tobacco-black-market/105908764</link><description>A new "National Disruption Group" will be convened to stamp out the exploding illicit tobacco market and other "converging" threats, the home affairs minister has announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cc3bdda511d1e9aa7bb583dee35ef1e</guid></item><item><title>Five suspected rat poison cases detected in south-east Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/qld-rat-poisoning-symptoms-reported-to-hospitals/105908798</link><description>Queensland Health is investigating after five people were hospitalised with symptoms of ingesting rat poison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17e5b91d5e833fa2e54a07c383a89f60</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou's Nottingham Forest stint a classic case of wrong place, wrong time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/ange-postecoglou-nottingham-forest-wrong-team-brian-clough/105908712</link><description>Ange Postecoglou was on a hiding to nothing at Nottingham Forest, his sacking the result of terrible recruitment and a knee-jerk appointment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0adc426b55b3caeb01dc1561cdfadbc</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan and Afghanistan agree to immediate ceasefire after peace talks in Doha</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/pakistan-afghanistan-agree-to-immediate-ceasefire-doha-talks/105908852</link><description>A week of fierce border clashes has seen the worst violence between the two countries since the Taliban seized power in Kabul in 2021.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ae3ed5418e4616f7f9a9cc4b9feaba5</guid></item><item><title>'Green bans' saved Sydney's historic buildings and taught economists a lesson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/green-bans-sydney-1970s-unions-nimby-yimby-milton-friedman/105903850</link><description>The "green bans" in the 1970s saved many of Australia's historic buildings and our cities are richer for them. But a famous economist didn't like them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abdb337970b734f91db4e99387b96c1a</guid></item><item><title>OC Spray deployed at Melbourne protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/oc-spray-deployed-at-melbourne-protest/105909070</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc0d8d881f3008d3eeb31c0d11da3341</guid></item><item><title>Australian Para Triathlon mixed relay team seal silver at World Triathlon Championship Finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/paratriathlon-relay-seal-silver-at-world-championships/105908976</link><description>Australia's para triathlon mixed relay team sealed a successful week by claiming a sensational silver medal on the final morning of the World Triathlon Championship Finals in Wollongong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9b6a331ee8dec8a3f69255dcf628bf3</guid></item><item><title>Anti-immigration rallies and counter protests held across the country with lower numbers — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/march-for-australia-anti-immigration-counter-protest/105908854</link><description>Demonstrators gathered in cities across the country today, with March for Australia rallies sparking counter protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc46a6a077edb7895f0c0b99d9e04d87</guid></item><item><title>Mollie O'Callaghan crushes 200m short course world record as post-Titmus era begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/mollie-o-callaghan-crushes-200m-short-course-world-record/105909080</link><description>Mollie O'Callghan breaks the women's short course 200m freestyle world record on day two of the World Aquatics Swimming World Cup second leg in Illinois.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6231da4c79de0162d4eb6b705e6680d</guid></item><item><title>Riot police move in</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/riot-police-move-in/105909206</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2a76d910b0fa478e8718288eb2db969</guid></item><item><title>Trent Dalton's Boy Swallows Universe wins the Top 100 Books countdown — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/top-100-books-of-the-21st-century-radio-national-live-updates/105900036</link><description>Trent Dalton's debut novel Boy Swallows Universe has won Radio National's Top 100 Books of the 21st Century countdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a93d820be1134030d36a0450e5827bd4</guid></item><item><title>How Claire's decision to be 'one and done' was rocked by divorce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/how-claire-feels-about-being-one-and-done-after-divorce/105870074</link><description>After a traumatic birth, followed by mental and physical health challenges, Claire was "one and done". But divorce made her think twice about her decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c4071ab0f2b41bc5ba8af85bdc44b4</guid></item><item><title>Tiger snake slides over passenger's foot during a drive on NSW far south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/tiger-snake-encounter-passenger-narooma-rescue/105909112</link><description>A passenger in a car has the fright of his life when a tiger snake slithers across his feet during a drive on the NSW far south coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2664ddc2ecf35a9e1c24c1ee8681b6ac</guid></item><item><title>North Adelaide golf course safeguards fall short, some Kaurna community members say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/liv-golf-aboriginal-heritage-reaction/105908982</link><description>As the Malinauskas government proceeds with its $50 million North Adelaide golf course upgrade, some Kaurna elders are grappling with the prospect that the redevelopment could uncover Aboriginal remains.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9101d5e10e56032ae087ac48805699a</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Reynolds to remain City of Perth Lord Mayor as counting continues in WA local government elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/wa-local-government-election-results-perth-lord-mayor/105905464</link><description>Bruce Reynolds has held onto the title of City of Perth Lord Mayor, while early figures from WA's local government elections show voter turnout is below what authorities hoped for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a54bf02a0f8001516a58239517b18816</guid></item><item><title>Wadeye traditional owners say Yidiyi cultural festival brings community together as 'one family'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/wadeye-nt-yidiyi-festival-2025-brings-community-together/105908796</link><description>Traditional owners of the remote NT Aboriginal community of Wadeye say the community has been brought "together as one family" at this year's Yidiyi cultural festival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d233684dc20b0f2b15cd1d575b533874</guid></item><item><title>Wayne Cheeseman speaks on Melbourne protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/wayne-cheeseman-speaks-on-melbourne-protests/105909574</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ab7ce796eb8aad3dfda4b8de5db0e10</guid></item><item><title>More than $6 million of cocaine and methylamphetamine seized during vehicle stop in southern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/highway-patrol-drug-haul-in-hay-nsw-vehicle-stop/105909462</link><description>Highway patrol stopped the black luxury SUV on a major New South Wales highway for a random drug and alcohol test on Friday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0b12cb731bfba08c1331b8020ab344b</guid></item><item><title>Bulldogs keep finals hopes alive with 66-point Suns trouncing, Lions and Tigers pick up wins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/aflw-bombers-lions-magpies-tigers-suns-bulldogs/105909452</link><description>The Western Bulldogs hammer Gold Coast by 66 points to keep their finals flame flickering, while Brisbane returns to the top four with victory over Essendon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">220f543ca713782ae1e2a21e7e2fa7c0</guid></item><item><title>Tensions erupt on Melbourne streets as opposing immigration rallies held across Australian capitals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/tensions-flare-melb-march-for-australia-anti-immigration-rallies/105908634</link><description>Two Victoria Police officers were hospitalised after violent clashes, while protesters were also arrested following scuffles in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0df5800a61965c627856a41a42a4d2f1</guid></item><item><title>Raúl Fernández wins Australian MotoGP as Jack Miller fails to finish</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/australian-motogp-raul-fernandez-wins-phillip-island/105909524</link><description>Raúl Fernández breaks through for his first MotoGP win, but Australian Jack Miller's race ends in agony at Phillip Island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c694a400ab3702b8a4fad7d55703dad</guid></item><item><title>If we're going cashless, why do we still pay card fees?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/if-we-re-going-cashless-why-do-we-still-pay-card-fees-/105909604</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99d81835be593f4489d729ef0cd5668f</guid></item><item><title>Possible space junk found near Western Australian mine site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/wa-space-debris-reentry-investigation/105909612</link><description>Suspected space debris is believed to have crashed near a WA mine site, with the Australian Transport Safety Bureau confirming the object was not from a commercial aircraft.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07160fd72846f9d8cf600d6423dfba11</guid></item><item><title>Trent Dalton's Boy Swallows Universe wins Radio National's Top 100 Books of the 21st century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/top-100-books-trent-dalton-boy-swallows-universe/105872764</link><description>The results are in — Trent Dalton's Boy Swallows Universe has won Radio National's inaugural Top 100 Books of the 21st Century.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cef78d8d8b4ac4e460acf0badccc758</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Matthew Hauser claims World Triathlon Championship Series crown with Wollongong victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/world-triathlon-championship-finals-matthew-hauser-wins/105909718</link><description>Australia's Matthew Hauser finishes on top of the men's World Triathlon Championship Series standings following his victory on home soil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ae60c8b144ff92de26c1543e5f8d92c</guid></item><item><title>Former March for Australia organiser shut down at latest anti-racism rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/march-for-australia-organiser-attends-anti-racism-rally/105909698</link><description>The organiser of the first March for Australia rally in Adelaide has distanced himself from that movement, attending a counter-protest on Sunday and declaring that "racism just has no place in Australia".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e621febcfc496a432f9bd8ab5fd8ff8</guid></item><item><title>Australia cruises to seven-wicket victory over India in rain-shortened ODI</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/odi-australia-defeats-india-by-seven-wickets-perth/105909904</link><description>Surviving a series of rain delays in Perth, Australia records a seven-wicket win over India in the first of three men's ODI matches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bfda650a8c1f1f7cac905e46ef4fbd7</guid></item><item><title>F1 United States Grand Prix: Oscar Piastri's championship lead trimmed, Max Verstappen beats Lando Norris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/f1-live-united-states-grand-prix-oscar-piastri-lando-norris/105894158</link><description>Max Verstappen has dominated from pole position to claim his fifth grand prix win of the season, as Oscar Piastri's lead of the Formula 1 drivers' championship was trimmed for the fourth consecutive weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bcdd6bd358bd86dd0f6bfeea97ab54e</guid></item><item><title>If AI and crypto aren't bubbles, we could be in big trouble</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/ai-crypto-bubbles-speculative-mania/105884508</link><description>Speculative manias where the first investors win because there isn't a bust are rare occurrences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">283c30df2984a269ddf09fef3456e7d6</guid></item><item><title>Reused signature among string of issues as home owner left with unfinished build</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/reused-signature-among-string-of-failures-on-home-build/105792444</link><description>When Matthew Mapley questioned why the bank had paid his builder for unfinished works, it said it had his written authority — except he hadn't signed it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">145bbaf8d8739f0ee1789f78d179e3e6</guid></item><item><title>How much do you know about Australia's epic 65,000-year history?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/deep-time-first-nations-history-australia/105906578</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7068111e58813c1ec3717ff7a0ba5b0</guid></item><item><title>How much do you really know about Australia's epic 65,000-year history?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/deep-time-indigenous-history-introduction/105907302</link><description>First Nations people have survived and thrived through an ice age and massive landscape changes — as well as sharing the land with giant animals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fac48bc54ea66e8592dfbaf1bfce506</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese's meeting with Donald Trump could hardly be timed better</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/albanese-trump-meeting-timing-critical-minerals/105909072</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is about to set foot inside the gilded cage of the Oval Office — and the timing could hardly be better.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d20e6cfd5af8252e5277f8c4a4af005</guid></item><item><title>Olympic BMX champion Saya Sakakibara still fears racing after brother Kai’s horrific crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/saya-sakakibara-bmx-champ-on-facing-her-fears/105873744</link><description>When Saya Sakakibara saw her brother nearly die in a BMX crash, fear took hold. It nearly broke the star siblings’ Olympic dream.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdae19b5295afb8401bfc230766e6f52</guid></item><item><title>Over a dozen unis are using AI to catch AI — and getting it wrong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/universities-using-ai-to-detect-students-cheating/105905804</link><description>At least a dozen Australian universities are using AI to detect AI. But they're not always catching cheats. Instead, they're wrongly accusing students of academic misconduct.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5ac54c938944764d045af8b0b3883b9</guid></item><item><title>20 per cent HECS cut does not address 'underlying problems', uni students and graduates say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/20-per-cent-off-australian-hecs-debt-but-underlying-problems/105888952</link><description>A 20 per cent reduction on HECS debt is a welcomed relief for some 3 million Australians with a student loan. But those who paid their HECS early or are yet to rack up a debt will miss out on the support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b09ab14b2ad609ce96fc07e9706db7c3</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia's President Prabowo Subianto has just marked one year in office. Here is what has happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/prabowo-subianto-one-year-indonesia-democracy-under-pressure/105899812</link><description>A year after Indonesian President Prabowo Subianto won the election, the families of Indonesians arrested in recent protests are expressing dissatisfaction with his leadership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b83a02a5ebdccb4bcb096e6d4cfd0d6e</guid></item><item><title>Teenager who died by suicide sent final message to Gold Coast health service, but it went unanswered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/neve-wright-gold-coast-health-service-death-calls-investigation/105902752</link><description>The ABC has uncovered the case as part of an examination of Gold Coast Hospital and Health Service's treatment of mental health patients and their suicides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80b94bbccc9715cedfe4fc21a97e430c</guid></item><item><title>Rabbit populations boom in parts of Australia as ideal conditions see pests return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/rabbit-populations-on-rise-in-southern-australia-after-rain/105903702</link><description>A resurgence of rabbit populations following recent rainfall is driving experts to urge for increased control measures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f0b63e3021992436e68289f3f87b2a2</guid></item><item><title>Daniil Medvedev wins Almaty Open, Elena Rybakina closes in on WTA Finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/atp-wta-tours-daniil-medvedev-elena-rybakina-win/105910582</link><description>Daniil Medvedev claims his first ATP Tour tournament win since 2023, while Elena Rybakina's push to reach the WTA Finals gathers momentum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d27928b89915e24efb9812cfeeed4e7</guid></item><item><title>Heatwaves to scorch and increase fire risk in parts of Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/sunny-weather-to-return-following-weekend-hailstorms/105908906</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology is predicting hotter than usual temperatures with a potentially record-breaking forecast for western Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1c87af1461ebfdcca64ed09da13305a</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: PM arrives in Washington DC, Nationals leader confirms he's spoken with Barnaby Joyce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/federal-politics-live-blog-october-20/105910558</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese lands in a wet and windy Washington DC ahead of his meeting with US President Donald Trump, saying "it's wonderful to be here". Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72bc8103d4f91ae0296dacb6042cd595</guid></item><item><title>Live updates: ASX flat as miners and gold stocks retreat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-october-20/105909396</link><description>The ASX has traded sideways despite miners and gold producers being sold off. Follow the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5928ef0e0c4f7a369dea8bcc22702546</guid></item><item><title>All the numbers behind Radio National's Top 100 Books of the 21st century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/top-100-books-radio-national-trent-dalton-numbers/105876550</link><description>The winner for the Top 100 Books has been announced. What do the votes behind it say about us?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eceddbdf78c0567b7386f67a77686872</guid></item><item><title>Millions being spent as Australia prepares for deadly H5 strain of bird flu</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/australia-prepares-for-deadly-h5-strain-of-bird-flu/105906562</link><description>The bird flu outbreak that saw millions of chickens culled and a national shortage of eggs has been declared eradicated, but scientists warn a much deadlier strain of avian influenza could arrive this spring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e83ea2739e1cc6e0699c27dab01c0b6a</guid></item><item><title>Healthscope under fire over proposal to farm millions in employees' tax benefits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/healthscope-proposal-for-workers-tax-benefits-under-fire/105894910</link><description>In-receivership hospital group Healthscope is taking radical steps to stay alive, converting to a charity and proposing to take 90 per cent of a benefit intended to reduce workers' taxable income.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54fe6626e9683e97ff7c755dc0f3b158</guid></item><item><title>Multiple sclerosis support group tries to fill gaps as Northern Territory services dwindle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/multiple-sclerosis-support-group-tries-fill-nt-service-gaps/105839144</link><description>Being diagnosed with multiple sclerosis can often be an isolating experience, and even more so for those in Darwin who lack access to on-the-ground supports. Despite these barriers, a group of local women have created a support group to help fill the service gap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14749aee6ee20b3feba95efcd80cf469</guid></item><item><title>Drone footage reveals Gaza City's destruction as people return home during ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/drone-footage-reveals-gaza-city-destruction/105906708</link><description>One week into the ceasefire in Gaza, Palestinians are returning to destroyed homes and trying to find shelter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3949b76fa29fedb2ce2ac2c7ac488821</guid></item><item><title>England records four-run Women's World Cup win over India to join Australia in semifinals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/cricket-world-cup-england-defeats-india-to-reach-semifinals/105910632</link><description>England secures its Women's World Cup semifinal spot with a tense four-run win over tournament co-host India at Indor's Holkar Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca127f26cc1b519429233a14a7576b44</guid></item><item><title>Tourism dollars roll into Carnamah a year after arrival of big tractor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/worlds-biggest-tractor-tourism-wa-midwest-town-carnamah/105893574</link><description>One year on from its opening, the orange icon has brought people from all over Australia — and the world — to WA's Midwest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e006f37718ddfa2b762776c7387048c2</guid></item><item><title>Police probing claims Prince Andrew tried to smear sexual assault accuser Virginia Giuffre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/police-looking-into-claims-prince-andrew-smear-virginia-giuffre/105910618</link><description>British police say they're probing claims that Prince Andrew asked an officer to dig up dirt for a smear campaign against his sexual assault accuser Virginia Giuffre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e42ba0d11b99fb0e6ffb5ef188a4743</guid></item><item><title>Caravans clog suburban streets sparking calls for new laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/caravan-street-parking-congestion-motion-put-forward-to-state/105905046</link><description>Queensland councils put forward a motion calling on the state government to implement strict laws on caravan street parking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43fef001bb1c8713271d0be4b79c9222</guid></item><item><title>India backs Virat Kohli to rebound after ODI duck against Australia in Perth series opener</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/cricket-odi-india-australia-virat-kohli-duck/105910756</link><description>Virat Kohli failed to score in the opening men's ODI in Perth. However, his India teammates expect their ex-skipper to quickly recapture his best form.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bc80acf1d0f546076475e758c726a92</guid></item><item><title>Holiday from Hospital virtual reality to transport patients to Australia's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/holiday-from-hospital-virtual-reality-program/105904452</link><description>A leukaemia survivor designs a VR program that will help patients travel to some of Australia's iconic locations from their hospital beds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86e927a78d6931f5a5bc765a1bd0349f</guid></item><item><title>Richmond is starting to play good footy. But in AFLW's short season there's no time left to build momentum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/richmond-aflw-short-season-limits-chance-to-build-momentum/105910676</link><description>After a 0-7 start to the season, Richmond are starting to notch wins on the board. But it's too late for much momentum to build in the short women's season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">069e771beb7b5a18b4ca2823e445cde9</guid></item><item><title>Some scientists challenge logic of Victoria's fuel reduction burns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/scientists-challenge-fuel-load-burns-victoria/105666680</link><description>Dry winter conditions have resulted in extra fuel reduction burns in regional Victoria ahead of the fire season. But some scientists are asking if fuel burns are the best way to reduce fire risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24063f01e48736dadc0cd1dc663f5536</guid></item><item><title>Wild weather hits Kununurra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/wild-weather-hits-west-kimberley/105909678</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">748792dce1c226c36b85230daf4fcbf5</guid></item><item><title>Wild weather hits West Kimberley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/wild-weather-hits-west-kimberley/105909692</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac796cb37493edf1acc6c3b15b51a407</guid></item><item><title>F1 standings: Oscar Piastri says too early for McLaren to prioritise drivers as Max Verstappen continues charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/f1-championship-standings-2025-piastri-verstappen-norris/105910856</link><description>Formula 1 championship leader Oscar Piastri says McLaren does not need to prioritise one driver over the other, as four-time world champion Max Verstappen continues to narrow the deficit to both.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6b6dbcdc3ff000bf792dec04e4a387f</guid></item><item><title>New childcare centres might ease waitlists in regional Victoria, but worker shortages endure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/childcare-worker-shortages-regional-victoria/105861138</link><description>Hundreds of children in a regional Victorian city are on childcare waitlists, but centres say they cannot open to full capacity as they struggle to find qualified staff.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f8b17ce3da65fae957a913f9d8b696d</guid></item><item><title>Warning over rare but deadly virus after bat bites Pilbara woman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/pilbara-bat-bite-lyssavirus-treatment/105903464</link><description>A Pilbara resident says an attempt to save a small bat stuck in her house has resulted in painful treatment for a deadly virus that can be passed onto humans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7649b3e7c5d127072e9734a5e6389db2</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr backed by Matildas coach Joe Montemurro to make impact in friendlies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/matildas-sam-kerr-joe-montemurro-wales-england-friendlies/105911490</link><description>Sam Kerr will return to the Matildas fold off the back of limited minutes at Chelsea, but coach Joe Montemurro is confident she will shine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55b775730bad08a65eaa25450f51842f</guid></item><item><title>Mossman sugarcane industry on its last legs as haulage deal ends</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/mossman-sugarcane-mulgrave-mill-transport-costs-too-high/105905656</link><description>A deal between Mossman sugarcane growers and a mill 100 kilometres away has been deemed unviable, leaving farmers without a place to send their product after this season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4f1c7e046b4e98aead821af1d28a44d</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the Louvre jewellery heist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/what-we-know-about-the-louvre-jewellery-heist/105910640</link><description>Here are the details on the items stolen in the Louvre heist that unfolded in broad daylight in Paris.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d269eaf9f556b0ba4f01c08707826645</guid></item><item><title>Vison broadcast on French TV appears to show Louvre thief</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/mobile-vision-purporting-to-show-louvre-thief-/105911652</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6728d820eb0c2de018ff21bbf736d48c</guid></item><item><title>Limp Bizkit bandmates pay tribute to bassist Sam Rivers after death at 48</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/limp-bizkit-bandmates-pay-tribute-to-bassist-sam-rivers/105911436</link><description>Fred Durst takes to social media to say he has shed "gallons of tears" since finding out about the death of his "truly wonderful" bandmate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1d63bc89303f861e3b31723c1277a98</guid></item><item><title>Cargo plane slides off runway at Hong Kong International Airport, two people dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/hong-kong-airport-cargo-plane-crash/105911458</link><description>The flight arriving from Dubai was landing at Hong Kong International Airport when it skidded off the runway, leading to the deaths of two men in a vehicle on the ground, according to police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">949790ffe37f5f7d2047c0e6ac8b0cee</guid></item><item><title>All around us, right across this country, there are windows to the deep past. You just need to know where to look.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/deep-time-indigenous-history-video-tour-australia/105906520</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f50e9a18ffc464ce9259a7b8384258a2</guid></item><item><title>Former Toowoomba Chronicle journalist Peter Hardwick sentenced over indecent treatment of child</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/qld-former-journalist-peter-hardwick-child-indecent-treatment/105911288</link><description>Peter Hardwick is sentenced after pleading guilty to two counts of indecent treatment of a child under the age of 12.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5215ec6b2a4623b1d02131cfd00d22d9</guid></item><item><title>Two ground staff killed after cargo plane slides off the runway at Hong Kong International Airport.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/cargo-plane-hong-kong/105911952</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac76c8269aef59460628e601742bb509</guid></item><item><title>The story of Budj Bim has been handed down for thousands of years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/story-of-budj-bim-handed-down-for-thousands-of-years/105906498</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a104339b1170d68a3dbc3cbda90877b</guid></item><item><title>Murujuga's rock art gallery dates back to more than 40,000 years ago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/murujuga-s-rock-art-gallery-dates-back-40-000-years/105906586</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f1a0ed52440b4bf96b20d9583ec18ed</guid></item><item><title>Live: Deep Time, a story 65,000 years in the making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/deep-time-launch-live-blog/105911270</link><description>ABC's Story Lab team has created an interactive tool to help Australians better understand the ancient history of our continent and its First Nations peoples. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9204ef8f5d9eebc4f3e76e50be4721ac</guid></item><item><title>Shane Wanganeen pleads guilty to criminal neglect following death of son</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/shane-wanganeen-pleads-guilty-to-criminal-neglect/105911944</link><description>A South Australian father has pleaded guilty to the criminal neglect of his seven-year-old son who died after not being treated for pneumonia in 2022. WARNING: Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander readers are advised that this article contains the name of a person who has died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3dddd8946d0112422d50d9ca6f97346</guid></item><item><title>Black Swans rowing crew from WA records win at Head of the Charles Regatta in Boston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/black-swans-rowing-crew-posts-win-at-head-of-the-charles-regatta/105912280</link><description>A group of West Australian former high-level rowers are still in shock after claiming a win at the world's biggest and most famous rowing event — The Head of the Charles Regatta in Boston.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c9029515cc34eb9eab3a0a5e60e4e01</guid></item></channel></rss>