<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 22:52:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>WA government releases business case and images of controversial $217m Burswood racetrack project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/wa-government-releases-images-of-burswood-racetrack-project/106042566</link><description>The deputy premier accuses the Town of Victoria Park of lying to ratepayers over the controversial $217 million entertainment and sporting precinct in Burswood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a7e961be9f631d804104d184430cf6b</guid></item><item><title>Bureau of Meteorology's new boss asked to examine $96.5m bill for website redesign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/bureau-of-meteorology-new-website-cost-blowout-to-96-million/106042202</link><description>Federal Environment Minister Murray Watt has asked the weather agency's new boss to examine how the website's cost and redesign went so wrong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77632c609a2a766464db3db93e3232ff</guid></item><item><title>Draws released for 2026 men's, women's and wheelchair rugby league world cups</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/rlwc-draws-released-2026-mens-womens/106042928</link><description>The draws for next year's rugby league world cups have been confirmed, with a format change on the cards for the men's and women's tournaments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1184e0900d191319d6c4d2b9dbcebb0a</guid></item><item><title>DOGE no longer exists, White House says, after Musk departure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/doge-no-longer-exists-white-house-says/106043076</link><description>The department, established by Donald Trump and once headed up by Elon Musk, promised to slash billions from the US government but has quietly faded into the background in recent months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0d5af77f52a8b16c7fbbaa3a6fe4351</guid></item><item><title>Israel kills top Hezbollah military official Haytham Tabtabai in air strike on Beirut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/israel-target-hezbollah/106043238</link><description>The strike on Lebanon's capital is the first by Israel since June, and follows intensifying attacks on southern Lebanon in recent weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f5c1f41ab674f67b28c8e571a3fbd35</guid></item><item><title>US, Ukraine negotiating 'updated and refined' peace proposal aimed at ending war with Russia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/trump-says-ukraine-zero-gratitude-us-support/106043358</link><description>The US and Ukraine say they have created an "updated and refined peace framework" to end the war with Russia, apparently modifying a Trump-backed plan Kyiv and its allies saw as too sympathetic to Moscow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53b45af3ff6d7d899b82c2b76c376f93</guid></item><item><title>Humanoid robots present an unprecedented dilemma for the economy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/artificial-intelligence-robot-humanoid-workforce-labour-tax-ubi/106034208</link><description>There is now a global race to build humanoids that can walk, talk, reason, lift, carry, fetch, stack and generally operate in a human environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11015f2f3ba4acc558810e73151bbb62</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley faces a fight for her political survival in parliament's final week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/sussan-ley-leadership-liberals-women-angus-taylor-andrew-hastie/105884524</link><description>The optics of rolling the Liberal Party's only woman leader when NSW and Victoria have managed to elevate traditional "small-l liberal" candidates is playing on the minds of some members.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eaee738e013977074c56a612f24dc099</guid></item><item><title>Murray Watt declares 'now or never' for environment laws as parliament stand-off looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/watt-declares-now-or-never-for-environment-laws/106042780</link><description>As politicians converge on Canberra for the last time this year, Labor is determined to pass its environment law reform and insists it will work with either the Coalition or the Greens to do so.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7275f31ad98a6ce8e5713f37f17da866</guid></item><item><title>Teenage boy charged after elderly man slashed during alleged robbery at Lilydale station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/teen-charged-after-elderly-man-slashed-lilydale-station/106043582</link><description>Police allege a 16-year-old boy has slashed an 80-year-old man with a knife while trying to steal his wallet in the car park of the railway station in Melbourne's outer east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d60de161b37f63beaf0725e00d5ecd5</guid></item><item><title>Australia records highest number of aircraft bird strikes in over a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/australian-aircraft-bird-strikes-highest-decade/106011582</link><description>The first recorded bird strike, when a bird collides with an aircraft, was in the United States in 1905 but now they occur almost daily. Last year, Australia recorded the highest number in more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49c4df962a4bb66106a0ba0a422d46f2</guid></item><item><title>Artist Paola Pivi's vibrant new exhibition fills Art Gallery of Western Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/paola-pivi-art-gallery-wa/106020310</link><description>Giant dancing polar bears covered in fluorescent feathers, a three-storey inflatable comic strip and a donkey in a dinghy have taken over the Art Gallery of Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71f3bc034ccf249a9594104d2728bc3e</guid></item><item><title>The democracy ambassadors smashing misconceptions about voting in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/democracy-ambassadors-making-voting-accessible/106016464</link><description>There are a lot of misconceptions about voting, particularly among marginalised groups. But these "democracy ambassadors" are working hard to ensure everyone knows their rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c7d770ef217a228f186aaeed1630f08</guid></item><item><title>The joys and challenges of connecting to nature as a person with disability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/connection-to-nature-hiking-with-disability/106005162</link><description>There are a multitude of physical and mental benefits that come with hiking and connecting with nature — but for people with disability across Australia, accessing the outdoors is often difficult.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da4dcc1038ff1f61c29eeef7c0c7e4f9</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Fina approaches northern West Australian coast at category four status</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/cyclone-fina-kimberley-coast/106037750</link><description>Residents in far-north WA are being warned of expected damaging wind and heavy rain today as Cyclone Fina approaches the Kimberley region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9f67560aae6e23322d1233a6cf38e41</guid></item><item><title>Growing complaints against Sydney shared housing provider ShareSorted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/nsw-complaints-against-sharesorted-affordable-housing-agency/105902466</link><description>A new face of Australia's housing crisis is emerging with companies making lucrative business out of university student tenants desperate to find somewhere to live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4a0e5b224694376679eaca57f5a1020</guid></item><item><title>Iranians fear taps running dry as country faces worst drought in 60 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/iran-facing-worst-drought-in-60-years/106035210</link><description>As Iran suffers through a drought and the president warns the capital could be evacuated, millions are worried about what the future will hold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbdcc6ab5444bc9838633f7144346b5e</guid></item><item><title>Big fines, little paid — the battle in Australia's illicit tobacco market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/illegal-tobacco-industry-millions-in-fines-unpaid-queensland/106030978</link><description>Data obtained in an ABC investigation shows the bulk of fines for selling illicit tobacco — tens of millions of dollars — are not being paid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b916256338855c8b9c2644425100e98</guid></item><item><title>England coach Brendon McCullum urges Ashes calm after first Test loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/england-coach-brendon-mccullum-urges-calm-after-ashes-test-loss/106043608</link><description>Brendon McCullum says England will find itself in trouble if it abandons Bazball now, with the team to double down on its aggressive tactics heading into Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a75de7821250fa7bd59909881e121b01</guid></item><item><title>Infuriated Inverloch community 'still waiting' as FOI reveals years of delay in erosion works</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/inverloch-coastal-erosion-foi-government/105995048</link><description>Inverloch residents are "infuriated" by the Victorian government's delay in spending $3 million in federal funding to help fix coastal erosion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7f453f7f7a27d787d012f8580e8fed3</guid></item><item><title>Calls to end water extraction from Great Artesian Basin before culturally significant springs are lost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/calls-for-end-to-water-extraction-at-great-artesian-basin/106038490</link><description>Environmentalists are calling for mining giant BHP to end its water extraction from the Great Artesian Basin when a major desalination plant is built in South Australia's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fca6049feefb20e454a9a71cee3b252</guid></item><item><title>Aftermath of suspected Israeli strike on Hezbollah leader in Beirut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/aftermath-of-suspected-israeli-strike-on-hezbollah-leader/106043600</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca8150ecbbf8a33843ef00050bb209f1</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Senate resumes after Pauline Hanson wears burka into the upper house — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/federal-politics-live-blog-november-24/106043610</link><description>The Australian Senate has resumed after it was shutdown when One Nation leader Pauline Hanson wore a burka on the floor of the upper house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59fc0e15d531f19470fa5c841384f91e</guid></item><item><title>Soccer journeyman Valentino Yuel travels around the world playing for different clubs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/valentino-yuel-football-player-travels-around-the-world/106003962</link><description>Since becoming a professional, Valentino Yuel has played in Australia's A-League, as well as for clubs in Türkiye, Iran, Qatar, Uzbekistan, Libya and now Hong Kong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f9ffc29427452bc19d6f8ac0542798c</guid></item><item><title>BHP says no takeover deal with Anglo American, ASX 200 gains 1.4pc — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/106042520</link><description>Preliminary talks between miners BHP and Anglo American end without a deal. The ASX rebounds more than 1 per cent after renewed hopes of a December rate cut powered Wall Street higher. Here's how the session played out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d69851811a14426709ca657d186a6827</guid></item><item><title>For people like Benn, the hope of a fairer law on medicinal cannabis is life-changing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/nsw-medicinal-cannabis-driving-bill/106034044</link><description>After years of chronic pain and legal uncertainty, a new bill could finally let NSW patients like Benn drive safely with medicinal cannabis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9819382a2fe6835e8a94246a13f148c</guid></item><item><title>Rubio touts Ukraine talks in Geneva as ‘best’ so far</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/rubio-touts-ukraine-talks-in-geneva-as-best-so-far-/106043594</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dce0ae0cd6bfcde8c5020488b00eecca</guid></item><item><title>Retailers in north-west Victoria fed up with increasing crime rates amid proposed state law change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/mildura-shops-fight-back-against-increasing-retail-crime/105920374</link><description>Retail stores in north-west Victoria are taking their own measures to curb increasing retail crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b81cf56e5289d295379ac18259fe70e</guid></item><item><title>Israeli military video purports to show strike on Beirut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/israeli-military-video-purports-to-show-strike-on-beirut/106043776</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b0fb1258818cd0282552d99f7a9dd7a</guid></item><item><title>Billion-dollar proposal to turn coal seam gas waste into valuable chemicals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/company-announces-plans-for-queensland-brine-processing-plant/106008970</link><description>Five million tonnes of salt could be dumped in ponds over the life of the coal seam gas industry. Now, there could finally be a better solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3d3a80f91eeb5b6c5f53734ecdcae5b</guid></item><item><title>Domestic abuse survivors in PNG have to 'queue in front of the police station' to report their husbands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/png-national-crisis-of-domestic-violence-port-moresby/106017140</link><description>Women are twice as likely to suffer domestic violence in Papua New Guinea compared with the rest of the world, a new report finds. Here's what the country is doing to fix it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a540cb88a5bc95363fd785a4b5df81e1</guid></item><item><title>Australian workers find it harder to change jobs, with concerns AI will cause further disruption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/australians-switching-jobs-as-ai-changes-workforce/106036106</link><description>Australians are finding it harder to change jobs. It comes at a time when artificial intelligence is poised to further disrupt the workforce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">721b43c75d43d74dc0e423af24d2f291</guid></item><item><title>Cristiano Ronaldo scores bicycle kick goal for Al-Nassr in Saudi Pro League</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/cristiano-ronaldo-scores-stunning-bicycle-kick-in-saudi-league/106043828</link><description>Veteran superstar Cristiano Ronaldo responds to a recent high-profile send-off with a brilliant bicycle kick for his Al-Nassr side in the Saudi Pro League.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edf7c4a8a089ddc2345e6c9f5c7c1666</guid></item><item><title>Environmental experts challenge prescribed burn assessment in endangered bird habitat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/prescribed-burn-lit-in-endangered-cockatoo-habitat/106041070</link><description>Environmental and conservation experts in Western Australia challenge claims by Environment Minister Matthew Swinbourn that two endangered bird species were not present in a patch of Great Southern bushland set ablaze.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ae37c4a3556018990629c93b129cf19</guid></item><item><title>What did McLaren do wrong to get Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris disqualified from the Las Vegas F1 Grand Prix?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/what-did-mclaren-do-wrong-at-the-las-vegas-f1-grand-prix/106043812</link><description>McLaren apologises to Norris and Piastri as F1 officials explain why the drivers were disqualified in Las Vegas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2671ab4d067425eab2cc4bd22461f6b1</guid></item><item><title>Fifty kidnapped Catholic school students escape captors in Nigeria, more than 250 still being held</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/nigerian-students-escape-kidnappers-st-marys-school/106043750</link><description>However, more than 250 students and 12 staff members are still being held, in what is one of the worst mass kidnappings ever recorded in the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5f9dc5586bfa5d99273f6c911c507cf</guid></item><item><title>Hinchinbrook candidates reveal key policies amid tough by-election campaign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/queensland-by-election-hinchinbrook-candidates/106028746</link><description>A hard-fought by-election in a north Queensland cane-growing district is growing more heated by the day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64a7d2040f6347d78085a81fe8395e4d</guid></item><item><title>The Wieambilla attack could not have been predicted, but extreme violence can be prevented</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/wieambilla-inquest-findings-trains-violence-recommendations/106042146</link><description>A coronial inquest does not fault police or the government for failing to pick up the curdling paranoia of the deluded Train family, but it does offer some paths forward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a23298d8ee96c11ad089c3515b873ed1</guid></item><item><title>Sustainable and organic wines pique interest of young people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/organic-wine-on-the-rise/106031838</link><description>Central-west New South Wales winemaker Sam Statham has noticed a trend that has nothing to do with price or palate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ef26eee022b81ec4396a6833a726cb0</guid></item><item><title>WA Spud King's newest supermarket revives memories of Kalgoorlie market gardens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/new-supermarket-revives-memories-of-kalgoorlie-market-gardens/106040602</link><description>The opening of a new supermarket franchise in one of Australia's biggest inland cities has revived memories from the past when Kalgoorlie-Boulder was home to at least 35 market gardens, run mostly by European migrant families.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c30282f64a3ba7fa08640ec02731912</guid></item><item><title>Alcoa shelves plans to explore Perth Hills for bauxite mining expansion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/alcoa-shelves-plans-to-explore-perth-hills-for-bauxite-mining/106044264</link><description>US mining giant Alcoa will withdraw part of its plans to expand its mining operations in the world's only jarrah forests, following community concerns around water security and environmental impacts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a44bf494203d43f3d0f84333355f125</guid></item><item><title>Erin Phillips hired as GM to help Gold Coast Suns' struggling AFLW program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/aflw-erin-phillips-hired-gm-gold-coast-suns-womens-program/106044648</link><description>Erin Phillips joins the Gold Coast Suns as the club's new general manager of women's football as she looks to bring a premiership culture to this year's wooden spoon winners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35b477d128fd0c9476ef3364123343b5</guid></item><item><title>Victims of AI deepfakes could sue for emotional damages under new bill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/victims-ai-deepfake-sue-under-david-pocock-bill/106037560</link><description>Australians who share AI deepfakes of another person without consent could be sued or fined under a new bill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbd5d269a8b787b6ae61c471cd090a28</guid></item><item><title>CFS firefighter Peter Curtis dies at scene of Eyre Peninsula blaze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/cfs-firefighter-dies-at-pinkawillinie-conservation-park-blaze/106044594</link><description>Emergency authorities are paying tribute to Country Fire Service firefighter Peter Curtis, who died in the line of duty at a conservation park on South Australia's Eyre Peninsula.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b4cf83fcec37422df0bee5cacf5d735</guid></item><item><title>Fifth person charged with murder over fatal Bega stabbing denied bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/fifth-person-charged-murder-bega-stabbing-death/106044146</link><description>Five people have now been charged with murder over a fatal stabbing on the NSW South Coast, after a 48-year-old man was arrested at a local hospital over the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">150c65dc1cf5e9c45b3fc656be4d5640</guid></item><item><title>History of market gardens in Kalgoorlie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/history-of-market-gardens-in-kalgoorlie/106044550</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02e042170a2b163572d2ad8a2d8a2fc9</guid></item><item><title>SA Police to restart search for 4yo Gus, six mine shafts to be searched</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/sa-new-gus-search/106045082</link><description>SA Police says it will restart its search for four-year-old Gus, who went missing in the state's Mid North almost two months ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32570b3c0f9532750a26f9debdd596d8</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins closes in on second Ashes Test berth, Josh Hazlewood to return 'at some point' in series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/australia-gives-latest-on-injured-pace-aces-hazlewood-cummins/106045008</link><description>Australia coach Andrew McDonald provides an update on sidelined quicks Pat Cummins and Josh Hazlewood ahead of the second Ashes Test at the Gabba.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f41cd57ae64bd410a3b1e2fae3e9f6e7</guid></item><item><title>Half tonne of cocaine retrieved from WA waters off Lancelin, as livestock vessel chief charged</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/lancelin-cocaine-bust-livestock-ship-afp/106045080</link><description>Police charge the chief officer of an international livestock carrier and three others, after half a tonne of cocaine was found floating off Western Australia's coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a64f00ebef23e7559b1008877c04f2bf</guid></item><item><title>ElecraNet to explore alternative options for Northern Transmission Project after farmers voice concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/northern-transmission-line-moved-from-south-australia-mid-north/106045600</link><description>ElectraNet are shifting their focus east, after farmers voiced concerns about renewable energy line Northern Transmission Project running through prime cropping country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87bbcecad36ba980df103634b30e7276</guid></item><item><title>Bendigo secondary school teacher Kirsten Thomas sentenced for raping student</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/bendigo-drama-teacher-kirsten-thomas-rape-jail/106021984</link><description>A Central Victorian drama and dance teacher is handed an 18-month jail term for raping a student at her home following an event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c032c5b39aa928fb51f642b29e3cbdad</guid></item><item><title>How last year's AFLW grand final loss made the Brisbane Lions rethink everything</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/brisbane-lions-with-game-style-for-aflw-grand-final/106046180</link><description>Brisbane returns to the AFLW grand final with a new game plan to tackle the unbeaten, reigning premiers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66c03d2ab340451e2d0d7d1a40a5c888</guid></item><item><title>The Trump presidency could be a priceless gift to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/trump-presidency-could-be-priceless-gift-australia-boyer-lecture/106028102</link><description>Trump cares little for alliances. So his presidency could well offer a priceless gift to Australia: a rare moment when national self-interest can eclipse sentiment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fab117e54e32bb81199e3000b090b31</guid></item><item><title>Port Pirie clean-up efforts continue after thunderstorms slams SA town</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/thunderstorms-slam-port-pirie-clean-up-extreme-weather-sa/106045154</link><description>Port Pirie residents and businesses are picking up the pieces after record-breaking thunderstorms hit town over the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e40c3be172a4e5cc1b74eff0d8200514</guid></item><item><title>In pictures: Berlin metro turns into urban warfare training ground</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/berlin-underground-warfare-training-drills-combat-russia-threat/106044394</link><description>As European security threats grow, German soldiers carry out drills in metro stations to prepare for urban warfare.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">686750acd3a1315be92eeda87cde91e0</guid></item><item><title>Man faces court charged over alleged car theft where toddler was left in a Shepparton car park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/car-theft-shepparton-shop-parking-lot-baby-box-court/106042544</link><description>A man charged over the alleged theft of a car from a supermarket car park which had a toddler inside has faced court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e6fd4bf11ac9d62fd617ad20dfd6e10</guid></item><item><title>NZ has halted access to puberty blockers. What does the rest of the world do?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/nz-halt-access-puberty-blockers-transgender-youth-australia/106036326</link><description>New Zealand has become the latest country to halt access to puberty blockers for young people with gender dysphoria but are they following best health practice or an outlier?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07004f410e596dbe19ea4c0009181e0d</guid></item><item><title>NT Health calls for new facility as Royal Darwin Hospital recovers from Tropical Cyclone Fina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/nt-royal-darwin-hospital-cyclone-fina-damage-government-funding/106045310</link><description>The Northern Territory's largest hospital is "literally creaking at the seams" after Tropical Cyclone Fina, prompting NT Health to call for more federal funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d30d8a698c8fc6d570e5e8735b7e2c4</guid></item><item><title>Severe thunderstorms and hail damage crops in WA's South West and Great Southern</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/south-west-wa-severe-thunderstorms-hail-causes-crop-damage/106044318</link><description>Farmers in southern WA say crops have been destroyed by hail and trees "snapped like matchsticks" during weekend thunderstorms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9901bcf44a39ef7413d69877c9643241</guid></item><item><title>Donald Glover reveals he had a stroke last year which forced him to cancel his New World tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/donald-glover-stroke-tour-cancellation/106046562</link><description>Despite a "really bad pain" in his head, Donald Glover performed a full show before heading to the hospital where he was diagnosed with a stroke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">360bf77f27a3b539d9f12a3845590444</guid></item><item><title>Senate shut down for 1.5 hours after Pauline Hanson's burka stunt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/senate-suspended-after-pauline-hansons-burka-stunt/106047124</link><description>The rare break in proceedings came after One Nation's Pauline Hanson strode into the chamber wearing a burka and then refused to leave after being slapped with a sanction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d6429f3e1262d2f2bb8f4a006772aae</guid></item><item><title>Teenage boy dies in stabbing at reserve near schools in Sydney's Rouse Hill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/teenage-boy-dies-in-stabbing-at-rouse-hill-reserve-sydney/106047158</link><description>NSW Police said two young boys were at a reserve at Rouse Hill when they were approached by three other boys about 4:20pm on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a98c35799035dabe2cc22516c4b5aa9</guid></item><item><title>Australia no guarantee to pick Usman Khawaja for second Ashes Test at Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/usman-khawaja-not-certain-for-second-ashes-test-at-gabba/106047330</link><description>Australia coach Andrew McDonald has failed to guarantee Usman Khawaja will be selected for the second Ashes Test, even if the under-pressure veteran opener is fit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ec38976abf860865945a537227d037c</guid></item><item><title>Bureau of Meteorology boss reveals website rebuild 'approved and funded' by Turnbull government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/bom-website-approved-by-coalition-ceo-says/106047518</link><description>The Bureau of the Meteorology's new chief executive has blamed a "miscommunication" for the furore that has erupted over a costly and controversial website redesign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3e1fd100defb0bfa9853d15887bab14</guid></item><item><title>Trees down at Bribie Island after Monday's storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/trees-down-at-bribie-island/106047544</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1125c7896e05d710d73f4cbc7b3af39</guid></item><item><title>Nikhil Chaudhary becomes first Indian to score Sheffield Shield century in the 2000s</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/nikhil-chaudhary-sheffield-shield-century-tasmania/106047722</link><description>Nikhil Chaudhary has become the first Indian to hit a Sheffield Shield hundred this century, helping put Tasmania in a position of utter dominance against NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47b1a7e563f24158fb103966d98eeb1b</guid></item><item><title>Aerial footage shows inmates on the roof on Banksia Hill Detention Centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/banksia-hill-disturbance-aerial-footage/106047822</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f29792297887e30ba65d7747c0e395db</guid></item><item><title>What is really in a vape?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/what-is-really-in-a-vape-/106047546</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92d6a952ac3d31ad31ba4da39f49a406</guid></item><item><title>Bollywood superstar Dharmendra dies in Mumbai, aged 89</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/bollywood-star-dharmendra-dies-aged-89/106048046</link><description>India's Prime Minister Narendra Modi is one of many to pay tribute to the icon of Indian cinema.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34b22d1d22ba520f5805e3d7d6efc5a1</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Cliff, reggae music pioneer, dies at 81</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/jimmy-cliff-reggae-music-pioneer-dies-at-81/106048100</link><description>Cliff was known for singles You Can Get It If You Really Want It and Many Rivers To Cross, as well as for his cover of Johnny Nash's I Can See Clearly Now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">942c2061a19b7baaa666a14ae1d9e1a1</guid></item><item><title>Cotality Housing Affordability Report shows 'extraordinary rise' in home values</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/housing-unaffordability-reaches-record-levels-in-australia/106044078</link><description>Home prices have risen by almost 50 per cent in the past five years, with more than a decade now needed to save for a standard 20 per cent deposit for a house in most capital cities, according to a new report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38c95cfa820797d880fc1ce28df23757</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos star Ash Riddell wins AFLW best and fairest award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/kangaroos-star-ash-riddell-wins-aflw-best-and-fairest/106047276</link><description>Runner-up to Adelaide's Ebony Marinoff last year, Riddell polled 23 votes to add the league's highest individual honour to her fifth All-Australian selection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4e13d0c58d7930b4fa3c009703f0047</guid></item><item><title>Kim Nok-wan sentenced to life in prison for sexual abuse and exploitation of hundreds of people in South Korea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/kim-nok-wan-jailed-for-life-for-south-korea-cybersex-crime-ring/106048240</link><description>A court in Seoul ruled that Kim Nok-wan's crimes were so grave they warranted his "permanent isolation from society."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5debb180e0cba4962183734008fe9e3c</guid></item><item><title>Volodomyr Zelenskyy warns Ukraine peace plan cannot change borders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/us-ukraine-refined-peace-plan-russia-invasion-europe/106048192</link><description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy warns his country's borders "cannot be changed by force", highlighting a key sticking point in negotiations with the US over a potential peace deal with Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2f57d8e7891cd5275398dacbdbfc1e8</guid></item><item><title>Woman found alive in her coffin at crematorium in Thailand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/woman-found-alive-in-coffin-at-crematorium-in-thailand/106048462</link><description>Temple staff in Thailand were shocked when the woman began knocking from the coffin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd190da0814db7d14915620665584d15</guid></item><item><title>Gaza Humanitarian Foundation closes as ceasefire holds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/gaza-humanitarian-foundation-closes/106048550</link><description>More than 800 Palestinians died in the vicinity of Gaza Humanitarian Foundation aid sites after it took over the distribution of all supplies in the strip in May.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71c7e704943714c236111d0736b4e75a</guid></item><item><title>Gambling ad ban would pass parliament with a conscience vote, Labor MP says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/gambling-advertising-ban-push-multi-partisan-support/106047600</link><description>Macarthur MP Mike Freelander believes the multi-partisan support for restricting gambling advertising means the reforms will "get there" eventually.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e33d844f39e4d1417a89e9b82f0353a</guid></item><item><title>Terminally ill man allegedly abused as a child at Ashley detention centre fights to access records</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/former-ashley-inmate-access-to-records-of-time-in-prison/106046056</link><description>The family of a dying man asked for his records from Tasmania's only youth detention centre, Ashley. They were told it could take eight months — time he does not have.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7212f1db7ad7d1f7718d838f33815e78</guid></item><item><title>Bitcoin crash unsettles financial markets, with 'contagion' fears surfacing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/cryptocurrency-fears-as-bitcoin-crash-unsettles-market/106044010</link><description>It's been a wild ride for bitcoin traders in recent months and, after a weekend of crypto and blockchain enthusiasm at a Sydney convention, sceptics continue to flag the risks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07e1206842ae36c450a4eab1f098a814</guid></item><item><title>Emergency department wait times for mental health patients stretching over 23 hours, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/emergency-wait-times-for-mental-health-stretch-out/106044964</link><description>New data shows some patients with serious mental health conditions have been waiting more than 23 hours for a bed in emergency departments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45ece3d20457fd9ca050c0ac0da5d45b</guid></item><item><title>Why APRA wants to slowly deflate the property bubble</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/apra-wants-to-deflate-australian-property-bubble/106046326</link><description>Amid global warnings of impending financial doom, APRA and the Reserve Bank are far more concerned about a home-grown bubble, one that's been taking in oxygen for almost three decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c8d98576355ba43ca8f264e08a431ae</guid></item><item><title>The 28-point peace plan for Ukraine mostly contains the same points previously made by Moscow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/what-we-know-about-the-28-point-plan-for-peace/106046140</link><description>A detailed look at the 28-point plan — as it has been reported — shows some very minor concessions to Russia. But it mostly contains all the same points that have always been made with more or less force by Moscow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bd44ea75eb058665f413b545a812ea8</guid></item><item><title>Gus search to extend to mine shafts as police vow to 'explore every avenue'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/police-search-mine-shafts-for-missing-boy-gus/106045808</link><description>In their effort to find missing four-year-old Gus, police have vowed "explore every avenue" — which now includes several mine shafts around the property where he disappeared.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab056a0216b3bf70bce39342402eb9c3</guid></item><item><title>Marufa Akter is inspiring Bangladeshi girls in a 'revolution' for women's cricket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/marufa-akter-bangladesh-womens-cricket-revolution/105993656</link><description>From ploughing rice fields during COVID, Marufa Akter’s remarkable rise to Bangladesh cricket star has inspired a generation of girls to take up cricket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09250b5262fc7064211e2f64187fbb7c</guid></item><item><title>Andor and Death by Lightning costumer designer Michael Wilkinson creates worlds with fabric</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/michael-wilkinson-costume-designer-andor-death-by-lightning/103577456</link><description>Michael Wilkinson won an Emmy for his intricate costumes in the celebrated Star Wars series Andor. Now, he is recreating 1880s America for Death By Lightning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d44e7c4f2be635334da31336676aa21</guid></item><item><title>Slain officer's friends don't want to hear Porepunkah gunman Dezi Freeman's name</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/porepunkah-three-months-dezi-freeman-neal-thompson/106022374</link><description>While Porepunkah residents are trying to move on from the tragic deaths of two police officers, there is one person they are eager to forget.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">557ccd7c0972adc5d74f366fc246f985</guid></item><item><title>Sydney architect Anthony Dibden, 78, jailed over 'disturbing' images of child abuse material</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/lane-cove-architect-anthony-dibden-convicted-child-abuse-materia/106045060</link><description>His crimes were so disturbing some police sources described it as the worst case of child abuse material they have ever seen in their careers. The man at the centre of it could be released next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">769deea839070616f3cbd5cfcdd7bb39</guid></item><item><title>Sydney photographer Gavin Libotte captures 'magic in mundane' with Wanderland collection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/sydney-street-photographer-gavin-libotte-wanderland-collection/106005106</link><description>Animals and objects dwarf humans in Gavin Libotte's unique perspective on suburban life, challenging the way we see the familiar world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddc677d641ae0f32a98aeffd59c400c0</guid></item><item><title>Yancoal begins plans to extend life of central Queensland coal mine to 2070</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/yancoal-central-queensland-coal-mine-extension-plans/106037050</link><description>Yancoal begins plans to extend the life of its central Queensland coal mine, which would see roughly 74 million tonnes of coal extracted over the life of the mine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4193c08b972127a904e0a454173cd539</guid></item><item><title>Experts respond to myths and truths around living with migraine and how to get treated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/living-with-migraine-myths-and-truths/106036406</link><description>More than 1,000 people got in touch directly with the ABC to share their experiences with migraine and now the experts have weighed in.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63e05a96e13f6dbab849c8f0314945de</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Pauline Hanson suspended from Senate for seven sitting days over 'disrespectful' burka stunt — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/federal-politics-live-nov-25/106047174</link><description>One Nation leader Pauline Hanson has been censured by the Senate and suspended for seven sitting days, a day after she wore a burka in the chamber to push for the garment's ban. Take a look back at the day's coverage here.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">794169b51c4293e066e74fbde1d44400</guid></item><item><title>Victorian government blocked fire service from pursuing US giant over PFAS contamination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/fire-rescue-victoria-pfas-3m-lawsuit-blocked-state-government/106044128</link><description>The ABC can reveal that in 2023 the Victorian government blocked Fire Rescue Victoria from pursuing legal action against PFAS manufacturer 3M.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af5e87b33d10b9249f00d5323898e221</guid></item><item><title>Cloncurry copper mine set to inject $17 billion into Queensland's economy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/harmony-gold-green-lights-eva-copper-project-cloncurry/106048642</link><description>South Africa's largest gold producer, Harmony Gold, has officially signed off on a significant outback copper mine that is set to boost Queensland's economy by $17 billion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3aee1dc676faca1ea5427b204f925c7</guid></item><item><title>Ash Riddell credits Kangaroos teammate Jasmine Garner after winning AFLW best and fairest award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/aflw-best-and-fairest-ash-riddell-jasmine-garner-kangaroos/106048756</link><description>Ash Riddell says her close relationship with North Melbourne teammate Jasmine Garner helped her win the AFLW's best and fairest award.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5607eafc02165d17cffa3820a0888ac3</guid></item><item><title>Tiwi Islanders tell of 'pretty terrifying' night as Tropical Cyclone Fina battered homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/nt-tiwi-islands-severe-tropical-cyclone-fina-damage-recovery/106044336</link><description>While Darwin experienced the outer edge of Severe Tropical Cyclone Fina this weekend, the eye of the storm came much closer to the Tiwi Islands. Locals in Wurrumiyanga share their experiences with the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88684b878eac2f3702f5052b8f9e4c63</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of women missing out on program dubbed maternity 'gold standard' care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/midwifery-group-practice-program-gold-standard-care/106044292</link><description>A free "gold standard" antenatal care program is proving hugely popular and successful, but women are scrambling to get access.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e097dedd701ae89c22f4ae1e488f6a86</guid></item><item><title>Bendigo Bank shares dive on money laundering worries, but ASX gains ground — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/asx-markets-business-live-news-25-nov/106048786</link><description>Australian shares gained ground on Tuesday, despite Bendigo and Adelaide Bank shares plunging more than 7 per cent after "deficiencies" in anti-money laundering systems were uncovered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6061900c7330739edff911117da0d170</guid></item><item><title>Thousands remain without power and 11 damaged schools closed after south-east Queensland storms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/residents-without-power-queensland-storms/106048734</link><description>Thousands of households remain without power and 11 state schools are closed after giant hailstones, destructive winds and intense lightning lashed south-east Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96877d27b3b04dca882c586192a585d4</guid></item><item><title>Severe thunderstorms slam southeast Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/severe-thunderstorms-slam-southeast-queensland/106048666</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abdbd6702aa27dc5c5bafd4a2fa9e719</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy explains Kyiv’s position in Ukraine talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/zelenskyy-explains-kyiv-s-position-in-ukraine-talks/106048672</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c48f591456da4fa5d098c3a2192a60dd</guid></item><item><title>More storms predicted amid 'very unsettled' Queensland weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/storms-queensland-very-unsettled-weather-tuesday/106044748</link><description>Storm-battered south-east Queensland is on alert again today while other regions endure a blistering heatwave as instability grips the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94389a8ece67fe8a8fa3ef8fe1c92aea</guid></item><item><title>Pep Guardiola apologises to camera operator after confrontation in Manchester City's Premier League loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/premier-league-pep-guardiola-apologises-camera-operator/106048840</link><description>Manchester City manager Pep Guardiola apologises to a camera operator after an incident during his side's Premier League defeat at Newcastle United.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb039c2d99cb2c23fea8cecb9f2c8f0e</guid></item><item><title>China's regional trade pact bid derails as Australia stalls and Japan tensions deepen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/china-japan-trans-pacific-partnership-australia-trade/106045604</link><description>China's escalating confrontation with Japan is colliding directly with its attempt to join one of the world's most demanding trade agreements.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69e3b2863001d8925873d7711d97d8e3</guid></item><item><title>Will the WA government's 'Perth Park' rebrand of Burswood motorsport precinct win over doubters?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/perth-park-governments-latest-rebranding-street-circuit/106045790</link><description>The WA government will be hoping its second crack at rebranding this project will capture the public's imagination, or it may be back to the drawing board.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50c7e8ecbeb4f4ec81eda17a42f16744</guid></item><item><title>Everton's Idrissa Gueye sent off for slapping teammate Michael Keane in Premier League match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/idrissa-gueye-michael-keane-everton-slap-red-card-premier-league/106048932</link><description>Idrissa Gueye is involved in a heated moment with Michael Keane during Everton's Premier League match against Manchester United.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d6e163678227986bf73960629bcdbd5</guid></item><item><title>Child murderer Bevan Spencer von Einem has short time to live, ABC understands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/sa-bevan-spencer-von-einem-in-yatala-infirmary/106047868</link><description>The ABC understands convicted child murderer Bevan Spencer von Einem has been taken to the Yatala infirmary in Adelaide where he only has a short time to live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">944a183101c1d73208a0e66f883b140c</guid></item><item><title>Historic pay deal with Uber Eats and DoorDash could set minimum pay for gig economy delivery workers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/minimum-wage-for-gig-workers-in-historic-deal-uber-eats-doordash/106048976</link><description>A deal between the Transport Workers Union and Australia's two largest on-demand delivery platforms looks set to rewrite the meaning of gig economy work, if it is approved by the Fair Work Commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40eb03c18c3becf155802cb33a951a6d</guid></item><item><title>Walkabout Creek Hotel from Crocodile Dundee sells after three years on the market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/crocodile-dundee-pub-the-walkabout-creek-hotel-sells/106048772</link><description>Famous worldwide, the Walkabout Creek Hotel has been sold for an undisclosed sum. The previous owners have retired, passing the reins to a young local family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13834599f4cedf0665f16a054f6b1836</guid></item><item><title>How Ash Riddell's rise to become AFLW's best mirrors Kangaroos' dominance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/aflw-ash-riddell-best-and-fairest-north-melbourne-kangaroos/106049038</link><description>Overlooked in multiple drafts before making her debut in 2019, North Melbourne's Ash Riddell is now the best player in the league.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b051580800df3932d5dc39a866fdb856</guid></item><item><title>Townsville man advocates for pancreatic cancer awareness after diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/malcolm-stephens-pancreatic-cancer-awareness-terminal-diagnosis/106028808</link><description>A Townsville man says there were no warning signs before he was told he had terminal cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7921e071781941a4550acd0ae98b079</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios's Australian Open wildcard campaign boosted with Kooyong Classic entry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/kyrgios-australian-open-wildcard-bid-heats-up-with-kooyong-entry/106049462</link><description>Nick Kyrgios's Australian Open wildcard campaign is on in earnest after the former Wimbledon runner-up was announced in the Kooyong Classic exhibition field.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">784d830bb0a03ea0b4a45c5888dcdded</guid></item><item><title>Teen charged with murder over Rouse Hill stabbing faces court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/rouse-hill-stabbing-15-year-old-faces-court/106049804</link><description>The 15-year-old allegedly fatally stabbed a 17-year-old boy on Monday a reserve in Rouse Hill in an "unprovoked attack".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a4157b10d3e9cb85700634a7d080c18</guid></item><item><title>Sister Kate's site to become home to Perth's first Aboriginal aged care facility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/sister-kate-perth-first-aboriginal-aged-care-home/106033104</link><description>The 100-bed facility will be constructed on a site where Stolen Generations were taken to against the will of their parents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02365fa4b61b4f91a0cd6ae1e3a54acc</guid></item><item><title>Joel Cauchi's psychiatrist gave 'wildly inconsistent' evidence, Bondi Junction Westfield attack inquest hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/bondi-junction-westfield-attack-cauchi-psychiatrist-inconsistent/106049828</link><description>The counsel assisting the coroner says Joel Cauchi's former psychiatrist showed an "exceptional level of belligerence and confrontation" at the inquest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fd6784ce1d94d163f9ebeb9679dce60</guid></item><item><title>What's feeding our fascination for murder mysteries and crime series?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/return-to-paradise-cosy-crime-why-we-like-murder-mystery/106019206</link><description>In an era of grim news and uncertainty, audiences are consistently drawn to murder mysteries. But what's behind that enduring fascination for the genre?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c433d85e0e4d20e45dbf82946d8e22c</guid></item><item><title>Bird flu confirmed in elephant seal population at Heard Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/avian-influenza-h5-bird-flu-found-on-heard-island/106050412</link><description>The federal government says testing confirms the presence of avian influenza in samples collected from southern elephant seals on Heard Island — a sub-Antarctic Australian external territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db1909e437b8539ed789301ea69ab7ad</guid></item><item><title>Sydney man avoids jail over $100,000 anti-Israel vandalism spree</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/no-jail-man-alleged-100-000-anti-israel-sydney-crime-spree/106049888</link><description>The court heard Thomas Stojanovski was financially motivated to help fund his illicit substance abuse for an injury he was dealing with at the time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76de88671ba23815b80cc3e047dd769b</guid></item><item><title>Detainees involved in rooftop protest at Banksia Hill detention centre moved to Unit 18</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/banksia-hill-youth-detention-roof-protest-fallout/106049434</link><description>WA's corrective services minister says three of the youths involved in last night's disturbance at Perth's juvenile detention centre have been moved to the notorious Unit 18, as he continued to take a hardline stance on youth detention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bf12a3ddc7783e7b438b8c86672335e</guid></item><item><title>Children removed from Australian-British couple living off-grid in Italian forest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/italian-court-removes-children-off-grid-australian-uk-couple/106049422</link><description>The family's alternative lifestyle came under scrutiny after the British-Australian couple and their three children were hospitalised last year with mushroom poisoning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f228341e12ae3c043f7b7a54adebd34</guid></item><item><title>Nauru president says NZYQ members could go home in interview about secretive deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/nauru-president-says-nzyq-could-go-home-/105982474</link><description>David Adeang said in an interview conducted in Nauruan that members of the NZYQ cohort could be returned to their home countries and suggested Australia should remain partially responsible for finding a longer-term solution for the group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89c364b0307b977adbe565ba87ad5cfc</guid></item><item><title>Cameron Smith trying to relax as he prepares for Australian PGA Championship in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/cameron-smith-australian-pga-championship-preparation/106050692</link><description>Cameron Smith admits he has felt every poor shot and poor round more than ever this season, but he will not reinvent himself to arrest the slide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dca9243ef077f59fb13fd929dfd79e4</guid></item><item><title>Jakarta overtakes Tokyo as world's largest city, according to UN</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/jakarta-overtakes-tokyo-as-worlds-largest-city/106049122</link><description>For decades Tokyo held the title of the most populous city on the planet. Yet the Indonesian and Bangladeshi capitals have overtaken the Japanese megacity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00d1c87a49d7134a4b5a7082ebd15cd2</guid></item><item><title>Superannuation giant Cbus ordered to pay penalty for breaking law over death and disability insurance claims handling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/superannuation-cbus-court-penalty-for-death-disability-claims/106046686</link><description>Superannuation giant Cbus will pay a $23.5 million fine after admitting it breached the law over major delays in its handling of insurance claims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07b2a951c5928e66469310e3b4652c1b</guid></item><item><title>Labor to squeeze public service, sparking warnings of job losses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/labor-to-squeeeze-public-service/106050668</link><description>After it campaigned against a Coalition pledge to cut 41,000 public servants, Labor is ramping up its own efficiency drive in a move expected to cost jobs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5670fcbadb8db958abbf3b9c7651badb</guid></item><item><title>Rare earth element exploration in early stages in SA Mallee region, with more drill testing to come</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/rare-earth-element-exploration-in-murray-mallee-region/106042826</link><description>A publicly listed resources exploration company says it will conduct further testing in early 2026 after initial drill samples show promising results.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7707ba8a5dfea83189e2af94f6e79c1</guid></item><item><title>US revokes immigration status for Myanmar nationals, points to 'sham' elections as progress</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/us-ends-temporary-status-myanmar-nationals-elections-progress/106050086</link><description>The US government is ending the temporary legal status of thousands of Myanmar nationals arguing they can safely return to the war-torn South-East Asian country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c9deb25577ed157e549567b6a12f7d0</guid></item><item><title>TasNetworks says 'large' executive payouts are due to legacy entitlements that no longer exist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/tasnetworks-legacy-entitlement-executive-payouts/106050224</link><description>Tasmania's state-owned electricity distributor says a wave of executives receiving six-figure termination payments will, in the end, save the utility money in the long run.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8772a5f6cef5623b07f721b6e81f141e</guid></item><item><title>Thousands to endure heatwave without power, as Sunshine Coast towns hit by intense storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/sunshine-coast-hail-coolum-storm-heatwave/106049686</link><description>A Queensland coastal town may go without power for days in heatwave conditions as it cleans up after a ferocious storm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ada9be3ed8aa2676d07b3dfc951f7b4</guid></item><item><title>West Coast Eagles draftee Josh Lindsay wants to carry on Troy Selwood's legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/west-coast-eagles-draftee-josh-lindsay-honours-troy-selwood/106051186</link><description>West Coast draftee Josh Lindsay has opened up about the devastation of losing his mentor Troy Selwood, saying the former Brisbane tagger played a vital role in helping him get on an AFL list.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61866e29459853828234c4031eb7c730</guid></item><item><title>How to take care of yourself online postpartum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/taking-care-online-during-postpartum/106045302</link><description>New mum Hannah Gheller says social media became a “shame-inducing tool” during the early postpartum weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc70621ab3e58cbf4f4b7f8ce8d1a3b0</guid></item><item><title>Matthew William Lawson jailed after severing Trae Black's leg in violent City Beach attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/matthew-lawson-jailed-over-attack-on-trae-black-in-city-beach/106051028</link><description>A man who severed a workmate's leg before viciously assaulting him with a demolition hammer during a violent attack in Perth's western suburbs is sentenced to 14 years in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0c6ad1b4fa1591cc77331c141fe2781</guid></item><item><title>Luxury tourism resort Berkeley River Lodge suffers 'significant damage' in Ex-Tropical Cyclone Fina direct hit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/tropical-cyclone-fina-impacts-luxury-resort-berkeley-river-/106050682</link><description>A luxury wilderness resort only accessible by sea and air has been significantly damaged in a direct hit from Ex-Tropical Cyclone Fina, which made landfall in an extremely remote part of WA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">892ce3017b1a66dffc907098cdc0f0f5</guid></item><item><title>Service NSW Centre windows damaged in Dubbo storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/service-nsw-centre-windows-damaged-in-dubbo-storm/106051070</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">835fa0199cf9ea242a81120b3801e176</guid></item><item><title>Damaging winds close Dubbo's Service NSW Centre as severe weather hits inland NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/wild-winds-damage-windows-at-dubbo-service-nsw/106050664</link><description>Wild winds of up to 100 kilometres per hour have battered inland New South Wales, with strong gusts knocking out the windows of a Service NSW building in Dubbo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6d4bf8dcf6ca76346908270ab9cdc5d</guid></item><item><title>Images of a dust storm at Griffith.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/dust-storm-at-griffith/106051020</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f70eed33a6ab326052917e3e926ebfa5</guid></item><item><title>Menulog signs agreement to send users to Uber Eats before ceasing operations in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/menulog-uber-eats-commercial-agreement/106050600</link><description>Uber Eats says a partnership with its fading competitor allows a "smooth transition" for Menulog users as the service delivers its last meals in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07d8e436971c10f2a5b1397e7b0d3868</guid></item><item><title>Vision of the storm that brought trees down near Poona</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/vision-of-the-storm-that-brought-trees-down-near-poona/106051352</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e696a22fc508e0ab7b335be2df38b3ad</guid></item><item><title>Australia's 2026 Census to include new questions on gender and sexuality in expanded topics list</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/2026-census-new-questions-and-topics-explained/106050584</link><description>For the first time, Australia's 2026 Census will ask participants to identify their sexual orientation and gender in a new topic in the population questionnaire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90b26e1dfcb6f2702d68cb842300a7ad</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos star Emma Kearney puts pressure on AFLW rivals to raise standard ahead of third straight grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/aflw-emma-kearney-kangaroos-pressure-rivals-standard/106051694</link><description>Emma Kearney says the pressure is on other clubs in the AFLW to raise their standard to North Melbourne's ahead of the club's third straight grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1d0613388696df99983d0c5e17079e2</guid></item><item><title>South-east Queensland has been lashed by hailstones again – are these storms getting more frequent?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/south-east-queensland-hailstorms-frequency/106049808</link><description>The region has been hit by another round of storms which brought large and even giant hailstones. Is this the new normal?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36df204f4c83d2863c49cb9c647af7a9</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast man dies after alleged one-punch attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/gold-coast-man-dies-after-alleged-one-punch-attack/106051818</link><description>The 62-year-old man died today after spending two days in an intensive care unit. A 32-year-old man has been charged over the incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">823f1500505d5730101218d996198fcc</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins continues recovery by bowling with pink ball ahead of Gabba day-night Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/pat-cummins-second-ashes-test-bowling-with-pink-ball/106051874</link><description>Injured Australian cricketers Pat Cummins and Josh Hazlewood have bowled in the nets as the pace stars attempt to return from injury for the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63dd5ae27f2e2ccce23fbac24decef3b</guid></item><item><title>First issue of Superman becomes most expensive comic ever sold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/first-issue-of-superman-comic-sells-for-record-price/106051860</link><description>The edition was found by three brothers while they were cleaning out their late mother's San Francisco home. Now it has become the most expensive comic ever sold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1d47252d2df42d97b5a81c2d716367d</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce's looming defection could spell trouble for the Nationals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/barnaby-joyce-looming-one-nation-defection/106051980</link><description>At the end of this week, Barnaby Joyce will either confirm his exit from politics or join One Nation — at least, that is the binary choice the maverick former deputy prime minister has set for himself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a523ea49955b58ceaff8f536973c83d3</guid></item><item><title>City of Joondalup councillor Nige Jones cautioned after claiming strip club drink as council travel expense</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/joondalup-council-nige-jones-genuine-mistake-strip-club-drink/106051914</link><description>A local councillor who tried to get reimbursed for a drink he bought at "the best strip club in Australia" during a work trip describes the incident as a "genuine mistake".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a84ee7da483efcb8ac6ed8c5d9f4328d</guid></item><item><title>Family of firefighter who died battling Eyre Peninsula blaze pays tribute to 'great bloke'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/cfs-firefighter-peter-curtis-remembered-family-bushfire-sa/106050654</link><description>Tributes flow for a firefighter who was killed while attending a scrub fire on the Eyre Peninsula over the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fc0fbae68031a71858993e77b35d2e0</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania defeats NSW by an innings for first Sheffield Shield win, Sam Konstas out for 19 in second innings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/tasmania-defeat-nsw-sheffield-shield-match/106052486</link><description>Former Australia batters Sam Konstas and Kurtis Patterson have been dismissed cheaply in NSW's crushing innings and 58-run Sheffield Shield defeat to Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23a793f5c70df78e4e98bdaa42fd6871</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106051108</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2624c057dd8feb2b963c4cc95b7dbe15</guid></item><item><title>Michelle Heyman 'uncomfortable' with missing ALW matches to play for Matildas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/michelle-heyman-uncomfortable-with-missing-alw-for-matildas/106052640</link><description>Michelle Heyman is 'uncomfortable' with the A-League Women continuing without international players as the Matildas prepare for their last matches before the AFC Women's Asian Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b7ddb0ae5088b8fde22bbc0b405eef3</guid></item><item><title>Clean-up bill for asbestos scare at SA schools tipped to exceed $1.5m</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/call-for-retailers-to-pay-for-schools-asbestos-sand-removal/106051882</link><description>SA's Minister for Education, Blair Boyer, is calling on retailers to help pay the climbing clean-up bill for removing coloured sand products linked to the asbestos scare.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c5bd927be26445137dc709c3964c15f</guid></item><item><title>Two climbers rescued, two others found dead on Aoraki, NZ's tallest peak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/nz-mountain-rescue-deaths-aoraki-mount-cook/106052520</link><description>Two climbers have died on Aoraki, New Zealand's tallest mountain, and two others from the same group have been rescued.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">039fc90cf1bbaabe1c80a7c402e9790e</guid></item><item><title>Japan scrambles jets after suspected Chinese drone spotted near Yonaguni island near Taiwan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/japan-scrambles-jets-after-suspected-chinese-drone-taiwan/106052948</link><description>The incident comes amid an ongoing diplomatic spat between Tokyo and Beijing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d245286f823a03451b8cb01e8683f0a9</guid></item><item><title>Trump orders peace envoy to meet Putin in Moscow to progress Ukraine plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/ukraine-wants-zelenskyy-trump-meeting/106053010</link><description>Donald Trump says he has instructed his special envoy, Steve Witkoff, to meet Vladimir Putin in Moscow to discuss a "fine-tuned" peace plan for Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48632deeec18c1e0fac5f290d827e861</guid></item><item><title>Four more arrested in connection with Louvre jewel heist, Paris prosecutor says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/four-more-arrested-in-connection-with-louvre-jewel-heist/106053150</link><description>Four other people were already arrested and placed under formal investigation on October 29 and November 1.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ef453a58747d532d8a9a72a0dcd22ec</guid></item><item><title>FBI to interview Democrats who urged US military to ignore illegal orders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/fbi-requests-interviews-with-six-us-democrats-illegal-orders/106053234</link><description>It comes after the six US politicians appeared in a social media video that Secretary of Defense Pete Hegseth described as "seditious".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16721c73ab5d27a79425abd4cffd72e0</guid></item><item><title>Grieving parents of 4yo boy who drowned in Officer suing Melbourne Water, Cardinia council</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/four-year-old-boy-lagoon-drowning-melbourne-supreme-court/106050926</link><description>The grieving parents of a four-year-old boy who drowned in a suburban lagoon are suing Melbourne Water and a council over the tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aff9abf6537ef911c122a5cd6e11b077</guid></item><item><title>Do you know fact from fiction in the world of forensic science?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/true-crime-quiz/105951756</link><description>Forensics has provided the biggest breakthrough in criminal justice in the last century. It's also become the perfect subject matter for TV crime shows. But do you know forensic facts from fiction? Take our quiz to find out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7baffa04dfa64e068d6df8e2a635d53</guid></item><item><title>How a daughter's 'puzzle' inspired the Polaroid camera and the 'instant photo'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/today-in-history-november-26-polaroid-camera/106017224</link><description>On November 26, 1948, the first Polaroid camera was released commercially, changing photography forever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6720c12f21408ac3b2e4587e8c1eef47</guid></item><item><title>Scammers and dodgy middlemen selling Indonesians a way to win 'war' for an Australian visa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/working-holiday-visa-whv-indonesia-letter-support-scam-sale/106023210</link><description>Thousands of young Indonesians want the chance to come to Australia to work, but first they have to win a visa application "war" that puts them in the sights of scammers and dodgy operators promising them what they want — for a price.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6baf6dc05d2d0def784bd525e533607</guid></item><item><title>Outgoing calls to family, friends from Tasmanian prisons impacted by staff shortages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/tasmania-risdon-prison-staff-shortages-lockdowns/106050432</link><description>The ABC has heard of a five-year-old's distress at being unable to speak with her father in a Tasmanian prison. Workers say that lockdowns due to staff shortages are to blame.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a38e4ae880a12fbeec30c4535d0af4e7</guid></item><item><title>Coalition makes tax cut pitch to young in bid to restore lost credibility among voters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/coalition-makes-tax-cut-pitch-to-young/106052086</link><description>Shadow Treasurer Ted O'Brien will address the National Press Club on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">920bb0d6ddaa67af84054020a35e96d4</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup underdogs India a 'realistic' chance to qualify for World Cup, coach says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/india-womens-asian-cup-qualify-fifa-world/106012642</link><description>Ranked 63rd in the world, India will need to finish ahead of Japan, Vietnam and Chinese Taipei to progress through next year's Women's Asian Cup and have a chance at their first-ever World Cup qualification.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e627e9b4fb9df330f0ec6beabedb9b9</guid></item><item><title>Researchers discover rare blooming flower in Sumatran rainforest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/researchers-discover-rare-blooming-flower-in-sumatran-rainforest/106051904</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb22041e3b17d2f416d686084420475a</guid></item><item><title>A 13-year search for one of the world's rarest flowers in Indonesia ends in a 'magical experience'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/the-13-year-search-for-a-rare-flower-in-indonesia/106047160</link><description>A team of researchers describe the "magical" experience of finding a rare species of flower in bloom deep in the Sumatran rainforest after a 23-hour trek.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">735f50f10a8ed44ebfdc54264135c463</guid></item><item><title>Pope Francis's Popemobile transformed into mobile clinic for Gaza children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/pope-francis-popemobile-becomes-health-clinic-for-gaza-children/106053046</link><description>A former "Popemobile" used by Pope Francis during his 2014 tour of the Holy Land has been transformed into a mobile health clinic for Gaza's children, but Israeli authorities are yet to give permission for it to enter the war-ravaged strip.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1399c355c288fc20a06cb794fdcdf20</guid></item><item><title>TGA says some vitamin B6 to be removed, prescriptions needed after toxicity cases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/tga-confirms-removal-of-toxic-vitamin-b6-from-shelves/106052270</link><description>After a rising number of Australians reported suffering from B6 toxicity, the TGA has been forced to act and remove some supplements from shelves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d525a7dce9ed703c45b28fb6b1a968b4</guid></item><item><title>APY Lands community members disappointed after delay into hearing on governance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/apy-lands-governance-hearing-delayed-indefinitely/106049734</link><description>Anangu Pitjantjatjara Yankunytjatjara (APY) Lands community members have been left disappointed by a last-minute decision to halt a hearing that was set to probe governance issues in the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79e0944f7b835eaf79a7ec71fd278eeb</guid></item><item><title>Police charge second 15yo with murder after fatal stabbing of teenager in Rouse Hill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/police-charge-second-15yo-over-rouse-hill-stabbing/106053318</link><description>A boy is arrested and charged with murder after Riot Squad police raid a home in Rouse Hill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b7f8b1e475732f1dde1aae58350da50</guid></item><item><title>Australia's east to get extreme weather with heat, winds and catastrophic fire danger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/hot-weather-this-wednesday-for-parts-of-eastern-australia/106051666</link><description>Eastern Australia is facing a barrage of extreme weather conditions this week, and for many areas the most intense conditions will arrive today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c71496fc41a2819077fa8210f9189911</guid></item><item><title>Lurker explores fans, obsession and modern fame</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/lurker-explores-fans-obsession-and-modern-fame/106023884</link><description>In a world where celebrities are accessible on social media in a way they never were before, has fame lost its shine? A new film explores the parasitic relationship between stars and their fans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c70ac53d051667db99fbdf46bad1786</guid></item><item><title>Concerns for pollination industry and beekeepers as varroa mite worsens across NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/varroa-mite-impacts-worsen-nsw-beekeepers/106049860</link><description>The cost of treating varroa mite in the beekeeping industry is flowing onto other food growers reliant on pollination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c33923736364bdf0c59ef28764625a87</guid></item><item><title>Minjee Lee wins fourth Greg Norman Medal after 2025 major-winning campaign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/golf-minjee-lee-wins-fourth-greg-norman-medal/106053368</link><description>After winning her third major at the Women's PGA Championship, Minjee Lee caps off the year by claiming Australian golf's highest individual honour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3d3ac85b3862f139f91b66d539d85df</guid></item><item><title>Why tens of thousands of houses ready for construction can't proceed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/new-homes-in-limbo-due-to-lack-of-sewerage-roads-water/106051656</link><description>Four years after buying a housing plot, the Websters' land is still vacant, without a water or sewer connection, and they have now been told to expect those services by 2028.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8f5c6b3bb33e52e8925015be89f0360</guid></item><item><title>Calls for greater financial support as regional apprentices left short-changed while attending TAFE</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/regional-sa-apprentices-travel-accommodation-costs-tafe/106044280</link><description>Regional apprentices are out of pocket for frequent travel and accommodation costs to attend city-based TAFE studies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21b5d9f1369e4a922abaa2efa580faed</guid></item><item><title>Community concerned over proposed Woodlawn waste-to-energy facility at Tarago near Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/sydney-rubbish-waste-to-energy-tarago-concerns/106000072</link><description>Farmers near Tarago in southern New South Wales fear a proposed waste-to-energy incinerator could threaten their health and livelihoods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7021296d33944de1d27ec4a9dd9f17bd</guid></item><item><title>Mine shaft search for Gus expected to resume as locals hold out hope of resolution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/mine-shaft-search-for-missing-boy-gus-continues-near-yunta/106050620</link><description>A renewed police search for missing four-year-old Gus is expected to enter its second day, with no indication of any clues revealed so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73d12e699511d287b9bc1457fbff055b</guid></item><item><title>Smashed solar panels, no power, schools shut as south-east Queensland storm clean-up continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/qld-storms-clean-up-power-outages-school-closures/106050126</link><description>Severe thunderstorms have rolled across south-east Queensland this week, causing widespread power outages, school closures, and restricting phone service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1f7b1257c9fe9b836079c3e80bbaebf</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians left without shelter after Gaza tent cities flood again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/gaza-tent-cities-flood-again-after-sudden-heavy-rain/106053266</link><description>Heavy rain causes significant flooding in Gaza, with thousands of Palestinians living in tents bearing the brunt of the sudden burst of winter weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a8de19235619158a4fb78f6d7b8d58f</guid></item><item><title>Storms to continue across Queensland in 'hot, humid, unsettled' weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/wednesday-queensland-weather-storms-heatwave/106050092</link><description>The south-east corner is once again bracing for severe storms for the third day in a row, while much of Queensland is sweltering under humid heatwave conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f01c82134dff49da61594cb434824a29</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: Jim Chalmers denies he directed public service to make cuts to find savings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/federal-politics-live-november-26/106052136</link><description>Jim Chalmers has denied he asked federal departments to cut staff and slash budgets after the government requested savings be found. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b44b2ab0c55c2d579cd58da9f6d92784</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners travel to Darwin as fight over aquifer reaches NT Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/nt-court-challenge-mataranka-water-allocation-plan-river/106049348</link><description>Dozens of Aboriginal Territorians from remote communities travelled to Darwin where they stand alongside Environment Centre NT in a bid to axe a controversial water allocation plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcfc162e595d6f9121ad6715fd34d9f2</guid></item><item><title>Heavy rain floods camp for displaced Palestinians in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/heavy-rain-floods-camp-for-displaced-palestinians-in-gaza/106053434</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67bd86b4d10b6d331c11f84231b20e1b</guid></item><item><title>Scientists and Indigenous rangers partner up in trial restoration of Great Barrier Reef</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/ceramics-and-floating-pools-used-in-battle-to-save-reef/106018712</link><description>From growing baby coral in floating pools to using Indigenous cultural knowledge, this trial hopes to regrow the Great Barrier Reef.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9219de6dff40615e1df6a4674cfa047f</guid></item><item><title>Strikers pip Heat in final-ball WBBL thriller to record six-wicket win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/wbbl-cricket-adelaide-strikers-brisbane-heat/106053508</link><description>With scores ties before the last delivery of the match, the Adelaide Strikers pull off a tense victory over the struggling Brisbane Heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05ef4937d0f2b73fad1e699eb3773e18</guid></item><item><title>Schools close as hot weather and dangerous fire conditions forecast across NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/nsw-schools-close-amid-catastrophic-fire-danger/106053408</link><description>Dozens of schools across NSW are forced to close as a combination of severe weather conditions creates dangerous fire conditions not seen in years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbcc03333920259aa4d3101f280f2572</guid></item><item><title>Residents, developers, investors camp out to secure blocks of land in Broome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/residents-investors-sleep-out-broome-land-release/106050212</link><description>A number of people slept in front of a real estate office in Western Australia's far north on Monday night in an attempt to purchase a block of land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f634b1c32babf17fe653e8a5b965234c</guid></item><item><title>Markets live: ASX likely to rise sharply and Wall Street rises on bets of December interest rate cut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/asx-markets-business-live-news-november-26/106053476</link><description>The Australian share market is likely to begin its day with strong gains following an upbeat session on Wall Street due to the odds of a December interest rate cut jumping above 80 per cent. Meanwhile, prices have fallen sharply on reports of Ukraine's intention to enter into a US-brokered peace deal with Russia. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e62a0a3201d896933b2fefbb245960b</guid></item><item><title>Family forced to flee Yarraville house after suspicious fire takes hold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/family-rescued-during-melbourne-house-fire/106053486</link><description>Police believe arsonists targeted a home in Melbourne's inner west overnight, forcing a family to flee the property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab35c1f3dde055276dcd22054ab51878</guid></item><item><title>Opposition leader speaks on Hollie Hughes' resignation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/opposition-leader-speaks-on-hollie-hughes-resignation-/106053554</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee336fcc9bdcac67b67611ca867499ef</guid></item><item><title>Trump says Ukraine peace deal is ‘close’</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/trump-says-ukraine-peace-deal-is-close-/106053404</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6508b6301bbab8aee8451cbe97153df6</guid></item><item><title>Central Queensland Fitzroy Resources coal mine sale secures 1,000 jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/queensland-company-buys-coal-miner-fitzroy-resources/106053568</link><description>A newly formed Queensland company has taken over a majority shareholding in a Bowen Basin coal mine, securing 1,000 jobs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd24bc63099c1ce6edf63b2942ee4dce</guid></item><item><title>Ley listening to women as she develops platform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/ley-listening-to-women-as-she-develops-platform/106053696</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94913a9f44dc2440c3c35c886b7af829</guid></item><item><title>Polystyrene boxes blown in high winds cause damage in Mango Hill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/polystyrene-boxes-blown-in-high-winds-cause-damage-in-mango-hill/106053688</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">389bd03980ba0c420ef0eefbe9a1e678</guid></item><item><title>Mother sentenced to life in prison for New Zealand's 'suitcase murders'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/mother-sentenced-life-in-prison-new-zealand-suitcase-murders/106053690</link><description>A mother who murdered her two children and stuffed them into suitcases stashed inside a storage locker is sentenced to life imprisonment in New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c80586926f7a364ccd40b478fb69653c</guid></item><item><title>Cristiano Ronaldo set to avoid World Cup ban as FIFA confirms draw shake-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/world-cup-cristiano-ronaldo-set-to-avoid-ban/106053604</link><description>Cristiano Ronaldo will likely avoid missing any Portugal matches at the men's World Cup, despite receiving a red card in a qualifier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6045e87725251c6040bb21cb8484d6d</guid></item><item><title>NT Integrity and Ethics Commissioner established amid opposition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/nt-integrity-and-ethic-commissioner-established-icac-parliament/106051172</link><description>The Northern Territory parliament has passed a bill creating an Integrity and Ethics Commissioner. It will take responsibility for four integrity bodies in the territory, including the anti-corruption watchdog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be5abcc402fa64ab4d6131d36017cc47</guid></item><item><title>Invasive Species Council blames government for booming rabbit numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/rabbit-boom-invasive-species-council-blames-government/106050286</link><description>Landholders across Australia say rabbit numbers in some areas are at levels never seen before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">668c4b4bff68a95a2912ec002f5026a8</guid></item><item><title>'We're not asking every department to cut their staff by 5 per cent': Chalmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/not-asking-every-department-to-cut-their-staff-by-5-per-cent/106053664</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96dde899e7581e9f667a58e12a90323d</guid></item><item><title>Optus investigating 'significant' outage in Frankston and the Mornington Peninsula</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/mornington-peninsula-frankston-optus-service-outage/106053774</link><description>Calls to emergency services have been impacted by the outage, the telco confirmed, with more than 14,000 customers affected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e98c33eba71aba9658d164a036c665b4</guid></item><item><title>Sir Richard Branson's wife Joan Templeman dies aged 80</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/joan-templeman-wife-richard-branson-dies-age-80/106053422</link><description>A down-to-earth Scottish woman who preferred to stay out of the spotlight, Templeman was frequently credited by Branson as a stabilising force on his career, providing a counter-balance to his extravagant personality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb99404a4a1a51da8898c13a2d1aa457</guid></item></channel></rss>