<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 23:13:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>USA beats Canada in overtime to end 46-year gold medal drought</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/winter-olympics-day-16-live-updates-indra-brown/106372016</link><description>Team USA beats Canada 2-1 in overtime to win the country's first men's ice hockey gold medal since 1980 in the last event of the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games, after Australian 16-year-old Indra Brown finishes fifth in the freeski halfpipe final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf4fef30a439dba6841e8f6da19912f4</guid></item><item><title>Coalition calls to criminalise assistance to ISIS-linked Australians seeking to return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-22/calls-to-criminalise-assistance-to-isis-linked-australians/106373812</link><description>The federal opposition proposes a new criminal offence to punish those who help Australians with links to Islamic State to return home, accusing the government of being complacent about the possible return of 34 wives and children of former fighters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22737ed2a7264d24948e5baf55fd9cb3</guid></item><item><title>Victorian IT projects blow out by $1.25bn over a decade, government data shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/victorian-government-it-ict-project-budget-timeframe-increase/106310548</link><description>Hundreds of Victorian IT projects have together blown out by more than $1.25 billion in the last decade, with some suffering years-long delays, as experts question whether taxpayers are getting value for money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73c47ba622e9b95baaf11006993d3e86</guid></item><item><title>Australian Antarctic Program relies on ice runway at Wilkins Aerodrome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/ice-runway-wilkins-aerodrome-australian-antarctic-program/106369198</link><description>The ice runway at Wilkins Aerodrome is a critical asset in the Australian Antarctic Program, but getting it ready for flights is nothing short of extreme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8c0ef758fa888d872b5a9505e1c4d00</guid></item><item><title>Micro-interventions to reduce stress in your day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/small-interventions-to-help-relieve-or-reduce-stress/106354572</link><description>Experts say we don't need to overhaul our lives to reduce our stress effectively. Here are some tips you can use right now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e0daa9fa68a0484a3e03818686a4267</guid></item><item><title>Simon Gordon's endometriosis surgeries were gynaecology's open secret. Now colleagues and patients are speaking out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/endometriosis-gynaecologist-simon-gordon-complaints-four-corners/106361726</link><description>Complaints had been made about this gynaecologist for years. Only when hospital management discovered that Four Corners was looking into his practice, did it start investigating further.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">546c584366e52080d406c7acee3f13ac</guid></item><item><title>Albanese changes tune on immigration and 'ISIS brides' as One Nation effect hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/one-nation-coalition-labor-isis-brides/106369478</link><description>A lot has been written about One Nation cannibalising the Coalition's vote, but less attention has been given to how the rise of the once-fringe party is also activating Labor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8211d1541a72fd4ec12b613f76841ed</guid></item><item><title>Reducing inequality means taxing capital more — including inheritances</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/reducing-inequality-means-taxing-capital-more/106369480</link><description>Intergenerational inequality will only be dealt with by taxing the people that have the money, not by cutting the taxes of those who don't have it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44b5a5f423885727fd91c6525a98d8c9</guid></item><item><title>Home owners struggle as insurance premiums rise more than 50 per cent in five years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/home-insurance-premiums-increase-51-per-cent-in-five-years/106308824</link><description>Home insurance premiums continue to rise, with properties in natural disaster-prone areas paying the most.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26e5815da54050b913be5dc0278140a0</guid></item><item><title>Three-year wait for national criminal history checker makes parents 'sick'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/working-with-children-check-parents-sick/106370632</link><description>A key government commitment to protect children from sexual predators will not be "fully functional" for at least three years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ef6a6547bd96861340c2a14311ce45d</guid></item><item><title>Arab and Muslim nations condemn Mike Huckabee's suggestion Israel could claim biblical right to territory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/arab-muslim-nations-condemn-us-ambassador-comments/106374092</link><description>Mike Huckabee suggests Israel could claim a biblical right to territory far beyond its borders in the Middle East.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44a371a1a79bb3c2f684a2b60ce8bfc8</guid></item><item><title>Marshall Islands launches first universal basic income scheme to stop outward migration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/marshall-islands-launches-first-ever-ubi-scheme/106363230</link><description>Citizens of the Marshall Islands will receive "free money" as the government launches a world-first universal basic income scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8121cbae8fdb05c2899cdba536aa36b</guid></item><item><title>Four years after an election defining promise, practitioners say the SA health system is still struggling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/sa-health-system-continues-to-struggle/106363666</link><description>It was the key promise of the 2022 SA Labor campaign: fix the ramping crisis. But four years on, the state's health system continues to buckle under never ending pressure, according to those on the frontline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49206904afe712b3cb177203ea8c56d4</guid></item><item><title>Andrew's arrest leaves questions for Sarah Ferguson but daughters could be protected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/the-future-of-sarah-ferguson-and-princesses-beatrice-and-eugenie/106368232</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's arrest has cast another long shadow over the York family. While his ex-wife, Sarah Ferguson, has vanished from public view, their daughters Beatrice and Eugenie face an uncertain future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98853504bf3e6f3631be59392fa5b973</guid></item><item><title>Film about new mother wins as Tropfest returns to Sydney with crowd of 35,000</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/nsw-tropfest-resurrected-results/106372220</link><description>Out of more than 700 entries, only 16 shorts made the premiere, but it was Sydney mum Lianne Mackessy who won the $50,000 award.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1394a433ae586fbcc962d8ff06197793</guid></item><item><title>From OKCupid to community wedding: Jackie and Aimee's love story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/love-story-jackie-aimee-sydney-gay-lesbian-mardi-gras/106359548</link><description>Neither Jackie nor Aimee wanted something serious when they met, but a COVID-19 lockdown helped them take the plunge. Now they're married, and had to tackle the "in sickness and health" part of their vows sooner than they expected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8db8d9d1a454d94b7a7f004f04535e01</guid></item><item><title>Eight rescued from floodwater as severe weather warning continues for western Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/severe-weather-flood-warning-western-queensland/106373516</link><description>A tropical low is sitting over the south-eastern part of the Northern Territory, bringing the risk of heavy rainfall to parts of western Queensland that are already flooding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e87f07279e89161db752ab6870018f7</guid></item><item><title>ASX slides, gold jumps and bitcoin slumps as Trump's new regime hits — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/106373894</link><description>The ASX lost ground across the session as concerns about the new tariff regime hit home and disappointing results were punished.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f6fd3ee9ed165ea66f5a57e1239ab74</guid></item><item><title>South Africa defeats India in T20 World Cup Super Eight by 76 runs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/south-africa-defeats-india-in-t20-world-cup-super-eight/106374804</link><description>South Africa bulldozed defending champions India by 76 runs in their Super Eight group one clash in the T20 World Cup, underlining their title credentials and sending a strong signal to their rivals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7ed58870a1d6e4bc5dc7eb957bf5427</guid></item><item><title>Coalition's approach to IS-linked families 'extraordinary', NGO says — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/federal-politics-albanese-taylor-labor-coalition-february-23-/106368876</link><description>Save the Children calls on political parties to "dial down the political rhetoric" and says no Australian child should be left "stranded".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b324f70376be8367c14e4b7253702d1e</guid></item><item><title>Mum of missing Windale man fears son murdered after hospital discharge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/andrew-dumbrell-mum-fears-son-murdered/106357520</link><description>The mother of a mentally ill man who went missing after he was discharged from hospital reveals she fears her son was murdered, having found a video on his phone showing a man threatening to kill him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77f2d84b6270233d5344ee9c87c9e965</guid></item><item><title>BAFTAs Film winners: Robert Aramayo wins best leading actor, Aussies miss out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/bafta-winners-key-moments-best-actor-upset/106368824</link><description>British actor Robert Aramayo has beaten frontrunners Timothée Chalamet and Leonardo DiCaprio to take the leading actor BAFTA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1433445240a650817b8aadb64bbfa76e</guid></item><item><title>Mount Gambier man given three months to live documents battle with rare lymphoma</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/mount-gambier-man-ben-whitehead-lymphoma-battle/106358942</link><description>Mount Gambier man Ben Whitehead's world changed when he was diagnosed with lymphoma and initially given three months to live, but he's doing his best to stay positive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5780e1ceb108b1454083b68992c2b911</guid></item><item><title>Matildas Sam Kerr and Mary Fowler receive boost before Asian Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/sam-kerr-mary-fowler-matildas-asian-cup-boost/106374902</link><description>Australia's two superstar Matildas will fly home for the Women's Asian Cup in buoyant mood after Mary Fowler made her first start in 315 days and Sam Kerr proved once again she's the queen of the FA Cup with a smartly taken goal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28734bf459e7285c48e325391e7635f3</guid></item><item><title>Opening of Midland Station marks end of Labor's flagship Metronet project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/midland-station-opening-marks-end-of-metronet/106372158</link><description>The completion of the new Midland train station brings an end to Labor's landmark Metronet project. At a cost of $15 billion, the project's final test now begins — whether West Australians believe it was money well spent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f006486452fff3d440a6117f9ae927a0</guid></item><item><title>Alleged car thieves charged as police bust high-tech Melbourne syndicate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/victoria-police-alleged-car-theft-syndicate-melbourne/106374872</link><description>Four men have been charged and more than 20 vehicles recovered by police as part of an investigation into a series of high-end car thefts across Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00c4fc0a75fd1074daa5c514df959052</guid></item><item><title>Australia's golden 2026 Winter Olympic Games could just be the latest step towards sustained glory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/australia-s-most-successful-winter-olympic-games/106374682</link><description>Australia's medal-filled 2026 Winter Olympics campaign will live long in the memory. Not as the peak of this sunburned nation's snowy achievements, though. Just the beginning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">159f4c3efe19b2b2305545869a4455ae</guid></item><item><title>Disposable cameras in focus for Perth photography project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/disposable-camera-project-perth-northbridge-common/106337692</link><description>A unique community exhibition in Perth is celebrating the "messiness and spontaneity" of the disposable camera.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61bfde116a91127ff739dc100ce528a5</guid></item><item><title>Micro-abattoir gives Kimberley cattle producer 'alternative' when markets get tough</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/micro-abattoir-new-path-kimberley-producer/106367438</link><description>West Australian cattle producers are turning to on-farm abattoirs to secure their supply chain from paddock to plate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac4fc8d41076b19586404de9c257680</guid></item><item><title>'Tough road ahead' for Burleigh Bears player Jacek McLaurin hospitalised by tackle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/burleigh-bears-jacek-mclaurin-hospitalised-tackle/106374948</link><description>Burleigh Bears outside back Jacek McLaurin was rushed to Princess Alexandra Hospital in Brisbane on Saturday and remains in a critical condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c604450f3e3601d08b95551b7120f53d</guid></item><item><title>For the Olympics to remain relevant, it is essential it embraces sustainability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/olympic-games-relevant-sustainability/106374848</link><description>Olympic Games chief executive Christophe Dubi tells ABC Sport that in order for the Olympics to remain relevant, it simply has to embrace sustainable practices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e0b88796cec3f7d546896144f8e3b64</guid></item><item><title>Homicide detectives investigate death at University Hospital Geelong mental health facility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/victoria-geelong-hospital-death/106375128</link><description>Officers have found a 31-year-old man dead at the Swanston Centre in Geelong, with another man at the facility currently being kept under police guard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85553b1e391e097cb5a96c8b5309f10a</guid></item><item><title>Mexican army kills 'El Mencho', leader of powerful Jalisco New Generation cartel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/cartel-boss-el-mencho-killed-by-mexican-army/106375040</link><description>Powerful Mexican drug lord Nemesio Oseguera Cervantes, known as "El Mencho", is killed in a military raid, sparking a wave of unrest and violence in several Mexican states.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f04b5e4339182072b655d11a426e6f02</guid></item><item><title>Police scour bushland for kidnapped Sydney man Chris Baghsarian</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/police-search-glenorie-bushland-for-kidnapped-chris-baghsarian/106374950</link><description>Police officers are scouring dense bushland in Sydney's north-west for the missing 85-year-old grandfather, following a police operation overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9131aac5977e0d02c076f3c6cbd5a249</guid></item><item><title>Reef researchers explore polyp prototypes to promote coral larvae settlement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/architecture-research-builds-structures-for-coral-settlement/106365276</link><description>Discovering what structure, material and colour is the most attractive for picky coral larvae could help bolster reef restoration and management efforts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">656cde68bcf26aefaa9775da995c22a8</guid></item><item><title>Scone breaks daily rainfall record in 2 hours but farmers say more is needed to rid region of drought</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/scone-breaks-daily-rainfall-record-in-two-hours/106374816</link><description>A NSW town in the grips of a dry spell breaks its daily rainfall record, but farmers say much more rain is needed to save the season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d447d62e4f137be8e55140c66db199c</guid></item><item><title>ACT Brumbies keeping cool after historic win over Crusaders in Christchurch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/act-brumbies-keeping-cool-after-historic-win-over-crusaders/106375922</link><description>ACT Brumbies coach Stephen Larkham has said his team "won't get ahead of ourselves" after producing a stunning win over the Crusaders in Christchurch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdf53d7337654e9cd6c959c369163e56</guid></item><item><title>Heavy rain soaks the Barkly and Central Australia, closing roads and inundating cattle stations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/nt-rain-barkly-central-australia-roads-closed-stations-inundated/106375970</link><description>A tropical low circling over south-eastern parts of the Northern Territory is continuing to bring damaging winds and heavy local rainfall in the Simpson and parts of the Barkly and Tanami areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6db61caa4b48c362f565819a981adb8a</guid></item><item><title>How to maintain Antarctica's ice runway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/wilkins-aerodrome-antarctic-runway/106376398</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f7c0416ce1043220b7ff29f053d161a</guid></item><item><title>Denmark and Greenland reject Trump's offer to send naval hospital ship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/denmark-greenland-reject-trump-offer-naval-hospital-ship/106376252</link><description>Denmark and its territory Greenland reject Donald Trump's offer to send a naval hospital ship to the Arctic island coveted by the US leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da6be898edb441a8825b6acb38f78a19</guid></item><item><title>Neighbouring farmers say overwhelming fire risk from Lake Magenta Nature Reserve in WA's south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/farmers-raise-concerns-over-lake-magenta-nature-reserve-fire/106370154</link><description>WA farmer Doug Giles has warned that parts of Lake Magenta Nature Reserve haven't been burned in 25 years, raising fears of a dangerous fire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2867bfbdd2ae8c4f834614c7020a00e2</guid></item><item><title>MAGA figure tells Australian conservatives Angela Merkel did more damage to Germany's fabric than Nazis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/advance-lobby-group-conference-centre-right-mass-immigration/106371720</link><description>Benjamin Harnwell, the "international editor" of Steve Bannon's War Room podcast, says centre-right politicians have "betrayed" the West by supporting "mass immigration".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c036dfffbc94d642235a37ef1b6e3399</guid></item><item><title>Wayne Klingberg avoids jail over crash that killed his employee in rollover near Hamley Bridge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/wayne-klingberg-sentenced-for-killing-employee-in-rollover/106373394</link><description>A man has been spared jail time after his "substandard" driving resulted in a crash that caused the death of his passenger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d7bc8a2fcdc95df3c711a87a46252bb</guid></item><item><title>What experts want you to know about endometriosis, diagnosis and surgery as treatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/endometriosis-surgery-treatment-explained-four-corners/106375904</link><description>Allegations about endometriosis surgery have alarmed experts and distressed women living with the condition. Here's what to know about the chronic disease that affects about one in seven Australian women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbaf9bd04ca59cd113da66ade8586963</guid></item><item><title>Ex-police officer Jonathan Andrew Beard cites 'cop's sixth sense' over allege knock and run assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/jonathan-beard-kings-cross-commander-assault-hearing/106376466</link><description>A former senior Sydney police officer accused of assaulting two men with a baseball bat who played a drunken game of knock and run at his house has told a court he "wasn't there to play" with home invaders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67cb7bed6b105f41f70b392fee95ea8a</guid></item><item><title>Two men charged after man stabbed during confrontation in Kambalda</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/two-men-charged-stabbing-kambalda-wa-goldfields/106376558</link><description>Two men are charged and another is flown to Perth with life-threatening stab wounds, after a weekend altercation in Kambalda.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a765daef73dcbfd6cf5eecd71ab51d08</guid></item><item><title>Darcy Moore downplays Collingwood's injury woes, Patrick Dangerfield optimistic on Jeremy Cameron's health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/afl-darcy-moore-patrick-dangerfield-downplay-pies-cats-injuries/106376972</link><description>Several of Collingwood's defensive stalwarts have suffered interrupted preseasons, but skipper Darcy Moore isn't concerned just yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bf987fc7214ac5f9d00e1721ab4492b</guid></item><item><title>SA pastoralists receive more than 60mm of rain in 24 hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/pastoralists-rain-drought-destocking-south-australia/106375318</link><description>South Australian pastoralists are preparing to buy livestock after the weekend's downpours brought more than 60 millimetres to some areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a993832dd084d2ff3fd4c53c14abfc0b</guid></item><item><title>Cyber attack takes major chicken processor Hazeldenes offline leaving businesses without meat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/cyber-attack-takes-major-chicken-processor-hazeldenes-offline/106376184</link><description>A cyber attack at Hazeldenes chicken processing plant in central Victoria has stalled production and left butchers and pubs across the state without chicken.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad7275d3ac33e822d86835f8e8ca6b93</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man jailed for 20 years for fatally stabbing his ex-wife in 2023</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/van-thanh-vu-jailed-20-years-murder-ex-wife/106375068</link><description>A 73-year-old man who fatally stabbed his former partner in their kitchen in 2023 has been sentenced in the ACT Supreme Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">046788bd6980dd463533c9c0710036bc</guid></item><item><title>Death of Kelly T'Hart inspires shake up of WA driving laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/wa-new-driving-bans-for-people-charged-with-driving-offences/106376430</link><description>Tougher WA driving laws are expected to be introduced to parliament after a drunk driver, who was charged with killing a 32-year-old, was allowed to drive just two months after the incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">865da2fafb865e027a4d14fd8445adfa</guid></item><item><title>Former UK PM Gordon Brown urges police to investigate if Andrew used RAF bases to meet Epstein</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/brown-urges-andrew-police-probe-over-epstein-raf-bases/106375734</link><description>Former British prime minister Gordon Brown urges British police to investigate whether Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor used taxpayer-funded jets and Royal Air Force bases to meet with convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b76c410513462e9b98bba684536256cd</guid></item><item><title>Horse endoscopy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/horse-endoscopy/106363588</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5a63fc0b398c1847ca2bfa97d2d4097</guid></item><item><title>Reo Te Whetu Marama Marsh given life sentence for murdering Mary Benedito on Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/qld-court-reo-te-whetu-marama-marsh-mary-benedito/106375280</link><description>Reo Te Whetu Marama Marsh, who was then 34 years old, was charged In November 2021 over Mary Benedito's death after she was found unresponsive in a Southport apartment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a561aa52664c78d8fb78e4dba685c3e</guid></item><item><title>These four salads are tasty and substantial meals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/these-four-salads-are-tasty-and-substantial-meals/106363054</link><description>If you’re after a healthy and summery dinner, these salads are a meal in a bowl and will tempt even the salad avoiders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b43ee09ed451f0e7f6420ed3472fbdff</guid></item><item><title>Richmond forward Mykelti Lefau suspended for two matches over drink driving charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/afl-mykelti-lefau-suspended-two-matches-drink-driving-charge/106377438</link><description>Mykelti Lefau is banned for two matches after a drink driving charge that will see him miss a pre-season clash as well as round one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c4ea2f9071e3790d91763c3026a1489</guid></item><item><title>Kalgoorlie-Boulder Airport's potential $100m redevelopment on agenda as FIFO activity soars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/kalgoorlie-boulder-airport-expansion-fifo-boom/106368120</link><description>A long-awaited feasibility study investigating the potential for a major expansion, estimated to cost up to $100 million, at one of Western Australia's busiest regional airports, is set to be delivered this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec57aef109eed981158c46ca0aaefcf7</guid></item><item><title>Lesbian group takes fight to Federal Court in bid to exclude transgender women from events</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/lesbian-group-transgender-exemption-federal-court/106375606</link><description>A Victorian-based lesbian group is seeking an exemption to the Sex Discrimination Act so it can legally discriminate against transgender women when it holds public events.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86011188a6449ec4a3f53945d7ead4da</guid></item><item><title>Bodycam footage shows tactical police officers using force on a handcuffed hit-and-run driver</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/body-camera-tactical-police-force-hit-and-run-driver/106377912</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">840067a62466a8723d5a50ce3878a332</guid></item><item><title>Police bodycam footage captures 'retributive' force used on St Edmund's College hit-and-run driver</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/act-tayler-hazell-police-bodycam-footage/106375728</link><description>Body-camera footage released by the ACT Supreme Court shows tactical police officers using force on a handcuffed hit-and-run driver outside St Edmund's College.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bc70d8008462d11e48f5dbd54482057</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106377930</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cd201e4cab12a1e8d9109dec7af0e4f</guid></item><item><title>Toddler found unresponsive at Sydney day care may have died from a bacterial infection, inquest hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/nsw-arianna-maragol-coronial-inquest-family-speaks-bacterial/106377282</link><description>A baby who died after being found unresponsive at a Sydney day care may have had a bacterial infection, an inquest has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfdde31cd10ef6f3a585059f10bac008</guid></item><item><title>SA Police postpone renewed search for missing Andamooka woman Trisha Graf</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/sa-police-scour-mine-shafts-search-for-missing-trisha-graf/106377578</link><description>Heavy rain has forced police to postpone a search for missing mother Trisha Graf in mine shafts near the outback South Australian town of Andamooka.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3ebd687d259d0790dfd4051686dccaa</guid></item><item><title>Arvind Ajay Singh extradited from Fiji to Sunshine Coast on rape charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/arvind-ajay-singh-returns-to-sunshine-coast-faces-rape-charge/106375712</link><description>A Fijian national charged over the alleged rape of a child four years ago returns to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3bfb5887669e3fe34e8697fcf80e78e</guid></item><item><title>Tabatha Badger angling to replace outgoing Greens senator Peter Whish-Wilson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/tabatha-badger-senate-tilt-to-replace-peter-whish-wilson/106377994</link><description>Tasmanian Greens MP Tabatha Badger is among the names vying to replace outgoing federal senator Peter Whish-Wilson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70b94d5a4e222251fa22d9491cae6035</guid></item><item><title>The Lion King musical makes its return to Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/the-lion-king-musical-makes-its-return-to-sydney/106378128</link><description>The Lion King musical makes its return to Sydney in April with the cast and crew opening its doors to rehearsals for a sneak peak.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cd895f5c24c035246533ab2c99be933</guid></item><item><title>Former youth worker Geoffrey Guest pleads not guilty to historical child sex abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/former-youth-worker-pleads-not-guilty-historical-abuse-charges/106376946</link><description>Geoffrey John Guest is standing trial in Cairns after being charged with the abuse of a child in the 1970s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be44341c902da3949f56ff003343bcbf</guid></item><item><title>Met Gala dress code announced as 'Fashion is Art' by New York's Museum of Metropolitan Art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/met-gala-theme-announced-as-fashion-is-art/106378808</link><description>The dress code for this year's Met Gala will be "Fashion is Art", the Metropolitan Museum of Art has announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1f7e332dacb9a78ac86ae62335f8472</guid></item><item><title>Simon Burke on how 19 years of Play School fed into The Elocution of Benjamin Franklin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/simon-burke-the-elocution-of-benjamin-franklin-play-school/106295868</link><description>After five years starring in major musicals, Simon Burke returns to a much smaller stage in a one-man play, on its 50-year anniversary: The Elocution of Benjamin Franklin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4458da0549bbbebe99b63d9648eb25af</guid></item><item><title>What is the difference between a homebirth and a freebirth?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/the-difference-between-a-homebirth-and-a-freebirth/106348232</link><description>Experts say creating awareness around how homebirthing and freebirthing differ is important in helping women make informed and safe decisions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a67b6ee22205e5375e88a384d9be9f5c</guid></item><item><title>Power supply for Macquarie Point stadium not yet costed or planned as key deadlines approach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/macquarie-point-stadium-power-options-uncosted/106377676</link><description>Major upgrades to Hobart's power grid to supply the Macquarie Point stadium are yet to be finalised or costed, with the final estimate for the precinct's energy demand increasing by almost 50 per cent in a year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0619a4ec6a598c4119df3c19a29dfbd9</guid></item><item><title>Trump's dispute with Denmark over Greenland 'far from over', warns intelligence expert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/us-denmark-feud-over-greenland-far-from-over-warns-analyst/106359334</link><description>A former chief analyst with the Danish Defence Intelligence Service warns diplomatic efforts to settle the Greenland dispute will fail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">caf70a88cade8101f8fcb73ba80cc069</guid></item><item><title>Could Canada and Australia form a critical minerals supergroup?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/critical-minerals-future-australia-canada-us-china/106368382</link><description>Canberra's decision to sign a bilateral agreement with Canada to join forces on everything to do with critical minerals could prove to be a forerunner of things to come.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16de728cafe7b3d7ac16ae0851dde9b8</guid></item><item><title>Australian exporters on notice as Trump tariff policy thrown into uncertainty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/australian-exporters-on-notice-as-trump-tariffs-in-chaos/106375716</link><description>Business representatives have warned all Australian exporters they will need to monitor US trade policy carefully over coming weeks and months, as one firm owner estimates tariffs have cost him $1 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0fbfe0f1b5a1ef08dac628ed21a5b5d</guid></item><item><title>Regulator 'dropped the ball' by dismissing complaints about gynaecologist's practices, expert says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/endometriosis-surgeon-simon-gordon-ahpra-complaints-four-corners/106376338</link><description>Australia's medical regulator, AHPRA, faces criticism for failing to act on complaints from patients about surgeries by Melbourne gynaecologist Simon Gordon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37e9c9955acd6273241e064c5b886efb</guid></item><item><title>Urgent care clinics ease emergency department demand but wait times unchanged</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/urgent-care-clinics-not-improving-hospital-wait-times/106377942</link><description>An independent review finds Labor's urgent care clinics face workforce shortages and problems with after-hours services, with no evidence hospital waiting times have improved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75eaec4d09e07adaa39fe8f1d3901729</guid></item><item><title>Matildas coach Joe Montemurro speaks to ABC Sport's Amanda Shalala.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/womens-asian-cup-2026-matildas-coach-joe-montemurro-interview/106372378</link><description>Sport news, live scores, features, analysis and photos from the world of sport. Comprehensive coverage of AFL, cricket, football, rugby league and rugby union. Audio interviews. News stories and highlights in video. Sports news bulletin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffdd65572a90557a39c7eced42c2e030</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup 2026: Matildas coach Joe Montemurro says 'we want to be a dominant force in Asia'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/womens-asian-cup-matildas-coach-joe-montemurro-dominant-force/106372410</link><description>Matildas coach Joe Montemurro, who has had nine months in charge leading into the Women's Asian Cup starting this week, has bold ambitions for the tournament and the future of women's football.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">353674cf248b7dd8c344aab288d0ee1c</guid></item><item><title>Regional Victoria among the worst areas for meth use police say after Shepparton bust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/shepparton-meth-bust/106378988</link><description>Police say methylamphetamine trafficking is "insidious" in regional Victoria, with almost one trafficker a week charged over the past year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c15262d03dacfd37831e0185811140b</guid></item><item><title>DV attacker photographed victim giving evidence, found guilty of contempt of court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/dv-attacker-found-guilty-of-contempt-of-court/106355262</link><description>A man standing trial for domestic violence charges took an image of the victim while she was giving evidence and recorded the prosecutor inside the court building, a court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea7ddb1679b1f9ccf535d4316d5e3bc0</guid></item><item><title>Solomon Islands denies China will run new police station in the heart of the capital Honiara</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/chinese-police-establish-temporary-post-solomon-islands/106376922</link><description>Authorities in Solomon Islands deny claims that Chinese police will run a new police post in Honiara's Chinatown district, but say Chinese police will instead "visit" the site.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa910e93601c07e2ab8d53a1e98a85f8</guid></item><item><title>Trump Tower pitched as Gold Coast magnet for wealthy but others prefer he 'kept himself in America'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/trump-tower-pitched-as-gold-coast-magnet-for-wealthy/106378024</link><description>A $1.5 billion Trump-branded skyscraper proposed for Surfers Paradise is being pitched as a major luxury tourism and investment draw for the Gold Coast, though some locals and visitors say the name could turn people away.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a69bab1944d9db1282ea258b9cc9086</guid></item><item><title>Hope south-east Queensland koala population can recover but advocates remain wary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/qld-koala-recovery-redlands-coast/106310380</link><description>Urbanisation has decimated south east Queensland's koala population, but new analysis suggests the decline has slowed in some areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c368680b2f2c0b62737c0f0724110feb</guid></item><item><title>Nathan Cleary's ban overturned as father acts as counsel at NRL judiciary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/nrl-nathan-cleary-ban-overturned-ivan-cleary-judiciary-counsel/106379116</link><description>Ivan Cleary's legal prowess comes in handy as his son, Panthers star Nathan Cleary, sees his two-match suspension overturned at the NRL judiciary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">124f69f96041c4e00733fb309dc8d7cb</guid></item><item><title>'Australia likes being first': PM defends bid to remove Andrew from succession — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/federal-politics-albanese-taylor-rail-live-blog/106377802</link><description>The prime minister has revealed he voluntarily wrote to his UK counterpart to offer his support for removing Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor from the line of succession.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c81fcafdad0f3b57e85f4602a2b33ee6</guid></item><item><title>Inspection reveals substandard housing for PALM scheme workers in Gippsland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/warragul-substandard-palm-housing/106331606</link><description>Migrant workers in Victoria's east were made to pay $190 a week to their employer for overcrowded, mouldy accommodation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">325b531c1d1e9a8e4a20fedfc3e837c1</guid></item><item><title>Nick Reiner pleads not guilty to murder of parents Rob and Michele Singer Reiner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/nick-reiner-pleads-not-guility-to-first-degree-murder/106379080</link><description>Nick Reiner has pleaded not guilty to two counts of first-degree murder in the fatal stabbing of his parents in December last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72c8efa2b22a2976ca629282d76fd3be</guid></item><item><title>Economist warns rural NSW shires are on the verge of financial ruin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/rural-nsw-councils-warn-of-financial-sustainability-crisis/106358104</link><description>Huge areas, spiralling costs and a small revenue base do not add up for a growing number of councils in NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f098cb9486b6e942d9b878225f901016</guid></item><item><title>ASX mostly flat amid tariff uncertainty on Wall Street — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/asx-markets-business-live-news-february-23-2026/106378530</link><description>With more tariff chaos from US President Donald Trump unsettling stocks globally, the ASX 200 was mostly flat on Tuesday. Look back on our blog from our ABC News business reporters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48fb3e07604fcbb38c9ebe7ae06d0fe3</guid></item><item><title>William Barton on blending the ancient First Nations instrument, the yidaki, with classical music</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/william-barton-yidaki-meet-classical-music-brodsky-quartet/106369492</link><description>Virtuoso William Barton, renowned for bringing together First Nations culture and European classical music, reflects on heritage and the lifelong pull of the yidaki.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18cd76c9661a9eaf25275f3a6f719215</guid></item><item><title>SA wildlife carers help animals hurt in Deep Creek fires as they emerge from refuges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/deep-creek-fire-wildlife-response-animals-south-australia/106334650</link><description>As the firefighters packed up and went home from the recent Deep Creek fires, other volunteers were just starting weeks of work finding injured wildlife in the charred landscape.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3dbf571a4cecf4cc8240f7815633a5d</guid></item><item><title>Alcoa under investigation for alleged breaches of state mining agreement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/alcoa-under-investigation-alleged-breach-state-mining-agreement/106376898</link><description>Just days after being forced to pay $55 million for unlawfully clearing land in the world's only jarrah forest, it is revealed Alcoa is under investigation for alleged breaches of its agreement with the WA government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eedb4193560a4bf3688ea7232bdda222</guid></item><item><title>BAFTA and BBC apologise for racial slur during awards show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/bafta-bbc-apology-racial-slur-awards/106379194</link><description>Tourette syndrome advocate John Davidson, who shouted the slur, says it is not a reflection of his personal beliefs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a7fad65bac06602f873108e4ab20230</guid></item><item><title>Homeless mother refused social housing after Centrelink payments deemed too high</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/homeless-mother-denied-social-housing-queensland/106376802</link><description>Welfare payments are Rissa Blakeley's only source of income, but she and her kids have been left with no choice but to live in a park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98537414ca6a771d738c2f0e9535e226</guid></item><item><title>Shimron Hetmyer blasts West Indies to record T20 World Cup score in win over Zimbabwe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/cricket-t20-world-cup-shimron-hetmyer-creates-west-indies-record/106379260</link><description>Shimron Hetmyer takes advantage of a dropped chance to blast his way to 85 as the West Indies maintain their unbeaten record at this year's T20 World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30debec237ed46aaceb6c212f28eafee</guid></item><item><title>Volunteer firefighters wasting hours 'babysitting' pole-top fires waiting for Western Power crews</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/pole-top-fires-firefighter-concern-western-power/106358052</link><description>Volunteer firefighters in regional Western Australia say fatigued crews are frustrated over time spent monitoring pole-top fires before Western Power crews travel to the scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5678f237dd6bc39a06f510c82496e39</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberal Party indicates One Nation preference as Alex Antic meets with Cory Bernardi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/sa-liberals-may-preference-one-nation-over-labor-greens/106379200</link><description>The South Australian Liberal Party has indicated it may direct preferences to One Nation ahead of Labor and the Greens. It comes as prominent Liberal senator Alex Antic was spotted having drinks with One Nation's lead SA candidate Cory Bernardi, amid speculation over a possible defection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72c419cb0694688644a18c3c1afcf669</guid></item><item><title>Victorian premier refers surgeon Simon Gordon allegations to police after Four Corners revelations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/simon-gordon-four-corners-allegations-premier-police-referral/106379430</link><description>Victorian Premier Jacinta Allan has referred allegations against gynaecologist Simon Gordon to police, but the government will not conduct its own investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbc42ddc66916a74d2eb01978ef31910</guid></item><item><title>Floyd Mayweather and Manny Pacquiao confirm rematch 11 years after 'Fight of the Century'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/boxing-mayweather-pacquiao-rematch-confirmed/106379582</link><description>Manny Pacquiao has a chance to face Floyd Mayweather again as the American star comes out of retirement for a blockbuster rematch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d0d4d1211f8e90f2f1c7ac5abb9b869</guid></item><item><title>Sunshine Coast's iconic venue Solbar to close after more than 20 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/sunshine-coast-solbar-closing-maroochydore/106379262</link><description>The Sunshine Coast's longest-running live music venue will close this weekend, after more than 20 years of hosting artists and performers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61ff7be6a3afe0bdc03cf355d504cfa6</guid></item><item><title>Bunbury backpacker hostels ordered to close after asbestos, safety warnings ignored</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/bunbury-backpackers-closed-after-asbestos-found/106377416</link><description>Two backpacker hostels in Western Australia's largest regional city have been ordered to shut due to serious health and safety concerns, including asbestos exposure risks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af5120aee3df7d826ba36674e3c73e11</guid></item><item><title>The 'first-night effect': Why it's hard to sleep when you're somewhere new</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/why-its-hard-to-sleep-when-you-are-somewhere-new/106377794</link><description>It's night-time and you're exhausted. But the hotel bed feels wrong. The mini fridge won't stop making that low, irritating hum. The power outlet lights feel brighter than the sun.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31c70a83ae2e841ba9faf3f83b43af1f</guid></item><item><title>Farmers rally against 96 million litres per year Southern Downs water extraction and bottling facility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/farmers-rally-water-extraction-bottling-cherrabah-southern-downs/106358124</link><description>A developer has lodged an application with a rural Queensland council to build a water bottling, storage and export facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">696c203be2eb87f4287a5969556c6e3a</guid></item><item><title>More than 70 dead after Mexico's biggest drug lord 'El Mencho' killed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/people-dead-in-mexico-after-drug-leader-el-mencho-death/106379184</link><description>At least 73 people have died in the attempt to capture cartel leader Nemesio Oseguera Cervantes and in the aftermath of his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d6e8bdec46001b4377710d416e49c9c</guid></item><item><title>Police suspect human remains to be abducted Sydney man</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/human-remains-found-in-search-for-sydney-man-chris-baghsarian/106350124</link><description>Eighty-five-year-old Chris Baghsarian was mistakenly snatched from his North Ryde property about 5am on February 13.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb560b2fcf4c45dbcccfe29cfb5b416a</guid></item><item><title>Opposition leader to boycott swearing-in of controversial new NT administrator David Connolly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/new-nt-administrator-david-connolly-swearing-in-boycott/106376176</link><description>Northern Territory Opposition Leader Selena Uibo says she will boycott the swearing-in of incoming administrator David Connolly, whose appointment has been embroiled in controversy due to a series of past social media posts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e17c784876f317725a0f6fdc31f88d6f</guid></item><item><title>Sam Walsh's eight-year contract extension the biggest deal in Carlton's history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/afl-sam-walsh-record-carlton-contract-extension/106379858</link><description>Carlton locks down Sam Walsh to a massive eight-year contract extension as he turns down the lure of free agency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3b2ac1e0ee2244745260bab311e3d2a</guid></item><item><title>Is couples counselling right for me and will the therapist take sides? An expert explains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/is-couples-counselling-right-for-me/106377918</link><description>Many people seek out couples counselling when going through a rough patch, or wondering how to improve their relationship. So, how do you decide if it's right for you?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4be6f26e0de6326cf36d9c3115b73ad1</guid></item><item><title>Grace Tame abuser Nicolaas Bester unfit to stand trial over alleged 'menacing' social media posts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/grace-tame-abuser-nicolaas-bester-unfit-to-stand-trial/105640758</link><description>Nicolaas Ockert Bester has been deemed unfit to stand trial in the Hobart Magistrates Court over three counts of using a carriage service to menace, harass or cause offence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beada0a8927ee572636c12af002e6bba</guid></item><item><title>Trump Tower developer Altus Property Group's David Young has twice gone bankrupt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/trump-tower-developer-went-bankrupt-twice/106379446</link><description>A search by the ABC of federal insolvency records reveals the developer has had personal financial scrapes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1cf983d1575d549dda1cde43880b004</guid></item><item><title>Australia confirms first full men's tour of South Africa since 2018 ball-tampering scandal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/cricket-australia-south-africa-2026-mens-tour-fixtures-confirmed/106380536</link><description>Steve Smith will be one of five Australian players from the infamous 2018 tour to return to South Africa later this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83339d68b9905f2e5b6c4db966984801</guid></item><item><title>For some families, the social media ban has made things harder. Here's why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/social-media-ban-choices-for-families/106334598</link><description>We spoke with three parents about how it has impacted their family and the different choices they are making around the ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9396f5068ed4179cc5d3622cc647caf3</guid></item><item><title>Kash Patel and US men's hockey team under fire after Donald Trump makes joke about women's team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/trump-us-mens-hockey-team-under-fire-mocking-womens-team/106380212</link><description>Viral video of Trump's White House invitation to the US men's hockey team sparks backlash online after the president jokes he would be 'impeached' if he did not also include the gold-medal winning women's team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f9e2ca77739ded4fef9d2c039565d60</guid></item><item><title>TasWater continues to push for higher water bills, despite regulator knock back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/taswater-argues-its-case-for-higher-water-bills/106379690</link><description>TasWater has continued to press its case for a steep water bill hike, despite the economic regulator's decision to halve its proposed price earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef5aff82a0977148ce84dae0cae1f60d</guid></item><item><title>Farmers are sick of being called 'resilient' and researchers say it's causing real harm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/why-calling-farmers-resilient-is-causing-real-harm/106380598</link><description>Farmers and mental health experts say it is time to stop calling farmers "resilient", with concerns it is making it harder for people to ask for, or be offered, help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8262c8df577b48206152fb3633b1c7b</guid></item><item><title>Blizzard hits US Northeast bringing cities to standstill, closing schools and disrupting flights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/new-york-blizzard-shuts-down-city/106380000</link><description>A record-breaking snowstorm pummels the north-eastern United States, bringing cities to a near-standstill for millions of residents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e189929376eb6370b3de7af3a9595cc</guid></item><item><title>WA Parliament to debate institutional child sex abuse laws in wake of 'retrograde' High Court decision</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/political-fight-brewing-over-wa-child-sex-abuse-laws/106378266</link><description>A tense political fight is brewing over the future of laws to compensate survivors of institutional child sexual abuse, as the government faces pressure to expand its scope beyond just churches and religious institutions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ebc9f878ee9aa4c53cfa620788901c2</guid></item><item><title>Former Matildas label new Football Australia membership program a 'silencing mechanism'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/football-matildas-alumni-silencing-mechanism/106380898</link><description>A new membership program launched by Football Australia puts former Matildas players in a difficult position if they want to criticise the governing body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12ab1a1fc7933a240faf717139d7e352</guid></item><item><title>Globetrotting ancient marine amphibians uncovered in lucky Kimberley fossil rediscovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/globetrotting-marine-amphibian-kimberley-fossil/106378096</link><description>A salamander-crocodile type predator survived five extinction events and travelled from waters off Norway to WA's Kimberley coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74546bf755e86634e833775195d5a28f</guid></item><item><title>Essential Caravans buys Zone RV, but customers left short-changed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/essential-caravans-buys-zone-rv-customers-owed-millions/106331548</link><description>A Melbourne-based company has purchased Zone RV, but customers who collectively paid millions before its collapse will be left out of pocket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">647be1b77de1ac880d3f94c8330ddf6e</guid></item><item><title>Former RBA governor Bernie Fraser calls for capital gains tax discount to be scrapped</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/former-rba-governor-bernie-fraser-calls-out-toxic-tax-debate-cgt/106381176</link><description>Bernie Fraser tells a Senate committee hearing on capital gains tax that, if it were up to him, he would abolish the discount, as he warns younger Australians are watching the unaffordable housing market in "dismay".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e2e581ae18667dd719881ee26af70c3</guid></item><item><title>Thousands without power as intense storms sweep across Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/storms-heavy-rain-create-flash-flooding-risk-melbourne-victoria/106381904</link><description>Storms dumped 50 millimetres of rain on parts of Victoria on Tuesday and cut power to thousands of homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd921bd2b66d090c85c4290ac02e432d</guid></item><item><title>Woman allegedly attempts to snatch hijab from teenage girl in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/police-investigate-alleged-hijab-snatching-brisbane/106377108</link><description>Queensland Police launch an investigation after a woman allegedly attempted to snatch a hijab from a teenage girl on the Brisbane bayside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecf3abd205bed7da3b3acea07677024e</guid></item><item><title>Could Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor be removed from the line of succession?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/could-andrew-mountbatten-windsor-be-removed-succession/106379724</link><description>Is it possible to remove him? The short answer is yes — but it would most likely be a time-consuming process involving many parliaments passing legislation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc7b6cf1265cee96550e880ac1189d24</guid></item><item><title>Utopia team tackles high-speed rail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/utopia-team-tackles-high-speed-rail/106379780</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cb443e1ef7c03abe11f3494051593d0</guid></item><item><title>Australia has been waiting more than 40 years for a high-speed train</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/high-speed-rail-timeline/106380200</link><description>It has been more than 40 years since the idea of high-speed rail was first floated in Australia, but is it finally about to become a reality?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b871f60ea4b939b39299867329db2d65</guid></item><item><title>Rodney Wayne Williams fails appeal to overturn conviction for murdering pregnant teenager</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/rodney-wayne-williams-fails-murder-appeal-again/106381496</link><description>Rodney Wayne Williams is serving life in jail for the murder of 16-year-old, pregnant Tiffany Taylor in Waterford West in July 2015.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ae0393e00ac7837b97eba078297d636</guid></item><item><title>AI body suddenly scrapped after 15 months spent finding experts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/ai-body-scrapped-15-months-spent-experts/106381560</link><description>It took 15 months to narrow a field of 270 AI experts to 12 appointees for an AI authority, at a cost of almost $200,000, before it was suddenly scrapped by the federal government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4d4a8e5bb2f4cb7d4740af807977d6a</guid></item><item><title>Gus Lamont's parents release public statement saying their lives have been 'shattered'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/gus-lamont-parents-release-statement-and-video/106382060</link><description>The parents of missing four-year-old Gus Lamont have released a public statement, saying "every moment without him is unbearable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d3e5c997663dc92e3421d5bad20eb45</guid></item><item><title>Australia's women's team wins first ODI against India by six wickets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/australia-rocked-by-injuries-for-odi-against-india/106382088</link><description>Half-centuries to Alyssa Healy and Beth Mooney help lead Australia to a six-wicket win over India in the first ODI.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ffe49e1fc9fac5bc4872e11ab263f28</guid></item><item><title>Explosive detection dog Flo Joe posthumously awarded for military service in Afghanistan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/explosive-detection-dog-honoured-for-afghanistan-service/106381612</link><description>In July 2007, explosive detection dog Flo Joe became the first Australian service dog to locate an improvised explosive device in Afghanistan. Today, she was posthumously recognised for her military service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a025209051ae4b48cc916b0eff99763</guid></item><item><title>Popular WA outback tourist property Wooleen Station to be sold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/wooleen-station-to-go-on-the-market/106380032</link><description>A pastoral station in WA's Murchison region which has become a high-profile example of conservation is to be sold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2629129ee45ba4e948d4323c0b0f54ca</guid></item><item><title>Half the country on flood watch as summer storms bring deluge of rain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/flood-watch-severe-summer-storms-rain-deluge/106380770</link><description>There are widespread warnings for intense rain and potential flooding, as summer storms hit southern states and an unusually slow-moving system soaks central Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cf44965fc7c5761beae2aa89fa43be8</guid></item><item><title>Geoffrey John Guest to face fresh trial after Cairns District Court jury discharged</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/geoffrey-john-guest-cairns-district-court-mistrial/106381884</link><description>The judge decided a witness's "inadmissible" response under cross-examination in the trial of Geoffrey John Guest left her with no choice but to discharge the jury the day after it had been empanelled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55d12e78f860c14d96031e44bd3fbd4b</guid></item><item><title>WA government announces $140m plan to prevent repeat of record-breaking flu season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/funding-announced-to-prevent-repeat-of-worst-wa-flu-season/106381138</link><description>Creating more beds and boosting immunisation are key features of a $140 million "winter strategy" aimed at avoiding a repeat of WA's worst-ever flu season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cdf32025a3e240599546afd0cac4a75</guid></item><item><title>Fire ant authority considers penalties for business that spread nests to central Qld</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/fire-ant-authority-considers-business-penalties-central-qld/106381870</link><description>The National Fire Ant Eradication Program is considering "enforcement actions" for a business accused of spreading nests to Queensland mine sites via a shipment of bricks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b7e49e3c8b3f0115d47c00005c53b9b</guid></item><item><title>Most flu deaths this century were recorded in 2025, ABS finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/most-flu-deaths-this-century-were-recorded-in-2025/106380626</link><description>There were more deaths associated with influenza last year than any other year this century, according to the Australia Bureau of Statistics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e3386c5443b969a614212741434003a</guid></item><item><title>New ACT firearms laws would allow police to search property of 'high-risk' individuals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/new-act-laws-to-target-high-risk-firearms-licence-holders/106379570</link><description>The ACT government's plan to strengthen firearms laws could raise human rights issues by interfering with the right to privacy, a lawyer has warned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1f4939ac3ca9f4d10abc422d74b3fcc</guid></item><item><title>Medicinal cannabis company offered 'kickbacks' to military advocates for veteran referrals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/medicinal-cannabis-company-offered-kickback-for-veteran-referral/106354294</link><description>A representative for a telehealth company has been caught offering a military advocate a "kickback" for every veteran who signs up to an ongoing medicinal cannabis prescription.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f1f5f0b22d4bd43ab825ed49b41993a</guid></item><item><title>Perth obstetrician Rhys Bellinge jailed over drunken high-speed crash that killed Elizabeth Pearce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/rhys-bellinge-dash-cam-vision-shown-at-manslaughter-hearing/106379994</link><description>A Perth obstetrician who killed a 24-year-old woman after smashing his high performance luxury car into the small hatchback she was a passenger in is sentenced to 10 years and six months in jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67f3bc7237cf123c2e550b516eb79a62</guid></item><item><title>Banning transgender women from lesbian group could 'undermine their dignity', court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/trans-women-ban-could-undermine-dignity-court-hears/106379566</link><description>Transgender women will have their dignity "undermined" and could be made to feel "inferior" if a lesbian group is allowed to ban them from events, a court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fff4a589cb54ef441b0031aadaecd259</guid></item><item><title>Trans-Tasman Yacht Race from Sydney to Auckland postponed after withdrawal of most entries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/inaugural-trans-tasman-yacht-race-postponed/106382816</link><description>The first running of the Trans-Tasman Yacht Race between Sydney and Auckland is called off days out from the start, after the withdrawal of the majority of entries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">439fd74ff186d18c86d500c7cbe2cae1</guid></item><item><title>France considering social media ban as devastated families launch legal action against TikTok</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/french-social-media-ban-families-suing-tiktok/106348256</link><description>France is set to follow Australia with a social media ban but for these families, who are suing TikTok over what they say is a harmful algorithm, the battle is only beginning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b3b1560d775c7fd8cd69af17d8f6724</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106381704</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39e60231a17d7a495fddc0419a39ae3a</guid></item><item><title>Torres Strait Island men jailed over 110kg cocaine bust at top of Australian mainland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/torres-strait-island-men-jailed-110-kg-cocaine-bust/106381388</link><description>One of three men who used a dinghy to haul 110 kilograms of cocaine onto the Australian mainland has been jailed after telling a court he was helping a friend in exchange for a free boat trip.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">541a6f2b789102f306eb4615606528d2</guid></item><item><title>Ash Barty to return to golf, as three-time tennis grand slam winner ready to play NZ Open pro-am</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/barty-to-dust-cobwebs-off-golf-clubs-at-nz-open/106383366</link><description>Ash Barty, Kelly Slater and Ricky Ponting are among the multi-talented sports stars in action in the pro-am component of the NZ Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">691e478bd06ca170a02cb11cd8010379</guid></item><item><title>Inquest into Aboriginal woman's death in custody hears of daughters' grief from losing 'loving mother'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/inquiry-into-tammy-shipley-indigenous-death-in-custody-underway/106375872</link><description>Tammy Shipley died in a NSW prison cell in December 2022 after consuming excessive water, a complication of schizoaffective disorder known as polydipsia. Today her children told a coronial inquest that "if love could have saved her, she could have lived forever".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ea20def3d0cef5ce9691ef8a1913353</guid></item><item><title>Sunshine Coast man Riccardo Valenza charged with 31 offences, including 11 counts of rape</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/sunshine-coast-riccardo-valenza-rape-sex-offence-charges/106383282</link><description>Sunshine Coast man Riccardo Valenza, 31, has been remanded in custody after police charged him with 31 offences relating to 11 alleged victims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2a0eaed5b17d352f1a7fa52c740a38c</guid></item><item><title>Gynaecologist referred to police after Four Corners report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/gynaecologist-referred-to-police-after-four-corners-report/106383070</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af5fa80a27c13ce749c4abd8cbf9c859</guid></item><item><title>This video shows Rhys Bellinge's erratic behaviour and driving in the lead-up to the fatal accident.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/rhys-bellinge-dashcam/106383724</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56edceffc1a1d0498e77c5721b86cb57</guid></item><item><title>WIN Network acquires Nine Darwin, expanding broadcast operations into the NT</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/win-network-expands-to-nt-acquires-nine-darwin-broadcast-licence/106381370</link><description>Regional news broadcaster WIN has announced it will acquire Nine Darwin, just over a year after the Nine Network suddenly axed its Darwin TV news bulletin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8baa7469fabfac9c6ed288c3f74508b5</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese evacuated from The Lodge following security incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/anthony-albanese-security-incident-at-lodge-police-canberra/106383816</link><description>The incident at Mr Albanese's Canberra residence led to the prime minister being taken to another location for several hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72b50206545d3ac787b1d543ef05a0cb</guid></item><item><title>Russell Brand pleads not guilty to further rape, sex assault charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/russell-brand-pleads-not-guilty-to-rape-sex-assault-charges/106383904</link><description>British actor and comedian Russell Brand pleads not guilty in a London court to two additional charges of rape and sexual assault nearly two decades ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b747accab501f137c5c60f8fc3286c92</guid></item><item><title>Reawakening</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/investigating-the-return-of-the-islamic-state-terrorist-group/106154258</link><description>The Bondi Beach terrorist attack signalled the resurgence of the Islamic State terrorist group in Australia. For the past two years, ABC Investigations has tracked the group's revival, identifying key figures, mapping the network and raising questions about the response of police, intelligence agencies and governments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ed875261411710cd5d9b1a2ae992a69</guid></item><item><title>Former Philippine leader Rodrigo Duterte drew up 'death lists' and boasted about murders, ICC prosecutors say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/rodrigo-duterte-drew-up-death-lists-icc-prosecutor-says/106383930</link><description>Former Philippines president Rodrigo Duterte personally drew up "death lists" and boasted about murders committed during his "war on drugs", an International Criminal Court prosecutor alleges at a crimes against humanity hearing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d06ac48619d2547d4416c2e55b69aa52</guid></item><item><title>Savannah Guthrie's family offers $1.42m reward to bring home missing mother Nancy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/brk-savannah-guthrie-million-dollar-reward-nancy/106384088</link><description>US TV host Savannah Guthrie has posted a video to Instagram offering a $US1 million ($1.42 million) reward for information leading to the recovery of her missing mother Nancy Guthrie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53947568c5673b9c16079b2e53f0b890</guid></item><item><title>Ramadan night market at Dandenong scaled up to become Melbourne's largest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/melbourne-ramadan-night-market-dandenong-hopes-to-rival-sydney/106357254</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese attended the opening night of the Ramadan night market in Melbourne's Dandenong, which organisers hope will attract at least a million people over the course of the holy month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7176ca510c3d56fefb572a594733e9c8</guid></item><item><title>Travel quiz, February 25: Can you win our race around the world?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/travel-quiz/106251072</link><description>Which European city is home to the Rijksmuseum? And which dance style is Argentina best known for?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12547cb9e33e987e219d6bc7abf94e46</guid></item><item><title>Salmon Tasmania fighting proposal by regulator to revoke its licence to use antibiotic florfenicol</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/salmon-tasmania-fighting-to-keep-florfenicol-licence/106379754</link><description>Tasmania's salmon industry is arguing the case to keep using an antibiotic being used to combat bacterial infection in fish stocks, as a possible ban on the drug's usage looms because of it being found in "non-target" species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e1bfed478e6d5edcba7362c9b4986f5</guid></item><item><title>Gay and bisexual Sydney teenagers lured and bashed on camera in IS-inspired attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/lgbtq-sydney-teenagers-bashed-on-camera-in-is-inspired-attacks/106381614</link><description>An ABC investigation has obtained distressing videos and victims' accounts of IS sympathisers hunting and bashing gay and bisexual boys on camera in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02cf66c55ec69f880e3809e1ee0429a4</guid></item><item><title>UK entry passport changes come into effect for dual citizens today. Here is what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/passport-changes-come-into-effect-today-what-you-need-to-know/106363364</link><description>Your guide to the dual citizen entry requirements for the UK that are coming into effect today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9997eacc232f10ff5de92ee2a93f44c4</guid></item><item><title>Endometriosis sufferers fear progress could be undone by one surgeon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/simon-gordon-actions-undo-decades-endometriosis-advocacy/106380210</link><description>Endometriosis sufferers have been left "sick" and reeling over the findings of a months-long ABC investigation into a Melbourne gynaecologist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb137f5b8e49938c0ab7401b57e03c07</guid></item><item><title>Russia casts net wide for mercenary recruits: fmr presidential adviser</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/fional-hill-iv-russia-recruits/106383740</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e046e0fde8c37bc2af5d53ee49ca9eee</guid></item><item><title>Four years of war in Ukraine leaves Russia a 'spent force' with diminished influence, analyst says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/russia-military-reputation-economy-after-ukraine-war-years/106382378</link><description>For the first time since its invasion of Ukraine, Russia has lost troops faster than it can replace them. It's one of many grim milestones of a bloody war that has now been going for four years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bced11945eb48f8283eac8c53bd02cf8</guid></item><item><title>Aiva Anagnostiadis looks to future after breaking leg during F1 Academy rookie year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/aiva-anagnostiadis-motor-sport-f1-academy-broken-leg/106380728</link><description>Armed with a strengthened determination to succeed on the race track, Aiva Anagnostiadis is ready to put her injury woes in the rear-view mirror.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77c674fd515793cfabe6c37ff1482519</guid></item><item><title>Kirsty Rosse-Emile was 'groomed' as a teenager to go to Syria and join Islamic State, sister says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/sister-isis-syria-kirsty-rosse-emile-stuck-children/106380344</link><description>The sister of an Australian woman who married an Islamic State fighter has revealed how her sister was "groomed" into travelling to a war zone in Syria, where she is now stuck.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2bd5be0ab6fff559bea90e80e8fba94</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup 2026: The uneven roads that lead to the trophy, from the intriguing North Korea, to favourite Japan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/matildas-women-asian-cup-uneven-roads-lead-to-trophy/106359648</link><description>The Women's Asian Cup in Australia provides a chance for the Matildas and visiting nations to create history, bring attention to their countries like never before, and seek respect and investment. But each have had varied paths to get here.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aacf7cdc0ca08ec21e067171a144021a</guid></item><item><title>Antisemitism royal commission underway, but does it have time to deliver effective change?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/antisemitism-royal-commission-takeaways-bell-under-pressure/106382176</link><description>The antisemitism royal commission is underway, but it faces some real tests in delivering justice to those impacted in the wake of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e594d0b66d135cb84779076f40a5e4d</guid></item><item><title>Sir Donald Bradman died a quarter century ago but will 'always be 99.94 not out'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/sir-donald-bradman-died-25-years-ago-but-his-legacy-endures/106380826</link><description>Sir Donald Bradman was a towering figure in Australian cricket and culture, and some of the game's commentators have paused to reflect on his ongoing significance to the sport 25 years after his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">975906e8b1e84eeb203f6986ecaf9129</guid></item><item><title>Mayor in Melbourne's west suspended after misconduct finding over Facebook post</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/vic-wyndham-mayor-suspended-after-misconduct-finding/106383594</link><description>Wyndham City Council mayor Josh Gilligan has been stood down for a month after an investigation found a social media post about a former mayor was belittling and demeaning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a49a5ca56c5146670422dd295621041</guid></item><item><title>SA Labor's stamp duty policy appears at odds with former treasurer Stephen Mullighan's views</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/sa-labor-stamp-duty-policy-at-odds-with-former-treasurer/106378424</link><description>SA Labor has announced a plan to abolish stamp duty for those aged over 60 and planning to downsize at the party's election campaign launch, in what seems to be a major policy shift from the position detailed by the state's former treasurer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37b27db3455f09fb4d6806cfb7711d05</guid></item><item><title>Armidale community rallies to welcome refugees from Democratic Republic of Congo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/congolese-refugees-welcomed-in-armidale-nsw/105972890</link><description>Churches and families rally around Congolese refugee arrivals in a NSW town known as a welcome zone for those fleeing crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f543759c3159899de0b556d015bc0898</guid></item><item><title>Irma Palasics's husband recounts her brutal murder in violent home invasion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/irma-palasics-husband-gregor-recounts-brutal-murder/106383678</link><description>A jury has watched hospital footage of Irma Palasics's husband describing the night she was killed in 1999, as two men stand trial over her death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b228934b08a6e5492eb7b74281967e33</guid></item><item><title>Australian Chamber Orchestra welcomes 416yo Italian viola into its collection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/416yo-maggini-viola-now-in-aco-golden-age-instrument-collection/106379198</link><description>The instrument is believed to be one of the finest tenor violas in existence and the only surviving example of its kind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1687be523fb662e38112f9e215a95c24</guid></item><item><title>UK government supports release of Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's trade envoy documents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/uk-supports-release-andrew-trade-envoy-documents/106384154</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor was arrested last week on suspicion of misconduct in public office amid claims he shared confidential government information with Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d235e2538bc53d7290a2f9b9495a41a5</guid></item><item><title>Trump Tower developer David Young ran business that collapsed owing $28 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/trump-tower-altus-david-young-business-collapse/106382270</link><description>The businessman behind a proposed Trump Tower on the Gold Coast ran a development business that collapsed owing $28 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20f0579935944319a141698f76e6a03a</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of former prisoners potentially exposed to HIV and hepatitis C after a prisoner shared needles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/hundreds-prisoners-exposed-hiv-hepatitis-needles-prison/106380582</link><description>A Queensland Health communique has revealed hundreds of former prisoners were potentially exposed to HIV and hepatitis C after an inmate shared injecting equipment in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ea1a73def8baa9b4fca1b38e40ca337</guid></item><item><title>Scott Vincent Ward charged with allegedly grooming Philippines mother to sexually abuse her children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/scott-vincent-ward-charged-allegedly-grooming-philippines-mother/106278470</link><description>The man was searched by Australian Border Force officers when he arrived at Brisbane Airport after returning to Australia on a flight from the Philippines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b0e9ca5da89c7b4e3f1b6ac1518eaae</guid></item><item><title>Live: Call to turn temperature down after 'very troubling' threat on PM's residence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/albanese-evacuation-labor-taylor-coalition-capital-gains/106382944</link><description>A Labor frontbencher has repeated a call for the temperature to be lowered after the prime minister's "very troubling" evacuation from The Lodge last night. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77348508578bc054179124f6660dcdaa</guid></item><item><title>The pilot program is based on the fact that some cases of diabetes are caused by undiagnosed pancreatic cancer.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/pancreatic-cancer-study-diabetes/106383428</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a81a0eba5ac0eb08d92891e8ce230d0</guid></item><item><title>Pilot study into early diagnosis of pancreatic cancer by screening diabetes patients to launch in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/pancreatic-cancer-pilot-study-diabetes-qimr-berghofer/106382922</link><description>The study is the first step into investigating whether pancreatic cancer screening — via a non-invasive CT scan — could help save lives by early detection or warning signs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf16cc4fc7e81bd913e1ef2a0c3a94bb</guid></item><item><title>Craig Tiley to leave Tennis Australia for role with United States Tennis Association</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/craig-tiley-leaves-tennis-australia-role/106384386</link><description>Tiley has been tournament director of the Australian Open since 2006 and Tennis Australia CEO since 2013. He'll remain in the role while Tennis Australia appoints his successor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a00aa6f512d90a459a2c2526fc89b3e</guid></item><item><title>Louvre Museum director resigns in wake of brazen October crown jewel heist in Paris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/louvre-museum-director-resigns-after-brazen-jewel-heist-paris/106384280</link><description>Louvre Museum director Laurence des Cars resigns after months of pressure following the brazen theft of crown jewels, water damage, staff strikes, overcrowding complaints and a suspected ticket fraud scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">831bd642e407e80da5f053df10bdaa0a</guid></item><item><title>Thirteen million trees to be replanted after pine plantation wiped out in Walwa-Mt Lawson fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/walwa-mt-lawson-bushfire-homes-destroyed-pine-plantation-burnt/106352790</link><description>The fire threat in Victoria's Upper Murray has eased, but the region's famously green, undulating hills still bear the black scars of a devastating bushfire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97c8fc075c444de8cd7ff73b22cbe99f</guid></item><item><title>Two men arrested over alleged kidnapping murder of Sydney grandfather Chris Baghsarian</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/arrests-made-in-relation-to-chris-baghsarian-kidnapping-sydney/106383878</link><description>The arrests come less than 24 hours after police discovered human remains near a golf club in Sydney's north-west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef24ed41a5bfff6d07da7264105ce998</guid></item><item><title>Live: ASX to rise after Wall Street rebounds easing AI concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/asx-markets-business-live-news-feb25-2026/106384410</link><description>A rally on Wall Street is likely to send Australian stocks higher, while the Australian Berau of Statistics is set to release the Consumer Price Index (CPI) for January at 11.30am AEDT. Follow the latest updates in our live blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed97b3919fb81e7d55a53a3b1198c44c</guid></item><item><title>US Winter Olympic ice hockey hero Jack Hughes excited to meet Donald Trump as mum defends Kash Patel video</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/jack-hughes-white-house-winter-olympics-womens-ice-hockey/106384348</link><description>US ice hockey star Jack Hughes defends his team after video of them laughing at Donald Trump's joke about the women's gold medallists sparks backlash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe483c4796cb5a3109bf95b4979dd780</guid></item><item><title>Open letter asks PM to 'urgently rescind' appointment of NT administrator David Connolly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/open-letter-call-for-anthony-albanese-intervene-nt-administrator/106382634</link><description>Politicians, advocates and civil society leaders have made a last-ditch plea for Anthony Albanese to intervene ahead of the swearing-in of controversial incoming NT administrator David Connolly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9f9004a6582dfbcb6d78bad56957c4d</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast council's international travel bill $46k higher than disclosed, committee hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/gold-coast-council-travel-bill-higher-than-disclosed/106383026</link><description>Gold Coast councillors question undisclosed staff travel costs after an extra $46,000 in spending is revealed, prompting calls for greater transparency and oversight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f677ae67d38c1e940df7ad67aaa3d285</guid></item><item><title>Mount Isa experiences most February rain on record</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/mount-isa-wettest-february-on-record/106376066</link><description>Dry red dirt turns to flowing rivers and lakes as heavy rainfall breaks a century-old record in Mount Isa.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18499cfff20111771fdd53839df128fa</guid></item><item><title>Connor Rogers learning to walk again after nearly losing leg in 'completely fair tackle' during local footy game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/connor-rogers-brutal-injury-football-local-div-12/106338682</link><description>A catastrophic footy injury during a Melbourne reserves game changed Connor Rogers's life in an instant. In the aftermath, the support of his local footy club helped him recover and showed him the power of community. WARNING: This article contains graphic imagery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">078399ef98a946f6de58bb17d264207d</guid></item><item><title>Iran signs 'secret' $700m deal for Russian air defence systems, reports say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/iran-missile-defence-deal-russia-verba-manpad-weapons/106380088</link><description>Iran has reportedly signed a secret arms deal with Russia to acquire thousands of advanced shoulder-fired missiles to help boost its air defences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b186d6b24a61905798a901db170096dd</guid></item><item><title>SA council sustainability rankings spark amalgamation debate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/amalgamation-councils-escosa-regional-sustainability-riverland/106375288</link><description>Council amalgamation is being discussed in South Australia, where multiple local governments have been ranked as unsustainable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0eec603983b4ab25aa6900830474120</guid></item><item><title>Connor Rogers learning to walk again after terrifying knee injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/connor-rogers-learning-to-walk-again-/106384584</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa36b24a3b079f4df41539f3d3e95124</guid></item><item><title>Thai officials say 72 tiger deaths at tourist parks not caused by bird flu</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/virus-that-killed-72-tigers-at-thai-zoos-not-bird-flu/106384442</link><description>Thai authorities say tigers in confined environments can be particularly vulnerable to the canine distemper viral infection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08d52138f42cb0ba31f2ed52368e5ca8</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous landscape board chair resigns amid investigation into Telstra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/landscape-chair-resigns-amid-investigation-into-telstra/106367584</link><description>The Alinytjara Wiluṟara Landscape Board chair steps down, saying his ability to speak for a region where Telstra is under investigation for alleged environmental breaches was impeded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">211a65bc84f648de9e49ef376f2bcd2b</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos truck crashes on Bruce Highway near Townsville, spilling load into creek</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/asbestos-truck-crash-townsville-spill-creek/106384658</link><description>A truck carrying asbestos has crashed on the Bruce Highway near Townsville early this morning, spilling its load into a nearby creek.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aebbb270a622f869b3b321a16ca4b297</guid></item><item><title>Perth doctor Rhys Bellinge's 'entitled, callous' behaviour killed Elizabeth Pearce and ruined lives, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/perth-doctor-rhys-bellinge-killed-elizabeth-pearce-ruined-lives/106383318</link><description>Sought-after obstetrician Rhys Bellinge appeared to have it all — but that changed in an instant when his drunken, high-speed driving killed a young university graduate and left a rideshare driver with permanent injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">355a8d87620787b2e6b4622688729230</guid></item><item><title>Wittenoom traditional owners launch $1.5b asbestos contamination claim against WA government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/banjima-traditional-owners-launch-billion-dollar-wittenoom-claim/106358598</link><description>Banjima traditional owners say the thousands of hectares left poisoned by decades of asbestos mining has left them with one of the highest death rates of mesothelioma in the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">889e0a097833cbe734c1fccb6cfd8878</guid></item><item><title>Lake Moondarra overspills for the first time since since 2011</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/lake-moondarra-overspills-for-the-first-time-since-since-2011/106384730</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f810b53ba9fc40815b8ed0f71911982</guid></item></channel></rss>