<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 03:34:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Halls Gap businesses reinventing themselves after bushfires wiped out trade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/halls-gap-pomonal-tourism-bushfire-recovery/106331718</link><description>After two consecutive summers devastated by bushfires, businesses in the region are reinventing themselves to stay afloat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60e94f2fcc4428c36c260d3a2cded9a2</guid></item><item><title>Meet GayC/DC, the world's only all-gay AC/DC tribute band</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/gaycdc-interview-gay-acdc-tribute-band-australia-tour/106331786</link><description>They worship the riffs, rewrite the lyrics and win over the toughest crowds. GayC/DC is a tribute band like no other.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d75dfaf3925eb31093fd2815687fbbc</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners 'won't accept' handback of rehabilitated Argyle diamond mine site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/argyle-diamond-mine-closure-traditional-owner-concerns/106339850</link><description>East Kimberley traditional owners are concerned Rio Tinto's closure plan will leave them with "a giant hole in the ground forever".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">920c2b711109c2ab18519ecaf2822c30</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Matt Graham on dual moguls 'dad podium' as weather forces reschedule — quick hits from day nine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-matt-graham-weather/106347344</link><description>A trio of dads fill the dual moguls podium as an "unfavourable" forecast leaves things up in the air. Here are the quick hits from day nine of the Milano Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">728d2c63e252485fc6b6ccaa8a108ac4</guid></item><item><title>Vermilion's Wandoo gas exports halted after December oil spill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/vermilion-wandoo-oil-spill-nopsema-exports-closed/106343518</link><description>Exports from an oil field off WA's Pilbara are at a standstill after an oil spill in December. The regulator says it has identified "systemic failures" at the Canadian-owned Wandoo facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">584938c64ecc4bec962163af6788452e</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic type B killer whales seen for first time near WA's Bremer Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/visiting-orcas-steal-the-feed-of-local-killer-whales-in-wa/106345466</link><description>Sightings of Antarctic orcas in Australian waters are very rare. A tour group in WA saw what appeared to be a pod of Antarctic type B killer whales muscle in and steal the meal of a local group of orcas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39f109d1374dbb8d8c0891214ddd9157</guid></item><item><title>Senior Liberals deny involvement in draft policy to ban migrants from Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/ley-draft-migration-policy-australian-values-statement/106348870</link><description>A leaked copy of the Liberal Party's migration policy prepared before Sussan Ley was ousted included plans to "elevate" the current non-binding Australian values statement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afcbb687b8d26ea4579377278e93aa57</guid></item><item><title>NRL opens door for New Zealand and England internationals to play State of Origin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/nrl-announces-origin-eligibility-changes/106349066</link><description>New South Wales and Queensland can now select players who are New Zealand and England internationals after the NRL confirmed a major change to the State of Origin eligibility rules.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">022358d3cebffadc6e741dffb4f62e42</guid></item><item><title>Maugean skate still faces 'catastrophic' risk from salmon farming, Commonwealth advice says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/maugean-skate-endangered-status-analysis/106348446</link><description>Official advice is unequivocal that salmon farming remains the main threat to the endangered Maugean skate. It remains to be seen if the federal environment minister will ask Tasmanian salmon farms to scale back their operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f16f18ad7cc496224dc41ec49e1e0093</guid></item><item><title>How cheating allegations have rocked the curling teams at the Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/winter-olympics-curling-cheating-allegations-explained/106349394</link><description>Controversy is swirling in curling at the Winter Olympics after the Canadian team was accused of cheating. Here's a look at the whole controversy and why it matters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">443f4b616e5ccdfab16fa6775d3ce790</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 10</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide/106348302</link><description>Find out what is on during Day 10 at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">babe139774c2ec18a2b959e9a68baa62</guid></item><item><title>CLP announces Anjan Paudel as Nightcliff by-election candidate, Phil Scott runs as independent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/nt-nightcliff-byelection-candidates-clp-independent/106350116</link><description>More candidates for the Nightcliff by-election are announced, with Phil Scott running as an independent and the Country Liberal Party preselecting Anjan Paudel, who has stumbled while answering basic policy questions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">214a6542d0a331ab8d4a1cac56b71edb</guid></item><item><title>Aussie Walker finishes outside of medals at Milano Cortina Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/winter-olympics-2026-live-milano-cortina/106350862</link><description>Australia's Bree Walker missed a spot on the podium but still managed a top-eight placing in the monobob at the Milano Cortina Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5c159af0301712a7a70fb5924b93991</guid></item><item><title>Australian women and children with links to ISIS forced to head back to camp in Syria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/australian-families-with-isis-links-leave-camp-in-syria/106351298</link><description>A group of Australian families with links to Islamic State fighters are forced to turn around after leaving a camp in Syria to try and begin their journey home to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d35a133c23ac9abe8c930ff01e24c75</guid></item><item><title>'Devastated' Australia on the brink of World Cup exit after Sri Lanka's record chase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/cricket-australia-sri-lanka-t20-world-cup-live-blog/106351564</link><description>Australia is on the cusp of a group stage exit from the T20 World Cup after crashing to an eight-wicket loss against tournament co-hosts Sri Lanka.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c69a6c4d3d6ed2d91ae06e9e0fd7374d</guid></item><item><title>The night snow came to Livigno, turning this surreal valley into an even greater paradise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/snow-livigno-winter-olympic-games/106351744</link><description>Livigno is an Italian outlier in more ways than one. Already known for its special tax status and fairytale quality, the town has had a phenomenal dumping of snow, causing a significant shuffling of events.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74681b168ba228a59936a1522013ca77</guid></item><item><title>North Korea builds homes for families of soldiers killed fighting in Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/north-korea-housing-for-soldiers-killed-in-ukraine-war/106351754</link><description>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un unveils new housing development in the country's capital, Pyongyang, to repay the "young martyrs" killed fighting in Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fb5a467f679f84a1526c5a726d07025</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, February 17: 20 years since The Chaser's War on Everything premiered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/the-chasers-war-on-everything-20-year-anniversary/106340294</link><description>The Chaser's War on Everything didn't start the fire, but the embers from the beloved satirical current affairs show are still warm after two decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">745f78b8b02649b29035b0cec81e7085</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor bets on migration politics amid global rightward shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/migration-social-cohesion-language-support-division-policy/106348608</link><description>If migration is treated primarily as a cultural fault line, rather than an economic system embedded in national growth, the debate will remain loud. The structural reform will remain unfinished.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86414a7a131a25b45dbc0a43798c1c16</guid></item><item><title>Robert Duvall, star of The Godfather and Apocalypse Now, dies at 95</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/robert-duvall-star-of-godfather-and-apocalypse-now-dies-at-95/106352132</link><description>Oscar winner Robert Duvall, known for films such as The Godfather and Apocalypse Now, has died at the age of 95.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c557714626458849acf4e2f9e4b0c251</guid></item><item><title>How to decide what type of car insurance is best for you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/how-do-i-know-what-car-insurance-is-best-for-me-/106260688</link><description>Choosing the right car insurance option can feel daunting, but it's the kind of task that it pays to get right. So, how can you decide which type is most suitable for you?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19c1a606228973fe803d3604b38ad3b1</guid></item><item><title>Results show high levels of lead contamination in dust around Hobart, as EPA flags further tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/nyrstar-lead-pollution-epa-tests-hobart/106339682</link><description>High levels of lead contamination have been found in dust samples taken from suburban locations close to Nyrstar's Hobart zinc smelter, documents obtained by the ABC show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df4c929be90ce6716c442950274a84e2</guid></item><item><title>Tradies consider leaving careers over lack of onsite toilets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/tradies-created-go-company-to-help-accessability/106244286</link><description>Tradies are walking out. Not over ability or aptitude but toilets — in a symbol of the sector's persistent barriers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2da70745cc00dda920be7b9032002395</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate hike worries? Here's some good news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/why-the-reserve-bank-interest-rate-hike-may-be-a-one-off/106350914</link><description>Fresh warnings of further rate rises have been enough to send shivers up the collective spine of new homeowners, but if there's any comfort to be had, it's this: Don't believe a word of the forecasts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67fb51f52c86bc4d83c2be7c7d52564e</guid></item><item><title>Anti-slavery commissioner calls for tougher laws amid forced labour concerns for Ansell and Kmart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/anti-slavery-commissioner-tough-laws-dumping-ground-kmart-ansell/106349728</link><description>Australia's anti-slavery commissioner calls for tough new laws forcing companies to take slavery in their supply chains seriously, as Ansell and Kmart face scrutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">304d8b8d78c81209b940b9f107989101</guid></item><item><title>Carlton's Jacob Weitering suffers rib fracture after AFL State of Origin, but cleared of other injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/carlton-jacob-weitering-afl-origin-rib-fracture/106352118</link><description>Carlton star Jacob Weitering has received some good news, with the Blues labelling their injured vice-captain as a "good chance" to feature in opening round.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0f4a31c564ffe953194ddf9d3fbcac4</guid></item><item><title>News quiz: Year of the Horse traditions, zodiac facts and festive customs across Asia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/lunar-new-year-of-the-horse-quiz-china-south-korea-vietnam-asia/106348886</link><description>How much do you know about the Year of the Horse and unique Lunar New Year traditions in Asian countries? Put your knowledge to the test with these 10 questions and see if you're a true Lunar New Year expert!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">664780860b8f5a75f0169a583ee380ca</guid></item><item><title>Irish rugby to investigate racial abuse towards Test debutant Edwin Edogbo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/ireland-rugby-test-debut-edwin-edogbo-racial-abuse/106352164</link><description>The Irish Rugby Football Union has said it will launch an investigation after turning comments off a social media post that congratulated the country's newest Test debutant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">261d685409d12066905edfb9104ada79</guid></item><item><title>Mould, asbestos, collapsed ceilings plague some South Australian schools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/sa-schools-in-need-of-repair/106334244</link><description>Almost two years after a state government report revealed 35 per cent of all buildings within the Department for Education's portfolio were past their design life, many schools are still plagued with issues including mould, asbestos and rotting windows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fabb2b4476c5886be92e1dda09f3283</guid></item><item><title>The Carters and Sartoris mark 70 years of marriage and 70 years as next-door neighbours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/two-broken-hill-couples-mark-70-years-marriage-neighbours/106346892</link><description>A month after Ron and June Carter got married and moved in together, his sister got married and moved in next door. This year marks not just 70 years of marriage for both couples, but 70 years of being next-door neighbours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1af71fd02e8fa3cdecaf30eb2bea72c</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the ISIS-linked families in Syria who want to return to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/who-are-isis-linked-australian-families-in-syria-al-roj-camp/106352074</link><description>Australia has made limited progress in clearing a passage for the Australian women and their children, citing safety issues in and around the camps, and security concerns back home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b94dd1490b366423951626bba907299</guid></item><item><title>Juanella Donovan reflects on People's Choice win at National Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Art Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/artist-juanella-donovan-wins-natsiaa-peoples-choice-award/106350062</link><description>Juanella Donovan has taken out the People's Choice category at the National Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Art Awards for the second time, emerging as the public favourite from more than 200 entries across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">729bb7b7ed08ea9b03a622bdc521303a</guid></item><item><title>Reducing run-off from macadamia farms improves soil but more needed to boost waterways</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/macadamia-farming-study-environmental-agricultural-benefits/106312398</link><description>A new study backs up the agricultural and environmental benefits of certain macadamia farming practices, but the industry says there is still a long way to go in improving waterway health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c45c15852872c7bf72216544f3531dec</guid></item><item><title>Illegal fishing vessels threaten Australia's agricultural sector as biosecurity concerns grow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/farmers-fear-pest-disease-outbreaks-from-illegal-foreign-boats/106349882</link><description>Australian primary producers say they are concerned about the risk of foreign pests crippling entire industries if overseas fishing boats continue to enter the nation's waters illegally.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8f3a85baf70328cdbd85ce22cd6d1ae</guid></item><item><title>A waterfall gushes at Python Pool in WA's Pilbara region.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/a-waterfall-gushes-at-python-pool-in-wa-s-pilbara-region/106349636</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">604d0c1d3c020236aecb16e168ed1c29</guid></item><item><title>Bushwalkers soak in near 'once-in-a-lifetime' waterfall after cyclone in WA's Pilbara</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/bushwalkers-once-in-a-lifetime-waterfall-rain-pilbara/106347066</link><description>The question of whether there is water in Python Pool is often asked around the pubs and message boards of WA's Pilbara. For the moment, the answer is very much yes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bb14e13e825585b5bae41897115415a</guid></item><item><title>Own goal ends Macclesfield's FA Cup fairytale against Brentford</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/fa-cup-macclesfield-brentford-fourth-round/106352296</link><description>Non-league English football club Macclesfield's tremendous FA Cup run has come to an end, falling to Premier League side Brentford.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ef3637794f7ad3aecb3526517be191b</guid></item><item><title>Pod Save America and why Australians remain obssessed with US politics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/pod-save-america-why-australians-are-obssessed-with-us-politics/106327878</link><description>Huge crowds have flocked to live shows for the popular and influential Pod Save America podcast, suggesting Australia's obsession with US politics isn't going away anytime soon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29fd6077abedec21a6c24a6198c4c894</guid></item><item><title>Australia leads the world in moguls skiing. This is why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/australia-winter-olympics-moguls-dominance/106346256</link><description>To the surprise of many, the "beach nation" that is Australia is the best moguls skiing nation on earth. How the team got there is no accident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edc24052fc71a153cb8523cb4c296d67</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Eileen Gu medals despite blizzard, Ilia Malinin breaks his silence — day 10 quick hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/winter-olympics-day-10-quick-hits/106351560</link><description>A Norwegian skier melts down in the Italian cold as the Canadian women's curling team hits back at cheating accusations. Here are the quick hits from day 10 of the Milano Cortina Winter Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3e902ec1235988fcd9d5cb6b4f1c4e4</guid></item><item><title>Emu raids on Nannup's rubbish tip spark growing concerns for mob's health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/nannup-emus-raiding-rubbish-tip/106350754</link><description>Emus raiding Nannup's rubbish tip are ending up with rotisserie chicken bags and piping stuck around their necks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3e26c1bad7063c7a6b6bdb8b3e5b325</guid></item><item><title>Criminal defamation case against Australian writer Murray Hunter withdrawn from Thai court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/australian-writer-murray-hunter-thai-defamation-case-dropped/106352654</link><description>The Malaysian Communications and Multimedia Commission has dropped a criminal defamation case against Australian writer Murray Hunter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e514a70ed3352a28b7274dd1ea2b8e2</guid></item><item><title>Nurses vote to go on strike at Lyell McEwin Hospital as SA government gives immediate pay rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/lyell-mcewin-hospital-nurses-vote-to-strike/106351466</link><description>Nurses and midwives at the Lyell McEwin Hospital remain set to walk off the job for 24 hours on Thursday, with the union saying the government's decision to introduce an immediate 4 per cent pay rise still falls short of expectations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d59c7aa464f39cac1635d8dcebe8a148</guid></item><item><title>Highly infectious 'Super-K' flu strain blamed for skyrocketing cases in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/queensland-influenza-cases-spike-super-k-strain/106350536</link><description>Increasingly low vaccination rates, more summer indoor gatherings and a new mutation of a highly infectious strain are driving the spike in flu cases, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58267ec2596bd9fdcb6c7fc3c97898d3</guid></item><item><title>Albanese says Australian government will not help ISIS-linked families leave Syria or return home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/anthony-albanese-on-isis-families-trying-to-leave-syria/106352492</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese insists the federal government will not repatriate the Australian families with links to Islamic State fighters who remain in Syria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faa866e3881f2d6646422dcbe7b56295</guid></item><item><title>Brain expert recommends learning new skills, taking on new challenges for healthy aging</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/brain-expert-recommends-learning-new-skill-for-healthy-aging/106348814</link><description>A brain health expert says you're never too old to learn new skills, as Queenslanders take on fresh challenges such as Pilates, running, and even a law degree later in life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">116ce8e09c22884efa0ce73a0c1212c2</guid></item><item><title>Plains-wanderer recorded for first time on outback Queensland cattle station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/rare-plains-wanderer-bird-recorded-on-cattle-station/106350256</link><description>A project with dozens of monitoring sites across the Queensland property confirms the presence of the critically endangered plains-wanderer by analysing bird calls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fb6753c73ebbb858ac8b4791fe49656</guid></item><item><title>Victorian government offers cash to try to secure Australian Motorcycle Grand Prix at Phillip Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/phillip-island-moto-gp-financial-lifeline-victorian-tourism/106330292</link><description>The Victorian government offers a financial lifeline to the MotoGP operators in a bid to keep the event on Phillip Island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">865c6031dd633c1a4179fcf4b9c9e5f2</guid></item><item><title>AFL Opening Round concept is 'unbelievably important', Tom Harley says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/afl-tom-harley-says-opening-round-concept-unbelievably-important/106353492</link><description>AFL chief operating officer Tom Harley insists the league's polarising Opening Round is here to stay, declaring it crucial to the competition's growth in northern markets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f27e67960c4dd64be08957056561d2a</guid></item><item><title>Brandan Koschel's antisemitic speech at Sydney March for Australia rally 'abhorrent', says prosecutor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/brandan-koschel-pleads-guilty-australia-day-antisemitic-speech/106353560</link><description>Brandan Koschel was arrested after he appeared on a stage for an open mic session during the anti-immigration March for Australia event in Sydney's Moore Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04cffeec705663059adc4465ec5fdbbb</guid></item><item><title>Former ACT commissioner Vanessa Turnbull-Roberts accuses public servant of sexual assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/vanessa-turnbull-roberts-alleges-sexual-assault/106352482</link><description>Vanessa Turnbull-Roberts says she stepped down as the ACT's first Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander children and young people commissioner to prioritise her safety after being subjected to sexual harassment and sexual assault by a public servant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d6b858d730eb0ebaae68c60183f36f5</guid></item><item><title>Four men again jailed for life for killing Albanian refugee Urim Gjabri in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/adelaide-albanian-refugee-murder-resentencing/106353932</link><description>Four men who faced a retrial over the murder of Albanian refugee Urim Gjabri in Adelaide's north in 2018 are again jailed for life, with the judge saying their crime was motivated by "greed and [a] desire to rob him of the cannabis".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eafda69581afff6cb8a576417c1b7585</guid></item><item><title>Western Australia's demersal fishing ban hits hard in coastal tourist town of Kalbarri</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/western-australia-demersal-fishing-ban-jackie-jarvis-kalbarri/106336464</link><description>People in the coastal tourist town of Kalbarri say they are already suffering the effects of WA's demersal fishing ban, less than two months after it came into force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b2b2f7a818984b5536b032082a9b2cf</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor reveals shadow ministry, elevating Andrew Hastie and Jacinta Nampijinpa Price</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/angus-taylor-preparing-to-unveil-shadow-ministry/106354092</link><description>The new Liberal leader announces his shadow ministry, elevating prominent right-faction supporters including West Australian MP Andrew Hastie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">989975fa7a8805821e114a08b60c7715</guid></item><item><title>Coles downplays meaning of 'Down Down' price tags and advertising in case against ACCC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/coles-accc-federal-court-down-down-promotion/106295044</link><description>Coles downplays what shoppers understood when they saw its "Down Down" price tags, saying "not much", on the second day of a bombshell federal court case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84bff0d113546722f611e198410a65d2</guid></item><item><title>Marquee Canterbury recruit Leo Thompson to miss 10 weeks following calf injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/leo-thompson-calf-injury-canterbury-bulldogs-update/106354494</link><description>Canterbury are dealt a hammer blow for their Las Vegas trip and beyond with prop Leo Thompson ruled out for 10 weeks due to a calf injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">036cfbbaa4ce64c8f213ea7592a8ab1a</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of murdering Canberra grandmother Irma Palasics pleads guilty to burglary charge as trial begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/irma-palasics-trial-begins-as-two-men-face-murder-charge/106348396</link><description>Lawyers for one of two men on trial for the 1999 murder of Canberra grandmother Irma Palasics tell the ACT Supreme Court he was just the lookout, and had nothing to do with her death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3017b2fe29aed44401597cb6ab90de37</guid></item><item><title>Fire crews battle blaze south of Launceston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/bushfire-warning-for-area-south-of-launceston/106355122</link><description>The Tasmania Fire Service has downgraded an emergency bushfire warning for an area south of Launceston, with helicopters and ground crews in attendance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00134fdf7a0cde3533cca8bcab9042fa</guid></item><item><title>Kyneton women's football players greenlit to join Central Victorian Football League</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/kyneton-womens-football-riddell-update-central-league/106354024</link><description>A long-running saga in country women's football is set to close as a central Victorian team that had been left without a competition will now be allowed to play in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54f16d5c55e8c9bba00d01c3d6d165d3</guid></item><item><title>Mobil Oil Australia to pay $16m fine for misleading claims about fuel sold in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/mobil-oil-australia-federal-court-fine-fuel/106354140</link><description>The ACCC said Mobil advertised its Mobil Synergy fuel but did not actually supply the product at the time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c4d1c10dddccaa2bbfc1015123368aa</guid></item><item><title>French Polynesia drug haul hits $2.4 billion in a month as third shipment intercepted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/french-polynesia-third-drug-shipment-cocaine/106352864</link><description>French authorities seized a 2.4-tonne drug shipment near French Polynesia during a joint operation with the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8b05b9703fd79abe25cc2318a523413</guid></item><item><title>Iran launches military drill as US deploys aircraft carrier on eve of nuclear talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/iran-us-military-drill-trump-geneva-nuclear-talks/106353940</link><description>Representatives from the two nations are set to meet in Geneva on Tuesday, local time, as US President Donald Trump tries to curb Tehran's nuclear program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94646181af842a5e1c582c59df894657</guid></item><item><title>Internal review finds almost half of all Queensland Health doctors at risk of burnout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/queensland-health-survey-doctors-clinicians-wellbeing-burnout/106355086</link><description>More than 2,000 doctors responded to the Medical Workforce Wellbeing Survey last year, which polled the wellbeing of medical clinicians state-wide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb62a16d53c341e3190fe492799a2d17</guid></item><item><title>Australian production company Matchbox Pictures to be closed by Universal International Studios</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/matchbox-pictures-closed-universal-international-studios/106355260</link><description>Matchbox Pictures, the local production house behind Dog Park, The Survivors and Secret City, will be closed by its international parent company, Universal International Studios.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78b9d935e059c11895c3efac8807b716</guid></item><item><title>Addin Fonua-Blake and Briton Nikora embrace chance to play State of Origin following eligibility changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/addin-fonua-blake-briton-nikora-state-of-origin/106355576</link><description>Cronulla duo Briton Nikora and Addin Fonua-Blake have both praised the rule changes that will give the pair a chance at State of Origin football they thought had long passed them by.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ec581ac1f034662bed78ff674c00b7</guid></item><item><title>Private health premiums to rise at fastest rate in almost a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/private-health-premiums-increase/106355550</link><description>Private health insurance premiums will rise at their fastest rate in almost a decade, after the federal government approved a 4.41 per cent average increase from April.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cf53e80cc9f8f5821a0c50d3aa7dd87</guid></item><item><title>Jury shown footage of alleged attack on Strathmerton postmaster John Burke</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/maskell-manslaughter-john-burke-strathmerton-service-station/106352992</link><description>A jury in the trial of Troy Maskell, accused of the manslaughter death of 73-year-old John Burke, has watched CCTV footage of the alleged incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41a1f3b7026ae81ae32623b92f63131e</guid></item><item><title>Police drop charges against WIM Resource employee accused of falsifying documents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/wim-resource-murray-wilson-fraud-charges-dropped/106355362</link><description>Victoria Police has dropped all charges against WIM Resource employee Murray Wilson, who worked on the controversial Avonbank Mineral Sands Project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e46ef3f04400c724cf57f4b12383ce25</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106355048</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110518261aa0e4650ee60d7c09f2b830</guid></item><item><title>Mother of former Manly player Keith Titmuss breaks silence on lawsuit against NRL club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/keith-titmuss-mother-speaks-on-manly-sea-eagles-lawsuit/106354504</link><description>The mother of Manly player Keith Titmuss, who died of exertional heat stroke following a 2020 Sea Eagles training session, breaks her silence on her family's multi-million-dollar lawsuit against the NRL club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0be5af7a65024f5d1249c96c36ab639d</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested after fatal Merrylands stabbing escaped care 10 days before attack, health authorities say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/man-arrested-after-merrylands-stabbing-escaped-hospital-care/106356218</link><description>A man arrested after a fatal stabbing in Merrylands escaped from mental health care while being transferred between hospitals more than a week ago, health authorities say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac37a20a68838d5f1d8ead99df730433</guid></item><item><title>Father whose son died in house fire accuses lawyer at coronial inquiry of 'degrading him'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/qld-fatal-fire-inquest-father-outburst/106354862</link><description>The father, in an emotional outburst, told the inquest he had spent thousands of dollars on psychiatric and hypnotherapy appointments so he could move on from the tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2817eed5da4210d086772b41a3286cb6</guid></item><item><title>Sydney’s great fatberg hiding in the sewers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/sydney-s-great-fatberg-hiding-in-the-sewers/106355414</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d86c2192d0e5b5504b2ff2bec1bd22ef</guid></item><item><title>ABC to move Adelaide office to new Tapangka site in CBD, alongside arts organisations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/abc-adelaide-to-move-to-new-cbd-arts-hub/106355280</link><description>The ABC has announced a new location for its Adelaide operations, moving to a new arts and media hub alongside other government arts organisation in the CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">304f07af147679233a1ce91d82d122b7</guid></item><item><title>Grammy-winning songwriter and hitmaker Billy Steinberg dies aged 75</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/grammy-winning-songwriter-billy-steinberg-dies-aged-75/106356348</link><description>Award-winning US songwriter Billy Steinberg, who wrote several top hit songs including Madonna's Like a Virgin, died on Monday aged 75, according to media reports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb0f5e86348cae84a5923360286fcd40</guid></item><item><title>Jail term increased for Roma man who stabbed police officer during call-out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/jail-term-increased-roma-man-stabbed-police-officer/106356242</link><description>A man who stabbed a police officer with a pair of scissors during a domestic violence call-out in regional Queensland has had his jail sentence increased.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb9dc470037d273fcec3966d6535d26a</guid></item><item><title>What is the future for the Whyalla steelworks?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/what-is-the-future-for-the-whyalla-steelworks-/106355456</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ed1eb3056229434e315eb0044020df9</guid></item><item><title>Aussie teen forced to wait for Olympic final as heavy snow wreaks havoc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-day-11-live-blog/106354466</link><description>Australia's Ally Hickman has to wait another day for the women's snowboard slopestyle final, as a snowstorm hits Livigno and causes scheduling delays.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0610df31fc2a456d285c9d60f0eeb066</guid></item><item><title>NSW man kept in custody for safety after allegedly 'squandering' $270k of drug-trade money</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/peter-john-howlett-accused-drug-smuggler-bail-denied/106356372</link><description>Peter John Howlett, who allegedly used a fishing trawler to import illicit drugs into Australia, is refused bail by Mackay magistrate concerned for his safety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc40f61151325b5ea412a6eadaf7b440</guid></item><item><title>Jesse Jackson, civil rights leader and US presidential hopeful, dead at 84</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/civil-rghts-leader-jesse-jackson-dies-age-84/106356528</link><description>The two-time Democratic presidential hopeful remembered for powerful speeches died peacefully surrounded by loved ones, his family said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bef1e4b64b56ce290b7d00444b297818</guid></item><item><title>Australia knocked out of T20 World Cup with one game left to play</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/australia-knocked-out-of-t20-world-cup/106356754</link><description>Australia can no longer catch up with Zimbabwe after it was awarded a point from a rained out match with Ireland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dfa50a4be411761518915d4c45e5985</guid></item><item><title>Richard Roxburgh, Damon Herriman and Toby Schmitz star in 'wickedly funny' play Art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/art-the-play-richard-roxburgh-damon-herriman-toby-schmitz/106051888</link><description>In the 1994 French play Art, Serge spends 160,000 euros on an all-white painting, horrifying his friend Marc. It might just wreck their decades-long friendship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf94795c60e3d3af64640f380e98e6b3</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian salmon industry subject to stricter mortality reporting rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/tas-salmon-mortality-reporting-new-rules/106355012</link><description>Biosecurity Tasmania has introduced stricter requirements for Tasmania's salmon companies reporting on farmed fish deaths — but whether the public finds out is another matter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b4561f315abfbba772d736bf48eab4d</guid></item><item><title>Millionaire Gary Stevenson's dire warning for Australian property market losing the 'fair go'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/economist-gary-stevenson-warns-australia-losing-the-fair-go/106342536</link><description>British economist Gary Stevenson is on a speaking tour, warning Australia will follow the path of the UK with "poverty exploding" unless politicians deal with inequality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f588e11282bda2e3e28ac0a5b4d7af5d</guid></item><item><title>HungryPanda riders say Chinese police intimidating families in China over Sydney protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/hungrypanda-riders-chinese-police-threats-sydney-australia/106353996</link><description>Riders embroiled in a dispute over pay and conditions with food delivery company HungryPanda in Sydney say Chinese police have asserted pressure back home to stop them protesting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00b78e0a081535d928622de443de63b8</guid></item><item><title>Private health insurance customers stung by exclusions after downgrading from gold policies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/private-health-patients-discover-exclusions-downgrade-policy/106325324</link><description>Australians are increasingly downgrading their health cover, with 360,000 people leaving gold policies since 2020. But some have been left out of pocket for surgeries they thought they were covered for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4543069212aa1935d9d011728be77184</guid></item><item><title>Aerials delay is not unusual, as snow causes chaos at Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/aerials-delays-2026-winter-olympics/106356762</link><description>Delays are nothing new in skiing events, with weather and light a constant battle for event organisers. However, the Australian aerials team has an unusual method to handle the disruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f49e711941aae6ee00c9b528308bb80f</guid></item><item><title>Investor's bet on empty building and passionate self-starters transform Charleville CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/young-business-owners-transform-charleville-cbd/106309412</link><description>A few years ago, Charleville's main street had lost its spark, with storefronts empty and windows shuttered. So, what does it take to bring a main street back to life?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab232bf6e0ba3b688550df9ce999546d</guid></item><item><title>Long-term solution to repeated Waterfall Way landslips on the horizon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/long-term-solution-repeated-waterfall-way-landslides/106353438</link><description>The NSW government hopes to reopen a key east-west transport route by April, as a long-term solution to frequent landslips in the area is explored.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93a127abafb503c04ed7b234a9aa7f0e</guid></item><item><title>Australia 'must allow' families with ISIS links to return home from Syria, legal experts say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/un-expert-says-isis-families-should-be-returned-to-australia/106354188</link><description>Australian families with links to Islamic State fighters should be returned to Australia to prevent harm and potential radicalisation of innocent children, according to United Nations special rapporteur Ben Saul.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">818cbd1d6ed9a8cbc938782a467bc2e0</guid></item><item><title>Man who escaped health care facility charged with murder over Merrylands stabbing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/man-charged-with-murder-merrylands-stabbing/106356990</link><description>A 25-year-old man police say stabbed a man to death in Merrylands days after fleeing from health authorities has been charged with murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">870b73a011304ffc3b9433a389ebee53</guid></item><item><title>The young volunteers keeping Brisbane's outer suburbs history alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/young-volunteers-keeping-history-alive/106315108</link><description>Rapid development is changing the look of Brisbane's historic outer suburbs. These young historians are trying to keep the stories from the past alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25218405f785b305100e94999cc2d869</guid></item><item><title>Hindmarsh Island bridge dispute told through Ngarrindjeri women's art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/ngarrindjeri-women-retell-hindmarsh-island-bridge-story/106282804</link><description>In the 1990s, a group of Indigenous women were accused of fabricating claims of sacred sites to stop the construction of a bridge south of Adelaide. It was a decision that has impacted a community for decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c8df9f180475c2f0cfe199f0433a284</guid></item><item><title>Disenfranchised Farrer voters turn out in droves to consider One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/one-nation-farrer-federal-by-election/106354342</link><description>This southern New South Wales town of Gerogery is typically dead on a Monday night, but that all changed when One Nation came to town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfeec7877eeface1749af84fb416ce74</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Highway cut by flooding at Proserpine as coast cops more than 300mm of rain in 24 hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/outback-queensland-communities-prepare-for-major-flooding/106355472</link><description>Parts of the Queensland coast have received more than 300 millimetres of rain in 24 hours, leading to road closures, including the Bruce Highway at Proserpine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b999fa1f13abf874299f6fa93e0343f4</guid></item><item><title>Living across the river from Nyrstar zinc smelter has Jan doing what she can to lower lead risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/living-across-from-nyrstar-hobart-zinc-smelter/106355866</link><description>Jan Twomey bought a house on Hobart's eastern shore just over a year ago, knowing full well it was across from a zinc smelter. But news of high levels of lead detected in dust samples has her concerned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f9c7a6c4056b671696fc0a27e2861ea</guid></item><item><title>OCD is often misunderstood. Elena wants you to know what it feels like</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/elena-ocd-heywire-quiz/106254504</link><description>Elena wants people with OCD to know they're not alone. But how well do Australians understand the condition?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c381c4562a28f911f49f436b138ce17d</guid></item><item><title>Matildas expected to name Mary Fowler in Asian Cup squad, injured Charli Grant set to miss out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/matildas-set-to-gamble-on-fowler-fitness-in-asian-cup-squad/106357060</link><description>Mary Fowler is expected to be named in Australia's Women's Asian Cup squad on Thursday despite having played limited minutes in her return from an ACL injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3411cba4c526944d5b5fb418a7a5f2db</guid></item><item><title>Telstra accused of environmental breaches in culturally-significant area in SA national park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/telstra-investigated-environmental-breach-south-australia-site/106349226</link><description>Sources say the actions will likely affect Aboriginal communities and that the investigation was not shared with the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b5f492e4ab694c6050d7c2fadc97f21</guid></item><item><title>Test results show high levels of lead dust around Hobart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/lead-dust-risk-nyrstar-smelter-in-hobart/106357116</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00dd140169e0498d91069943911894da</guid></item><item><title>Space industry firm Terram Astra launches with plans for outback Northern Territory, South Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/nt-new-outback-space-project-alice-springs-terram-astra/106352872</link><description>A new company sets its sights on the Australian outback, with bold ambitions of creating a high-tech hub capable of communicating with outer space.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cfd735ac65a201f73b2d4a1425fc3ff</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Jürgen Klopp makes Milano Cortina Games cameo, ice hockey fight ban labelled a 'joke' — quick hits from day 11</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-day-11-quick-hits/106356448</link><description>Football manager Jürgen Klopp makes an appearance at the Milano Cortina Games, while French ice hockey players are unhappy about the ban handed to a teammate for fighting. Here are the quick hits from day 11.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9e6fc860b11cec670fa7d512e4c8727</guid></item><item><title>Riverland wine grape growers want to rezone land for housing to exit industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/housing-plan-riverland-wine-grape-crisis-rezoning-land-sa/106243944</link><description>The wine grape industry in South Australia's Riverland continues to face unprecedented levels of uncertainty, as growers look to exit the industry and turn their land into residential housing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b952a8705ecf3fd902de2cb20e0489c</guid></item><item><title>Parkes Shire Council formally opposes controversial waste incinerator</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/parkes-shire-council-objects-to-waste-plant-/106353452</link><description>The Parkes Shire Council has formally objected to controversial plans to dispose of some of Sydney's red-bin rubbish on the edge of its biggest town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d99d0f29b19f948bbe7a21bfd5e94e4</guid></item><item><title>Eungella residents want an alternative exit after Cyclone Koji cuts the range road again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/call-for-road-upgrades-after-cyclone-isolates-north-qld-town/106341980</link><description>The remote mountain community of Eungella was cut off for the second time in three years after Cyclone Koji brought debris down on the range road. After years of inaction, the community want more options when severe weather strikes again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be9369955e49f53b9d4c0f229ec2db27</guid></item><item><title>Daly River flood evacuees threatened with edged weapon in incident outside Darwin evacuation centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/nt-daly-river-flooding-foskey-evacuation-centre-weapon-incident/106354738</link><description>As Daly River flood evacuees near their second full week in Darwin, residents staying at the showgrounds say they feel scared after a group was threatened with an edged weapon on Monday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">442adf31e6390d8dc213bea3d8ab2463</guid></item><item><title>Iran announces temporary closure of Strait of Hormuz during US nuclear talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/iran-announces-closure-of-hormuz-strait-amid-us-nuclear-talks/106356970</link><description>Iran says it temporarily closed the Strait of Hormuz — a vital international shipping route — as it entered a new round of talks with the US over its nuclear capabilities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">811f56dfe4adc1e2398db88c571e6b4b</guid></item><item><title>Federal Court finds factional and 'oppressive' control in South West Aboriginal Medical Service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/factional-disruption-oppression-swams-south-west-wa/106356254</link><description>A federal court judge has found that two board members factionally controlled a South West Indigenous Medical Service and unfairly expelled members to avoid scrutiny and maintain control.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f7c32eb3790c07f0e4455fc6dafbed2</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Writers' Festival announces Randa Abdel-Fattah for 2026 program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/randa-abdel-fattah-to-feature-at-sydney-writers-festival/106357178</link><description>Sydney Writers' Festival has defended featuring Randa Abdel-Fattah on its 2026 program, saying it is "not in the business of cancelling or censoring writers".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27fd50a9ce304983c79c05fe33b13137</guid></item><item><title>Pauline Hanson issues partial apology for suggesting there are no 'good' Muslims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/pauline-hanson-partially-apologises-for-muslim-remarks/106357130</link><description>The One Nation leader qualified her earlier remarks, which had been met with condemnation, while reiterating calls for tougher vetting processes for Muslim migrants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef8666bfdfbfd0c8dffd9a0c82b5b3cd</guid></item><item><title>Foo Fighters announce 2026 Australian stadium tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/foo-fighters-to-tour-australia-2026-dave-grohl-special-guests/106357718</link><description>American rock superstars Foo Fighters will return to Australia for a run of stadium shows before the year is out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a1855fdd5149c72de22208ce0af24ae</guid></item><item><title>Real Madrid star Vinícius Júnior says Benfica's Gianluca Prestianni racially abused him in Champions League match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/champions-league-racism-vinicius-junior-real-madrid-benfica/106357730</link><description>Real Madrid forward Vinícius Júnior accuses an opponent of racially abusing him during a Champions League game against Benfica, leading to the game being halted for nearly 10 minutes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">659589228e0656b84af72920641782c0</guid></item><item><title>Australia's most successful Winter Olympics coach Peter McNiel and how his moguls team led the Milano Cortina gold rush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/australia-winter-olympics-coach-peter-mcniel-moguls/106356920</link><description>With a background in mathematics and an enviable attention to detail, it would be tempting to think of Australian ski coach Peter McNiel as moguls' answer to Moneyball. The truth is far more detailed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">525992813f56d82643171c38d6db94ad</guid></item><item><title>Police release man arrested over Galiwin'ku stabbing death without charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/nt-man-released-without-charge-after-fatal-galiwinku-stabbing/106357704</link><description>Police say a 19-year-old man arrested over the stabbing death of another man, 27, on Elcho Island on Saturday has been released without charge "pending further investigations".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a506da9a67db14560688134793469b6f</guid></item><item><title>Police charge man and woman with cocaine and cannabis offences at Airlie Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/police-charge-man-and-woman-with-drug-offences-at-airlie-beach/106358094</link><description>Two people have been charged after police allegedly found drugs, utensils and cash at an Airlie Beach property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01f78ae7b2f5026f3965a4198f2c5b45</guid></item><item><title>Housing to play part in future of both old and new ABC sites in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/housing-plans-for-new-and-old-abc-adelaide-sites/106357376</link><description>The ABC's managing director says its current Adelaide bureau could be redeveloped in a similar way to an apartment building nearby, while the premier says affordable apartments will still be included on the new CBD site.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">016a01cde2182b1aeb6e120fc901d875</guid></item><item><title>Data reveals 'real wages' position of workers as wage price index lags inflation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/wage-price-index-lags-inflation-real-wages-of-workers/106356432</link><description>Wage rises are not keeping up with inflation, meaning household budgets are being increasingly squeezed with inflation outpacing wages growth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0733d2135573eecb22a5e1c3ad34498</guid></item><item><title>Qld Police seize $100,000 worth of illicit drugs at Airlie Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/100000-dollars-worth-of-illicit-drugs-seized-at-airlie-beach/106358680</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b0e26ce64d29fea2c43d13f8a1a1427</guid></item><item><title>As Donald Trump's first Board of Peace meeting approaches, Indonesians are watching their own president closely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/donald-trump-first-meeting-board-of-peace-indonesian-president/106348628</link><description>Ahead of the inaugural meeting of US President Donald Trump's Board of Peace, charged with leading the way forward in Gaza, Indonesian President Prabowo Subianto faces perhaps his most significant foreign policy test yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d30635e040376ea60c805df9793c8cb</guid></item><item><title>Is it ever a good idea to stay together for the kids?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/should-you-ever-stay-together-for-the-kids/106281890</link><description>When a relationships breaks down, sometimes we think staying in the familiar discomfort is less scary — and even protective — for our kids. But is it ever a good idea to stay in an unhappy relationship for the sake of the children?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbe4bbc74caa9ba1918949fae6630fe1</guid></item><item><title>Legends slam Australia's 'not surprising' T20 World Cup crash out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/aussie-t20-world-cup-eliminated-shock-loss/106359106</link><description>For the first time since 2009, Australia won't advance from the group stage of a cricket World Cup and some of the game's greatest ever players are demanding answers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbd3f4835d2882acc4aa5f3b0c0d541b</guid></item><item><title>Launceston Council scraps 4-day work week plan after backlash from business sector</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/launceston-council-scraps-4-day-work-week-after-backlash/106358434</link><description>A Tasmanian council's move to introduce a four-day work week, in part to attract and retain staff, has been abandoned after pushback by a business lobby group and what has been described as "unacceptable hostility" towards staff on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a5c0f5a516d42058b0f4ea6fedf631a</guid></item><item><title>James Slipper set to play 200th Super Rugby match as ACT Brumbies travel to face Crusaders in Christchurch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/james-slipper-set-to-play-200th-super-rugby-match/106359004</link><description>James Slipper will become the first Australian player to reach the 200-game milestone in Super Rugby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">666672c36683f7dfca20fa7cad0c1916</guid></item><item><title>Chalmers suggests ex-RBA governor's spending critique is due to personal vendetta</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/chalmers-dismisses-criticism-from-philip-lowe/106359398</link><description>Treasurer Jim Chalmers says Philip Lowe was critical of the government over spending because it did not re-appoint him as RBA governor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4578c9f616d6026ee0f378a69efa25e</guid></item><item><title>Mazda, Nissan, Hyundai and Subaru face multi-million-dollar penalties under NVES</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/new-vehicle-efficiency-standard-results-mazda-nissan-penalties/106358770</link><description>Major car brands are staring down the barrel of multi-million-dollar penalties for exceeding their emissions, the first results of the federal government's climate laws for new vehicles have revealed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45198840bd21329442d531c79bcbff0d</guid></item><item><title>Planned nurse strike rescheduled at Lyell McEwin Hospital amid pay dispute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/nurses-strike-rescheduled-at-lyell-mcewin-hospital/106357820</link><description>The South Australian government says plans from Lyell McEwin Hospital nurses to strike tomorrow have been postponed, amid an unresolved industrial dispute over pay and conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ffbe0d18fbda24b0ebc0a4110aec457</guid></item><item><title>Brandan Koschel jailed over antisemitic speech at Sydney Australia Day protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/nsw-brandan-koschel-jailed-antisemitic-speech-australia-day/106358160</link><description>Brandan Koschel is jailed after pleading guilty to inciting hatred on the grounds of race during an Australia Day protest in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ef34d325e8991026763f4c848c743ca</guid></item><item><title>Jesse Jackson helped lay the groundwork for Barack Obama and kept the fight for justice in the public eye</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/jesse-jackson-groundwork-for-americas-first-black-president/106359248</link><description>Reverend Jesse Jackson, who died on Tuesday aged 84, leaves behind a towering legacy in politics and the fight for justice in the United States and abroad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0665d46428bd50fafd1d8f2ab4989a0</guid></item><item><title>'Thunderous applause' as vicarious liability laws pass Victoria's upper house</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/vicarious-liability-legislation-passes-in-the-upper-house/106359120</link><description>A bill reversing a High Court decision that found the Catholic Church could not be sued for the actions of a priest passes unopposed through Victoria's upper house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fe6a4d7c63aa01a9a0145cad8065175</guid></item><item><title>Alcoa hit with record fine for unlawfully clearing WA jarrah forests for bauxite mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/alcoa-fined-for-clearing-jarrah-forest-for-bauxite-mine/106359988</link><description>US mining giant Alcoa is forced to pay $55 million after unlawfully clearing parts of a Western Australian native forest to mine bauxite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f74bb47c6f321183a916fc154005c8ee</guid></item><item><title>Former Coles manager admits 'human error' over Shapes 'Down Down' pricing in federal court showdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/coles-accc-discounts-federal-court/106358474</link><description>A former Coles manager has given evidence in the federal court on day three of a bombshell case between the consumer watchdog and supermarket giant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fac3387b11a41f3cb04ca5d82d1e043</guid></item><item><title>Man blamed dog for baby's death at Queensland caravan park, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/baby-death-caravan-park-queensland-robert-alan-gee/106359034</link><description>The man became frustrated with five-week-old's crying, violently shook him and threw him onto a couch, the court heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed0f0d4317c0d7888568f64ef9ef6407</guid></item><item><title>Australian citizen with ISIS links in Syria hit with exclusion order, federal government says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/australia-issues-teo-against-isis-linked-citizen-in-syria-camp/106360092</link><description>The federal government has temporarily banned an Australian citizen linked to ISIS fighters from returning home from Syria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c976fea9e60fc65335285f7b529e237</guid></item><item><title>Sovereign citizen convicted of stalking, intimidating NSW police officer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/sovereign-citizen-convicted-stalking-nsw-police-officer/106358344</link><description>A man who a court heard fell victim to an "explosion" of extremist views and misinformation has been convicted of stalking and intimidating a Hunter Valley police officer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdbc509ea6d1c30a9a567cae09c0215e</guid></item><item><title>Victoria loses Australian MotoGP with 2026 race to be last in state</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/victoria-loses-motogp-after-refusing-to-move-from-phillip-island/106360086</link><description>Victoria loses the rights to host the Australian Motorcycle Grand Prix, ending a three-decade association with the event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfccc65e1d8b9b3f86fe36579af25b73</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Macarthur FC captain Ulises Dávila fined $11k over A-League card fixing saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/ex-a-league-captain-ulises-d%C3%A1vila-fined-over-betting-scandal/106358086</link><description>Former Macarthur FC captain Ulises Dávila avoids jail time over his involvement in a card fixing scandal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d649323fcbad3f77ec947285f3251da</guid></item><item><title>Overnight rain at Kilto Station.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/overnight-rain-at-kilto-station/106359962</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cb8089671d57d545b956c3341acefb5</guid></item><item><title>Heavy rainfall in WA's Kimberley sees students go to extra lengths to get to school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/broome-water-kimberley-heavy-rainfall-hard-school/106359220</link><description>Heavy rainfall in WA's far north has led to some students having to make alternative arrangements to get to school, including using a helicopter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab169a794f18ae909f63b27c1c12f38f</guid></item><item><title>Blue Bush Floodway enjoyed by all.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/blue-bush-floodway-enjoyed-by-all/106360146</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbd2f162df0e8fed005d6a35a8340a73</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106359046</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">077e4b34cad227fccef803151960b1af</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 12</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide/106357404</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5927607c6b226a4fc3cd81eec0fa5c61</guid></item><item><title>Queensland man accused of offering $730 to adopt and abuse overseas children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/qld-man-refused-bail-over-alleged-child-sex-procurement-plot/106360740</link><description>A Queensland man accused of offering to pay more than $700 to adopt children overseas so he could have sex with them is refused bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0adc407b09567e623482d48b0cf6af66</guid></item><item><title>Ex-cop granted bail over alleged stalking following neighbour dispute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/ex-cop-granted-bail-over-alleged-stalking-charges/106359998</link><description>A former Queensland police officer accused of allegedly wearing a balaclava and Easter bonnet to harass and intimidate a neighbouring family has been granted bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aea69af313928f8cdfdf95d42f0e5112</guid></item><item><title>Man fined $32,000 for poaching rare snakes from Far North Queensland rainforest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/man-fined-for-poaching-rare-snakes/106360544</link><description>The court heard Clinton Spiteri was with two others when he visited a rainforest in the Cape York area to steal eight snakes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e054b8dba8caac08516c2d5f4789e82</guid></item><item><title>More delays for Winter Olympics as 'severe' weather approaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/winter-olympics-day-12-live-blog/106358928</link><description>Milano Cortina organisers have been forced to postpone the men's aerials event, featuring Australian Reilly Flanagan, due to another forecast of inclement weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1afa317592e146df44942abefc37c8a4</guid></item><item><title>Should the ISIS brides be allowed to return to Australia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/should-the-isis-brides-be-allowed-to-return-to-australia-/106360436</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">028d6caee7cc69d021c5f5eb7ced7db5</guid></item><item><title>South Australia could host the Australian Motorcycle Grand Prix from 2027</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/sa-could-host-the-australian-motogp/106360386</link><description>An announcement on the future of the Australian Motorcycle Grand Prix is expected as soon as Thursday amid widespread speculation the event is set to shift to South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b26fba3656006cb6dacc897cffc47d8</guid></item><item><title>Driver charged over Camden fatal crash escaped Cumberland Hospital mental health care before incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/cumberland-hospital-patient-absconded-before-camden-fatal-crash/106361010</link><description>A driver charged over a double-fatal crash used a staff pass to escape hospital the day before an alleged Sydney stabber fled the same mental health facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9b460c845ba44fdb8e18d6fdf3752c5</guid></item><item><title>Tackling 'blatant' fake discounting, restoring consumer trust among ACCC's priorities for 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/accc-outlines-priorities-for-2026-including-fake-discounting/106359994</link><description>ACCC chair Gina Cass-Gottlieb outlines the consumer watchdog's priorities for 2026, including targeting "blatant" fake discounting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2937ff2740ca14e3dac8a4082576d74e</guid></item><item><title>Danielle Scott wins silver medal in women's aerials event at 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/winter-olympics-dani-scott-silver-womens-aerials/106361098</link><description>Danielle Scott ends a 12-year drought for Australia by winning the silver medal in the women's aerials final at the Milano Cortina Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3820d5e835f545e590e5477cd6c61b06</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine reclaims more than 200 square kilometres of territory as Elon Musk blocks Russian army's internet access</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/ukraine-reclaims-territory-as-musk-blocks-russian-army-internet/106356642</link><description>Ukraine has made its largest battlefield gains in more than two and a half years, retaking more than 200 square kilometres of its territory from Russia in just five days, according to a new analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e4eeb80452a2963e88ee75deff26d71</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic pioneer John King Davis's grave was unmarked – until now</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/unmarked-grave-of-antarctic-pioneer-john-king-davis-found/106357712</link><description>Captain John King Davis was one of Australia's greatest Antarctic explorers, but for decades, his final resting place was an unmarked grave in Melbourne. Today, that will change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f55c0796c4ce772d58aac0922060d57</guid></item><item><title>Underground car park at Macquarie Point stadium no longer in plans, Hobart councillors told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/macquarie-point-stadium-car-park-axed-from-plan/106353980</link><description>Nearly a quarter of attendees are expected to drive to Tasmania's new AFL stadium, but the local council says it's been told an underground car park is no longer part of site plans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cb3bc337880f91f94b2e083ba92ba36</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian EPA drops plan to implement tighter lead controls after pushback from Nyrstar smelter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/epa-folds-after-nyrstar-pushback-on-tougher-lead-emissions/106352924</link><description>Three years ago, Tasmania's environment watchdog proposed to tighten lead emission limits from Hobart's zinc smelter to bring the state into line with national standards — but after pushback from the operator, that plan was dropped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8b8d1991b39bb3d2dd77b421c60cd3b</guid></item><item><title>Mary Fowler named in Matildas Women's Asian Cup squad, Sam Kerr to captain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/matildas-womens-asian-cup-squad-mary-fowler-return-sam-kerr/106358720</link><description>Considered the Matildas' X-factor, Mary Fowler has been named in the Women's Asian Cup squad, just 10 months after sustaining an ACL injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94e1148a75a920a6b5eef99a0cdf14d1</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, February 19: Britpop, beats and a lust for life on Trainspotting's deathless soundtrack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/trainspotting-soundtrack-30th-anniversary-danny-boyle-britpop/106354570</link><description>Most films are lucky to get just one needle-drop moment embedded in the Zeitgeist. Trainspotting boasted several.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ab3fc2c71c82699927e06d1a58d6cf7</guid></item><item><title>Quiz: Which books are these literary quotes from?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/famous-book-quotes-quiz/106321984</link><description>Are you happiest with your nose in a book? Did you spend summer reading at the beach? This quiz is for you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93263cc459c19ed242af066f07f52020</guid></item><item><title>Government spending is creeping up and threatening Australia’s 'low-debt' status</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/government-spending-threatening-australias-low-debt-status/105579046</link><description>Australia will cease to be a low-debt country and be more vulnerable in a future crisis without a combination of spending restraint and tax reform, a new report has warned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13ac01b1668865c59fb5bf518f92a919</guid></item><item><title>Senate committee features climate disinformation, the Atlas Network, and Dr Karl's clash with One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/climate-disinformation-senate-committee-dr-karl-atlas-network/106350002</link><description>The scourge of AI-slopaganda, viral disinformation campaigns and online attacks against individuals and institutions is going to get far worse before it gets better, if the latest public hearings on the topic are any indication.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc806ab7e06e7cc45d048d4f225dbed0</guid></item><item><title>Trump official says US did not censor Colbert interview but is probing The View</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/fcc-confirms-investigation-into-the-view/106361394</link><description>The confirmation of a probe into the daytime talk show came after it interviewed the same Democratic candidate whose interview with Stephen Colbert was allegedly barred from airing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00896e420fd548e96575bb0b6c4b91f3</guid></item><item><title>Perth couple Jonathan and Amy Carr-Knox locked in international surrogacy battle to bring home daughter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/battle-bring-home-sophie-after-surrogacy-red-tape-argentina/106126626</link><description>Jonathan and Amy had a child via surrogacy in Argentina. They have been stuck there for 12 months, unable to bring their daughter home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e1192412c2820ccafbe31fa94aa760c</guid></item><item><title>Danielle Scott's Winter Olympic silver ends years of pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/danielle-scott-aerials-silver-medal-2026-winter-olympics/106361322</link><description>In this most tension-filled Winter Olympic sport, it's no wonder tears are a by-product of both success and failure. Thankfully for Dani Scott, this time she was crying tears of pure joy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e5d5a3ecb08453f6f6bb9cdeaccc263</guid></item><item><title>Renewable energy company abandons native title court application over Darwin solar farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/darwin-solar-farm-court-application-abandoned/106357534</link><description>A renewable energy company planning to build a solar farm near Darwin withdraws a court application that traditional owners argued would "erase" their rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16119d56006ff2c8aae6209ef2b53cf7</guid></item><item><title>Could SA Liberal leader Ashton Hurn lose her seat at the next election?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/could-ashton-hurn-lose-her-seat-at-the-next-sa-election/106357818</link><description>It's an almost unthinkable scenario, but the fact it's even being discussed shows the extent of the Liberal Party's predicament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9786f949730f20ebd11b7fd76ff59c7f</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs churches work together to serve community during Lent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/alice-springs-churches-work-together-for-lent/106360090</link><description>Nearly 300 parishioners attended Ash Wednesday mass in churches across Alice Springs yesterday to mark the start of Lent and begin 40 days of fasting leading up to Easter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abdefb0926bfd9149a1729b5da32bcd5</guid></item><item><title>Eight back-country skiers found dead, one missing after avalanche in California</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/eight-skiers-found-dead-after-avalanche-in-california/106361508</link><description>Eight skiers have been found dead and one is missing after an avalanche in California, making it the deadliest avalanche in the US in forty years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efb463cd4b229ad526424b48c504d1a7</guid></item><item><title>Advocates call for more accessible cool spaces for people with heat regulation impairments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/heat-regulation-impairments-urban-planning-disabilities-sa/106348980</link><description>With heatwave events set to be more frequent across the country, researchers say thermoregulation must be part of urban planning to avoid risking the lives of people with heat regulation impairments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">216a8c869b4587c68f7909785495ccb2</guid></item><item><title>Court documents reveal messages between Chinese official and trio accused of foreign interference</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/court-releases-accused-chinese-spy-correspondence/106361016</link><description>The police case relies on WeChat communication allegedly between the trio in Australia and a person at China's Public Security Bureau.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be6195ffc2e68e452832a76360e909da</guid></item><item><title>PM says he 'has nothing but contempt' for women in Syria linked to ISIS — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/federal-politics-live-blog-australians-isis-syria/106361474</link><description>The prime minister says he has "nothing but contempt" for Australian women who travelled to Syria to join ISIS.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80178581b7509cf8fa5d7e51e9704896</guid></item><item><title>Cherbourg turns to emerging technology while it waits for $26m water treatment plant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/cherbourg-uses-new-atmospheric-water-generation-technology/106359278</link><description>Just three hours from Brisbane, the residents of Cherbourg need to boil the town water to make it safe to drink. Delays to a new water treatment plant have driven them to use emerging technology that creates clean water from thin air.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">266c61156c671a486ddd0d7e7b72d819</guid></item><item><title>Fiji's former prime minister Frank Bainimarama charged with inciting mutiny</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/former-fiji-prime-minister-bainimarama-arrested-charged-mutiny/106360516</link><description>Long-serving Fiji prime minister Frank Bainimarama and a former police commissioner will face court on Tuesday on charges of mutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfb056a8d72b38a8175534edc2ea18aa</guid></item><item><title>Live: ASX follows Wall Street higher, unemployment steady</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/106361544</link><description>While the unemployment rate remains steady, the ASX opened strongly on the back of a batch of solid results. Follow the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4078cdb537970968fcf1992614fe87b4</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Dog invades cross-country skiing, Americans get engaged as Ally Hickman feels the pain — day 12 quick hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/winter-olympics-day-12-quick-hits/106360904</link><description>A pair of US athletes announce their engagement as Ally Hickman's medal bid turns sour and a dog steals the show at the cross-country skiing. Here are the quick hits from day 12 at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd59fe51c584fb48b6564fd085361a09</guid></item><item><title>Moyne Shire Council never wanted Port Fairy's pool, yet it paid $3.4m for it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/port-fairy-pool-moyne-shire-cost-belfast-aquatics/106345296</link><description>A Victorian community group promised its local shire a new pool would not cost it money once it was built. In less than three months, the promise was broken.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8cfb04cc8a00decf70f2adc47081828</guid></item><item><title>Outback families hope for change amid review into Queensland Patient Travel Subsidy Scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/travel-subsidy-scheme-review-outback-queensland-patients/106358404</link><description>The cost of living is hurting outback residents who need to travel for medical treatment. They say government subsidies need to increase as the price of everything continues to rise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d837333d6979b3e02127123d5a34593</guid></item><item><title>James and Sophie among West Australians keen to give back as regional doctors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/kalgoorlie-students-following-dreams-medical-career/106325718</link><description>After graduating six years apart at the same high school in Kalgoorlie, both James Gent and Sophie Barton are following their dream of becoming a doctor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74f984707ff32b96a738d83a30123435</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Channel Nine reporter Danika Mason apologises after viral Today show cross</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/winter-olympics-2026-danika-mason-channel-nine-live-cross/106361740</link><description>Danika Mason has apologised for letting her standards slip during a live cross to the Today show from the Winter Olympics in Milano Cortina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">587053632e396210a542b81ba13dccca</guid></item><item><title>Mark Zuckerberg tells court Meta no longer designs apps to maximise screen time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/meta-ceo-mark-zuckerberg-trial-over-youth-social-media-addiction/106361496</link><description>The Meta chief executive's comments were made in a landmark trial over youth social media addiction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0f5700c9189cbb596e9bc5000e1c747</guid></item><item><title>Indian university kicked out of summit for falsely claiming credit for Chinese-made robotic dog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/chinese-robotic-dog-indian-university-kicked-out-of-ai-summit/106361756</link><description>An Indian professor has sparked ridicule after falsely suggesting a commercially available Chinese robot dog displayed at a major AI summit in New Delhi was developed by her university.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f29670d2a9fcccc5e0e68270b1dfb47f</guid></item><item><title>Home and businesses raided as Darwin NDIA employee arrested for alleged $5m NDIS fraud</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/darwin-ndia-employee-arrested-for-alleged-5m-ndis-fraud/106361742</link><description>A 47-year-old Darwin public servant has been arrested and charged for allegedly defrauding $5 million from the National Disability Insurance Scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08c4965dbddd6b1045f2d272a06f8834</guid></item><item><title>After this Sydney cathedral burnt down, the priest forgave the arsonist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/priest-forgives-parramatta-church-arsonist-30-years/106329456</link><description>John Boyle says Corrective Services officers suspected he wanted to harm the man who torched St Patrick's Cathedral in 1996, but the Sydney priest's only intention was to practice what he preached.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b92856641bb878ff725aaa80c7a2b025</guid></item><item><title>Midwest farmers want Defence action on explosive risk after fire at Depot Hill wildflower reserve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/farmers-want-answers-midwest-bushfire-explosive-risk/106332262</link><description>Residents are calling for clarity and action over the risk of unexploded WWII ordnance after a popular wildflower reserve was torched in WA's Midwest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af835f318aa5ac64f28c3077c486b11b</guid></item><item><title>From crime heists to a BDSM love story, here's what's in cinemas this month</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/what-to-watch-movies-february-pillion-crime-101/106352928</link><description>Australians will also finally be able to catch Sirât and The Voice of Hind Rajab, two movies that will be vying for Best International Film at the Academy Awards next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8040a86763a5a4d748d6c02c57f6603a</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane's Lang Park concert cap almost doubles under new trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/qld-lang-park-suncorp-concert-limit-to-almost-double/106360994</link><description>A one-year trial will see the number of concerts at Brisbane's Lang Park almost double from 12 to 21 per year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e40403a7bf49eabd7e064b1ff94cddfd</guid></item><item><title>How exclusion orders could ban Australian citizens from returning home indefinitely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/australian-citizens-banned-returning-overseas-exclusion-orders/106361634</link><description>One of the Australian women being held in a Syrian refugee camp has been barred from returning home after being given a temporary exclusion order — but the ban may not be as temporary as the name implies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b69ea4e5ccbec5d9f3ed7794e281795c</guid></item><item><title>Lakemba Mosque calls for more security after third threatening letter as Ramadan begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/lakemba-mosque-third-threatening-letter/106361678</link><description>Another threatening letter has been sent to Lakemba Mosque in Sydney's west, the third in recent weeks just hours before the start of Ramadan on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e08c365e2757731d8a0052e8d565fb82</guid></item><item><title>SA secures Australian MotoGP, world-first street circuit announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/sa-secures-motogp-world-first-street-circuit-announced/106361722</link><description>The South Australian government has confirmed the Australian MotoGP will move to Adelaide from 2027, bringing with it huge economic benefits, but the opposition and Greens say the state has other priorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a957e6c008c2cd348424eaa2acecad49</guid></item><item><title>The Kyneton women's football team's story was always about more than just one club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/kyneton-womens-football-story-widespread-issue/106338680</link><description>The women's team from Kyneton's 15-month public and bitter saga suggests it is the canary in the coal mine of a widespread issue for women's players across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af213a5a4c0ac76bfd7fb9926ae5b4ef</guid></item><item><title>Unemployment rate remains at 4.1pc in January</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/unemployment-rate-australia-january-2026-steady/106362428</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate remained at 4.1 per cent in January, with 17,800 more employed people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3deb22f01e8aa72f8fccc75f74faf25b</guid></item><item><title>Canberra bar declared a crime scene as police seize 'clearly satirical' posters under new Commonwealth hate laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/canberra-bar-declared-crime-scene-displaying-posters/106361644</link><description>Police have seized five posters on display in the window of a Canberra bar, declaring a "crime scene" while they investigate the artworks under new Commonwealth hate laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28f4acd2c8de3673dff101dd5a9f181e</guid></item><item><title>Feed and water supplies dry up in NSW as drought tightens grip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/drought-tightens-grip-nsw-feed-water-supplies-dry-up/106360686</link><description>Over this season's hot and dry summer in New South Wales, farmer Ryan Staniforth has spent much of his time carting water to keep his sheep alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46db9976c248632ce753eccaa9b15e80</guid></item><item><title>BlueScope remains in race for Whyalla steelworks as analyst warns of market concentration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/bluescope-and-foreign-bidders-race-to-buy-whyalla-steelworks-sa/106358600</link><description>Twelve months since the Whyalla steelworks was forced into administration, the sale process has entered its final stages, with the number of interested buyers narrowing from a field of 70 to five. Only one is an Australian-based bidder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4978ed303afd5ee0b5a590f6ec370084</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Pickering on his ADHD, satire and the 'ludicrous' Trump era</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/charlie-pickering-the-weekly-interview/106307588</link><description>Political satire occasionally comes at a price, but Charlie Pickering still believes the right joke at the right time can have a huge impact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7c1acd1c8fd008196d50eecb9154256</guid></item><item><title>The heartwarming tribute to injured aerials star Laura Peel at the Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/heartwarming-aerials-tribute-laura-peel/106361392</link><description>This Winter Olympics aerials competition saw plenty of Aussies achieve lifetime goals, but they never forgot the one person who was missing — injured champion Laura Peel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">837dd8955b1207595385711ea5af7ba8</guid></item><item><title>Wayne Gardner, Casey Stoner slam Victorian government over Phillip Island MotoGP loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/phillip-island-motogp-loss-wayne-gardner-casey-stoner/106361880</link><description>Former Australian Motorcycle Grand Prix winner Wayne Gardner has lashed out at the Victorian government over the loss of the Phillip Island MotoGP, saying he has been left "disappointed" and "sad" by the decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf3ff0ae76acea3e2fe354f880cbf507</guid></item><item><title>Wayne Gardner disappointed Victoria won't host Australian MotoGP</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/former-motogp-champion-disappointed/106363350</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">431dc933aa3e70b73ec6f2262d8685f3</guid></item><item><title>Labor opposition propose five-day kindergarten for Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/tas-labor-announces-five-day-kinder-policy/106362388</link><description>Tasmania's state opposition unveils a policy to extend kindergarten to five days a week in an effort to tackle the state's underperforming education system, but the government says Labor is "light on details".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20d131e8503e551f43bd2fd1d742e601</guid></item><item><title>Premier Chris Minns questions what went wrong amid Cumberland Hospital patient escapes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/nsw-premier-chris-minns-concerned-by-cumberland-hospital-escapes/106362938</link><description>NSW Premier Chris Minns says it is "deeply distressing" after two mental health patients who escaped from the same Sydney hospital within 24 hours went on to allegedly kill three people between them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40a75e6cfb2d8eb4e72c618a140267a6</guid></item><item><title>Alcoa's environmental record 'disappointing' says WA premier after $55m payment for unlawful jarrah forest clearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/alcoa-environment-record-disappointing-says-roger-cook/106363128</link><description>Roger Cook criticises Alcoa's "disappointing" environmental record, after it agreed to pay $55 million for clearing a native jarrah forest in WA's south without approval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">297fe700fe6b245c2b7d9210aafd3c92</guid></item><item><title>CFS sirens during Macclesfield bushfire reignite debate about technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/cfs-sirens-macclesfield-bushfire-reignite-debate/106360584</link><description>Residents of Macclesfield were woken by a CFS siren at 2am this week as a bushfire threatened, with many saying they would have otherwise kept sleeping as danger edged closer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a841915a4066ca23d9ca8a59bddc59f6</guid></item></channel></rss>