<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 19:31:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hunter S Thompson's wife heard suicide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2005-02-26/hunter-s-thompsons-wife-heard-suicide/1525746</link><description>Anita Thompson was talking on the phone with her husband,"Gonzo" journalist Hunter S Thompson, when she heard the trigger click in the gun the renowned US author used to kill himself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4c23464e39f765ddb82d8b23c7432f0</guid></item><item><title>Helen Garner wins $US150,000 Windham-Campbell prize for non-fiction body of work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2016-03-02/helen-garner-spam-email-200000-windham-campbell-prize/7215622</link><description>When the email first arrived, Australian writer Helen Garner thought somebody was "having her on".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b869a1e18b52f95a7f7cd234fa8a8ed1</guid></item><item><title>Why losing a dog can be harder than losing a relative or friend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-03-15/why-losing-a-dog-can-be-harder-than-losing-a-relative-or-friend/8356594</link><description>Many are embarrassed to publicly show too much grief over the death of a dog, but research has shown just how devastating the loss can be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ddb281f0c71e19eba2785f1abb2a6d6</guid></item><item><title>Cairns children killings: What drove Raina Thaiday to slay eight kids?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-05-04/cairns-children-killings-what-drove-raina-thaiday-slay-8-kids/8492742</link><description>Raina Thaiday's mental health issues went undiagnosed for years until they culminated in an "apocalyptic delusional state" which saw her violently kill her seven children and niece.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50a129868e3cc2ee9b0bd46e53298356</guid></item><item><title>"Strong evidence" of citrus canker in NT</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2018-04-20/citrus-canker-northern-territory/9676776</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">750855eb2d75707489e44bc9baa17d08</guid></item><item><title>Jeffrey Epstein, US financier charged with sex trafficking, found dead in jail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2019-08-10/jeffrey-epstein-found-dead-in-jail-cell/11402808</link><description>American financier Jeffrey Epstein, who was jailed pending trial on federal sex trafficking charges, is found in cardiac arrest in his jail cell and dies at a local hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bbdb916049690bd39ae7b55330c84a7</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew withdraws from public duties, ready to cooperate with authorities over Jeffrey Epstein investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2019-11-21/prince-andrew-withdraws-royal-public-duties-jeffrey-epstein/11723752</link><description>Prince Andrew announces he will withdraw from public duties "for the foreseeable future" after his disastrous interview about his friendship with convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47298c87e98970307799dc9f31bc7d73</guid></item><item><title>Trent Dalton’s Boy Swallows Universe premieres at Queensland Theatre as part of Brisbane Festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2021-09-01/boy-swallows-universe-trent-dalton-queensland-theatre/100414388</link><description>As the adaptation of Trent Dalton's bestselling debut novel Boy Swallows Universe premieres in his hometown, the author celebrates how it invites people from working-class Brisbane to the theatre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">228dbd9ddb5e4e5919fcfacc4af4edb4</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew, Virginia Giuffre reach settlement in civil case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2022-02-16/prince-andrew-giuffre-reach-settlement/100833618</link><description>The Duke of York and Virginia Giuffre reach a settlement in the civil case she brought against him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">518368625da9fdad78d22a09c75d03f3</guid></item><item><title>National Indigenous Fashion Awards in Darwin showcases growing fashion industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2022-08-04/national-indigenous-fashion-awards/101300394</link><description>Indigenous fashion is a gateway to broader recognition of Aboriginal culture, according to one of the people behind the National Indigenous Fashion Awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fd68b14747d5f92dd619dff2e2ffa2d</guid></item><item><title>Cooly Rocks On pin-up models embrace vintage vibes but invert vintage values</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2023-06-10/vintage-vibes-not-values-celebrated-by-cooly-rocks-on-models/102460062</link><description>Pin-up models like Jessica Woods represent a growing community embracing the style and nostalgia of yesteryear while inverting many of its patriarchal views.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bdd9945ad5c753330dd5c0a032d967e</guid></item><item><title>Spotlight forum: the transition to clean energy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2023-10-26/energy-spotlight/103026768</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">644120ae1bf63ea4ccf5fa3e1bc0916a</guid></item><item><title>Boy Swallows Universe: Trent Dalton's novel goes from page to screen in star-studded Netflix adaptation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-01-10/trent-daltons-boy-swallows-universe-series-hits-netflix/103296290</link><description>Trent Dalton's bestselling debut novel Boy Swallows Universe cemented his place in Australia's literary landscape. Now, a seven-part Netflix series is about to bring his epic coming-of-age saga to a global audience.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a81bb7c04e8598dde14494cb0c96aa16</guid></item><item><title>Ways to let go of your childhood belongings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-03-05/what-to-do-with-your-childhood-belongings/103517594</link><description>Every item has history and memories attached, so it's hard to get rid of our childhood belongings. But these tips can help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e3a83e163a62a290bc9e62ba8eae08f</guid></item><item><title>Women in the fashion industry share tips on how to be a more sustainable shopper</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-03-30/women-fashion-industry-how-to-be-a-more-sustainable-shopper/103643678</link><description>Whatever your motivation, re-examining your approach buying clothes can be good for your budget and the planet. We spoke with a stylist, a sustainability advocate and a designer, to get some tips on how to maintain your personal style while being environmentally conscious.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">269268e7ecfd6416256c614134d9b90a</guid></item><item><title>Op shops give away clothes as surging donations put pressure on global fabric recycling system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-07-22/pressure-on-fabric-recycling-system-and-local-op-shops/104103836</link><description>Most of us feel good when we drop off a bag of clothing at an op shop, but stores are receiving so much stock they may have to send some to landfill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2729bf23c810136fc8dff32f8321b2af</guid></item><item><title>How to wash your winter woollen jumpers at home according to textile experts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-09/how-to-wash-your-woollen-jumpers/104195942</link><description>Do you have a woollen jumper you've been giving a precautionary whiff before throwing back on again? Here's how to give it a wash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d521cf989719e98c875d48322afb04e</guid></item><item><title>NT Education Minister Jo Hersey's plan to take truancy fines from Centrelink branded a 'scare tactic'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-11-30/doubts-raised-over-nt-government-truancy-fines-centrelink-plan/104665394</link><description>The NT opposition has criticised a government plan to direct unpaid truancy fines to be taken out of the Centrelink payments as a campaign of "fear and punishment" against parents and says the government doesn't have the jurisdiction to do it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4de6924da9e9a8e907762b472b585f70</guid></item><item><title>Tobacco Wars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-03-04/tobacco-wars/105006876</link><description>Four Corners is the home of Australian investigative journalism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7016c72456df640586fd3d6509bae898</guid></item><item><title>Betrayal of Trust: Australia's Childcare Crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-03-17/betrayal-of-trust/105063150</link><description>Four Corners is the home of Australian investigative journalism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95b04766effe22c7795f5a0edc6a2e16</guid></item><item><title>The Agent Inside</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-21/the-agent-inside/105198860</link><description>Four Corners is the home of Australian investigative journalism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe5267caa680beaa0cc4c1c6c2a8a4fc</guid></item><item><title>Final Fantasy XIV composer Masayoshi Soken on making music that stops the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-29/final-fantasy-xiv-masayoshi-soken-game-show-distant-worlds/105142026</link><description>Video game composer Masayoshi Soken shares how he makes his music part of the full gaming experience.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">438f6dc8459dcdd9a4407d9236ddcf05</guid></item><item><title>Mums turning to video games to bond with kids and de-stress, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-14/mums-playing-video-games-to-bond-with-kids/105272322</link><description>Gaming can bring numerous benefits for mums, research shows, but there is still stigma to be faced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff0b7a247201c9ed66dda9e3b9e4cdd3</guid></item><item><title>Virtual reality gaming 'not dead' but cutting edge technology facing challenges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-16/virtual-reality-games-not-dead-but-tech-challenges-remain/105254626</link><description>While sales decline and game studios close, Australian players and developers say VR gaming is "a stable niche" with a future full of possibilities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16ec2e066004f1a9108af5b6bc884290</guid></item><item><title>Rock art expert says WA government doctored elements of Murujuga rock art report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-27/murujuga-rock-art-benjamin-smith-government-cover-up/105342280</link><description>One of the world's leading rock art specialists accuses the WA government of burying evidence that shows current pollution levels in the state's north has left ancient petroglyphs resembling "Swiss cheese".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f5277360e66fa7256c2aa83c6b01d10</guid></item><item><title>Northam shire to remove more works of artist Kirk Garlett convicted of child sex offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-30/child-sex-offencer-kirk-garlett-artwork-removed-northam/105348864</link><description>The Shire of Northam will remove two more of Kirk Garlett's paintings from public display after the artist was jailed for possessing child exploitation material.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec2fc96f611eefd26e6dd330b8492f42</guid></item><item><title>Retro gaming's nostalgia-fuelled evolution from niche hobby to global subculture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-06-14/how-retro-video-games-obsolete-collectors-items/105331068</link><description>Not so long ago, old video games and consoles were the kind of thing you found in hard rubbish — or maybe at a garage sale. Now, they're collectibles. Sometimes extremely valuable ones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ece9938cdda38a4ca8c62dc0bc8e2401</guid></item><item><title>Concerns upcoming NDIS price changes could force providers to stop out of office services</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-06-28/act-support-providers-struggle-make-sense-ndia-pricing-review/105469646</link><description>Canberra therapy providers say looming changes to the National Disability Insurance Scheme are "devastating", forcing some to reduce their fees and leaving others staring down another year with no price increase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d3e4c58dea491642bf297175ca6abbc</guid></item><item><title>Basketballer Caitlin Cunningham is a 'health goth' and wants to show sport is for all</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-07-01/caitlin-cunningham-health-goth-basketball-caitlin-dark/105477712</link><description>Caitlin Cunningham, aka Caitlin "Dark", has attracted global attention for sporting full goth make-up on the basketball court — and they want others to embrace self-expression.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">660462a14ccfb6589efe5f27a61b6748</guid></item><item><title>Is $14m and a 10-minute beach trip enough to show the feds care about the algal bloom?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-07-23/sa-toxic-algal-bloom-funding-analysis/105559558</link><description>During his visit to Adelaide, the environment minister bats away criticism about his government's response to SA's algal bloom crisis. Is $14 million and a 10-minute beach inspection enough to show the Commonwealth cares?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d4447d659e1c51031bd370448db972b</guid></item><item><title>Warlpiri elder Ned Jampijinpa Hargraves releases protest song from Yuendumu</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-07-27/warlpiri-elder-ned-jampijinpa-hargraves-releases-protest-song/105571696</link><description>Ned Jampijinpa Hargraves has been at the forefront of the campaign to ban police guns in Indigenous communities, and a new song with his grandson is spreading the message.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91d6fcd73f282295a968f1bfd7a1bf1f</guid></item><item><title>No Return: Australia's Missing Billions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-07-28/no-return:-australias-missing-billions/105582946</link><description>Four Corners is the home of Australian investigative journalism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">013e1bdc9494c22cabc593e1f1f455da</guid></item><item><title>Iconic Kylie Minogue song narrowly missed the Hottest 100 of Australian Songs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-01/hottest-200-101-australian-songs-kylie-minogue-gold-hotpants/105594434</link><description>Wondering where your votes wound up after the Hottest 100 of Australian Songs? You'll find what you're looking for in the other big countdown: The Hottest 200 to 101.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbfebec216aa8d4cd6ce5cbfd3cf2523</guid></item><item><title>Rugby League 26 video game developer hits back at criticism from players who 'should know better'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-02/rugby-league-26-video-game-ross-symons-big-ant/105600772</link><description>After a launch mired by bugs, server outages and criticism around player likenesses, Rugby League 26 video game developer Ross Symons defends his company and says unhappy players "should know better".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3deefa1f41c92a3fc7b2b940bbbad866</guid></item><item><title>Country to Couture fashion show puts First Nations artists in spotlight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-06/country-to-couture-fashion-show-marks-10th-anniversary/105612748</link><description>This week marks the 10th anniversary of Darwin's biggest fashion show, Country to Couture, with the event shining a spotlight on some of Australia's finest First Nations artists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b19cf9b9498cab01157f133fde1d9f3</guid></item><item><title>Model Cindy Rostron named this year's young achiever at the National Indigenous Fashion Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-07/cindy-rostron-young-achiever-national-indigenous-fashion-awards/105621440</link><description>Bununggu and Warraingu model Cindy Rostron is named one of the industry's rising stars in this year's National Indigenous Fashion Awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44f77e4302de1bb924ab7a84d88b331e</guid></item><item><title>Disability job service Forrest Personnel closes amid 'non-viable' federal reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-07/disability-job-service-forrest-personnel-closes-affects-hundreds/105620708</link><description>Disability employment support service Forrest Personnel is shutting down after four decades, saying new contracts offered by the federal government makes the program unviable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d7dd40d1d4a3522f0bfbc211381f942</guid></item><item><title>NATSIAA 2025: Gaypalani Waṉambi wins $100,000 at National Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Art Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-08/natsiaa-2025-winners-gaypalani-wanambi-aboriginal-art-award/105616136</link><description>Gaypalani Waṉambi, daughter of the late Mr Waṉambi, has won the top prize at the National Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Art Awards, for work about an ancient honey hunter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5e5a4d45f6dc4b5778603ec9eb72ff8</guid></item><item><title>Framing My Story shows Ballarat's disability pride in words and photos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-09/ballarat-exhibition-celebrates-disability-pride/105622832</link><description>Ballarat artists share their story with the community, sparking positive conversations about disability and inspiring others to be unapologetically themselves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08dc2c9fa9c879438d2285f3289f2282</guid></item><item><title>Dehydration determined as cause of death for dementia patient missing from Qld hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-13/dementia-patients-walking-out-of-hospitals/105486528</link><description>A coroner rules a dementia patient who disappeared from a regional Queensland hospital in 2023, never to be seen again, died from dehydration. It prompted security changes, but did not stop similar incidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18b6c4334ae32b36966863c403968102</guid></item><item><title>Sunshine Coast residents unsure if homes will be resumed for transport project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-13/mountain-creek-residents-homes-resumption-decision-for-the-wave/105641172</link><description>Residents who hoped their homes would be spared when plans for the Maroochydore rail line fell over still have no certainty over potential resumptions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8455e8e2313d2af7f554a55509713583</guid></item><item><title>Algal levels rising near two Adelaide jetties amid bloom 'buck-passing' claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-14/algal-bloom-testing-shows-rising-levels-near-jetties/105651306</link><description>As the latest water testing results reveal rising algal levels along parts of the Adelaide coast, the opposition says Freedom of Information documents show government "buck-passing" marked the early months of the bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">223217747c93513acee5bd50456b18dc</guid></item><item><title>Australia beats Iran 92-48 in Jeddah to reach FIBA Asia Cup final against China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-17/boomers-beat-iran-to-power-into-asia-cup-final-against-china/105663800</link><description>Australia's spectacular all-round team effort sets up an Asian Cup final with China, brushing aside Iran in Jeddah.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1987369c08a663edfa478f80fd907b59</guid></item><item><title>Boomers hold on to beat China in thriller to claim third straight Asia Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-18/boomers-australia-beats-china-asia-cup-final/105665592</link><description>Australia survives a frantic finish to lift the Asia Cup for the third time in a row with a 90-89 victory over China in Jeddah.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ded37fce7a53d1d6ac08d2617b7907bc</guid></item><item><title>Elder and artist Uncle Rex Greeno remembered as 'universally loved'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-20/tasmanian-aboriginal-elder-uncle-rex-greeno-remembered/105672160</link><description>Uncle Rex Greeno, who became the first Tasmanian Aboriginal man to have a solo exhibition at the Tasmanian Museum and Art Gallery last year, dies aged 83.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24700eb3174da6adc4afd4a116314e1e</guid></item><item><title>Readers on the challenges and guilt around caring for an aging parent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-20/readers-on-caring-for-an-aging-parent/105636350</link><description>From having to give up a job, to feeling like life is on hold, readers share the challenges and guilt around caring for an aging parent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d71547aaf42c37b13df1be1ba55ad4f5</guid></item><item><title>US algal bloom expert suggests modified clay as mitigation measure for SA outbreak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-21/us-algal-bloom-expert-suggests-using-clay-as-mitigation-measure/105667730</link><description>A US scientist invited to South Australia for his algal bloom expertise, says modified clay could be an effective small scale mitigation measure — but warned there is no way to predict when the bloom will disappear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36cc6ee9def633a7979a2c14c53a550e</guid></item><item><title>Jeffrey Epstein accuser Virginia Giuffre posthumous new memoir to be released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-25/virginia-giuffre-memoir-jeffrey-epstein-to-be-released/105692304</link><description>A posthumous memoir by Virginia Giuffre, who alleged she was trafficked for sex to Prince Andrew by Jeffrey Epstein, will be published later this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f8e48cebe58f06941476017e369183b</guid></item><item><title>Laramba Roos defeat Western Aranda Bulldogs in CAFL community grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-25/laramba-roos-beat-western-aranda-bulldogs-in-cafl-grand-final/105694140</link><description>Laramba has defeated Western Aranda to take out the Central Australian Football League senior men's community competition in Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b08d0a66ffd305be74c8a31db9739944</guid></item><item><title>New Queensland Translink app receives scathing reviews as old app is retired</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-29/new-translink-app-receives-scathing-reviews/105711240</link><description>Queensland commuters leave scathing reviews after the state's official public transport app was replaced with a new version that is missing critical features.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2430136228d16e60a42f91cf57aa358</guid></item><item><title>NBL player Ben Griscti waited 90 minutes for ambulance after backboard fell on him at Canberra's AIS Arena</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-02/ambulance-wait-after-nbl-player-injured-backboard-collapse/105724082</link><description>NBL player Ben Griscti fractured a vertebra after a backboard collapsed on him during training, before waiting more than 90 minutes for an ambulance to take him to a nearby hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52e257bb94ababfb236c752d10ae6aad</guid></item><item><title>Scathing report into Libraries ACT finds staffing shortages, burnout and low morale among issues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-03/act-scathing-report-on-libraries-burnout-morale-closures/105725214</link><description>An independent working group has found systemic issues within Libraries ACT, including that workplace culture is affecting morale and contributing to increased closures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09e911c7a610152be1e2ea08e3c63f96</guid></item><item><title>Labor bows to pressure on home care packages and agrees to fund extra 20,000 immediately</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-03/labor-bows-to-pressure-on-home-care-packages/105729668</link><description>After enduring a week of pressure over its delays to aged care reforms, the government has struck a deal with the Coalition to bring funding for home care packages forward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c768d495226bcea427b44a85520e5ac7</guid></item><item><title>Giorgio Armani, legendary Italian fashion designer, dies aged 91</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-04/giorgio-armani-dies-aged-91/105621180</link><description>The Italian founded a fashion empire that became synonymous with elegance, style and Hollywood red carpets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c56832bf10d59e41cee48b034a4a99e</guid></item><item><title>Ballina tip audit shows clothes discarded in near-perfect condition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/ballina-tip-audit-clothing-waste-fast-fashion/105724116</link><description>A Ballina Council audit finds 80 per cent of clothes thrown away are in perfect or near-perfect condition, sometimes with the tags still on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90222814b8fb47e9300798a64966e257</guid></item><item><title>Photographic portrait marking 50-year career of Tina Arena goes on display at National Portrait Gallery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/tina-arena-50-year-career-portrait-gallery/105738816</link><description>The new portrait comes in two parts — known as a diptych — and will be on display at the National Portrait Gallery from September 6 to mark Tina Arena's 50-year career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e901bdd980de79df4a9b723b051c3da6</guid></item><item><title>Giorgio Armani's simple, glamorous designs have always made women feel beautiful</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-06/giorgio-armani-simple-glamorous-designs-women-beautiful/105729572</link><description>It's impossible to overstate the importance of the Armani suit for a woman, both the real thing and every label that followed in his path.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74e3649feaa7e5ef6157944209601479</guid></item><item><title>National Drought Forum convenes in SA to put policy under scrutiny</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/national-drought-forum-convenes-in-sa-farmers-want-policy-review/105739102</link><description>The nation's drought supports will come under scrutiny at a major national forum today as southern farmers continue to battle dry times.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">396bdee2ec757393ed7b2bec61d19392</guid></item><item><title>These images show the damage wrought by the shot hole borer on Hyde Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/these-images-show-the-damage-wrought-by-the-shot/105741042</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af481785da688b26e7b4f6dba03dabb5</guid></item><item><title>South Australia’s algal bloom is ‘apocalyptic’</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/south-australia%E2%80%99s-algal-bloom-is-%E2%80%98apocalyptic%E2%80%99/105759774</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">561ac2215e7614b4599b619c312ea3bd</guid></item><item><title>Inside Perth's gaming addiction clinic — the first in a public hospital in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/video-game-addiction-clinic-fiona-stanley-hospital/105758590</link><description>With gaming disorders estimated to affect hundreds of thousands nationwide, an Australian-first clinic at Fiona Stanley Hospital is helping people who struggle to control their use to turn their lives around.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a697290b8974a67635f6f69c3000a9fb</guid></item><item><title>Service resumes after tram derailment in heart of Gold Coast tourist strip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/gold-coast-tram-derails-in-surfers-paradise-driver-hospitalised/105766496</link><description>Crews worked throughout the night to get services up and running again after a tram derailed and hit a pole in Surfers Paradise on Friday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b04a4994903de4a57a530f5b2238cda</guid></item><item><title>Canberra Catholic Bishop Pat Power remembered as 'outspoken supporter for the poor and marginalised'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/outspoken-catholic-bishop-pat-power-dies-aged-83/105774870</link><description>Bishop Pat Power is being remembered as a much-loved Canberran who leaves a legacy of compassion and hope.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec5fe1ef05799a8c0da662ae50df09c8</guid></item><item><title>Lisa Reihana's exhibition, Voyager, recasts history through an Indigenous lens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/lisa-reihana-ngununggula-exhibition-voyager-indigenous-maori/105760474</link><description>The internationally renowned Maori artist's technically complex, visually mesmerising exhibition spans nearly a decade of artwork.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ed46a76298102094bcf604b8536fb9b</guid></item><item><title>A 3D model displays the 2D levels in Hollow Knight Silksong.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/hollow-knight-3d-level-exploration/105783332</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">521f86c718d53a7270ee9120c8861f67</guid></item><item><title>Rural citizen scientists monitor wildlife activity to help conservation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/rural-landholders-monitor-wildlife-helping-conservation/105774622</link><description>Citizen scientists have collected more than 1.4 million photos and 15,000 hours of audio recordings to help shape the future of conservation management.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7a1f22fdf4d0278c08a2ff9b874099c</guid></item><item><title>ASX slips amid Santos sell-off, weak jobs data and 2035 emissions target — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/asx-markets-business-live-news-sep18-2025/105786834</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate remains steady at 4.2 per cent in August with a decline in full-time employment that drove the overall drop in employment numbers, according to ABS.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c9b52757d4c8bed330dd9676c5f85da</guid></item><item><title>Australian authors give us a glimpse into their book shelves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/-what-are-abc-presenters-reading-/105676714</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a70d451a510b6f8010d66cf89f2de1f</guid></item><item><title>Victor Caulfield moved to Florence in his 70s and became an artists' model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/victor-caulfield-moved-to-florence-and-became-an-artists-model/105762988</link><description>Victor Caulfield packed up his Australian home and moved to Italy, where he fell into the art scene as an accidental model.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf11c6e1cc2bef7d1c59c017a7b1915d</guid></item><item><title>Women celebrate vintage glam, self-love and healthy body image with pin-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/women-embrace-modern-pin-up-culture/105574140</link><description>Women are embracing modern pin-up culture as a way to express confidence and joy in their own skin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccb73a345a28b69e567f342e489c58be</guid></item><item><title>Penola High School's agriculture program revives community and enrolments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/penola-high-school-ag-program-revives-falling-enrolments/105787042</link><description>Cory O'Connor's three-week teaching placement turned around his hometown high school. Now he's receiving an award for the agriculture program he started there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">800678cadea15a18ec482186c893d046</guid></item><item><title>Super Netball's Sunshine Coast Lightning enters new Global Sports Fund Management Group ownership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/super-netball-sunshine-coast-lightning-new-ownership/105801344</link><description>Almost a decade after being co-founded by the Melbourne Storm and University of the Sunshine Coast, Super Netball's Lightning is entering a new era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">725e5769d7aa41a90979ec4d3e47f5bd</guid></item><item><title>Brownlow Medal 2025: All the best fashion looks from AFL's night of nights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-red-carpet-wrap/105802436</link><description>Just after the fashion from this evening's Brownlow Medal? We've got you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8922390581e8430e878c1aa384dd8e2d</guid></item><item><title>Warragul man knocks back dream job after NDIS funding for van rejected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ndis-rejects-van-man-needs-to-drive-to-dream-job/105762830</link><description>Josh Evans, who uses a wheelchair, had to turn down a job with the Bureau of Meteorology because he was unable to get NDIS funding for a vehicle to drive himself to work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21c25c4b57843d7697e914107db94243</guid></item><item><title>Why did the UN escalator stop after Donald and Melania Trump stepped on it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/donald-melania-trump-escalator-teleprompter-un-marcon-call/105810256</link><description>Footage of the US president and his wife's reactions to the mishap was shared widely on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87fdb12fe7af401b7964018acf19bc5f</guid></item><item><title>Elevated E. coli levels recorded at major NT crocodile farm owned by luxury label Hermès</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/lambells-lagoon-crocodile-farm-nt-high-e-coli-levels-in-water/105806340</link><description>One of Australia's largest crocodile farms, owned by a subsidiary of luxury label Hermès, is consistently irrigating with water containing E. coli concentrations almost 500 times the national guidelines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcebaaf92f52cb686dddde475db8c67b</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide 36ers terminate Montrezl Harrell's contract amid China doping case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/montrezl-harrell-dropped-by-36ers-while-doping-ban-continues/105817866</link><description>The Adelaide 36ers terminate Montrezl Harrell's contract while he serves a provisional ban after testing positive for an illicit substance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51284986b60e643af30239de40743cff</guid></item><item><title>When does the RBA meet next? Why aren't we expecting a rate cut?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/when-does-the-rba-meet-next-september/105805912</link><description>Cutting the cash rate results in cheaper mortgage repayments for most people paying off a home loan — but economists aren't generally expecting that to happen this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ceb26b9ef24d8699d82a621f37c5ebb</guid></item><item><title>Why Bad Bunny is a controversial choice to headline Super Bowl half-time show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/why-bad-bunny-is-a-controversial-choice-for-super-bowl/105834094</link><description>Grammy-award winning rapper and singer Bad Bunny receives mixed reactions to the news he will headline the 2026 Super Bowl half-time show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f773b39eed99469859ef72baf7b22b5</guid></item><item><title>What is the Riyadh Comedy Festival? The Saudi Arabia event stirring controversy in Hollywood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/riyadh-comedy-festival-begins-with-pete-davidson-bill-burr/105833686</link><description>The Riyadh Comedy Festival stars A-list comedians like Peter Davidson, but despite its blockbuster acts, it has copped backlash for what one human rights organisation says is a "whitewashing" of a "brutal repression of free speech".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">781f8dbcd30903d7de8068b4d1880cbf</guid></item><item><title>Mark Speakman declares Coalition 'will build metros' if elected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/cost-of-sydney-metro-west-line-could-be-two-billion-dollars-over/105835500</link><description>NSW Opposition Leader Mark Speakman says the Coalition will build new metros if elected, making it a key plank of the Liberal Party's election platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01d28ac9522280924815265bb2c1e1d1</guid></item><item><title>Nicole Kidman files for divorce from Keith Urban after 19 years of marriage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/nicole-kidman-files-for-divorce-keith-urban/105837586</link><description>The Oscar-winning actor files for divorce in a Nashville court a day after reports emerged of the couple's separation, with a source saying the decision to leave was Keith Urban's.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6b869ba2fc37bf31b91a90fcd1870dc</guid></item><item><title>Van Gogh painting among 'rarely seen' collection of art to be exhibited in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/vincent-van-gogh-exhibition-in-adelaide/105834014</link><description>A "rarely seen" collection of works from renowned artists Vincent van Gogh, Claude Monet and Henri Matisse will be on display in Adelaide next year, as part of 57 works on loan from the Toledo Museum of Art in the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0084a43aa4c726640e5a07bb4947f03d</guid></item><item><title>Beloved Aussie author Trent Dalton gets emotional talking about who he writes for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/beloved-aussie-author-trent-dalton-gets-emotional/105835128</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7602f04bbfef792b723bece5e82df61f</guid></item><item><title>When parallel parenting might be needed after separation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/when-parallel-parenting-might-be-needed-after-separation/105762786</link><description>Parallel parenting is an approach that can occur after a high-conflict separation or where there has been family violence, but also when parents simply want space from one another.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ddd7d5d45889b15ac283b481af2b74f</guid></item><item><title>The pros and cons of the expanded home buyer scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/first-homebuyer-scheme-explainer-income-limits-property-caps/105838164</link><description>The revamped scheme has come into effect, with first home buyers of all income levels now able to purchase a property with only a 5 per cent deposit. Here are all the changes explained.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">164b15e14b7ab8348ed381818b59b1cf</guid></item><item><title>Former employees of sunscreen testing lab Princeton Consumer Research blow whistle on alleged questionable practices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/australian-sunscreen-brands-dump-spf-testing-lab-pcr/105841262</link><description>Two former employees of a leading international testing laboratory used by major Australian sunscreen brands have blown the whistle on alleged questionable data and incorrect testing practices, amid ongoing concerns about whether consumers can trust the products they are relying on for sun protection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1829a9601e42cc7008ce391c382c56a0</guid></item><item><title>ASX gains 1.1per cent led by miners and banks, RBA says Australia 'well positioned' as global risks rise — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-oct-2/105841806</link><description>The ASX jumped more than 1 per cent as investors renewed their appetite for risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">030adf06ec31175c91063eb0242a1246</guid></item><item><title>Helen Garner shortlisted for Baillie Gifford Prize for collected diaries, How to End a Story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/helen-garner-diaries-baillie-gifford-prize-how-to-end-a-story/105841834</link><description>This year, Helen Garner has been in Dua Lipa's book club and the SATC spin-off. Now she's in the running for the Baillie Gifford Prize for non-fiction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14369602aedac3875a90957a25b1e898</guid></item><item><title>Hopes new Australian fabric will revitalise domestic clothing manufacturing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/mud-to-marle-project-australian-cotton-wool-blend-fabric/105782204</link><description>Scientists, farmers and the fashion industry collaborate to create a natural fabric that is both woven and knitted, low on emissions and set to shake up how we think about clothing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8786260615151a28c4914c124e51572</guid></item><item><title>Derailed Melbourne train was travelling on a recently upgraded set of tracks, preliminary report says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/derailed-melbourne-train-travelling-on-fresh-tracks-report-finds/105847388</link><description>A Melbourne passenger train that derailed earlier in the year was travelling on a set of tracks that had been upgraded just days earlier, a preliminary report into the incident has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c8a334378ef384e48ad54ed280da149</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fall to 28-14 defeat against All Blacks in Bledisloe Cup contest in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/live-updates-wallabies-vs-all-blacks-bledisloe-cup-perth/105852258</link><description>Australia's hopes of an unlikely Rugby Championship triumph have been extinguished with a 28-14 loss to New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7c86ac526474fe90d71c39a421320a3</guid></item><item><title>Inside the mission to rescue dachshund Valerie from wild 529-day Kangaroo Island ordeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/how-valerie-became-the-worlds-most-notorious-sausage-dog/105832548</link><description>Valerie's disappearance on South Australia's Kangaroo Island unleashed a 529-day hunt. She dodged rescue attempts and traps and had some wondering whether the sausage dog was mocking them and having the time of her life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98688fa4bd2992085d88df58549d292f</guid></item><item><title>ASX falters short of a record, gold and bitcoin jump and Japan surges on news of a new PM — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-october-6/105854602</link><description>The ASX was dragged down by selling in banks outpacing demand for gold and rare earth stocks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be521882fb5d64f5bdf480bb82489fec</guid></item><item><title>Broncos shares surge 40 per cent after Grand Final win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/broncos-shares-surge-40-after-grand-final-win/105858608</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb9f530fa3b53960f57deb774eadfed4</guid></item><item><title>TasTAFE to remove subsidy for lab training, design, media and courses that 'don't align with jobs market'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/tastafe-course-fee-subsidies-cut-tasmania-government/105858120</link><description>Tasmanian TAFE graduates worry as some locally taught courses that helped them forge a career may disappear as the cost to study them increases dramatically.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4047a4692b67df396d06e8970f44855e</guid></item><item><title>New WA program aims to improve access to childcare for children with disabilities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/childcare-children-with-disability-pilot-program-trial-perth/105854018</link><description>An Australian-first pilot program gets underway in WA in the hope of not only giving the parents of children with complex needs a break, but helping them navigate the maze of different support systems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a8e1b30ed0de1380c55df9e7d995ea6</guid></item><item><title>ASX slips as banks, miners, energy stocks sold off, gold hits record high — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/asx-markets-business-live-news-october-7/104980306</link><description>Australia's share market lost ground after financials, energy and mining stocks were sold off, while the gold price hit another record high. Catch up on the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">636e58b8da854c899f6805c4e43597d3</guid></item><item><title>NT government to refer parents for income management if child repeatedly skips school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/nt-government-school-truancy-plan-backlash-education/105856318</link><description>Parents in the NT who frequently fail to send their children to school, without a valid reason, may have their income managed by the Commonwealth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12aae044282aa406d31b3ff38d42c37d</guid></item><item><title>Planning can help save you money this festive season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/preparing-financially-for-christmas-and-holidays/105795388</link><description>Australians estimate Christmas costs them about $800 a year, on average, but planning ahead can reduce the financial burden.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">158e6acd232ffd0c3bea1632ef3d82e3</guid></item><item><title>South Australia declared free from brown rugose fruit virus after more than a year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/south-australia-tomato-virus-free-brown-rugose/105861964</link><description>More than a year since South Australia's $230 million tomato and capsicum sector was plunged into turmoil by the first discovery of the tomato brown rugose fruit virus in Australia, the state has been declared free of the exotic disease.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f9a128f54240cc9f99a036c7afaba14</guid></item><item><title>Scientists win Nobel Prize in Physics for discoveries in quantum mechanics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/scientists-physics-nobel-prize-quantum-mechanics-discovery/105863766</link><description>Three scientists have won the 2025 Nobel Prize in Physics for "the discovery of macroscopic quantum mechanical tunnelling and energy quantisation in an electric circuit".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e33d892453da0aeb26e45b03f8612f75</guid></item><item><title>Australian dollar jumps to 10-month high against yen, ASX slips as gold price hits new record — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/asx-markets-business-live-news-october-8/105864736</link><description>The ASX 200 closes slightly down as gold maintains record highs. The Australian dollar surges against the Japanese yen on speculation its central bank will delay lifting interest rates. Look back on all the day's business and finance news.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">471479ca258fb1f4149bb57c197138cf</guid></item><item><title>Australian merino wool future positive after surging price restores grower confidence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/surging-wool-price-restores-grower-confidence-in-aussie-merino/105845730</link><description>Amid a run of price rises at Australian wool auctions, the next generation of growers say global demand and fresh confidence could mark a turning point for the fibre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a54f47d8d99a1127e10b40056ef58297</guid></item><item><title>Federal support for national Aboriginal art gallery in Alice Springs in doubt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/federal-government-pulls-support-art-gallery-alice-springs/105864926</link><description>The Northern Territory treasurer says the federal government will not support the proposed Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander art gallery in Alice Springs in its current form.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82cf4df7f9637b711426b3da5f97e8be</guid></item><item><title>Trio of scientists awarded Nobel Prize in Chemistry for 'development of metal-organic frameworks'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/nobel-prize-in-chemistry-announced/105868538</link><description>Scientists Susumu Kitagawa, Richard Robson and Omar Yaghi receive the 2025 Nobel Prize in Chemistry "for the development of metal-organic frameworks", the award-giving body announces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f15011661bf2d10170a38ea0db800969</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur wins 50th tennis match for 2025, reaching Shanghai Masters clash with Daniil Medvedev</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/alex-de-minaur-wins-50th-match-of-2025-at-shanghai-masters/105869206</link><description>Alex de Minaur wins 50 matches in a season for the first time in his career as he reaches the quarterfinals at the Shanghai Masters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f318b33e8803f18a1248bbeb3fc659a</guid></item><item><title>Beast of War is the indie shark movie that bit off a lot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/beast-of-war-kiah-roache-turner-mark-coles-smith/105857098</link><description>Mystery Road star Mark Coles Smith and his Beast of War director Kiah Roache-Turner on taking a chomp out of WWII soldiers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c11e53d16ff74618f42da0430ef3787b</guid></item><item><title>Albany's tiny art gallery joins growing global community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/tiny-art-gallery-albany-global-movement/105857528</link><description>A new tiny art gallery on WA's south coast adds to a growing global movement of community verge-side offerings that range from puzzles to seed exchange.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbdc3d5da80b26f3c016522a14117d79</guid></item><item><title>Competition watchdog approves Elders' $475m acquisition of agribusiness rival Delta</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/elders-delta-acquisition-approved-by-accc-competition-watchdog/105869652</link><description>The consumer watchdog has given the go-ahead for Elders to acquire its competitor, Delta, but it must sell six Delta stores in WA to improve competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dda21e910c76f2e0fe579ad341f4b7a</guid></item><item><title>Deloitte caught out using AI in report for federal government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/deloitte-caught-out-using-ai-in-report-for-federal/105874634</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73a40e241a39295c35b76e8f87cb1de6</guid></item><item><title>László Krasznahorkai awarded Nobel Prize in Literature for 'visionary' work that 'reaffirms the power of art'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/l%C3%A1szl%C3%B3-krasznahorkai-nobel-prize-in-literature-2025/105874554</link><description>László Krasznahorkai has been awarded the Nobel Prize in Literature, one of the world's most prestigious writing awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcaabf1e799e51426d25d8a82300fd8f</guid></item><item><title>RBA governor Michele Bullock fronts Senate hearing, ASX ends the week lower — As it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/asx-markets-business-live-news-10-oct/105875398</link><description>Michele Bullock says either shoppers or merchants will have to pay more under the central bank's proposed debit and credit card changes. The ASX closed lower after oil and gold prices retreated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7b054430694d7b28c309ac6d16c7891</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic advances to Shanghai Masters semifinals, qualifier Valentin Vacherot continues fairytale run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/novak-djokovic-advances-to-semifinals-of-shanghai-masters/105875540</link><description>Fourth seed Novak Djokovic battled past a spirited Zizou Bergs 6-3 7-5 on Thursday to reach the Shanghai Masters semifinals for a 10th time, setting up a clash with surprise package and world number 204 Valentin Vacherot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">745b0675e4a5c74aaa50698faa310769</guid></item><item><title>Principals' power to ban aggressive parents from school grounds to extend to social media behaviour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/safety-protections-parents-schools-aggressive-parents-review/105875552</link><description>Principals in Victoria already have the power to ban aggressive or violent parents from school grounds, but the state government is looking to apply the power to parents' behaviour on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cfdbdd1cc62140ca01e0eeea675488e</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur loses 6-4, 6-4 to Daniil Medvedev in Shanghai quarterfinals to miss out on career milestone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/de-minaur-bows-out-to-medvedev-in-shanghai/105880016</link><description>Alex de Minaur is eliminated from the Shanghai Masters, going down 6-4, 6-4 to former world number one Danil Medvedev in the quarterfinals, denying the 26-year-old Australian a chance of his 300th tour win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d00438342ad763a6953e65f8b5283119</guid></item><item><title>Fashion's misogyny problem might end up in your wardrobe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/fashion-gender-equality-dior-chanel-misogyny/105858400</link><description>Men sit at the top of the world's fashion houses while women designers get torn apart online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35cb2c216556832c5dcdb317d8f6718a</guid></item><item><title>Roaring jet boats to return to Victoria for first time in 15 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/jet-boats-find-home-in-elmore-victoria/105865604</link><description>From tractors to jet boats at Elmore, as Victoria prepares to host Australian series jet boat event in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bd1a38cda11cf4c394fc5acf0033196</guid></item><item><title>Genomic medicine could be huge but 5 million Australians may miss out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/genomic-medicine-could-be-huge-but-5-million/105878606</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ed6e2fb9d4d9d0324e237a7c8b62bfe</guid></item><item><title>Las Vegas Aces complete WNBA Finals sweep of Phoenix Mercury with 97–86 win in Game 4</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/wnba-finals-las-vegas-aces-phoenix-mercury-game-four-aja-wilson/105880922</link><description>For the third time in four seasons, the Aces lift the WNBA trophy following an inspired performance from A'ja Wilson in Game 4 of the finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a3bbc2774987c4cdf5cd593c4d51338</guid></item><item><title>Women express disappointment with some Chinese matchmaking platforms in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/women-disappointed-with-some-chinese-matchmaking-platforms-/105844094</link><description>Chinese Australian women are paying thousands of dollars to find love on matchmaking platforms in Australia, but behind the glossy promotions lies a different reality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de33ea3b1474e557375d1f80e4808280</guid></item><item><title>Nick Offerman from Parks and Recreation stars as sovereign citizen Jerry Kane in new movie Sovereign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/nick-offerman-sovereign-citizen-jerry-kane-christian-swegal/105867130</link><description>In Sovereign, Nick Offerman stars as real-life radical-right sovereign citizen Jerry Kane, who, with his son, killed two cops in Arkansas in 2010, drawing parallels to Australian fugitive Dezi Freeman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f83d47504974cf5d7dcf916a63e8e8</guid></item><item><title>Ethan Strange stars as PM's XIII defeat Papua New Guinea 28-10</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/strange-stars-pms-xiii-down-png/105882870</link><description>Ethan Strange underlines his case for Kangaroos selection and Trai Fuller scores four tries in the Prime Minister's XIII 28-10 defeat of Papua New Guinea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eed2497e30235bd850a45f4d7782c62</guid></item><item><title>Taskforce launched as search for Gus expands in SA's mid-north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/search-for-gus-focuses-on-expanded-area-in-outback-sa/105886332</link><description>As SA Police and the Australian Defence Force resume their search for missing four-year-old Gus in South Australia's arid mid-north, authorities have announced a new taskforce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd0d718ad9ecf977e8a8303c21f43125</guid></item><item><title>Noosa mayor says fraudsters used AI imitation in $2.3m council scam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/noosa-council-scam-mayor-blames-ai-imitation/105887962</link><description>The mayor of a small council that lost nearly $2 million in a "sophisticated" scam says international fraudsters were able to "imitate personalities" using AI.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ad393b46f5cfb4651924cd453233651</guid></item><item><title>'Appalling history' of abuse at Mount Penang Juvenile Justice Centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/mount-penang-juvenile-justice-centre-child-abuse-trial/105880634</link><description>A former detainee at a notorious Central Coast juvenile justice facility is suing the state of NSW over alleged sexual abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ea58877b31a0dbb108948f4a003a7ce</guid></item><item><title>Victory in Socceroos' friendly against United States could ease World Cup draw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/socceroos-friendly-against-us-could-impact-world-cup-draw/105890480</link><description>The Socceroos' friendly against the United States is a positive step in their World Cup preparation, while a positive result could also influence their tournament draw.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">818fc0fb7ab727bff2ff2f14d8091448</guid></item><item><title>Indie film producers tell SXSW Sydney about how to survive and thrive making horror</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/sxsw-sydney-indie-producers-on-how-to-survive-making-horror-film/105890988</link><description>Horror films can be a great training ground for filmmakers, but there is also a gritty reality, a panel of indie producers tells SXSW Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1c6edf129ce345474e049a6b56c5528</guid></item><item><title>ACT Director of Public Prosecutions says she may have to turn away some cases if funding not increased</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/act-top-prosecutor-concerned-cases-may-be-dropped/105889058</link><description>The ACT Director of Public Prosecutions says her office does not have enough funding to deal with an increasing annual case load of more than 23,000 charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">847e8e82d9373bc775e40e74105a64c0</guid></item><item><title>Coroner makes rare public statement as NSW records most Indigenous deaths in custody in a year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/nsw-coroner-confirms-12-first-nations-deaths-in-custody-2025/105890400</link><description>NSW Coroner Teresa O'Sullivan's rare public comment on the "entrenched over-representation" of Indigenous prisoners as the state records the most ever in a single year, is welcomed by the grieving family member of a man who died in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7425c8c84b1cdadda86460fb9f8cc6d</guid></item><item><title>Japan makes history as Brazil records 'unacceptable' 3-2 loss in international friendly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/japan-beats-brazil-in-football-international-friendly/105893036</link><description>For the first time in 14 meetings, Japan defeats Brazil 3-2 in their international friendly at a sold-out Tokyo Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6454207cf8d9709c6caca8495b04511c</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos lose 2-1 to USA in international friendly, ending Tony Popovic's unbeaten start</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/live-updates-usa-socceroos-international-friendly-fifa-world-cup/105884330</link><description>The Socceroos suffer defeat for the first time under Tony Popovic, falling to a 2-1 defeat against the USA in Colorado.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ce54438a6647fef94dd054d64e53f08</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, deadline day recap: Zach Merrett stuck at Essendon as Charlie Curnow and Christian Petracca find new homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/afl-trade-period-day-live-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca/105893932</link><description>The clock runs out on deadline day of the AFL trade period, with Hawthorn failing to seal a deal for Zach Merrett, while the Swans hand over a raft of picks to clinch a move for Charlie Curnow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1880fba71c2089a10a592d3d6c29bd87</guid></item><item><title>Search continues for missing bushwalker Daryl Fong in Tasmania's Mount Field National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/search-for-hiker-missing-in-mt-field-national-park-continues/105893390</link><description>Tasmania Police Inspector Luke Horne says gale force winds and deep snows are slowing search crews on day three but they still hold out hope.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">390b73e5cb58f0ab0c47066c89188622</guid></item><item><title>Mother of 11yo girl says sexual offender Shegu Bobb caused trauma to whole family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/act-shegu-bobb-mother-11yo-victim-says-family-traumatised/105894708</link><description>The mother of an 11-year-old girl who was the victim of a Canberra man's sexual offences says his actions have had a lasting impact on her entire family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dc348b1801209be8159885fd820a468</guid></item><item><title>Hamas executes 'collaborators and lawbreakers' in graphic scenes in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/abc-news-verify-hamas-executions-gaza-city/105893350</link><description>Masked gunmen have carried out "extrajudicial executions" in the streets of Gaza City as an expert claims the terror group is trying to regain control of the destroyed enclave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">011b7d02b9a4606194657179c44c731f</guid></item><item><title>Police charge two men after raids on alleged safe houses used by South-East Asian drug gang</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/police-seize-drugs-in-raids-on-south-east-asian-drug-gang/105895348</link><description>Investigators are probing links between a haul of drugs seized on Tuesday and the South-East Asian gang allegedly behind a failed hit in Western Sydney last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b2dd9d3f7b882327d1b570132b6d61c</guid></item><item><title>Victims share trauma at inquiry into stamp duty concession reassessment scheme likened to Robodebt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/act-stamp-duty-concession-scheme-inquiry-robodebt/105894632</link><description>Eighteen months after Canberran Cathy Weeden and her kids purchased a home and left temporary accommodation, she received out-of-the-blue correspondence that she owed $50,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb8ff916f6185052e848dad5135a251b</guid></item><item><title>Three Australian men accused of killing Zivan Radmanovic in Bali could face death penalty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/three-australian-men-could-face-death-penalty-bali/105896428</link><description>Indonesian police allege Zivan Radmanovic was killed when two Australian men stormed the villa, shooting him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4bb686a2307e1685b9fddd02d399650</guid></item><item><title>Boat approaches southern right whales off Albany coast in WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/boat-approaches-southern-right-whale-and-calf-wa/105893974</link><description>The latest close encounter with a protected whale species has renewed calls for the public to give the animals space.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d402bafad752b1c94a1343f0154bcac</guid></item><item><title>Police charge man with Armadale murder after alleged altercation leaves older man dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/homicide-squad-investigates-armadale-death/105896646</link><description>Police charge a 35-year-old man with murder after the death of a 49-year-old man in the Perth suburb of Armadale.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7b9b6705107b6ff5b738b62d81c44fc</guid></item><item><title>Dead koala found after sighting of the endangered animal halted ACT suburb's construction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/act-dead-koala-found-as-new-suburb-development-on-hold/105896808</link><description>The construction of new homes in Canberra's north remains on hold after a koala was spotted. Now, a dead koala has been found nearby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">662b333c24de695d37cbf543e12d606a</guid></item><item><title>Nikon Small World photomicroscopy competition's top 15 images of 2025 capture our tiniest signs of life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/nikon-small-world-photomicrography-competition-2025-winners/105880892</link><description>Extreme close-ups of rice weevil, pollen in a spider's web and a geometer moth laying eggs are among this year's Nikon Small World competition entries from thousands of scientists and artists across the globe. Here are the judges' favourites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">422146c134220b9daaeb85e97181786b</guid></item><item><title>England saved by rain in Pakistan World Cup match as Australia prepares to face Bangladesh</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/cricket-world-cup-england-pakistan-banadoned-colombo/105897648</link><description>Only a rain downpour against Pakistan prevents England from recording its first defeat of the World Cup, as Australia looks to book its berth in knockout stages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">149a025fb79f05b67378d20a66adf0e4</guid></item><item><title>Country GP crushed by vintage tractor in Denmark issues safety warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/safety-warning-after-country-gp-crushed-by-heritage-tractor/105885980</link><description>What started as a routine day of chores for a country GP and his son became a life-or-death situation after he was crushed by a vintage tractor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc4c053f90131636fe18b998de8dcf1f</guid></item><item><title>Former US Marine Pilot Dan Duggan appears in person at appeal against extradition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/us-marine-pilot-dan-duggan-appears-appeal-extradition/105898850</link><description>US authorities want Dan Duggan extradited from Australia for allegedly training Chinese pilots in South Africa in 2012. An appeal to avoid the extradition has started in the Federal Court today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e24e51691d3df5e1bb5646ddb4181f4a</guid></item><item><title>Hope at last for families as NSW backs inquiry into unsolved murders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/hope-as-nsw-backs-probe-into-unsolved-murders/105898598</link><description>The NSW Parliament has backed an inquiry into decades of unsolved murders and missing persons cases, following a campaign led by Illawarra families.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">967e3ff5e688cbc3cc4d948f1955a838</guid></item><item><title>Essendon CEO says Hawthorn AFL trade tactics for Zach Merrett were surprising</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/essendon-ceo-says-hawthorn-afl-trade-tactics-merrett-surprising/105900392</link><description>Essendon chief executive Craig Vozzo says the club was surprised Hawthorn waited until late in the AFL trade period to make an offer for their captain, Zach Merrett.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e96f0a6c62b0d3f1e70f37fd7a66a0b2</guid></item><item><title>Jim Chalmers and Tony Burke are in a long race for prime position</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/jim-chalmers-tony-burke-leadership/105884226</link><description>There is general agreement in Labor that Jim Chalmers is the government's best communicator. But insiders watching this race know Tony Burke is the master tactician.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93f58dc170f3f37c70cca03a69e3a6f5</guid></item><item><title>Coronado Curragh fined for death of miner Clark Peadon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/coronado-curragh-fined-for-death-of-worker-clark-peadon/105893210</link><description>The MEU has described the fine as "inadequate" for the loss of someone's life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">302b71db67d68b4b399d0e78f4be1f6f</guid></item><item><title>How wild bird poo testing in northern Australia is helping keep eggs on the shelves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/bird-flu-poo-testing-in-northern-australia-keeps-eggs-on-shelves/105894598</link><description>Hundreds of kilometres from the nearest supermarket, Indigenous rangers in Australia's remote north are working to keep eggs on your breakfast table.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">126bc279f84d1b05bc9d6ac31fa6b513</guid></item><item><title>Bears kill record number of people in Japan amid scores of attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/record-number-of-bear-attacks-in-japan/105902770</link><description>At least seven people have been killed by bears in the country since April and many more have been injured as the hungry animals venture into human territory to find food.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41b4b93bb120166534952debb22263e8</guid></item><item><title>WA farmers and caravaners defend Australia's growing love affair with US-style utes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/big-cars-us-style-trucks-tax/105901678</link><description>As American-style utes gain popularity across the country, there are calls for owners to face higher taxes for their "big cars, causing big problems".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">184ba6d7bde7a359132586201a8b0e76</guid></item><item><title>Video of attempted strip search that breached Aboriginal woman's human rights made public</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/video-of-attempted-strip-search-canberra-jail-released-court/105904704</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3fd11c0749eadaff81abffecd47f378</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/friday-finance-with-david-chau/105906178</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6b775f25a05cb343702a02cf5d8de47</guid></item><item><title>Former Japanese prime minister Tomiichi Murayama, famous for WWII apology, dies aged 101</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/ex-japan-prime-minister-tomiichi-murayama-dies-aged-101/105906158</link><description>Known for his landmark apology for Japan's World War II aggression and the phrases "deep remorse" and "heartfelt apology", Tomiichi Murayama has died at a hospital in Oita City.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03b35ac069e03d3037f52ba5261468f2</guid></item><item><title>Water testing in the Murweh Shire returns negative for dangerous amoeba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/murweh-mayor-charleville-hospital-negative-water-testing-amoeba/105899494</link><description>South-west Queensland residents are questioning the detection of a dangerous amoeba at Queensland Health sites after all follow-up tests were negative.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f732b4b65ef2c9618812d9b472a6ce26</guid></item></channel></rss>