<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 05:18:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Australia to focus on basics against India in second match of ODI series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/cricket-odi-australia-india-odi-hobart-ash-gardner/106392878</link><description>Ash Gardner says mastering a simple game plan was the key to Australia's convincing six-wicket win over India in the ODI series opener Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cefb056636d5b3b4f664e3d2545d0a7e</guid></item><item><title>Raymond Reddington found guilty of murdering wife Sharon Fulton 40 years ago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/raymond-reddington-found-guilty-of-murdering-wife-sharon-fulton/106392508</link><description>A jury in the murder trial of Raymond Reddington, 79, finds him guilty of killing wife Sharon Fulton 40 years ago, despite a body not being found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">359c04b5c367936a518c34a78c521973</guid></item><item><title>Thursday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106393546</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b150fb4de907d597621b793d4d355cf</guid></item><item><title>Should there be changes to the capital gains tax system?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/should-there-be-changes-to-the-capital-gains-tax-discount-/106393248</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97c16db80118d62ac14a1376a2c04cba</guid></item><item><title>What is the future for Tennis Australia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/what-is-the-future-for-tennis-australia-/106393266</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1176dd5e009fba79f12d96c5dbbe0ddb</guid></item><item><title>Funding axe looms for nine childcare centres failing standards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/childcare-funding-cuts-safety-rules/106392910</link><description>Nine childcare services that have failed to lift standards will only be named if the federal government decides to cut their taxpayer funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96b01329881bbb1370099da2e2185b61</guid></item><item><title>Health, environment departments questioned 'evidence' cited in salmon antibiotic approval for florfenicol in Tasmanian waterways</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/tas-concerns-over-salmon-antibiotic-approval-process/106391438</link><description>Tasmania's health department and environment watchdog questioned the scientific rigour behind an application to use the antibiotic florfenicol in salmon farms, including a lack of evidence about its impact on humans, documents show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6791dafaccc5a00178a77268c129c24</guid></item><item><title>From A$AP Rocky to Megadeth — these 10 great albums got 2026 started right</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/best-new-albums-2026-asap-rocky-j-cole-megadeth-willow/106381570</link><description>This year has already given us a bounty of beautiful new records. Here are just 10 of the best we've heard so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2a4e4f793d56ceea4d1588e71a989e5</guid></item><item><title>What is the best wash cycle to use on your washing machine?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/best-wash-cycles-to-use-at-home-for-clothes-towels-linen/106361962</link><description>Eco, fast, cotton, heavy, intense cold? Experts on the most cost-effective and efficient wash cycles for your home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ded506332417d3a6ce5c5116c4dee33</guid></item><item><title>Crown prince Reza Pahlavi on US military intervention in Iran and how a post Islamic Republic 'transition' would work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/reza-pahlavi-on-military-intervention-in-iran-and-his-transition/106382722</link><description>As the United States and Iran held their third round of nuclear talks on Thursday in Geneva amid heightened regional fears of the prospect of another war in the Middle East, Iran's exiled crown prince Reza Pahlavi says now is the time to move forward with military intervention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f1509ae4c9c1413d71cb2760111720c</guid></item><item><title>How Australia's lax property tax has created a class system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/australias-lax-property-tax-has-created-a-class-system/106391788</link><description>Australian real estate now is among the world's most expensive, and that has made it a red-hot political issue as demographics shift.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a31c0c5d0a59e1d562ac1a42edfcb654</guid></item><item><title>Thousands break into property market with 5% Deposit Scheme for first home buyers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/five-pc-home-deposit-scheme-influx/106136868</link><description>The number of people buying their first home with a 5 per cent deposit surges after the federal government makes sweeping changes to the scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">055b8bde6bb91a5be7130ae021c2fd32</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar military using festivals as propaganda to hide war zone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/myanmar-festival-propaganda-hiding-war-amid-air-strikes/106382144</link><description>As Myanmar's junta celebrates Chin National Day in an effort to project control, air strikes on civilians underscore a deepening civil war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">656854e7d08816135ef808492c3d120f</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup 2026: 'Proactive' Matildas aiming for Asian Cup glory under Joe Montemurro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/proactive-matildas-2026-womens-asian-cup-sam-kerr-mary-fowler/106388102</link><description>Although filled with familiar faces, the Matildas are now a completely different side to the one that captured hearts and minds at the 2023 World Cup. This is how a "proactive" Australian side is likely to line up at the Women's Asian Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">093451dc407c262e3909ee0f0ff52e93</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous people are going to jail at a record rate — what's the solution?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/solutions-focused-courts-helping-reduce-recidivism/106391944</link><description>The number of Indigenous people behind bars is rising. But some judges are bucking the trend by taking a different approach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b32b1f3d871b83341d8e3bd141d8b73</guid></item><item><title>HungryPanda alleges blackmail, intimidation amid dispute with delivery riders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/hungrypanda-alleges-blackmail-intimidation-amid-dispute/106392560</link><description>The dispute between HungryPanda and some of its riders has taken another twist, with the food delivery company accusing some workers of intimidation and blackmail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1445c8e14cdfa8b004c9936e189292eb</guid></item><item><title>'Awful' wall at Strahan subject to ridicule as Tasmanian council continues consultation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/strahan-wall-council-consulting-with-community/106390240</link><description>Tasmania's West Coast Council is holding monthly community meetings until April as it continues consultation over a concrete wall locals say is blocking views and restricting access to the working wharf.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13f9b9304028be2776e14a3bad61000d</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberal Party flirting with fire as One Nation preference deal looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/liberal-one-nation-potential-preferences-analysis/106391418</link><description>South Australia's embattled Liberals have openly declared their willingness to strike a preference deal with One Nation. Will it help or hurt them on election day?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e771204d6dcf2bd5343cf65a3370d3d</guid></item><item><title>Albanese celebrates his caucus unity but it comes at a cost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/labor-government-caucus-unity-anthony-albanese-left/106380394</link><description>Behind the scenes, the troops are carefully managed. Opinions are expressed at factional meetings and the prime minister meets with the factional conveners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31d1a41ec7748747a7b08a90b06f6374</guid></item><item><title>India beats Zimbabwe, South Africa beats West Indies at T20 World Cup as Proteas reach semifinals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/india-south-africa-win-at-t20-world-cup/106394592</link><description>The final four at the Twenty20 World Cup is taking shape after South Africa progressed on the back of a victory over West Indies, and India's victory over Zimbabwe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d23b9ec599ecde8c0cd0ce335169eaf</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley officially resigns two weeks after being ousted as Liberal leader — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/federal-politics-live-blog-fri-feb-27/106391736</link><description>Two weeks after losing the Liberal leadership, Sussan Ley officially handed in her resignation letter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d12040c259fa0fa707e41a7a04c4d981</guid></item><item><title>Bad Bunny tour unites Sydney's Latin diaspora with Australian concerts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/nsw-fans-prepare-for-bad-bunny-sydney-tour-latin-dispora/106387764</link><description>Global powerhouse Bad Bunny is bringing together Sydney’s Latin diaspora and exciting fans who cannot speak a word of Spanish.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a664ab78b523b7abf65836d23ea30a17</guid></item><item><title>ASX correction 'likely', Coles shares plummet — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/asx-markets-business-live-news-feb27-2026/106394660</link><description>Analysts say a share market correction is 'likely' as the ASX hits record high.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dc00f0217d7da6178314dbb98598387</guid></item><item><title>Blind refugee from Myanmar dies after detention by US border agents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/blind-refugee-dies-after-detention-by-us-border-agents/106394744</link><description>Nurul Amin Shah Alam's family had expected him to be released from a New York jail and reported him missing. He was found dead after temperatures dropped below freezing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4572df42a0748e277e2d05533f2a87e</guid></item><item><title>Birdsville nears annual rainfall in two days as south-east Queensland faces wet start to weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/birdsville-annual-rainfall-in-days-wet-weekend-south-east-qld/106394700</link><description>Parts of outback Queensland have been drenched with almost a year's worth of rainfall in just two days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01eb4c0d489919e96ae78112ab6b5430</guid></item><item><title>Two new Hans Christian Andersen adaptations prove fairy tales as relevant as ever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/hans-christian-andersen-tree-of-light-meow-meow-red-shoes/106364412</link><description>Two wildly different shows, The Tree of Light by Slingsby Theatre Company and Meow Meow's The Red Shoes, re-imagine classic fairy tales by Hans Christian Andersen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ef5fdd737cde8a3a507cf76b1c72769</guid></item><item><title>Teenage boys drive homophobic anti-LGBTQIA+ attacks, NSW Police data shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/nsw-lgbt-hate-data-released-ahead-of-mardi-gras/106394004</link><description>Police recorded 197 incidents of LGBTQIA+ hate-related violence and charged 103 people over the attacks since 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3a477e689ba3c07354ce5be230b6831</guid></item><item><title>Police charge 25 over 'family-run drug syndicate' seizing $3m in drugs at Gladstone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/police-charge-25-people-with-drug-offences-in-gladstone/106394952</link><description>Dozens of people are charged after a raid in central Queensland seized more than $3 million worth of drugs from what people say was a "deeply entrenched drug syndicate".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">809039c034f575ef5a197af6f6d52b61</guid></item><item><title>Labor not ruling out negative gearing changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/labor-not-ruling-out-negative-gearing-changes/106395074</link><description>A government source said it would make sense to consider changes to negative gearing and capital gains tax together, but that no decision was close to being made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57ef2e8357ae14f0ed1eab92322752ec</guid></item><item><title>Judge rejects request to block Trump White House from building its $560 million ballroom project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/judge-allows-trumps-white-house-ballroom-project-to-proceed/106394882</link><description>A US judge rejects a preservationist group's request to block the Trump administration from continuing construction of a $560 million ballroom to replace the demolished East Wing of the White House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2da5cc859c0258e4a51f7784657bdf6b</guid></item><item><title>Royal Australian Mint unveils new limited edition $1 coin with subtle change to mark 60 years of decimal currency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/mint-unveils-new-limited-edition-1-dollar-coin-extra-kangaroo/106394730</link><description>The Royal Australian Mint releases a limited edition $1 coin to mark the 60th anniversary of the introduction of decimal currency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32f5ac1f674d4cf6bfabe89872fb9144</guid></item><item><title>ABC to broadcast Matildas' Women's Asian Cup games as well as knockout matches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/abc-radio-broadcast-matildas-womens-asian-cup/106395182</link><description>Just days out from the start of the Women's Asian Cup, the ABC has locked in radio broadcasting rights for the tournament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4525c54c6737ed61e3faaf1577489894</guid></item><item><title>Sydney solicitor accused of stealing $15 million from clients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/nsw-solicitor-steals-almost-15m-from-clients/106395324</link><description>Police had been investigating Benjamin Paul Reid at a Bondi Junction law firm since September last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b939318072c8b3bb6fabc162ed7293a3</guid></item><item><title>$3 million in drugs seized in Gladstone drug trafficking operation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/-3-million-in-drugs-seized-in-gladstone/106395608</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0681bcb712c55b346069a8fe45f191a1</guid></item><item><title>Deepfakes back in the headlines after a federal law was used for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/rise-in-sexualised-deepfakes-new-laws-explainer/106390940</link><description>As the first case under new anti-deepfake legislation goes before the courts, authorities and experts say the rise in the creation of the non-consensual sexually explicit material is concerning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da4118b9f6f994212728c2883b3b0bd4</guid></item><item><title>Air strikes hit Afghan capital of Kabul, hours after Taliban attacks Pakistan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/taliban-launches-retaliatory-strikes-against-pakistan/106395580</link><description>Pakistan is responding to "unprovoked fire" by Afghan forces at multiple locations along the border, the Information Ministry in Islamabad says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">723636784f9962da68e0b01185be66b9</guid></item><item><title>Protestor arrested as NT Administrator David Connolly sworn in</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/nt-administrator-david-connolly-swearing-in-parliament-arrest/106393862</link><description>A protester has been arrested amid chaotic scenes outside of NT Parliament, where David Connolly has been sworn in as the new administrator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a09d17d197bc6018672c8c52798f531</guid></item><item><title>171 bodies found in mass graves in eastern Congo after withdrawal of M23 rebel group</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/congo-bodies-found-mass-graves/106395864</link><description>Mass graves with at least 171 dead bodies have been found in the eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo, in a region the M23 rebel group has recently withdrawn from.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cb8612f5f98425316681232fce5aca9</guid></item><item><title>Bendigo Swordcraft rallies around one of their own after Harcourt bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/bendigo-swordcraft-larp-henry-of-harcourt-victorian-bushfires/106352450</link><description>Michael Henry's armour and weapons survived January's bushfires, as the Swordcraft community helps him rise from the ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24d209dd01eeee8c3f01a75bb5cfd606</guid></item><item><title>Instagram to alert parents if teens 'repeatedly' search for self-harm terms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/instagram-to-alert-parents-of-teen-suicide-searches/106395120</link><description>The new feature will be rolled out in Australia from next week, but there are concerns about loopholes and limitations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">200c4245e8ca3ad7f521dff90f5a1629</guid></item><item><title>Protestors outside NT Parliament attempted to intervene</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/protestors-outside-nt-parliament-attempted-to-intervene/106396172</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54d7142e0d3e445963499ef0af0834e5</guid></item><item><title>How Manly backrower Hugo Hart went from American high school football to the brink of the NRL</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/nrl-manly-sea-eagles-hugo-hart-nfl-high-school-football/106392204</link><description>After some eye-catching performances in the pre-season, young Manly backrower and former American high school football linebacker Hugo Hart is edging closer to an NRL debut.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eab60549feb59ed9ffc9f61f26e689a0</guid></item><item><title>Baby rhino born in NSW wildlife park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/baby-rhino-born-in-nsw-wildlife-park/106391240</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c1a4782c0ee42eca3a3379b2ab7f6eb</guid></item><item><title>Riverina community steps up to feed baby rhino after mum abandons him at birth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/white-rhino-ck-embraced-by-community-after-rejection-at-birth/106392160</link><description>Just like "Punch" the monkey, this adorable baby was abandoned by its mother soon after birth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1cddebabeb59cc75e46df1af60d3c04</guid></item><item><title>In photos: Extreme weather sweeps across large parts of Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/extreme-weather-sweeps-across-large-parts-of-australia/106395148</link><description>At least four states are facing extreme weather and heavy rain, with some areas tipped to receive the heaviest rainfall in more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">314212cea7670e933f1a5796ad376ddc</guid></item><item><title>Western Sydney youth tell their stories of postcode wars via play</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/western-sydney-postcode-war-play-180-inspire/106296574</link><description>Jaani Pani knows how loyalty to a postcode can shape your life in Western Sydney. He is telling his story for the stage to inspire the next generation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e5bf6b6023e0db6a5047c2e62fbf47f</guid></item><item><title>Terella Brewing to close amid legal battle with Sunshine Coast Council</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/teralla-brewing-to-close-its-doors-amid-legal-battle/106395960</link><description>Popular Sunshine Coast brewery and music venue Terella Brewing will close after a legal stoush with the local council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a5de76c0655eae2c97b7931d6b8c24f</guid></item><item><title>Comedian Magda Szubanski in remission after stage 4 blood cancer treatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/magda-szubanski-stage-4-blood-cancer-remission/106396740</link><description>The Australian entertainer reveals she is in remission after completing chemotherapy treatment for stage 4 blood cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02c295aa806c4b19a1a7af666f1fcf8c</guid></item><item><title>Crew-11 NASA astronaut behind mission-ending medical issues identifies himself</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/crew-11-nasa-astronaut-behind-mission-ending-health-issues/106395048</link><description>The 58-year-old spaceflight veteran has identified himself as the astronaut whose illness prompted NASA's first medical evacuation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd932f2d6b20c020c5606c312a535772</guid></item><item><title>Protestors outside Parliament House tried to intervene when the man was arrested</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/protestors-outside-parliament-house-tried-to-intervene-arrest/106396980</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06acfaf640b986f856542784fd1cf9d1</guid></item><item><title>Australian Electoral Commission proposes changes to Tasmanian voting boundaries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/electorate-boundary-changes-proposed-for-tasmania/106395702</link><description>Under proposed changes to Tasmania's electorates, Lyons would decrease in area while Clark would increase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a86d788ef63c809696a7a63f7bc011c9</guid></item><item><title>Coles 'Down Down' in the supermarket wars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/coles-financial-results-go-backwards-with-shares-following/106396060</link><description>Financial results for supermarket giant Coles underperform, with stocks following suite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02d38172bafbfff12219f98d41817fb0</guid></item><item><title>Health authorities reject claims Sydney hospital fungal infection outbreak covered up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/nsw-government-rejects-cover-up-claims-over-hospital-fungus/106396224</link><description>Health authorities reject claims information about a fungal infection outbreak which could have caused the death of two patients at a Sydney hospital was deliberately withheld from the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8edbf8ed64af07c418ede9750b35d09</guid></item><item><title>How young people are coping with the rising cost of living</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/how-young-people-are-coping-with-the-rising-cost-of-living/106385806</link><description>Many people are struggling with the cost of living and increasingly, young Australians say they are not just worried about the situation now, but also what it means for the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64f6e8f2391b28b8f248ff3473f09f7e</guid></item><item><title>'Child first, offender second' approach to Tasmania's young offenders unveiled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/replacement-ashley-youth-detention-centre-unveiled-tasmania/106395206</link><description>The Tasmanian government announces a "child first, offender second" approach for the operation of a new youth prison, which it says will offer small "home-like" accommodation for detainees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07efca627ee741a17e9d08fbc10015aa</guid></item><item><title>Police reinstate murder charge against alleged killer of Kaiden Morgan-Johnston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/kaiden-morgan-charges-reissued/106330296</link><description>Police have reinstated murder charges against a man accused of killing an 18-year-old in Victoria's east last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df9a97acbfb9e7c725b7235657e4edd8</guid></item><item><title>Super Bowl winner Michael Dickson puts Matt Burton's boot up with NFL punters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/michael-dickson-matt-burton-nrl-nfl-code-switch/106396080</link><description>Australian Super Bowl winner Michael Dickson says the booming boot of Bulldogs five-eighth Matt Burton could cut it in the NFL, but not without some major adjustments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1a2746cbe842599da2b26dc6ab44583</guid></item><item><title>Perth mother blames WA's mental health systemic failures for her teen daughter's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/perth-mother-blames-systemic-failures-for-her-daughter-death/106396758</link><description>The mother of a teenage girl who took her own life a few hours after being released from a Perth mental health ward says a series of systemic failures is responsible for her daughter's death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd2adb250d2d4bf3298ec45d056b46a3</guid></item><item><title>Family of David Collisson who was burned after being shot dead tells of struggle to deal with trauma</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/family-of-murdered-david-collisson-tells-court-struggle-trauma/106391990</link><description>The son, sister and mother of David Collisson who was murdered near Mudgee speak of their unimaginable pain in coming to terms with how he died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4228f51ec4898d561ff59689c7f232d</guid></item><item><title>Murder accused argues self-defence after alleged Dubbo drug hunt ends in death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/murder-accused-argues-self-defence-alleged-dubbo-drug-hunt-death/106391568</link><description>A man who stands accused in fatal stabbing that broke out over an alleged drug-related dispute pleads his innocence on grounds of self-defence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91f18bfc52394ef3dc459d0403c799ab</guid></item><item><title>Liberal Party will not publish its internal review into the 2025 election loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/liberal-party-election-review-will-not-to-be-published/106398462</link><description>The review received hundreds of submissions and was finished months ago, but today the Liberal Party's federal executive revealed it would never be made public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c3db63f84d80a3125794937ad6fa8e5</guid></item><item><title>Police foil alleged terror attack plan on public buildings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/man-charged-with-preparing-for-terrorist-act-perth/106397996</link><description>Police have charged a 20-year-old man they allege was planning a "mass casualty" terror attack targeting public buildings and Muslim places of worship in Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f6e90e8199b420c9aef4cca97a9647</guid></item><item><title>Parents charged with manslaughter after Gold Coast crash kills 3yo boy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/parents-charged-with-manslaughter-after-gold-coast-crash/106398698</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b679bde28339a7a7880256287eb01dbd</guid></item><item><title>Ex-SA Liberal leader David Speirs says he will contest state election, 10 months after drug conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/david-speirs-announces-political-comeback-for-sa-election/106389794</link><description>Former SA Liberal leader David Speirs has confirmed he has nominated to run in his former seat of Black in the state election, 10 months after he was convicted of drug supply offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d38a917197cbbdc68d82b2dd2ac06cf</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup 2026: Katrina Gorry has done it all for the Matildas. Now she wants a trophy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/womens-asian-cup-matildas-katrina-gorry/106398594</link><description>Katrina Gorry embodies all the characteristics that are celebrated in Australian football, and the veteran midfielder wants to lead the Matildas all the way to the Asian Cup trophy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02ede07013e6f10ff3550784cc2d2253</guid></item><item><title>Tropical low to move south-east across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/tropical-low-to-move-south-east-across-australia/106399150</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">586129c2627f359cc04c97eb5c82fbbc</guid></item><item><title>Teenage boy dies after being hit by two cars crossing busy road in Warnbro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/teenage-boy-dies-after-being-hit-by-two-cars-in-warnbro/106398090</link><description>A teenage boy has died after he was hit by two cars on a busy dual-lane road in Perth's southern suburbs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5992c6fa12de3a910e4ab07ad39eab3d</guid></item><item><title>David Speirs's comeback attempt is a risk for everyone — including himself</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/david-speirs-comeback-attempt-a-political-risk-analysis/106390998</link><description>The former opposition leader's attempt at a political comeback is a risk for both the major parties — but also himself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c920c14086d0b426fa48504f14566d2b</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Reds defeat Highlanders, Western Force beat Moana Pasifika in Super Rugby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/western-force-defeat-moana-pasifika-for-first-super-rugby-win/106399112</link><description>The Queensland Reds and Western Force have recorded their first wins of the Super Rugby Pacific season in round three.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">094d1db7cab1156c1469b611fe18bc53</guid></item><item><title>An unexpected baby boy gives hope to the all-female Akuntsu tribe in Brazil's Amazon rainforest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/amazonian-tribe-akuntsu-gives-birth-to-first-boy/106399170</link><description>As they advanced in age without a child to carry on the line, many expected the Akuntsu to vanish when the three remaining women died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7e97cd520f8aef2465852b7401719a0</guid></item><item><title>Georgia Voll blazes century as Australia defeats India by five wickets and takes 6-4 series lead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/georgia-voll-strikes-century-australia-downs-india/106399172</link><description>Georgia Voll strikes her second ODI century after being dropped on 99, as Australia cruises to a five-wicket win over India and takes a 6-4 lead in the multi-format series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3a54020baa22342ddd21f6f8d97aadf</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106397788</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">692093cbbec66533ee074a199a24c6a3</guid></item><item><title>Best books of the summer, from Julian Barnes, Tim Ayliffe, Madeline Cash and more</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/best-books-summer-what-to-read-next-julian-barnes-tim-ayliffe/106255824</link><description>Wondering what to read next? Buzzy debuts, gripping thrillers and lyrical literary fiction are among our critics' latest recommendations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d662d4d63148a453f7ff498b9e9d47a</guid></item><item><title>Bill Clinton tells congressional committee he had 'no idea' about Jeffrey Epstein's crimes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/bill-clinton-deposed-at-congress-epstein-committee/106399884</link><description>The former US president is being questioned by the House Oversight Committee, which is looking into the US government's handling of the Epstein case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53b397dffffca63baeab729b1fdeacd5</guid></item><item><title>Temporary reprieve for Gaza healthcare system as Israel's attempt to block Doctors Without Borders and other aid groups is stopped</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/israel-s-top-court-allows-aid-groups-to-keep-working-in-gaza/106395150</link><description>Israel's Supreme Court on Friday temporarily blocked the government from shuttering the Gaza operations of dozens of aid organisations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d8106ebce829154edc7ead3d88f4cd3</guid></item><item><title>Warning about financial abuse of First Nations elders as lack of digital literacy risks security</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/warning-financial-abuse-of-first-nations-elders-digital-literacy/106396092</link><description>Experts are warning elders are suffering in silence and are calling for more awareness around financial abuse to understand how it manifests within families and communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fc26cfc809fcdf89d8911517a353dca</guid></item><item><title>These Australians are saving and restoring native grasslands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/native-grasslands-victoria-endangered-restoration-seed-demand/106391114</link><description>Native grasslands across southern Australia are slowly making a comeback, driven by conservationists, farmers and a growing native seed industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7c3a1948c6b245028fc0ac26ebd688b</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup 2026: Holly McNamara in career-best form and ready for breakthrough Matildas moment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/holly-mcnamara-asian-cup-matildas/106376910</link><description>Four years on from her first Asian Cup, Holly McNamara begins her second in career-best form. The 23-year-old has her eyes on the ultimate prize.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eaa536064839f25872f9c7a9172059e4</guid></item><item><title>How a 20yo living with his parents in regional WA allegedly plotted a terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/how-20yo-allegedly-plotted-a-terror-attack-in-wa/106399408</link><description>History was made in WA when police charged a person for the first time with preparing a terrorist attack. What do we know?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7ddc32017fca19f8fa072d18b854488</guid></item><item><title>Former prince Andrew's scandals pose an almighty challenge for Prince William</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/prince-william-is-set-to-inherit-the-andrew-problem-/106385970</link><description>When Prince William and Princess Catherine stepped out for their first public appearance since Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's arrest, an innocuous question was levelled at them. The candid response was perhaps more revealing than anticipated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d63fb62d0d20990cd1a6057cff850ab</guid></item><item><title>The battery that divided Narrabri: How misinformation derailed a renewable energy project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/misinformation-kills-narrabri-community-battery-project/106120264</link><description>A community battery project three years in the making, run by a local not-for-profit and backed by the council, was killed after a spark of misinformation about its fire risk was ignited.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32dae321540fd913dc51081e8a4e2fd0</guid></item><item><title>Archaeologists relocate lighthouse keeper's wife's remains on remote Qld island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/low-isles-grave-relocated-rising-sea-levels-queensland/106386250</link><description>The bones of a Queensland lighthouse keeper's wife were almost lost as a result of rising sea levels nearly 150 years after her death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ee9540858c797f22d9aa32263fbced4</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan and the Taliban edge closer to 'open war' — but neither can win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/afghan-taliban-pakistan-full-scale-war-not-likely/106399784</link><description>Pakistan's declaration of an "open war" with the Afghan Taliban sounds dangerous, but analysts say neither side has the capacity to win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0ca6a6a48cd4b94617f1ae46784ba1c</guid></item><item><title>OFC Pro League launches new soccer competition across seven Oceanic nations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/ofc-pro-league-launches-new-soccer-competition/106392686</link><description>A new professional soccer league has launched across Australia, New Zealand and the Pacific, though questions remain over whether it can survive long-term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57c07edf9ab625e86fce2fda21261414</guid></item><item><title>Tennis star Destanee Aiava 'scared' to walk on court because of death threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/destanee-aiava-death-threats-tennis-retirement/106395342</link><description>Destanee Aiava was once called the best 14-year-old female tennis player in the world. Just over a decade later, she is walking away from the sport and calling out its toxic culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59261a1ab537058a040f541e555479bf</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup 2026: Where is it being played, how can I watch the Matildas, and is it a big deal?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/women-asian-cup-2026-everything-you-need-to-know/106383868</link><description>Australia is hosting the Women's Asian Cup for the first time in 20 years, and this could be the Matildas' best chance to finally add another trophy to their cabinet. Here's everything you need to know about the tournament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11682c6de16ff8294aba9bee9dd6919f</guid></item><item><title>Crunch time for Victorian farmers refusing VNI West work as forced access looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/crunch-time-farmers-block-transmission-line-vni-west-assessments/106385682</link><description>Landholders opposed to VNI West have been given 30 days to allow environmental assessments before authorised officers can enter by force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03626040d9562e4e350feee56767cb9c</guid></item><item><title>Red-hot Socceroos striker Mohamed Touré set to miss World Cup warm-ups with groin injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/mo-toure-socceroos-striker-groin-injury-world-cup/106399958</link><description>After starting in Norwich in record-breaking form, Socceroos striker Mohamed Touré will almost certainly miss Australia's crucial World Cup warm-up games in March.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d862e59a65b94bce260b6f78bf297f6</guid></item><item><title>Documents reveal how thwarted kidnapping led to billion-dollar Sydney drug bust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/ryde-billion-dollar-cocaine-bust-after-kidnap-thwarted/106357602</link><description>Four masked men are arrested breaking into a Ryde apartment in Sydney's north. What officers stumbled upon inside would be one of the biggest cocaine hauls in NSW Police history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a1376d1575231c1e9595590ed5123fa</guid></item><item><title>Greens unfazed by polling and sticking to their guns on AUKUS ahead of SA election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/greens-unfazed-by-polling-ahead-of-sa-election/106381914</link><description>Ahead of the SA election, the Greens have made only modest gains in polling compared to rival minor parties, but party leader Robert Simms is not disappointed by the result.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46a6270d356079379b95a63c34f70a49</guid></item><item><title>America's Next Top Model's feigns accountability in new docuseries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/americas-next-top-model-documentary-netflix-tyra-banks/106380392</link><description>America's Next Top Model has aged terribly. What does accountability even mean for an era of unprecedented exploitation on screen?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2cd55205f433e51319ad2435188be00</guid></item><item><title>Everyday items from ancient Greece and Rome in the spotlight at ANU Classics Museum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/act-ancient-rome-greece-everyday-objects-anu-classics-museum/106397440</link><description>It doesn't look like much from the outside, but the inside of the Australian National University Classics Museum in Canberra is akin to peering into the cupboards of a kitchen from 2,000 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">facf511869d1c565b2557aca8148a305</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says of Iran 'sometimes you have to' use force, as US-Tehran tensions mount</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/iran-trump-use-force/106399936</link><description>The US has amassed a huge military presence in the region after the president threatened military action if Tehran refused to forswear nuclear weapons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea98612409185080edb3b70d51f71f49</guid></item><item><title>Queensland shark-monitoring drone trial reveals shark sightings beyond nets and drum lines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/shark-monitoring-program-queensland-nets-and-drumlines/106314156</link><description>The results of a four-year-trial were obtained by a conservation group under right to information laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27372842aee46767ace52090362fc1e0</guid></item><item><title>US Republicans call for Australian lamb investigation as new bill proposes 30pc tariff</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/republicans-call-for-australian-lamb-tariff-investigation/106339474</link><description>Republicans write to Donald Trump's top trade officials to request an investigation into Australian lamb, as several members of Congress sponsor a bill for a 30 per cent tariff on Australian sheep products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f39fe59cc62d4d403ae9d05565b29e6</guid></item><item><title>Australian Antarctic team yields big haul of fresh produce with hydroponics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/antarctic-garden-yields-big-haul-of-fresh-produce/106385768</link><description>Antarctica is the coldest, driest and windiest continent on the planet. But at Casey Station, Australian expeditioners have grown 130 kilos of fresh produce in a year thanks to a hydroponics facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29d3acdb2f66cfb3b7166a26f7fef394</guid></item><item><title>Launceston City Council reveals $13 million increase for Princess Theatre, Earl Arts Centre upgrade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/questions-over-budget-for-earl-arts-centre-princess-theatre/106393242</link><description>The Launceston City Council has revealed the redevelopment of a historic theatre and arts centre will cost almost 50 per cent more than expected, but the mayor insists it is "not a cost blowout".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c867c47211d71550a54c83d463a4b741</guid></item><item><title>Doctor claims 'eleventh hour' condition on state election promise could tank Launceston hospital plans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/launceston-health-hub-hospital-state-government-jerome-muir/106350148</link><description>Medical experts fear a recently revealed condition on a Tasmanian election promise could kill a new hospital proposal, amid escalating concern about health facilities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">866cfd5db73d2a76f8bc3451b99d2c98</guid></item><item><title>Deniliquin mother creates sensory cape to support neurodivergent kids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/sensory-suit-developed-by-mum-for-neurodivergent-kids/106305416</link><description>Lucy Horne has spent years perfecting a "sensory suit" to help her autistic son with overwhelming situations like going to the hairdresser, and now she wants to share it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49ff6005e44ab1a53591d0726957d914</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal community, linguists revive ancient Ngaiawang language of River Murray</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/ngaiawang-language-of-river-murray-revived-indigenous/106393092</link><description>Ngaiawang language, once spoken frequently along the sweeping bend of the River Murray or the Rinta, was almost wiped out by colonisation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60a199f204cedf6d8cf654d5d717370b</guid></item><item><title>Quick and easy green ginger and miso noodles made from pantry staples - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/phoebe-thorburn-spinach-ginger-miso-noodles-/106382102</link><description>Close the delivery app and get through some kitchen staples with this easy spinach, ginger and miso noodle recipe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54c8a9905e900c361424d1fe4f90a79e</guid></item><item><title>Safety warning to Victorian farmers after four work deaths in two months</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/worksafe-victoria-farm-safety-campaign-agricultural-fatalities/106385668</link><description>The recent death of a respected Victorian dairy farmer has prompted fresh warnings about workplace dangers in the agricultural sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c6e834a24d9191eaacf9d50985fba3d</guid></item><item><title>Neil Sedaka, singer of Breaking Up Is Hard To Do, dies aged 86</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/neil-sedaka-dies-aged-86/106400078</link><description>Neil Sedaka, the American singer and songwriter who sold millions of records worldwide, dies aged 86.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1962d8f736a6fc3d1c94a074027fbcad</guid></item><item><title>How the 'amazing' Pretzel will help Scott march in Sydney's iconic Mardi Gras parade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/guide-dog-helps-owner-march-mardi-gras-parade-sydney/106397574</link><description>When Scott Dixon-Smith started his career, his workplace accommodated his blindness but not his sexuality. Tonight, he will march in the pride parade with the help of his guide dog, Pretzel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c6ca74b39b85087737841065748ca6e</guid></item><item><title>US President Trump orders six-month phase-out of Anthropic AI technology across government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/us-president-orders-six-month-phaseout-of-anthropic-technology/106400088</link><description>The Trump administration has ordered all US agencies to stop using Anthropic's artificial intelligence technology and imposed other major penalties, culminating an unusually public clash between the government and the company over AI safeguards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e455b1289cb17057b4778c442f3d86a</guid></item><item><title>Australian documentary Floodland uncovers human toll of 2022 Lismore floods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/floodland-jordan-giusti-director-lismore-floods-documentary/106374088</link><description>Four years after floodwaters peaked at 14.4 metres in Lismore, a new documentary looks at how the town moved forward — and what more needs to be done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">250daf5a8fa92c7b262c219308388272</guid></item><item><title>Calls for SA election commitment to maintain feral deer eradication funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/sa-election-call-for-deer-eradication-funding-boost/106398198</link><description>More than 28,000 feral deer have been eradicated in South Australia since a program began in 2022, but conservationists say it needs a long-term funding commitment to finish the job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aee662c443c4b79f0cf31cbb2c658ddc</guid></item><item><title>What a Paramount-owned Warner Bros Discovery means for the movies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/what-happens-to-movies-if-paramount-owns-warner-bros/106400154</link><description>The proposed takeover of Warner Bros by Paramount could reshape Hollywood, movie theatres and the wider media landscape.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2555721a13a4e68aa1dcf008b72a1f08</guid></item><item><title>Facing threats of war, Denmark turns to a new weapon: women</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/denmark-female-conscription-in-face-of-russia-us-threats/106339920</link><description>Denmark is fast-tracking female conscription as it muscles up to Russia and faces threats of invasion from the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17358269058443d144971ac8ba75b733</guid></item><item><title>Bolivian military plane crash kills 15</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/bolivian-military-plane-crash-kills-15-/106400308</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6ca75350046e2e4c423fda323b51d92</guid></item><item><title>NASA shakes up Moon program with new test mission before astronaut lunar landing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/nasa-shakes-up-moon-program-with-new-test-missio/106400186</link><description>NASA shakes up its Artemis Moon exploration program, adding an extra practice flight before a crewed lunar landing planned for two years' time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb040ecf12ae12852f2b7da8dfae70d2</guid></item><item><title>Peter V'landys confirms NRL's intentions to expand internationally beyond Las Vegas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/nrl-vlandys-confirms-expansion-plans-after-vegas-success/106400294</link><description>After experiencing tremendous success in Las Vegas, Peter V'landys is planning to take the NRL to other major cities around the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a42a88997457a5c0515338cc65f4b5e</guid></item><item><title>FIFO workers keep football leagues alive in Pilbara towns with transient populations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/fifo-workers-keep-football-leagues-alive-in-pilbara/106259408</link><description>Local football leagues depend on FIFO workers to boost player numbers in remote and regional WA, and the workers say getting involved makes being away from home a little more enjoyable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62323fa63e19cc6d99ee7c449a160c7a</guid></item><item><title>Australia's almond industry cracks $1.3 billion mark as Chinese demand rises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/almond-industry-record-value-china-demand-increases/106394784</link><description>Australian almonds are breaking records as the trade war between the United States and China rolls on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6580d7c48ec5c7049f988870efb200b8</guid></item><item><title>Tiny Victorian photo album provides snapshot of a bygone era</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/tiny-victorian-photo-album-little-gem-tintype-photos/105925926</link><description>While wealthy upper-class colonial families were sitting for expensive studio portraits in the 1880s, many with less money were collecting miniature portraits in tiny photo albums like this one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97c44ec944e3b12b0b87483a28e9ff42</guid></item><item><title>Gorillaz album The Mountain exorcises death with Indian music greats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/gorillaz-the-mountain-album-damon-albarn-grief-india-afterlife/106381294</link><description>Damon Albarn and Jamie Hewlett discuss how trips to India, grieving and A-list collaborations shaped the latest genre-defying Gorillaz album, The Mountain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">001f036c6ad742a6590c591522d16158</guid></item><item><title>Professor MaryAnn Bin-Sallik remembered as a 'trailblazer' in Aboriginal education, health and rights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/aboriginal-professor-maryann-bin-sallik-remembered/106396478</link><description>MaryAnn Bin-Sallik was the first Aboriginal nurse graduate in Darwin and the first Aboriginal person to receive a PhD at Harvard University. Following her death at age 85, the Djaru Elder is being remembered for her work in Indigenous education, health and human rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eaa3845831af7ecac1f05a52c3f4330c</guid></item><item><title>Lorraine Bayly, former Play School host and star of The Sullivans, dies aged 89</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/lorraine-bayly-playschool-sullivans-actor-dies/106400388</link><description>Lorraine Bayly, star of long-running soap opera The Sullivans and a former Play School host, has died aged 89, after years of ill health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fe0ad5896953b2ec458205c4b93fbd6</guid></item><item><title>Terror charges against Liam Hall and Jayson Michaels reveal challenge of maintaining social cohesion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/wa-terror-charges-threaten-social-cohesion/106400272</link><description>The charging of two young West Australian men with terror offences show the challenges facing social cohesion, and solving the problem is not going to be easy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e448820cf6c05290302532c88848f20b</guid></item><item><title>Terror police investigate disturbance, white powder at Perth Mosque</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/perth-mosque-target-of-disturbance-terror-police-probing/106399406</link><description>Terrorism police in Perth investigate a disturbance outside a Perth mosque overnight and the discovery of a "non-suspicious substance" on the footpath outside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">031550aefff469583806fe1c9e91ffb5</guid></item><item><title>Triple Melbourne Cup winner Makybe Diva dead at 27 after sudden health battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/horse-racing-makybe-diva-dad-after-health-battle/106400516</link><description>The champion racehorse who rose to fame after combining with Glen Boss for three-straight Melbourne Cup wins has died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ddb2a0f0d676a2d35140651e7dcf887</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberal and Labor to preference David Speirs last at state election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/sa-liberal-and-labor-to-preference-david-speirs-last-at-election/106400228</link><description>Both major parties in South Australia say they will preference former opposition leader David Speirs last at the state election, as he rules out returning to the Liberal Party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">858aa0addc895a2b2f16c9582523701c</guid></item><item><title>Trump says US has launched 'major operation' against Iran, with Israel calling 'pre-emptive' attack a joint effort</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/iran-israel-explosion-tehran/106400716</link><description>US-Israeli strikes on Iran have prompted a string of retaliatory attacks and travel chaos across the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08b282e975f497e6702d24fbf479c050</guid></item><item><title>Explosions across Middle East as Iranian retaliation puts Israel on alert — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/israel-us-attacking-iran-live-updates-blasts-in-tehran/106222024</link><description>Israel and the US have attacked Iran, with a swift response from Tehran threatening to widen the conflict across the Middle East. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28e2c3495d0aab60defa50b96b22c569</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump: Major combat operation in Iran underway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/donald-trump-major-combat-operation-in-iran-underway/106400848</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">730b480acf65495e3c77f60a56ce015b</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr admits to doubts surrounding injury issues ahead of Matildas Asian Cup campaign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/football-sam-kerr-injury-doubts-matildas-asian-cup-campaign/106400764</link><description>Sam Kerr says she is still not at 100 per cent as she details her moments of self-doubt during her return to Matildas colours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">720394a3977d5b26e4bddf5d880fb862</guid></item><item><title>Israel and US attack Iran, sparking retaliatory strikes. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/what-we-know-about-the-israel-us-iran-strikes/106400988</link><description>After weeks of anticipation, Israel fired the first shot on Iran, drawing in the US and sparking retaliatory strikes that have hit several countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1321199f078f4813240a61e56426afa2</guid></item><item><title>Albanese says Australian government 'supports US acting to prevent Iran obtaining a nuclear weapon'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/australian-government-responds-to-united-states-attack-on-iran/106401108</link><description>Anthony Albanese says the international community has been clear that the Iranian regime can never be allowed to develop a nuclear weapon".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c2f23b0cd2e71f7e9b9f6cbc888ee23</guid></item><item><title>This US-Israeli strike on Iran is different and could lead to a longer, deadlier war</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/us-israeli-strikes-on-iran-could-lead-to-longer-war/106401110</link><description>It was clear within hours that this conflict is different and threatens to engulf the region in a longer, deadlier war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">273f7ec3f98962cc24efe688cd7b67d7</guid></item><item><title>Travellers stranded as US-Iran conflict throws international flights into chaos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/us-iran-conflict-causes-flight-chaos-strands-travellers/106401500</link><description>Nations closing airspace and suspending flights include major international transit hubs connecting Australian travellers with Europe and Asia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ed61425da9b1866c16d96d5df55fb15</guid></item><item><title>Live: Loud blasts heard over Dubai and Doha as Iran responds to US-Israel strikes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/us-israel-launches-airstrikes-in-iran-live-blog/106401380</link><description>Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has been killed in Israeli and US strikes, Iran's state-controlled media has reported. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d6fbd10c4210381350cc28a80b77bfd</guid></item><item><title>Astrology vs the algorithm: Why my Indian parents are hunting for my husband</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/marriage-arranged-indian-astrology-dating-app-romance-love-match/106382436</link><description>From Tinder-style apps to astrological birth charts — how today's arranged marriages blend tech and tradition in unexpected ways.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2efc790083a43943bd3233246fccb3b7</guid></item><item><title>Punch the monkey reminds us 'we all need soft spaces'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/punch-monkey-japan-soft-spaces/106393016</link><description>There's surely a reason we all went briefly nuts about a lonely little snow monkey called Punch living in a Japanese zoo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b443c70c362af315a7938db6500270c</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Get ready trivia nuts. It's time to play, HARD!</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/106288026</link><description>Have you been waiting all week to give this quiz another crack? You should probably find a hobby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b745c69ce66ba561ce92a9a71c75a666</guid></item><item><title>Arrested Development's long love affair with Australia continues with a trip to WOMADelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/arrested-development-speech-interview-womadelaide-hip-hop/106358486</link><description>The pioneering hip hop group returns to Australia this week, with big ideas about the future of hip hop.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c4b6da2fbbd729977da4a8498c16e81</guid></item><item><title>Cheat Sheet: Weinstein, Gaza boycotts, dead bodies and 30 years of Scream</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/scream-7-boycott-melissa-barrera-neve-campbell/106392542</link><description>Weinstein, copycat panic, leaked scripts, closed studios and departing stars — Scream's 30-year journey has been anything but smooth and the seventh edition in the cornerstone slasher series is no different.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73bb21de7b19759ac88047148fe57a61</guid></item><item><title>Women trafficked, kids taught to shoot in PNG's tribal warfare industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/modern-weapons-changing-png-tribal-warfare/106380226</link><description>The proliferation of illegal high-powered guns is fuelling tribal warfare across Papua New Guinea and warlords claim children as young as eight are being trained to carry the weapons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28f8428117a4428745463fe19c0bb2d8</guid></item><item><title>Former NSW prison officers say system protects abusers and silences women</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/former-prison-officers-speak-out-about-nsw-corrections-system/106398318</link><description>Current and former NSW prison officers describe what they say is a toxic workplace culture and a system that shields officers accused of serious misconduct, rather than holding them accountable. They argue it has driven younger officers out of the service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5be0483b18c80258ab18af5e93a6d50</guid></item><item><title>Seventh narco sub discovered in the Pacific as Australia's cocaine habit drives heavy traffic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/drugs-cocaine-australia-narco-subs-pacific/106390402</link><description>At least seven narco subs have been discovered in Pacific waters near Australia in the past 18 months, with experts warning that Australia's cocaine demand means more are on the way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d8f98671f5b2c416d5ca85587c9a1b1</guid></item><item><title>NSW unveils sweeping foster care reforms for thousands of vulnerable children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/nsw-foster-care-reforms-for-thousands-vulnerable-children/106398894</link><description>While some child protection services will continue to be outsourced, the NSW government will play a larger role in the sector, including through the recruitment of foster carers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd068b66bee5e482846c38b6f2fa10bc</guid></item><item><title>Meet the mapmakers recording every remote road in Australia to keep travellers safer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/map-patrol-checks-remote-tracks-google-maps-cannot-cover/106259210</link><description>Google Maps has made city driving a dream, but it's putting lives at risk in the bush. Meet the mapmakers taking on Australia's roughest roads to try to change that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99176f0634c7c7b6a8b216a7e0764087</guid></item><item><title>Medical Board of Australia to appeal decision allowing Dr Dileepa Jayaweera to continue working at Ballarat clinic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/medical-board-australia-appeals-dileepa-jayaweera-vcat-decision/106375838</link><description>The Medical Board of Australia is appealing a tribunal decision that allowed a Ballarat doctor accused of digitally penetrating a female patient to continue working at the same clinic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bc0b420ffd3a0f947f7bc82026273d1</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup hopes to change women's football in Australia — again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/womens-asian-cup-hoped-to-change-womens-football-in-australia/106400994</link><description>The Matildas' run in the 2023 World Cup saw unprecedented media coverage and crowds, and a participation boom among girls and women. Can the Asian Cup do the same?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7eedc698a02dcf53314a05b0f1d9b2f4</guid></item><item><title>US President Donald Trump says 'evil' Iranian leader is dead after US-Israeli air strikes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/iran-missiles-shake-gulf-states-after-us-israel-strike-tehran/106401498</link><description>US President Donald Trump says Iranian Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has been killed in US air strikes. Iran's state media has confirmed the ayatollah has died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67cfa34aa78f84889fa47788b0af65a9</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup 2026: What time do the Matildas play? How to watch and follow Australia vs the Philippines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/matildas-vs-philippines-how-to-watch/106399058</link><description>The Women's Asian Cup is finally upon us, with the Matildas beginning their quest for a second continental crown against the Philippines in Perth. This is all the need to know information, plus how to watch and follow the tournament opener.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5cfee17f0c281d226b3b73bd0621938</guid></item><item><title>Domestic violence accounts for 40pc of the more than 200 reported kidnappings that take place annually in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/nsw-records-more-than-200-kidnappings-40pc-due-domestic-violence/106397414</link><description>Data shows that in the year to September 2025, NSW Police received 230 abduction and kidnapping reports — up from 224 in the previous year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebd11b90588784e4e19e5eb40128237b</guid></item><item><title>Minjee Lee and Hannah Green set for all-Aussie shootout in Women's World Championship final round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/minjee-lee-hannah-green-lead-womens-world-championship/106401716</link><description>Australian duo Minjee Lee and Hannah Green share a one-shot lead in Singapore with 18 holes of the Women's World Championship to play.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7377e54378f97806cb229256f38a10a</guid></item><item><title>Growing expectations Lake Eyre could reach full capacity for first time in decades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/could-lake-eyre-finally-reach-capacity-after-decades/106395774</link><description>In the centre of Australia, there are whispers that Kati Thanda-Lake Eyre is experiencing conditions strangely similar to those that set a record depth of 6 metres in 1974.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a7da95dcdc507290d245f264442922f</guid></item><item><title>Extreme rhetoric in Australia's right-wing political circles deserves more attention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/extreme-rhetoric-australia-right-wing-circles-deserves-attention/106395138</link><description>The rhetoric in Australia's right-wing political circles is getting more extreme and the media should be paying more attention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">348954e35462858407cf5ddf639ebafc</guid></item><item><title>How easy is it to buy a gun in NSW after the Bondi terror attack?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/nsw-firearm-licence-process-after-bondi-terror-attack/106311394</link><description>Law reforms were swiftly passed following the massacre in December. So how difficult has it become to legally own a firearm in the state?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73ddd1df1bcf6d24fc88f90f0f34ed4c</guid></item><item><title>Calls to modernise Australia's surrogacy laws as couples continue to look overseas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/qld-calls-to-update-australian-surrogacy-laws/106348962</link><description>Australia's complex surrogacy laws are under review, but in the meantime, couples like Alex and his husband say they are being pushed to look overseas to add to their families.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e3bc8b394559ae347ce32b58c92b5e0</guid></item><item><title>How on-campus university life has changed as studies shift online</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/how-uni-life-has-changed-on-campus-utas-online-experience/106196352</link><description>Two students who went to the same university 30 years apart share their radically different experiences as lectures go online and face-to-face contact takes a back seat in the post-pandemic world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d793e1e6b1459382224df761446729d</guid></item><item><title>Smoked crocodile on pub menu brings tourists to far north Qld town El Arish</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/smoked-crocodile-tourism-drawcard-for-far-north-queensland-town/106391750</link><description>Tourists are travelling hundreds of kilometres to the small town of El Arish in far north Queensland to get a look at its smoked crocodile.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cabca723bf687d4d240a4b89d22e760c</guid></item><item><title>US military releases vision of reported strikes in operation targeting Iran's supreme leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/us-military-releases-vision-of-reported-strikes-on-iran/106401814</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2a70b74bbdf5d216e98083c461d5814</guid></item><item><title>Bowling green's 'unbelievable' 86C temperature highlights need for urban heat mitigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/heat-imaging-highlights-urban-planning-heat-mount-gambier/106348418</link><description>Drones are measuring the temperatures of common surfaces in regional cities and the results have stunned emergency services, with Mount Gambier's lawn bowls turf recording a temperature of 86 degrees Celsius.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c62e50ede0ff579b0a4933f44187a74f</guid></item><item><title>Serious Tasmania Police officer misconduct allegations more than double in three years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/tasmania-police-misconduct-allegations-increase/106398482</link><description>Allegations of the most serious rated police misconduct have more than doubled in three years, according to police data, with complaints including family violence and possession of child exploitation material.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab94b565912a3ce376ed88078c1bc9f7</guid></item><item><title>Australian in Dubai describes Iranian missile strikes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/australian-in-dubai-describes-iranian-missile-strikes/106401914</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d90f4b63ff55aba720577bc45853469</guid></item><item><title>Record rain falls in parts of South Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/record-rain-in-eyre-peninsula-sa-west-coast/106401748</link><description>Heavy rain has fallen in parts of South Australia, bringing relief to some dry regional areas, with more expected for parts of the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45a9f1bd9cbe7205e03d44b581846cc3</guid></item><item><title>Tropical low develops off North Queensland coast as rain begins to ease in flooded far west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/tropical-lows-develop-coral-sea-rain-eases-western-qld/106400164</link><description>Weather conditions in North Queensland are forecast to get wetter from today, but communities along the coast will be keeping an eye on the potential for a low pressure system to move toward land this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd35e1e707e138f288f074ae0572d290</guid></item><item><title>Aftermath of a missile strike on Tel Aviv</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/aftermath-of-a-missile-strike-on-tel-aviv/106401996</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e51fc2235e8fe683e4cf1a8c0388d23f</guid></item><item><title>Bruce the bull makes appearances at Albany’s local bowling alley and pool rooms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/bruce-the-bull-makes-appearances-at-albany-s-bowling-alley/106386354</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c43ff5abeb22f1c8926dd338337b0ab</guid></item><item><title>Brahman bull called Bruce shifts animal stereotypes in WA's Great Southern</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/brahman-bull-travels-to-albany-great-southern-beach/106382298</link><description>Rescued nearly a decade ago by his owner, Bruce the Brahman bull has since grown into one of the Great Southern's most beloved icons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b0134f9a97ab26b9ce31ec84c04f7e5</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand into T20 World Cup semis despite Pakistan win over Sri Lanka</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/new-zealand-pakistan-sri-lanka-t20-world-cup-semifinals/106401888</link><description>New Zealand has made the semis at the T20 World Cup after Pakistan beat Sri Lanka but not by enough runs to steal the last-four place from the Black Caps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c4729fbb67501d14eb5876ce97e7f8b</guid></item><item><title>Iran's Ayatollah Ali Khamenei was a staunch hardliner who mastered the art of playing his enemies off each other</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/ayatollah-ali-khamenei-obituary-supreme-leader-iran-revolution/105436050</link><description>A conservative Islamic scholar with a head for politics, Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei succeeded his mentor in the wake of the Iran-Iraq War — and consolidated his grip on power over the following decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">474f8fca83d68d59e9f28336e6554dc8</guid></item><item><title>Australia 'did not participate' in Operation Epic Fury in Iran</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/australia-not-involved-iran-operation-epic-fury/106401742</link><description>Foreign Minister Penny Wong has confirmed Australia was not involved in the major Israeli-United States operation in Iran that has reportedly decapitated its leadership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">897d14caa3899ecf309e3db5bedea22c</guid></item><item><title>At least 100 reportedly killed in strike on Iranian school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/at-least-100-reportedly-killed-in-strike-on-iranian-school/106402036</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8607a2a9e79cb7309430cf9d4c22455e</guid></item><item><title>Dom Aboud explores different cuts of meat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/dom-aboud-explores-different-cuts-of-meat/106397432</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">941e2dff02512529a1ffaf991d17ef64</guid></item><item><title>Chef utilises whole steer and cooks 'funny' meat cuts to reduce food waste</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/chef-tackles-food-waste-by-cooking-funny-meat-cuts/106384778</link><description>Some high-end restaurants are turning to an uncommon practice to save money and hundreds of kilograms of beef.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">924d487f02b6bf9f04287cfbffd1f5da</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup 2026: From Mary Fowler to Jamilla Rankin, here's your guide to the entire Matildas squad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/womens-asian-cup-matildas-squad-guide-mary-fowler-sam-kerr/106399190</link><description>You know the big names — Sam Kerr, Mary Fowler, Steph Catley — but what about the emerging Matildas stars who are looking to make an impact at the Women's Asian Cup in Australia? Here's your guide to every squad member.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">763f794188f823248918c46cc59a3c87</guid></item><item><title>Gippsland wildlife carer uses dental technique to save injured turtles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/dental-supplies-and-resin-healing-injured-turtles/106336388</link><description>When turtles are struck on country roads, their shattered shells can mean certain death, but one rescuer in Victoria's east is patching them up and sending them home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">477b2481a6e9db237a882be300f5b9e1</guid></item><item><title>Iran conflict has financial markets preparing for oil price shock and economic damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/iran-conflict-impact-on-oil-price-and-australian-economy-/106401868</link><description>Global financial markets expect a damaging spike in the oil price tomorrow, with a critical shipping route for the Gulf's biggest producers now a war zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4868e440a14027f89545e69289ae6105</guid></item><item><title>Buskers at Australian championships showcase why live is best</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/buskers-perform-at-australian-championships-heat-stanthorpe/106400160</link><description>Musicians young and old battle it out for the prize of top busker at a national event in Southern Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acca6d7badf1086ea29bfb339d33a97e</guid></item><item><title>Caring for carers: How respite services can make all the difference for those looking after others</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/respite-services-and-caring-for-carers/106348298</link><description>Each Wednesday, Meika Robertson's husband Rob spends the day in respite care going on outings and chatting with others. While Rob enjoys a day away from home, Meika catches her breath.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84fc0935fac64a240e4cbd64ef7f9eed</guid></item><item><title>Illawarra community centre programs to continue using $65,000 art sales cheque</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/art-show-illawarra-social-housing-residents-bundaleer-barnardos/106381822</link><description>The future of a community centre of social housing residents in the NSW Illawarra region has been secured using donations from a charity art exhibition at Sydney's Botanic Garden.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa1b5954bd15f33033d01954702b7f1f</guid></item><item><title>How eastern quolls, once extinct on the mainland, have returned to Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/eastern-quoll-breeding-in-western-victoria/106380674</link><description>Once dubbed the Australian "native cat", the eastern quoll was abundant before it was completely wiped out on mainland Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf8d3d731a351321e89acf8785fb658d</guid></item><item><title>Live: Knights end losing streak in Vegas despite devastating injury to young star</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/nrl-las-vegas-live-knights-cowboys-bulldogs-dragons/106402102</link><description>The Dragons take on the Bulldogs in Las Vegas after Newcastle five-eighth Fletcher Sharpe goes off injured early as the Knights beat the Cowboys to kick off the 2026 NRL season. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8959d0d0c8e4ce9462dccef09c201996</guid></item><item><title>'Strong and resilient' stories of Goldfields elders preserved in Legacies exhibit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/goldfields-legacies-karlkurla-elders-oral-history-exhibition/106381410</link><description>An oral history exhibition shares the lifetime stories of First Nations elders and their experiences at critical moments in Australian history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d6c97723abf22582477d99d1dc0f593</guid></item><item><title>WA government fights to keep current GST deal amid cost blowouts, seeks mining exemption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/wa-government-wants-keep-gst-deal-as-it-is/106396492</link><description>WA is desperate to retain the GST deal it struck with Scott Morrison as the Productivity Commission looks to rein in cost blowouts, and says exempting 25 per cent of mining revenues could help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f93e91cc798e5663fcba5fdc372a27ee</guid></item><item><title>Attacking Iran is risky but Trump knows Americans like to win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/trump-iran-taste-for-attacking-other-countries/106402042</link><description>Trump once proclaimed: "I am especially proud to be the first president in decades who has started no new wars." Now things have changed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54c6c851587822ddd8ae61777e49e0f8</guid></item><item><title>Twelve new offences added to Queensland's 'adult crime, adult time' policy bringing total to 45</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/new-offences-added-to-adult-crime-adult-time-policy/106401834</link><description>Offences like unlawful stalking and conspiring to murder are among the 12 to be added to the Queensland government's third expansion of the "adult time, adult crime" policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08735803463e8ae22b0bf7ccf063c9b8</guid></item><item><title>Childhood cancer survivor vowing to live 'life to the fullest' after heart transplant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/cancer-survivor-heart-transplant-recipient-organ-donations/106395354</link><description>After overcoming cancer as a child, scans revealed her heart was "working under half of what it should".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c32486b50a8092b9713488ee287065f</guid></item><item><title>Smoke rises from Leadership House in Tehran</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/ugc-tehran-compound/106402186</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b84d4555d82236e687d875534d7c83f9</guid></item><item><title>Satellite images show destruction of Iran's Ayatollah Khamenei's Leadership House</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/abc-verify-satellite-over-ayatollah-compound/106402030</link><description>Iranian state media has confirmed the death of Ayatollah Khamenei, and a high-definition satellite image shows the home of the supreme leader in ruins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">556353e5fa88d2425f965def2738794f</guid></item><item><title>'More than 100 children' dead in US and Israel strike on Iranian school, Iran says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/iran-school-children-killed-strikes-us-israel-hundred-dead/106402152</link><description>Vision has emerged of crowds of people searching through the rubble of a girls' elementary school in the city of Minab in southern Iran. Iranian authorities say a US and Israeli air strike killed more than 100 children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9e1072a2c49fcc27054e7fd282e4f25</guid></item><item><title>People chanting and cheering in Tehran after reports of Ali Khamenei’s death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/people-chanting-and-cheering-in-tehran/106401898</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88099765e0329b132c91f33b3251c6e1</guid></item><item><title>Man dies after reportedly being washed away at Eurelia, SA Police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/sa-man-drowns-eurelia-southern-flinders-ranges/106402384</link><description>Police say emergency services were called to the area, about 30km north of Orroroo, following reports a motorcyclist had been washed away when attempting to cross a flooded creek.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55248336fdee9b7df9a8806db65f4528</guid></item><item><title>Severe weather warning in place as more wild weather lashes Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/severe-weather-warning-victoria-thunderstorm-rain-emergency/106402136</link><description>Thunderstorms and heavy rain are expected to continue across Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b43e28b44a2e05eb9741d0f1f4850940</guid></item><item><title>Who was Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/who-was-iran-s-supreme-leader-ayatollah-ali-khamenei-/106402442</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa3446f658dad687f1425fc6fc80078c</guid></item><item><title>Amid mixed feelings about war, Iranians celebrate killing of Iran’s supreme leader and hope freedom is near</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/amid-mixed-feelings-iranians-celebrate-death-of-khamenei/106401952</link><description>As news reports emerge that Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has been killed, Iranians begin celebrating what they hope is the end of a brutal regime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ee424fec924a2d328ecbf2ccc901944</guid></item><item><title>Bali police re-enact shooting crime scene</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/bali-police-re-enact-shooting-crime-scene/106399314</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bd6166e58750c79ff3578e1c1ee7100</guid></item><item><title>A Bali birthday and a mistaken murder: How shooting death of Melbourne father played out in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/australians-face-murder-sentencing-in-bali-shooting-case/106398148</link><description>Three Australian men are waiting to be sentenced after a months-long trial for the alleged murder of a Melbourne father. Police say it was a deliberate hit job, while the men say it wasn't intentional.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">579fb25cba40f542bd8598e0f2bf5dca</guid></item><item><title>The US and Israel have struck Iran: Who has been killed?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/us-and-israel-have-struck-iran-who-has-been-killed/106401908</link><description>A growing list of Iran's top leadership has been reportedly killed in ongoing strikes by Israel and the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17e0e5c0bc9022b56fb8c519de49db2e</guid></item><item><title>Crocodile at Wallsend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/crocodile-at-wallsend/106402432</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e9872d20123669d1c7f3edf1fb9791e</guid></item><item><title>Crocodiles spotted in Newcastle creek</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/crocodiles-spotted-in-newcastle-creek/106402122</link><description>Reptile experts are searching for several juvenile freshwater crocodiles that have been spotted in a New South Wales creek.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72b44ccecfac4ec158e8c63eb49dfbfd</guid></item><item><title>Iranian news anchor announces Ayatollah Ali Khamenei's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/iranian-news-anchor-announces-ayatollah-ali-khamenei-s-death/106402542</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01239b66d62883a944cc9d6c936013f3</guid></item><item><title>Indepedent review of Inpex Ichthys LNG project finds emissions were 'systematically underestimated' for years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/review-finds-inpex-lng-emissions-systematically-underestimated/106400678</link><description>An independent review into oil and gas company Inpex has found widespread and persistent failures in how emissions were calculated, recorded and reported, dating back to the start of production in 2018.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5331e1a213c954b55d9cca0a65bca8e</guid></item><item><title>Celebrations mixed with grief as Iranian Australians react to US-Israeli airstrikes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/us-iran-airstrikes-australian-reaction/106402200</link><description>A Melbourne woman who fled Iran 19 years ago has described the US-Israeli air strikes on Iran — and the death of its supreme leader — as the country's "Berlin Wall moment".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1e46595629345dbce1b9d48a011e770</guid></item><item><title>Iranian strikes damage Dubai international airport and Burj Al Arab luxury hotel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/iranian-strikes-damage-dubai-airport-and-luxury-hotel/106402154</link><description>Iran's retaliatory strikes have damaged Dubai's international airport and the landmark sail-shaped Burj Al Arab hotel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba8e6920910531663c5048389f5e5a67</guid></item><item><title>Piper James farewelled by family and friends after her death on Queensland's K'gari</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/family-friends-farewell-piper-james-request-for-coronial-inquest/106395954</link><description>The 19-year-old is remembered at a funeral on Vancouver Island as her parents call for an inquest into her death on Queensland's K'gari.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c4a176d11de658392dea2e3c45ffdf3</guid></item><item><title>Ayatollah Ali Khamenei's death may not lead to regime change in Iran</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/iran-supreme-leaders-death-may-not-spark-regime-change/106402086</link><description>The death of Iran's supreme leader leaves a power vacuum in a perilously unstable country. It could end with a military takeover and a new leader with a no-limits approach to war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">daa277d2907b7a43a15418029eeda2ee</guid></item></channel></rss>