<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 07:12:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>What we know about the 15 explosive devices found around Canberra this week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/act-what-we-know-about-pipe-bombs-found-around-canberra/106238418</link><description>The discovery of 15 explosive devices along footpaths near a Canberra lake shocked residents this week, raising questions about how the devices came to be there and who could be responsible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">019150209eaeb46fa7b03c8846218bfe</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Aboriginal inmate's connection to country stays strong through art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/sydney-aboriginal-inmates-connection-to-country-through-art/106189742</link><description>With each paint stroke and dot placement, art gives John the opportunity to express his culture, with some of his fellow Aboriginal inmates joining him in creating artworks while incarcerated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7b5839fd6a30d886691909f21ba0d06</guid></item><item><title>Tasty one-tray lemon garlic chicken with green beans and potatoes - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/lemon-garlic-chicken-with-green-beans-and-potatoes/106232614</link><description>This bright and flavourful chicken tray bake take just 15 minutes to prep and bakes in one tray.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a73c160b2a519f90a88a4f5dff57b6cc</guid></item><item><title>Age-old 'seat of knowledge' tradition alive and well in North Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/seat-of-knowledge-tradition-lives-on-in-north-queensland/105088332</link><description>Every day in these North Queensland towns, familiar faces gather to have a yarn in public spaces — just as people have done for centuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">325869c7d1ae1830039386227e137093</guid></item><item><title>Outback NSW lake home to hundreds of turtles set to run dry in 130-year first</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/imperial-lakes-broken-hill-drying-up-water-emergency-wildlife-sa/106231978</link><description>Imperial Lakes Nature Park may soon dry out for the first time in over a century, creating an environmental crisis for the region and the hundreds of native animals that call the lakes home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d7d3b7026a65c01e693993a1ed3446a</guid></item><item><title>Darwin midwife banned from working unsupervised handed $1.1 million NT government contract</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/midwives-in-darwin-private-practice-contract-nt-government/106228974</link><description>Darwin midwife Claire Marks, who has been placed under a number of conditions by Australia's medical regulator, will continue to run the Northern Territory government's new private practice midwifery service, it's been confirmed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">898f33552c4b6b06b8287c8c6b52eadb</guid></item><item><title>Matteo Berrettini fighting illness ahead of Australian Open clash against Alex de Minaur</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/matteo-berrettini-illness-australian-open-tennis-alex-de-minaur/106240240</link><description>Alex de Minaur's first-round opponent, Matteo Berrettini, faces a race against time to be fit for the start of the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">add7f046c505e63ba5a21535ac437487</guid></item><item><title>Linguists and First Nations community work together to 'awaken' Bunurong language</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/bunurong-languages-dictionary-spoken-100-years/106159478</link><description>After more than a century of silence, the Bunurong language is being brought back to life by elders, linguists and community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">515aff92716327e8e9d519b3d139b14c</guid></item><item><title>Taking paracetamol during pregnancy not linked to autism or ADHD in children, Lancet study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/lancet-rejects-trump-paracetamol-pregnancy-autism-claims/106236278</link><description>Just months after US President Donald Trump warned women about taking paracetamol during pregnancy, a new study finds there is no evidence linking the painkiller to autism in children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5de1a4dfed93e58310a9ec2b4600e8f0</guid></item><item><title>Greek tourist Ioannis Vidiniotis flooded with support after tragic accident at Cottesloe Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/greek-tourist-ioannis-vidiniotis-injured-at-cottesloe-beach/106237774</link><description>A young Greek tourist is flooded with donations and support after a tragic accident at Perth's most iconic beach left him with life-changing injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a1dd2bb32494b5c19fd59882ebd35a2</guid></item><item><title>Fishers and authorities in WA's Gascoyne fear overfishing after demersal ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/fishers-authorities-fear-overfishing-gascoyne-demersal-ban/106150920</link><description>Fishing stocks have rebounded in WA's Gascoyne with authorities hoping it will model recovery efforts statewide. But that success could be undone by fishers fleeing restrictions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f38c6332fb3d32cad83360ed57de96c</guid></item><item><title>Geraldton's Horizon Ball sculpture draws large crowds as international visitor numbers rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/horizon-ball-geraldton-sculpture-tourism/105874130</link><description>Geraldton's Horizon Ball sculpture is drawing huge crowds of tourists after the spot gained international attention on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eba3cf9d89c6c4bef13d23466afa00e</guid></item><item><title>Chinese debate Iran crisis as official and public views diverge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/chinese-people-debate-iran-crisis/106233150</link><description>As protests rage in Iran, Chinese netizens are openly debating freedom, repression and global power politics, even as Beijing keeps its criticism focused on Washington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cb409cb7ff6c28214b6ec8d97672506</guid></item><item><title>Eighteen bikies charged after Kwinana Freeway incident in Perth's southern suburbs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/bandidos-bikies-charged-incident-perth-kwinana-freeway-baldivis/106240552</link><description>Police charge members of the Bandidos outlaw motorcycle gang after an incident in Perth's southern suburbs on Friday evening that led to a section of the Kwinana Freeway being blocked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2b29320fd6426f556a7c36c6983a9a0</guid></item><item><title>Michael Zerafa has been accused of quitting against Nikita Tszyu. There is no more heinous crime in boxing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/michael-zerafa-quit-nikita-tszyu-boxing-brisbane/106240558</link><description>To be called a quitter is the lowest insult in boxing. But whether Michael Zerafa was guilty of this or not, he has successfully ostracised himself from the sport's fraternity for the second time in his career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">666c36595d1ab5ab540ee320d55b3322</guid></item><item><title>Woman dies after tree falls on her car south of Wollongong as winds and rain lash NSW coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/woman-dies-tree-hits-car-at-macquarie-pass-winds-rain-lash-nsw/106240346</link><description>Emergency services were called to the Illawarra Highway near Clover Hill Road just before 4pm after a tree branch fell onto a passing vehicle on a busy road.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">787443ac31c67f6ad25ac254b1fe21d8</guid></item><item><title>Why the chase for the grand slam record is not a burden for Novak Djokovic ahead of Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/novak-djokovic-australian-open-grand-slam-record-wins/106240934</link><description>After two years stuck one shy of the all-time grand slam titles record, Novak Djokovic believes the Australian Open is as good a place as any to make his greatest piece of history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a317a3b7e35d5a435b5869ec5fe052ec</guid></item><item><title>Lawyers, rights groups and civil libertarians call on NSW Police Commissioner to not extend protest restrictions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/legal-rights-groups-call-nsw-police-commissioner-end-protest-ban/106240338</link><description>Lawyers, human rights advocates and civil libertarians are urging the NSW Police Commissioner not to extend a ban on authorised public assemblies as January 26 approaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7021a3ef7f4894f3d88960244194671f</guid></item><item><title>'I'm back!' Australian cricket great Damien Martyn shares heartfelt update on remarkable recovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/damien-martyn-shares-heartfelt-health-update/106240912</link><description>Australian cricket great Damien Martyn has paid tribute to the support he has received during his remarkable recovery from meningitis, while revealing he was given a "50:50 chance" of surviving the illness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eca2cb00c8f48fd37b04e0f5eb7d1a03</guid></item><item><title>How charging board or rent to adult children can help them and you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/what-is-fair-when-charging-young-adult-children-board-or-rent/105913086</link><description>Experts on the benefit of charging board and expenses if you’re sharing a home with young adults, and how to calculate it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f013049216634a8617431620cd4371e3</guid></item><item><title>Russian President Vladimir Putin wants to 'make a different world' and Iran is vital to his plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/putin-wants-to-reshape-world-and-iran-is-vital-to-his-plan/106235534</link><description>Tehran is the epicentre of the nightly protests shaking Iran's regime, but the reverberations are being felt loud and clear in Moscow, too.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd497b3f576d298b64f3e57ea045a281</guid></item><item><title>Liberal Party election autopsy delayed after Peter Dutton suggests report defames him and his staff</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/peter-dutton-election-loss-liberal-party-report-delayed/106240876</link><description>The report, co-authored by Liberal grandees Pru Goward and Nick Minchin, has now been sent to a legal team to ensure it is watertight while the party decides what step to take next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b60e19eca9f7586a8f4206ba63ebeffd</guid></item><item><title>BHP gaining ground as CBA loses its shine in market power struggle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/bhp-popular-with-investors-as-cba-loses-market-favour/106238676</link><description>The year is barely underway but already there's a power struggle between our biggest corporations as they fight it out for line honours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeb0f98b47bad2c6a579105a2a0e9c3f</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Refreshed after a break and ready to flex your trivia muscle?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/106220390</link><description>Wow, you really don't quit. Let's see how poorly you perform this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">497407b3cf3c86b4d01057c744d6d31d</guid></item><item><title>Australian woman documents her stint in Chinese weight loss 'prison'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/weight-loss-prisons-obesity-rising-in-china/106236242</link><description>Camps offering intensive weight loss programs are on the rise in China as the country faces skyrocketing obesity rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">874810325ae70eec5fc8bd9f0d4253f1</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr scores twice for Chelsea in Women's FA Cup, declares her best form is not far away</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/sam-kerr-comeback-continues-with-fa-cup-double-chelsea/106241588</link><description>Sam Kerr declares she is approaching her best form after scoring twice for Chelsea in a Women's FA Cup victory over Crystal Palace.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e507bcbe5096fda3243668d35e4a988</guid></item><item><title>Supreme Court case continues despite more than 200 interpreter errors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/victorian-supreme-court-case-200-language-interpretation-errors/106173346</link><description>A Victorian Supreme Court trial is forging ahead with amended transcripts after an interpreter made more than 200 translation errors during a key witness' evidence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">036ee554afd22b63f6f81f5c81333097</guid></item><item><title>Grandmother's support group becomes a lifeline for Lithgow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/grandmother-led-support-group-becomes-a-lifeline-for-lithgow/106098374</link><description>It started as a Facebook page and now it is a vital charity. Here is how this group run by grandmothers is fighting loneliness in the NSW Blue Mountains.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2eb9d750a3d061eaece11cc2cee617bd</guid></item><item><title>Mount Lofty Ranges koala population boom risks starvation, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/researchers-find-mount-lofty-ranges-koala-boom-risk-starvation/106156850</link><description>South Australia's Mount Lofty Ranges is experiencing a koala population boom that would likely lead to starvation and deaths, researchers say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55d754e13667dfb466a6f2c599b46e8f</guid></item><item><title>Forgotten tracks from the 2005 Hottest 100 you need to hear again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/forgotten-songs-from-2005-hottest-100-bloodhound-gang/106146344</link><description>We've dug out some standout tracks from the Hottest 100 of 2005 that you need to hear again. Relive the mid-2000s music that defined an era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc09e85614dc423c888ef09906b13089</guid></item><item><title>Bourke artist Jenny Greentree's career sprouted during millennium drought</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/drought-sparked-back-o-bourke-art-gallery-jenny-greentree/106175110</link><description>Jenny and Steve Greentree's young family faced losing everything in the millennium drought. Twenty years on, their thriving art gallery has helped to put Bourke on the map.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d286846e2dad00a047b8c1f2b22adfb</guid></item><item><title>Why Abbey Barrett's mum wants more federal government funding for brain cancer research</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/brain-cancer-abbey-barrett-family-campaigning-for-funding/106231668</link><description>Abbey was "joy on two legs" and now she is gone, another lost to brain cancer. Somehow her family must carry on, as the fight continues for more funding to bring this horror disease to an end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ec9d9719847601eb996db80054f8f03</guid></item><item><title>The central Queensland town of Agnes Water and its surfing culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/agnes-water-surfing-culture/106078546</link><description>Former professional surfers and board makers have chosen this small coastal paradise as their home, but with smaller waves, what makes it so special?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b8aba4dba07fb14409df5310038cfba</guid></item><item><title>Flash flooding, heavy rainfall and gusty weather keeps SES busy on NSW coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/flooding-heavy-rainfall-severe-weather-nsw-coast/106241644</link><description>The State Emergency Service responds to more than 2,300 incidents and 25 flood rescues, most of which involve people driving through floodwaters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">682c9a58e4ded3172424c5883c33001a</guid></item><item><title>Torres Strait Islanders commemorate the legacy of 1936 pearl industry maritime strike</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/torres-strait-islanders-commemorate-1936-maritime-strike/106185202</link><description>Fed up with restrictions over what they earned and where they could go, pearl boat workers embarked on nine months of industrial action that would change the face of their communities forever. Ninety years on, their legacy is still felt across the Torres Strait.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bbdd6f0c5d68b167bcdb5801855febc</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026 live: Venus Williams knocked out by Olga Danilovic, Zeynep Sönmez helps ball kid after fall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/australian-open-2026-live-updates-sabalenka-alcaraz-berrettini/106238282</link><description>It was a busy day at Melbourne Park but it was the night session that saw both the men's and women's world number ones progressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4c6da1c1e570acfa84f69ab5872ca93</guid></item><item><title>Belconnen man charged in relation to 15 pipe bombs found in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/man-charged-over-pipe-bombs-found-in-canberra/106241830</link><description>The 41-year-old Belconnen man is charged in relation to the 15 pipe bombs found along the shore of Canberra's Lake Ginninderra this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0dc9e987c3793bd3ea0506e103b01883</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's animal populations suffer as state is ravaged by bushfires, extreme heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/victoria-wildlife-animals-suffering-bushfires-heatwave/106219826</link><description>From animal shelters to "entire generations" of bat colonies, heartbreaking stories of the significant loss of animal life are beginning to emerge in the wake of Victoria's disastrous bushfires and severe heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">246fa1e142bbfb8793f30a1c3d549ee0</guid></item><item><title>Status of hate laws remains uncertain as politicians converge on Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/status-of-hate-laws-uncertain-ahead-of-parliamentary-sitting/106242028</link><description>A special sitting to respond to the Bondi terror attack will begin in Canberra on Monday, but the government is no closer to landing changes to hate laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">255e439147fc4cb47e4707425c861a98</guid></item><item><title>NBA great Allen Iverson meets hundreds of fans in Australia, including NBL star Bryce Cotton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/nba-great-allen-iverson-meets-hundreds-of-australian-fans/106241020</link><description>NBA great Allen Iverson left hundreds of fans star struck at a meet-and-greet event in Perth, none more so than one of the best NBL players of all time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b373847c5a5d4039376decd597e93c92</guid></item><item><title>WA government announces Department of Health taskforce to crack down on illicit tobacco trade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/wa-tobacco-wars-police-to-recruit-retired-officers/106242124</link><description>A taskforce will be assembled to combat Western Australia's illicit tobacco market, with plans to pull retired and current police officers into the Department of Health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08dff102ed11f6d8820fe8684e6738e7</guid></item><item><title>Pasa Faho to screen at Sydney Opera House after creating a bit of buzz</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/pasa-faho-to-screen-at-sydney-opera-house/106219252</link><description>Pasa Faho is the story of a shoe salesman who struggles to save his small business and pass on his values to his son.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72a5355a25ce77e7fc6326115bb7b45b</guid></item><item><title>World's first legally binding treaty to protect oceans and marine life takes effect</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/high-seas-treaty-marine-protection-in-effect/106241974</link><description>The High Seas Treaty will govern about two-thirds of the planet's oceans including vast areas beyond any country's borders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">689da612d25cd88f659134fa3cc9f955</guid></item><item><title>Denver Broncos quarterback Bo Nix's season-ending ankle injury throws Super Bowl race wide open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/nfl-playoff-denver-broncos-bo-nix-quarterback-ankle-injury/106242230</link><description>As the final four NFL teams prepare to battle it out for a place in the Super Bowl, a last-minute injury to Denver quarterback Bo Nix has thrown the race for the championship into chaos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c034ea9c6f12ed153bb2d45859cff93d</guid></item><item><title>Talia Gibson moves through to Australian Open second round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/australian-open-talia-gibson-wins-first-round-melbourne-park/106242036</link><description>Talia Gibson prides herself on her aggressive on-court approach, which was on full display in her convincing first-round victory at Melbourne Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43668a5df364b7db43c9c951d67baef6</guid></item><item><title>Darwin gathers for Geektacular cosplay event celebrating geek culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/geektacular-nt-darwin-is-geek-culture-cool-nerd-community/106241848</link><description>Has a surge in the popularity of hit shows like Stranger Things led to an uptick in geekiness, changing how we feel about nerd culture? The ABC attended Darwin's Geektacular event to find out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95b123f4e86653bc014839e025f23438</guid></item><item><title>Why Alex de Minaur will lean into his 'selfish' side for the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/alex-de-minaur-australian-open-draw-first-round/106242496</link><description>As the nation's great hope for the Australian Open, Alex de Minaur is ready to unleash his selfish side in an effort to secure his first grand slam title.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b153f752f5b400fa206021a2a3f8dbf</guid></item><item><title>Boy, 12, in critical condition after being bitten by a large shark at Sydney Harbour beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/shark-attack-boy-suffers-critical-injuries-vaucluse-east-sydney/106242502</link><description>Emergency services were called to Hermitage Foreshore Walk near Shark Beach at Vaucluse about 4:20pm on Sunday afternoon following reports of a boy being bitten by a shark.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d4a045dd3eae0df5ada21ab4b2d9396</guid></item><item><title>Writers' Week letter shows premier backed removal of Randa Abdel-Fattah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/premier-letter-on-randa-abdel-fatah-at-writers-week-released/106241792</link><description>South Australia's premier told the Adelaide Festival board it would open itself to "accusations of hypocrisy" and "legitimate public ridicule" if it did not cancel the appearance of Randa Abdel-Fattah from Writers' Week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83b2891c320c941cac6481cb385e83d8</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of WA fishers congregate to protest against ban on demersal fishing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/wa-fishing-ban-protest-dozens-gather-ozone-park/104760976</link><description>Around 200 disgruntled fishers have journeyed through the streets of Perth to protest against the state government's decision to ban demersal fishing, as the WA Premier Roger Cook confirmed he planned to meet with the industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0833f292c27266d407a9d8a7702f3963</guid></item><item><title>Body found among wreckage of Indonesian plane that lost contact mid-flight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/body-found-among-wreckage-of-plane-in-indonesia/106242700</link><description>A body has been found among the wreckage of an Indonesian plane that lost contact mid-flight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db885b01bccd5ca18317d0cde9a36a3e</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka advances to Australian Open second round at Melbourne Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/australian-open-aryna-sabalenka-first-round-melbourne-park/106242750</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka again proves she is compulsive viewing, as she moves through to the second round with a straight-sets win at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67e6df23b1e21ab03fae823a5e8f1746</guid></item><item><title>Venus Williams lost in the first round. But she still gave fans an emotional evening</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/venus-williams-first-round-loss-in-emotional-return/106242736</link><description>Undisputed great of the sport Venus Williams was welcomed back to Melbourne Park with multiple standing ovations but bowed out in the first round to Serbian Olga Danilovic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2896ce50a37c4ece236ddfb91dd87fd3</guid></item><item><title>Unregulated fishing keeps Seahorse World locked out of traditional Chinese medicine market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/unregulated-seahorse-trade-hampers-beauty-point-seahorse-world/106225110</link><description>A seahorse farm in Tasmania thought it was onto a sure thing; exporting dried seahorses to the Chinese market — it turned out not to be as easy as hoped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e8e27a55b03ef0979521c99d06b70a2</guid></item><item><title>What psychologists have to say about the seven types of rest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/what-are-the-seven-types-of-rest/106076824</link><description>Have you ever found yourself still exhausted and deflated after an eight-hour sleep? Perhaps sleep isn't the reset you need.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">072209ca692c4f26d317f79697d0defa</guid></item><item><title>AI platforms like Grok are an ethical, social and economic nightmare — and we're starting to wake up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/ai-grok-ethical-social-and-economic-nightmare/106242320</link><description>As 2025 began, I thought humanity's biggest problem was climate change. In 2026, AI is more pressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0956e00f7c9111bf96801d7da3854c5</guid></item><item><title>Tribunal bans senior nurse for trying to take patient's medication, altering hospital records</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/modbury-nurse-banned-stealing-patients-adhd-medication/106229238</link><description>A senior public hospital nurse has been prohibited from working for four years for attempting to steal medication from a patient and manipulating a co-worker's Facebook account in an attempt to cover it up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a458cc28e2befbbf188f607c29e61cab</guid></item><item><title>Frustrated fans, Zverev confused and a ball kid collapses — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australian-open-2026-quick-hits/106242092</link><description>Fans were left queuing for hours after play started, Alexander Zverev got confused by a gate and Maria Sakkari smashed an insane shot. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8de558ff26a80cd67bd1bee03b1b19e0</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith amuses and delights, Sam Curran fires as the Sydney Sixers lock in BBL finals berth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/steve-smith-sam-curran-fire-sixers-to-bbl-finals/106242754</link><description>Steve Smith oscillates between the ridiculous and the sublime as the Sydney Sixers get the better of the Brisbane Heat in a do-or-die clash at the Gabba.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1ef7e0ae732c5419057160e3a03d756</guid></item><item><title>Calls for an industry-standard heat policy to be implemented on worksites as summers get hotter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/calls-for-industry-standard-heat-policy-on-worksites/106234134</link><description>It has been 13 years since Jenny Newport's son died from extreme heat while on a worksite in Queensland. She believes not much has changed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60f002407b15690de7b318b7c9777c52</guid></item><item><title>The highly detailed, invisible work that goes into 'near real-time' bushfire mapping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/near-real-time-fire-mapping-victoria-vicemergency/106229148</link><description>As the devastating fires in Victoria spread earlier this month, people at home could see how they were moving across the state — not just in videos on the news and social media, but on an interactive map.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">469e416c8b8bc080ac586637f311738e</guid></item><item><title>Meals you can get kids on board with</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/fun-and-easy-recipes-kids-can-help-with/106116250</link><description>We’ve put together four recipes that are fun and easy enough for kids to help with.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60feacb4ce01787344636e59ad880e34</guid></item><item><title>Three performers talk about bringing their clown shows to Perth Fringe World</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/perth-fringe-world-festival-clowning-comedy/106134970</link><description>Three performers at Perth Fringe World talk about why the magic of clowning is getting adults to let down their walls and embrace their inner child.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c3258a63e2472d4f0d5955909eb9d5f</guid></item><item><title>Shark attack at Sydney Harbour beach leaves boy in intensive care with critical injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/nsw-sydney-harbour-shark-attack-boy-update-beach/106243340</link><description>Police say the boy was pulled aboard a vessel by water police officers "within minutes" of the Triple Zero call being made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">601ce151705bbedc4941c852971a37ec</guid></item><item><title>Charles Darwin University researchers investigate whether old tyres can strengthen roads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/nt-cdu-recycled-rubber-tyres-stronger-roads-heat-waste/106204858</link><description>Roads buckle under the pressure of the Northern Territory's harsh climate, but a group of researchers think repurposing discarded materials may be the solution — not only helping the environment, but government budgets too.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">313dc4fe7c3b7f9dddeda018717ab128</guid></item><item><title>Conservationists alarmed by plan to remove rare bird habitat in Sydney's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/conservationists-alarmed-riverstone-wetland-replacement/106227536</link><description>A set of ponds built for a since-shuttered abattoir in Sydney's north-west has become a habitat for rare migratory birds from Alaska and Antarctica.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e97bf8d3994084dbcbcf0225e73b07c4</guid></item><item><title>Two people seriously injured in shooting at Huntfield Heights, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/two-injured-in-shooting-in-adelaide-southern-suburbs/106243568</link><description>Two people have been seriously injured in a shooting at a home in Adelaide's southern suburbs, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53f9a0827c06f656a37b0657ae838015</guid></item><item><title>Cross-cultural sharing is at the heart of Townsville's community garden</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/multiculturalism-thrives-in-townsville-community-garden/106171508</link><description>In the heart of north Queensland, Ukrainians, Fijians, Zimbabweans and Koreans gather in the dirt to help each other grow vegetables.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">747778fb8e47c03a41a45f71a8a4227f</guid></item><item><title>Violent crime spreading to regional towns as WA waits for strengthened tobacco laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/illegal-tobacco-vapes-violent-crime-in-regional-towns/106207292</link><description>Community leaders have called on the West Australian government to take concrete action as violence and crime associated with the illegal tobacco trade spreads to the state's Wheatbelt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7e3842f3ba51094b5b8f8d6f013ec4c</guid></item><item><title>Explosives discovery in Kalgoorlie reno sparks memories of time when gelignite was sold in shops</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/old-explosives-found-in-kalgoorlie-bring-back-gelignite-memories/106240594</link><description>A recent gelignite discovery during a Kalgoorlie renovation has brought back memories of a time when explosives were "freely available" in the mining city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64d37227f41c3e3ac11f2ee1b1eb2dce</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026 live: Djokovic 'excited' to be a centurion as he wins 100th match at Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australian-open-2026-live-alex-de-minaur-novak-djokovic/106243798</link><description>The 10-time champion joined Roger Federer at that milestone after he defeated Pedro Martinez in straight sets on day two.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b57b9ccbcf4cbb0da12d29ad9bb65e74</guid></item><item><title>Senegal storms off field in penalty protest, before returning to beat Morocco in mad AFCON final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/senegal-protests-then-wins-afcon-final-morocco/106243788</link><description>Senegal's players storm off the pitch in furious protest of a refereeing decision late in the Africa Cup of Nations final, but then return to score an extra-time winner against Morocco.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">610d9d94eb36d431cac87390846e0a05</guid></item><item><title>Oxfam wants tougher tax on billionaires as wealth grows 'by half a million dollars a day'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/income-inequality-oxfam-report-calls-to-tax-billionaires/106236612</link><description>Oxfam Australia is calling on the federal government to tax the super-rich to help tackle growing inequality, as billionaires grow their wealth by more than half a million a day on average.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4724ee211a3150b0e7fdb71b1aa50dff</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate death of Canadian hostel worker on K'gari (Fraser Island)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/police-investigating-death-of-woman-on-kgari-fraser-island/106244106</link><description>Police say the woman was working at a backpacker's hostel and went for an early morning swim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f409dea814fdda70230765a9e94b1ae4</guid></item><item><title>Adam Walton reveals what it's like to play Carlos Alcaraz at Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australian-open-adam-walton-carlos-alcaraz-first-round/106244122</link><description>As first-round opponents go, they do not come any tougher than Carlos Alcaraz, as Australia's Adam Walton found out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4124a2c909f8f8034f2ae8a1edd2c277</guid></item><item><title>Bondi victim Matilda's parents doubt hate laws will prevent future violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/matilda-parents-bondi-beach-hate-speech-laws/106241800</link><description>In their first wide-ranging interview, the parents of 10-year-old Matilda, the youngest victim of the Bondi attack, say the federal government's hate laws offer little reassurance that another terror attack will be prevented.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">405f80b4737eaa53d8bbde13d0a4d3d0</guid></item><item><title>Three men charged over death of 16yo Ater Good in alleged Fitzroy drive-by shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/vic-three-people-charged-fitzroy-drive-by-shooting/106244268</link><description>Sixteen-year-old Ater Good died after being found by officers who heard gunshots near the Fitzroy Police Station earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35ad69d653c570fa2bc9dbf7360adb4b</guid></item><item><title>Randa Abdel-Fattah's lawyer serves second concerns notice to SA premier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/randa-abdel-fattahs-lawyer-serves-second-concerns-notice/106244418</link><description>Palestinian Australian author Randa Abdel-Fattah says her lawyer has served a second concerns notice for defamation on South Australian Premier Peter Malinauskas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5070a5a415b4ba1efc660416513153cb</guid></item><item><title>Man faces court charged with planting pipe bombs along Canberra footpaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/man-who-allegedly-made-pipe-bombs-fronts-court/106243948</link><description>Damien Paul O'Brien was arrested in Gungahlin on Saturday night after officers attached to ACT Policing allegedly found items used to assemble pipe bombs during a search of his Belconnen home earlier in the day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">996e13ccf288fcc044fbb0ff0a38074c</guid></item><item><title>'Extremely large' brief of evidence in murder case against Tanika Bromley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/large-brief-of-evidence-in-pheobe-bishop-murder-tanika-bromley/106244508</link><description>Hundreds of statements gathered in murder case against Tanika Bromley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bf0f652b576628b5c3808bcf7764382</guid></item><item><title>Labor identity Tim Picton dies three weeks after alleged Northbridge assault, family confirms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/tim-picton-dies-three-weeks-after-nightclub-assault/106244678</link><description>Former Labor strategist Tim Picton dies in hospital, weeks after he was allegedly assaulted outside a Perth nightclub.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d9df645f784d9937ec88dc8a71dd414</guid></item><item><title>Aerial vision shows extent of destruction from Chile wildfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/aerial-vision-shows-extent-of-destruction-from-chile-wildfires-/106244352</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d08bef0b4bf3af07ee7964b45038b9a2</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open fans wait hours to enter Melbourne Park as Craig Tiley admits surprise over record crowds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/tennis-craig-tiley-surprised-australian-open-crowds-wait-times/106244434</link><description>Thousands of fans are forced to wait in queues for hours, even as Australian Open boss Craig Tiley promised extra resources to aid entry into Melbourne Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e1e9771e052990b4a23a911f74f1c67</guid></item><item><title>Four arrested as Queensland Police seize guns, kilos of drugs in Townsville</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/townsville-police-arrest-guns-drugs-trafficking/106244526</link><description>Police find 100kg cannabis, 8kg of methamphetamine and 1kg of cocaine as well as illegal firearms hidden in bush at a Townsville property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecd99c93b49491f432b2888450905a34</guid></item><item><title>Perth's median house price surges through $1m million mark, new data finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/perth-s-median-house-price-surges-through-1m-mark/106244510</link><description>Domain's latest quarterly house price report has found the cost to buy a home increased by 9.9 per cent in the last quarter of 2025, to a median of $1,087,762.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b643bd9313af2e8b2963681c2ca6a582</guid></item><item><title>House flooded with raw sewage still uninhabitable six months on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/raw-sewage-repairs-six-months-after-spill/106244944</link><description>Six months on from a major sewage spill in Perth's south, one resident whose house was substantially damaged still has not been able to get the repairs he needs to move back in, blaming both the Water Corp and his insurance company for the delay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15da64016c0383c97df8ceb06c38d311</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith focuses on reclaiming Australian T20 spot for Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/steve-smith-t20-world-cup-olympics/106244980</link><description>Steve Smith has lit up the Big Bash since returning to the Sydney Sixers, but concedes the ship has sailed for him to play in next month's T20 World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">840498619d37e7667d0ac59def0a7633</guid></item><item><title>Young Sydney surfer uninjured after shark bites board at Dee Why Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/nsw-young-surfer-second-sydney-beach-shark-encounter/106245088</link><description>Surf Life Saving NSW confirms a boy is unharmed after an encounter with a shark at Dee Why Beach just before lunchtime on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d27f26f3f0945b4bf3612f160d05785d</guid></item><item><title>Roger Allers, co-director of The Lion King, dies aged 76</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/co-director-of-lion-king-roger-allers-dies/106244066</link><description>Roger Allers was known for working on various Disney films including The Lion King, The Little Mermaid and Aladdin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a0ef8a277b8d386b9b932a2c9c5d992</guid></item><item><title>Elphinstone Engineering director sentenced for interfering with Aboriginal relics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/graeme-elphinstone-allegations-interfere-with-aboriginal-sites/106243968</link><description>Graeme Elphinstone, the founder and director of Elphinstone Engineering, avoids conviction and is fined $12,000 for interfering with Aboriginal relics on his land on Tasmania's east coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ad5307c820eb3687e361788dd9c66bf</guid></item><item><title>Storm Hunter wins at Australian Open after thinking her career was over</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australian-open-storm-hunter-reaches-second-round/106244620</link><description>A ruptured Achilles tendon threatened to send Storm Hunter into retirement, but her perseverance pays off with a first-round victory in Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fa04a6d2e7099ffe2cd1b1e136b11dc</guid></item><item><title>Switzerland's Noemi Reugg powers home to defend Tour Down Under title</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/tour-down-under-noemi-ruegg-final-result/106245676</link><description>After being dropped on the first two ascents of a pivotal section of the final stage, Switzerland's Noemi Reugg fights back brilliantly to claim back-to-back Tour Down Under victories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09f302101eab6ed8f9b48dfd7bb2b595</guid></item><item><title>Petition asks Alice Springs Public Library to extend opening hours amid outback heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/nt-petition-alice-springs-public-library-weekend-opening-hours/106244058</link><description>In one of Australia's hottest towns, the library is an important air-conditioned public space offering a no-cost respite from burning summer temperatures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48234b555f036ba2f92ff1804e8371f6</guid></item><item><title>Bondi survivor Ya'akov Tetleroyd lost his father and nearly his arm in Bondi Beach terrorism event. He forgives the gunmen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/bondi-terror-survivor-yaakov-tetleroyd-speaks-naveed-akram/106238196</link><description>Ya'akov Tetleroyd's father died in the Bondi Beach shootings. He nearly lost his arm as a result of being shot, yet he told 7.30 in an exclusive interview that he forgives the gunmen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">036a2c4738ac88afd5123eda6fe48589</guid></item><item><title>WA is losing the tobacco wars as gangs target vape stores and cheap cigarettes flood market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/wa-losing-the-fight-to-control-illegal-cigarettes/106242556</link><description>Burnt out storefronts in Perth and regional cities are testament to the government's inability to control the illegal tobacco trade — and it's not clear when things will change, writes Keane Bourke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">280b53748e89776c07bee7fd574bc253</guid></item><item><title>Kalumburu on flood watch after heavy rain as tropical low has high chance of developing into cyclone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/wa-kimberley-kalumburu-on-flood-watch/106244930</link><description>People living in Kalumburu, one of the most remote communities in Western Australia's far north, are being warned of rising river levels and floods, after heavy rain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6621008c253fa957e1d6b3469b7b33b</guid></item><item><title>Flooding in Kalumburu, in the Kimberley region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/flooding-in-kalumburu-in-the-kimberley-region/106244868</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecd2065eee0e20c7912c37c6bb104e1f</guid></item><item><title>What has caused a 'smack' of jellyfish to wash up on Melbourne's south-eastern beaches?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/lions-mane-jellyfish-melbourne-port-phillip-bay/106244362</link><description>Visitors to Melbourne's south-eastern beaches over the weekend were surprised to see an influx of crimson jellyfish bobbing in the water. One expert says a "perfect storm" of factors has brought them to the coastline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e313ec9d19ef5439121c1957e9127cd9</guid></item><item><title>Weekend deluge causes flooding in far-north WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/weekend-deluge-causes-flooding-in-far-north-wa/106246064</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f57d668cd54ac57ee76274d8260c3d64</guid></item><item><title>Nicolas Cage shrine amid weird pranks at Mount Gambier deputy mayor's home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/mount-gambier-deputy-mayor-celebrity-letterbox-mystery/106245108</link><description>A Nicolas Cage-themed shrine is the latest of a series of celebrity-themed pranks that Mount Gambier's deputy mayor says have befallen his home in recent weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">613d4d6f79a342e68fef76235e90f105</guid></item><item><title>Monday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106245916</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bfd8c1fab3cd958260d324a03f7b0f3</guid></item><item><title>Teenage boy dies of injuries at bottom of cliff near Jerrabomberra Waterhole</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/act-teenager-dies-at-jerrabomberra-waterhole-bottom-of-cliff/106246244</link><description>A member of the public tried to perform CPR on a teenage boy suffering serious injuries at the bottom of a cliff near Canberra, but he died at the scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e11e9a0e318dcb3d76efc7eef5c7678</guid></item><item><title>Man critical after being bitten by a shark at North Steyne Beach in third incident in two days</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/shark-attack-north-steyne-beach-nsw/106246378</link><description>A man in his 20s is in a critical condition after he sustained leg injuries in another shark attack at a Sydney beach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01ac466828db525eeb0257f91ad7b0b0</guid></item><item><title>Man faces court after 2kg of meth seized in Katherine roadside drug bust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/katherine-drug-bust-meth-allegedly-bound-for-darwin/106245962</link><description>A 22-year-old man has faced court after police allegedly found 2 kilograms of methamphetamine, along with large quantities of other drugs, during a traffic stop in Katherine last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98effadd199406586f274ffc8312e87e</guid></item><item><title>Iranian official says verified deaths in Iran protests reach at least 5,000</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/iranian-official-says-verified-deaths-in-iran-protests-5000/106246384</link><description>The death toll includes about 500 security personnel and exceeds that of any other round of protest or unrest in Iran in decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1881129ec8352a4f180454980115f1f</guid></item><item><title>Helicopter at North Steyne Beach after shark attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/helicopter-at-north-steyne-beach-after-shark-attack/106246484</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">593dba8cca07aa1b05943aea09a7b2b3</guid></item><item><title>What is it like to live and work in the Antarctic?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/living-and-working-in-the-antarctic/106246052</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d13273f34a29dd8e349e41e8e456cd05</guid></item><item><title>Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi to dissolve parliament and call snap election for February 8</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/japan-prime-minister-calls-snap-general-election/106246400</link><description>Japanese Prime Minister ⁠Sanae Takaichi will ​dissolve parliament ‌on ‌Friday ‌and call a snap ​election for February 8 ⁠to seek voter backing ‌for her ​spending ​plans and ‍other ⁠policies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6762019ff9f76327ee529684d85c451</guid></item><item><title>Victim Tanya urges alleged Mullewa shooter Kenneth Giles to come home safe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/mullewa-shooting-victim-makes-public-statement/106246464</link><description>In her first statement since she was shot through the hand on January 7, Tanya says she wants Kenneth Giles to know she wants him to return home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d217f22671f03c4ca8f601a436780f7b</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump links Greenland takeover threat to Nobel Peace Prize snub, amid tariffs row with Europe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/trump-norway-prime-minister-no-longer-obligation-peace/106246538</link><description>President Donald Trump sends a text message to Norwegian Prime Minister Jonas Gahr Støre saying he "no longer [feels] an obligation to think purely of Peace" after being denied the prize by the Nobel Committee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20ba7c8762afea740f16f5db3b8abfdc</guid></item><item><title>Land council chair calls for block on appointment of incoming NT administrator David Connolly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/nlc-calls-on-nt-administrator-david-connolly-to-step-down/106244078</link><description>Former Northern Territory Cattlemen’s Association president David Connolly is set to be sworn in as NT administrator next month, but the emergence of past social media posts have led to calls for his appointment to be blocked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1c54e45e5ef104dac2cd71b7015e15a</guid></item><item><title>Philippines star Alexandra Eala sends Australian Open crowds into a frenzy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australian-open-alexandra-eala-philippines-melbourne-park/106246520</link><description>Alexandra Eala, ranked 49 in the world, attracts a crowd that virtually brought the Australian Open to a standstill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed8e4fa5d5e748dd1e7b20e436cc5910</guid></item><item><title>Man critical after being bitten by a shark in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/man-critical-after-being-bitten-by-a-shark-in-sydney/106246594</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e136a9efd0474d1502b11b3ec4dc15a</guid></item><item><title>Prince Harry's court battle against British tabloids reaches final chapter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/prince-harry-returns-to-court-in-battle-with-british-tabloids/106246678</link><description>Prince Harry has returned to court in London in his third and final attempt to tame the British tabloids through the legal system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">370456cf33716b09f3e36a9a21e41ba5</guid></item><item><title>Deadly Pakistan shopping plaza fire death toll rises to 23</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/deadly-pakistan-shopping-plaza-fire-death-toll-rises/106246696</link><description>Pakistani firefighters began pulling bodies from the smouldering remains of a sprawling Karachi shopping mall on Monday where dozens of people remain missing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e150196ed19b2ece558297a16bcff946</guid></item><item><title>What we know so far about Spain's fatal high-speed train crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/what-we-know-about-spain-deadly-high-speed-rail-train-crash/106246960</link><description>Spanish authorities have declared three days of mourning after two trains collided on a track south of Madrid, killing at least 40 people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a439df12ad3524c4e55faa1833f926ca</guid></item><item><title>Italian fashion designer Valentino dies aged 93 in Rome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/italian-fashion-designer-valentino-dies-aged-93-in-rome/106247130</link><description>The fashion icon's creations were adored by Hollywood stars, royals and first ladies for his fail-safe red carpet designs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46af3ffb2731ac5d3650837108493b36</guid></item><item><title>EPA asks Victorians to check water quality before swimming in Port Phillip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/port-phillip-bay-water-quality-summer-beach-reports-epa/106158836</link><description>Victoria's Environment Protection Authority says people wanting to cool off at bay beaches this summer should stay across its regular pollution updates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea04c727cb0b034491d7cd8c93a10cc6</guid></item><item><title>Oak Tasmania issued $1.1m penalty over hundreds of NDIS compliance failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/tas-ndis-provider-1-1m-penalty-for-breaches/106246414</link><description>Oak Tasmania admits to 474 compliance and reporting failures, as well as breaches that resulted in the hospitalisation of multiple NDIS clients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9e88e8b1c262ca731e0c1c273ec6e75</guid></item><item><title>Travel quiz, January 20: Which Australian state has the most wine regions?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/travel-quiz-january-20/106245804</link><description>Do you know where Marco Polo Airport is? And which is the biggest island in Australia?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c9c978f27dccabcd2105d5892e4b823</guid></item><item><title>How lifting gave me back the power to feel good at sport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/how-powerlifting-gave-me-back-the-power-to-feel-good-at-sport/106234088</link><description>As a child, Julie "wasn't one of the sporty kids". A safe gym environment and then a supportive powerlifting community helped her realise that wasn't actually true.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2abbef65f571e75069d3d1abdc6f375</guid></item><item><title>Labor 'really close' to deal with Liberals on hate speech laws, Tony Burke says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/labor-coalition-hate-laws-deal-deadline-looms/106244300</link><description>Liberal MPs gathered to discuss the draft laws at a party room meeting in Canberra on Monday evening after Opposition Leader Sussan Ley and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese met to hash out an agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a2526f58a5d9b6415bdab9d0bbe190d</guid></item><item><title>China ramps up crackdown on Christians amid global political pressures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/china-ramps-up-crackdown-on-underground-christian-churches/106228908</link><description>Dozens of church leaders and members have been arrested in China in recent months, which advocates say is indicative of intensifying persecution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c54c22a63990022797415619510f9303</guid></item><item><title>China's population declines for a fourth straight year amid record low birthrates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/china-population-decline-fourth-straight-year/106245406</link><description>National data shows that in 2025, China's population shrank by 3.39 million people, as experts warn the trend is likely to continue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5e802e05f3c7a95834eb029793b0ed4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump heading to Davos as bond market vigilantes plot against him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/donald-trump-us-federal-reserve-powell-interest-rates/106245010</link><description>There are signs Donald Trump's bold strategy to artificially lower interest rates could backfire, as a level of disquiet emerges on money markets, particularly in bonds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65e936bbb965d193d01d5df138ff1bd8</guid></item><item><title>First Nations employee asked by supervisor about eating ants takes transport department to court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/sa-transport-department-federal-court-case/106231982</link><description>A First Nations employee at South Australia's Department for Infrastructure and Transport (DIT) has claimed she was sexually harassed by her supervisor and racially discriminated against when asked about eating ants before a cultural training session, court documents reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7374c2347019e1b32db9a67988ee3efb</guid></item><item><title>In Iran, Elon Musk's Starlink helped citizens get messages beyond the 'digital prison'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/in-iran-starlink-helped-citizens-break-out-of-the-digital-prison/106244360</link><description>In Iran, Starlink has provided a line to the outside world, but now there are fears about such vital technology being in the hands of one company.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbf024ef38c524a39f1172af74e69250</guid></item><item><title>New Trump tariffs on European allies could push EU to use 'trade bazooka'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/trump-tariffs-european-allies-trade-bazooka/106243894</link><description>Following the Trump administration's recent tariff threat on European allies, some experts warn it may push Europe closer to China, and potentially see the European Union use its anti-coercion instrument, also known as a "trade bazooka", in response.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfd83a0c8c002868f5bb1a1d952c2109</guid></item><item><title>Victorian bushfires squeeze beekeeper access to high-quality trees for bees ahead of winter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/victoria-bushfires-beekeeper-access-restrictions/106243830</link><description>Apiarists in Victoria are wondering how they will keep their bees fed during winter after bushfires two years in a row render certain areas inaccessible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53ba80cd946bb3fbcb843855ca6d35a4</guid></item><item><title>Dissecting Donald Trump's Greenland message to Norway's PM, line by line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/donald-trump-greenland-message-analysed-line-by-line/106246964</link><description>A text message from the US president to Norway's prime minister has fanned the flames of the geopolitical dumpster fire engulfing Greenland. We've analysed Donald Trump's claims to see if they stack up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81dd92b61485bb709c037d07f0241a9b</guid></item><item><title>Women's captain departs football club after men's offensive Silly Saturday costumes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/box-hill-north-fc-womens-captain-leaves-club-after-men-behaviour/106190266</link><description>A women's senior football captain has stepped away from her local club after photos of the senior men's leadership team were posted online during their "Silly Saturday" post-season celebrations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ffb103fdb7886c68801e2562aeef8ca</guid></item><item><title>Stan Wawrinka's impressive win, a wheelchair exit and Alja Tomljanović tells off her dad — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/australian-open-2026-quick-hits/106243998</link><description>One player had to be wheeled off the courts in a wheelchair, while Alja Tomljanović was wishing her dad would be quiet in the crowd. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5d4a55ec566caaa313f28eb7c9913b7</guid></item><item><title>Ipswich residents frustrated as nickel waste stored near homes without council approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/ipswich-residents-nickelwaste-dumped-nearhomes-council-approval/106244714</link><description>The dumping of the waste is the latest in a series of similar events for Ipswich, the city which some now call "Australia's waste capital".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">098856adadd618e6d5f95435a562ca83</guid></item><item><title>Shellharbour mayor's quick thinking during call may have saved deputy's life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/shellharbour-councillor-kellie-marsh-aneurysm-emergency/106245410</link><description>A mayor's split-second decision to answer a phone call instead of heading into the surf may well have saved the life of his deputy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d92c75f46d2dd5048aa680d5e3e2bc68</guid></item><item><title>Flooding impacts low-lying areas in Rockhampton, as residents prepare for Fitzroy River's peak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/rockhampton-prepares-for-flooding-as-fitzroy-river-rises/106243980</link><description>Flooding on the Fitzroy River will be less severe than originally predicted, however about 280 properties could still be impacted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46307e6ceb28c50848a1e3fe59e9e7c9</guid></item><item><title>Foo Fighters are playing their only Australian show in Launceston on Saturday, here's what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/foo-fighters-launceston-concert-what-you-need-to-know/106243618</link><description>Tasmania's "biggest ever concert" is heating up Launceston this weekend, and whether you have tickets or not, there are a few things you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">756623b97549184033b8460854e8b087</guid></item><item><title>Alexei Popyrin shattered as Australian Open campaign ends in first round following thriller against Alexandre Muller</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/tennis-aus-open-popyrin-shattered-muller-defeat/106247208</link><description>Alexei Popyrin concedes he will look inwards once again to think about his career after a crushing loss sent him out of the Australian Open in the first round.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f28d48e2dc361558508277915e9e9d5c</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: PM defends action on antisemitism in QT as debate kicks off in Senate — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/federal-politics-live-blog-jan-20/106245678</link><description>The prime minister defends the government's action on antisemitism in the first Question Time of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce2a21bbf58cf609b34b039baf956196</guid></item><item><title>Man found dead in back of car near Corowa hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/dead-body-found-car-corowa-hospital/106247200</link><description>A police investigation is underway after a man was found dead inside a car near a hospital on the NSW–Victoria border.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffbe1c57c1a4bb08978725b53ff36d04</guid></item><item><title>'Promising' results for AI fish passage aiming to help stop another Menindee mass fish kill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/ai-fish-passage-fishnet-darling-river-trial-mass-fish-kill-nsw/106221776</link><description>The $6.5 million Menindee fish passage trial is now in year two and results are "promising", but not everyone is buoyed by confidence in the project's ability to prevent another mass fish kill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">189c0bfe4dba5512db02a22c6a101b9f</guid></item><item><title>ASX trades down, BHP shares slide, IMF calls out Australia's 'drawn-out' inflation — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-tuesday-20-january/106247268</link><description>The ASX trades down on Tuesday. The International Monetary Fund says Australia, alongside Norway, is projected to see persistent above-target inflation. Follow the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9583dd3a472f2001cb9f12c33d757786</guid></item><item><title>Front lines in 'ghost net' war expand to Australia's north with $25m funding boost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/ghost-nets-funding-remote-nt-blue-mud-bay-indonesia-fishing/106244780</link><description>A $25 million funding injection will help expand the Top End's war on ghost nets, as ranger groups shift focus to the heavily fished seas to Australia's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">486f3c79d2cb26ac2906752d5be6b54c</guid></item><item><title>WA Opposition Leader Basil Zempilas seizes on fishing, tobacco to challenge government's dominance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/basil-zempilas-fishing-ban-tobacco-challenge-state-government/106246436</link><description>While many West Australians were competing for parking spots at beaches on their holidays, Basil Zempilas latched onto two hot topics on which to challenge the government — the demersal fishing ban and WA's illicit tobacco trade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e3968683f38c8c701336ac2ede5ca0d</guid></item><item><title>Attempted murder charges laid, firearm recovered after Huntfield Heights shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/attempted-murder-charges-over-huntfield-heights-shooting/106247230</link><description>A man and a woman are expected to face court after each was charged with two counts of attempted murder over a shooting at a Huntfield Heights home that left two people in hospital, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">728ff3de3a647b50be77716cf4db2799</guid></item><item><title>Pilbara water sources drying up as blistering heatwave continues in Karratha</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/harding-dam-karratha-low-water-storage-levels-heatwave/106237810</link><description>Water sources are depleting in the Pilbara as the arid region endures a summer with little rainfall and temperatures close to 50C.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42ae93a704d37666b5838230f66f76df</guid></item><item><title>'You look younger, richer, more powerful'... fashion giant Valentino farewelled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/naus_nrvalentinosm_2001/106247666</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f55a04f575cb44e8880515f4cf11b986</guid></item><item><title>Morocco accepts Trump's invite to 'peace' board as Putin yet to decide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/morocco-accepts-trump-invite-to-peace-board-putin-yet-to-decide/106247306</link><description>Morocco's King Mohammed VI is the latest leader to accept an invitation to join US President Donald Trump's so-called "Board of Peace", as Russian President Vladimir Putin weighs up his invitation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d516db80e2891a350c5a2049803e63f8</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane suffers vaccine shortages after wall collapses at Toll Group distribution centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/brisbane-hit-by-vaccine-shortages/106247402</link><description>Brisbane parents are being turned away from GP clinics due to a shortage of childhood vaccines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95c7e8806a61ca804b73a3bea4054c5a</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026 live: Taylah Preston advances, Maya Joint eliminated; Jannik Sinner, Madison Keys start title defence on Rod Laver Arena</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/australian-open-2026-live-updates-jannik-sinner-naomi-osaka/106247690</link><description>Australian qualifier Dane Sweeny is not receiving much home-court advantage as he goes up against retiring French fan favourite Gael Monfils in the Australian Open first round. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0df00c26a62e3ee2d269780de89c116</guid></item><item><title>Eraring coal-fired power station to stay open until 2029</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/eraring-coal-fired-power-station-to-stay-open-until-2029/106247568</link><description>The operator of Australia's largest coal-fired power station is to extend the life of its plant in the NSW Hunter Valley for another two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa4566311697a925b7bfb77a6bef8f96</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate report of antisemitic incident against five teenage boys in Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/vic-police-investigate-st-kilda-east-antisemitic-abuse/106247632</link><description>Police have been told the occupants of a white ute yelled abuse before driving at a group of teenage boys in the Melbourne suburb of St Kilda East.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7af758667550d1b0fd6a051ca95fe5f1</guid></item><item><title>Dual British-Australian citizens look to renounce UK nationality over new passport entry rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/dual-british-australian-citizens-look-to-renounce-uk-passport/106244606</link><description>Frustrated dual British-Australian citizens are weighing up their options in response to new passport rules. Here's why some are letting go of their British citizenship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f630d2fdf57d7fc38a6673bde5c08450</guid></item><item><title>How a lion crushed a Datsun with newlyweds inside in 1970s Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/lion-crushed-datsun-newlyweds-adelaide-bullens-safari-park/106245924</link><description>The pair had made an on-the-spot decision on the way home from their honeymoon to visit a drive-through safari park where lions roamed free — and their little brown Datsun came out worse for wear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43ee7f7f3d6b74a70e1cd8189e8b25db</guid></item><item><title>Mile Jedinak joins Socceroos coaching staff ahead of FIFA World Cup as Australia reveals warm-up opponents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/mile-jedinak-joins-socceroos-coaching-staff-fifa-world-cup/106247740</link><description>The former Australian captain is back in the fold for another World Cup, except this time he will be on the sidelines as one of the team's coaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81fdcba14bb2153f890de445e389887c</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged with attempted murder after child allegedly stabbed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/child-with-knife-wounds-flown-to-melbourne-for-treatment/106248002</link><description>Police are investigating after a child presented to the Launceston General Hospital with serious injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a596a4f476857f12bbadc0a70f6d9bc</guid></item><item><title>Surfer bitten by shark at Point Plomer on NSW Mid North Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/nsw-surfer-bitten-by-shark-at-point-plomer/106247202</link><description>The 39-year-old man was surfing at Point Plomer, near Crescent Head, this morning when the shark bit through his board.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb653505bc6e2a92572d8c8cb09c6e0f</guid></item><item><title>Jessica Pegula reveals what goes on inside the Australian Open locker room</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/australian-open-melbourne-park-jessica-pegula-locker-room/106247748</link><description>According to Jessica Pegula, sometimes it is best to stay out of your opponent's way when you are sharing the same locker room.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a1c583886473dd9b6f5188701bb226f</guid></item><item><title>Two dead after car and freight train collide at Cressy, west of Geelong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/two-dead-after-car-and-train-collide-at-cressy/106248126</link><description>Police say "vehicle trouble" or "driver error" may have caused a collision between a car and a train west of Geelong on Tuesday morning that killed two people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5fc5642c346d8651e83f96775a360d9</guid></item><item><title>Six people charged after investigation into footage of burnouts and fireworks on Brisbane's Gateway Bridge on New Year's Eve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/queensland-police-charge-six-burnouts-gateway-bridge-nye-hooning/106247238</link><description>Police allege several vehicles blocked northbound lanes of Brisbane's Gateway Motorway at Murarrie before a group performed burnouts and let off fireworks just before midnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ec618034d256aea7c8a3aa7b536ad9f</guid></item><item><title>Man in his 20s attacked by crocodile near Ingham in north Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/crocodile-attack-north-queensland/106248118</link><description>It is understood the man in his 20s suffered puncture wounds to his lower back, upper legs and hand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f379283597f65dde7888e2168a2c4020</guid></item><item><title>Increase in suspicious fires puts emergency services under pressure in WA's South West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/south-west-wa-suspicious-fires-arson-increase/106224380</link><description>A growing number of suspicious fires left police and firefighters under significant pressure over the Christmas period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d791a57fff1587aacc6ed5ba010c0fb7</guid></item><item><title>Hate laws to pass after Labor and Liberal deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/hate-laws-poised-to-pass-after-labor-liberal-deal/106248432</link><description>The Liberal Party strikes an agreement with Labor to tighten the scope of a bill to ban hate groups, but the position of the Nationals is unclear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b34a07a73e9a13ce0ed28c59db72ba8d</guid></item><item><title>ABC appoints Isabella Higgins as new host of AM radio program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/abc-appoints-isabella-higgins-as-new-host-of-am/106247652</link><description>The former Europe correspondent succeeds Sabra Lane, who has announced she will step down after nine years of presenting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a68c9cd1acf1b461c6b7335a635ccbde</guid></item><item><title>Rangers increase patrols on K'gari (Fraser Island) after dingoes found surrounding dead woman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/increased-ranger-patrols-woman-found-dead-on-kgari-fraser-island/106247890</link><description>The woman was found surrounded by dingoes after going for an early-morning swim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dacce30c93163641174c887bd95d813</guid></item><item><title>Why could Donald Trump's Board of Peace be a threat to the United Nations?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/what-is-donald-trump-s-board-of-peace/106247750</link><description>Donald Trump appears to be trying to build his own international peacekeeping body, which he calls the "Board of Peace". Here's why experts think it might attempt to rival the UN.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5b33664544fb9cc37564486eeb34924</guid></item><item><title>Detectives investigate death of man, 63, in Gippsland town of Maffra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/maffra-death-investigation-homicide-squad/106247384</link><description>The homicide squad has been called to investigate the death of a 63-year-old man in the Gippsland town of Maffra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e35864efde16cf45eb55cc09727ebd2</guid></item><item><title>Brain cancer survivor who finished year 12 hoping medication can get PBS listing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/brain-cancer-survivor-hoping-medication-can-get-pbs-listing/106163562</link><description>Just over a year ago Sienna was shocked to discover she had a rare brain cancer. She's taking a new drug to slow its growth, but it's come at great cost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21adf0d155fecef77dd6873776191137</guid></item><item><title>Man, 29, charged with bushland murder of Matthew O'Brien</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/police-nowra-suspicious-murder-man-charged/106205866</link><description>Police have charged a 29-year-old man after the alleged murder of a 60-year-old man, who was found with serious head injuries on a fire trail in Nowra in December 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1717537b3d9e2a3f71c8e00e16ab753a</guid></item><item><title>French media releases new security footage of thieves in Louvre heist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/new-security-footage-of-louvre-heist-released/106248086</link><description>The security footage shows the thieves smashing the glass on the display cases where the jewellery was kept.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9556ee4895b887312e1e10433709e155</guid></item><item><title>Gilmour Space receives federal funding boost for homegrown rockets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/gilmour-space-funding-boost-for-homegrown-rockets/106247624</link><description>The company hailed the launch of its first Australian designed and manufactured rocket a success, despite it being airborne for just 14 seconds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ef86a9d002caca346cff368daa291fc</guid></item><item><title>Parole Board seeks judicial review of decision blocking release of Snowtown killer James Vlassakis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/parole-board-judicial-review-james-vlassakis-parole-decision/106244864</link><description>South Australia's Parole Board has confirmed it will lodge an application for a judicial review of the decision to keep the youngest of the Snowtown killers James Vlassakis behind bars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5708fe33c430b65e04fbfc33b4e0012</guid></item><item><title>Writers' Week replacement likened to 'thought bubble', but backer says it is 'happening regardless'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/adelaide-council-votes-on-writers-week-alternative/106247520</link><description>Adelaide City Council commits to supporting, but not funding, a replacement event to fill the void left by Writers' Week, as the lord mayor describes the proposal as "not much more" than a "thought bubble".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03b47a20c6ad1ec840fbc6a6d97cd5de</guid></item><item><title>UN representative says Iran's death toll is rising and there could be investigations into 'crimes against humanity'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/united-nations-iran-deaths-investigation-crimes-against-humanity/106238634</link><description>An independent fact-finding mission should investigate potential crimes against humanity committed by the Islamic Republic of Iran, according a UN-appointed representative.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9eb9554dc290945551a0d9273835ced</guid></item><item><title>Brooklyn Beckham has cut ties with his famous parents. What can we learn from it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/brooklyn-beckham-statement-cuts-ties-with-family/106247778</link><description>Celebrity family rifts are not new. Experts weigh in on how they can spark negative feelings about our own family dynamics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b2cd51e90201aa458b1662acb5a3c4c</guid></item><item><title>Four shark attacks in 48 hours on NSW beaches. What do we know about them?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/nsw-what-we-know-about-the-shark-attacks/106248186</link><description>Four shark attacks are documented within 48 hours at beaches across New South Wales, lifting the anxieties of swimmers and surfers who are considering a dip in the ocean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdd09d7f88d80c01ef397e46b5b0f25f</guid></item><item><title>One Nation's ambitious plan raises stakes for major parties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/pauline-hanson-one-nation-polling-state-election-mainstream/106244024</link><description>While she's made no secret of her desire to eventually unseat Anthony Albanese, the One Nation leader's immediate electoral strategy is to gain ground at upcoming state elections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9378de660f955ea3ba520a0ae352651f</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese pays tribute to Tim Picton in parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/anthony-albanese-tim-picton-tribute-parliament/106248850</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">815bd620806de5ee13098374c96a6344</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police commissioner extends Sydney protest restrictions with 'significantly limited' scope</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/nsw-police-update-on-public-assembly-restriction-declaration-law/106248964</link><description>NSW Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon has announced restrictions on protests in parts of the state will be extended.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97b157a8e4854c3a779102cd09f55e8f</guid></item><item><title>Three federal politicians demand incoming NT administrator David Connolly apologise for 'offensive' posts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/nt-administrator-david-connolly-criticised-by-labor-politicians/106248300</link><description>Past social media posts made by incoming Northern Territory administrator David Connolly have been labelled "reprehensible" by three federal politicians, who are also demanding he apologise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5197dd5fd318bec2e8fec957cce707e5</guid></item><item><title>Maya Joint vows to 'come back stronger' after early Australian Open exit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/australian-open-maya-joint-loses-first-round/106249028</link><description>Maya Joint's first Australian Open appearance as a seed did not go according to plan, following a straight-sets defeat on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d1cfb70cdfd67e0e62683a684a60cf7</guid></item><item><title>Hackers disrupt Iranian state TV to support exiled crown prince</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/iran-state-tv-hacked-support-exiled-pahlavi/106248974</link><description>Hackers break into Iranian state television satellite transmissions to air footage supporting the country's exiled former prince and calling on security forces to lay down their weapons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2d6af2341a8b6d36468dc784a517900</guid></item><item><title>Vision of penguin colonies in Antarctica. (Supplied: Ignacio Juarez Martinez)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/vision-of-penguin-colonies-in-antarctica/106247756</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dec1770683327687bcebe5fa04da608f</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic penguin breeding cycles changing rapidly in response to climate change, study shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/antarctic-penguin-breeding-cycles-changing-climate-change/106247472</link><description>Penguins in parts of Antarctica are breeding up to two weeks earlier than a decade ago, likely in response to climate change, according to a long-term study.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">195f7747bf8736cce5a600570b4a107c</guid></item><item><title>Having a big sign at your house may be breaking planning rules. Here's what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/hobart-council-threatens-fines-over-yard-signs/106243974</link><description>Talk may be cheap, but telling others what you think via permanent signage in your yard could be about to cost you big if you live in Hobart. Here is why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1998249271547d56555b8bf620d66e54</guid></item><item><title>Surf webcam captures moment of shark attack at North Steyne beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/surf-webcam-captures-moment-of-shark-attack/106249880</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3383f67b3bfc1661108740bd4f07b134</guid></item><item><title>Valentino's legacy as 'one of the last true titans' of Italian fashion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/valentino-remembered-as-titan-of-fashion-industry-after-death/106247774</link><description>"Valentino red", now synonymous with the Italian designer, was introduced to the world in 1959. But it wasn't until years later he commanded true global attention — and with an entirely different dress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">650b53dff8ce0884258262001076422b</guid></item><item><title>Aussie Dylan Joyce's punt blocked for a touchdown as Indiana down Miami in college football title game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/dylan-joyce-punter-miami-indiana-college-title-game/106249630</link><description>A few months ago, Indiana had the worst record in college football history, and while the Sooners have completed one of the greatest rises in American sports to win the national championship against Miami, it came following a tough moment for an Australian import.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2149ae4285c6910a968f99f276b5563b</guid></item><item><title>Patients relocated at Calvary Mater Hospital after maggot discovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/calvary-mater-hospital-maggot-infestation/106247526</link><description>Patients have been transferred out of the Calvary Mater Hospital in Newcastle after maggots were discovered in a hospital room.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">630c8463627690f66988483b432836f9</guid></item><item><title>Blue Mountains council closes Lincoln's Rock lookout after safety concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/popular-lookout-lincolns-rock-in-blue-mountains-closed/106245326</link><description>A council will shut an iconic Blue Mountains cliff after being overrun with tourists, sparking serious safety and environmental concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ada72b20a8c3f9c6a85fe9134a0fc19f</guid></item><item><title>Prime minister, WA premier pay tribute to former Labor political strategist Tim Picton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/tim-picton-death-tributes-continue-police-minister-sends-message/106248466</link><description>The death of Labor identity Tim Picton rocks his former political colleagues, prompting warnings from WA's police minister about the devastating consequences of one-punch assaults.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84736ea419e0f2b89d15dd485f1e46a2</guid></item><item><title>Hawthorn's Will Day to miss first half of the AFL season with shoulder injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/will-day-hawthorn-shoulder-injury-return-afl/106250104</link><description>Hawthorn star Will Day is set for a lengthy stint on the sidelines after dislocating his right shoulder during pre-season training and undergoing surgery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d307d6fe71f40e6d700287b246f166</guid></item><item><title>Sydney NDIS provider director accused of $3.6m fraud as cash seized at home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/ndis-provider-director-allegedly-defrauded-millions-from-claims/106249802</link><description>Australian Federal Police allege Billal Chami submitted claims for supports and services never provided to participants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df504b690a294a5a80851df23bf1f1ff</guid></item><item><title>CCTV of kitten dumping in Adelaide's north-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/cctv-of-kitten-dumping-in-adelaide-s-north-east/106250206</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a12459f3ea305052690e39c57ca7bc71</guid></item><item><title>Thousands in Albany told to switch to LPG bottles as gas supplier ATCO decommissions network</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/albany-gas-network-to-be-decommissioned/106246382</link><description>The Albany mayor says the city has been blindsided by a decision to decommission the local gas network and transition thousands of customers onto bottled LPG gas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f1c800231c6ac81005eafc6625d1958</guid></item><item><title>Midnight Oil drummer Rob Hirst dies aged 70</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/midnight-oil-drummer-rob-hirst-dies/106249816</link><description>Rob Hirst was diagnosed with pancreatic cancer in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b535d98e30538a1047c5fa6e1db1103a</guid></item><item><title>Do Woolworths shoppers want Google AI adding items to buy? We'll soon find out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/woolworths-google-ai-items-shopping-groceries/106243642</link><description>Without scrutiny, agent-led shopping risks quietly reconfiguring consumer behaviour in ways that are difficult to detect — and even harder to reverse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e87faa771f8a6692e3910d20b01de1f</guid></item><item><title>Deborah Roberts not guilty after mass cattle death at Old Man Plains Research Station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/deborah-roberts-not-guilty-mass-cattle-death/106244294</link><description>Deborah Roberts has been cleared after being charged with animal cruelty and a failure to provide a minimum level of care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d99a7462f5193ea0a7d2aa9e1f8b8ac</guid></item><item><title>Is there a 'normal' amount of sex couples should be having?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/defining-a-healthy-and-fulfilling-sex-life/106100374</link><description>Whether it's TV shows or what our friends say, we pick up an idea of "normal" sex frequency from lots of places. But experts say how often you're having sex doesn't tell you much about whether it's satisfying or enjoyable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d933f11a6d491d896029179c92bdd34a</guid></item><item><title>Helen Manuell changed careers in her 50s from bridal design to sustainable fashion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/helen-manuell-fashion-designer-bridal-knitwear-rmit/106231758</link><description>Helen Manuell changed career paths in her 50s, swapping bridal couture for award-winning sustainable fashion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e16e712493ce4cb02d37d38df466c8c</guid></item><item><title>Maggot-infested meal halts work at $1 billion hydro project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/maggot-meal-halts-work-at-1-billion-dollar-hydro-project/106248782</link><description>An investigation into a maggot-infested meal halts work on a key pumped hydro project in North Queensland, with more than 100 workers flown out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b40fe65ed30e5a5b4dd8904eac05d5b4</guid></item></channel></rss>