<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 18:11:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Security threat prompting PM evacuation linked to intimidation of Chinese dancers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/albanese-lodge-bomb-threat-linked-chinese-dance-group/106384392</link><description>The prime minister was forced to evacuate the Lodge last night due to a bomb threat linked to performances in Australia by a classical Chinese dance and music group that is banned in China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c2f24aaf18103c78d63480741dc5a2f</guid></item><item><title>Sydney doctor Jamal Rifi says IS-linked families in Syria should return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/sydney-doctor-helping-australian-isis-families-in-syria/106385212</link><description>Australian doctor Jamal Rifi has been helping to coordinate a potential repatriation effort from Syria, including by obtaining passports for the families.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d9895896c97fafd5b0ddb78fbb0745c</guid></item><item><title>Australian man Peter Williams given seven years' jail for selling US trade secrets to Russian broker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/australian-sentenced-7-years-jail-selling-us-trade-secrets/106385636</link><description>A judge in Washington has sentenced Australian man Peter Williams to 87 months in prison for selling sensitive information to a Russian broker.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eb2b43d9f83ddf83d0cd30591a8558a</guid></item><item><title>Cull and swimming ban resume after fatal shark attack in New Caledonia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/cull-and-swimming-ban-resume-fatal-shark-attack-new-caledonia/106382354</link><description>New Caledonian authorities ban beach swimming and resume shark culling despite concern from environmental groups, after a wing foiler is killed in an attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a8bb518e0a3ed323ae5f8dadc1b4f49</guid></item><item><title>Woman's family sues NT government over Tennant Creek watch house death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/kumanjayi-dempsey-family-negligence-lawsuit-nt-government/106377134</link><description>The family of a woman who died in police custody in Tennant Creek is suing the Northern Territory government for negligence, alleging officers failed in their duty of care after her arrest and that the 44-year-old was held in an "overheated" cell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c13a5a9ed71fa1e03c03fe256cc4765</guid></item><item><title>NSW premier flags new laws after IS-inspired attacks on gay and bisexual teens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/hate-laws-nsw-after-isis-inspired-sydney-attacks-on-sexuality/106386596</link><description>The New South Wales premier has flagged harsher punishments and new criminal offences in response to gay and bisexual teens being lured online and bashed on camera.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e338e8b970cd0bf9e75722c8533b5172</guid></item><item><title>Payne Haas rejects Michael Maguire rumour in NRL move from Broncos to Rabbitohs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/nrl-payne-haas-brisbane-broncos-south-sydney-rabbitohs/106387292</link><description>Payne Haas speaks publicly for the first time about his move to South Sydney in 2027, explaining why he is leaving the Brisbane Broncos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23d7f158569fe37628f68a479c16b32b</guid></item><item><title>Southern Downs Regional Council rejects developer's proposal for water bottling facility on Cherrabah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/council-knocks-back-cherrabah-water-bottling-plan/106386412</link><description>Farmers say their fight continues after the local council knocked back a Chinese company's bid to extract almost 100 million litres of groundwater a year to bottle and sell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00dcddd89aafebd16a661ba8753b1230</guid></item><item><title>What is duty sex and how do you stop having it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/how-duty-sex-differs-from-maintenance-sex/106325270</link><description>Obligatory or duty sex is most common in long-term relationships, but can also happen in casual relationships where sex is the basis of the connection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdd191427baeb061fa035de6a2d105b3</guid></item><item><title>Connor Rogers learning to walk again after terrifying knee injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/connor-rogers-learning-to-walk-again-/106387768</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9867c848077ceb2f5c362549a6816fd1</guid></item><item><title>Troy Maskell found guilty of 73-year-old Strathmerton postmaster's manslaughter in retrial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/troy-maskell-trial-john-burke-strathmerton-verdict/106357564</link><description>A jury has found Troy Matthew Maskell guilty of a 73-year-old Strathmerton postmaster's manslaughter during a retrial ordered due to inadmissible evidence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d65488cc4991e44ceb6a584155755bb</guid></item><item><title>Alleged bomb threat against Gold Coast's HOTA theatre over Chinese dance group</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/alleged-bomb-threat-against-hota-hosting-shen-yun/106387762</link><description>Shen Yun has been the subject of several threats, including one against Australia's prime minister on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">801ec2a28bbf45bb3b0b2fae7382a49e</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor says federal Liberals must 'do better' as he joins Ashton Hurn in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/angus-taylor-in-adelaide-ahead-of-state-election/106386578</link><description>Opposition leader Angus Taylor responds to SA Liberal leader Ashton Hurn's criticism of her federal counterparts, as he joins her on the state campaign trail in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f59ec12c36a5f5b1cfe00a530da36eb</guid></item><item><title>AFL says umpires' opinion still matters after announcing Brownlow Medal voting change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/afl-brownlow-medal-umpires-voting-statistics/106388170</link><description>The AFL confirms umpires will be able to access player statistics before casting their votes in a bid to quell any controversy around the Brownlow Medal count.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34b913b9bfef804143a58f698ebb4095</guid></item><item><title>Rhys Bellinge manslaughter sentence supported by Roger Cook, but Basil Zempilas disagrees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/roger-cook-backs-rhys-bellinge-manslaughter-sentence/106387722</link><description>WA's political leaders are at odds over the sentence given to obstetrician Rhys Bellinge for a fatal drunken car accident, with Premier Roger Cook backing it and Opposition Leader Basil Zempilas saying it was "on the light side."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e77f4634f119cc9545ec53464d670ed</guid></item><item><title>Suspects arrested in relation to kidnapping murder of Chris Baghsarian</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/kidnapping-murder-of-chris-baghsarian-arrest/106388262</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfb258075adc61818508acad08810fee</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man accused of sexually assaulting woman he held captive tells jury he was under attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/canberra-man-accused-holding-woman-captive-says-he-was-attacked/106388054</link><description>A man accused of holding a woman captive and sexually assaulting her until she fled naked into a Canberra street has told a jury he was the one under attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3649ce1ac7ac040e5511bf11176913d6</guid></item><item><title>Police find car of alleged Mullewa shooter Kenneth John Giles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/car-of-alleged-shooter-kenneth-john-giles-found-/106386140</link><description>Police find a white Nissan Patrol belonging to alleged gunman Kenneth John Giles nearly two months after he allegedly shot his partner and sparked a major manhunt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">786c0c415c0a743457b7b99b8f34cb21</guid></item><item><title>Teenager first in SA to be prosecuted for allegedly creating deepfake images</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/william-yeates-charged-deepfake-image-creation/106387272</link><description>A suppression order has been lifted on the identity of the first South Australian man to be prosecuted for allegedly creating and sharing sexually explicit deepfake images.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0579c79d828d326b52afce269b7d6298</guid></item><item><title>Matildas goalkeeper Mackenzie Arnold unfazed by minimal preparation ahead of Asian Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/asian-cup-australia-matildas-mackenzie-arnold/106388852</link><description>Mackenzie Arnold says she has enough game time and form behind her to perform in Australia's Asian Cup tilt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28ed29e6bbd568d94cc5f8aa03c63e1f</guid></item><item><title>Edith Cowan University's $853 million Perth CBD campus evacuated three days into first semester</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/edith-cowan-university-perth-cbd-campus-evacuated/106388646</link><description>The brand new Edith Cowan University precinct in Perth's CBD is evacuated, with hundreds of students pouring into city streets just three days into the first semester.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e02d5881e243d598bcd67edfd0415d0</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106386834</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc77f1a15284d522020f534db0b0c8e6</guid></item><item><title>Evelyn Araluen wins $100,000 Victorian Prize for Literature for poetry collection, The Rot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/victorian-premiers-literary-awards-2026-winners-evelyn-araluen/106384572</link><description>Eveyln Araluen has taken out the top award at the Victorian Premier's Literary Awards for The Rot, the follow up to her award-winning debut, Dropbear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bebb932a2fa98bee2945eeb2fb336817</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth Bank prepares for the AI revolution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/commonwealth-bank-prepares-for-the-ai-revolution/106388678</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f20171107cc65f5abbf42be0fd5df81</guid></item><item><title>Algal bloom report blames 'convergence' of factors, but ecologist questions flood finding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/sa-algal-bloom-blamed-on-convergence-of-events-including-floods/106387416</link><description>The SA environment minister says preliminary results of an investigation into the causes of the harmful algal bloom back up what scientists had long suspected, but an ecologist who has criticised the government's response says more detail needs to be released.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1f960b541a4d056d1edfb90a54fb85e</guid></item><item><title>Khaled Sabsabi to exhibit two new works at Venice Biennale after controversial dumping and reinstatement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/khaled-sabsabi-venice-biennale-australia-pavilion/106374090</link><description>Last year, Khaled Sabsabi was dumped from the Venice Biennale to avoid "divisive debate". Now, he announces his work will feature in both the main exhibition and the Australia Pavilion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6dd07d28e8e02e7ca920afa0c6c8bcf</guid></item><item><title>Man dies, woman in hospital following unit fire at St Marys, Western Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/man-dies-woman-in-hospital-unit-fire-st-marys-western-sydney/106389368</link><description>A man dies and a woman is taken to hospital in a serious but stable condition after a unit fire at St Marys in Sydney's west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08caa1485b253c49e3755a9683454471</guid></item><item><title>First home buyer affordability slips further, new real estate report shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/first-home-buyer-affordability-slips-domain-real-estate-report/106383700</link><description>The Australian dream of home ownership is becoming an increasingly unrealistic goal for young Australians, new research from Domain has found, with repayments on an entry-level house now averaging almost half a couple's combined income.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5f91f211f4a344ae15a0d4e2a576d54</guid></item><item><title>Bomb threat against Albanese underscores how complex security has become</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/albanese-security-threat-turn-the-heat-down/106380398</link><description>It's tempting to treat the evacuation of the prime minister from the Lodge this week as a bizarre outlier but that would miss the point.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e4503626e9691dc733a2c5f805a1369</guid></item><item><title>Call to find paintings by Tasmanian colonial-era artist William Charles Piguenit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/tasmanian-colonial-era-artist-william-charles-piguenit/106385300</link><description>Experts believe "countless" artworks by a famed colonial artist could be sitting in Tasmanian homes, with the owners unaware of their true value.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff9e75914cf2c39951090bcb5706032e</guid></item><item><title>Mamma Mia! star Amanda Seyfried tackles her wildest musical yet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/amanda-seyfried-interview-testament-of-ann-lee/106327294</link><description>The Oscar-nominated star adored working with director Mona Fastvold to resurrect an astonishing religious figure in The Testament of Ann Lee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6fa40b70280c35ee226e6f5049e8501a</guid></item><item><title>More Australians switching to 'riskier' super funds, as industry calls for tighter regulation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/more-australians-switching-to-potentially-riskier-super-funds/106386326</link><description>More young Australians with less super are moving away from tightly regulated super funds to platform-based or self-managed super funds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e07614748294caff87601e6fc541c23</guid></item><item><title>Labor's capital gains hints are getting less subtle, but will the compromises be worth it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/labors-capital-gains-tax-conundrum/106388456</link><description>The hints are getting less subtle and Labor's plans on capital gains tax are becoming clearer, but a proposal laden with compromises risks undermining any intergenerational argument.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4df2472d99b1fe23e38173f9a3755f0</guid></item><item><title>Australia's first Deafblind class created in mainstream public school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/australias-first-deafblind-class-created-in-public-school/106375588</link><description>Australia's first Deafblind class in a mainstream school has been established after a mother spent two years advocating for her son.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1c86d81c26f56d10e6b6ed0fe3974ae</guid></item><item><title>WARNING: DISTRESSING FOOTAGE Young man kicked unconscious in IS-inspired homophobic attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/young-man-bashed-in-is-inspired-attack/106389330</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4d41882bd965b5d87ade0edc06fdf6f</guid></item><item><title>Suspected serial offender linked to Islamic State walks free over filmed gay bashing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/attacker-linked-to-islamic-state-walked-free-over-gay-bashing/106386334</link><description>A suspected serial violent homophobe linked to an Islamic State terrorist network has walked free on probation after pleading guilty to a brutal snuff-video-style gay bashing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea37089a655fdc17ef25d61f1c048503</guid></item><item><title>Female athletes found to fear 'nothing is going to happen' when speaking out on gender-based violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/gender-based-violence-in-sport-abc-womens-sport-survey/106355578</link><description>Experiences shared by athletes who participated in the ABC's Elite Athletes in Australian Women's Sport survey found many fear "nothing is going to happen" when speaking out on gender-based violence and harassment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49bf3603d609a975bc44ec238194bbd7</guid></item><item><title>Boy, 10, in serious condition after e-scooter struck by car in South Granville, Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/boy-in-serious-condition-after-escooter-struck-by-car/106389620</link><description>A 10-year-old boy remains in a serious condition after he was struck by a car while riding an e-scooter in Sydney's western suburbs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8b1291ff17cb91839ae1e4bb39ac33a</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide theatre company Slingsby says funding loss forces final curtain call</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/adelaide-theatre-company-slingsby-starts-farewell-tour/106367266</link><description>Key figures from Adelaide-based family theatre company Slingsby have decided to let the curtain drop for the final time after missing out on federal government funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d85e2629617cd7592e0f926505694a95</guid></item><item><title>Larry Summers to resign from Harvard over Jeffrey Epstein ties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/larry-summers-harvard-epstein/106389644</link><description>The former US Treasury secretary says it was a "difficult decision" and he will leave at the end of the academic year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9254f19e7c976bba78ff9a76859508fa</guid></item><item><title>Support options for those who receive inappropriate medical treatment for endometriosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/endometriosis-raise-complaint-process/106385704</link><description>If allegations that a surgeon performed surgery for "severe" endometriosis on women with little or no sign of the disease have you questioning your own treatment, here is where you can voice your concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">593b11fc4c09901ad192693bb324451c</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane could fall behind in student accommodation supply, warns Property Council of Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/qld-property-council-brisbane-needs-more-student-accommodation/106297024</link><description>It is no secret finding a rental as a university student can be a challenge. Some are opting for purpose-build accommodation instead, but this major city could be at risk of falling behind in its supply.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23390ea95c0486ac83b722677517771f</guid></item><item><title>Why Australia has become an unlikely getaway for South Korea's biggest baseball teams</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/korea-baseball-teams-in-australia/106386266</link><description>Australia emerges as an unlikely getaway for some of South Korea's biggest baseball stars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42d8d0ae580160f5d463a8afa9c1485e</guid></item><item><title>Iceland to hold referendum on joining EU a decade after abandoning membership talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/iceland-referendum-joining-eu/106389608</link><description>In 2013, Reykjavik abandoned EU membership talks after four years of negotiations, but rising living costs and the ongoing war in Ukraine have rekindled the island nation's interest in joining the bloc.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ed42bbcd692cfa3cce50eb9e3f3e7ce</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand knocks Sri Lanka out of Twenty20 World Cup in super eight match in Colombo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/new-zealand-knocks-sri-lanka-out-of-t20-world-cup/106389722</link><description>New Zealand knocks tournament co-hosts Sri Lanka out of the Twenty20 World Cup with a 61-run win in their super eights game in Colombo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">946bb9ae9286d5dbe9dd2e108f4073dd</guid></item><item><title>Expanded Newcastle Art Gallery finally opens after decades of turmoil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/newcastle-art-gallery-expansion-opens-after-decades-of-turmoil/106385406</link><description>It has been two decades in the making, but the troubled Newcastle Art Gallery expansion is finally opening its doors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcfca6bd1010a9aa2ce40e8b3f3a2cb2</guid></item><item><title>Guide to Listening: ABC Classic's Festival of Female Composers and International Women's Day on ABC Jazz</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/guide-to-listening-international-womens-day-abc-classic-abc-jazz/106383718</link><description>For 10 years, in the lead-up to International Women's Day, ABC Classic has celebrated classical music by women across centuries. Here's what's in store for 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b5147af3995708c9117e85ca3177439</guid></item><item><title>Prosecutor's breach of WA evidence rules triggers retrial for man accused of child sex offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/prosecutor-breach-evidence-rules-retrial-man-sexual-abuse/106388342</link><description>A man found guilty of sexually abusing his stepdaughters wins a retrial because a "serious breach" by a prosecutor resulted in a "miscarriage of justice".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b37eaa2d3d8ee5fec2440ccb2517ab43</guid></item><item><title>Gary Foley Collection tells activism history through Aboriginal lens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/aboriginal-activism-history-foley-collection-victoria-university/106385374</link><description>The ABC gets a rare look at the Aboriginal History Archive, a little-known collection of thousands of items collected by the well-known activist Gary Foley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e237149f16ae0e60b0f75d33622d850</guid></item><item><title>Australians fear falling victim to AI-related crimes, deepfakes and hacks, research shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/australians-fear-ai-related-crime-deepfakes-hacks-study-shows/106381232</link><description>More than half of Australian adults are worried about AI being used to cause them harm, and almost as many fear falling victim to a crime enabled by the technology, a report found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7d976faa70ea67fec95df8618d826fe</guid></item><item><title>What is Shen Yun, the group named in a threat against Prime Minister Anthony Albanese?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/what-is-shen-yun-group-named-in-albanese-threat/106387128</link><description>Police are investigating a bomb threat against a Gold Coast theatre hosting a classical Chinese dance group after a threat was also made against the prime minister's official residence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb107db72e70382ec5b59cc45c2d6fb6</guid></item><item><title>Dolphin injured in suspected boat strike</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/dolphin-injured-in-suspected-boat-strike/106389198</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b18c0e7ddbd7d009a0273e097773ce12</guid></item><item><title>US tariffs on Australia remain at 10 per cent — for now</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/australia-to-escape-higher-tariffs-threatened-by-trump/106390024</link><description>Trade Minister Don Farrell hopes Australia can dodge a higher tariff rate being imposed by the US, saying trade officials overnight confirmed the tariff rate on Australia would remain at 10 per cent — at least for now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce900e2d0989046389098bd767e1f8ce</guid></item><item><title>New Shanghai Chinese restaurant in Katherine rocked by pre-dawn machete attack, carjacking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/new-shanghai-restaurant-katherine-alleged-carjacking-machete-nt/106385582</link><description>A Top End Chinese restaurant manager says the eatery's staff have left town after its chef was allegedly threatened with a knife in a pre-dawn carjacking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33e1e166001f7064df661973091a7005</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup 2026: Philippines up for the fight against the Matildas in tournament opener</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/philippines-matildas-womens-asian-cup-preview/106365770</link><description>The last time the Filipinas faced Australia they were trounced 8-0. But they have a renewed side and spirit, and are ready to push the Matildas all the way in the first Women's Asian Cup game in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">260c4faeead5a0a6c64116506be67ecc</guid></item><item><title>RBA governor Michele Bullock calls for patience as rate decisions get harder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/rba-governor-bullock-unveils-how-cash-rate-decision-being-made/106389044</link><description>Michelle Bullock gives more details on how quickly developments affecting monetary policy have moved since the middle of last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95c9f11a6694d0a98d40e8d6013c7283</guid></item><item><title>Teenager Jeremy Webb died of meat allergy from tick bites, coroner finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/jeremy-webb-first-confirmed-red-meat-tick-allergy-death/106390088</link><description>Teenager Jeremy Webb's death in 2022 is the first documented fatal case of mammalian meat allergy in the country and second in the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d7da6aa182c61e11bf7a1fdc257a5a1</guid></item><item><title>Former Australian of the Year Grace Tame responds to Anthony Albanese's 'difficult life' apology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/albanese-apologises-for-calling-grace-tame-difficult/106389860</link><description>Grace Tame criticises Prime Minister Anthony Albanese's qualified apology after he described her as "difficult", saying "what a patronising cop-out".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c5456cedc7e1df5461328c7fb225c62</guid></item><item><title>INXS nominated for induction into Rock &amp; Roll Hall of Fame</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/inxs-nominated-for-rock-and-roll-hall-of-fame/106390218</link><description>INXS will be considered for induction into the Rock &amp; Roll Hall of Fame and is one of 10 first-time nominees on the ballot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfee5f25d80a5a69d1dfaaec1ebd3c4c</guid></item><item><title>Concerns over Medicare changes restricting rural mental health treatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/concerns-over-medicare-changes-mental-health-access-rural/106385282</link><description>A regional patient and psychologists say changes to Medicare restricts access to telehealth and video psychologist services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">916e2ffc2d62708eda2db7dc80d6bbeb</guid></item><item><title>Gas giant Arrow Energy takes Australia's biggest pork producer to court over gas pipelines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/arrow-energy-launches-legal-action-against-sunpork-in-land-court/106384552</link><description>A major energy company is taking Australia's largest pork producer to court over plans to build gas pipelines through its property on Queensland's Western Downs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">766a03eccf79e7872514ec826aa04eb0</guid></item><item><title>US women's ice hockey captain Hilary Knight disappointed by men's team's call with Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/donald-trump-womens-ice-hockey-gold-medallists-respond/106390304</link><description>Members of the US women's ice hockey team respond to Donald Trump's phone call with the men's team after both won Winter Olympics gold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef8e94aac987f4adbb79323477274e5e</guid></item><item><title>The AFL's ruck rule changes spark fears of an injury influx as Shannon Neale limps off in preseason</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/afl-ruck-rule-change-injury-fear-shannon-neale-max-gawn/106390750</link><description>Geelong's Shannon Neale might have escaped a serious injury, but coaches and players are beginning to voice concerns the AFL's rule changes could lead to more rucks getting hurt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">996afcf51bcb663d506e4e5dd8095e6b</guid></item><item><title>Sunset Strip residents learn water unsafe even for washing in after 66 years using it to brush teeth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/sunset-strip-residents-learn-water-unsafe-after-66-years-nsw/106375164</link><description>Residents in Sunset Strip knew their water was not safe to drink, but it came as a great shock to read a letter stating it was not safe to bathe in or wash with either.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6fbbc176affd623ab8bfde04c2c4451</guid></item><item><title>Former patient of gynaecologist Simon Gordon, Sarah Hayden speaks out about her treatment.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/simon-gordon-former-patient-sarah-hayden/106390946</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3247b769f86765b73c4f82cc84590280</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of former patients of gynaecologist Simon Gordon join support group</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/endometriosis-womens-health-gynaecologist-simon-gordon-/106390516</link><description>More former patients of Melbourne gynaecologist Simon Gordon have come forward to express distress over their treatment with many joining a newly-formed private support group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37d2dfbf266603d49c6ff41b9a8d2128</guid></item><item><title>Defence lawyers argue Greg Lynn 'cannot possibly' have fair retrial this year, as 59-year-old makes bail bid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/former-jetstar-pilot-greg-lynn-bail-hearing/106389956</link><description>The Supreme Court of Victoria hears the former Jetstar pilot's application to be bailed ahead of his retrial over the alleged 2020 murder of Carol Clay in Victoria's High Country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dba28b386639f322735cd9dbc18f77c</guid></item><item><title>Senator Sarah Hanson-Young calls for Triple Zero overhaul at Optus outage hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/optus-call-centre-panic-during-triple-zero-crisis/106391184</link><description>A Senate committee hears bombshell testimony about Optus's processes during an outage that led to the deaths of multiple customers who were unable to call Triple Zero.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd0236ca1fe1907ada8d8a7aee9449fe</guid></item><item><title>Debate about children of 'ISIS brides' has become hyper-politicised</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/children-isis-brides-politics-anthony-albanese-coalition-greens/106382326</link><description>The fate of the "ISIS brides" is inextricably linked to constitutional facts but the debate about their future is not taking place in a legal chamber — it is being fought in the court of public opinion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9a4b4b60f030a3b4951f9b27cc4b5ca</guid></item><item><title>Qantas shares fall more than 6 per cent after first-half profit announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/qantas-first-half-profit-2026-shares-decline/106390004</link><description>Qantas' first-half profit result has disappointed shareholders, but chief executive Vanessa Hudson says the airline's largest fleet renewal in history will pay off.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7da08d86b99e41a9921fa0921a55a00</guid></item><item><title>Australians will receive nationwide mobile alert in July under emergency notification trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/national-emergency-mobile-alert-system-trials-to-begin/106390534</link><description>Most Australians will receive a mobile phone alert in July this year, as part of a nationwide test of a new emergency warning system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4db5049e09d9645dbd501418beda950</guid></item><item><title>Pro-democracy Hong Kong media mogul Jimmy Lai's fraud offence overturned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/jimmy-lai-fraud-sentence-overturned/106391580</link><description>Hong Kong's Court of Appeal overturns the lower court ruling against Jimmy Lai on a fraud offence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be862b59ab1790d12271d8fc1eb231fe</guid></item><item><title>Christopher Turner jailed over fatal gas mix-up at Bankstown-Lidcombe Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/christopher-turner-jailed-over-fatal-gas-mix-up-hospital/106390672</link><description>Newborn John Ghanem died, while baby Amelia Khan suffered severe and permanent brain damage when they were inadvertently given nitrous oxide instead of oxygen after their births.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f120c7d7649eac16be028cd79fb49f5</guid></item><item><title>89-year-old man struck by car in Canberra's north dies in hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/act-police-still-investigating-as-84yo-man-struck-by-car-dies/106391482</link><description>An 89-year-old man dies in hospital after being struck by a car in Lyneham earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">811b540c148e4d2c4f2446a16d630c35</guid></item><item><title>Grandmaster Viswanathan Anand believes Australia ready to become chess country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/chess-grandmaster-viswanathan-anand-visit-australia-scg/106387668</link><description>Five-time World Chess Champion Viswanathan Anand says he believes Australia could be on the verge of becoming a proud chess nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48a4eccbbad1817a139d04f15aee8b32</guid></item><item><title>What is mammalian meat allergy and how do you develop it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/what-is-mammalian-meat-allergy/106390604</link><description>Jeremy Webb's death in 2022 from a tick-induced red meat allergy is the first to be recorded in Australia. Here's what we know about mammalian meat allergy and how to avoid it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe373c32057149f397d0b5aaf6ac1eba</guid></item><item><title>Mother and daughter discover largest known coral on Great Barrier Reef</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/mum-and-daughter-discover-largest-known-coral-great-barrier-reef/106383412</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3daef36d07767054d10828bf2ba66f43</guid></item><item><title>Coral colony discovered by mother and daughter citizen scientists could be world's largest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/citizen-scientists-discover-great-barrier-reef-coral-colony/106386786</link><description>Mother and daughter citizen scientists find what is believed to be the largest coral colony on the Great Barrier Reef and possibly in the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91fa00279ea7b18d4fa86fca3a923a8f</guid></item><item><title>How an onstage clash between a future NT administrator and a political hopeful drew battle lines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/david-connolly-phil-scott-onstage-clash-political-fault-lines/106382028</link><description>A keynote speaker shoved an environmental activist at a conference in 2023. Now, one of them is the Northern Territory's next administrator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e75b45dd5e0004999c99eefa241bb377</guid></item><item><title>High levels of E. coli and dead fish found in River Torrens, causing a stink</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/e-coli-dead-fish-found-in-river-torrens/106390262</link><description>Rowers have had to move their training and a boat operator has held off bookings after high levels of E. coli were detected alongside dead fish on a stretch of the River Torrens in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ad59d33fd1590d282aa013f1573296d</guid></item><item><title>Man, two girls injured after suspected lightning strikes during Perth storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/three-people-reportedly-struck-by-lightning-during-perth-storm/106391898</link><description>Two teenage girls and a man in his 70s are receiving medical care after lightning strikes in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1e2a03de3030d0583fb35ea7299b9f5</guid></item><item><title>SA coroner recommends life jacket rule change after boating deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/sa-coroner-makes-lifejacket-recommendations-after-boating-deaths/106390748</link><description>South Australia's coroner has recommended the state "lead the nation" by making it mandatory for people to wear a life jacket when aboard any boat up to 7 metres in length.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5486e423401701cab96ae9cc65aa00b4</guid></item><item><title>Hikers found after 24-hour rescue mission in Snowy Mountains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/hikers-rescue-mission-snowy-mountains-geehi/106349146</link><description>Emergency service crews have conducted a 24-hour rescue mission, involving 350 metres of a vertical climb, to locate two hikers who became stranded on a ledge in the Snowy Mountains.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9b24590c61cca8c46954332db3ba540</guid></item><item><title>Abattoir Beaufort River Meats halts operations as $20m in live export transition grants are rolled out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/sheep-transition-grant-funding-revealed-farmers-processors/106389306</link><description>Forty farming families and five processors have secured live sheep transition funding from more than 260 applicants, including Beaufort River Meats in the Great Southern, which has temporarily shut down amid ongoing livestock shortages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3ed5e4e0e96f265b1cdd291d0715f3b</guid></item><item><title>Foreign terror attacks could be used to enact NSW's protest laws, activists argue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/activists-appeal-nsw-protest-restriction-laws/106391960</link><description>The demonstrators are arguing in the state's highest court that the laws introduced by Premier Chris Minns after the Bondi Beach terror attack should be ruled unconstitutional.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f53260ff384c2558e9dde21966918b17</guid></item><item><title>Cuba claims 'armed terrorist infiltration' prevented during open water speedboat shootout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/cuba-says-terrorist-infiltration-stopped-by-speedboat-shootout/106391348</link><description>Cuban coastguard troops shot dead four people and injured six others they claimed were approaching the country on a speedboat filled with weapons set to be used in an act of terror.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24bb4712029afa19a478adb89c5c09ce</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's week unravelled by one-word description of Grace Tame</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/anthony-albanese-bomb-threat-grace-tame-isis-brides/106380004</link><description>The prime minister was this week evacuated from the Lodge over a bomb threat and later got stuck in a tit-for-tat with a former Australian of the Year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0315cf7f99182f207e068ea2908c3b93</guid></item><item><title>Switzerland's Crumbling Giants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/switzerland-s-crumbling-giants/106392636</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07d4c54905d4e3033fb33d529d9e4ec8</guid></item><item><title>Dingo advocates call for end to culls and recognition of environmental and cultural value</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/wa-cc-thurs-dingo-advocates-call-for-greater-protection/106390662</link><description>A campaign to introduce protections to native dingoes has taken its fight to parliament house, arguing that treating dingoes as pests is causing deep cultural and environmental harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45fd7eaff14717b891fd17fae8140d9b</guid></item><item><title>Winegrape growers welcome the establishment of national vineyard register</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/grape-growers-welcome-national-vineyard-register-amid-oversupply/106390054</link><description>Grape growers have endured a tough few years and there are hopes that a national database will help to improve the industry's fortunes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9444becd9e08bb1b3103ab723d04ddf</guid></item><item><title>Sharp decline in tobacco sales linked to illegal sales, not people quitting, says researcher</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/sharp-decline-in-tobacco-sales-linked-to-illegal-sales/106367890</link><description>Business managers and researchers are concerned that a sharp decline in tobacco sales in Alice Springs could mean more people are taking up smoking illegal tobacco.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a398206ec2b41104eded0f00a0c5343a</guid></item><item><title>Fungal infection cluster at Royal Prince Alfred Hospital linked to deaths of two patients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/nsw-rpa-fungus-cluster-two-dead/106392254</link><description>The cluster of infections at the transplant unit at the Royal Prince Alfred Hospital late last year saw two people die, health bosses say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3be2c63a8de9d2e30a48f6a420875dd8</guid></item><item><title>NT cattle stations assess flood damage, as rain in central Australia declared natural disaster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/flood-damage-cattle-stations-nt/106391070</link><description>Disaster recovery funding is activated by the NT and federal governments, as flood-affected communities begin counting the cost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56b3004fc60d2b339d9c3cba1d43389c</guid></item><item><title>SPC Global scales back plans for Shepparton juice production move with Fair Dinkum deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/spc-global-move-juice-production-griffith-shepparton-mill-park/106391490</link><description>SPC Global is moving juice production away from Melbourne in a bid to save $8 million a year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c020c9d7252db26c07fffba7721ad9c</guid></item><item><title>Australia to focus on basics against India in second match of ODI series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/cricket-odi-australia-india-odi-hobart-ash-gardner/106392878</link><description>Ash Gardner says mastering a simple game plan was the key to Australia's convincing six-wicket win over India in the ODI series opener Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cefb056636d5b3b4f664e3d2545d0a7e</guid></item><item><title>Raymond Reddington found guilty of murdering wife Sharon Fulton 40 years ago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/raymond-reddington-found-guilty-of-murdering-wife-sharon-fulton/106392508</link><description>A jury in the murder trial of Raymond Reddington, 79, finds him guilty of killing wife Sharon Fulton 40 years ago, despite a body not being found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">359c04b5c367936a518c34a78c521973</guid></item><item><title>Former teacher Stephen Fane Noga denies allegations by former student they had sex while she was his student</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/stephen-fane-noga-gives-evidence-hobart-teacher-rape-trial/106334334</link><description>Stephen Fane Noga has denied allegations he had sex with a former student while he was one of her teachers at Hobart Matriculation College in the 1980s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc4cd3c50b93f321eaaaeaf2f8b464a9</guid></item><item><title>Thursday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106393546</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b150fb4de907d597621b793d4d355cf</guid></item><item><title>Palaeontologists hope ancient whale fossil found on Victorian coast will be a window to evolution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/21-million-year-old-whale-fossil-extracted-from-ocean-grove/106392450</link><description>A 21-million-year-old fossil found along Victoria's Bellarine Peninsula has been recovered in what has been described as one of the largest and most complicated excavations in the state's history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6438d20bcf61ca8135fd1d1efde3a23</guid></item><item><title>Governor-General Sam Mostyn speaks with Jess Ong on ABC Radio Darwin ahead of David Connolly's swearing in.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/governor-general-sam-mostyn-abc-darwin-david-connolly/106393038</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70286a7949a56219e725796ca39a3409</guid></item><item><title>What is the future for Tennis Australia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/what-is-the-future-for-tennis-australia-/106393266</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1176dd5e009fba79f12d96c5dbbe0ddb</guid></item><item><title>Former Burgertory owner Hash Tayeh found to have incited racial hate at pro-Palestine rally in Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/former-burgertory-owner-found-to-have-incited-racial-hate/106393920</link><description>The former burger chain owner has been found to have breached Victoria's hate speech laws at a pro-Palestine rally in the CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8500940b127f1d4d27d9b7990006460d</guid></item><item><title>Funding axe looms for nine childcare centres failing standards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/childcare-funding-cuts-safety-rules/106392910</link><description>Nine childcare services that have failed to lift standards will only be named if the federal government decides to cut their taxpayer funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96b01329881bbb1370099da2e2185b61</guid></item><item><title>Danish PM Mette Frederiksen calls snap election after standoff with Trump over Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/danish-prime-minister-calls-a-parliamentary-election/106394144</link><description>Denmark will hold a parliamentary election on March 24, Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen announces, seeking to capitalise on a surge in support for her defiant stance against US pressure over Greenland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d98e15f84b88dc7b648d666bc236b7ef</guid></item><item><title>Health, environment departments questioned 'evidence' cited in salmon antibiotic approval for florfenicol in Tasmanian waterways</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/tas-concerns-over-salmon-antibiotic-approval-process/106391438</link><description>Tasmania's health department and environment watchdog questioned the scientific rigour behind an application to use the antibiotic florfenicol in salmon farms, including a lack of evidence about its impact on humans, documents show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6791dafaccc5a00178a77268c129c24</guid></item><item><title>What is the best wash cycle to use on your washing machine?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/best-wash-cycles-to-use-at-home-for-clothes-towels-linen/106361962</link><description>Eco, fast, cotton, heavy, intense cold? Experts on the most cost-effective and efficient wash cycles for your home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ded506332417d3a6ce5c5116c4dee33</guid></item><item><title>From A$AP Rocky to Megadeth — these 10 great albums got 2026 started right</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/best-new-albums-2026-asap-rocky-j-cole-megadeth-willow/106381570</link><description>This year has already given us a bounty of beautiful new records. Here are just 10 of the best we've heard so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2a4e4f793d56ceea4d1588e71a989e5</guid></item><item><title>Student protesters in Tehran shout "Long Live the Shah!"</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/student-protesters-in-tehran-shout-long-live-the-shah/106393898</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ee7c96df770a01d1cd59ee386a0a47f</guid></item><item><title>The ABC speaks to Iran's exiled crown prince Reza Pahlavi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/the-abc-speaks-to-iran-s-exiled-crown-prince-reza-pahlavi/106393904</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d28ecba24cdf789646027b28ea41295f</guid></item><item><title>Crown prince Reza Pahlavi on US military intervention in Iran and how a post Islamic Republic 'transition' would work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/reza-pahlavi-on-military-intervention-in-iran-and-his-transition/106382722</link><description>As the United States and Iran held their third round of nuclear talks on Thursday in Geneva amid heightened regional fears of the prospect of another war in the Middle East, Iran's exiled crown prince Reza Pahlavi says now is the time to move forward with military intervention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f1509ae4c9c1413d71cb2760111720c</guid></item><item><title>How Australia's lax property tax has created a class system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/australias-lax-property-tax-has-created-a-class-system/106391788</link><description>Australian real estate now is among the world's most expensive, and that has made it a red-hot political issue as demographics shift.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a31c0c5d0a59e1d562ac1a42edfcb654</guid></item><item><title>Thousands break into property market with 5% Deposit Scheme for first home buyers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/five-pc-home-deposit-scheme-influx/106136868</link><description>The number of people buying their first home with a 5 per cent deposit surges after the federal government makes sweeping changes to the scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">055b8bde6bb91a5be7130ae021c2fd32</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar military using festivals as propaganda to hide war zone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/myanmar-festival-propaganda-hiding-war-amid-air-strikes/106382144</link><description>As Myanmar's junta celebrates Chin National Day in an effort to project control, air strikes on civilians underscore a deepening civil war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">656854e7d08816135ef808492c3d120f</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup 2026: 'Proactive' Matildas aiming for Asian Cup glory under Joe Montemurro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/proactive-matildas-2026-womens-asian-cup-sam-kerr-mary-fowler/106388102</link><description>Although filled with familiar faces, the Matildas are now a completely different side to the one that captured hearts and minds at the 2023 World Cup. This is how a "proactive" Australian side is likely to line up at the Women's Asian Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">093451dc407c262e3909ee0f0ff52e93</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous people are going to jail at a record rate — what's the solution?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/solutions-focused-courts-helping-reduce-recidivism/106391944</link><description>The number of Indigenous people behind bars is rising. But some judges are bucking the trend by taking a different approach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b32b1f3d871b83341d8e3bd141d8b73</guid></item><item><title>HungryPanda alleges blackmail, intimidation amid dispute with delivery riders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/hungrypanda-alleges-blackmail-intimidation-amid-dispute/106392560</link><description>The dispute between HungryPanda and some of its riders has taken another twist, with the food delivery company accusing some workers of intimidation and blackmail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1445c8e14cdfa8b004c9936e189292eb</guid></item><item><title>Hillary Clinton slams Epstein committee for grilling her instead of Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/hillary-clinton-gives-deposition-at-jeffrey-epstein-committee/106394500</link><description>Hillary Clinton blasts a Republican-led congressional committee for summoning her to answer questions about Jeffrey Epstein while failing to push US President Donald Trump to do the same thing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24bc3f1862f71db70614627e2bb7a2ed</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: A lonely monkey, a BAFTA winner and the end of the Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/weekly-news-quiz-february-26/106391856</link><description>It's been a big week in the news. Did you catch these stories?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">479f73547ec028e59987b985cce3c0cf</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberal Party flirting with fire as One Nation preference deal looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/liberal-one-nation-potential-preferences-analysis/106391418</link><description>South Australia's embattled Liberals have openly declared their willingness to strike a preference deal with One Nation. Will it help or hurt them on election day?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e771204d6dcf2bd5343cf65a3370d3d</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide University students fear merger could extend their degrees and increase debt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/adelaide-uni-students-fear-merger-could-extend-degrees-and-debts/106393264</link><description>Some students at Adelaide University say they are frustrated by ongoing communication and enrolment issues post-merger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8926c3d9c72edb1648c59137327027b9</guid></item><item><title>Albanese celebrates his caucus unity but it comes at a cost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/labor-government-caucus-unity-anthony-albanese-left/106380394</link><description>Behind the scenes, the troops are carefully managed. Opinions are expressed at factional meetings and the prime minister meets with the factional conveners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31d1a41ec7748747a7b08a90b06f6374</guid></item><item><title>Flood rescues, power outages after heavy rain and flash flooding smashes Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/nsw-flash-flooding-homes-without-power-sydney/106393834</link><description>Dozens of people needed to be rescued and thousands of properties were without power after intense rainfall and flash flooding wreaked havoc across Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51e4167aacfc25659e95aa60397ddd0a</guid></item><item><title>Celine Cremer's sister says family 'finally have answers' as police 'provisionally' identify remains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/human-remains-identified-as-celine-cremer/106298210</link><description>Celine Cremer's family say she will now "be able to rest in peace surrounded by the love that never left her side".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">969441e26ff87355269fa4f18314928b</guid></item><item><title>India beats Zimbabwe, South Africa beats West Indies at T20 World Cup as Proteas reach semifinals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/india-south-africa-win-at-t20-world-cup/106394592</link><description>The final four at the Twenty20 World Cup is taking shape after South Africa progressed on the back of a victory over West Indies, and India's victory over Zimbabwe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d23b9ec599ecde8c0cd0ce335169eaf</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley officially resigns two weeks after being ousted as Liberal leader — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/federal-politics-live-blog-fri-feb-27/106391736</link><description>Two weeks after losing the Liberal leadership, Sussan Ley officially handed in her resignation letter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d12040c259fa0fa707e41a7a04c4d981</guid></item><item><title>US and Iran make 'significant progress' in nuclear talks, mediator says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/us-and-iran-make-significant-progress-in-talks-mediator-says/106394614</link><description>While the US did not comment after the talks ended, Iran's foreign minister told Iranian state television they had been the most intense exchanges between the two countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6ac007417ea0b8825863c96ebeaecf5</guid></item><item><title>Bad Bunny tour unites Sydney's Latin diaspora with Australian concerts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/nsw-fans-prepare-for-bad-bunny-sydney-tour-latin-dispora/106387764</link><description>Global powerhouse Bad Bunny is bringing together Sydney’s Latin diaspora and exciting fans who cannot speak a word of Spanish.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a664ab78b523b7abf65836d23ea30a17</guid></item><item><title>ASX correction 'likely', Coles shares plummet — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/asx-markets-business-live-news-feb27-2026/106394660</link><description>Analysts say a share market correction is 'likely' as the ASX hits record high.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dc00f0217d7da6178314dbb98598387</guid></item><item><title>Georgia Griffith to collect world indoor championship bronze medal after Diribe Welteji's doping violation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/georgia-griffith-world-indoor-championship-diribe-welteji-doping/106394648</link><description>Georgia Griffith looks likely to be awarded a belated world indoor championships bronze medal, her first global senior medal, after Ethiopian Diribe Welteji copped a doping ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a273094ffa579436a9946a36e6fa9a0</guid></item><item><title>Parents charged with manslaughter after Gold Coast crash kills 3yo boy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/man-woman-charged-manslaughter-after-fatal-gold-coast-crash/106394740</link><description>Police say the 22-year-old mother was driving with the 24-year-old father, along with two boys aged one and three, when she crashed into bushland at Stapylton on October 25.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bb109a5a066fe791f840d49c2462fc2</guid></item><item><title>Amy Sayer eager to represent Matildas at Asian Cup after long-term knee injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/amy-sayer-return-from-injury-asian-cup/106391934</link><description>After a long-term injury seriously derailed her career, Australian soccer player Amy Sayer is looking to leave a mark on this year's Asian Cup, which begins for the Matildas on Sunday in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cb7768dc6051a8e002e6d5db68e5b8e</guid></item><item><title>Seismologists investigate 'mysterious' earthquake swarm near Gnowangerup in southern WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/earthquake-swarm-rattles-gnowangerup-southern-wa/106382850</link><description>After a dozen earthquakes in a single day and more than 70 over the course of February, farmers in Gnowangerup are curious about what is rumbling their paddocks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c2486aa99f39f551c9d485d32ab1924</guid></item><item><title>Blind refugee from Myanmar dies after detention by US border agents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/blind-refugee-dies-after-detention-by-us-border-agents/106394744</link><description>Nurul Amin Shah Alam's family had expected him to be released from a New York jail and reported him missing. He was found dead after temperatures dropped below freezing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4572df42a0748e277e2d05533f2a87e</guid></item><item><title>Teenager rescued after climbing 30-metre-tall crane in Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/teenager-rescued-after-climbing-crane/106394622</link><description>A teenager who scaled a crane and became stuck in Melbourne's north-east has been rescued by firefighters who brought in an expert team to help him down to safety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">669c0f91bc7847efc0c08ed8be6da00c</guid></item><item><title>Two new Hans Christian Andersen adaptations prove fairy tales as relevant as ever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/hans-christian-andersen-tree-of-light-meow-meow-red-shoes/106364412</link><description>Two wildly different shows, The Tree of Light by Slingsby Theatre Company and Meow Meow's The Red Shoes, re-imagine classic fairy tales by the famous Danish author.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ef5fdd737cde8a3a507cf76b1c72769</guid></item><item><title>Teenage boys drive homophobic anti-LGBTQIA+ attacks, NSW Police data shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/nsw-lgbt-hate-data-released-ahead-of-mardi-gras/106394004</link><description>Police recorded 197 incidents of LGBTQIA+ hate-related violence and charged 103 people over the attacks since 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3a477e689ba3c07354ce5be230b6831</guid></item><item><title>Police charge 25 over 'family-run drug syndicate' seizing $3m in drugs at Gladstone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/police-charge-25-people-with-drug-offences-in-gladstone/106394952</link><description>Dozens of people are charged after a raid in central Queensland seized more than $3 million worth of drugs from what people say was a "deeply entrenched drug syndicate".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">809039c034f575ef5a197af6f6d52b61</guid></item><item><title>Labor not ruling out negative gearing changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/labor-not-ruling-out-negative-gearing-changes/106395074</link><description>A government source said it would make sense to consider changes to negative gearing and capital gains tax together, but that no decision was close to being made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57ef2e8357ae14f0ed1eab92322752ec</guid></item><item><title>Judge rejects request to block Trump White House from building its $560 million ballroom project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/judge-allows-trumps-white-house-ballroom-project-to-proceed/106394882</link><description>A US judge rejects a preservationist group's request to block the Trump administration from continuing construction of a $560 million ballroom to replace the demolished East Wing of the White House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2da5cc859c0258e4a51f7784657bdf6b</guid></item><item><title>Hillary Clinton speaks after testifying about Epstein ties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/hillary-clinton-speaks-after-testifying-about-epstein-ties-/106395198</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">259c4844eda3097d8d620a9c8736e797</guid></item><item><title>Tens of thousands of Budget Direct customers overcharged, ASIC alleges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/asic-sues-budget-direct-misconduct-allegations/106395196</link><description>The corporate regulator is taking legal action over allegations Budget Direct customers lost online discounts they were promised and were overcharged.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7882a655ec61e37e6201c5bdb8cc0ae3</guid></item><item><title>Royal Australian Mint unveils new limited edition $1 coin with subtle change to mark 60 years of decimal currency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/mint-unveils-new-limited-edition-1-dollar-coin-extra-kangaroo/106394730</link><description>The Royal Australian Mint releases a limited edition $1 coin to mark the 60th anniversary of the introduction of decimal currency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32f5ac1f674d4cf6bfabe89872fb9144</guid></item><item><title>ABC to broadcast Matildas' Women's Asian Cup games as well as knockout matches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/abc-radio-broadcast-matildas-womens-asian-cup/106395182</link><description>Just days out from the start of the Women's Asian Cup, the ABC has locked in radio broadcasting rights for the tournament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4525c54c6737ed61e3faaf1577489894</guid></item><item><title>Sydney solicitor accused of stealing $15 million from clients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/nsw-solicitor-steals-almost-15m-from-clients/106395324</link><description>Police had been investigating Benjamin Paul Reid at a Bondi Junction law firm since September last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b939318072c8b3bb6fabc162ed7293a3</guid></item><item><title>$3 million in drugs seized in Gladstone drug trafficking operation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/-3-million-in-drugs-seized-in-gladstone/106395608</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0681bcb712c55b346069a8fe45f191a1</guid></item><item><title>Deepfakes back in the headlines after a federal law was used for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/rise-in-sexualised-deepfakes-new-laws-explainer/106390940</link><description>As the first case under new anti-deepfake legislation goes before the courts, authorities and experts say the rise in the creation of the non-consensual sexually explicit material is concerning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da4118b9f6f994212728c2883b3b0bd4</guid></item><item><title>Air strikes hit Afghan capital of Kabul, hours after Taliban attacks Pakistan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/taliban-launches-retaliatory-strikes-against-pakistan/106395580</link><description>Pakistan is responding to "unprovoked fire" by Afghan forces at multiple locations along the border, the Information Ministry in Islamabad says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">723636784f9962da68e0b01185be66b9</guid></item><item><title>Netflix declines to raise offer for Warner, paving way for Paramount takeover</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/netflix-declines-to-raise-its-offer-to-buy-warner/106395308</link><description>Netflix has declined to raise its offer to buy Warner Bros Discovery's studio and streaming business, in a stunning move that effectively puts Paramount in a position to take over the fellow storied Hollywood giant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51d70c394a73c36f28ee9b369ca98761</guid></item><item><title>Protestor arrested as NT Administrator David Connolly sworn in</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/nt-administrator-david-connolly-swearing-in-parliament-arrest/106393862</link><description>A protester has been arrested amid chaotic scenes outside of NT Parliament, where David Connolly has been sworn in as the new administrator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a09d17d197bc6018672c8c52798f531</guid></item><item><title>171 bodies found in mass graves in eastern Congo after withdrawal of M23 rebel group</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/congo-bodies-found-mass-graves/106395864</link><description>Mass graves with at least 171 dead bodies have been found in the eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo, in a region the M23 rebel group has recently withdrawn from.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cb8612f5f98425316681232fce5aca9</guid></item><item><title>Bendigo Swordcraft rallies around one of their own after Harcourt bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/bendigo-swordcraft-larp-henry-of-harcourt-victorian-bushfires/106352450</link><description>Michael Henry's armour and weapons survived January's bushfires, as the Swordcraft community helps him rise from the ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24d209dd01eeee8c3f01a75bb5cfd606</guid></item><item><title>Instagram to alert parents if teens 'repeatedly' search for self-harm terms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/instagram-to-alert-parents-of-teen-suicide-searches/106395120</link><description>The new feature will be rolled out in Australia from next week, but there are concerns about loopholes and limitations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">200c4245e8ca3ad7f521dff90f5a1629</guid></item><item><title>Authorities 'planning for the worst' for downpour to hit northern SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/heavy-rainfall-warning-sa-north-and-west/106394942</link><description>South Australia's emergency services are on high alert ahead of possible intense rainfall of up to 120 millimetres in parts of the state, which may lead to flash flooding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1289e07a5f7dda0595f8c8b6a1cde2d6</guid></item><item><title>WA drivers reeling after passengers caught out by AI-powered safety cameras</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/seat-belt-cameras-catch-drivers-in-costly-mistake/106395672</link><description>WA drivers given large fines or a licence suspension after their passengers were snapped wearing seatbelts incorrectly say they are being punished for behaviour beyond their control.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f49310eb8696921b88ac0f51d3ea1c4b</guid></item><item><title>Alleged terrorist who stabbed Sydney bishop diagnosed with schizophrenia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/teenager-stabbed-sydney-bishop-schizophrenia-wakeley/106395940</link><description>A teenager who slipped the intelligence net and stabbed a Sydney bishop in an alleged terrorist attack 20 months before the Bondi Beach massacre has been diagnosed with schizophrenia, a court hears.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3449122db62e4f51e5c815eafdc3095</guid></item><item><title>How Manly backrower Hugo Hart went from American high school football to the brink of the NRL</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/nrl-manly-sea-eagles-hugo-hart-nfl-high-school-football/106392204</link><description>After some eye-catching performances in the pre-season, young Manly backrower and former American high school football linebacker Hugo Hart is edging closer to an NRL debut.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eab60549feb59ed9ffc9f61f26e689a0</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's finances to 'rapidly deteriorate', Treasury warns, with state unable to grow its way out of trouble</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/tasmania-finances-to-rapidly-deteriorate-treasury-warns/106395370</link><description>Tasmania's Department of Treasury and Finance has issued a dire warning about the state's finances, and says there are no easy fixes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d33fa61505b600e8f187e6f145f2ccd8</guid></item><item><title>Baby rhino born in NSW wildlife park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/baby-rhino-born-in-nsw-wildlife-park/106391240</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c1a4782c0ee42eca3a3379b2ab7f6eb</guid></item><item><title>Riverina community steps up to feed baby rhino after mum abandons him at birth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/white-rhino-ck-embraced-by-community-after-rejection-at-birth/106392160</link><description>Just like "Punch" the monkey, this adorable baby was abandoned by its mother soon after birth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1cddebabeb59cc75e46df1af60d3c04</guid></item><item><title>In photos: Extreme weather sweeps across large parts of Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/extreme-weather-sweeps-across-large-parts-of-australia/106395148</link><description>At least four states are facing extreme weather and heavy rain, with some areas tipped to receive the heaviest rainfall in more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">314212cea7670e933f1a5796ad376ddc</guid></item><item><title>Western Sydney youth tell their stories of postcode wars via play</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/western-sydney-postcode-war-play-180-inspire/106296574</link><description>Jaani Pani knows how loyalty to a postcode can shape your life in Western Sydney. He is telling his story for the stage to inspire the next generation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e5bf6b6023e0db6a5047c2e62fbf47f</guid></item><item><title>Federal MP Tim Wilson's event gatecrashed by ethno-nationalist group National Workers Alliance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/tim-wilson-goldstein-event-gatecrashed-national-workers-alliance/106394854</link><description>Police said they were called to the scene after the National Workers Alliance, an ethno-nationalist organisation, gatecrashed a community event held by Shadow Treasurer Tim Wilson in Melbourne on Thursday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">475dc7ba7aeccb212edbd07243635845</guid></item><item><title>Terella Brewing to close amid legal battle with Sunshine Coast Council</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/teralla-brewing-to-close-its-doors-amid-legal-battle/106395960</link><description>Popular Sunshine Coast brewery and music venue Terella Brewing will close after a legal stoush with the local council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a5de76c0655eae2c97b7931d6b8c24f</guid></item><item><title>Comedian Magda Szubanski in remission after stage 4 blood cancer treatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/magda-szubanski-stage-4-blood-cancer-remission/106396740</link><description>The Australian entertainer reveals she is in remission after completing chemotherapy treatment for stage 4 blood cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02c295aa806c4b19a1a7af666f1fcf8c</guid></item><item><title>Crew-11 NASA astronaut behind mission-ending medical issues identifies himself</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/crew-11-nasa-astronaut-behind-mission-ending-health-issues/106395048</link><description>The 58-year-old spaceflight veteran has identified himself as the astronaut whose illness prompted NASA's first medical evacuation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd932f2d6b20c020c5606c312a535772</guid></item><item><title>Australian Electoral Commission proposes changes to Tasmanian voting boundaries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/electorate-boundary-changes-proposed-for-tasmania/106395702</link><description>Under proposed changes to Tasmania's electorates, Lyons would decrease in area while Clark would increase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a86d788ef63c809696a7a63f7bc011c9</guid></item><item><title>Coles 'Down Down' in the supermarket wars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/coles-financial-results-go-backwards-with-shares-following/106396060</link><description>Financial results for supermarket giant Coles underperform, with stocks following suite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02d38172bafbfff12219f98d41817fb0</guid></item><item><title>Mitch Brown co-hosts Sydney Gay and Lesbian Mardi Gras six months after coming out as bisexual</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/mitch-brown-hosts-mardi-gras-parade/106388108</link><description>Just six months since coming out, ex-AFL player Mitch Brown is now co-hosting Sydney's Mardi Gras parade. He hopes his journey can help other players embrace who they are.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">206fcf0d74b4b47e34764aab1b2500a2</guid></item><item><title>Health authorities reject claims Sydney hospital fungal infection outbreak covered up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/nsw-government-rejects-cover-up-claims-over-hospital-fungus/106396224</link><description>Health authorities reject claims information about a fungal infection outbreak which could have caused the death of two patients at a Sydney hospital was deliberately withheld from the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8edbf8ed64af07c418ede9750b35d09</guid></item><item><title>After day of lightning strikes across Perth, expert shares tips for avoiding injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/lightning-expert-grant-kirkby-tips-avoiding-lightning-strikes/106396874</link><description>After a day that saw 10,000 lightning strikes across Perth, three people suffer injuries, and a pet dog killed, an expert shares tips for avoiding injury during electrical storms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">330bdaad8aa809c2dd6d4f3bf80bb3e3</guid></item><item><title>How young people are coping with the rising cost of living</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/how-young-people-are-coping-with-the-rising-cost-of-living/106385806</link><description>Many people are struggling with the cost of living and increasingly, young Australians say they are not just worried about the situation now, but also what it means for the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64f6e8f2391b28b8f248ff3473f09f7e</guid></item><item><title>'Child first, offender second' approach to Tasmania's young offenders unveiled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/replacement-ashley-youth-detention-centre-unveiled-tasmania/106395206</link><description>The Tasmanian government announces a "child first, offender second" approach for the operation of a new youth prison, which it says will offer small "home-like" accommodation for detainees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07efca627ee741a17e9d08fbc10015aa</guid></item><item><title>Kimberley man faces Broome court on 18 domestic violence charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/kimberley-man-charged-18-domestic-violence-offences/106397526</link><description>West Australian police have charged a Kimberley man over alleged domestic violence offences stretching over two decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51a11a5a2cd64537ae7ddbf9e7f148b7</guid></item><item><title>Foreign nationals arrested following probe into alleged money laundering scheme in Mildura</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/mildura-money-laundering-investigation-arrests/106397902</link><description>Four foreign nationals have been arrested and bank accounts worth more than $3.3 million have been seized as part of what police say is a "sophisticated money laundering operation" in Mildura.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2428cd3e88f642d6702ec6fa4b9ddc9c</guid></item><item><title>Charles Darwin University scraps London campus plans following vice-chancellor resignation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/cdu-scraps-london-campus-after-vice-chancellor-resignation/106396848</link><description>Charles Darwin University has ditched its plan to establish a campus in London after investing nearly $2 million in the proposal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a314ae50a6e39b80a94fb788810186d8</guid></item><item><title>Police reinstate murder charge against alleged killer of Kaiden Morgan-Johnston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/kaiden-morgan-charges-reissued/106330296</link><description>Police have reinstated murder charges against a man accused of killing an 18-year-old in Victoria's east last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df9a97acbfb9e7c725b7235657e4edd8</guid></item><item><title>Super Bowl winner Michael Dickson puts Matt Burton's boot up with NFL punters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/michael-dickson-matt-burton-nrl-nfl-code-switch/106396080</link><description>Australian Super Bowl winner Michael Dickson says the booming boot of Bulldogs five-eighth Matt Burton could cut it in the NFL, but not without some major adjustments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1a2746cbe842599da2b26dc6ab44583</guid></item><item><title>Perth mother blames WA's mental health systemic failures for her teen daughter's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/perth-mother-blames-systemic-failures-for-her-daughter-death/106396758</link><description>The mother of a teenage girl who took her own life a few hours after being released from a Perth mental health ward says a series of systemic failures is responsible for her daughter's death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd2adb250d2d4bf3298ec45d056b46a3</guid></item><item><title>Deputy Chief of Army delivers speech at Parliament House</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/deputy-chief-of-army-delivers-speech-at-parliament-house/106397912</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0991f0c4ed27c217cab87bc6f6a653f2</guid></item><item><title>Deputy chief of army warns ADF has become 'detached' from violent nature of war</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/deputy-army-chief-warns-adf-detached-from-violent-reality-of-war/106397538</link><description>Major General Chris Smith delivered an excoriating address to a major conference last year, declaring "managerial and advertising logic and double speak" had "polluted" the military.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c4fd608b9bff1e25a19116bbd27ce17</guid></item><item><title>Family of David Collisson who was burned after being shot dead tells of struggle to deal with trauma</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/family-of-murdered-david-collisson-tells-court-struggle-trauma/106391990</link><description>The son, sister and mother of David Collisson who was murdered near Mudgee speak of their unimaginable pain in coming to terms with how he died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4228f51ec4898d561ff59689c7f232d</guid></item><item><title>Murder accused argues self-defence after alleged Dubbo drug hunt ends in death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/murder-accused-argues-self-defence-alleged-dubbo-drug-hunt-death/106391568</link><description>A man who stands accused in fatal stabbing that broke out over an alleged drug-related dispute pleads his innocence on grounds of self-defence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91f18bfc52394ef3dc459d0403c799ab</guid></item><item><title>What to check out this weekend: Gorillaz, Chris Fleming and a pasta salad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/what-to-watch-read-and-listen-to-this-weekend/106376414</link><description>Looking for something diverting for the weekend? We've got you covered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64b88fb74d30e6cccd8c6fbbc63e719d</guid></item><item><title>Liberal Party will not publish its internal review into the 2025 election loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/liberal-party-election-review-will-not-to-be-published/106398462</link><description>The review received hundreds of submissions and was finished months ago, but today the Liberal Party's federal executive revealed it would never be made public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c3db63f84d80a3125794937ad6fa8e5</guid></item><item><title>Police foil alleged terror attack plan on public buildings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/man-charged-with-preparing-for-terrorist-act-perth/106397996</link><description>Police have charged a 20-year-old man they allege was planning a "mass casualty" terror attack targeting public buildings and Muslim places of worship in Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f6e90e8199b420c9aef4cca97a9647</guid></item><item><title>Parents charged with manslaughter after Gold Coast crash kills 3yo boy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/parents-charged-with-manslaughter-after-gold-coast-crash/106398698</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b679bde28339a7a7880256287eb01dbd</guid></item><item><title>House of Darwin founder Shaun Edwards faces court on domestic violence charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/house-of-darwin-shaun-edwards-court-domestic-violence-charges/106397706</link><description>The founder of popular fashion label House of Darwin has faced court on assault, choking, and strangling charges after an alleged domestic violence incident last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abf66494d6ff57ff941b935b1933fbf0</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Liberal MP Rory Amon denies sexual assault complainant told him he was 15</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/former-nsw-mp-rory-amon-gives-evidence-underage-sex-assailt-case/106396128</link><description>Former Liberal MP Rory Amon has told a jury the complainant in his sexual assault trial told him he was 17 before they discussed meeting up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b4446c57f1988a4c74c877541084fa4</guid></item><item><title>Federal Court orders South West Aboriginal Medical Service board be dismissed, new election at AGM</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/federal-court-orders-swams-reelection/106396674</link><description>The Federal Court has dismissed the entire board of one of WA's largest Aboriginal medical services, due to factional and 'oppressive conduct'.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4ffb1a5928abe9558adba400c154393</guid></item><item><title>Ex-SA Liberal leader David Speirs says he will contest state election, 10 months after drug conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/david-speirs-announces-political-comeback-for-sa-election/106389794</link><description>Former SA Liberal leader David Speirs has confirmed he has nominated to run in his former seat of Black in the state election, 10 months after he was convicted of drug supply offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d38a917197cbbdc68d82b2dd2ac06cf</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup 2026: Katrina Gorry has done it all for the Matildas. Now she wants a trophy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/womens-asian-cup-matildas-katrina-gorry/106398594</link><description>Katrina Gorry embodies all the characteristics that are celebrated in Australian football, and the veteran midfielder wants to lead the Matildas all the way to the Asian Cup trophy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02ede07013e6f10ff3550784cc2d2253</guid></item><item><title>Evidence concludes in coronial inquest into three-year-old's Alice Springs house fire death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/mitchell-thomas-inquest-alice-springs-house-fire-last-evidence/106388010</link><description>The inquest into three-year-old Mitchell Thomas's death in an Alice Springs house fire in 2023 has finished hearing evidence, with the coroner examining standards of maintenance, record-keeping and electrical safety regulation in the NT's public housing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fe4819baeb3b731a8f76073c9e1ddba</guid></item><item><title>Teenage boy dies after being hit by two cars crossing busy road in Warnbro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/teenage-boy-dies-after-being-hit-by-two-cars-in-warnbro/106398090</link><description>A teenage boy has died after he was hit by two cars on a busy dual-lane road in Perth's southern suburbs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5992c6fa12de3a910e4ab07ad39eab3d</guid></item><item><title>David Speirs's comeback attempt is a risk for everyone — including himself</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/david-speirs-comeback-attempt-a-political-risk-analysis/106390998</link><description>The former opposition leader's attempt at a political comeback is a risk for both the major parties — but also himself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c920c14086d0b426fa48504f14566d2b</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Reds defeat Highlanders, Western Force beat Moana Pasifika in Super Rugby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/western-force-defeat-moana-pasifika-for-first-super-rugby-win/106399112</link><description>The Queensland Reds and Western Force have recorded their first wins of the Super Rugby Pacific season in round three.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">094d1db7cab1156c1469b611fe18bc53</guid></item><item><title>An unexpected baby boy gives hope to the all-female Akuntsu tribe in Brazil's Amazon rainforest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/amazonian-tribe-akuntsu-gives-birth-to-first-boy/106399170</link><description>As they advanced in age without a child to carry on the line, many expected the Akuntsu to vanish when the three remaining women died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7e97cd520f8aef2465852b7401719a0</guid></item><item><title>Native title holders awarded more than $54m for economic, spiritual loss from NT's McArthur River Mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/nt-mcarthur-river-mine-case-traditional-owners-win-compensation/106398116</link><description>Native title holders in the Northern Territory have been awarded more than $54 million in compensation for the impacts of large-scale mining on their country, in just the second case of its kind in Australian history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f8889d955272a5e47af0d8be651b159</guid></item><item><title>Georgia Voll blazes century as Australia defeats India by five wickets and takes 6-4 series lead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/georgia-voll-strikes-century-australia-downs-india/106399172</link><description>Georgia Voll strikes her second ODI century after being dropped on 99, as Australia cruises to a five-wicket win over India and takes a 6-4 lead in the multi-format series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3a54020baa22342ddd21f6f8d97aadf</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106397788</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">692093cbbec66533ee074a199a24c6a3</guid></item><item><title>Islamic State claims credit for Bondi massacre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/islamic-state-claims-credit-bondi-massacre/106399514</link><description>Islamic State has embraced Sajid and Naveed Akram as "soldiers" and urged other supporters to continue attacks on Jews and Christians, as they claimed credit for the Bondi massacre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e5e8c45aed5825daa6f1ef8f07fbffd</guid></item></channel></rss>