<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:35:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ben Hunt's Golden Point field goal sends Brisbane Broncos into NRL prelims after downing Canberra Raiders in all-time classic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/nrl-live-updates-finals-canberra-raiders-brisbane-broncos/105767630</link><description>Jamal Fogarty scores a try in Golden Point to send the Raiders to a preliminary final only for it to be disallowed before Ben Hunt delivers a dagger field goal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6df4f99fbc4ba21354c9bf49bf40731</guid></item><item><title>FBI director Kash Patel to face congressional hearing amid missteps on Charlie Kirk assassination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/kash-patel-faces-congressional-hearing/105771606</link><description>Kash Patel faces a clear test of whether he can convince the country that the FBI, under his watch, can avoid compounding its mistakes in a time of political violence and deepening distrust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff3edf3e8615beb76880722256515f03</guid></item><item><title>AFLW Round 5 Sunday wrap: Kangaroos claim grand final rematch against Lions as Saints and Cats record big wins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/aflw-round-5-sunday-wrap-kangaroos-beat-lions-gf-rematch/105771940</link><description>North Melbourne continues its blistering start to the AFLW season as Geelong and St Kilda also record big wins in Round 5.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cee53d3f18feb5d3f6fa788a7a48b761</guid></item><item><title>Belgians break Australian hearts in Davis Cup classic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/tennis-de-minaur-australia-belgium-davis-cup-wrap/105772264</link><description>Beligum's Raphael Collignon wore down late stand-in Aleksandar Vukic in the deciding rubber to lead Belgium to the quarter-finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48108db3db36157632582610dcc8f4ed</guid></item><item><title>Reece Walsh grabs the Sun to lead Brisbane to an all-time victory over Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/canberra-raiders-brisbane-broncos-nrl-finals-reece-walsh/105767838</link><description>Brisbane and Canberra went to the great beyond in their golden point finals match and it was Reece Walsh who led the Broncos to the promised land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">863df8dd52133df36ae1790ea450fe7c</guid></item><item><title>The year Australia is due to blow its carbon budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/australia-carbon-budget-2035-emissions-target/105341080</link><description>Unless Australia lifts its ambitions, its "fair share" of carbon emissions will be spent 14 years early. With the government announcing a 2035 climate target this week, there is intense debate on how high the government should aim — and whether it will be enough to help limit global warming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92c26486065559e6e68fc907f4300c31</guid></item><item><title>The higher Australia's 2035 emissions target, the more necessary a carbon tax will be</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/albanese-government-2035-climate-emissions-target/105771566</link><description>Australia's emissions reduction number is, in short, a laugh-or-cry-o-meter, or perhaps more accurately, a tax-o-meter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5aae41b286ff6b7c3400069e180e67f</guid></item><item><title>GIM Trading accused of defrauding millions from ordinary Australian investors with 'low risk' bonds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/gim-trading-alleged-fraud-investors-bonds/105747410</link><description>A Gold Coast musician approached by a man he knew from a local bar went on to front a trading company, later accused of defrauding millions from ordinary Australian investors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef7a680d03253010b78fa5b88e06a4f0</guid></item><item><title>Dads leaving sex education to mums, report finds, with concerns young boys are missing out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/dads-leaving-sex-education-to-mums-boys-missing-out/105761172</link><description>New report finds mothers do more of the sex education at home, raising concerns that young boys are missing out on key information from their dads.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09373ae607cb293f5028b7499dce7b5a</guid></item><item><title>Family violence survivors waiting years for social housing as demand surges in Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/social-public-housing-wait-times-victoria-family-violence/105655044</link><description>As family violence survivor and mother-of-two, Maya was assessed as a high priority for social housing. Eight years later, she's finally moved into a suitable home in outer-suburban Melbourne, with vulnerable Victorians left waiting for years as the social housing waitlist soars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e74302190404e5284428c6e45ccbce8a</guid></item><item><title>Weather to warm up in Queensland, as more rain forecast for the north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/warmer-weather-tipped-for-much-of-queensland-as-spring-sets-in/105771650</link><description>The southern half of Queensland can expect fine weather at least for the first half of the week, while more rain is on the way for the north of the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44a26254dc8a8890086a64f319e0fce8</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic expeditioners join research project to help astronauts on space missions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/antarctic-expeditioners-join-astronaut-research-project/105767136</link><description>Expeditioners at Australia's Antarctic stations are taking part in a research project to better understand the cognitive and physiological impacts of extended deployments — which can include actual "brain shrinkage".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d57ace742d2dab72c8470091d9eea61</guid></item><item><title>How Sydney's Olympic legacy continues to unfold, 25 years on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/2000-sydney-olympics-25-year-anniversary-legacy-reflections/105764442</link><description>Largely regarded as one of the most successful modern Olympics, years of work went into ensuring Sydney could fully capitalise on its moment in the spotlight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">917e1ac91bb7370325e50d1950ba2a40</guid></item><item><title>Residents say former Moe Hospital could become public housing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/moe-hospital-newborough-derelict-building-social-housing/105637366</link><description>A retired nurse who worked at Moe Hospital says the closed facility could be used for housing rather than left to further rot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d6259927cc7b3ea15a9fcb2704c8b7c</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr scores 100th goal for Chelsea in long-awaited WSL return from knee injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/sam-kerr-makes-wsl-chelsea-return-from-torn-acl/105772878</link><description>Matildas star Sam Kerr scores her 100th goal for Chelsea just minutes after returning to the pitch for the Blues for her first game since 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bae5f25a567be7986ec4489f569f5f25</guid></item><item><title>Road repairs after flood delayed by 'excruciating' eligibility criteria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/buloke-shire-flood-funding-pot-holes-delays-unsafe-roads/105733714</link><description>Victorian councils say they are required to provide before-and-after photos of every 100 metres of road in order to be eligible for flood recovery funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d6870a6663a3b8139b0e567866cd586</guid></item><item><title>Nepalese migrants in Australia turning to parents to help with childcare and culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/canberra-nepalese-community-family-tradition-and-culture/105772020</link><description>For many Nepalese families living in Canberra, the arrival of parents from overseas is both a helping hand with raising children and a connection to their homeland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83d7bb8c245d2e5d11433eda0c9b3fd1</guid></item><item><title>Documents reveal unauthorised sediment releases at Blackwater Coal Mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/blackwater-coal-mine-contamination-sediment/105769922</link><description>A report obtained by lobby group Lock The Gate under right-to-information laws reveal a mine in central Queensland was releasing sediment into environmentally sensitive areas for more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c0e5d78e0e78c7d0e25c51e02aed43f</guid></item><item><title>Fortunes change quickly in AFLW as round of upsets shakes up ladder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/round-of-upsets-shakes-up-aflw-ladder-mid-season/105772256</link><description>After a tough start to the year, Geelong sit just outside the top eight and equal on points with the reining grand finalists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a314ed873d6767758eb39088f9f9e0f6</guid></item><item><title>Traditional custodian readies for 'challenge' over North West Shelf gas project extension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/traditional-custodian-fights-north-west-shelf-approval/105770306</link><description>Environment Minister Murray Watt approved the extension of Australia's biggest gas project last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fff78b1c904abb60057a8fd295536c56</guid></item><item><title>Specialist GPs to diagnose ADHD in WA amid calls for further easing of restrictions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/wa-gps-soon-start-diagnosing-adhd/105759814</link><description>As a select cohort of WA GPs begins to diagnose ADHD in people older than 10, parents of younger children and some medical professionals have expressed concerns about the scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32f743c6d37c23f14438dac29a9eb199</guid></item><item><title>Reece Walsh fined for headbutt, Pat Carrigan banned for high shot in NRL finals win over Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/reece-walsh-headbutt-pat-carrigan-bans-from-broncos-raiders/105772942</link><description>Superstar Broncos fullback Reece Walsh will be free to play in the NRL preliminary finals after avoiding suspension for a headbutt on Hudson Young in Brisbane's epic win on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69bc0f4f4df315eed7d8c781e1acb538</guid></item><item><title>Emmys 2025 red carpet: Jenna Ortega, Lisa, Sydney Sweeney, Aimee Lou Wood, Walton Goggins, Selena Gomez and Pedro Pascal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/2025-emmys-red-carpet-fashion/105752046</link><description>The stars of the television industry are bringing the drama with their fashion choices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85981e3d6d9c2977cda8244d6580248c</guid></item><item><title>WA's expanded container deposit scheme to cost wineries, distilleries millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/container-for-change-wa-wine-expansion-hits-small-business/105763914</link><description>Producers in Western Australia's premier wine region say the state government's expanded bottle recycling scheme is set to cost them millions of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16ff8a6ec9140b73f0af3e85a003dec0</guid></item><item><title>Australia beats India in first of three ODIs before Women's Cricket World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/australia-beats-india-in-odi-world-cup-warm-up/105773182</link><description>Australia's Cricket World Cup preparations are in full swing as three batters score half-centuries in a big run chase in the first of three ODIs against India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a29f09f0be7bd9b554de11bd5f4906d1</guid></item><item><title>Emmy Awards 2025: The Pitt, Adolescence and The Studio win big as Owen Cooper makes history — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/emmy-awards-2025-live-blog-latest-updates/105757172</link><description>The Pitt wins Best Drama at the 77th Annual Primetime Emmy Awards, with The Studio, Adolescence and even Stephen Colbert walking away as the biggest winners of the night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f0dab0d1494400d0b01fc6483c43b32</guid></item><item><title>Port Hinchinbrook marina remains inaccessible despite dredging project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/port-hinchinbrook-marina-remains-inaccessible-after-dredging/105739106</link><description>Mud and silt continue to choke the channel connecting the controversial development to the Great Barrier Reef, once again putting industry and conservationists at odds over the fix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00377919955e2acc697f9565f436b2a9</guid></item><item><title>Outback ringmaster Fred Brophy takes his boxing tent to Birdsville for last time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/fred-brophy-takes-boxing-tent-to-birdsville-for-last-time/105761756</link><description>Fred Brophy will sell you a ticket, spin you a yarn and dare you into the ring, but at 73, the outback ringmaster is slowing down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9c596e0ff31abe53e3cdc3f15b54fcc</guid></item><item><title>First climate risk assessment finds 1.5m Australians at risk from sea level rise by 2050</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/climate-risk-assessment-sea-level-rise-2035-target/105765456</link><description>One and a half million Australians are at risk from sea levels rising by 2050 unless climate change can be limited, Australia’s first national climate risk assessment warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84bc65afd0d8a3b350ab90314dff5f21</guid></item><item><title>Nepal's Gen Z demands reform as country begins new political path</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/nepal-generation-z-anti-corruption-protests-kathmandu/105773042</link><description>Protesters in Nepal say their Gen Z-led movement was not just about removing one leader, but about reforming the system to ensure accountability and protect Nepal’s future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">836ee3f4801e6cf8e546d51627e6e4b8</guid></item><item><title>From Tantanoola to Essendon, Angus Clarke reflects on AFL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/angus-clarke-on-south-east-sa-breakfast/105773582</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32b5ad4ec4dbc2210f1b5997bfa6ec36</guid></item><item><title>Australian rules football and SANFL administrator Max Basheer dies aged 98</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/sanfl-administrator-max-basheer-dies-aged-98/105773500</link><description>Max Basheer — the football administrator who oversaw the creation of the Adelaide Crows and the purpose-built stadium Football Park — has died aged 98.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">594325c3e747906c91d2cd8c90983d6f</guid></item><item><title>AFL State of Origin will return, with Western Australia-Victoria clash confirmed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/afl-announces-state-of-origin-return-with-wa-vic-clash-confirmed/105773392</link><description>AFL chief executive Andrew Dillon confirms Western Australia will play Victoria in Perth next February in the first State of Origin match since 1999.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d22aa23c3e429a537fcaf8a6093051d</guid></item><item><title>Prince Harry says he has no regrets about 2023 memoir Spare</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/prince-harry-defends-his-memoir/105773344</link><description>Prince Harry has defended his tell-all autobiography Spare, insisting he has no regrets about its publication.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">822f9b8bfc9e038c4a05c240f351b362</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with giving Nazi salute at Brisbane Lions v Gold Coast Suns AFL game at the Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/qld-man-charged-nazi-salute-at-afl-game-banned/105773522</link><description>A 39-year-old man has been charged with giving a Nazi salute at the AFL semifinal in Brisbane on Saturday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10247763ed0af9c91511f307aea12cd7</guid></item><item><title>Indian cricketers refuse to shake hands with Pakistani counterparts at Asia Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/indian-cricketers-refuse-to-shake-hands-with-pakistanis-asia-cup/105773820</link><description>Indian captain Suryakumar Yadav refuses to shake hands after his side's seven-wicket win over Pakistan at the Asia Cup in the latest controversial episode between the two rivals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e14fcc55b27a2d660ff4a5b3250b9de6</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Roosters confirm ACL injury for Tarryn Aiken on eve of NRLW finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/sydney-roosters-confirm-tarryn-aiken-acl-injury-nrlw/105773930</link><description>Tarryn Aiken will miss the Sydney Roosters' NRLW finals campaign, with scans confirming a knee injury that will require a knee reconstruction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">880a495525ca619936ce2de16f4379d3</guid></item><item><title>Inquest hears prison system failed Aboriginal inmate before he died</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/inquest-examines-clinton-austin-death-loddon-prison/105735924</link><description>A coronial inquest hears the system failed First Nations prisoner Clinton Austin before his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3728f892b4b408407004793ea3dc66f</guid></item><item><title>Emmys 2025 winners: Adolescence, Severance, The Pitt and The Studio win big</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/primetime-emmy-awards-ceremony-winners-list/105752034</link><description>The 77th Primetime Emmy Awards are honouring the best and brightest in the US television industry. Here are the shows that picked up the trophies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d8d75f9c20e7825a51aab42eb0d2ca3</guid></item><item><title>Starving wallabies at The Briars spark urgent Mornington Peninsula Shire council meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/the-briars-mornington-peninsula-wallaby-overpopulation-council/105773468</link><description>A study prompted by the deaths of wallabies at a beloved wildlife reserve south of Melbourne finds the population has grown five times larger than what The Briars sanctuary can sustain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">424a62aaec22ec8d6b644d8c878fed7b</guid></item><item><title>SA to roll out ChatGPT-style AI app in all high schools as tech experts urge caution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/education-chat-gpt-style-ai-app-to-roll-out-to-sa-high-schools/105772944</link><description>A ChatGPT-style app to be rolled out at all South Australian high schools next term has been welcomed by tech experts, who are also warning its use should be carefully managed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd8111de02cfad378cd6bbaeb5b75896</guid></item><item><title>2025 Emmys key moments: From Hacks star Hannah Einbinder's acceptance speech to chants for Stephen Colbert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/emmys-2025-key-moments-from-hannah-einbinder-to-stephen-colbert/105773412</link><description>From a rallying political cry from Hacks star Hannah Einbinder to standing ovations for Stephen Colbert, here are your Emmys 2025 key moments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5949a0290fa0abaf999a6b633f1291cd</guid></item><item><title>How much fish is in tinned tuna, and how to shop for your needs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/packaged-foods-content-supermarkets/105707244</link><description>When you're at the supermarket, do you wonder how much much tuna you're getting in a can? A series of popular social media has been comparing how much food there is in some packaged items.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c07e1af76a9ce085f39b2e2924bc18d</guid></item><item><title>How is Australia affected by climate change? The National Climate Risk Assessment models the future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/national-climate-risk-assessment-and-why-it-matters-explained/105773936</link><description>For the first time, the government has modelled the threats from climate change on Australia's future. What's the point of a document like this, and can it help us avoid the worst-case scenarios?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ad84229da5de3e8a79b28e4eacc8cab</guid></item><item><title>Cricket Tasmania seeking ways to make proposed Macquarie Point stadium 'compatible' for matches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/cricket-tasmania-support-macquarie-point-afl-stadium/105774588</link><description>After initial concerns that the roof design of the proposed Hobart AFL stadium at Macquarie Point would hinder cricket matches, sporting authorities have thrown their support behind the build, saying "we will find a way".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52fc9b1b49c5b01644f528cf1efb60b0</guid></item><item><title>Australia's richest person among hundreds of donors to NT senator's legal fund</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/gina-rinehart-jacinta-nampijinpa-price-defamation-legal-fund/105775036</link><description>Australia's richest person, Gina Rinehart, has helped fund Senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price's crowd-funded defence to a defamation action brought by the head of a Northern Territory land council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d91909126ee3a35177e1e241ad2e0c3</guid></item><item><title>Defence dilemma facing Anthony Albanese as he heads to New York</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/the-defence-dilemma-facing-albanese-as-he-heads-to-new-york/105775954</link><description>Amid uncertainty over whether the prime minister will secure his first one-on-one meeting with Donald Trump, the political test is whether his recent defence commitments will be seen as a genuine step-up on capability or a sidestep from American calls to spend more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30bac552ea1477bb6ea09d9f427e1a77</guid></item><item><title>Inmate tells inquest guards referred to Indigenous man who died in custody with derogatory slurs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/guards-referred-to-tj-denniss-with-derogatory-slurs-inquest-told/105775100</link><description>An inmate, who cannot be named, provided details of an Indigenous man's treatment in custody, as an inquest into the man's death continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48ae914a843526cfeb88ffed2cbfb41d</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle Knights announce Justin Holbrook as new NRL head coach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/-newcastle-knights-justin-holbrook-nrl-head-coach/105776208</link><description>Sydney Roosters assistant coach Justin Holbrook has been named the new head coach of the Newcastle Knights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1dd4d58f20f4f23adda8178a9bef8c9</guid></item><item><title>Shadow minister Andrew Hastie says he will be 'without a job' if Liberals don't abandon net zero</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/andrew-hastie-flags-resignation-or-sacking-over-liberal-net-zero/105776432</link><description>Liberal frontbencher Andrew Hastie indicates he will quit or be dumped from the shadow cabinet if the Coalition does not abandon the target of achieving net zero greenhouse gas emissions by 2050.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d65a81fca15feb36d2a53c3d3bdd85a3</guid></item><item><title>Whispering Jack: The John Farnham Musical to premiere in Sydney Theatre Company's 2026 season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/whispering-jack-john-farnham-musical-sydney-theatre-company-2026/105766868</link><description>Whispering Jack: The John Farnham Musical is one of 13 plays coming to Sydney Theatre Company next year, alongside shows starring David Wenham and Miranda Otto.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ade2dd75f87979058d05fced4a9318</guid></item><item><title>NRL announces preliminary finals dates, Melbourne Storm on Friday, Brisbane Broncos play Sunday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/nrl-preliminary-finals-dates-melbourne-brisbane/105776416</link><description>The NRL has shaken up its preliminary finals weekend, electing to host one of its grand final qualifiers on a Sunday for the first time in 18 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29c35159922bc6cf9a11532627c3c244</guid></item><item><title>All the latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/all-the-latest-financial-news/105776480</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f073c7f7020949078deb2eb0c7a85c</guid></item><item><title>Final rules for social media ban revealed, with no legally enforceable effectiveness standard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/social-media-ban-final-rules-announced/105776730</link><description>While substantial fines would apply to social media platforms that make no effort to ban under-16s, they would not need to test the age of every user.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bf25735e4356b3846b028a3101595a6</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste students protest government plan to buy new cars for parliamentarians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/timor-leste-protesters-demand-repeal-of-plan-to-buy-cars-for-mps/105776898</link><description>About 1,000 students hit the streets of the capital to rally against the plan, before police clashed with some protesters who reportedly threw rocks and damaged properties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ce414e161409b0fcdd72ce826062fbc</guid></item><item><title>Israel's Benjamin Netanyahu won't rule out striking Hamas 'wherever they are' as Marco Rubio visits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/benjamin-netanyahu-talks-hamas-as-marco-rubio-visits-israel/105776816</link><description>The remarks were made as US Secretary of State Marco Rubio visited Israel seeking answers from Mr Netanyahu about how Israel intended to proceed in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c254873aa4a240907d518a5f986b7f76</guid></item><item><title>US and China agree to TikTok 'framework' ownership agreement at trade talks in Spain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/us-and-china-agree-to-framework-for-tiktok-sale/105776964</link><description>US Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent says the framework would see the platform switch to US ownership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5792446bfea9843c09b316ffd472ee8e</guid></item><item><title>Australia-PNG defence treaty will require countries to 'act' if either one is attacked</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/australia-and-png-defence-treaty-could-oblige-military-action/105776214</link><description>Australia and Papua New Guinea will be legally obliged to defend each other from a military attack on either territory under a landmark defence treaty, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a01cbea51a11c9d04e1bcff45aa8aa5</guid></item><item><title>DNA at crime scene matches Charlie Kirk murder suspect, FBI says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/charlie-kirk-crime-scene-dna-matches-murder-suspect/105777360</link><description>Tyler Robinson, 22, was arrested last week over the death of conservative influencer Charlie Kirk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7cf3e37a6ee22b7ae5bb477725734fa</guid></item><item><title>Lawyers urge Australians to ensure valid will in place as house prices rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/lawyers-urge-australians-to-ensure-valid-will-in-place/105767604</link><description>Lawyers urge Australians to ensure they leave behind a valid will to avoid legal disputes as surging house prices and superannuation balances increase the size of inheritances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a89e25f073724834a4daf823bb8d4cd</guid></item><item><title>Fewer Aussies would need NDIS if government boosted mental health support, expert says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/psychosocial-disability-mental-health-ndis/105773308</link><description>As the Albanese government seeks to rein in the cost of the NDIS, a former Australian of the Year says money could be saved with this one shift.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5bca27cbb4ae9aab43ea5684315161e</guid></item><item><title>Climate Risk Assessment's 'high risk' warning for 1 million Australian homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/climate-risk-assessment-million-homes-insurance-gdp-costs/105774418</link><description>One in 10 homes could be effectively uninsurable by 2050, while lost labour productivity to extreme weather could wipe $211 billion in household wealth, the Climate Risk Assessment warns, with tourism, trade, and property values forecasted to take a dive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">801dfb5f2bac8394e795c9893975dce2</guid></item><item><title>ANZ commits bank errors in its favour. Is there any other kind?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/anz-slammed-for-bank-errors-in-its-favour/105775702</link><description>ASIC has lived by that aphorism in its decision to strike a settlement deal with ANZ over a raft of wrongdoing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eab85143099e30eb989aba207539b011</guid></item><item><title>Use constitutional power to raise age of criminal responsibility nationwide, lawyers tell PM</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/pm-letter-raise-the-age/105748868</link><description>Forty years ago, the federal government used the constitution to halt construction of the Franklin Dam. Now lawyers want the Albanese government to do the same to keep kids out of jails.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7b875978506038b9b93d5a66cdfdece</guid></item><item><title>How Melbourne mosquitoes are being used to fight dengue fever and save lives in Laos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/melbourne-mosquitoes-fight-dengue-fever-laos-save-the-children/105773926</link><description>They are the deadliest animals in the world, and millions of them are being sent from Australia to the Laos capital Vientiane in a bid to save lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a24e6c7c32402fe5603b887c428f2552</guid></item><item><title>Pathological Demand Avoidance, a little-known profile of autism affecting kids and adults</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/pathological-demand-avoidance-awareness-of-autism-subtype/105772066</link><description>A surge of professional and personal interest in Pathological Demand Avoidance (PDA), an autism subtype — which in children can affect everything from cleaning teeth to attending school — has led to Australia's first-ever PDA conference, to be held in Perth in November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21dc9dcc25ab99ec13266f4d172f1692</guid></item><item><title>What to expect from Donald Trump's state visit to the UK</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/what-to-expect-donald-trump-uk-state-visit-king-charles/105776968</link><description>The US president will arrive in London on Tuesday evening, local time, for an unprecedented second state visit to the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19d933d53256fb1c8c6c8419ba9dba94</guid></item><item><title>WWII-era bombs are killing and injuring thousands in PNG. Now trainees will learn how to remove them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/png-world-war-2-unexploded-ordnance-removal/105774308</link><description>Trainees in Papua New Guinea will learn to remove unexploded ordnance, as fading memories of World War II expose more people to the conflict's dangerous legacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8bf240cd5378047327fc404a9e7f897</guid></item><item><title>Victorian childcare worker denies abusing toddlers, says he is appealing ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/victorian-childcare-worker-denies-abuse-appeals-ban/105702584</link><description>A Goodstart worker who allegedly abused toddlers at a Ballarat centre speaks out for the first time and says he is appealing after being banned from working with children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77e6b47d221359d2363dbff039a62a30</guid></item><item><title>Western Sydney is set to dramatically heat up, this is how communities are preparing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/western-sydney-plans-to-address-climate-change-warming/105775030</link><description>A "shocking" warning that heatwave deaths could skyrocket brings the issue of urban heat back into sharp focus, particularly in the city's west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8587e0ed7880e781adeb84da2b9f99da</guid></item><item><title>Will it happen? Crunch time imminent for Tasmania's proposed Macquarie Point stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/macquarie-point-stadium-planning-decision/105759040</link><description>It's not the be all and end all — but the impending delivery of the Tasmanian Planning Commission's final report is a major moment for the Macquarie Point stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b39f129ad1988ebe3b71971d4e7bb065</guid></item><item><title>Residents encouraged to attract native bees amid varroa mite spread</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/backyard-owners-encouraged-to-attract-native-bees-gardening/105767140</link><description>A pollination ecologist says it is important people play their part in preserving native bees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2de85a81cf81cdc683c925dfd059c30</guid></item><item><title>Jacinta Nampijinpa Price and Kerrynne Liddle a 'unity ticket' on Indigenous affairs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/kerrynne-liddle-backs-jacinta-nampijinpa-price/105776102</link><description>Kerrynne Liddle speaks for the first time since Jacinta Nampijinpa Price was dumped from the frontbench, saying the pair are "on a unity ticket" when it comes to Indigenous affairs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">baf6de4a9c0796b996abab3ba46e1810</guid></item><item><title>Fears parts of Queensland will have to 'retreat' amid predicted sea level rise and increased severe weather events</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/climate-report-national-climate-risk-assessment-queensland/105775976</link><description>The warning comes amid a national report finding up to 185,000 residential buildings in Queensland could be in "very high-risk areas" if climate change is not addressed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c13eb12a1db1234d6f66dae28d2620c</guid></item><item><title>The hidden impact of injuries costing AFL clubs millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/the-hidden-costs-of-injuries-costing-afl-clubs-millions/105777624</link><description>New research highlights the financial impact of injuries in the AFL, with one club losing $13 millions over six seasons, nearly 17 per cent of its total player salaries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1df9a60d5e14380c28dd088a5cbf203a</guid></item><item><title>Rex Airlines apologises after wheelchair-using passenger stranded for six hours at Perth Airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/rex-passenger-issues-albany-perth-wheelchair-user-/105774708</link><description>Albany woman Debby Butler says she had to ask strangers to help her to the bathroom after Rex delayed her flight home from Perth Airport and left her without a wheelchair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbfe858ddf70fc0694fbe80e02bdc22a</guid></item><item><title>Cathy Freeman and Ian Thorpe among Stadium Australia's first hall of fame inductees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/cathy-freeman-ian-thorpe-stadium-australia-hall-of-fame/105777908</link><description>The first golden group of inductees were honoured at an event that threw back to the Sydney 2000 games with Nikki Webster reproducing her iconic opening ceremony performance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdef62442b745f1023ee6848ed55f9e3</guid></item><item><title>Nikki Webster sings with her children for 25th anniversary of Sydney Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/nikki-webster-sings-with-her-children-for-25th/105778014</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c83bf0274f16a9fa314e120145c3d8f</guid></item><item><title>Shire of Coolgardie awaits decision on future after giving evidence to minister</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/shire-of-coolgardie-show-cause-notice-response/105774072</link><description>The embattled Shire of Coolgardie waits to hear whether it will be suspended ahead of local government elections over concerns about financial and managerial mismanagement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a60af1587b72855d0965e133f66c3a65</guid></item><item><title>Vantara wildlife facility cleared of wrongdoing by court-ordered probe in India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/vantara-wildlife-facility-cleared-of-wrongdoing-by-indian-probe/105777330</link><description>Conservationists had raised concerns about Vantara but investigators say the issues raised are "devoid of merit".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ae8a80b362270975ef42f54dcbd8c5</guid></item><item><title>Lisa Reihana's exhibition, Voyager, recasts history through an Indigenous lens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/lisa-reihana-ngununggula-exhibition-voyager-indigenous-maori/105760474</link><description>The internationally renowned Maori artist's technically complex, visually mesmerising exhibition spans nearly a decade of artwork.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ed46a76298102094bcf604b8536fb9b</guid></item><item><title>How to determine if your kid is well enough for child care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/the-advice-around-sending-a-sick-kid-to-child-care/105734762</link><description>Work demands and a lack of village mean keeping a child at home from care every time they have a sniffle can be a dilemma for many parents. So when it it OK to send them?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3431c0d66326982196374e9a6c348b5f</guid></item><item><title>Family comes first for Queensland newsreader Rob Brough after months off air</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/newsreader-rob-broughs-family-battle/105775464</link><description>The long-time nightly newsreader says it was an "instant choice" to leave work as his daughter faced a battle with cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23d10f83e00ccce3717d0f0a569d4a1c</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump to send National Guard into Memphis to combat crime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/donald-trump-to-send-national-guard-to-memphis-to-combat-crime/105777774</link><description>Donald Trump signs a memorandum to send the National Guard into Memphis to combat crime, setting up another major test of his presidential power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c86283160022e1f0e8600e6a1f66f14</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Olympics inflatable art reappears after 25 years in rural NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/sydney-olympics-reg-mombassa-inflatable-art-reappears-in-nsw/105735020</link><description>A Coonabarabran artist made a lucky find at an online auction two years ago when she recognised a Reg Mombassa art piece from the Sydney Olympics mixed in with advertising devices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f4eacf145efc7f64bf56ffdaca13099</guid></item><item><title>As the Trump administration blows up suspicious boats, legal experts raise red flags</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/trump-administration-lethal-force-drug-cartels-international-law/105778434</link><description>Donald Trump is using the US military to bomb boats suspected of carrying drugs in international waters. But little is known about who is being killed, and military and legal experts are raising several red flags.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f45edea7a8f89a760d2113ff13065ce7</guid></item><item><title>Craig McLachlan withdraws from Cluedo stage show following backlash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/craig-mclachlan-withdraws-cluedo-the-play/105779280</link><description>Less than a week ago, Craig McLachlan was announced to play Colonel Mustard in the forthcoming national tour, making his return to the theatre after The Rocky Horror Show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2abe05c441b509ea22995eb926f87711</guid></item><item><title>Planning commission rejects bid to turn Redbank Power Station into bioenergy hub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/planning-commission-rejects-redbank-power-station-biofuel-plan/105777592</link><description>The Independent Planning Commission of NSW knocks back plans to restart Redbank Power Station in the Hunter Valley, fuelling it with biomass instead of coal tailings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">149bdcd14f72ed4787e50322861090cb</guid></item><item><title>Australia Diamonds announce netball squads for Test series against New Zealand, South Africa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/australia-diamonds-announce-test-netball-squads-new-zealand-sa/105779230</link><description>Goal-shooter Lucy Austin is a shock selection in the Australian netball squad to face South Africa, winning a place after initially being included as an "invitee" to their training camp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f84722b6abee542504171a8343b1b82</guid></item><item><title>Central Queensland included in fire ant biosecurity zones</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/fire-ant-biosecurity-zones-introduced-in-central-queensland/105777728</link><description>New restrictions in place on moving materials into five central Queensland sites to reduce the spread of the invasive species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f62a27c6d9e79b642f55fa3dab985fb8</guid></item><item><title>Where and how to watch the 2025 Primetime Emmy award-winning shows in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/where-and-how-to-watch-the-emmy-award-winning-shows/105778142</link><description>From The Studio to The Pitt, here's how to stream the biggest winners of the 2025 Primetime Emmy Awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">243532cd9f64922ef9206ce0ccd4940d</guid></item><item><title>Victoria delays Gippsland offshore wind auction, stalling developers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/victoria-offshore-wind-auction-delay/105778708</link><description>The Victorian government pushes back its timeline for new offshore wind farms in the state's east in a blow to developers looking to move their projects to the next stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80c982b89a58ea8f9bc5c06f098af297</guid></item><item><title>Aaron Chen talks comedy, faith, and moving to New York</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/aaron-chen-take-5-comedy-interview-music-tonight-fisk/105773602</link><description>How Aaron Chen went from being booted out of Sydney pubs to winning Logies and chasing global stardom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd43f88c371be470e8b83b1b925f650a</guid></item><item><title>Does washing your fruit and veggies remove chemicals?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/best-way-to-wash-fresh-produce-fruits-veggies-remove-chemcials-/105773664</link><description>This is what experts have to say about washing fruit and veggies, with removing chemicals and reducing the amount we consume in mind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57b4d4864180c3c11eed8be0eca03f20</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump files defamation and libel lawsuit against The New York Times, claiming 'massive economic damage to his brand value'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/trump-files-us15-billion-lawsuit-against-new-york-times/105779782</link><description>In a lengthy post on his social media platform, the US president accused The New York Times of lying about him, his family and his business.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">025394af4103f19c4c76069f86680f4b</guid></item><item><title>Concurrent disasters will overwhelm responders, stress ADF, risk report warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/defence-forces-disaster-response-climate-risk-assessment/105778304</link><description>A dedicated disaster recovery force is needed, or else responders and defence forces could be "overwhelmed" by multiple concurrent natural disasters, the National Climate Risk Assessment warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79a82e7988ce64cb47e2aea9d939b300</guid></item><item><title>Breastfeeding Gold Coast mum says she was asked to leave Virgin Australia lounge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/virgin-australia-apologises-mother-pumping-breast-milk/105779738</link><description>Mother-of-two Elise Turner says she was asked to leave the Virgin Australia business lounge after refusing to go to a bathroom to pump breast milk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a5d01ae6ec3bc3224e376127e761ff5</guid></item><item><title>How Isabelle Kelly shook off getting her 'teeth pushed back' to return for Roosters' NRLW finals charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/isabelle-kelly-injury-jaw-teeth-roosters-nrlw-finals/105780582</link><description>Isabelle Kelly was meant to rest up for a few weeks after suffering an oral fracture that nearly cost her several teeth but the Roosters skipper missed just one match and has now returned to lead the club's premiership charge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">062a7201f7cd32cadeb54c8069a61337</guid></item><item><title>China has a 'chokehold' on the rare earth supply chain. Could Australia offer an alternative?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/china-rare-earths-monopoly-australia-alternative-supplier/105748058</link><description>Rare earths are critical for manufacturing everything from electric vehicles to wind turbines and defence equipment, and with China's dominance over the supply chain, they have also become inextricably enmeshed in geopolitics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7e66c6df15c930bf8fa103970dac05b</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of pigs die as Andgar Proprietors piggery catches fire with two sheds burning for over 12 hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/andgar-piggery-fire-kills-200-animials-sa/105780636</link><description>The Department of Primary Industries and Regions says about 200 animals died in the blaze while another 45 pigs were euthanised by the department and RSPCA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8d637dff0fa3ce0bdf9aee2457db201</guid></item><item><title>Israeli military launches ground offensive to occupy Gaza City</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/idf-launches-military-offensive-to-occupy-gaza/105777948</link><description>The Israel Defense Forces says its expanded operation in Gaza City "to destroy Hamas's military infrastructure" has begun, with residents warned to move south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80bfd937165cc59a068b4d0ad85e2045</guid></item><item><title>Israel is committing genocide in Gaza, major United Nations report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/israel-committing-genocide-in-gaza-un-report-says/105780230</link><description>Israel has committed and is continuing to commit genocide in Gaza, according to the "most authoritative assessment" to date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e547fcd275b42fb12bbaa7d9028fd7aa</guid></item><item><title>James O'Connor still hopeful of playing Bledisloe Cup for Wallabies against All Blacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/james-oconnor-still-hopeful-of-playing-bledisloe-cup/105780738</link><description>James O'Connor has flown to England with his Test future still up in the air, but the Wallabies playmaker has not given up on playing in his first Bledisloe Cup match in five years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fe6060cfa537dad8e49fa78e8c41f63</guid></item><item><title>A UN report says Israel is committing genocide. Experts hope it spurs Australia to act</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/un-report-on-israel-genocide-msg-to-nations-including-australia/105777232</link><description>What ultimately determines whether the UN's report joins the list of other shocking but overlooked inquiries is whether this latest finding moves any governments, including Australia's, to take further action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">121775c05df3d7bd0ed0b0d63cee2c23</guid></item><item><title>Approval of $453 million battery project angers Kiewa Valley residents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/victorian-premier-approves-kiewa-valley-battery-project/105779392</link><description>The state government approves the development of a $453 million energy storage system by a Chinese company in the state's north-east, angering nearby residents who say their concerns have been ignored.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0714747da477ffd0c9e429861e28643d</guid></item><item><title>Jacinta Allan's trip to China aims to court investment and voters back home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/victorian-premier-jacinta-allan-in-china-analysis/105780358</link><description>Jacinta Allan's one week trip to the Middle Kingdom is a show with two audiences, as she eyes Chinese investment and hopes to solidify her party's relationship with Chinese Victorians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dda66615efc3bab85e42708bef31ff82</guid></item><item><title>China accuses Philippines of 'illegal' intrusion at its new nature reserve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/china-accuses-philippines-of-illegal-intrusion-at-new-reserve/105781038</link><description>China's coastguard has accused Philippine ships of illegally entering China's territorial waters at a shoal that is internationally recognised as within the Philippines' exclusive economic zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d22fae2218c2b953ce31ac500d27401e</guid></item><item><title>NRL finals week two team lists: Canterbury Bulldogs pick new halves combination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/nrl-finals-week-two-team-lists-bulldogs-panthers-raiders-sharks/105781098</link><description>Winger Jacob Kiraz has revealed he is happy to keep playing with painkilling injections as a patched-up Canterbury turn to a barely tested halves combination of Lachlan Galvin and Toby Sexton to save their NRL season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e00963cd95ccbc1a7f4dac1f88d12452</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105781402</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e2b5a3b30f5fdf1b8c8739f00047ca8</guid></item><item><title>Man 'choked to death' on ribbons and food in Adelaide nursing home, inquest told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/sa-inquest-hears-nursing-home-resident-choked-on-ribbons/105697736</link><description>A nursing home resident known to wander and ingest foreign objects died after choking on ribbons at a facility in Adelaide’s north, an inquest has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95ba5d590939d36f5248d85d89547a6f</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull wins 1,500m bronze, Peter Bol crashes out at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-jess-hull/105778240</link><description>Jess Hull claims bronze in the women's 1,500m at the World Athletics Championships, after Peter Bol was eliminated from the 800m in the heats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7250f2b7b3eaaed7b8f51092ef3fc818</guid></item><item><title>Robert Redford, Hollywood idol of the 1970s and Oscar-winning director and actor, has died aged 89</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/actor-and-activist-robert-redford-dies-aged-89/105781564</link><description>Redford died "at his home in Sundance in the mountains of Utah" surrounded by family, his publicist announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f08a88e14f2b784115f4aa8b363f1ecc</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump takes aim at ABC journalist as he suggests he'll meet Albanese 'very soon'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/donald-trump-john-lyons-exchange-before-anthony-albanese-meeting/105781624</link><description>Donald Trump takes aim at the ABC's Americas editor during an extraordinary exchange at the White House, as the president suggests he will meet Prime Minister Anthony Albanese "very soon".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">156db315a11501aa8fbeaf35550e4091</guid></item><item><title>New York judge dismisses state terrorism charges against Luigi Mangione</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/judge-dismisses-terrorism-charges-against-luigi-mangione/105781696</link><description>The 27-year-old Ivy League graduate still faces New York state second-degree murder charges and a federal death penalty prosecution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdb179c60ca3cc9f40d0ef6ea086656d</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste protesters vow to continue rallying until plan to buy MPs 65 cars is overturned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/timor-leste-protests-over-mp-car-plan-grow/105781726</link><description>The protests nearly doubled in size on Tuesday as people continued to vent their frustrations at a plan to buy MPs 65 new SUVs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">feeb6a6ab4a2322ebf2709358b8c2353</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk shooting suspect Tyler Robinson charged with murder as prosecutors seek death penalty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/alleged-charlie-kirk-shooter-tyler-robinson-charged/105781872</link><description>Utah prosecutors say they will seek the death penalty for the 22-year-old alleged shooter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87bd66a147b9d8ff76e79fdd79e8ff76</guid></item><item><title>Australians too dependent on government, says Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/australians-too-dependent-on-government-says-sussan-ley/105781276</link><description>In her first major economic speech, the opposition leader hits out at universal subsidies and says "dependency" has affected Australia's "national character".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">651c319b8e005af88f9f36c064e26d9e</guid></item><item><title>Britain is hoping it has a secret weapon to charm Donald Trump this week: 'all his favourite things'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/donald-trump-heads-to-uk-for-second-state-visit/105764556</link><description>The US president has been given something no other world leader has ever received: a second state visit invitation from Buckingham Palace. But assessing the trip's success means looking beneath the pomp and pageantry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">816968e21bc208bd8ed8cd9ca5863c1d</guid></item><item><title>Botox, fillers among the cosmetic injectables targeted in medical regulator's new rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/cosmetic-injectables-rules-botox-fillers/105778596</link><description>New rules have come into place aimed at better protecting patients from unsafe cosmetic procedures. Here's what it mean for your next appointment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f034dc98c168b046f196741357b091bf</guid></item><item><title>Threat of stagflation bears down on world's largest economy as Federal Reserve decision looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/threat-of-stagflation-bears-down-on-world-s-largest-economy/105781264</link><description>The world's largest central bank is less than 24 hours from announcing one of the most anticipated interest rate decisions of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">317d2acf44c6b55d5cef638469f7338f</guid></item><item><title>What time does Gout Gout run at World Athletics Championships? How to watch Gout Gout's 200m heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/when-does-gout-gout-run-200m-at-world-athletics-championships/105775006</link><description>Gout Gout will make his World Athletics Championships debut at the Tokyo National Stadium on Wednesday night. Here's how to watch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d64ce570ae00cb2a79c594c389ec4b0</guid></item><item><title>A plan to simplify Melbourne's bus network went to government, so why hasn't it happened?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/victoria-bus-system-public-transport/105780926</link><description>Victoria is spending the least per capita on its urban bus system of any state, leaving some Melbourne residents in the lurch at their local bus stop.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cb0b4a268780d533d155aede414aefc</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump chastised ABC journalist John Lyons over questions about his business dealings.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/trump-tells-off-australian-reporter/105781964</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4126cdea12b1cfee4255c1102333a08</guid></item><item><title>The Federal Home Guarantee Scheme is expanding, but just how many will be able to afford to buy in?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/home-loan-guarantee-scheme-cost-first-home-buyers/105772918</link><description>The expansion of the scheme, which allows first home buyers to purchase a property with as little as a 5 per cent deposit, has some warning it will also inflate the market. Here's what you'll need to be earning to get a foot in the door.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4fd4e5c6040f2d8b9de5c0800458317</guid></item><item><title>Fingal Post Office saved from closure after local farmers confirmed as new operators</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/fingal-post-office-in-tasmania-saved-by-local-pig-farmers/105779962</link><description>A rural Tasmanian community has fought to keep its post office open, fearing losing the important service could lead to their hometown disappearing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08e347abc9bfa22abeb9447ad06020ab</guid></item><item><title>SA's ongoing harmful algal bloom labelled 'cultural emergency' by First Nations groups</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/sa-algal-bloom-cultural-emergency/105631230</link><description>First Nations South Australians say the harmful algal bloom impacting the state's coastline is a cultural emergency, as it continues to devastate beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ed15cf74630a813b331beecfe638cdf</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians fear they have no place to flee as Israel's army pushes deeper into Gaza City</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/israel-push-deeper-gaza-city-palestinians-fear-no-place-to-flee/105781870</link><description>Israeli troops encircle Gaza City as the UN chief slams the offensive as "systematic destruction", with thousands of Palestinians unable or unwilling to flee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d201c662cb235506a4e3a65fa23e2158</guid></item><item><title>For the Adelaide Crows, the AFL season was a matter of 'what could have been'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/adelaide-crows-reflect-on-afl-finals-exit-after-minor-premiers/105778196</link><description>After an eight-year AFL finals drought, the Adelaide Crows finished this year's home-and-away season as minor premiers — but the club's hopes were dashed by consecutive defeats that left the players and their fans wondering about what might have been.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b79b17dec6a9f9b23b4349c7283d3818</guid></item><item><title>Children are being 'poisoned' by high lead levels as state government agency is accused of report cover-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/broken-hill-lead-poisoning-cover-up-mudgee-silver-mine-fears/105775230</link><description>A state government body sat on a report into lead dust that was "poisoning" children for nearly four years and tried to keep its release quiet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c539d0a8e324dc8143836fe465192aec</guid></item><item><title>Griffith locals push for new health district to meet needs of their community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/griffith-locals-push-for-new-health-district/105729862</link><description>Residents and medical professionals in south-western NSW are pushing to establish a new local health district in Griffith, arguing current services are not good enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">811a2f3a903585b4dace7ad758f6a3f0</guid></item><item><title>Cashrewards's abrupt closure leaves shoppers many unanswered questions. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/cashrewards-abrupt-shutdown-stuns-many-australians/105765936</link><description>Two and a half million Australians have signed up for this cashback app, which leaves them wondering what's next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74d5aaf89ebaad05dd5c26265b442d23</guid></item><item><title>New doco Signorinella: Little Miss celebrates the Italian women who shaped modern Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/signorinella-little-miss-documentary-italian-film-festival/105774428</link><description>Signorinella: Little Miss, the new documentary from the filmmakers behind Lygon St — Si Parla Italiano, celebrates the tenacity of Italian Australian women in business and beyond.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dc3ea23b27aab754a73fa0319a25aee</guid></item><item><title>Starving wallabies on the Mornington Peninsula have been spared from euthanasia after council motion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/vic-briars-wallabies-council-decision/105781992</link><description>A council on Victoria's Mornington Peninsula has voted to relocate starving wallabies from The Briars wildlife sanctuary, rather than destroy them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02ef3566afd789e1a2e2de6749141251</guid></item><item><title>Sam Konstas scores Australia A century in four-day game in India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/sam-konstas-scores-australia-a-century-against-india-a/105782060</link><description>Sam Konstas's push for an Ashes spot continues as he clatters a century in an extended session for Australia A in Lucknow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cec1e71dd86b61ad4d12f75e6292662</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull completes second act at World Athletics Championships as quest for gold continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/jess-hull-world-1500m-bronze-medal-wants-gold/105781748</link><description>Jess Hull claimed Australia's best result in a 1,500m at the world championships with a bronze medal, but she wants to make it gold next time around.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b678c9c3d3bc90e24f522348f78b840</guid></item><item><title>ASX closes down, BHP to axe 750 jobs in Queensland — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/asx-markets-business-live-news/105782190</link><description>The Australian share market has closed down after a negative session on Wall Street ahead of tomorrow's Federal Reserve decision, while BHP will sack 750 workers in its Queensland coal division. Look back on the day's business and finance news.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acd1d6f1424bebf9031a3c2efe25f550</guid></item><item><title>BHP alliance to sack 750 workers blaming Queensland government mining royalties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/bhp-alliance-to-sack-750-workers-qld-mining-royalties-saraji/105782302</link><description>One of Queensland's biggest coal miners says it does not want to see jobs lost but blamed "the Queensland government's unsustainable coal royalties and market conditions".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b896656142195d5941582f9cbb0f9982</guid></item><item><title>South Australia's feral deer culling program targets eradication amid plague warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/sa-deer-eradication-program-aerial-culling-reduces-population/105763068</link><description>South Australia has ramped up its feral deer aerial culling program as drought-affected farmers battle the pest on their properties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62ba923682e9f4c1c2fea7cd969ab7fd</guid></item><item><title>Australia and PNG fail to clinch defence agreement, resorting to communique</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/australia-png-fail-defence-agreement-communique/105782424</link><description>A major defence treaty between Australia and Papua New Guinea has failed to get over the line today, with the countries resorting to signing a communique in lieu of the actual document.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d5916f8d88a6bb049ef9ef389165d8e</guid></item><item><title>Rainbow bee-eaters prevented from nesting on Qld festival site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/rainbow-bee-eaters-prevented-from-nesting-at-agnes-water-site/105773530</link><description>Conservationists say one of the country's largest colonies of a protected native bird is under threat at a two-day festival site.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c2f01e7162df177f029c3df3ed57e39</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Roosters, Brisbane Broncos NRLW favourites, Andrew Abdo banking on finals surprise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/roosters-broncos-nrlw-dominance-ahead-of-finals/105782346</link><description>As the NRLW finals kick off with the Roosters and Broncos miles ahead of the competition, chief executive Andrew Abdo is hoping the unpredictability of sudden-death finals will generate some surprises.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86b0bb2a5b175f5f803d5ee41052ecb1</guid></item><item><title>Macquarie Point stadium report recommends project not proceed, as Tasmanian Planning Commission flags concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/tasmania-hobart-afl-macquarie-point-planning-commission-findings/105781448</link><description>The proposed Macquarie Point AFL stadium in Hobart should not proceed, a long-awaited assessment from the Tasmanian Planning Commission recommends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7a468158b9bcb2474776c465e5ce225</guid></item><item><title>UK protesters arrested for beaming Epstein video on Windsor castle before Donald Trump's visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/protesters-beam-epstein-video-as-trump-visits-uk/105782420</link><description>The shots included Donald Trump's mugshot, portraits of Epstein, newspaper headlines, and footage of the two men dancing together.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fbdd2e588435c6e7184adb4bba39607</guid></item><item><title>Court documents reveal how Charlie Kirk shooting suspect Tyler Robinson allegedly confessed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/charlie-kirk-alleged-killer-tyler-robinson-charge-sheet-details/105782040</link><description>Key moments that led to the identification and arrest of the man accused of murdering Charlie Kirk have been laid out in fresh court documents released by US authorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a5af82cd0969572b0774a4509146ef7</guid></item><item><title>Police arrest man over alleged domestic violence-related death of female partner in Palmerston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/nt-police-arrest-man-over-death-of-female-partner-in-palmerston/105782526</link><description>A man has been arrested over the alleged domestic violence-related death of his female partner overnight, after she was found unresponsive in the front yard of a Palmerston home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7c47df92c73582fdc3ec37e313630f3</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters honoured for Black Summer efforts as CFA warns about fire season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/black-summer-five-years-on-albury-wodonga/105761592</link><description>Firefighters say they learnt a lot from the Black Summer bushfires, but fear Victorians have become complacent in preparations ahead of this fire season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fccaf6727b3b5a68b220b1fb5f86623b</guid></item><item><title>Only social media companies know for sure how the teen ban will work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/social-media-ban-law-rules-analysis/105780188</link><description>The social media saga has produced its fair share of intrigue. But the latest big reveal on how the ban will work has left us with just another cliffhanger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81ea0e9097c27edcfe3bce09fd63b970</guid></item><item><title>Conservation foundation maps environmentally friendly areas for fast-tracking renewables</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/australian-conservation-foundation-maps-areas-for-renewables/105777696</link><description>The Australian Conservation Foundation says it has mapped the east coast of Australia to identify sites suitable for renewable projects that do not impact on biodiversity, helping Australia reach net zero by 2050 with limited damage to nature.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c8fd4a43925a8dac2bfe58190aa0e7f</guid></item><item><title>Khapra beetle, a threat to grains industry, discovered in imported nappy pants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/khapra-beetle-found-in-imported-nappy-pants-threatens-grains/105782306</link><description>Authorities are investigating how khapra beetle, the number-one-priority pest for the grains industry, entered Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c65ef8036bcd15cd64dcb1342bb737aa</guid></item><item><title>Warnings of flash flooding after torrential rain drenches Far North Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/weather-warning-rain-far-north-queensland/105783282</link><description>Huge rainfall totals of more than 300 millimetres have taken even rain-hardened Far North Queenslanders by surprise at a typically drier time of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4fd41dcd4db489d39bf56181f35eeaf</guid></item><item><title>Why 'everything feels easier' for Chloe Rykers since her breast reduction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/breast-reduction-changed-my-quality-of-life-chloe-rykers/105763294</link><description>Chloe Rykers says her "big boobs" had, in various ways, made her career harder and left her feeling uncomfortable and in pain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfb6d7d9d5d29c944f231ddddf5980dc</guid></item><item><title>Robert Redford's most notable movies with Jane Fonda, Barbra Streisand and Paul Newman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/robert-redford-movies-jane-fonda-barbra-streisand-paul-newman/105782412</link><description>The Hollywood icon leaves a legacy of classic films with a career that stretched over decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a65466a8bed654c5a2f46954d2cfb614</guid></item><item><title>GIM Trading director Darren Geddes blocked from leaving Australia in court order</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/asic-court-order-gim-trading-bond-fraud-allegations/105782628</link><description>After the ABC revealed GIM Trading had raised millions from customers who later suspected fraudulent activity, a judge has prohibited the current director from leaving the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86e4cbcd5a0b521eec9f167fe445b92f</guid></item><item><title>Peter Bol's World Athletics Championships exit a sign of the times for Australian track and field</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/peter-bol-on-the-next-stage-of-australian-athletics/105783168</link><description>Peter Bol finished fourth in the 800 metres at Tokyo's National Stadium four years after doing the same thing at the Olympic Games, but the results could not have been more different.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31a5ddd55b49bbfa4c1b064045a9ad0e</guid></item><item><title>Major reforms for NSW planning system aim to curb 'maze' of current process</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/nsw-development-changes-planning-system-overhaul/105783324</link><description>The proposed centrepiece is a "single front door" authority to provide advice on development applications on behalf of all government agencies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">852e7381bb09830b61e462fd16c8e8b1</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Barnes, Dave Faulkner among music industry voices in open letter urging ANU to keep School of Music</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/jimmy-barnes-against-anu-school-of-music-cuts/105784002</link><description>Jimmy Barnes is among more than 40 music voices supporting an open letter to the embattled Australian National University (ANU) calling for the School of Music to be saved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c2e11e10aa99b2ef294abc946d1feaa</guid></item><item><title>Man admits he claimed to be Charlie Kirk gunman so real suspect could flee</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/man-admits-he-falsely-claimed-to-be-charlie-kirk-gunman/105783512</link><description>US police have charged a 71-year-old man they say has admitted to yelling out that he shot conservative activist Charlie Kirk in order to "allow the actual suspect to flee".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de1fbb93cdf9eb43245231ba9e88c8c4</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's only large-scale private mental health clinic, the Hobart Clinic, to close inpatient site by end of October</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/tasmanian-mental-health-inpatient-site-hobart-clinic-to-close/105783678</link><description>The Hobart Clinic, which employs 100 people and has provided private mental health services for Tasmanians for 40 years, will close its inpatient site by the end of October, citing financial woes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd61d37d4e64d804e365a3ede3165983</guid></item><item><title>Hawks AFL coach Sam Mitchell reacts to speculation over Zach Merrett meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/afl-sam-mitchell-zach-merrett-hawthorn-hawks-essendon-bombers/105784298</link><description>As his young Hawks squad prepare for their preliminary final against the Cats, Sam Mitchell opens up about the club's pursuit of Bombers captain Zach Merrett.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">862f69660065f08d0572520ae7565aab</guid></item><item><title>Farmer asks partner to marry him with special canola crop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/farmer-asks-partner-to-marry-him-with-canola-crop/105783070</link><description>NSW farmer Will Henderson had no choice but to bide his time to pop the question. In the end his efforts were rewarded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05e5cefa73531016d6c02d243bfa85a7</guid></item><item><title>Panthers reflect on how Knights loss fuelled run to NRL semifinals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/nrl-penrith-panthers-canterbury-bulldogs-semifinal/105784766</link><description>The Panthers were last on the ladder after round 12, but a "brutal reality check" helped fuel the four-time defending premier's run to this season's finals series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0dcc57f6305015fb40b939f591ef646f</guid></item><item><title>Does the damning planning report mean the end for Hobart's Macquarie Point stadium?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/is-hobart-stadium-now-dead-explainer/105780834</link><description>The Tasmanian Planning Commission described the Hobart stadium as a "singular, large, bulky monolith" with "optimism bias" in the government's cost-benefit figures. What does this mean for the stadium?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6d2b782c8ad36854242ff8269a71dd8</guid></item><item><title>Toucans and other exotic animals rescued in major Brazilian trafficking bust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/toucans-tortoises-rescued-in-major-brazilian-trafficking-bust/105784392</link><description>Brazilian authorities say they have disrupted a major animal trafficking ring, rescuing hundreds of exotic animals and making dozens of arrests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09bc369000da1fa79f9a9a98afcdd0bc</guid></item><item><title>Tesla settles lawsuits over two fatal crashes involving autopilot software</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/tesla-settles-lawsuits-fatal-crashes-involving-autopilot/105784748</link><description>The lawsuits relate to separate crashes in California in 2019, including one that killed a 15-year-old boy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4de78b32e20d1ad05d9bce7b2fd9fb36</guid></item><item><title>UTS to axe 1,100 subjects across education and public health, cuts 134 full-time jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/uts-cuts-subjects-job-cuts-restructure/105783978</link><description>The University of Technology Sydney will close its schools of education and public health under a multi-million-dollar restructure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">745b450ac59dd82dd2a07962aa9b5e5c</guid></item><item><title>Albanese has found out nailing down Pacific agreements is harder than expected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/papua-new-guinea-defence-treaty-delays/105783902</link><description>Anthony Albanese was meant to emerge from his recent flurry of Pacific diplomacy holding no fewer than two major agreements — instead he's returning home conspicuously empty-handed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef894cba91b42943ab469518f13e2d11</guid></item><item><title>In Donald Trump's America, questions not to the president's liking are met with hostility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/president-donald-trump-and-hostile-relationship-with-media/105783964</link><description>As America enters a dark tunnel of dangerous internal divisions and an increasingly violent public discourse, Donald Trump is escalating his attacks on many of this nation's institutions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d3fbf6b1e6db2875d16740bdc3f6ed4</guid></item><item><title>Australia's first Aboriginal parliamentarian Neville Bonner commemorated with bronze sculpture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/first-indigenous-parliamentarian-neville-bonner-bronze-sculpture/105784526</link><description>Neville Bonner is honoured as Australia's first Indigenous parliamentarian.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f34625e3694dce1ffe76963cc385cf62</guid></item><item><title>New WA youth detention centre likely three years away, documents show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/new-wa-youth-detention-centre-is-years-away/105782632</link><description>A planned youth prison in Perth for high-risk offenders to replace the notorious Unit 18 could still be three years away and cost at least $50 million more than the initial estimate, previously unseen documents reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d542037c2e8b6b88d7a03be262af2764</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder after bones found in search for Susan Goodwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/bones-found-in-search-port-lincoln-susan-goodwin/105783230</link><description>Bones have been found at a Port Lincoln property in the search for the remains of Susan Goodwin, who went missing in Port Lincoln decades ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47a23ba13bc9bbf6569415a0f2e39a33</guid></item><item><title>Prosecutor tells jury not to accept former Broome pub manager's evidence in indecent assault trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/former-roebuck-bay-pub-manager-trial-closing-statements/105778818</link><description>A prosecutor tells a WA District Court jury to use "common sense" when deliberating whether a former pub manager indecently assaulted staff and a patron.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcb7d5f215f5d6cffae81bca4d7633e9</guid></item><item><title>German suspect in Madeleine McCann case freed from prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/christian-brueckner-released-madeleine-mccann-suspect/105785722</link><description>Christian Brueckner is released from a German prison where he has been serving a seven-year sentence for an unrelated sex crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9680ca551af052634e1f606b55ea6fed</guid></item><item><title>Perth council City of Bayswater loses legal bid to stop pet cats roaming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/cat-confinement-laws-dismissed-perth-council-wa/105784434</link><description>The WA parliament has intervened to stop a Perth council from bringing in fines for people who allow their cats to leave their properties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e72259dd0fa8caf004c4a13f0837cef5</guid></item><item><title>Australia refusing to panic over Pat Cummins's injury ahead of Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/ashes-cricket-australia-england-pat-cummins-injury/105785808</link><description>Australia coach Andrew McDonald is confident injured captain Pat Cummins will be fit to play a major role in the men's Ashes, even if he does not feature in all five matches of the series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3764f86fe491f37a58f6d749d3f0b446</guid></item><item><title>WA government minister John Carey has revealed he has donated sperm to assist and support couples in experiencing the joy of parenthood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/wa-government-minister-john-carey-has-revealed-he/105785740</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9b035aa4bafdf7463217d1986b535b9</guid></item><item><title>Labor MP John Carey fathers five children through sperm donation, as WA surrogacy debate continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/wa-minister-john-carey-anonymous-sperm-donor/105785570</link><description>Western Australian Labor MP John Carey reveals he is a sperm donor for five children, as parliament debates legislation to change the state's surrogacy and in vitro fertilisation (IVF) laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">260ee303852d33207bc186fbf514847a</guid></item><item><title>Police up reward money in long-term NT unsolved mysteries to $500,000 each</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/nt-police-missing-persons-reward-money-increased/105776164</link><description>Northern Territory police have increased the reward money for information related to two unsolved cold cases to $500,000 each.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a395c3573a956900fdfe25b338193874</guid></item><item><title>ACT government and ACT Greens negotiate revived rental relief scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/act-government-rent-relief-fund-to-return-in-canberra/105784522</link><description>Negotiations between the ACT government and ACT Greens will lead to the return of a lifeline for renters on the financial brink.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f1c28963ed563a5ae41ba584b124488</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105786068</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4fdf32035483c97cc8e3b3c2ceb960b</guid></item><item><title>Hasan Piker opens up on Charlie Kirk's death, Donald Trump and Elon Musk's campaign against him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/hasan-piker-speaks-charlie-kirk-death-and-death-threats-trump/105784072</link><description>Prominent left-wing commentator Hasan Piker opens up to 7.30 on Donald Trump's left-wing crackdown, the Charlie Kirk he knew and attempts to have him deplatformed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b7081bd7a10cb144ba6685b100983fa</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout, Torrie Lewis, reach semifinal of 200m at the 2025 World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-2025-gout-gout/105784336</link><description>Gout Gout has powered home to claim third place in his heat and secure a spot in the 200m semifinals at the World Athletics Championships in Tokyo, after Torrie Lewis ran a PB to reach the semifinals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30386c1b59e0b9ff2526e8b4bc706a4f</guid></item><item><title>South West WA man Brett Anthony Cohen jailed for possessing child abuse material</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/brett-anthony-cohen-jailed-child-abuse-material-possession/105785456</link><description>Australind man Brett Anthony Cohen has been sentenced to five years behind bars for the possession and dissemination of "truly vile" child abuse material. He will be eligible for parole in three years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbd73acd27c144483d182b17371215d9</guid></item><item><title>Frank Pangallo 'should have checked his sources' for algal bloom claims, Tarzia says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/vincent-tarzia-rebukes-frank-pangallo-over-research-bungle/105785006</link><description>Opposition Leader Vincent Tarzia says new Liberal Party recruit Frank Pangallo "should have checked his sources" before supplying a parliamentary committee with inaccurate research citations to back up the latter's claims that desalination plants can contribute to algal blooms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f2d86a40712753343f527b6748c98b3</guid></item><item><title>Alexei Navalny's wife says new tests show former Russian opposition leader was poisoned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/alexei-nalvalny-poisoned-says-wife-yulia-navalnaya/105786116</link><description>Yulia Navalnaya says that laboratory analysis of smuggled biological samples had found he was killed by poisoning while incarcerated in prison in February 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fe9f91d93abaeaa861fc8cb19ecd191</guid></item><item><title>Fears of a coverup after high levels of lead found at Broken Hill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/fears-of-a-coverup-after-high-levels-of-lead-found/105786166</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bb0a9672d92faa1d7bda0135c14d4fc</guid></item><item><title>What happened to the defence deal with Papua New Guinea?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/what-happened-to-the-defence-deal-with-papua-new/105786170</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7d8d649bc5f56fab61d7d89b4c54488</guid></item><item><title>Report finds Hobart’s planned AFL stadium will have ‘unacceptable’ impacts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/report-finds-hobart%E2%80%99s-planned-afl-stadium-will/105786176</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f66e09995a3156f59e87d6feabfef96</guid></item><item><title>Ben &amp; Jerry's co-founder, Jerry Greenfield, quits over Gaza dispute with parent company Unilever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/ben-jerrys-co-founder-resigns/105785958</link><description>Ben &amp; Jerry's co-founder, Jerry Greenfield, has resigned after a feud with parent company Unilever over Gaza conflict.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e788c44c33e590bcd5f58e11d005c9b9</guid></item><item><title>Left-wing influencer Hasan Piker discusses the death of Charlie Kirk.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/left-wing-influencer-hasan-piker-discusses-the/105786198</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fea9259171b7307705dded16e4ea492</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout makes his senior debut at the World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/gout-gout-makes-his-senior-debut/105786306</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a6f67c414742d7e07f12c1c5287ed55</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout finishes third in 200m heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/gout-gout-finishes-third-in-200m-heat/105786314</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d8312214b2b9a31a74786f0c79c4763</guid></item><item><title>Top stories from ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/top-stories-from-abc-news/105786368</link><description>Listen to ABC News interviews and commentary and analysis from radio programs like AM, PM and The World Today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a13b754279888c4d15fc95c10fb89ff8</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump arrives at Windsor Castle and greeted by British royal family for unprecedent second UK state visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/donald-trump-second-state-visit-uk-met-with-protests/105786186</link><description>The US president has received a royal welcome to mark the start of his second official state visit, but not everyone is happy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">576545f23dd21127388a3bd3042f9430</guid></item><item><title>European Commission lays out new tariffs and sanctions on Israel over war in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/eu-lays-out-new-tariffs-and-sanctions-on-israel/105786322</link><description>The European Union's executive arm has made a series of proposals aimed at forcing an end to the Israel-Hamas conflict.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcf8968b74aefc70146386449173685e</guid></item><item><title>Australia's 2035 climate target will strike a middle path. Will it be enough?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/2035-climate-emissions-target-middle-path/105782220</link><description>Australia's next major climate commitment will be above the ambitions of New Zealand and Canada, but below the United Kingdom, as the government strikes a middle path in pursuit of both an "ambitious" but "achievable" 2035 target.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09490579740954d02af7a3ac935593e5</guid></item><item><title>NT regulator takes new side job with miner amid calls to quit over gas leak 'scandal'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nt-regulator-takes-new-side-job-with-miner-amid-calls-he-quit/105783120</link><description>The chair of the Northern Territory's Environment Protection Authority has become a "strategic adviser" to a miner but denies he has a conflict of interest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80fb3748f8891eb305aaaffb96c7fc55</guid></item><item><title>Why rower Jean Mitchell got an Olympic rings tattoo over her chemo scar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/olympics-jean-mitchell-rowing-olympic-rings-tattoo/105722046</link><description>Making it to the Paris 2024 Olympics was a career highlight for Jean Mitchell — and the brain cancer survivor marked the achievement in a special way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d089a522d586e7ccb4748b49b146ed6</guid></item><item><title>Son of imprisoned Aung San Suu Kyi speaks to the ABC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/son-of-imprisoned-aung-san-suu-kyi-speaks-to-the/105785814</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e90cfcb403292e306b39658e625b2123</guid></item><item><title>Fears human rights activist Aung San Suu Kyi could 'die' in a 'hellhole' prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/aung-san-suu-kyi-needs-urgent-medical-care-son-says/105779816</link><description>One of the world's most recognised pro-democracy activists needs urgent medical care as she serves a 27-year sentence in a "hellhole" prison, her son has claimed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c3c46168a5e4d40865d7addf1355e38</guid></item><item><title>Fewer than a third of bus travellers are touching on, and experts say it's a problem</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/victoria-bus-fare-evasion-public-transport-myki/105785946</link><description>Documents say less than a third of Melbourne bus commuters are touching on their Myki card to pay the fare, with the revenue loss potentially climbing into the millions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe191d6c706881f14edb8c142e38c77a</guid></item></channel></rss>