<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 05:04:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tameka Yallop waits on scan results that could put Asian Cup campaign in jeopardy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/tameka-yallop-hamstring-injury-ahead-of-matildas-asian-cup/106119984</link><description>Matildas stalwart Tameka Yallop's Asian Cup campaign hangs the balance as she awaits news on the hamstring she suffered over the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f0d00cd65166b56f01ab3005823edd6</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese delivers eulogy at Graham 'Richo' Richardson's state funeral</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/nsw-graham-richardson-state-funeral/106116350</link><description>Hundreds of former and current politicians from all sides of the spectrum gathered to remember powerbroker and kingmaker Graham 'Richo' Richardson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bba30371e6067e2b9a76aa0391892a10</guid></item><item><title>Five questions the watchdog overseeing NSW Police will consider about Lindy Lucena's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/nsw-lecc-ballina-lindy-lucena-death-police-response-hearings/106118320</link><description>NSW Police has been probed about "proper practice" and what could be done differently after first being alerted to Lindy Lucena's fatal bashing on the NSW north coast, with multiple delays in the force's response.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e4339d728098a88d575e89703b03ab0</guid></item><item><title>Paramedic Graham Phillips pleads guilty to possession, transmission of child abuse material</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/nsw-paramedic-admits-child-abuse-material-possession/106120246</link><description>A New South Wales paramedic and former Scouts volunteer admits possessing and transmitting child abuse material.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91e5388e44323dcba59cd3c87a686e00</guid></item><item><title>CCTV shows person leaving car fire where Joel Vrtacnik's body was later found</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/police-seek-person-with-burn-injuries-from-western-nsw-car-fire/106116774</link><description>Police appeal for information about a person seen walking away from the inferno, who they say would likely have suffered burns to their hands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db0a42e608e3ba2135591e6020800574</guid></item><item><title>Brewarrina investigation shows figure leaving crime scene</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/brewarrina-investigation-shows-figure-leaving-crime-scene/106116990</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33afd64798a9939e9689db5be82b5e61</guid></item><item><title>Dylan Jake Fitzgerald sentenced to 2 years for dangerous driving following Bruce Highway police chase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/dylan-jake-fitzgerald-sentenced-following-bruce-hwy-police-chase/106119214</link><description>An intoxicated driver was jailed for leading police on a wild chase up the Bruce Highway, sparks flying from the bare wheel rims of a stolen food truck.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9d4099e59085adfde0556f7a42691d1</guid></item><item><title>Phillip Reginald Rudd's death no longer deemed accidental as police re-examine eight-year-old case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/cold-case-appeal-phillip-reginald-rudd/106118708</link><description>Police say the death of Phillip Rudd, once thought to be an accident, could be more sinister following new information.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a6aa4757a2411834744499c5a3517af</guid></item><item><title>Woman accused of murder at Bethanie Waters aged care home in Port Kennedy deemed unfit to stand trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/woman-accused-of-wa-aged-care-home-murder-deemed-unfit-for-trial/106120168</link><description>A 76-year-old woman accused of murdering her aged care roommate in Perth is deemed unfit to stand trial by a Supreme Court judge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2570d597594264451dea7a9f39f17221</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested following 'direct and significant' threats to Crows player Izak Rankine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/arrest-after-crows-player-allegedly-threatened-on-social-media/106120732</link><description>SA Police have arrested a 31-year-old man after he allegedly sent five threatening messages on social media to a Crows player, who the ABC understands is Izak Rankine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a57f2db2aecb089b0107bec1776ef6b</guid></item><item><title>Popular Bluey, Paw Patrol toy sets recalled over asbestos fears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/popular-bluey-paw-patrol-toy-sets-recalled-over-asbestos-fears/106120502</link><description>The three "sensory activity sets" from HL Toys International include sealed tubs of coloured sand which Kmart said may contain the toxic mineral.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c543ab4844a699d3b7981e15b1e19f1d</guid></item><item><title>Mackay set to host first Test cricket match when Australian men face Bangladesh in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/mackay-first-test-cricket-match-bangladesh/106120442</link><description>The Australian men will play a two-match series against Bangladesh in 2026, with the second venue yet to be decided.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">350f478bd03b64460b75dbf6cbde5bbf</guid></item><item><title>Life-saving blood platelets found to be effective when frozen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/blood-platelets-found-to-be-effective-when-frozen/106110512</link><description>Research proves that frozen blood platelets are safe and effective to use on critically injured patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aba1abdc29be0f93c88d1fc82ca21b4a</guid></item><item><title>Body of Western Australian man found after he reportedly fell off jetty at Coffin Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/body-of-wa-man-found-near-coffin-bay/106121134</link><description>The body of a Western Australian man missing in waters off Coffin Bay on South Australia's Eyre Peninsula has been found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ab8a31f2fad958c3c4a0ab7faceea06</guid></item><item><title>Patients say pelvic botox injections ease endometriosis pain, but access has been pulled from the ACT public system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/act-doctor-ordered-to-stop-botox-injections-for-endometriosis/106119880</link><description>Patients have described the procedure as "life changing" but pelvic botox injections are no longer available publicly in the ACT, with Canberra Health Services ceasing the procedure "as a precaution due to unknown risks".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">776d2c5deeb527199442777fa4cbbb92</guid></item><item><title>Phone calls by criminally neglectful mother showed 'callous disregard' for sick daughter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/crystal-hanley-phone-calls-made-before-daughters-death/106119580</link><description>A South Australian court releases audio of prison phone calls made in the lead-up to the death of a six-year-old girl in 2022. WARNING: Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander readers are advised this article contains the first name and image of a person who has died. Readers are also advised this story contains content which may be distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64ad3d9b6bb265a623b931b0532dbe3e</guid></item><item><title>Small ways to teach babies and toddlers body safety and consent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/teaching-babies-and-toddlers-about-consent-and-body-safety/106026064</link><description>Narrating nappy changes is one way parents and caregivers can strengthen bonds and start lessons around body safety early.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a833a4932bef9d8cd9d0fc724760c23d</guid></item><item><title>Family of teenager killed in e-bike collision pay tribute to 'beautiful' 14-year-old</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/melbourne-e-bike-crash-diamond-creek/106121284</link><description>The family of a teenager killed in a collision in Melbourne's north-east has paid tribute to their "beautiful" 14-year-old son.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42e9a2b6a8e7fc28a7faad10c2d1681e</guid></item><item><title>Wells initiates audit of expenses as Shorten defends her against 'pile-on'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/wells-initiates-audit-of-expenses-as-shorten-defends-her/106121558</link><description>The sports minister maintains all her taxpayer-funded expenses have been within the guidelines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcc6d6fc2462e8a41d1a3538f647f210</guid></item><item><title>Canberra doctor ordered to stop botox injections for endometriosis pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/act-doctor-ordered-stop-botox-injections-for-endometriosis-pain/106121916</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78776bc7f795577774761fe5d1d5dc63</guid></item><item><title>People have been filmed swimming with sharks at Byron Bay.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/swimming-with-sharks-at-byron-bay/106121628</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b58fde1c722be35fe4840e91f135e73</guid></item><item><title>Byron Bay shark frenzy attracts onlookers and a warning to steer clear</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/byron-bay-shark-frenzy-bait-fish-marine/106120054</link><description>A marine scientist warns against getting in the ocean with sharks after footage emerges of swimmers at Byron Bay next to a huge school of bait fish and hundreds of the predators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b506d6361289ffe47d63439b3fbe309c</guid></item><item><title>Union calls on SA government to reach urgent pay agreement to end prison lockdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/ongoing-prison-lockdowns-could-impact-inmates-health/106120918</link><description>Advocates for prisoners and the union representing correctional officers are calling on the government to reach an urgent pay agreement to help end the statewide prison lockdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">709fe9ecd5055d004c765074ebb60dcd</guid></item><item><title>Woodford Folk Festival founder Bill Hauritz dies at 73</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/woodford-folk-festival-founder-bill-hauritz-dies-at-73/106119912</link><description>Woodford Folk Festival founder Bill Hauritz has died after a lengthy illness, but his grieving loved ones say his legacy will live on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6f371b4e87d96d72b2afcc929d5b404</guid></item><item><title>Two women found dead in Rosanna home following welfare check</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/victoria-police-two-women-deaths-rosanna/106122022</link><description>Two women, aged 84 and 64, were found dead in a home in Rosanna following a welfare check on Tuesday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d05c91dafb1c18aed1ca44bdfd0dd40</guid></item><item><title>England quick Mark Wood to fly home after being ruled out of final Ashes Tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/mark-wood-injury-ashes-ruled-out-knee/106122064</link><description>England's Ashes woes have continue with spearhead quick Mark Wood ruled out of the rest of the tour with a knee injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f63ca2ef36edd3b563f640b67c3c8dc7</guid></item><item><title>Canberra doctor ordered to stop botox injections for endometriosis pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/doctor-ordered-stop-botox-injections-endometriosis/106122142</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6996c6af1f8d722d8483289513235541</guid></item><item><title>Prosecution tells jury a jailhouse confession proves Jodie Hill was involved in alleged murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/jodie-hill-dimboola-alleged-murder-of-john-hunter/106121116</link><description>The prosecution has begun its closing arguments in the final stages of Jodie Hill's three week murder trial following the brutal killing of an elderly man in his Dimboola home almost three years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24924d56bd3a654f74a8daaf6759fade</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106122084</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c21b8d7898702e4a9a0aa8d34e792f65</guid></item><item><title>More crocodiles to be targeted for removal under expansion of Queensland management plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/expansion-of-queensland-crocodile-management-plan/106122482</link><description>The government says the plan will help improve public safety and make it easier to remove crocodiles in hotspots along the coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7643c257a92de6d8610cfc839d0b4457</guid></item><item><title>Linda Reynolds will fight Commonwealth government 'until the bitter end' in lawsuit related to Brittany Higgins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/linda-reynolds-on-brittany-higgins-lawsuit-albanese-government/106122202</link><description>Former defence minister Linda Reynolds says Coalition colleagues failed her and she will not stop fighting to clear her name against "lies", no matter the cost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d47e08dbc17e691cf6ddc7be39ca2ed8</guid></item><item><title>Inquest wraps up into death of Perth 10yo boy in Department of Communities care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/coronial-inquest-boys-death-state-care/106119640</link><description>The inquest into the boy's death in state care hears he was a bright and mischievous boy who was proud of his heritage. WARNING: This story contains distressing content.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c8aee7e439269d996632f3e856c75ef</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 10: How Lord of the Rings changed cinema — and New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/today-in-history-december-10-lord-of-the-rings/106088682</link><description>Peter Jackson's life wouldn't be the same after that red carpet event on December 10, 2001, but it's fair to say cinema, and New Zealand, wouldn't be the same either.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c66528cfccf90a3b11cde05e03e5ad0a</guid></item><item><title>Borders quiz: How well do you know Australian geography?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/geography-quiz-australian-borders/106117786</link><description>Which state has the longest land border? Test your knowledge in today's quiz.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8418d66f47f32f5513dfacbd0f7e2b9f</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate rises replace cuts on Michele Bullock's RBA agenda</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/no-interest-rate-cuts-on-horizon-rba-december-decision/106120192</link><description>The Reserve Bank governor has opened the door to interest rate hikes in 2026, but how soon will she walk through it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53e6bff8894500c822d365e08bcbc61b</guid></item><item><title>Australia's social media ban for under-16s starts today. Here is what you should know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/australias-social-media-ban-for-under-16s-starts-today/106119800</link><description>After months of build-up, the time has finally come. From today, Australians under the age of 16 are banned from having a social media account.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a4c2f9c3bb4a52b674bb0cb3610c885</guid></item><item><title>Penalties push for financial abusers who draw partners into tax and company fraud</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/penalties-call-for-perpetrators-coercive-financial-abuse-fraud/106093388</link><description>Perpetrators of financial abuse commit fraud by impersonating their partners, making them company directors in secret and putting business and tax debts in their names. The government wants to fix the problem, but will its proposed reforms go far enough?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c0103b20da54e62ba192f00031481d1</guid></item><item><title>Demand for water cannot be an 'afterthought' in AI push</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/demand-for-data-centre-water-in-ai-push/106102208</link><description>Australia has more than 250 data centres and more in the pipeline, prompting experts to warn against using drinking water to cool servers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a5bd0c991902768cecab60b229aa0cb</guid></item><item><title>AEMO slashes forecasts for wind farms as falling costs fuel solar and batteries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/aemo-isp-slashes-wind-forecasts-as-solar-batteries-rise/106120076</link><description>Soaring costs and trenchant criticism from some put the brakes on wind and transmission as the sun shines on big solar and batteries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90d859eebe5329bffe3e92e1956af9a9</guid></item><item><title>Federal politicians charge taxpayers $1.1 million for family travel in 12 months</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/pollies-charge-taxpayers-for-family-travel/106122328</link><description>Family reunion travel is under scrutiny as new analysis shows federal MPs and senators spent $1.1 million on flying and driving their loved ones to Canberra and around Australia in 12 months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c99d94530ebf0f953b42ed026043308</guid></item><item><title>The best albums of 2025 from Lorde, Tame Impala, FKA twigs and more</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/double-j-50-best-albums-of-2025/106096938</link><description>It's been an incredible year of music. Did your favourite album of 2025 make our list?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e420c61da6e6b1442e1abcf07c9f9154</guid></item><item><title>ABC 2026 Heywire winners bring 'raw, honest storytelling' of life in regional Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/abc-2026-heywire-winners-tell-of-life-in-regional-australia/106021792</link><description>Thirty-five young people have been named 2026 ABC Heywire winners for the bravery and authenticity of their life stories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c61b48b006d0310fe5b555ccd5171a3</guid></item><item><title>Widespread rain across NSW to reduce threat of bushfires leading up to Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/widespread-rain-forecast-for-nsw-a-relief-for-bushfire-threats/106121526</link><description>The most widespread rain in three months will develop across New South Wales during the coming days, reducing the threat of bushfires in the lead-up to Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49da9ef067c2ff0b09f499e9525d7e9f</guid></item><item><title>Abuse survivors say Centrelink's 'couple rule' puts women in danger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/couple-rule-centrelink-income-test-concerns/106100196</link><description>Financial and domestic abuse survivors say the way Centrelink assesses benefit payments for people in a relationship makes it harder for women to leave dangerous relationships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df9ee2f41264eeace457f874b59e068c</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police charge 19yo over alleged grenade, gunfire attack at Tallawong home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/man-charged-over-grenade-gunfire-attack-tallawong-home/106123066</link><description>A 19-year-old is expected to front court on Wednesday after been charged over the alleged shooting at a Tallawong home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f35db945aa17061eea479523aebef76</guid></item><item><title>Scorchers take aim at Sixers ahead of WBBL semifinal after eliminating Stars in knockout final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/cricket-wbbl-scorchers-aim-at-sixers-after-beating-stars-final/106123136</link><description>The Perth Scorchers keep their WBBL title hopes alive with a win over the Stars in a knockout final, as youngster Chloe Ainsworth shows her credentials on the big stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68ef51afed024ed6a33a6d8c3ab91f31</guid></item><item><title>Taronga Zoo to 'rewild' cleared farmland in northern NSW with native Australian animals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/taronga-zoo-to-rewild-cleared-farmland-with-native-animals/106121552</link><description>Taronga Zoo has successfully bred native Australian animals for years — but it now has a vision on how to re-establish their populations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6c2a1e5a637e00e6fe97b1cdfef3359</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal group left without legal recourse without federal human rights act</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/wunna-nyiyaparli-title-fight-human-rights-act/106036872</link><description>Legal experts say Australia is lagging in its human rights approach and should adopt a federal human rights act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd168af02397f759e879efd42ef0044c</guid></item><item><title>Ten-year-old snake bite survivor gives back to community through cow sale</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/10-year-old-snake-bite-survivor-giving-back-to-community/106114456</link><description>This 10-year-old is selling her family's cows to help raise funds for those who rescued her when she suffered a potentially deadly snake bite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c8898cb976b32ba6705953d32764ac0</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Albanese says social media ban biggest 'cultural change' Australia has faced — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/federal-politics-live-blog-december-10/106120662</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese says Australia's social media ban will change lives as Australia takes "back control" from social media companies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1ff720287ed0c2f11b929cfb5ed3724</guid></item><item><title>US judge approves release of grand jury documents against Ghislaine Maxwell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/us-judge-approves-release-of-documents-against-ghislaine-maxwell/106123122</link><description>The judge grants the Justice Department's request under a new law requiring the release of files related to Jeffrey Epstein and Ghislaine Maxwell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">debcadced8c2241d8734bcafbc24d8e9</guid></item><item><title>Why is Elon Musk fighting with the European Union over social media platform X?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/elon-musk-fighting-with-european-union-over-x/106117886</link><description>The latest target of Elon Musk's ire is the European Union, which he has called a "bureaucratic monster" that "should be abolished". So, what's going on?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ead87207d43858d0d334a7337c9b1679</guid></item><item><title>Mayhem at Brisbane Lady Gaga concert as long queues blamed on 'technical issues'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/fans-report-waiting-hours-to-get-into-brisbane-lady-gaga-concert/106122524</link><description>The stadium says "technical issues" identified during a sound check meant the gates did not open until 50 minutes later than scheduled, which caused long queues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b49b600c553349c4191db9c0fcf5ad5f</guid></item><item><title>South Africa dismissed for its lowest ever T20 score as India sends ominous message to rivals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/cricket-south-africa-lowest-t20-score-india-world-cup-rematch/106123238</link><description>The rematch of last year's T20 World Cup final is dominated by India as South Africa is dismissed for just 74 runs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e17db46b43fe455f0053c869e6f32bb</guid></item><item><title>Report finds 'shockingly low' government spend on preventing child removals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/snaicc-family-matters-report-calls-for-investment-in-prevention/106114764</link><description>Only 15.6 per cent of national child protection funding goes towards family support services aimed at keeping families intact, a report has found. Advocates are urging the government to "invest in families, not crisis".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1544693c4556d3b47c92547a3625a01</guid></item><item><title>'Integrity' of environmental approvals questioned in WA government's attempt to balance nature and industry in new laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/state-development-laws-wa-analysis/106119780</link><description>As WA's state development laws make their way through parliament, critics are worried about environmental approvals and concentration of power, but the government insists the changes mean more transparency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a2c6a5a4c2925cd9dd74ff67db7c18e</guid></item><item><title>Homicide detectives investigate death of man in Newcastle unit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/police-investigate-cooks-hill-death-newcastle/106123284</link><description>Police launch a homicide investigation after the death of a man in a home at Newcastle early this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efacb2141272921318df783ffcc14c08</guid></item><item><title>Pet cam captures bull and horse sneaking into home of NT politician Andrew Mackay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/dogs-let-bull-and-horse-to-enter-nt-politicians-home/106118568</link><description>An NT resident tells of discovering he had unexpected guests in his home, after his dogs were filmed nudging open a door and letting inside a pet bull and horse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9537621f3ff0b957105d2fb27fec790d</guid></item><item><title>Volunteer WA firefighter with rare and aggressive cancer calls for compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/volunteer-firefighter-fighting-cancer-calls-for-compensation/106054572</link><description>Matthew Petch says firefighters like him are being left behind by an outdated compensation scheme and a lack of health screening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cdcb02a9468eb0fac75e6784d411e21</guid></item><item><title>Hannah Wilson has quit medicinal cannabis but has been relentlessly targeted by advertisements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/how-cannabis-companies-exploit-australias-legal-loopholes/106074556</link><description>Hannah Wilson says she found it shockingly easy to obtain a medicinal cannabis prescription, despite her history of schizophrenic psychosis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed85e20d31c6a635d841a3adababa780</guid></item><item><title>Formal complaint filed to FIFA over Gianni Infantino's peace prize awarded to US president Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/complaint-filed-to-fifa-over-peace-prize-awarded-to-donald-trump/106123358</link><description>A human rights organisation files an official complaint to FIFA over its peace prize awarded to US President Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e14bd5d331879d3b0f8004d5d410ade9</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian ministers access $45,000 in free NBL and AFL tickets in a year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/tas-gift-registry-for-politicians-published/106119614</link><description>Tasmanian government ministers have accessed more than $21,000 of free tickets to Tasmania JackJumpers games in the past 12 months, available as part of an agreement with the basketball club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ea0ae056c66fbc39dd6bff1d95c87c2</guid></item><item><title>Social media ban: Families, teens question new access and verification rules — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/social-ban-experts-blog-media-under-16/106118846</link><description>Ten major platforms are now expected to check the ages of all their Australian users and prevent anyone found to be under 16 from holding an account. Our experts have been answering your questions to help clear up confusion around the new access and verification rules. Look back on our live coverage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fda3457cf8713a8cb496b9c238627241</guid></item><item><title>Rare brain illness could not stop Milly from making country netball history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/milly-brock-tongala-netball-encephalitis/106098456</link><description>A rare brain illness left Milly Brock unable to walk or speak, but eight months later, she was back leading her regional netball club on grand final day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">821bba383f0020f9d6f99b0b9a15f322</guid></item><item><title>Sydney lawyer Sylvan Singh charged with alleged attempts to import drugs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/sydney-lawyer-sylvan-singh-charged-shooting-drug-importation/106123490</link><description>Solicitor Sylvan Singh, 26, is granted bail after being charged with four counts of attempting to import a commercial quantity of drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4d90537381dcbf1049bd12e1e2ea7b7</guid></item><item><title>In Data Dreams: Art and AI at the MCA, 10 artists explore the impact of AI on contemporary life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/data-dreams-art-and-ai-mca-sydney-christopher-kulendran-thomas/106115358</link><description>Can you tell what's real and what's fake online? Data Dreams: Art and AI at the MCA, featuring a Kim Kardashian deepfake, looks at the impact of AI on everyday life</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6da8bd58bdbf5d37f5aac827b55e6a1</guid></item><item><title>Union votes for correctional officers to continue strike, leaving prisoners in SA locked down indefinitely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/sa-prisons-remain-locked-down-indefinitely/106123454</link><description>The union representing correctional officers has voted to strike indefinitely, while officers who monitor 1,500 people on home detention will stop work for 24 hours</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de83151db4cfaac739301d3b4df83317</guid></item><item><title>Karen community keeps traditional sport of sepak takraw alive and kicking in Bendigo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/sepak-takraw-sport-connects-karen-refugees-bendigo/106114240</link><description>Karen and Karenni refugees in central Victoria are taking a traditional sport to the world championships and staying connected in the process.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a02849ca09108d493102694c09cd4b0d</guid></item><item><title>Dancing gorilla wins Comedy Wildlife Photo Awards 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/wildlife-comedy-photo-awards-winners-2025/106123480</link><description>The winning images pair talented nature photography with humour that often relies on capturing a moment at just the right time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50aafd52b8ccb489374be2add3c97440</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins returns as Australia names squad for third Ashes Test in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/cricket-pat-cummins-returns-australia-3rd-ashes-test-squad/106124238</link><description>Australia's captain is poised to make his return to the Ashes as Australia names its squad ahead of the third Test at the Adelaide Oval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c153466865a6d565b0c36df8cd289167</guid></item><item><title>Wells says 'gut reaction' to travel claims fair but she has 'upheld' rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/anika-wells-gut-reaction-travel-expense-rules/106118512</link><description>Communications and Sports Minister Anika Wells accepts her taxpayer-funded travel claims have prompted a "gut reaction" in people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b44d2a73090ecce02214e2201b1dfe7e</guid></item><item><title>Liverpool records Champions League win without Mohamed Salah amid public fallout with coach Arne Slot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/football-champions-league-wrap-salah-slot-liverpool-win/106123934</link><description>Liverpool coach Arne Slot picks up a crucial win against Inter Milan with his tenure on shaky ground amid a public fallout with his star winger Mohamed Salah.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c89422b7d8d41e1ddf25b4ebf161c809</guid></item><item><title>Man found 'hiding underwater' after Beenleigh fatal shooting charged with murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/qld-man-charged-with-murder-after-beenleigh-fatal-shooting/106124016</link><description>Police have charged 22-year-old Paul Tagirara over a fatal shooting in Beenleigh, south of Brisbane, earlier this month which claimed the life of a 35-year-old man.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">029ce655ad188b4cbebcc8652fb489d7</guid></item><item><title>Testing on supermarket imported honey finds some is not all honey</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/testing-finds-some-imported-honey-not-honey/106119344</link><description>Australian beekeepers are funding their own investigation into the authenticity of imported honey, with tests showing other products are being added.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a452fb7b1b2545a83a7b102f3a342b2</guid></item><item><title>Daniel Craig and director Rian Johnson on how they assemble the remarkable Knives Out cast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/daniel-craig-and-director-rian-johnson-on-how-they-assemb/106124508</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db427001260fdb1d9835b8beb97c8ede</guid></item><item><title>Crucial koala corridors are dwindling in Sydney's south-west, conservationists warn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/koala-corridors-under-threat-in-sydney-conservationists-warn/106099774</link><description>Key wildlife links between two of Sydney's major rivers are under threat from land clearing for housing, according to a koala conservation group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f91af6ff105daa364b7ab66152f69f9a</guid></item><item><title>Woman critically injured in alleged domestic violence attack in Sydney's south-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/nsw-woman-critically-injured-in-dv-incident-narellan-vale/106124450</link><description>A 36-year-old woman has been airlifted to Liverpool Hospital in critical condition. A man known to her has been charged with seven offences over the alleged attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ff88cf1e43581b0046f3499b607e3b2</guid></item><item><title>Mother whose son died after deliberately-lit house fire in Sydney says 'life is precious'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/arthur-haines-house-fire-manslaughter-mother-victim-impact/106124786</link><description>The mother of a teenager who was killed in a deliberately-lit house fire has told a Sydney court her son taught her "life is so precious" and she longed to be with him again for the rest of her days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db28f1e4f8b6f53849fe0a5cbf6f9a1c</guid></item><item><title>AI to be trialled at Royal Perth Hospital in bid to reduce pressure on WA health system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/wa-health-system-turns-to-ai-in-bid-to-free-up-doctors-nurses/106124964</link><description>A trial of artificial intelligence at Royal Perth Hospital is announced in an attempt to help health workers focus on patient care, as new data reveals WA's emergency departments are among the most stretched in the nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">916420c5a5be3e9614bebad33b7e6ec3</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste remembers Indonesian invasion 50 years after military assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/timor-leste-invasion-indonesia-anniversary/106118850</link><description>Survivors still have clear memories of the invasion by Indonesia, as Timor-Leste this week commemorates the beginning of a brutal 24-year occupation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb2d22cb023e1625be40a01636cd7005</guid></item><item><title>Star-studded cast of James Cameron's third Avatar film on what makes the movie series so special</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/star-studded-cast-of-james-cameron-s-third-avatar-film/106124758</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cbc9edb17d13ab3422fa7c0bc3c7c9f</guid></item><item><title>Taliban arrests young men in Afghanistan for Peaky Blinders dress-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/taliban-arrests-afghan-men-for-peaky-blinders-dress-up/106119104</link><description>Morality police in Afghanistan detain several influencers who have gone viral for dressing up as 1920s gangsters in the style of BBC series Peaky Blinders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b60e2a3095ffcf14564a6d30d3f6b72f</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne nutrition influencer died from postpartum haemorrhage after freebirth, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/stacey-warnecke-free-birth-death-coroner-investigates/106124514</link><description>A coroner's court has heard Melbourne nutrition influencer Stacey Warnecke died from a postpartum haemorrhage following a freebirth in September.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5cfcb104032fdb91e4e566b5242f6c8</guid></item><item><title>Police charge 16-year-old boy over fatal stabbing at Ascot Vale intersection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/detectives-arrest-teenager-following-ascot-vale-stabbing/106125282</link><description>Homicide detectives have charged a 16-year-old boy with murder three days after a 40-year-old man was found with stab wounds in Melbourne's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2b5fbcb1fa729673520c9d58e116bfe</guid></item><item><title>CFS firefighter Peter Curtis's 'great courage' remembered at funeral service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/cfs-firefighter-peter-curtis-remembered-at-funeral-service/106123650</link><description>Peter Curtis, who died at a bushfire ground on SA's Eyre Peninsula last month, has been remembered as a loving husband, father and grandfather, and a firefighter who "led from the front" and was a "bloody good bloke to have around".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4caa694bc7bc38cedf0419b7e3011d0</guid></item><item><title>Four more teenagers charged over stabbing at Ellenbrook Secondary College</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/ellenbrook-school-stabbing-three-more-teenagers-charged/106125770</link><description>A 10th teenager is charged over an alleged premeditated gang attack at Ellenbrook Secondary College on Monday that left a student with stab wounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3bdb120f5abcc8527b2d16b44b6ac22</guid></item><item><title>Stieglitz residents stay to defend homes amid bushfire near St Helens on Tasmania's east coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/st-helens-stieglitz-locals-praise-community-spirit-bushfires/106124180</link><description>As a bushfire rages on Tasmania's east coast, bayside resident Paul Worsteling shelters in his car, charging his phone while saltwater rains down on the roof.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">becb31f702320a39f9b429aefcc7cad1</guid></item><item><title>From peacekeeping in Timor-Leste to PTSD in Afghanistan: The beauty and terror of being an official war artist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/being-an-official-war-artist/106074572</link><description>Australia has been sending artists to the frontline since World War I, with more than 50 local artists taking part since then. But what's it actually like to head into war armed with a paintbrush?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0869c324d87322e512f070bec50429fd</guid></item><item><title>Bodycam vision shows initial police encounter with Luigi Mangione.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/bodycam-vision-shows-initial-police-encounter/106125496</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a27646895597dc3baa6ec0b2c9b7d9b6</guid></item><item><title>Alex Volkanovski hoses down retirement rumours ahead of first UFC title defence on Australian soil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/alex-volkanovski-ufc-325-diego-lopes-fight/106125956</link><description>Alex Volkanovski hoses down retirement rumours ahead of his first hometown fight in almost a decade with Australia's greatest ever UFC fighter aiming for another lengthy run defending the featherweight title.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75fbbb1fadea9b7e6985f043af6c40aa</guid></item><item><title>WA opposition blames police staffing levels for slow response to Boulder ambulance emergency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/wa-opposition-blames-police-numbers-for-slow-ambulance-response/106119620</link><description>The WA Liberals say a slow police response to a violent incident involving St John Ambulance officers in the Goldfields is due to understaffing but the claim has been rejected by the police minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89a501a2552c0abb67b6dad738e4d227</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's bushfire danger arrived suddenly. Here's how to prepare</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/tasmania-bushfire-preparation-explainer-what-to-do/106125742</link><description>Tasmania's bushfire season has suddenly arrived, with two catastrophes within days of each other. Here is how to prepare if one comes your way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b16253a54f55c77704f587d31bb4f7d</guid></item><item><title>Children as young as 10 could be fitted with ankle monitors under proposed Queensland laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/queensland-proposed-laws-crime-children-ankle-monitors/106126136</link><description>The legislation removes the requirement for either the child, or their parent or guardian, to consent to wearing the device.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5f1ff9a7a6110c8e573a7b919ca2410</guid></item><item><title>Defence briefs Pacific nations on China's naval flotilla but 'final destination' unknown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/australia-briefs-pacific-nations-chinese-navy-flotilla/106125002</link><description>Australian Defence officials have been briefing Pacific nations about the formidable capabilities and weaponry of a Chinese naval flotilla in the region, which the ADF is continuing to monitor closely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db439db52988340f905c0e260d1bb3ff</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle musician Taison Brockbank talks of flashbacks and pain after being set on fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/rap-musician-fight-back-tears-when-describing-being-set-on-fire/106125498</link><description>Newcastle rapper Taison Brockbank tells the court he nearly died after being set on fire during an attack in inner-city Newcastle in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b82af3830d8926fc3b46bb742adabf13</guid></item><item><title>Coroner finds police action 'inadequate' in lead-up to murder-suicide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/lynette-thompson-inquest-domestic-violence-murder-suicide/106119798</link><description>Lynette Thompson was set on fire by her partner who later committed suicide. A coroner wants NSW police to change their procedures in dealing with domestic violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ecc6cb1a56d684447a509949476c7c2</guid></item><item><title>Woman found dead in NSW police station car park feared she was being stalked, father says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/woman-found-dead-at-nsw-police-station-had-stalker-fear/106124756</link><description>According to her father, Kirsten Moriarty had lodged a stalking report prior to her body being found in a car outside a NSW police station.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24a959929e4d55bed5d0e15eb7e47eca</guid></item><item><title>Retailer Bed Bath N' Table wins High Court case against competitor House</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/bed-bath-n-table-high-court-win-house-similar-name/106125788</link><description>The stoush began in 2021 when the company House began opening new stores selling soft furnishings under the name House, Bed &amp; Bath.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e42f94bf6a8533b4e92049feb814fce</guid></item><item><title>Halls Creek man arrested after allegedly selling $45k worth of alcohol in dry WA communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/halls-creek-alcohol-sly-grogging-money-laundering-charge/106126488</link><description>The man allegedly bought large quantities of beer, champagne and rum in Darwin before selling it in WA's Kimberley region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2051a7f7ce917ea09a9f94d88ea4d89</guid></item><item><title>Teen's video diary on social media ban morning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/teens-video-diary-on-social-media-ban-morning/106126866</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d10543e40a5204d040f0e428b810b8eb</guid></item><item><title>Bail denied for 16-year-old accused of murdering Melbourne teenager Dau Akueng</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/cobblebank-stabbing-death-dau-akueng-chol-achiek-bail/106125272</link><description>A teen charged with the stabbing murder of a 15-year-old boy in Melbourne's west will remain in youth custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5bd34b36ffd93a333f427c3bac8eab6</guid></item><item><title>Victim statements redacted in 2014 fatal SA freeway crash court hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/south-eastern-freeway-fatal-crash-victim-impact-statements/106126356</link><description>The daughters of a man who died in a truck crash at the bottom of the South-Eastern Freeway in 2014 have their heavily redacted victim impact statements read aloud in court, more than 11 years after their father died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1dc19e37a9e8742d452e5c79fcaebad</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of men march against domestic violence in Alice Springs on Human Rights Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/hundreds-of-men-march-against-domestic-violence-alice-springs-/106126534</link><description>Up to 300 men — and a similar number of women — have taken part in the annual Ingkintja Men's March Against Domestic Violence under the slogan End the silence! Stop the violence! in Alice Springs, coinciding with the International Human Rights Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afb9de3eaad61b077c62d7b9feab54d1</guid></item><item><title>Age verification errors see some under-16s retain access to banned social media platforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/social-media-ban-day-one-teen-access/106126706</link><description>It's day one of the social media ban, but dozens of parents have told the ABC their children have already been able to get around the restrictions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24031d86565b1c6820fd19fd4b8bb05b</guid></item><item><title>New order banning supply of NSW North Coast green prawns a 'death knell' for industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/five-year-ban-on-nsw-raw-prawn-supply-due-to-white-spot-disease/106123412</link><description>White spot disease in prawns has led the NSW government to issue a new, five-year control order which will ban the sale of green prawns caught in affected waters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49297718e7446a4d6c754181c2e15c1d</guid></item><item><title>New crocodile management plan draws mixed response in north Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/north-queenslanders-split-over-new-crocodile-management-plan/106125448</link><description>The new management plan sees the expansion of crocodile removal zones across north and far north Queensland. Some say it will not increase safety without better community education.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d527c03e914a223eb5eb665d7dd0aa2</guid></item><item><title>Man found guilty of raping 76yo woman at Coffs Harbour aged care facility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/hayden-carl-skinner-guilty-of-raping-woman-at-aged-care-facility/106118594</link><description>Judge Michael McHugh finds Hayden Carl Skinner guilty of sexually assaulting a woman after breaking into a Coffs Harbour aged care facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9c3dfe96fd72e4892d8d2041a0f7c21</guid></item><item><title>Police discover remains while investigating 2014 disappearance of Melbourne toddler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/missing-toddler-remains-brookfield-victoria-police/106127540</link><description>Detectives have discovered what appear to be human remains while investigating the disappearance of a Melbourne toddler 11 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f766faaa59cca7afdffa0e118733055</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Supreme Court judge says burning Charlie Gander's body was a 'horrible thing to do'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/charlie-gander-murder-sentence-hearing/106123548</link><description>A Victorian Supreme Court judge says the destruction of 19-year-old Charlie Gander's body after his murder has added to the impact on his family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39907e0f8f2a2907cccd9b9d67e27913</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106127258</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e85aeff20efe1d71f9c55706e4551a44</guid></item><item><title>Hervey Bay residents successfully protect Torquay caravan park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/fraser-coast-council-retain-torquay-caravan-park/106127240</link><description>Fraser Coast Regional Council has decided to retain a beloved caravan park after thousands of locals fought to protect the site.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c087cb733f626d8f4494f95e3dd407d</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne expect to land former number one AFLW draft pick Kristie-Lee Weston-Turner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/north-melbourne-aflw-former-number-one-pick/106127740</link><description>North Melbourne have been unable to trade for Kristie-Lee Weston-Turner but the two-time defending AFLW premiers are still confident they'll secure the former number one draft pick.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ea6b8b1cac99bb7b87d916611cd573f</guid></item><item><title>Former specialist school worker strongly denies child sex abuse charges, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/endeavour-hills-sexual-assault-court/106125344</link><description>The former staffer of a school for children with disabilities vigorously denies child sex abuse allegations, a court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a7ef6bcac422f27cd3baeee08496d4a</guid></item><item><title>Climate crisis is threatening disabled Australians' access to nature</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/climate-crisis-access-to-nature-disability/106116294</link><description>From bushfires and decreasing air quality to flooding and erosion, climate change is threatening our relationship with nature, and people with disability are being disproportionately impacted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e6030aecdfc7bd4bfb090bffc4c8061</guid></item><item><title>At least 22 killed in collapse of two buildings in Morocco, state news agency says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/people-killed-in-collapse-of-two-buildings-in-morocco/106127820</link><description>Two adjacent four-storey buildings home to eight families collapsed during the night, the country's state news agency says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92bd56a8fa8414d90108a0b6e7481e91</guid></item><item><title>Inquest into toddler's septic tank death sparks calls for improved maintenance in remote NT public housing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/septic-tank-death-kumanjayi-fly-public-housing-coronial-inquest/106118886</link><description>Aboriginal housing advocates are calling for urgent improvements to the way remote public housing is maintained in the Northern Territory, after the coroner found the death of a toddler who fell into a backyard septic tank could have been prevented.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">caec77585ea2e595da2a95f4e9e2f192</guid></item><item><title>Australia records highest number of Indigenous deaths in custody since 1979</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/largest-number-of-indigenous-deaths-in-custody-since-1979/106121828</link><description>Australia has recorded the highest number of Indigenous deaths in custody since 1979. Experts say over-incarceration remains a national crisis and prisons are neglecting the physical and mental health of vulnerable people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beaf475b8b27faa178ef96c69cf1409b</guid></item><item><title>Marco Rubio orders US State Department to revert to Times New Roman font, calling Calibri adoption 'wasteful'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/us-state-department-reverts-times-new-roman-font/106127732</link><description>In a leaked internal cable, Secretary of State Marco Rubio calls the department's decision to adopt Calibri in 2023 a "wasteful" diversity move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f98705a0075c776b00b9cb6290441f9</guid></item><item><title>US backs Japan in dispute with China over radar incident as tensions escalate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/us-backs-japan-in-dispute-with-china-over-radar-incident/106128020</link><description>China and Japan have given differing accounts of the incident, which was a major escalation in tensions between the two nations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f7c862084fd730289846293bc733530</guid></item><item><title>Nearly 200 children conceived from sperm donor with increased cancer risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/children-conceived-from-sperm-with-cancer-risk/106128026</link><description>Between 2006 and 2022, the man's sperm was sold to 67 clinics in 14 countries, whereas 99 children were fathered by the donor in Denmark alone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cd952c66ea268a278bb59c7d05297ca</guid></item><item><title>US plans to order foreign tourists, including Australians, to disclose social media histories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/white-house-plans-social-media-requirement-visa-exempt-countries/106128022</link><description>Applicants would also have to submit phone numbers, email addresses, personal details of family members and biometric information under the plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91b5c6ed58ba5307414ebb7f60b53bb4</guid></item><item><title>Half a million people flee Thailand–Cambodia border conflict as Trump moves to intervene again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/half-a-million-people-flee-thailand-cambodia-border-conflict/106128158</link><description>Thailand has rejected Donald Trump's plan to call both sides to achieve peace, with half a million people forced to flee the fighting along the border.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2187d0404028679ddc4bb7ef75216c4e</guid></item><item><title>Sophie Kinsella, author of the best-selling Shopaholic novels, dies at 55</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/sophie-kinsella-author-of-shopaholic-book-series-dies-aged-55/106128174</link><description>Kinsella, who also published under her real name, Madeleine Wickham, announced in April 2024 that she had been diagnosed in late 2022 with glioblastoma, an aggressive form of brain cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5df3ad8902d66540f2d3c6b1a47afb4</guid></item><item><title>Democracies must fight for freedom, Nobel Peace Prize laureate Machado says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/democracies-must-fight-for-freedom-nobel-peace-prize-machado/106128196</link><description>Democracies must be prepared to fight for freedom in order to survive, Nobel Peace Prize laureate and Venezuelan opposition leader María Corina Machado says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a802fb115dd97304b5ad35f3a4d04cf9</guid></item><item><title>Formula 1 quiz: How much do you remember from the 2025 season?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/formula-1-quiz-test-your-2025-season-knowledge-oscar-piastri/106124134</link><description>After 24 grand prix and plenty of champagne, the Formula 1 2025 World Championship is over. But between all the races and rivalries, points and penalties — how much do you remember?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81eb62d04ff26dd2500736d5c77b76fc</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 11: How a van full of armed men and millions of dollars inspired Goodfellas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/today-in-history-december-11-lufthansa-heist/106116722</link><description>It has been almost 50 years since armed men burst into the Lufthansa cargo terminal at New York's John F Kennedy International Airport and got away with stealing millions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa60e0fd4333897c002bc02951aff74a</guid></item><item><title>Landmark case aims to force betting agencies to return gambled stolen millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/case-seeks-to-recover-gambled-stolen-millions-from-bookmakers/106127214</link><description>A landmark legal case against three of Australia's biggest online betting agencies has been filed in the Federal Court, aimed at recovering millions of dollars' worth of stolen money that was gambled away and kept by corporate bookmakers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdbffe5eb41d9639002ebac899132190</guid></item><item><title>Meta ran ads for bond scheme run by GIM Trading that allegedly defrauded millions from investors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/meta-ads-gim-trading-alleged-bond-scam/106077848</link><description>Tech giant Meta ran advertisements used to lure Australian investors into a fraudulent bond scheme that allegedly defrauded tens of millions of dollars from them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bae24be29737c8b1263ca154a35d4a2</guid></item><item><title>Nationals MP's high family travel bill highlights generous rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/nationals-mps-high-family-travel-bill-highlights-generous-rules/106126842</link><description>Calls for politicians' family travel entitlements to be tightened are growing, as analysis shows one Nationals MP was allowed to charge taxpayers more than $80,000 to fly his spouse to and from Canberra 27 times in two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7e02c292ccefc5d6bca00c1bf777cbb</guid></item><item><title>Australia's energy rule-maker calls for 'Netflix-like' power charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/aemc-calls-for-netflix-like-power-charges-in-major-overhaul/106128042</link><description>Australians' electricity bills have become a nightmare of complexity and high prices. An energy regulator says subscription fees could be an answer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b932288f47de30e7aa6d8804e28b922b</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's bushfires may be an indication of what's to come this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/tasmania-summer-bushfire-drivers-and-outlook-bom/106126762</link><description>Just days into summer, Tasmania is battling bushfires and their presence can be linked back to a rare spike in temperatures above Antarctica back in September.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc7f21634c642fd281ef2a19b45bb506</guid></item><item><title>Why Ashton Hurn may, or may not, succeed as SA Liberal leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/ashton-hurn-vs-peter-malinauskas-election/106115114</link><description>Ashton Hurn now has the job she said she didn't want. Could she be the leader the South Australian Liberal Party needs?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09d86e9573dbb3d47b5534e04b272ccf</guid></item><item><title>Third time is the charm as long-running soap opera Neighbours wraps up, again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/tv-neighbours-ends-again/106127164</link><description>After more than 40 years on air, the final credits will roll on the iconic soap Neighbours — again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9294b4c1ba5afc18d168fbb6beb71c5a</guid></item><item><title>NSW government acquires two outback stations to convert into national parks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/corinya-and-tasman-stations-to-be-converted-into-national-parks/106125500</link><description>Two outback stations 800 kilometres west of Sydney are purchased by the state government in an effort to protect the environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e08563b4690939a2d3bb0a924a889be</guid></item><item><title>Australia's education system 'highly segregated' says former minister Susan Close</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/susan-close-on-socio-economic-divide-in-schools/106126084</link><description>South Australia's former deputy premier Susan Close has called out what she describes as "extreme" socio-economic segregation in Australian schools.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0a681652a4d06ad13dadca8a80d4be4</guid></item><item><title>Australia's grand social media experiment is finally live. Teens say nothing has changed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/social-media-ban-under-16s-day-one/106120020</link><description>After a year of waiting, Australia's world-leading laws to block kids from accessing social media are officially enacted. But the teens they're meant to impact say not much has actually changed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">605110735879eabae4a76f4e3ea6f4d8</guid></item><item><title>Australia's strategic fleet tender stalls amid growing maritime vulnerabilities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/delay-in-national-marine-strategic-fleet/106121772</link><description>Australia's long-promised strategic fleet tender is delayed, raising concerns over the nation's maritime resilience and skills pipeline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">734021665b72b27a2e31f4fa3009b052</guid></item><item><title>Fears of 'another Cronulla riot' 20 years on from violence at beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/fears-of-another-cronulla-riot-20-years-on-from-sydney-fights/106120526</link><description>Two decades on from the racially-fuelled brawls at Cronulla, experts warn something similar could happen amid anti-immigration rhetoric.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">530eb8b1f8a7882b31e610972e8f7881</guid></item><item><title>Households now need six-figure income to comfortably rent in any capital city</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/qld-rental-prices-data-six-figure-income/106126784</link><description>The average income needed to comfortably rent a median-priced home in any Australian capital city is now more than $112,000, according to new analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0f4eb594289999d4b1f9675bab6d71c</guid></item><item><title>National Library of Australia reveals its treasures with exhibition showcasing books from throughout history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/national-library-australia-exhibition-reveals-treasures/106126192</link><description>The NLA has more than 10 million items, but they are all in storage. Now a new exhibition reveals a selection of its hidden treasures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">225fb88ccc28e7fd81c2aa21f6d60d91</guid></item><item><title>Mildura man Jordan Stewart Blair found guilty of rape, brutal assault of woman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/jordan-stewart-blair-guilty-of-rape-assault/106112222</link><description>Mildura man Jordan Stewart Blair has been found guilty of sexually assaulting a woman less than a day after he viciously bashed her in May, 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e536157fa64eab48041ce39ea4e8375</guid></item><item><title>US Republicans and Democrats push for Australian-style kids' social media ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/us-republicans-democrats-praise-australias-u16-social-media-ban/106128242</link><description>As Australians under 16 lose their social media accounts, influential Republicans and Democrats are pushing the US Congress to consider a similar ban for children under 13.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">203e1f6da89e43fe3b2617333f18dddd</guid></item><item><title>Guilty verdict brings end to seven-year wait for justice over Toyah Cordingley's 2018 murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/guilty-verdict-ends-seven-year-wait-justice-toyah-cordingley/105427012</link><description>The 24-year-old is remembered for her generous spirit and love of animals. It took a protracted effort to bring her killer back to Australia and before a court, during which time he revealed little emotion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db8cd2a8ad9712c472f3ea1c9e1aa852</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka adamant 'Battle of the Sexes' clash against Nick Kyrgios will help women's tennis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/tennis-aryna-sabalenka-nick-kyrgios-defend-polarising-match/106128302</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka is adamant her upcoming clash against Nick Kyrgios will not prove to be a gimmick that damages women's tennis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4923bb3d0bc8d79da189a795d6da956</guid></item><item><title>Cabinet ministers debate whether gas reservation plan can cut power prices as hoped</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/gas-reservation-power-price-fears/106125184</link><description>A long-awaited scheme to force east coast energy giants to set aside gas for Australian use is being finalised in down-to-the-wire negotiations between half a dozen cabinet ministers grappling with concerns it may not lower prices as much as hoped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">863c406b91f7e9e36fe01e9992b3f2b5</guid></item><item><title>National Anti-Corruption Commission chief updates official declaration of interests to disclose defence link</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/nacc-chief-updates-official-declaration/106126738</link><description>National Anti-Corruption Commission chief Paul Brereton formally discloses his consulting work for the defence watchdog after the ABC reveals the links.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d086faaba53f92740d46dcb677157195</guid></item><item><title>'Zombie-proof' EV ad tops complaints list as social media cases rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/the-most-complained-about-ads-of-2025/106105394</link><description>As more businesses look to do their own advertising, audience complaints for social media ads are growing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3859fe975c24dd1d54d1615daa78299f</guid></item><item><title>Markets live updates: ASX off highs, RBA interest rate hike expectations on the rise after mixed jobs report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/asx-markets-business-live-news-dec-11-2025/106128346</link><description>Market pricing for a February rate hike is on the up after the unemployment rate remained steady at 4.3 per cent, while fewer people have been in work or looking for a job. Meanwhile, APRA is taking action against super giant HESTA. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6528d38e5edbcfd547a1f22d0a1824a8</guid></item><item><title>Seasonal conditions lead to supersized strawberries in Australian stores</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/supersized-large-stawberries-in-australia/106120026</link><description>Seasonal conditions are leading to big berries this summer, with the fruit on the larger side in some regions because of a wetter spring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f94adb5d206a0c79c684f67387fce243</guid></item><item><title>US seizes oil tanker off coast of Venezuela, Donald Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/us-seizes-oil-tanker-off-coast-of-venezuela/106128382</link><description>US President Donald Trump says the tanker is "the largest one ever seized".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df8042715ed4912de309799be119c949</guid></item><item><title>Murray River water thieves hit with $558,000 fine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/david-littore-jindalee-road-wines-water-theft/106124764</link><description>Jindalee Road Wines and its former manager have been penalised $558,000 for illegally tapping into an irrigation pipeline and stealing water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d3c35e88314dc643b4f56233b142cd3</guid></item><item><title>Federal Court hears bid from Regis Resources to overturn protection order that stopped McPhillamys Gold Mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/regis-resources-bid-overturn-nsw-gold-mine-protection-order/106123596</link><description>Regis Resources argues the federal environment department was "uncritical" in accepting evidence about a First Nations Dreaming story that led to its proposed gold project being halted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d92a43c5ba9086c9d1d582cb8395d195</guid></item><item><title>Tiwi Islands become 700,000-hectare Indigenous Protected Area under federal agreement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/nt-tiwi-islands-becomes-indigenous-protected-area-ipa/106126788</link><description>The agreement with the federal government sees the Tiwi Islands included in Australia's national parks and reserves system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15956b1a0b81e5bb1868c3a086c4fabd</guid></item><item><title>Why WA's housing crisis is proving a roadblock to easing family and domestic violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/wa-housing-crisis-is-a-roadblock-to-dv-victims/106127682</link><description>The WA government is talking up its efforts to stamp out domestic and family violence, but there is one fundamental roadblock to alleviating the situation for women in crisis, and that is the state's housing crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38986bea311fba1f1a8a0a102c475fc2</guid></item><item><title>Woman dies in house fire in Elizabeth Vale</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/72yo-woman-dies-in-house-fire-at-elizabeth-vale/106128448</link><description>Firefighters called to a large blaze at a house in Adelaide's north find the body of a 72-year-old woman inside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51bd4799c12a205ab70616c7a016b96f</guid></item><item><title>Flare activated in residential backyard during extreme bushfire warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/flare-fire-resident-geraldton/106102690</link><description>A woman in WA's Midwest says she found a lit flare in her backyard in the early hours of the morning during extreme bushfire conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1587f0c3e44c2d84c39dda8e78948c4c</guid></item><item><title>Greg Lynn's murder conviction set aside, new trial ordered — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/live-blog-greg-lynn-high-country-appeal-court/106124374</link><description>Greg Lynn has had his conviction for the murder of Carol Clay set aside by Victoria's Court of Appeal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">713e7fef41c022b28587f1909512686e</guid></item><item><title>Egypt and Iran complain to FIFA over potential LGBTQ+ pride match at World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/football-egypt-iran-complain-fifa-over-world-cup-pride-match/106128348</link><description>Iran and Egypt's group stage clash at next year's FIFA World Cup in Seattle is set to be a celebration of LGBTQ+ pride, and both federations are not happy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9067be37645d23b6f582902d41be1550</guid></item><item><title>Mount Isa inquest into the three-year disappearance of Tallis Ahfat concludes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/tallis-ahfat-disappearance-inquest-mount-isa/106095296</link><description>The inquest into a man missing in Queensland's north-west for the past three years has heard CCTV footage at a drug dealer's home from the night of the disappearance had been erased.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adbbd9fc64b7accb35521613a32df6c9</guid></item><item><title>Threat eases from Stieglitz bushfire near St Helens on Tasmania's east coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/tasmania-st-helens-stieglitz-fire-threat-eases-road-reopening/106128334</link><description>Firefighters are hoping to reopen the road to residents of a bushfire-struck community on Tasmania's east coast today, as the fire between Dianas Basin and Stieglitz is brought under control.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">771055f203fc1c8421dd97504bd5a741</guid></item><item><title>Man attempted to abduct child outside Hobart Domain playground, police investigate white van</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/child-approached-by-stanger-in-hobart-domain-area/106128418</link><description>A man wearing a medical mask, sunglasses and bandages attempted to usher a primary school child into his van near a Hobart playground, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">552d115d07b322728d04acd45e20ede3</guid></item><item><title>Half Big Brother, half late-night talk show: The WNBA stars revolutionising sports media</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/wnba-studbudz-natisha-hiedeman-courtney-williams-sport-marketing/106090546</link><description>The WNBA's 'StudBudz' are using live streaming to build a brand and community, while providing lessons in marketing women's sports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cd56cfc0c9fbc505e1e9c6f24777a14</guid></item><item><title>Phillip Island business community fights to keep the MotoGP on track</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/phillip-island-motogp-contract-extension-business-cowes-san-remo/105802952</link><description>The MotoGP has been held on Victoria's Phillip Island for almost 30 years, but the community fears it could be lost when its contract expires next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">678d6675e88808db68b6c44b35b4bb60</guid></item><item><title>Greg Lynn's murder conviction for death of High Country camper Carol Clay quashed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/greg-lynn-appeal-decision-high-country-camper/106128570</link><description>Former Jetstar pilot Greg Lynn has had his conviction for the murder of retiree Carol Clay overturned by Victoria's Court of Appeal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50db3535022f96b757cf6a5962cf132c</guid></item><item><title>Nicole Kidman to co-chair Met Gala with Beyoncé, Venus Williams and Anna Wintour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/nicole-kidman-beyonce-venus-williams-chair-met-gala/106128614</link><description>The museum also announced a gala host committee, chaired by designer Anthony Vaccarello and filmmaker Zoë Kravitz.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eac6c7a5126cc2aca138e618c40905d8</guid></item><item><title>AUKUS ministers meet in Washington as Hegseth praises Australia for 'stepping up'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/aukus-submarine-project-on-track-richard-marles-says/106128670</link><description>The defence minister insists the AUKUS program is on track to provide Australia with nuclear-powered submarines in the next decade — despite the delays plaguing shipbuilding programs in both the US and the UK.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d156d1724b200e852ed8945aec05c7cc</guid></item><item><title>Greg Lynn arrives at court for appeal decision</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/greg-lynn-arrives-at-court-for-appeal-decision/106128928</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">684b5ba1950dc8f14c30fe8960826a92</guid></item><item><title>Walter Sofronoff loses appeal against finding he engaged in corrupt conduct during inquiry into Bruce Lehrmann's prosecution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/walter-sofronoff-loses-appeal-against-corruption-finding/106126878</link><description>The man who led the inquiry into the criminal prosecution of Bruce Lehrmann loses his appeal to have serious corruption findings against him overturned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d23e60051e9d89e5f5b4b02e819cf382</guid></item><item><title>US authorities seize Venezuela oil tanker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/us-authorities-seize-venezuela-oil-tanker/106128742</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a31913eac113556360db67ab47e0eaf7</guid></item><item><title>Michigan fires football coach Sherrone Moore over 'inappropriate relationship' with staffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/michigan-football-coach-sherrone-moore-fired-staffer-scandal/106128866</link><description>Sherrone Moore's rollercoaster tenure with Michigan comes to an end midway through its second season as the college shows zero tolerance for his actions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cfba8bc214c7876a27b4b7b804d381f</guid></item><item><title>Italian food given UNESCO status</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/italian-food-given-unesco-status/106129008</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">059095b74cf5f659902772666aa377be</guid></item><item><title>SA courts close amid escalating dispute over correctional services pay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/courts-close-amid-escalating-pay-dispute-over-prison-staff-pay/106128312</link><description>Strike action involving prison officers has again escalated, forcing the closure of SA's major courts and causing disruptions to case hearings, which will now be rescheduled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7ca7e18e36096f2c902a696849898e8</guid></item><item><title>Superannuation giant HESTA hit with extra licence restrictions as APRA raises governance, risk concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/super-fund-hesta-hit-with-extra-conditions-apra-governance-risk/106128664</link><description>APRA says the fallout of HESTA's planned outage led to a "severe, prolonged disruption" that caused direct harm to some of its 1.1 million members, in a damning assessment of the fund.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35554f5c84bc7088fdb2609c8d5613dc</guid></item><item><title>Collingwood employee resigns after alcohol-fuelled incident at Alice Springs training camp</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/afl-collingwood-employee-resigns-alcohol-fuelled-incident/106128612</link><description>A Collingwood employee hands in his resignation following an incident on an interstate trip that required an investigation by the club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21f893a5d3a036c1e738cb694cfb4f8b</guid></item><item><title>ACCC opposes sale of RAC WA's insurance arm to Sydney-based IAG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/accc-opposes-sale-of-racwa-to-sydney-company-iag/106128754</link><description>The Australian Competition and Consumer Commission finds IAG's proposed acquisition of RAC WA would "eliminate the significant competition" between the two major insurance companies and likely result in higher premiums.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3690b642d2949473d2562499f335689</guid></item><item><title>Critical incident declared as stolen ute crashes in Liverpool after police pursuit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/liverpool-crash-police-pursuit-critical-incident/106129344</link><description>A critical incident has been declared after a teenage boy led police on a pursuit and crashed into several cars in Western Sydney last night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84900d5af985e19afb257875cba79a82</guid></item><item><title>Australia's unemployment rate remains at 4.3 per cent, but underemployment surges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/australia-unemployment-rate-november-2025/106129300</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate holds steady at 4.3 per cent in November, but the underemployment rate jumps to 12-month high.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1516dc0d7c467b531207223b29f02c64</guid></item><item><title>This Grand Designs Australia house cost $320k to build. Here's how its owners pulled it off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/grand-designs-cheap-house-320k-how-couple-did-it/106102674</link><description>Bespoke architectural builds on small budgets may seem like an impossible housing dream, but James and Rita managed to turn their vision into a reality — without breaking the bank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1959b70829d84196ecd189375f3325da</guid></item><item><title>Bureau of Meteorology makes major changes to $96.5m website after refresh backlash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/weather-bureau-updates-new-website-after-critisicm/106128956</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology has updated the rain radar, temperature information and warning displays on its new website in response to public feedback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b3801ebd5ac3764a1b79ef836e78a63</guid></item><item><title>Aussie travellers who criticise US most at risk as Trump administration proposes social media disclosures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/us-travel-social-media-privacy-concerns/106128910</link><description>Australians travelling to the United States could soon face an unprecedented invasion of privacy, an international law expert has warned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61166d67d8b553711c2276287271feff</guid></item><item><title>Italian cooking and its rituals get United Nations designation as World Heritage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/italian-cooking-and-rituals-recognised-by-unesco/106129504</link><description>Already loved around the world for its palate-pleasing tastes, UNESCO has now added the rituals surrounding Italian food preparation and consumption to its list of the world's traditional practices and expressions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14ed96ff5eeafa5a64158ddeaafd999c</guid></item><item><title>Call for youth curfew in Tennant Creek after cars stolen, businesses damaged</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/tennant-creek-business-calls-for-youth-curfew/106124142</link><description>A business owner has called for a youth curfew in Tennant Creek, after a weekend crime spree involving the theft of multiple cars, rams raids and a police chase through the Northern Territory town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">534f4d730fd3638207cce9bdca2259a7</guid></item><item><title>Four French nationals charged with stealing $10 million in luxury items from Canberra home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/french-nationals-charged-burglary-10-million-canberra-home/106129586</link><description>Police allege the men travelled to Australia to rob a Canberra home, stealing distinctive, luxury items.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c55d53a719157d8ddc067fdceb438799</guid></item><item><title>Iceland becomes fifth country to boycott Eurovision 2026 over Israeli participation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/iceland-not-participating-in-eurovison-2026/106128592</link><description>Iceland has joined Ireland, the Netherlands, Spain and Slovenia in boycotting the competition in protest against Israel's participation in the song contest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">202f76c005b4117588c215f1ac71821b</guid></item><item><title>AC Milan Serie A Perth soccer game in serious doubt amid FIFA roadblock</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/ac-milan-serie-a-perth-soccer-game-in-trouble-rita-saffioti-fifa/106129592</link><description>Plans to host seven-time European champions AC Milan in Perth for an Italian league game are in trouble, with growing concerns soccer's global governing body will not sign off on the event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4f29263e2e479f6c6974d076a7c091f</guid></item><item><title>Council investigates mould, food safety complaints at Civeo Coppabella mining camp</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/isaac-council-investigates-complaints-civeo-coppabella/106128686</link><description>Isaac Regional Council says it is looking into multiple claims about a fly-in, fly-out camp capable of housing more than 3,000 workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0189961ee7be0b9ce9b6da5155f87a8</guid></item><item><title>Abercrombie &amp; Fitch ex-CEO Michael Jeffries fit to stand trial on sex trafficking charges, prison officials say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/abercrombie-fitch-michael-jeffries-fit-to-stand-trial/106130406</link><description>Former Abercrombie &amp; Fitch boss Michael Jeffries, who is part of a trio accused of luring men to drug-fuelled parties with the promise of modelling jobs, is facing federal sex trafficking charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a06b10ec457c5dbbdacea0c84a0c5b6d</guid></item><item><title>Sentence handed to Darwin fatal hit-and-run driver Jake Danby 'shocked public consciousness', appeal hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/darwin-hit-and-run-driver-jake-danby-prosecution-appeal-reserved/106124686</link><description>The NT Court of Criminal Appeal has heard an appeal against the sentence for a 24-year-old driver who avoided a jail sentence after hitting two Aboriginal pedestrians with his vehicle, killing one, and then boasting about it over text.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4025212876e9275aa51fea604bffd7c</guid></item><item><title>PM distances himself from politician spending rules amid Anika Wells controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/pm-distances-himself-from-politician-spending-rules-anika-wells/106130760</link><description>Pressed on whether his government should review the rules that allow politicians to fly their families around the country in business class, the prime minister says his focus is on the social media ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">daea64309046e0955b2f7c7122665131</guid></item><item><title>States lash Commonwealth's revised public hospital funding offer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/albanese-offers-extra-funding-for-public-hospitals/106130754</link><description>The prime minister wrote to states and territories this week, upping the Commonwealth's offer for public hospital funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81a7feea6b061580a3e2b8c23982ed32</guid></item><item><title>The Golden Spurtle takes audiences into the heart of the World Porridge Making Championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/the-golden-spurtle-porridge-making-championship-documentary/106118710</link><description>Every year, the Scottish town of Carrbridge hosts a porridge competition. Its contestants and chieftain are larger than life and celebrated in the new Aussie documentary The Golden Spurtle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12ad0434302f24dc80fd695083ecdc14</guid></item><item><title>The two Navy officers breaking ground, heading towards Winter Paralympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/navy-officers-breaking-ground-towards-winter-paralympics/106126742</link><description>It has been 20 years since Australia sent a biathlete to the Winter Paralympics, but two serving Navy personnel are hoping to change this.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51d23b79d9fb3944846f47d09d70d0b7</guid></item><item><title>Coalition agrees to sweeping changes to NSW workers' compensation scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/workers-compensation-scheme-changes-coalition-kellie-sloane/106129434</link><description>NSW Opposition Leader Kellie Sloane says changes to the state's workers' compensation scheme are an important "reset".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7bc0b41a8aaabca09dc7bc682b92037</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic science and logistics given $208m federal funding boost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/antarctic-science-and-logistics-given-208-million-funding-boost/106130794</link><description>The federal government has announced more than $200 million in additional funding over the next seven years for Antarctic science and logistics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec45dc9da2fbe532cb1d7bb4cc378f8f</guid></item><item><title>Blackwater massage therapist Donovan Webb charged with additional sexual assault offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/blackwater-masseuse-donovan-webb-charged-with-sexual-assault/106130814</link><description>Blackwater massage therapist Donovan Webb has been charged with a further 40 counts of sexual assault alleged to have taken place during massage therapy sessions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b56008589ec5c4d75baa46e402c8563</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested for alleged murder of father-of-two Chris Robertson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/lonsdale-alleged-murder-arrest/106131440</link><description>Police have arrested a 30-year-old man for the alleged murder of Adelaide father-of-two Christopher Robertson, who was found dead in a Lonsdale workshop in September.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc8679b4efb2bc0c83388052adeecb88</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Police investigate death at Townsville's Riverway Lagoon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/police-investigate-death-at-townsville-riverway-lagoon/106131338</link><description>A 39-year-old man has died after found unresponsive and pulled from a public pool in Townsville about 11am on Thursday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54a2d85fcc8e6fd968760712ea44e92b</guid></item><item><title>Australian hooker Harry Grant awarded rugby league Golden Boot for 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/harry-grant-golden-boot-australia-dylan-brown/106131732</link><description>New Zealand's Dylan Brown seemed a certainty to claim the Golden Boot as rugby league's best international player for 2025 but the Kiwi five-eighth has missed out in a stunning twist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6805ac76cd4379fd23324a09498cabc3</guid></item><item><title>Sixth person charged with murder over stabbing of Gordon Kessey in Bega</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/shoalhaven-man-tehata-hapuku-charged-over-alleged-bega-murder/106129076</link><description>Tehata Hapuku has been named as the sixth person charged over the fatal stabbing of Nowra man Gordon Kessey near a park in Bega on the NSW far south coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99605fc1b80669384300cfdf48c1dade</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government moves to lift ban on political donations from property developers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/political-donations-qld-property-developers/106130862</link><description>The attorney-general said the proposed laws would level the political playing field, labelling the ban as a "gerrymander" by the former Labor government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c49306a158c5f48a15cc52eee8051bcc</guid></item></channel></rss>