<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 10:47:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How Brisbane's culture of empowerment has allowed its youngsters to be fearless on the AFL's biggest stage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/afl-brisbane-lions-empowerment-youngsters-grand-final/105833746</link><description>Brisbane's youngest players rise to the occasion on the biggest stage, led by its 21-year-old Norm Smith medallist Will Ashcroft. Here's how the two-time premiers allow their kids to thrive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c817f23b0eba7b31b09a29d4859ec37</guid></item><item><title>Geelong is known for its accessibility on Mad Monday, but Bailey Smith's posts have unravelled years of goodwill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/geelong-mad-monday-analysis-goodwill-unravels/105833790</link><description>Geelong forged years of goodwill via its accessibility to Mad Monday — now the club faces a mess that it never saw coming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb01a53a558c07a149255170f2a7537a</guid></item><item><title>Missing boy's family releases statement as search continues in mid-north SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/missing-4yo-boy-family-release-statement/105834906</link><description>The devastated family of a missing four-year-old boy has released a statement saying it is holding on to hope "he will be found and returned safely" as authorities and community members continue the search in mid-north South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7906f16cd7afb2eb27bc054e9012f08b</guid></item><item><title>'Complex' brief of evidence after group charged with stealing crocodile eggs from Kakadu National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/nt-unauthorised-taking-crocodile-eggs-kakadu-national-park/105834370</link><description>Four men, including a pilot who survived a fatal chopper crash in 2022, are facing Commonwealth charges for allegedly stealing saltwater crocodile eggs from Kakadu National Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0304fdecbe772deca4891e4a06f31fe9</guid></item><item><title>Stolen WWII ledger returned to St Luke's church in Toowoomba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/st-lukes-toowoomba-stolen-wwii-ledger-found/105831060</link><description>The historic ledger, which bears the names of Toowoomba locals who served in WWII, went missing a month ago, but now it is back in safe hands thanks to a string of unlikely coincidences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8961c39443bc027c4a2c1ae8b7abdd58</guid></item><item><title>Australia ready to defend Women's Cricket World Cup trophy in India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/australia-ready-to-defend-women-s-cricket-world-cup-india/105835898</link><description>Australia's all-conquering generation of women's cricketers has one last Cricket World Cup feat to tick off, setting their sights on defying almost 40 years of history to win back-to-back ODI tournaments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4f0edc1a54eab871471c231f8d5855d</guid></item><item><title>West Coast Eagles handed extra draft pick, four rookie list spots to help climb up ladder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/west-coast-eagles-priority-pick-afl-assistance-package/105836060</link><description>The West Coast Eagles are handed an extra first-round draft pick and four additional rookie list spots from the AFL, in a bid to help the ailing club return to competitiveness after four dismal years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9feff746910248fecc11a86219cb423d</guid></item><item><title>Speaking to others without kids helped me find a future after IVF</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/sashi-perera-finding-joy-after-stopping-ivf/105735290</link><description>The more people I spoke to, the less frightened I felt of my future. I could shift my focus to what I can do because I don't have a kid, instead of what I was missing out on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b4f48fad02df065f9a736939478d498</guid></item><item><title>Jessica Ann Walker among trio accused of murdering Jayden Selfe in Attadale</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/jessica-ann-walker-accused-murder-jayden-selfe/105831694</link><description>Pictured riding on a luxury boat and posing on the deck of a multi-million-dollar home with sweeping views of the Swan River, life appeared good for Jessica Ann Walker in 2022 — but just three years later she would be charged with murdering a man.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bee22e867fede4d5afda761e4fe5161b</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm and Brisbane Broncos name NRL grand finals teams, NRLW teams announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/melbourne-storm-brisbane-broncos-nrl-grand-final-teams/105836192</link><description>Brisbane Broncos' mid-year recruit Ben Talty has been dropped for this Sunday's NRL grand final, making way for the returning Pat Carrigan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b139d1c93ffd07d1815afdf4c95d2f09</guid></item><item><title>Rescuers search for missing students after Indonesian school collapses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/rescuers-search-for-missing-students-after/105836782</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e4c38a84fcb1e7d43df1f20332c5006</guid></item><item><title>Kash Patel gave New Zealand officials 3D-printed guns illegal to possess under local laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/kash-patel-gave-new-zealand-officials-3d-printed-guns/105836578</link><description>On a visit to New Zealand in July, FBI Director Kash Patel presented three senior security officials with 3D-printed guns that were later destroyed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bf94ff62ee2982a0d805eadf8a4de47</guid></item><item><title>Nicole Kidman and Keith Urban separate after 19 years of marriage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/nicole-kidman-and-keith-urban-separation/105833442</link><description>A source close to the couple tells the ABC the separation was not a mutual decision, saying it was Urban's decision to leave the relationship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e81cf0bb0bb7525617787a8a43998838</guid></item><item><title>Clean-up underway after 'devastating' industrial spill in Far North Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/clean-up-underway-after-boral-spill-at-smiths-creek-in-cairns/105835936</link><description>Building company Boral works to clean up thousands of litres of kerosene and bitumen that have spilled into a creek in Cairns, connecting to an inlet that leads to the Great Barrier Reef.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a973536937e2bf9984291a17c0344987</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds gather in Morwell to remember life of 18-year-old Kaiden Morgan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/kaiden-morgan-memorial-morwell/105835204</link><description>Friends and family have gathered in Victoria's east to remember the life of a beloved young man who died in an alleged attack on the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6d85845fd60ddcc6c5210eaccc4ba81</guid></item><item><title>Michele Bullock on relationship between interest rates and property prices.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/michele-bullock-on-relationship-between-interest/105836842</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08f6913eba53ec251c45a4cfc5a903ec</guid></item><item><title>RBA governor Michele Bullock warns housing supply improvement is likely to be several years away</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/rba-governor-says-dont-expect-housing-supply-quick-fix/105836722</link><description>In a rare candid moment, the Reserve Bank governor concedes that, despite the best efforts of policy makers, chronic housing undersupply will continue for at least the next two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">980e38be9487fe7fd38b666262ccb47d</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105837158</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a7ee7d282fc391b8348730ed53c63a4</guid></item><item><title>More sunscreens pulled from shelves over SPF concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/more-sunscreens-pulled-from-shelves-over-spf-concerns/105836976</link><description>Ten further sunscreens have either been pulled from shelves or "paused" from supply to retailers over concerns about their sun protection claims, the Therapeutic Goods Administration (TGA) announces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d13dbff1397dfc72d067ab8fb5d26cf</guid></item><item><title>Hegseth declares an end to 'politically correct' leadership in the US military</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/hegseth-declares-end-politically-correct-leadership-us-military/105837252</link><description>Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth summoned hundreds of US military officials to an in-person meeting to declare an end to "woke" culture in the military.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ccba28430ac9aca5a55e9e56beb767c</guid></item><item><title>AI tool detects tiny brain lesions to help children with epilepsy live seizure-free</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/ai-tool-detects-epilepsy-lesion-seizure-free-brain-surgery/105833450</link><description>Melbourne researchers test a new AI tool that detects tiny lesions in children with epilepsy, leading to surgeries that leave them seizure-free.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6d7c60e521147b2214309d24a96abd9</guid></item><item><title>Public prostate cancer patients told treatment provided by public hospitals no longer available</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/prostate-cancer-drug-plutetium-unavailable-in-public-hospitals/105817548</link><description>Men with aggressive prostate cancer who were being treated with a groundbreaking drug have been told the therapy is no longer available at public hospitals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a5cfb55375dcb15bc428ab457951289</guid></item><item><title>$50m fund for clean energy apprenticeships remains untouched</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/clean-energy-apprenticeship-fund-unspent/105817458</link><description>A $50 million fund to support students wanting to study clean energy trades is yet to pay out a single dollar, nearly a year and a half after it was funded in the budget.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acc8b5fb442feb919b43f9894e313116</guid></item><item><title>Will Australia's democracy survive global collapse?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/boyer-lecture-democracy-justin-wolfers/105834256</link><description>This year's Boyer Lectures will consider whether our democratic system will hold in the face of global headwinds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dad177c98e314880fe2f419a1557c4ae</guid></item><item><title>Communications Minister Anika Wells finds herself in the eye of Optus political storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/anika-wells-optus-triple-0-calls-coalition/105836652</link><description>Touted in some insider circles as future Labor leadership material, self-identified millennial Anika Wells finds herself in a storm over the nation's emergency triple-0 system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffdf07b1df2855649ee7be32eec987e6</guid></item><item><title>When it comes to business, size does matter — and smaller isn't necessarily better</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/size-based-subsidy-policies-for-business-not-fit-for-purpose/105834696</link><description>The economic contribution of start-ups has been overlooked, as a new study suggests age and performance should be taken into consideration when it comes to incentive policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">212458ec44fca2265c41d59a51d12418</guid></item><item><title>Inside a children's court, a magistrate hears of fearful victims and young people living with trauma</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/victoria-a-week-inside-childrens-court-bail-remand/105736320</link><description>The ABC spent a week inside the court that presides over youth crime and witnessed fearful victims, young people living with trauma and magistrates facing the difficult to decision to bail or remand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd0dcb1be140486961acd7bd8683cc04</guid></item><item><title>Australia and Türkiye try to break diplomatic stalemate over COP31 climate summit hosting rights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/australia-and-turkiye-negotiate-over-cop31-hosting-rights/105837208</link><description>Australia and Türkiye are at loggerheads over who will host the massive international event, with insiders suggesting the countries could share the hosting rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dcbb38a7c5fa3798ca94f5cb8e1fdef</guid></item><item><title>Two years since Tasmania's commission of inquiry, report reveals which recommendations are still underway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/tasmania-commission-of-inquiry-recommendations-two-years-on/105829022</link><description>Victim-survivor Katrina Munting says she remains hopeful, but she is concerned the government isn't implementing the commission of inquiry's recommendations quickly enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7af4c80f86d6405035e88f89a3f0ab0c</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri feeling positive ahead of Formula 1 Singapore Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/oscar-piastri-formula-1-singapore-grand-prix/105831828</link><description>Oscar Piastri believes McLaren "on paper" should be suited to the high temperatures expected for this weekend's Formula 1 Singapore Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8173544c8af86a69ec3e5eb6e9c683e</guid></item><item><title>Kiama resident launches petition to disqualify MPs convicted of serious crimes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/gareth-ward-constituent-starts-petition-to-stop-mp-pay-in-jail/105836568</link><description>Disgraced former MP Gareth Ward was paid a weekly salary of more than $3,000 while waiting to be sentenced for sexual offences. An Illawarra resident wants to ensure that never happens again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b949cacb11450b44191bd38f72673433</guid></item><item><title>When do I need to do my tax return by? Here's what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/tax-return-deadline-2025/105820288</link><description>The 2024/25 tax deadline is fast approaching, and missing the cut-off date could end up costing you. Here's what you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb7d7b46e9afaf15f58ef29da7a57d30</guid></item><item><title>Australia's southern coast is in uncharted waters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/algal-bloom-has-left-the-sa-coast-in-uncharted-waters/105784050</link><description>The disastrous algal bloom that has been lapping at South Australia's shores has turned a coastline into a frontline, leaving many swimmers, surfers and seaside business operators wondering what the upcoming summer will look like.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88a6dd01c869f326eb8cabe34a95aeaa</guid></item><item><title>South Australia looks to defend Sheffield Shield and One Day Cup titles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/sa-sheffield-shield-title-defence/105830672</link><description>South Australia is looking to repeat its success and win the Sheffield Shield title, after a decade-breaking win last season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23e43b9737521f7aa31cdda18b686651</guid></item><item><title>Nicole Kidman files for divorce from Keith Urban after 19 years of marriage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/nicole-kidman-files-for-divorce-keith-urban/105837586</link><description>The Oscar-winning actor files for divorce in a Nashville court a day after reports emerged of the couple's separation, with a source saying the decision to leave was Keith Urban's.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6b869ba2fc37bf31b91a90fcd1870dc</guid></item><item><title>How Shane Perry worked as a mortgage broker, played without a contract and helped Brisbane to an NRL premiership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/shane-perry-nrl-grand-final-2006-brisbane-broncos/105836598</link><description>Only three men have steered Brisbane to a premiership, and Shane Perry is the only one who has done it while working a full-time job and playing without a contract.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3f75edf709bb06b44970503060d738f</guid></item><item><title>Lithgow schools teach teenagers to build drones in transition away from coal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/lithgow-coal-transition-drone-education-program/105749190</link><description>Students are looking to aero technology for new skills in Lithgow, where almost half the local economy is driven by the declining coal industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1eb111131e33d3ea3fb46173e3b52f82</guid></item><item><title>India beats Sri Lanka in Women's Cricket World Cup opener after rain delays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/india-beats-sri-lanka-in-womens-cricket-world-cup-opener/105837612</link><description>India recovers from a disastrous collapse to beat Sri Lanka in a rain-shortened first game at the Women's Cricket World Cup in Guwahati.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df91984c047bb7eeeb9bc01676c5acba</guid></item><item><title>WA Police find 'insufficient evidence' to charge officer in alleged choking complaint after road incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/wa-police-alleged-choking-complaint-fight/105830352</link><description>A man who alleges he was choked by an off-duty police officer in front of his daughter says he has lost trust in the police force, after they found "insufficient evidence" to lay charges over the road incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fa8d6c0a811e923d088ab3ce045a9bf</guid></item><item><title>Sydney's heritage-listed urinal tells story of Australia's public loos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/sydney-heritage-listed-urinal-pissoir-mary-mcgillivray/105830378</link><description>Tucked away at Dawes Point, under Sydney Harbour Bridge, is one of the city's most unexpected heritage-listed sites: a cast-iron urinal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8a86be5817ac130591bc1399095b50a</guid></item><item><title>Why Phoebe Litchfield's first ODI World Cup could signal a new era in Australian cricket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/phoebe-litchfield-cricket-world-cup/105831198</link><description>Having burst onto the scene as a 16-year-old batting alongside Brian Lara, Phoebe Litchfield was a cricketing prodigy. At her first ODI World Cup, she has a chance to become a world beater.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d56a08bf54d3662e236789b345c86f1</guid></item><item><title>Van Gogh painting among 'rarely seen' collection of art to be exhibited in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/vincent-van-gogh-exhibition-in-adelaide/105834014</link><description>A "rarely seen" collection of works from renowned artists Vincent van Gogh, Claude Monet and Henri Matisse will be on display in Adelaide next year, as part of 57 works on loan from the Toledo Museum of Art in the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0084a43aa4c726640e5a07bb4947f03d</guid></item><item><title>Many waiting longer than clinically recommended for orthopaedic surgery in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/long-wait-time-orthopaedic-surgery-canberra/105837678</link><description>After 36 years working as a house cleaner, Judy Harman needs a knee replacement, but there are hundreds of people in front of her on the wait list for orthopaedic surgery in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a42f98aca637506617f58e04a8fc6f72</guid></item><item><title>Yulella Aboriginal Corporation's 'Vision' shop combats cost of remote living</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/outback-community-shop-provides-produce-essentials-remote-town/105835646</link><description>A community group in an outback town is fighting high prices to offer more affordable food, clothing, and other essentials that were previously only available hundreds of kilometres away.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7c53736b7ac03dbf6f5d2bd0102385a</guid></item><item><title>Health battle heralds end of an era for family-run festival favourite Wignalls Wines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/wignalls-wines-retires-label-after-blood-cancer-diagnosis/105834752</link><description>WA vigneron Rob Wignall, who built a legacy of award-winning Great Southern wines and star-studded music festivals, says it is time to move on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd664f0c7a398350bdb9452787df4c55</guid></item><item><title>Widow petitions for MRI machine at regional Queensland hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/widow-launches-petition-for-mri-machine-at-queensland-hospital/105830312</link><description>A year before her husband died, Helen Schmidt was forced to make a gut-wrenching decision after learning there was no MRI machine at their regional hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9e2c123ffcac8ffdc1721ce11e0b36f</guid></item><item><title>Rio Tinto's Gladstone coal-fired power station could be retired early</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/rio-tinto-announces-early-closure-of-gladstone-power-station/105838270</link><description>Rio Tinto tells workers the Gladstone Power Station could retire six years earlier than expected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1402498dcfccda613c86dbf8fe53e48</guid></item><item><title>Prime minister 'concerned' by reports of Chinese ban on BHP iron ore imports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/albanese-concerned-reports-china-ban-bhp-imports/105838320</link><description>China's state iron ore buyer has ordered steelmakers to pause purchases of iron ore shipments from BHP, according to media reports, as they continue hardball negotiations with the company.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70ff7451bd093e4fa67169aeed9ac3fa</guid></item><item><title>AFL ditches centre bounce for men's game, and sub rule after grand final criticism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/afl-ditches-centre-bounce-sub-rule-changes/105838544</link><description>The AFL will no longer have the traditional bouncedown to start men's games, and has also ditched the controversial sub rule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a6b8a2709641f1dede1168ea7de372b</guid></item><item><title>Powerful Philippines earthquake leaves at least 69 people dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/at-least-69-people-dead-after-powerful-philippines-quake/105838220</link><description>The quake, which struck the central Cebu province, injured many others and sent residents scrambling out of their homes and into the darkness as the intense shaking cut off power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f4365721a7971c1facd973e26fff422</guid></item><item><title>Mount Gambier football referee Bill Stephenson hangs up whistle after 35 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/veteran-mount-gambier-junior-football-referee-retires/105834024</link><description>Bill Stephenson started refereeing to support his kids' dreams and he worries abuse will stop more like him from taking up the whistle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a709a3f751be6e3b9c5d2f125a40f92a</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon sworn in, vows to tackle organised crime and domestic violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/nsw-police-commissioner-mal-lanyon-sworn-in/105838570</link><description>In a ceremony on Wednesday, Police Minister Yasmin Catley paid tribute to the new commissioner, recalling the "bad bastards" he chased down in his career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e58fcafe101d8d0855f365ae7f9e403</guid></item><item><title>Hollywood veteran Bruce Beresford slams Donald Trump's plan for 100pc tariff on movies made outside US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/director-says-trump-does-not-know-what-he-is-talking-about/105838560</link><description>Renowned Australian director and screenwriter Bruce Beresford says US President Donald Trump's plan to impose a 100 per cent tariff on all foreign-made movies cannot be done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9319a3f94a0ec855b915ec072b58c26d</guid></item><item><title>Police find 'insufficient evidence' to charge officer in alleged choking complaint</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/police-find-insufficient-evidence-to-charge/105837218</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ee549d335c63d647c954a929a3630b</guid></item><item><title>Army reservist Mitchell John Hogan avoids jail for threatening police officer over WA gun laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/mitchell-john-hogan-avoids-jail-over-wa-police-officer-threat/105838924</link><description>A gun enthusiast who rang a WA Police acting inspector who was involved in the state's firearm reforms and told him "we're coming for you" three times is ordered to do community work and undergo counselling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e9b3645092cf6ebeb337a6ca2154708</guid></item><item><title>Fat Bear Week 2025 won by 32 Chunk, who overcame broken jaw to stack on pounds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/fat-bear-week-2025-winner-32-chunk/105838322</link><description>A hunky brown bear named 32 Chunk has waddled away with the Fat Bear Week title for 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcd91d4c1814f89a6974b0f878c1ed55</guid></item><item><title>Dan Murphy's receives second knockback over planned Daylesford store</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/daylesford-celebrates-liquor-store-knockback/105837910</link><description>Australia's largest retail drinks network has been knocked back for a second time in its legal bid to open a liquor store in the heart of Daylesford.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35116099c72d212bb0d144230e407c25</guid></item><item><title>Total fire bans in place for large parts of Queensland amid hot, dry conditions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/queensland-total-fire-bans-amid-hot-dry-windy-conditions/105837860</link><description>An area of southern Queensland larger than Tasmania is under a total fire ban that will be extended from central Queensland to the Gold Coast from Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a9b808600138b8d10ce9b0c9ea18645</guid></item><item><title>Vandalism at Wybalenna site on Flinders Island condemned by Aboriginal community, police and politicians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/vandalism-at-historic-wybalenna-site-condemned/105837718</link><description>Members of the Aboriginal community are reeling after vandals allegedly performed donuts at Wybalenna on Flinders Island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c4fbfd4627a6d4e09ef4d256aa99351</guid></item><item><title>Qantas to close staff bases in Canberra, Hobart and Mildura amid restructure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/qantaslink-closure-staff-bases-canberra-hobart-mildura/105839248</link><description>The closure of the three bases will take effect in 2026 and affect about 70 personnel, who will be supported throughout the process, the airline said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d08ce611e5c62fe32513b9325ecf8d83</guid></item><item><title>EPA to begin 'extensive' lead dust deposit monitoring near Nyrstar smelter and MMG mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/tasmania-epa-lead-dust-health-risk-monitoring-nyrstar-mmg-mine/105838520</link><description>Hobart suburbs bordering a zinc smelter and a mining town in north-west Tasmania will undergo human health risk monitoring for lead deposit rates, the state's environment protection watchdog has announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d71b9b2fd7b9605695e8ad39b6add3f4</guid></item><item><title>Health sector unions develop five-point plan to tackle record ambulance ramping in WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/health-union-plan-for-ambulance-ramping-after-record-set/105838024</link><description>More aged care beds, a bolstered workforce and streamlined patient care are needed to tackle ambulance ramping in Western Australia, the health sector’s unions say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ee7065287378984a7a00fa200ec86f5</guid></item><item><title>Boy, 3, in serious condition after being hit by car in Bellambi, NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/boy-hit-by-car-near-wollongong-in-serious-condition/105839116</link><description>The three-year-old was airlifted to a Sydney hospital after he was run over by a vehicle reversing out of a driveway in Bellambi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2b845f5fd652a3ebdcb02bf2fa2599d</guid></item><item><title>US government shutdown begins as politicians remain in funding deadlock with 'the rules radically changing'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/us-government-shutdown-begins/105838572</link><description>A US government shutdown — the first in more than six years — begins after Congress fails to pass a measure that would have kept federal funds flowing, threatening tens of thousands of jobs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ff043a45f41aa716bdc7f147e83daff</guid></item><item><title>When parallel parenting might be needed after separation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/when-parallel-parenting-might-be-needed-after-separation/105762786</link><description>Parallel parenting is an approach that can occur after a high-conflict separation or where there has been family violence, but also when parents simply want space from one another.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ddd7d5d45889b15ac283b481af2b74f</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Wallabies coach Michael Cheika accepts full-time role with Roosters NRL team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/nrl-sydney-roosters-ex-wallabies-coach-michael-cheika/105839652</link><description>In a switch between the rugby codes, former Wallabies coach Michael Cheika takes another step towards an NRL head coaching role.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65f545b9ed07a7a263b2b4b43ededa73</guid></item><item><title>How has the first home buyer scheme changed and who's eligible?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/first-homebuyer-scheme-explainer-income-limits-property-caps/105838164</link><description>The revamped scheme has come into effect, with first home buyers of all income levels now able to purchase a property with only a 5 per cent deposit. Here are all the changes explained.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">164b15e14b7ab8348ed381818b59b1cf</guid></item><item><title>WA to roll out nasal spray flu vaccinations for children after severe flu season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/new-jab-free-flu-vaccination-aimed-at-children/105839610</link><description>A new jab-free flu vaccination aimed at children frightened of needles is being rolled out across Western Australia in a bid to boost child vaccination rates after one of the worst flu seasons on record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b7eac2589f500f8dc713da4b268a11e</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies record-holder James Slipper to quit Test rugby after Bledisloe Cup clash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/rugby-union-wallabies-james-slipper-test-retirement/105839948</link><description>After 15 years of international rugby union, Wallabies veteran James Slipper announces he is drawing the curtain on his Test career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ffecfce94e3b873d8115a7aeb921b38</guid></item><item><title>Demolition of fire-ravaged Morley Market begins as community rallies around impacted businesses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/morley-market-demolition-begins-after-devastating-fire/105839612</link><description>Demolition works begin at the Morley Market in Perth's north-eastern suburbs, a month after small businesses were destroyed in a fire at the complex.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90585504615c3b8b13c1e7d7e5e723e5</guid></item><item><title>States shoot down hospital funding offer, claiming it amounts to a shortfall of 'billions'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/states-shoot-down-commonwealth-hospital-funding-offer/105839904</link><description>State and territory leaders say the Commonwealth's offer for the next five years of hospital funding would leave them billions out of pocket, claiming the federal government is walking back a promise to pay 42.5 per cent of the share of expenses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fedb548d09882166c3bc80df7a44fd0a</guid></item><item><title>Search for missing man Mark Sear scaled back in WA's far north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/outback-search-for-missing-62-year-old-scaled-back/105839580</link><description>WA Police say the search for Mark Sear has been scaled back pending further information.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d7d69e731186a8dc3dc3610d6dbc3d9</guid></item><item><title>Roadworks completed as construction of new Paradise Dam wall sparks environmental concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/paradise-dam-construction-progresses-amid-environmental-concerns/105838512</link><description>More than 53 hectares of bushland and riverine habitat will be cleared for a major upgrade to a regional Queensland dam, prompting environmentalists to raise concerns about protected lungfish and turtles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36ad0a2a27ea2e06aac14038c314e3da</guid></item><item><title>Will Keir Starmer become the latest UK prime minister to be ousted?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/will-keir-starmer-latest-uk-prime-minister-to-be-ousted/105837812</link><description>A successful party conference speech has rallied the troops and offered the Labour leader a reprieve from mounting speculation about his leadership, but for how long?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">413558c3fafc2465097322840acb6e67</guid></item><item><title>SA Police issue warning about fake currency after more than 200 incidents and two arrests in recent months</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/sa-counterfeit-currency/105839292</link><description>SA Police says there have been more than 200 reported cases of counterfeit currency being used in the state in the past two months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdb80015a7fe1737a385a7a52823ec03</guid></item><item><title>Last Cab to Darwin director advocates for voluntary assisted dying as film marks 10-year anniversary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/last-cab-to-darwin-film-anniversary-voluntary-assisted-dying-vad/105834830</link><description>The director of Last Cab to Darwin — which explores the subject of voluntary assisted dying — wants all terminally ill Australians to be afforded access to dignified end-of-life care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14a49f6a2666dabe169977d9ff867027</guid></item><item><title>Why the NRLW 2025 grand final looms as a defining moment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/nrlw-grand-final-broncos-roosters-premiership/105839942</link><description>The Roosters and Broncos have both dominated the NRLW, but the winners this weekend can legitimately stamp themselves as the pre-eminent club in the competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20618a0d68e527c2ac06c1f2e48522f3</guid></item><item><title>Former prisoners to stand trial over alleged extortion, murder of inmate Benn Schinkel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/qld-court-hearing-alleged-murder-extortion-inmate-benn-schinkel/105839586</link><description>Two fellow prisoners, who were charged over the 2022 alleged murder and extortion of Benn Schinkel, will stand trial in the Supreme Court in Brisbane over his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d72e2ac6a28835428c1ecb9ac214b635</guid></item><item><title>Australia posts six-wicket win over New Zealand in opening men's T20I</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/t20-new-zealand-vs-australia-scorecentre/105840160</link><description>The Australian men's team claims a 1-0 series lead after recording a six-wicket win over New Zealand at Tauranga's Bay Oval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f2d3e8a19b888d2019cba126eba9dde</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian Devils' AFL draft concessions for 2028 announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/tasmania-devils-afl-draft-concessions-2028-team-announced/105838224</link><description>Tasmania's fledgling AFL team, the Devils, will have a $5 million signing bonus pool in addition to the salary cap to help lure players from interstate. It's one of the many draft concessions released by the AFL for the team's entry to the national league.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8a0eb552ee496d363a82b4911b1ab47</guid></item><item><title>NSW government to allow registration of old farm utes and trucks used to fight fires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/incentive-helps-farmers-register-firefighting-vehicles/105838510</link><description>Farmers will pay lower registration fees on the old vehicles they keep on hand to fight fires under a new scheme in NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13f635fcd1378b8a6166f1da1e3f9825</guid></item><item><title>Inside the search for missing four-year-old boy Gus on isolated SA sheep station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/missing-boy-gus-yunta-search-timeline/105838592</link><description>Authorities are searching for a missing four-year-old boy on a sheep grazing station in the mid-north of South Australia. Here's what we know about the search so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1d3ba565b40f77a7bb990999b5cf38f</guid></item><item><title>NT Police seize more than 240 guns from former Kakadu park ranger who captured 5.1m crocodile, Sweetheart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/nt-police-seize-more-than-240-guns-from-dave-lindner-at-kakadu/105839596</link><description>A Kakadu National Park firearms dealer faces charges by NT Police for failing to properly store hundreds of guns being kept on a property at the park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be39bbc31ad71ea60ba658e07138213c</guid></item><item><title>Specialist search teams deployed near Benalla in search for Dezi Freeman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/fugitive-gunman-dezi-freeman-search-continues/105841044</link><description>Police are continuing the search for alleged gunman Dezi Freeman, deploying search teams to the area around Benalla in Victoria's north-east on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">741e4d73a1bdb12e6fbbd2e3251cf425</guid></item><item><title>Woman remains traumatised by police strip search as new commissioner issues apology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/woman-strip-searched-police-commissioner-offers-apology/105839310</link><description>At just 18 years old, Kristelle would step through the gates of a music festival in Sydney's west and leave feeling like she had been sexually assaulted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ace58a0669684993b23ba5cede75a806</guid></item><item><title>Wagga Wagga horse trader pleads not guilty to running an illegal knackery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/wagga-horse-trader-charged-over-alleged-illegal-knackery/105839370</link><description>Wagga Wagga property operator Adrian Talbot has been charged with operating a knackery and "animal food van" business without a licence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d21eb5cdfc6ca4179a624a5f6211876</guid></item><item><title>Dally M Awards 2025: James Tedesco and Tamika Upton win medal for second time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/dally-m-awards-2025-james-tedesco-tamika-upton/105841076</link><description>Sydney Roosters NRL captain James Tedesco and Brisbane Broncos NRLW fullback Tamika Upton have each created their own slice of history, winning the Dally M Medal for a second time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7d15948e9e4e8f20a40a16f5bf7f935</guid></item><item><title>Alleged cop killer Dezi Freeman's extreme and fanatical views existed for many years, say family and former friends</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/dezi-freeman-nephew-luke-filby-extremist-views-growing-pre-covid/105832296</link><description>Luke Filby remembers looking up to his uncle Dezi, right up until the point he didn't. And he's not alone in having stepped away before the killing of two police officers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9fe3822f92ca6b8d9c2d6f295f35c03</guid></item><item><title>Dally M 2025 red carpet: NRLW and NRL stars dress up for awards night</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/dally-m-awards-nrl-red-carpet-2025/105840674</link><description>The awards night for the NRL and NRLW gives players the chance to step out in something other than their grass-stained jerseys. So we're expecting big things on the Dally M red carpet in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec60f31828c3b9e85686085732fa31d7</guid></item><item><title>Cats apologise for 'inappropriate' Mad Monday behaviour, AFL 'not thrilled'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/afl-geelong-cats-bailey-smith-mad-monday/105840052</link><description>Geelong breaks its silence about the club's Mad Monday antics, revealing future post-season events "will not continue in this current form".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c7def3975ba28ff2ad000b6f29bec31</guid></item><item><title>Ash Gardner century guides Australia to win over New Zealand to start Women's World Cup defence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/womens-cricket-world-cup-australia-new-zealand/105839424</link><description>All-rounder Ash Gardner makes a landmark century as Australia kicks off its World Cup defence in India with a comfortable win over New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9571e8acd588e7d317bd8785353cb2a</guid></item><item><title>Dr Marianne Gale appointed new Queensland Chief Health Officer after lengthy search</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/dr-marianne-gale-named-as-queensland-chief-health-officer/105841346</link><description>Dr Marianne Gale previously held the high-profile role of NSW deputy chief health officer during the pandemic and will take on the top job in December.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5ddcb051f4f568ecba7e33265ebedbd</guid></item><item><title>2005 Bali bombings at Jimbaran Bay, Kuta remembered by survivors in Newcastle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/2005-bali-bombings-newcastle-vigil-20th-anniversary/105829890</link><description>Survivors of the 2005 Jimbaran Bay bombings gather in Newcastle to mark the 20th anniversary of the tragedy, which some feel is not as widely remembered as the 2002 Kuta blasts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46ee6ed8cdbc027297022965358254a9</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105841486</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da667996abee3f16b01a9ce07a601c25</guid></item><item><title>Former employees of sunscreen testing lab Princeton Consumer Research blow whistle on alleged questionable practices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/australian-sunscreen-brands-dump-spf-testing-lab-pcr/105841262</link><description>Two former employees of a leading international testing laboratory used by major Australian sunscreen brands have blown the whistle on alleged questionable data and incorrect testing practices, amid ongoing concerns about whether consumers can trust the products they are relying on for sun protection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1829a9601e42cc7008ce391c382c56a0</guid></item><item><title>The number of large companies paying no tax in Australia has declined, says ATO</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/companies-paying-no-tax-in-australia-has-declined/105838268</link><description>The proportion of large companies in Australia that paid no tax in the most recent income year has declined from 36 per cent to 28 per cent over the past 11 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">265d9aa2fb2dc799537c0206ea4c6c0b</guid></item><item><title>Israel steps up Gaza City offensive as Hamas weighs up ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/israel-issues-last-warning-to-leave-gaza-city/105842102</link><description>Witnesses reported heavy bombardment in Gaza City, as Israel's defence minister, Israel Katz, said the army was tightening its encirclement of the city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3c4fc429c7c0ff3156393e578aa6fb5</guid></item><item><title>Jane Goodall, renowned conservationist, dies aged 91</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/jane-goodall-dies-aged-91/105842164</link><description>The conservationist was renowned for her groundbreaking chimpanzee field research and globe-spanning environmental advocacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0bc08ad97bebddf06a9725d1cdcebd0</guid></item><item><title>Social media and online dating exposes girls to greater risks of child marriage, new report shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/social-media-digital-connection-child-marriage/105837010</link><description>Modern technology is allowing girls to choose their own partners but some remain vulnerable to child marriage to escape hardship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffcbc8ff415233f19e015967f810d465</guid></item><item><title>Victorian church under investigation after pastor's son sexually assaulted teenager</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/encourage-church-romsey-under-investigation/105820656</link><description>Multiple investigations are examining a Victorian church's response to an assault committed by a senior pastor's son, amid allegations that information was withheld from the church community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06a5c5aacc965d20272df373cc9834ed</guid></item><item><title>Five people pulled alive from site of Indonesia school collapse as rescuers race against time to find others</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/five-people-pulled-alive-from-indonesia-school-collapse/105842052</link><description>Authorities say those rescued alive were able to communicate with rescuers, with another three people killed in the disaster also pulled from the rubble.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b6d29e9b5598c8c4327fecfa5782ccc</guid></item><item><title>Greta Thunberg detained as Israel's military intercepts Gaza-bound aid flotilla</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/global-sumud-flotilla-intercepted-by-idf-near-gaza/105838920</link><description>The activists are expected to be detained and then taken to Ashdod, where they will be told to sign deportation orders and flown out of the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">535a79372b15f15f2a53967a4057c0a7</guid></item><item><title>From pharmaceuticals to kitchen cabinets, Trump's tariff program expands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/us-tariffs-industries-countries-most-impacted/105822256</link><description>Since returning to the White House, the US president has placed tariffs on more than 90 countries and a number of industries. Here are the countries and sectors most impacted by the tariffs from the Trump administration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52611230484b1f07cb56204c72c8d01c</guid></item><item><title>Calls to reform Australia's pension age as labourers consider early retirement due to injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/reform-by-occupation-needed-for-australian-pension-age/105836058</link><description>For some Australians, continuing to work until the pension age of 67 can be a struggle. Peita says a life of heavy lifting has taken its toll on her body, and she is trying to survive on JobSeeker payments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26bcf63c522f3bbec3e132d84b8f6b43</guid></item><item><title>The oceans keep score in a year of record heat around Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/hottest-year-on-record-in-oceans-around-australia/105698530</link><description>For the past year, Australia's oceans have been hotter than ever before. The impacts are being felt all across the nation — as far away from the coast as you can get.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54120136b83762f1dbbc0ac1cb4070b3</guid></item><item><title>Ocean heat animation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/video-animation-hot-oceans/105835076</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09af910d7d97b0dd8187ffc42c35365b</guid></item><item><title>VPNs, 'old man' masks, and AI: The holes in the social media ban and their fixes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/social-media-ban-vpns-masks-age-checks-disguises/105836134</link><description>From December 10, social media platforms will be forced to block under 16s in Australia from holding accounts, but experts warn age checks can be easily bypassed in several ways, including a $22 "old man" mask.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eeaf0bd64c8eab6d67fcdb13899b31a8</guid></item><item><title>Low-income, vulnerable residents would have to evacuate proposed Ipswich development under flood warnings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/qld-flood-apartments-ipswich-development-approvals/105820118</link><description>A major developer wants to build 500 apartments on the banks of a river to Brisbane's south, but some concerned residents say the flooding risk is too high.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f62f6732bb329b4263c6d2123d66efb</guid></item><item><title>Family of Indigenous man says NSW government apology for death in custody 'too little, too late'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/tj-denniss-family-rejects-apology-for-death-in-custody-inquest/105839270</link><description>The family of an Indigenous man who died in prison says an apology from Corrective Services NSW has come "too little, too late".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04c76042f49ade389bcc63a0798c2772</guid></item><item><title>New 124-bed Launceston private hospital a step closer after unanimous council approval for planning change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/launceston-health-service-124-bed-private-public-hospital-plans/105839626</link><description>A plan that will enable a state-of-the-art medical facility with 10 operating theatres, a laboratory, pharmacy, helipad and a bridge to Launceston's public hospital is unanimously supported by all Launceston councillors in a vote.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f47005e2d71424e267f82803cbee7f82</guid></item><item><title>Staff shortage limits maternity services at St Vincent's Private Hospital Toowoomba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/staff-shortage-st-vincents-private-hospital-special-care-nursery/105810290</link><description>St Vincent's Private Hospital at Toowoomba sets up a hotline for expectant mothers, after temporarily scaling back services at its special care nursery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c2590f3ffce4756af342cf85ef62a7f</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide lord mayor confident on being COP31-ready despite hosting decision delays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/adelaide-confident-cop31-despite-delays/105841520</link><description>Adelaide's lord mayor is confident the city will be prepared to host the event, even though it is 13 months away and Australia remains in a deadlock over hosting rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30d7b35793ec02998db83cdcf2e64a0f</guid></item><item><title>'International Stabilisation Force' in Trump Gaza plan will be biggest challenge in peace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/international-stabilisation-force-trump-gaza-challenge-analysis/105841802</link><description>The US president's peace plan for Gaza includes the creation of a temporary "International Stabilisation Force", but analysts say this will be a challenging task.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c53e75be6fe418aeb21bbde7b2cbb21</guid></item><item><title>Police issue warrant for Sydney rapper YC Ewzy, aka Harley Johan, over Niddal Acherkouk shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/sydney-rapper-yc-ewzy-harley-johan-wanted-for-niddal-acherkouk/105842176</link><description>Police are looking for a Sydney rapper they believe fled the country after a gangland murder where a man was ambushed and gunned down at an inner-city service station in 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe9e6f30645a8932851c084664536574</guid></item><item><title>CCTV captures gangland hit in Surry Hills</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/cctv-captures-gangland-hit-in-surry-hills/105842278</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b25756d85203218d412b33410564738</guid></item><item><title>Year 7 students build open-source, 3D-printed hand for classmate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/3d-printed-hands-made-by-port-macquarie-high-school-sudents/105793670</link><description>Lois Agnello was born with only part of her left hand and came up with the idea to use her school's 3D printer to make a new one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3d31eb73797a3b74b3190d03ddcc240</guid></item><item><title>In winning his second Dally M player of the year award, James Tedesco is defying time itself</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/james-tedesco-sydney-roosters-dally-m/105841906</link><description>Roosters fullback James Tedesco held off the challenge of players over a decade his junior to defy time and claim his second Dally M player of the year award.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9b7d4d89b657c972a250ec831d33d86</guid></item><item><title>Disability advocates call for rethink after Palmerston Hospital's hydrotherapy pool closes to external providers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/palmerston-hospital-hydrotherapy-pool-closed-disability-provider/105833492</link><description>Robyne Burridge lives with a disability that severely impacts her mobility, and hydrotherapy is vital. But she hasn't received that treatment in months after the NT government cut off public access to the only suitable local facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">858ae7fc55c0e624a6ba1987e542bfa7</guid></item><item><title>Police release first picture of Gus as ADF joins the search for missing child</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/outback-search-for-boy-enters-sixth-day/105838064</link><description>Police have released the first image of Gus since his disappearance, with almost 50 members of the Australian Defence Force joining the search for the four-year-old in mid-north South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a99525f04f4d120b81c167ff33648857</guid></item><item><title>US government shutdown impacts felt across America as Trump administration threatens mass sackings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/us-government-shutdown-effects-day-one/105842146</link><description>The effects of the US government shutdown are being felt across America as the White House warns federal workers will be fired en masse if Democrats don't back down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e9e638864316a79689e887f741d2e58</guid></item><item><title>Australia's favourite authors share their top books of the 21st century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/radio-national-top-100-books-favourite-authors-21st-century/105835904</link><description>We asked Australia's favourite authors to share their top books of the 21st century. Here's what they said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16bbbcadeaf709b20e67dc7f0e8047f0</guid></item><item><title>Employee injured after he was startled by wasp has $870k damages win upheld</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/employee-who-suffered-trip-injury-has-damages-win-upheld/105834350</link><description>A groundsman who tripped over a bag of rubbish as he tried to evade a wasp says he wants workers to understand their rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2388d0a1754c37cc486832d75ae0e870</guid></item><item><title>'Tomorrow could be the day': Jordan Brunoli from Bugs opens up about terminal cancer fears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/bugs-bassist-jordan-brunoli-on-terminal-cancer-diagnosis/105839994</link><description>At 29, Australian musician Jordan Brunoli was diagnosed with incurable cancer. He says he's terrified of what comes next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa08a02f5d726657bc79b3e01ede5fdb</guid></item><item><title>Top statistician accuses government of spinning rock art science</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/top-statistician-accuses-government-of-spinning/105841800</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74b9c5052592fd07c029066450853c90</guid></item><item><title>Top statistician breaks silence over Murujuga rock art study near Woodside gas plant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/murujuga-rock-art-study-woodside-government-interference/105806508</link><description>A scientist who quit a major study on WA rock art is accusing the government of downplaying findings linking damage to heavy industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f66f15af3b15830fb1d8d958a73a835</guid></item><item><title>Police find prisoner who went missing from Julia Creek Work Camp</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/prisoner-tory-ross-rose-absconds-from-julia-creek-work-camp/105842320</link><description>A 32-year-old serving a prison sentence for serious assault has been located after going missing in north-west Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0321481fde77c73c331ccb1dca5840dd</guid></item><item><title>ASX gains 1.1per cent led by miners and banks, RBA says Australia 'well positioned' as global risks rise — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-oct-2/105841806</link><description>The ASX jumped more than 1 per cent as investors renewed their appetite for risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">030adf06ec31175c91063eb0242a1246</guid></item><item><title>NSW EPA blamed for slow contamination warning on Belubula River</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/belubula-river-community-unhappy-with-epa-response-on-pfos-pfas/105694456</link><description>Documents sought through freedom of information laws show the extent of fish contamination in a NSW river, information an inquiry found the EPA kept from the community for eight months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">237721a66d2f4bf2d0d31e48419bee52</guid></item><item><title>Phil Gould hospitalised over heart concerns, Canterbury Bulldogs football boss says 'everything is OK'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/phil-gould-hospitalised-with-heart-concerns/105842400</link><description>The Canterbury Bulldogs boss assures fans he is on the mend after being hospitalised when doctors found a problem during routine blood tests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fca2cdafe9c2f3febde1b0d4f863fc0</guid></item><item><title>Matildas star Mary Fowler continues her Manchester City career with one-year contract extension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/mary-fowler-extends-manchester-city-career-with-new-contract/105842402</link><description>Mary Fowler praises Manchester City for its support as the Matildas star announces a contract extension.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6cf27bc6840cef2b50b5c49c1eb7bbe</guid></item><item><title>Geraldton residents push for public medical imaging amid high costs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/geraldton-medical-imaging-petition-hospital-redevelopment/105822158</link><description>Residents in WA's Midwest are travelling hundreds of kilometres to avoid costly medical imaging fees. They say it is time that changed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8015e6d7b246dbcdd4c566c71b6bb96c</guid></item><item><title>Nicole Kidman and Keith Urban have split. Here's what couples can expect when separating</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/nicole-kidman-keith-urban-what-couples-separating-can-expect/105837112</link><description>Nicole Kidman and Keith Urban are separating after 19 years of marriage. Separation is common — and here’s what experts say those of us living outside the public eye can expect when going through it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd0db49d65e1ac8c4979b60f6ecc9cc9</guid></item><item><title>Greta Thunberg encounters Israeli officials during navy interception</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/greta-thunberg-encounters-israeli-officials/105842562</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d279961c538eb3ce8a61d27e8af6998</guid></item><item><title>Atherton small butcher buys local meatworks to supply beef across the country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/doug-cross-butcher-buys-innisfail-meatworks-to-expand/105830022</link><description>A Far North Queensland butcher expands his business into an established beef brand, with products sent all over Queensland and interstate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8762f2eb885bbdcb0827ce47f0596d66</guid></item><item><title>Couple rescued from Cradle Mountain Overland Track sheltered in 'freezing' conditions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/tas-cradle-mountain-hypothermia-rescue/105842526</link><description>Two bushwalkers with mild hypothermia have been walked out of Cradle Mountain National Park in Tasmania's central highlands after activating their emergency beacon on Wednesday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eea6e9808b60f9ef16b3c4563b262f98</guid></item><item><title>Helen Garner shortlisted for Baillie Gifford Prize for collected diaries, How to End a Story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/helen-garner-diaries-baillie-gifford-prize-how-to-end-a-story/105841834</link><description>This year, Helen Garner has been in Dua Lipa's book club and the SATC spin-off. Now she's in the running for the Baillie Gifford Prize for non-fiction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14369602aedac3875a90957a25b1e898</guid></item><item><title>Jane Goodall, who revolutionised our understanding of animals, dies at 91</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/primatologist-jane-goodall-obituary/102197696</link><description>British primatologist Jane Goodall entered the African wilderness at 26, without any formal scientific training or university degree. She emerged with research that forever changed how we understand the animal kingdom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">153dfb487b399dbad44404420549f752</guid></item><item><title>Mushroom murderer Erin Patterson's lawyer announces intention to appeal guilty verdicts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/vic-mushroom-murderer-erin-patterson-to-appeal-guilty-verdicts/105842550</link><description>The 51-year-old's lawyer says she will appeal a jury verdict that found her guilty of three murders and attempted murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e31e686a882dd6aa36f2c2b8d0bbe8c6</guid></item><item><title>Rheed McCracken wins second World Para Athletics silver, Briseis Brittain makes international debut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/rheed-mccracken-wins-world-para-athletics-championships-silver/105842664</link><description>Rheed McCracken wins his second silver of the world championships despite the world record holder's disqualification, while Briseis Brittain begins her quest to emulate the great Cathy Freeman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75975bf7defcb04be0b28cd92487af3f</guid></item><item><title>Date set for Townsville mayoral by-election by postal ballot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/townsville-mayoral-election-date-confirmed/105842690</link><description>Townsville voters who have been in limbo since their mayor was suspended last year will vote in a by-election to select the city's next civic leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71672c41ad5dd03e2bd1ee3e3924c63d</guid></item><item><title>Review of west coast bushfires finds flaws in Tasmania's firefighting responses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/west-coast-bushfires-review-finds-flaws-tasmanian-response/105841250</link><description>A COVID outbreak that "spread quickly" through a cramped fire management headquarters was just one issue faced during the response to Tasmania's west coast fires last summer, a review finds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a66366e3bfd9f6a757b4494ed77ee3f9</guid></item><item><title>Dartbrook Hunter Valley mine to stop running after failed revival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/dartbrook-coal-mine-to-go-into-care-and-maintenance/105842500</link><description>The struggling Dartbrook Coal Mine will stop running less than a year after its new operators tried to revive it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dcd01bc3041595dab52e5bcf36d840c</guid></item><item><title>Global financial stability risks have not receded, Reserve Bank warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/rba-financial-stability-review/105842650</link><description>The Reserve Bank warns risks to the global financial system are "rising", not receding, and Australia is not immune from any fallout.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">851ae0a01a9787f56e8f54291d6c183c</guid></item><item><title>Death of Dr Tiffany Wilkes and her daughter in suspected murder-suicide 'keenly' felt by medical community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/kenmore-hills-tiffany-wilkes-death-suspected-murder-suicide/105842600</link><description>Queensland's child safety and domestic violence prevention minister says the death of a mother and her daughter has "shocked" the community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe6f17f27398642dc58882c618fe80a8</guid></item><item><title>Glenelg beach blanketed with foam as Premier announces algal bloom hotline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/algal-bloom-hotline-phone-glenelg-beach-foam/105843172</link><description>Brown foam has blanketed one of the state's most popular tourist beaches in South Australia, as the state government launches an algal bloom hotline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2d5b9e47ac46a5465fba869e25c0169</guid></item><item><title>China's K visa scheme has some worrying about jobs in a country already facing challenges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/china-k-visa-draws-fierce-criticism/105840312</link><description>The new visa is designed to attract top global STEM talent but has sparked fierce backlash, with critics warning it could squeeze Chinese nationals out of the graduate job market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83c304642bcc0e464acc5ea89a172ec6</guid></item><item><title>First survey in five years shows feral deer population boom in Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/tas-new-feral-deer-survey-shows-population-boom/105843366</link><description>The first survey for feral deer in Tasmania in five years reveals an unanticipated increase of nearly 20,000 to the population.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcb4298825aee50a26688ab98726401b</guid></item><item><title>Murder investigation launched after father-of-two Chris Robertson's body found at Lonsdale workshop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/murder-inquiry-launched-after-body-found-at-lonsdale/105843258</link><description>The death of Chris Robertson, whose body was found at an industrial site in Adelaide's south on Tuesday, is now being treated as a major crime, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c06e6a130e76bcde2bf3ac0ea885de4e</guid></item><item><title>Papua New Guinea's cabinet approves 'Pukpuk' defence treaty with Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/papua-new-guinea-australia-pukpuk-treaty-signed/105843900</link><description>A landmark defence treaty between Australia and Papua New Guinea has been approved by PNG's cabinet, marking Australia first new alliance in more than 70 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8acda269673abe0de338cc7fb4537d4c</guid></item><item><title>Proposal for Gaza's future governance revealed in leaked draft plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/leaked-document-reveals-details-of-trump-peace-plan/105839640</link><description>A leaked document reveals details on how the authority charged with governing and rebuilding the Gaza Strip could operate, and how it could be structured.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fac20f9cd529140d313c96e36a794eac</guid></item><item><title>Aussie travellers devastated after US government shutdown forces tourist attractions to close</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/us-government-shutdown-impact-on-australian-travellers/105842656</link><description>Australian travellers heading to the United States are being warned to expect disruptions with some tourist attractions closed, flights disrupted and national parks and museums affected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5165a8eefde415a0ffc3c848e0f0e8f</guid></item><item><title>Appeal for help over body in burnt-out SUV on Kamilaroi Highway near Brewarrina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/body-in-burnt-out-vehicle-kamilaroi-highway-brewarrina/105843926</link><description>Detectives have a possible identity for a body in a burnt-out station wagon in north-west New South Wales and have appealed for more information.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b22552689a4014f473aaf7cc7fece89e</guid></item><item><title>Afghan women's refugee team return to international football amid calls for more autonomy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/fifa-afghanistan-women-refugee-team-pauline-hamill-khalida-popal/105654814</link><description>Australian-based players headline the Afghan women's refugee football team preparing to play for the first time since the Taliban takeover in 2021, but they're still pushing for greater autonomy over their future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0d7815cd16393d1fc9c4d303f42e392</guid></item><item><title>Jarred Drew Heath pleads guilty after pointing replica gun at police in Gatton caravan park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/jarred-drew-heath-guilty-assaulting-police-after-gatton-incident/105844036</link><description>Jarred Drew Heath told police he wished he had a bullet and an "AK" to shoot officers with.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf1a67e48829338e5f0f6558b2899a44</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth Bank fixes 'issue' affecting payments, online access and ATMs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/commonwealth-bank-commbank-outage-app-payments-atms/105844224</link><description>The bank says banking services, including payments, online access and ATMs, are now working.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a61a427b839d5abccc236282e3aa5e4</guid></item><item><title>Menindee fish passage trial aimed at preventing mass deaths enters second stage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/menindee-murray-darling-basin-fish-passage-trial-stage-two/105834850</link><description>A fish passage that connects the Darling River with Lake Wetherell in order to redistribute native fish is being trialled with the aim of preventing more ecological disasters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55ec4cb350395391058860ad9a46d492</guid></item><item><title>Players to watch this Sheffield Shield season ahead of Ashes Test summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/players-to-watch-in-sheffield-shield-season-for-ashes/105842346</link><description>With Australia's men's Test team largely settled, there are a few key spots that could hang on a handful of Sheffield Shield performances before the start of the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">789a6a04a5d751968e98ce58ea9ea421</guid></item><item><title>Max Verstappen has never won the F1 Singapore Grand Prix but has a chance as he chases Oscar Piastri and McLaren</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/max-verstappen-f1-singapore-grand-prix-oscar-piastri/105843662</link><description>Max Verstappen has won the previous two grands prix in Formula 1, but this weekend's race in Singapore is the only circuit on the calendar on which he has never triumphed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87e6eaeb3c042f6e16d829282d81e75c</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia boarding school collapse reflects a 'widespread' building problem</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/indonesia-boarding-school-collapse-reveal-building-flaw/105842728</link><description>An operation to rescue around 60 children trapped under an Islamic boarding school in Indonesia’s East Java province has now shifted into a recovery operation, with the death toll expected to significantly rise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23bfe7434da9ebb565a471325bafb552</guid></item><item><title>Organisers refuse offer to move Agnes Water festival off rainbow bee-eater bird nesting site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/1770-cultural-festival-fears-for-protected-bird-nests/105835892</link><description>A two-day cultural festival will go ahead this weekend on top of a protected bird's nesting site in Queensland after organisers declined an offer of help to relocate it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4434e606677c5097da9ee84055bb42e9</guid></item><item><title>Ley fires off letters, Albanese reminds everyone he's home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/albanese-trip-optus-crisis-sussan-ley-letter/105830528</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and opposition energy spokesperson Dan Tehan have both arrived home from trips abroad with a spring in their step.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6219bec9e7727d19bcd5b5a19e1e3221</guid></item><item><title>What to know about the international flotilla that sought to break Israel's blockade of Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/what-to-know-about-global-sumud-flotilla-gaza/105842900</link><description>The activists expected Israeli authorities to intercept them, as has happened in past flotilla attempts to reach Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4684825a8da0061bdbad1d685ccd055</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Kaylen Bassett wins bronze at ICF Slalom World Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/icf-slalom-world-championships-bassett-bronze/105844750</link><description>Australia's Kaylen Bassett manages Australia's first podium finish at the ICF Slalom World Championships in Penrith, while Olympic gold medallist Noémie Fox is left to reflect on what might have been.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c36f3ebff2b86d3940711747156cc086</guid></item><item><title>Retired detective hopes for justice in Cheryl Grimmer missing person case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/search-conducted-for-missing-child-cheryl-grimmer-remains/105841818</link><description>A retired detective is urging the man who once confessed to Cheryl Grimmer's murder to hand himself in, as volunteers search for her remains in Wollongong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a5cc40529897054c7661a9c21f1fadc</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Constance's Shoalhaven council CEO appointment to be probed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/investigation-after-andrew-constance-appointed-shoalhaven-ceo/105843568</link><description>The NSW Office of Local Government will investigate the appointment of former state minister Andrew Constance as the CEO of Shoalhaven City Council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdcfb2a15b8d24f408232acc12f76327</guid></item><item><title>Tesla and SpaceX CEO Elon Musk becomes world's first person to be valued over $500 billion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/elon-musk-worlds-richest/105844954</link><description>The Tesla and SpaceX CEO's net worth hit $US500 billion ($755 billion) on Wednesday, the "Real-Time Billionaires" tracker reported.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f5f4348c0e522fc29cd9a6ee3775837</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with lighting fires after start of fire bans in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/alleged-chinchilla-fire-starter-in-court-during-qld-fire-ban/105842770</link><description>A 27-year-old man has been charged with deliberately setting fire to bushland in Blackswamp, south-west Queensland, during a total fire ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">043ca5e23eb0529cbc5cb8bf7e1966fc</guid></item><item><title>Details of sophisticated drug distribution system run by teenager revealed in ACT Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/act-teenager-faces-court-for-running-sophisticated-drug-ring/105844950</link><description>Details of a sophisticated drug distribution system run by a teenager emerge after she pleads guilty to charges including attempting to possess a marketable quantity of cocaine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2be80fc3aada161e9b9e6812f55a6d1b</guid></item><item><title>Bryson's make-a-wish comes true with help of NSW Police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/bryson-police-officer-for-day-make-a-wish-foundation/105843866</link><description>For 12-year-old Bryson, being sworn in as an honorary NSW Police officer and heading his very own investigation in the heart of Sydney is a wish come true.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eda94484ceef36847d39f83a2e73d6a8</guid></item><item><title>South West Aboriginal Medical Service members expelled after allegedly 'storming' headquarters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/south-west-aboriginal-medical-service-members-expelled/105835570</link><description>The South West Aboriginal Medical Service has expelled several of its members who it has accused of sowing community division.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d58f590226ffd5ec4e623b45427995e</guid></item><item><title>Search for alleged Porepunkah gunman Dezi Freeman remains focused on Mount Buffalo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/dezi-freeman-porepunkah-search-remains-focused-on-mount-buffalo/105844636</link><description>An additional 100 specialist officers and search dogs from Queensland joined the search around Porepunkah this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe93be13f2539292b3dcfc5d80ce12dd</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies bolstered by Will Skelton's return for Bledisloe Cup Test against All Blacks in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/wallabies-all-blacks-bledisloe-cup-rugby-championship/105845674</link><description>The Wallabies regain enforcer Will Skelton for Saturday night's sold-out Bledisloe Cup Test in Perth, but veteran fly half James O'Connor is dropped to the bench.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77cf19e4d52cf3a8b1ad279f6be25948</guid></item><item><title>Review finds Barkly bushfire overwhelmed authorities and killed 37,000 cattle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/barkly-fire-killed-thousands-of-cattle-review-finds/105842564</link><description>The fire threatened communities, destroyed more than 3,500km of fencing and cost the NT's cattle industry an estimated $120 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf2f515eef61b0484d09c2a9ceec4e9f</guid></item><item><title>Part of a New York City apartment building collapses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/part-of-a-new-york-city-apartment-building/105844652</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">caef96935568c26c131d72b284279cdf</guid></item><item><title>Residents of a New York City apartment block escape unharmed after chimney collapses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/new-york-building-collapse/105843738</link><description>An explosion in a New York City apartment block has caused a brick chimney running 20 storeys up its side to collapse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e597db1388f0af7c0db89414d6c9a993</guid></item><item><title>Report into proposed Burswood racetrack finds noise concerns for locals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/burswood-racetrack-noise-concerns-report/105845314</link><description>Noise levels from a controversial motorsport racetrack planned for inner-city Perth are likely to be excessive for residents of nearby apartments and guests at the adjacent Crown entertainment complex, a new report finds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dde0f26a9c584b6ebb95b4b4c84f567</guid></item><item><title>Australian Army's new Apache attack helicopters arrive in Townsville</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/australian-army-apache-helicopters-arrive-in-townsville/105833650</link><description>The first two of 29 new attack helicopters acquired by the Australian Army have arrived in Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d09fdf76f9536875718f8e6e3d7ead6d</guid></item><item><title>Fertility treatments impacted by donor limit mix-up can proceed under NSW Health exemption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/fertility-treatments-to-proceed-after-nsw-health-exemption/105845260</link><description>Fertility treatments in NSW will be able to continue even in cases where the family donor limit has been breached after the state government issued a temporary exemption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7a47a0b5e094fc99008d0d76761db5b</guid></item><item><title>Colonnades, Modbury, Tea Tree and Rundle Mall among latest shopping centres to become Declared Public Precincts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/colonnades-modbury-tea-tree-plaza-rundle-mall-public-precincts/105844740</link><description>Three Adelaide shopping centres are among the latest sites where police can search for knives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e424510c86d4274f12853bc186cfbf98</guid></item><item><title>Coutts Crossing bushfire downgraded from emergency to advice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/coutts-crossing-bushfire-emergency-nsw-north-coast/105845190</link><description>A day into the bushfire season, a blaze threatening more than a dozen buildings in the Clarence Valley has been downgraded after escalating to an emergency level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">883abe4989535ef75a9a275843e0cfd0</guid></item><item><title>Who was Jane Goodall? Here's a look back at her life in photos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/jane-goodall-chimpanzees-photos-/105842700</link><description>Primatologist Jane Goodall has died aged 91, leaving behind an impressive legacy in science and conservation. Here's a look back at her life in photos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed6bf152f63bc75d080dd7d2fa4d7230</guid></item><item><title>The moment a thieving magpie snatches the earphone from Ash Azra's ear.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/thieving-magpie-snatches-the-earphone-from-cyclist-ear/105845816</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fda1a564ec6a0a0f796aed623a199700</guid></item><item><title>Canberra cyclist captures 'incredible' moment magpie plucks earphone from his ear on camera</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/magpie-swoop-pluck-earphone-from-ear-captured-camera/105845372</link><description>A Canberra man has captured footage of the dramatic moment a magpie plucked his earphone from his ear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b576bf57bf07e8e6ec534073ae5af4a1</guid></item><item><title>Demons meet with Clayton Oliver amid rumoured exit from AFL club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/afl-melbourne-demons-clayton-oliver-christian-petracca/105845936</link><description>Clayton Oliver appears set to leave Melbourne after the Demons reveal they will not stand in his way if he wants to consider a trade to another club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd9730e9523ad122afacace37169f5a2</guid></item><item><title>Broncos respond to Storm star Stefano Utoikamanu's 'stuck up' barb ahead of NRL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/nrl-grand-final-brisbane-broncos-melbourne-storm/105846050</link><description>The mind games continue in the build-up to Sunday's season decider, with the Broncos reacting to Storm front-rower Stefano Utoikamanu's sledge earlier this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">108176c74a5c4c7627684927f34b7745</guid></item><item><title>Endangered numbats stressed by over-eager nature photographers, authorities say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/photographers-urged-to-maintain-distance-from-numbats-wa/105844130</link><description>Authorities say getting to close to numbats can make them anxious enough to abandon their young and are urging photographers to give the endangered animals their space.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67cb631989ddbc5dd6344e8eb42942fe</guid></item><item><title>Mildura leaders label Qantas staff base closure a 'slap in the face' to region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/closure-of-mildura-qantas-staff-base-slammed-by-politicians/105839232</link><description>Regional politicians unanimously condemn Qantas over the impending closure of its Mildura crew base, saying it underscores the city's vulnerability to the "whims" of private transport companies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36df8aca49b62a9d5ccd4097b776a5df</guid></item><item><title>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy accuses Russia of raising nuclear risk after Chernobyl power cut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/ukraine-accuses-russia-of-raising-nuclear-risk-chernobyl/105846000</link><description>Volodymyr Zelenskyy said more than 20 Russian drones had been deployed in the attack on the town of Slavutych that cut power to the nearby Chernobyl plant for three hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdc2f2d1ffa9520461b858bd3a31e5c0</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/105846282</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40beaae9cbc027d987206ec2f8fee66f</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire threatens homes outside Coutts Crossing on NSW north coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/bushfire-threatens-homes-outside-coutts-crossing/105846250</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38c2ee3a07eb338d2112c7dd7a7fdae4</guid></item><item><title>Review into senior NT police appointments made under ousted commissioner released to the public</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/review-into-nt-police-senior-appointments-released/105845308</link><description>An inquiry into recruitment processes for senior NT police positions recommends "significant improvements", noting there are "widely held beliefs" that "bias", "favouritism" and "nepotism" have impacted promotions within the force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">439354def5398861162db68ac6aadc7b</guid></item><item><title>Arrests at pro-Palestinian rally at Sydney Town Hall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/arrests-at-pro-palestinian-rally-at-sydney-town/105846320</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa0909ad8e3a3576275d103a6d89c680</guid></item><item><title>BBC exposes hidden culture of misogyny and racism inside UK Police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/bbc-filming-exposes-hidden-culture-of-misogyny-and-racism-inside/105846128</link><description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer has called for a "robust" response by the head of London's Metropolitan Police after an undercover investigation exposed the force's hidden culture of misogyny and racism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a5e49ee8734de794306f0e01d0f37e5</guid></item><item><title>Protesters restrained at snap pro-Palestinian rally at Sydney Town Hall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/nsw-floatilla-protest-sydney-town-hall-police-restrain/105846204</link><description>The unauthorised event was held in response to the interception of a Gaza-bound aid flotilla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d349b964559368d88442b48dbc749c73</guid></item><item><title>Fears the expanded Home Guarantee Scheme will send property prices into overdrive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/fears-the-expanded-home-guarantee-scheme-will-send/105846400</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db40f12f71ec90bfbf785eb0d3e03094</guid></item><item><title>State premiers in funding clash with federal government over health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/state-premiers-in-funding-clash-with-federal/105846414</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5f1d6bdd7618f3ae079c69ca29098a2</guid></item><item><title>Director James Cameron: There needs to be “massive guardrails” around AI</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/director-james-cameron:-there-needs-to-be-%E2%80%9Cmassive/105846420</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7375b7238d33857cf34b0267389c312c</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm and Brisbane Broncos face off in NRL Grand Final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/melbourne-storm-and-brisbane-broncos-face-off-in/105846424</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7c17a506df456fc9c620d5c07d1e268</guid></item><item><title>One of nature’s fiercest protectors, Dr Jane Goodall, dies at age 91</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/one-of-nature%E2%80%99s-fiercest-protectors,-dr-jane/105846432</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4834f867eea0755799498b4bc68992a8</guid></item><item><title>Four people injured after car ramming and stabbing outside Manchester synagogue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-02/people-injured-synagogue-attack-manchester/105846410</link><description>Four people have been injured after a car was reportedly driven at pedestrians and people were stabbed near a synagogue in Manchester, British police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c5e6627daeeefa8748a2db262478f45</guid></item></channel></rss>