<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 07:46:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Exploitation claims have been levelled against cruise ship company Carnival. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/carnival-cruise-exploitation-claims-what-we-know/106325788</link><description>A major cruise ship has been investigated by the maritime safety regulator for claims around poor working conditions. A spokesperson for The Carnival Cruise Line says it has "nothing to hide" and welcomes AMSA's oversight. Here's what we know so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fb766396c9c7d4da6c405ce6634ae51</guid></item><item><title>Sydney man avoids jail over 'abhorrent' social media posts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nsw-man-avoids-jail-over-threatening-pm-via-social-media-posts/106326690</link><description>A Sydney man who made "abhorrent" social media posts that promoted sexual violence and threatened the prime minister has been spared time in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17d442d03f2268671f08f95e7ebe2047</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds rally against police response to night of violent protest clashes in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nine-charged-sydney-protest-isaac-herzog-protest/106326288</link><description>Hundreds of protesters have gathered outside a police station in Sydney to criticise the force's response to Monday night's rally against the visit of Israeli President Isaac Herzog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c07cd60e5cebc012e0adb7e616dc9f7f</guid></item><item><title>Mackay MP Nigel Dalton crosses the floor to oppose LNP ban on abortion debate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nigel-dalton-crosses-floor-opposing-lnp-abortion-debate-ban/106327032</link><description>First-term Liberal National Party MP Nigel Dalton votes to overturn a ban on debating abortion — in defiance of his party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c85acc349c94f7e5ef78c2f5a8611f2</guid></item><item><title>Grace Tame criticised for leading intifada chants at Sydney protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/grace-tame-criticised-for-sydney-protest-intifada-chant/106326896</link><description>Grace Tame accuses Australia of being "a so-called democracy" that punishes peaceful protesters, before chanting "from Gadigal to Gaza, globalise the intifada!"</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9dc912a9d76603ba103ace6885715f4</guid></item><item><title>Deadline looms for Warren Tredrea to pay Nine's legal costs after failed appeal against unfair dismissal case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/warren-treadrea-deadline-to-pay-legal-costs-to-nine/106326298</link><description>Former footballer Warren Tredrea has an imminent deadline to pay $149,000 to his former employer, Channel Nine, following a failed appeal against an unfair dismissal case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8204048fc3858d5ea8943a955cc6d4ba</guid></item><item><title>At school, I was my brother's protector. But I needed more support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/support-i-wish-i-had-at-school-while-caring-for-my-brother/106279156</link><description>I was my brother's protector at school, but the education system could have done more to support us both.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8737a14dea75637ab0e525bab21121a9</guid></item><item><title>Global Athlete accuses IOC of 'kowtowing' to Russia by including AIN athletes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/russian-winter-olympic-athletes-milan-cortina/106327282</link><description>Advocacy group Global Athlete has accused the IOC of enabling Russia by allowing 13 Russian and seven Belarusian athletes to compete at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c9a39c00f74fc512b507557d2b1ac8f</guid></item><item><title>Craig Goodwin's World Cup hopes cop hammer blow after groin injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/craig-goodwin-s-world-cup-hopes-dashed/106327940</link><description>He was one of the Socceroos best in Qatar but now Craig Goodwin will need a minor miracle to make this year's World Cup after the veteran suffered a groin injury for Adelaide United that will sideline him for some time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">832f24e225d388d7831d181361338c99</guid></item><item><title>Shark filmed in deep Antarctic waters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/shark-filmed-in-deep-antarctic-waters/106321640</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4eb3f0f8027a13b7cb77a572c9acacff</guid></item><item><title>Elvis Presley 'unguarded' in unseen footage used in new Baz Luhrmann film</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/elvis-presley-unguarded-in-unseen-footage-in-baz-luhrmann-film/106327408</link><description>When director Baz Luhrmann and his team uncovered hours of previously unseen Elvis Presley recordings, Luhrmann abandoned his original plans, deciding to "get out of the way" and let Presley tell his own story.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18a8befc1c6399e513d75719298bd33a</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man staged scene and lied to Triple Zero after murdering his partner, court documents reveal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/adam-britt-staged-murder-tiffany-spence-act-supreme-court/106327390</link><description>New details have emerged about the murder of Canberra woman Tiffany Spence, as court documents show her partner staged the scene before calling Triple Zero.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">160376561c043d82e2e0548892ecf6e5</guid></item><item><title>Tahmoor Coal placed into administration as court hears creditor winding-up bid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/tahmoor-coal-mine-placed-into-voluntary-administration/106326534</link><description>Tahmoor Coal has been placed into voluntary administration just as the Supreme Court was set to hear a creditor's winding-up application.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">953d7d3b73b007feb1525c6e38b10dea</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government appoints tenderers for new oil and gas exploration in Taroom Trough</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/oil-gas-exploration-queensland-taroom-trough/106325922</link><description>The Queensland government approves new oil and gas exploration in a region they believe could become Australia's first new major oil province in 50 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ce99f23603aeb7aa96f732ac4f261b6</guid></item><item><title>Ex-student tells court of pregnancy scare after alleged abuse by Hobart Matriculation College teacher</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/hobart-matriculation-college-former-student-gives-evidence-rape/106326618</link><description>When recounting the first time her former teacher allegedly raped her, the woman told the court he was "like a big monster" on top of her and she "could hardly breathe". The woman is suing both her former teacher and the State of Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffa175ff6b6b2b70b45b9744a5d361fb</guid></item><item><title>Raymond Reddington murder trial hears Sharon Fulton seemed scared in hours before 1986 disappearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/sharon-fulton-murder-trial-raymond-reddington-woman-was-scared/106327376</link><description>A close friend of a woman allegedly murdered by her husband in Perth 40 years ago tells a Perth court she seemed frightened in the hours before her disappearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78ffe88ad62d326c893e3ac20446550a</guid></item><item><title>Top barrister and charity boss Mark Philip Dennis dead after child abuse arrest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/barrister-mark-dennis-dead-child-abuse-arrest/106328484</link><description>The 60-year-old was found dead at his Leichhardt unit in Sydney's inner west on Monday evening, NSW Police said in a statement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89ae82097c264f14c6bb51a0c601ca54</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106326714</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f1e6a5abe89487f45e90e88fb30e856</guid></item><item><title>Cam Bolton fractures neck as training falls rule two Aussies out of Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/winter-olympics-2026-live-milano-cortina-moguls-ice-hockey/106326694</link><description>Australia's Cam Bolton and Misaki Vaughan are ruled out of the Games after training falls, while reigning Olympic gold medallist Jakara Anthony advances to the women's moguls final at the Milano Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf10d0c49b40e45eace54bd9ee12cefa</guid></item><item><title>Australian government puts pressure on Lao authorities over methanol poisoning deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/methanol-poisoning-holly-bowles-bianca-morton-jones-laos/106328530</link><description>The Australian government calls in the Lao ambassador in Canberra, amid criticism of the country's response to a fatal methanol poisoning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc5e186c3bcd06980d9bd00b9b489bd6</guid></item><item><title>Former NT police officer James Kirstenfeldt sentenced on drink driving, weapons offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nt-james-kirstenfeldt-sentenced-drink-driving-weapons-charges/106313314</link><description>A former Northern Territory police officer has been ordered to pay almost $5,000 in fines and undergo supervised treatment for post-traumatic stress disorder after drunkenly crashing his car outside his suburban Darwin home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94f3ae08a6978aeffd227f1b28acd709</guid></item><item><title>Health warnings about ultra-processed foods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/health-warnings-about-ultra-processed-foods/106328288</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52af8963f7db51a368846c06aa60a304</guid></item><item><title>Liberals plot resignations to pave way for leadership challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/liberals-plot-mass-resignation-to-force-leadership-spill-/106328762</link><description>Liberals are bracing for a wave of frontbench resignations as soon as Wednesday to pave the way for Angus Taylor to mount a leadership challenge against Sussan Ley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68227eb101c335608129c57bdf313d7f</guid></item><item><title>WA police investigate possible tobacco wars link to fire at Kelmscott store</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/fire-alleged-linked-to-illicit-tobacco-under-investigation/106325512</link><description>WA Police Commissioner Col Blanch confirms officers from Taskforce Maverick, which investigates crime linked to the illicit tobacco and vape trade, are involved with the investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c193a813072c7da9378b52e50d8e27c3</guid></item><item><title>Police warn against 'false hope' as cold case search bones identified as 'non‑human'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/bones-found-in-yatina-search-not-human/106325728</link><description>Bone fragments found during a private search for evidence relating to the disappearance of two girls in 1973 are "not human remains", according to police, who have issued a public warning against actions that create "false hope".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8578a06110098fdaac062e5d7e5de7e0</guid></item><item><title>Three key moments in police clashes with Sydney protesters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nsw-police-israel-herzog-protest-town-hall-key-moments/106325680</link><description>Competing narratives have emerged from NSW Police and protesters who were at Monday night's demonstration near Sydney's Town Hall. ABC NEWS Verify has gathered footage and spoken to witnesses in an early attempt to examine what happened in detail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55bfcaef3544b431846d0937470d213b</guid></item><item><title>Bulk-billing rates rebound on back of government's multi-billion-dollar policy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/bulk-billing-rates-rebound-after-multi-billion-dollar-investment/106327456</link><description>Bulk-billing rates have rebounded in the first clear measure of the impact of the government's multi-billion-dollar pledge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d77c00d7ce459a8883fdcf39108f49f</guid></item><item><title>Rental affordability hits record low as rents rise 2.5 times faster than wages, analysis shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/rental-affordability-rents-rise-faster-than-wages-cotality/106327364</link><description>Tenants now pay an average of 33.4 per cent of their pre-tax income on rent, which is the highest level on record, according to a property research firm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6fc06f379d9dabc4c56af45e59d226cc</guid></item><item><title>ASIO ordered independent review into Bondi terror case, stands by 2019 assessment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/asio-ordered-independent-review-into-bondi-terror-case/106329140</link><description>The nation's top spy has welcomed a royal commission into the Bondi terror attack, vowing to "own any mistakes" uncovered by the probe as his agency comes under pressure over whether the tragedy could have been prevented.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29ab83ff049297eda1f7acea4b877675</guid></item><item><title>The desperate toll of Australia's 2026 Winter Olympic Games injury chaos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/australian-injury-hell-at-2026-winter-olympic-games/106329260</link><description>Games-ending injuries to Cam Bolton and Misaki Vaughan have emphasised the dangers of winter sport as the Australian team copes with issues early in the Milano Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f1a5314017e313b221ef7737afe9b23</guid></item><item><title>Israel tightens grip over West Bank while Herzog visits Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/isaac-herzog-visit-protest-police-west-bank-annexation/106325902</link><description>While Israeli President Isaac Herzog visited Sydney, his government was taking concrete actions in the West Bank designed to "continue to kill the idea of a Palestinian state".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">728001663fca5f0a0371d55a7b3d1249</guid></item><item><title>FBI releases surveillance pictures of masked man at Nancy Guthrie's home on morning she disappeared</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/fbi-release-pictures-of-masked-man-at-nancy-guthries-home/106329322</link><description>FBI director Kash Patel has posted the images on social media, saying they had been recovered after days of work by investigators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">728b1ecdd6098f978fa86fe8a55eede2</guid></item><item><title>Protesters were punched, pushed, and arrested but were NSW Police actions excessive?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/verify-police-use-of-force-town-hall-protest/106328358</link><description>What is reasonable? It's a question being asked by some after footage of clashes in Sydney's CBD, during a rally against Israeli President Isaac Herzog's visit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc032833c827cf116d697c6b10faca22</guid></item><item><title>The Epstein files are shaking Britain, but Donald Trump could still have 3 million reasons to worry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/epstein-files-shake-uk-but-white-house-could-still-be-worried/106324788</link><description>Donald Trump's enemies made no secret of their hopes the documents would contain something explosive enough to bring the president down, but right now the Epstein spotlight is on Britain's politicians and palaces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd62bb34a29f437c14df3ee1992e6c76</guid></item><item><title>Uber quietly agrees to external review after woman sues over guide dog refusals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/uber-agrees-to-review-after-guide-dog-refusal-case/106307858</link><description>Uber quietly agrees to an external review of its Australian operations after settling a Federal Court case brought by a woman refused more than 30 rides while travelling with a guide dog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7dae27423705f7913b0c26f0c1f43a5</guid></item><item><title>Jakara Anthony picture perfect, Matt Graham with room to improve at 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games moguls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/jakara-anthony-matt-graham-pressure-moguls-qualifiers/106324214</link><description>Jakara Anthony will do anything aside from thinking about moguls skiing after qualifying number one for Wednesday's 2026 Winter Olympics final, taking to Lego, a puzzle and Grey's Anatomy instead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c5b1f5d3da4862fb201d76474dc2318</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberals face wipeout not seen since state bank election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/sa-liberals-face-wipeout-not-seen-since-state-bank-election/106325582</link><description>Labor faced a humiliating election loss following the state bank collapse in the early 90s. Now, recent polling shows a collapse of another kind could be brewing for the Liberal Party with One Nation hot on its heels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d37b7dfeb9d62359f82edf2221b3e29</guid></item><item><title>How 'capacity constraints' are linked to inflation and your hip pocket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/what-are-capacity-constraints-economic-growth-inflation-rba/106322390</link><description>It may sound boring, but "capacity constraints" are to blame for your higher mortgage repayments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">945ab804992cc48ca6c41e4f4a2a3d57</guid></item><item><title>Food ministers move closer to mandating Health Star Ratings on packaged food</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/move-to-mandate-health-star-ratings-on-food-and-drink/106231700</link><description>The nation's food ministers will this week take a crucial step towards mandating the Health Star Rating scheme on packaged food products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d49aa89b821cfcbaa27037bef0288134</guid></item><item><title>How to reduce loneliness while working remotely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/how-to-reduce-loneliness-while-working-remotely/106286338</link><description>Working remotely can be a lonely experience. Here's what you can do about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07ee38b05fb1af72edee6be374ac35ed</guid></item><item><title>Hume City Council wants action over thousands of tyres dumped in Melbourne's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/illegal-tyre-dumping-and-hume-council-action/106328912</link><description>A council in Melbourne's north wants the federal government to establish a free tyre recycling scheme to stop thousands of tyres being dumped, causing a potential environmental hazard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1abf383c1d01a41e7eb877b26adf62af</guid></item><item><title>Cricket umpire numbers rise since COVID, but regions still in 'dire' need</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/victorian-cricket-umpires-referee-shortage/106313892</link><description>Cricket umpire numbers increase significantly in Victoria, but some regions remain in desperate need.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c25e208a1280b6ca42f95914eb0b617</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor resigns from Liberal frontbench ahead of expected leadership spill — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/federal-politics-estimates-albanese-ley-herzog/106328310</link><description>Angus Taylor has resigned from the shadow frontbench ahead of an expected Liberal leadership spill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9652a4c3a8e2cd737e83d0b30398df6</guid></item><item><title>Australian T20 World Cup squad looks different but do not count it out, Mitch Marsh says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/injury-hit-australia-open-t20-world-cup-campaign-against-ireland/106329438</link><description>Despite a slew of key injuries leaving the Australian team unrecognisable, captain Mitch Marsh is confident about the experience left in the side.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e7e79b7afbfde0a033b919098cc0b12</guid></item><item><title>Limestone Coast hospital's staff shortage in spotlight after former administrator's fall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/limestone-coast-hospital-staff-shortage/106318896</link><description>David Walshaw spent 20 years looking after the Limestone Coast's hospitals, but a fall made him realise the system was failing patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63b01408b05a077885b47352dd28bbdc</guid></item><item><title>Surgeon Kelvin Kong's life growing up Chinese and Indigenous in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/kelvin-kong-s-growing-up-chinese-and-indigenous-australia/106326388</link><description>Australia's first identified First Nations surgeon, Dr Kelvin Kong spoke about his Malaysian Chinese heritage during the annual Wang Gungwu lecture at Parliament House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3366e9b48200b228bb48ce12f315720</guid></item><item><title>Citizen scientists work on 100-million-year-old ichthyosaur fossil in Winton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/ichthyosaur-winton-australian-age-of-dinosaurs-fossil/106310754</link><description>Participants from across Australia and the world travelled to outback Queensland to clean up the near-complete ichthyosaur fossil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af8a6ea34ab1f32371b167c057d77dd9</guid></item><item><title>Feral camels wreaking havoc in remote communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/naus_nrcamels_1102/106329560</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39d1f28190cf1e1b316f199910e1f838</guid></item><item><title>Images of alleged tobacco wars kingpin Kazem Hamad released in Iraq</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/images-of-kazem-hamad-released-by-afp/106329460</link><description>Hamad was deported from Australia in 2023 and has been a key person of interest relating to firebombings at Victorian tobacco shops and businesses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e824b5d9e2cfb1c10502ba2cb1ccb7d</guid></item><item><title>Trump told police chief 'everyone' knew about Epstein, FBI document says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/trump-commerce-chief-claims-no-relationship-with-epstein/106329468</link><description>Donald Trump allegedly told police in 2006 that people in New York knew about Epstein, a newly uncovered FBI interview shows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3c205dcd4860dd580cc592880560660</guid></item><item><title>Five-year-old girl killed in ATV rollover on Queensland's Western Downs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/girl-5-killed-atv-rollover-queensland-property/106329550</link><description>A young girl has died and a boy has been injured after an ATV being driven by a child rolled rolled on a rural property near Chinchilla on Tuesday evening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdda000adf2d614bb5aca14a04fad009</guid></item><item><title>Volunteers say neglect by state's wildlife department caused bushfires on WA's south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/fitzgerald-river-bushfire-dbca-mismanagement/106321810</link><description>Farmers and volunteer firefighters say decades of neglect by WA's Department of Biodiversity, Conservation and Attractions is at the heart of fires that ripped through more than 200,000 hectares of state-managed land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40f45582a4045e521119758ac54edc75</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Stunning cheating admission overshadows medal win as Naumov brings tears with tribute — quick hits from day four</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/sport-quick-hits-winter-olympics-day-four-cheating-nauov-tribute/106329142</link><description>A Norwegian's first-ever medal is overshadowed by a stunning admission to reporters as Maxim Naumov pays tribute to his parents in the most beautiful way. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4ddae6dcef41de86448ed66a84d4881</guid></item><item><title>Western quoll joey born in outback NSW likely to be first in a century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/western-quoll-thrive-outback-nsw-after-taronga-program/106304882</link><description>Once thought to be extinct in NSW, the small, spotted, and highly photogenic western quoll is making a hard-fought comeback to the wild.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1127d8b0dfa1ad403186fda2e24d1f68</guid></item><item><title>Fateful wrong turn, quiet cancer battle possible factors in missing prospector's suspected death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/barry-podmore-inquest-potential-wrong-turn/106328254</link><description>An inquest into Barry Podmore's disappearance in WA's remote Wheatbelt hears the 73-year-old was waging a private battle with cancer and may have become lost in bushland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70fd4d4de62cfa6ad418be560e1027f2</guid></item><item><title>What 30 years on the domestic violence front line taught police negotiator Vincent Hurley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/conversations-vince-hurley-domestic-violence-hostage-negotiation/106224980</link><description>Years on the front line of domestic violence surfaced in a frustration-filled moment on national television for Vincent Hurley. He explains what motivates him to keep fighting for change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bbd7954a3ffef22e74026708d401305</guid></item><item><title>Race against bulldozers to save ancient grass trees in WA's South West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/race-to-save-grass-trees-south-west-wa/106323778</link><description>Some of WA's oldest grass trees are being rescued from land clearing and development amid a population and property boom, preserving a unique part of the South West's natural heritage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c035d16240b39fbe758a3a7788f5176</guid></item><item><title>Queensland records first outbreak of Mimosa pigra — giant sensitive tree — in 25 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/giant-sensitive-tree-mimosa-pigra-detected-in-qld/106327380</link><description>A giant sensitive tree infestation has been detected near a lake near Brisbane and authorities say they have "no idea" how it got there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d606b67f355e1baa958386464d8e8d19</guid></item><item><title>Rental prices in WA soar 66pc in five years, the biggest increase in the nation, Cotality data shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/wa-rents-soar-66pc-in-five-years-the-biggest-increase-in-nation/106329614</link><description>The cost of renting in WA has soared 66 per cent over the past five years, the biggest increase in the nation and 3.5 times more than the rise in wages, according to data from property research firm Cotality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f861bd35a332fcf536510ba0b39fef07</guid></item><item><title>Dungeons and Dragons-inspired game breaks down social barriers for neurodivergent kids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/dungeons-and-dragons-inspired-game-for-neurodivergent-kids/106321560</link><description>An Adelaide clinical psychologist creates a simplified version of Dungeons and Dragons to help neurodivergent children and young people learn social skills and develop peer connections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6f190df99526fce8245046efec4cbf7</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos striker Mo Toure scores hat-trick on starting debut in English Championship for Norwich</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/socceroos-striker-mohamed-toure-hat-trick-debut-norwich/106330220</link><description>Mohamed Toure moved to England recently on a $5 million deal and it is already looking like a great decision for the 21-year-old forward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ecfd2aa16103898748a1ab83e8c75e7</guid></item><item><title>High Court finds Catholic Church liable for priest's sexual abuse but halves compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/high-court-catholic-church-liable-priest-sexual-abuse/106329926</link><description>A man who suffered sexual abuse at the hands of a priest in the 1960s has won his High Court battle over liability, but had his compensation nearly halved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">115a801497fb65d312764e99856603d5</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth Bank shares rise after CBA reports increased profits as it lifts home lending volumes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/cba-shares-up-increased-profits-first-half-financial-year/106329968</link><description>CBA's net profit for the first half of the financial year rose 5 per cent to $5.367 billion, beating analyst expectations, on the back of increased lending and deposit volumes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dbf165da5a6dc26e708af53e3360fc9</guid></item><item><title>Milano Cortina 2026 is the most gender-equal Winter Olympics ever, aside from Nordic Combined</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/winter-olympics-2026-milan-cortina-nordic-combined-inequality/105991114</link><description>Nordic Combined is the only sport at any Olympic Games — summer and winter — that does not have an event for women. It's an omission that is putting the entire future of the sport at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1a0f1fcfce4eb1284b220db9b93d2fd</guid></item><item><title>Outgoing Queensland Police Commissioner Steve Gollschewki confident service 'heading in right direction'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/police-commissioner-gollschewski-retires-amid-cancer-diagnosis/106329604</link><description>Police Commissioner Steve Gollschewski has announced his retirement to focus on his family and health after a 46-year career with the service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdc395f5464b0622d6318ea4963cc02d</guid></item><item><title>Perth Festival opens with outdoor music, light sculptures and stories shared via old red telephone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/perth-festival-opens/106328574</link><description>Australia's longest running arts event, the Perth Festival, began on the weekend with Humans of New York-style videos in which locals tell their stories using an old red telephone on a bridge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">471448dd08cd988b876b0d8d841cb742</guid></item><item><title>Former Gidarjil CEO Kerry Blackman to face trial on five charges of sexual assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/kerry-blackman-to-stand-trial-on-sexual-assault-charges/106327292</link><description>Kerry Blackman will face trial in the Bundaberg District Court in June, charged with five counts of sexual assault.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7deebe3550be4f8148a82c0beb111e66</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 5, Wednesday, February 11</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide/106325628</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4808821c5d5c5ad794f816a30958d89</guid></item><item><title>DPP apologises after office 'dropped the ball' over police officer assault case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/sa-police-grant-stevens-concerned-about-police-assault/106329878</link><description>A court decision in which a woman who assaulted a South Australian police officer with a glass bottle was spared jail prompts an extraordinary concession from the Director of Public Prosecutions (DPP).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8f6d35fb3085ec7867365bd29fc6a55</guid></item><item><title>Missing man Corey Chugg separated from friend while collecting firewood, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/search-for-missing-man-corey-chugg-in-tasmania/106328680</link><description>A 32-year-old man missing in Tasmania's north was collecting firewood with a friend when the pair became separated on Sunday, police have said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e1ef0edf011bcec194b5dfaf7f996fe</guid></item><item><title>Person detained for questioning over disappearance of Nancy Guthrie, Arizona law enforcement says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/nancy-guthrie-person-detained-questioning-kidnapping/106331392</link><description>Law officials in Arizona say a person has been detained for questioning in relation to the disappearance of Nancy Guthrie, the 84-year-old mother of Today show host Savannah.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c03d86c8d87c3051a49958cd259c0fd</guid></item><item><title>Police say there was 'serious, imminent risk' of child kidnapping in Perth by Jason William Forbes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/baldivis-child-kidnapper-jason-william-forbes-update/106327906</link><description>WA Police say "something terrible" could have happened if there was a delay in intercepting a Baldivis man who planned to abduct and sexually abuse a child in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9cb2e1663474710cf734cdb38d48828</guid></item><item><title>Doongmabulla Springs decision leaves Qld government to weigh appeal or face trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/doongmabulla-springs-qld-government-appeal-or-face-trial/106305714</link><description>Wangan and Jagalingou peoples await the state government's next move after a win in their fight to have alleged damage to a sacred site near a mine in Central Queensland investigated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">409498e1a5333e429fc6fc92646dec77</guid></item><item><title>Two more Chinese nationals accused of foreign interference after allegedly gathering information in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/chinese-nationals-accused-foreign-interference-canberra/106331328</link><description>A task force investigated the alleged covert collection of information about a Canberra Buddhist association.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a1ec680cbea7b7a88f62860b8627475</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia readies up to 8,000 troops for Board of Peace efforts in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/indonesia-to-send-8000-troops-to-gaza-idf-peacekeeping/106330718</link><description>The move makes Indonesia the first country to clearly commit troops to a multinational peacekeeping effort in the war-torn enclave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb09709ab6a43276c0ef5777b42146b8</guid></item><item><title>No body-worn video evidence available for inquest into Krista Kach's death, coroner hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/krista-kach-inquest-no-body-worn-camera-evidence/106330358</link><description>A court hears a NSW inquest will need to rely on eyewitness accounts of the 2023 death of Krista Kach, who was shot with a beanbag round following a 10-hour stand-off with police in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e1eb69fc8206627f42ed509806f3904</guid></item><item><title>What to watch in February, from puppy love to Muppet hijinks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/what-to-watch-the-muppets-scrubs/106325818</link><description>Kermit, Miss Piggy and the rest of the crew are back to celebrate their 50th birthday with a one-off special that has the potential to turn into a whole new series for the beloved characters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09b335d5b372e0742b8c096839af2dff</guid></item><item><title>Dinosaur dig on Victoria's Bass Coast uncovers more than 60 bones and fossils</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/dinosaur-dig-at-inverloch-finds-bones-and-fossils/105904132</link><description>A collection of more than 60 dinosaur bones and fossils are unearthed from rocks at the site of a fossil dig in Victoria's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d67f1ab883871846b55d6387f0f8bd4a</guid></item><item><title>Perth brothers Nezir and Enver Ibrahimovic avoid jail for assault at Scarborough bar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/bouncers-avoid-jail-scarborough-bar-assault/106331266</link><description>Two brothers working as bouncers when they assaulted a man at a Scarborough bar avoid jail after a magistrate recognised the trauma they suffered in the Bosnian war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78455998eac3b4222b694f47d3f06d7a</guid></item><item><title>Mother of teenager allegedly assaulted by NSW Police at Sydney protest to press charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/nsw-police-protest-allegedly-assaulted-teenager-mother-claims/106329674</link><description>The mother of a 16-year-old who alleges he was "pushed, kicked, dragged on the ground" by officers at a Sydney protest against the Israeli president's visit says she wants to press charges against police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30d0c8531d4d566ed060274bb1773187</guid></item><item><title>Cryptosporidium cluster at Waterworld leads to closure of Adelaide Aquatic Centre pools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/adelaide-aquatic-centres-close-after-cluster-of-gastro-cases/106330324</link><description>SA Health is urging people with gastroenteritis symptoms not to visit public swimming pools after eight cases at one swimming centre, including one child who was hospitalised and another who also visited the Adelaide Aquatic Centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">feaa7c2df6769e23acd9a68078708dfc</guid></item><item><title>Axed literary magazine Meanjin is resurrected by Queensland University of Technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/meanjin-magazine-finds-new-home-queensland-university-technology/106331850</link><description>The 85-year-old literary journal Meanjin will return to Brisbane, where it was first published, after it was controversially closed by Melbourne University Press last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8381f55200bc2cef76893ac168c73d93</guid></item><item><title>Telstra to axe up to 650 roles in mass redundancy round, some jobs to be outsourced to India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/telstra-axes-600-roles-in-redundancy-round-outsourcing-to-india/106331708</link><description>Telstra notifies staff of plans to outsource hundreds of jobs to an India-based technology company.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a54d2039d987947db967f7534c2af1d8</guid></item><item><title>Former Carlton legend Peter Dean hospitalised after serious assault in Albury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/former-carlton-legend-suffers-serious-assault-in-albury/106331586</link><description>Former AFL player Peter Dean is recovering in hospital after he sustained serious head and facial injuries in an alleged assault at Albury on the New South Wales Victorian border.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4ceb1d2b4738f0666d773a5bf7a2435</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Tropical Cyclone Mitchell brings damage and rain to farmers in WA's south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/strong-winds-wreak-havoc-on-farm-properties-wheatbelt-region/106329960</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says a weather system influenced by ex-Tropical Cyclone Mitchell delivered storms to the Great Southern and central Wheatbelt this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe2f4307942ad8b54d9b5037e79ee1e6</guid></item><item><title>US politician Ro Khanna reveals names of six 'powerful men' scrubbed from Epstein files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/ro-khanna-reveals-names-redacted-from-epstein-files/106331712</link><description>US politician Ro Khanna has publicly named six men whose identities were scrubbed from the Epstein files, including the former boss of Victoria's Secret, who the FBI suspected was a co-conspirator of the sex offender's crimes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5436a5f0bc8f114fceefe16bdeef79e9</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide's own a medal contender for US in women's double luge at Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/winter-olympics-chevonne-forgan-womens-doubles-luge-adelaide/106331288</link><description>The driest state in the driest country of the world might seem the unlikeliest of places for a star in the Winter Olympics sport of luge to emerge, but Chevonne Forgan will be a medal contender tonight — albeit for Team USA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8190dc66c1226686cb38afb044c221c4</guid></item><item><title>Supersized fatberg clogging Sydney sewer blamed for mysterious debris balls on beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/supersized-fatberg-clogging-sydney-sewer-debris-balls/106309658</link><description>The debris balls that have washed up on NSW beaches in recent years are likely to continue as Sydney Water admits a massive fatberg it cannot reach is clogging sewers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e47536114404d9c787ba564b5b869472</guid></item><item><title>Mum of motorcyclist fatally hit by car tells court of 'immeasurable' devastation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/victim-impact-statement-after-motorcyclist-killed-in-crash/106331510</link><description>A grieving mother whose 21-year-old son died after he was struck by a car while riding his motorcycle south of Adelaide tells a court of her devastation and issues a plea to drivers to "check, double check and check again" for bikes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd9c850d55ea31fc30c7fe349201dec0</guid></item><item><title>Ex-student tells court alleged abuse by Matriculation College teacher led to theft and 'warped' relationships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/hobart-matriculation-college-former-student-gives-evidence-rape/106332498</link><description>A woman suing her former teacher has told a court that the alleged abuse impacted her future relationships and "warped" her professional boundaries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa634835bf36571a04b2a810f331b12b</guid></item><item><title>NSW soccer coach Tullio 'Tony' Giacomo Cigana jailed over child abuse material</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/nsw-soccer-coach-jailed-over-child-abuse-material/106332804</link><description>A once well-regarded soccer coach has been handed a 12 month jail sentence for possessing child abuse material, after a Sydney court heard he has been disowned by family members.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46189d96dae7bf43bc8498eec2003538</guid></item><item><title>New video sheds light on beginning of altercation between police officers and Town Hall protester</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/-white-shirt-man-town-hall-protests-punched-new-video/106332094</link><description>A new video filmed by a bystander and shared with ABC NEWS Verify shows the full minute before two police officers began punching a protester, shedding light on the beginning of the altercation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4fecc044fc46d6003450c9200ac8eba</guid></item><item><title>Bondi: Path to Terror</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/bondi-path-to-terror-four-corners/106332752</link><description>Four Corners is the home of Australian investigative journalism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3e3ec0c11f67bf60a856adfabe308d3</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the mass shooting in Tumbler Ridge, Canada</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/tumbler-ridge-canada-school-shooting-explainer/106331730</link><description>Police confirmed the suspect was a woman but have yet to identify the victims of the mass shooting that left nine people, including the alleged shooter, dead in the rural town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8e3d7cc9020ede54a38960ebbd3624f</guid></item><item><title>Israeli President Isaac Herzog welcomes 'new beginning' in meeting with Anthony Albanese</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/protesters-rally-as-mps-skip-question-time-for-herzog-visit/106331226</link><description>Israeli President Isaac Herzog meets with the prime minister at Parliament House in Canberra, saying his visit to Australia has been "very emotional".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">579de49026fcdc60f86649be3a4bb35f</guid></item><item><title>Australian dollar reaches '40-year high' against Japan's yen, as cheap holidays fuel tourism surge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/australian-dollar-japanese-yen-currency-exchange-rate-tourism/106332346</link><description>Australia's exchange rate with Japan has grown increasingly favourable to tourists, which have surged to record numbers and topped more than one million visitors in 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7abbc35d9096aae897d046e36ccf9990</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds treated for e-bike injuries in 2025 at Sydney St Vincent Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/ebike-injuries-double-at-sydney-hospital/106332460</link><description>More than 200 people were treated for e-bike related injuries at a single Sydney hospital last year, with one medical professor describing the trend as an "epidemic".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51176d07eca703bb7654923149b12871</guid></item><item><title>RBA deputy governor defends central bank from critics, wonders if Australia is more inflation-prone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/rba-deputy-governor-says-rba-not-criticise-government-policy/106331502</link><description>RBA deputy governor Andrew Hauser says central banks should not criticise normal government spending choices, but he wonders if Australia's economy is more inflation-prone because it is so finely balanced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f806f14f928362b28b219b82a640327b</guid></item><item><title>Australian fans miss out on World Cup tickets as prices skyrocket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/world-cup-ticket-prices-aussie-fans-miss-out/106332736</link><description>A host of Australian fans will be denied the chance to watch the Socceroos World Cup campaign amid accusations of price gouging by FIFA as tickets to the tournament soar to astronomical prices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cb80105f0eeb0984e8c6d7afad7d449</guid></item><item><title>Labor tries again on super taxes, but yet to secure Greens support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/labor-tries-again-on-super-taxes/106331524</link><description>A second attempt to raise taxes on high super balances has been presented to parliament, but will require the support of the Greens to secure Senate passage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a466ab31df35bf825a2dc9c0feee1d03</guid></item><item><title>US bars Palau senate president and former Marshall Islands mayor over alleged corruption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/us-bars-palau-marshall-islands-officials-for-alleged-corruption/106329288</link><description>A senior Palau politician rejects accusations from the United States Department of State that he accepted bribes from "government, business, and criminal interests from China".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4c5d3311f093881fd48b21aa27d5d56</guid></item><item><title>Austin Appelbee's Triple Zero call to save family swept out to sea at Geographe Bay released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/austin-appelbee-triple-zero-call-released/106333174</link><description>Police release the recording of the Triple Zero call made by 13-year-old Austin Appelbee after his marathon 4 kilometre swim through rough seas to save his family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">080bb848fb9e646a03ddfb0802a198e8</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106332300</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b1ea351c35c93ca1ce9d6966ef4ae9d</guid></item><item><title>Kane Dallow sentenced to two years in prison on fraud and other charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/tasmanian-man-kane-dallow-jailed-for-28-offences/106227598</link><description>A Tasmanian man who impersonated the Launceston Magistrates Court has been convicted on 28 crimes relating to fraud, forgery and perverting justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a46ce2b2cf467d06b9f88e5ba53d770b</guid></item><item><title>Chinese flotilla sailed to edge of Australia's waters, ADF chief reveals at Senate estimates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/chinese-flotilla-edge-australian-exclusive-economic-zone/106333020</link><description>Under questioning in Senate estimates, the chief of the Australian Defence Force reveals that a Chinese flotilla sailed within seven nautical miles of Australia's 200 nautical mile exclusive economic zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54162e69e9611e52a37af7ad332cce70</guid></item><item><title>NSW Parliament backs Cheryl Grimmer's family after 56-year quest for justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/cheryl-grimmer-parliament-motion-buckingham/106332722</link><description>Decades after three-year-old Cheryl Grimmer vanished from Fairy Meadow Beach, NSW MPs move to support her family's fight for justice, as Jeremy Buckingham directly addressed the alleged perpetrator under parliamentary privilege.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9f2d8b7e5889008ddc973077711f317</guid></item><item><title>Surveillance devices captured accused talking about alleged murder of Geoffrey McLean, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/court-hears-evidence-over-alleged-murder-of-geoffrey-mclean/106333170</link><description>An SA Supreme Court trial hears listening devices captured alleged murderer Mark Murphy admitting to his role in killing Geoffrey McLean in 2022. Warning: This story contains details that some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dee7af032cb8fec1ac1248900b766e93</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor resigns from front bench ahead of expected leadership challenge to Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/angus-taylor-resigns-from-frontbench-sussan-ley-leadership/106332492</link><description>Angus Taylor says the Liberals are at their weakest point since the party was formed as he announces his resignation from the front bench.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">719ec35aae82fd4ae16e34d338c37aa1</guid></item><item><title>Parents association fined after allowing alleged sexual offender to keep working at care centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/cranbrook-state-primary-school-parents-association-fined/106333024</link><description>A North Queensland parents association is fined $50,000 for failures in handling allegations of sexual abuse at an after school care service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6337111b808dadf036441dc7b286623c</guid></item><item><title>Olympic great impressed by Aussies as James and Guseli reach halfpipe final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/winter-olympics-2026-live-jakara-anthony-scotty-james/106329908</link><description>Australian Scotty James starts his quest for a third Olympic medal, qualifying in first place with a phenomenal run in snowboard halfpipe qualifying at the Milano Cortina Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bde28b9ffb03fa5cbe8c29b66aac219b</guid></item><item><title>Audio of Austin Appelbee's incredible Triple Zero call after marathon swim to save family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/audio-of-austin-appelbee-s-incredible-triple-zero-call-after-mar/106333512</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a07e12a8516d493dc30141c630813b8</guid></item><item><title>Australia cruises to victory over Ireland in T20 World Cup opener</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/cricket-t20-world-cup-australia-ireland-blog-scores-stats/106330266</link><description>Australia beats Ireland by 67 runs to win its first game at the T20 World Cup, after captain Mitch Marsh was a late out due to testicular bleeding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f10653e8e126254d5fa9b92b8b0d7bf</guid></item><item><title>Channel Nine says Warren Tredrea has now paid costs over long-running legal battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/channel-nine-says-warren-tredrea-has-paid-legal-costs/106333410</link><description>Channel Nine has confirmed it has received legal costs from former AFL player and sports presenter Warren Tredrea, who was ordered to pay $149,000 to his ex-employer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f2d55f17d07ae474e5568f1f5fecbde</guid></item><item><title>More homes in Daly River damaged by flooding, with water levels expected to recede from Thursday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/nt-daly-river-flooding-more-homes-damaged-peak-level/106332666</link><description>Floodwaters have spilled inside "quite a number of homes" in the remote Northern Territory town of Daly River, authorities say, with still-rising water levels delaying the return home for evacuated locals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5b71bf10fc0c6c8a81cf3ddd4040ccf</guid></item><item><title>PM condemns 'white supremacy ideology' behind alleged Invasion Day terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/prime-minister-closing-the-gap-speech/106332998</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has condemned the "racism and hatred" and "white supremacy ideology" behind the alleged terrorist attack on the Invasion Day rally in Borloo/Perth last month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e3643c30243d9459a9602b299a97cc4</guid></item><item><title>Britney Spears sells rights to music catalogue in reported $281m deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/britney-sells-rights-music-catalogue-primary-wave/106333696</link><description>Spears is the latest music star to sell the rights to their work, a decade after the release of her ninth and last studio album.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46d37ff06c7881b67f6362f876d81145</guid></item><item><title>Jakara Anthony misses medals at 2026 Winter Olympic Games in Milano Cortina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/jakara-anthony-2026-winter-olympics-moguls-final-wilson/106333690</link><description>The Australian spectators in Livigno are stunned as defending champion Jakara Anthony crashes out of contention in the women's moguls final at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a060f999a428f2c8f193deb043d835a1</guid></item><item><title>Xi Jinping says China's army has undergone 'revolutionary tempering' in corruption crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/xi-jinping-acknowledges-army-corruption-crackdown/106333834</link><description>Xi Jinping's comments were the first public admission of issues in China's armed forces since an investigation was launched into senior members of the body that overseas the country's military.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c77d72b3b87ccaf57b6cca7a5238b8a</guid></item><item><title>El Paso flights resume after US anti-drone system prompts sudden shutdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/faa-closes-airspace-around-el-paso-airport/106333810</link><description>A secret military laser-based anti-drone system prompted the Trump administration to ban air traffic for more than seven hours in and out of the Texas border city of El Paso.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06473436525f8abf18f0d4e972c40d40</guid></item><item><title>Jakara Anthony may not have won Winter Olympics moguls gold, but winning is not always measured in medals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/jakara-anthony-2026-winter-olympics-moguls/106333208</link><description>Disaster stared Jakara Anthony in the face and meted out the cruellest of injustices as she missed out on a moguls medal at the 2026 Winter Olympic Games. But her response showed us the character that should make Australia proud regardless.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e7220da0752d7dbb33f88021143e2b1</guid></item><item><title>The identities linked to corruption at the CFMEU, according to Queensland's Commission of Inquiry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/cfmeu-inquiry-report-corruption/106333306</link><description>Members of bikie gangs, convicted murderers and violent criminals are among more than 25 people who allegedly benefited from or are linked to corrupt behaviour at the CFMEU, according to a report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79526cb09b14525015408b39b1c1b5b4</guid></item><item><title>Crack found in new $786m Bridgewater Bridge, RTI documents reveal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/concrete-cracks-in-bridgewater-bridge-rti-documents-reveal/106326476</link><description>Days before the official opening, the Tasmanian government's largest-ever infrastructure project hit a hurdle, with a large crack picked up in one of the Bridgewater Bridge's piers detected and fixed, documents show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dedb596ad7690da3fa77fd190349acb0</guid></item><item><title>Kath &amp; Kim is back on ABC iview. Test your Fountain Lakes fan credentials with our quiz. It's noice, it's different, it's _____</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/kath-and-kim-quiz/106286470</link><description>It's an Aussie classic, but do you know who delivered these iconic lines in Kath &amp; Kim? Put down your cardonnay and footy franks and show us what you've got.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b67dba22afc919812a6491878f676fa7</guid></item><item><title>Several Liberals considering their options as race for leadership heats up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/angus-taylor-supporters-sussan-ley-liberal-leadership-spill/106333642</link><description>Angus Taylor's decision to quit the front bench ahead of an expected leadership spill has several Liberals considering whether to throw their hat in the ring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bba6b7e2bc707e5854d76d47b7af8765</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor is moving to challenge Sussan Ley — but not on his terms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/angus-taylor-sussan-ley-leadership-timing-not-wanted/106331132</link><description>Angus Taylor was holidaying in Europe when his colleagues began manoeuvring to topple Sussan Ley. A leadership spill this week wasn't what he or Sussan Ley wanted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32d6f00ceb18364ee804ea3ff647cbdf</guid></item><item><title>Transparency concerns as Bougainville's Panguna mine that sparked civil war on path to reopen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/bougainville-signs-secretive-deal-to-reopen-panguna-mine/106331778</link><description>The Autonomous Bougainville Government signs a secretive deal to reopen the huge Panguna gold and copper mine that sparked a catastrophic civil war three decades ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7a5ff00e0503cc102c30c6e22dae858</guid></item><item><title>Australia's toxic legacy at Wilkes Station in Antarctica</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/wilkes-station-in-antarctica-a-toxic-legacy/106281888</link><description>The ABC has been given rare access to an abandoned Australian base in Antarctica that continues to pose a threat to the environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86fbd4ded36d272a381c32bb0d71bd55</guid></item><item><title>Old Bureau of Meteorology website still getting thousands of clicks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/old-bom-website-drawing-traffic-months-after-new-page-launch/106326812</link><description>The new BOM website is still drawing criticism, with 400,000 users turning to the old site, despite $1.15 million in recent updates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6571b8e0e99bb64c79240519d9e09619</guid></item><item><title>The weekend Adelaide becomes a Saudi Arabian sports utopia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/sa-how-adelaide-became-shining-light-for-liv-golf/106330622</link><description>Saudi Arabia’s LIV Golf project is facing plenty of problems across the world, but you would not read about it when the circus flies into Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff1f35542fe0cac1fbe33fb295905553</guid></item><item><title>Australia Diamonds defeat Jamaica 80-33 in third netball Test to claim 3-0 series win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/australia-diamonds-defeat-jamaica-80-33-in-third-test/106333890</link><description>Coach Stacey Marinkovich believes a refreshed Diamonds squad has found its "identity" ahead of attempting to become the first Australian netball team to defend Commonwealth Games gold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">572f0f2c0fcd545047cd50c575ce4950</guid></item><item><title>A look at the ballistic missile program Iran refuses to negotiate on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/iran-ballistic-missile-program-weapons-us-talks-trump/106307798</link><description>Iran has spent decades building the largest and most diverse ballistic missile stockpile in the Middle East and is refusing US demands to put limits on the weapons program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43b81c86e32420037a6e9d60aa99108f</guid></item><item><title>Thirty people stranded by floods in outback NT angry at police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/people-stranded-in-nt-flood-angry-at-police-response/106326132</link><description>A day trip to the Tjoritja/West MacDonnell National Park became a 24-hour ordeal for almost 30 people when the Hugh River unexpectedly cut off Namatjira Drive, 50 kilometres from Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">120c5f850f4631f4a3c7d5f0c1c42567</guid></item><item><title>Possible El Niño within months raising potential for hot, dry year across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/possibe-el-nino-potential-hot-dry-year-australia/106332446</link><description>The first El Niño in three years could develop during the coming months, raising the possibility of worsening drought and extreme heat across Australia in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2184da61b7edc5c55fb541a361d2f6ad</guid></item><item><title>Animal abuse charge takes one year as RSPCA prosecutions in Queensland drastically decline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/queensland-rspca-drop-in-prosecutions-animal-cruelty/106277220</link><description>A man has been charged with animal cruelty a year after neighbours first made a complaint to the RSPCA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cd8515cd059d1ed39c4f1b8f6e3e75d</guid></item><item><title>Lando Norris quickest on day one of F1 preseason test, Oscar Piastri drives well and Max Verstappen impresses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/f1-preseason-test-bahrain-norris-piastri-verstappen/106333906</link><description>McLaren's Formula 1 world champion Lando Norris was fastest on the first day of preseason testing in Bahrain, but Max Verstappen and Red Bull caught the attention with pace and plenty of laps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba0e6f82ba0e8d4236049cdf992c4cb9</guid></item><item><title>Baker Boy talks new album Djandjay, Riverboats festival and family legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/baker-boy-djandjay-album-riverboats-festival-racism-fresh-prince/106321578</link><description>The Yolŋu artist known as the Fresh Prince of Arnhem Land is the king of feel-good bilingual bangers. But heavy is the crown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a7e4fe54da381b9b3169df148ff7976</guid></item><item><title>James Van Der Beek, star of Dawson's Creek, dies aged 48 after colorectal cancer diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/james-van-der-beek-dawsons-creek-star-obituary/105821848</link><description>The American actor was best known for his starring role as Dawson Leery in Dawson's Creek from 1998 to 2003.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0a7efc4b90b9a094e5d4af5773abbca</guid></item><item><title>Canada school shooter 18-year-old Jesse Van Rootselaar acted alone, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/canadian-shooter-identified-in-school-attack/106333992</link><description>Police identify the person who carried out a school massacre in a remote Canadian community as an 18-year-old woman with mental health issues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3aa7b080fb4f452119e946dd95e8524</guid></item><item><title>Severe weather warning issued for heavy rain across south-east Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/qld-south-east-temperatures-peak-heatwave-rainfall-storms/106331426</link><description>A severe weather warning has been issued for south-east Queensland after a day of scorching heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d556db13a5bfa50ba00c3ef5b2711b11</guid></item><item><title>Liberal frontbench resignations snowball as Ley backer resigns -as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/federal-politics-live-blog-sussan-ley/106333952</link><description>Angus Taylor has confirmed he will challenge Opposition Leader Sussan Ley for the leadership at the meeting. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c870442734b3073dc8ba7593b59edcb</guid></item><item><title>Women reveal alleged assaults near Daylesford after solo hiker raises alarm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/women-reveal-alleged-assaults-after-solo-hiker-safety-concerns/106321554</link><description>A woman's solo hike through regional Victoria took a disturbing turn near Daylesford, raising questions about safety and police responses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f26aa974b43557ea835742330da7382</guid></item><item><title>Pam Bondi grilled over Epstein files as survivors express fury over redactions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/pam-bondi-faces-congress-questions-over-epstein-files/106329688</link><description>US Attorney-General Pam Bondi faces furious questions over the censorship of names in the Epstein files at a heated hearing before a committee of Congress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f6370664d2895327e9152794883f228</guid></item><item><title>RBA concedes 'our forecasts are often wrong'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/asx-markets-business-news-feb12-2026/106334054</link><description>Asked by a journalist, "Was it perhaps overenthusiastic to cut interest rates three times?" The RBA's chief economist responded, "Forecasting is really difficult business, our forecasts are often wrong ... it is what it is."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0416d5b9ac46a1dd16ff15863726771f</guid></item><item><title>Australians feel divided as Albanese asks to 'turn the temperature down'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/social-cohesion-anthony-albanese-isaac-herzog/106294752</link><description>Most Australians want greater social cohesion here, even if they don't see much of it right now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa28ba119db2dd3922f89dee680cc738</guid></item><item><title>Darwin traditional owners feel 'bulldozed' by ambitious solar farm company's approach to consultation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/darwin-traditional-owners-bulldozed-solar-farm-legal-case/106325986</link><description>A renewable energy company planning to build a solar farm near Darwin is seeking a court ruling that no native title claim exists at the proposed site.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3568f961affbc4c6c592ec5ca4aea80</guid></item><item><title>Carers WA struggling to cope with unprecedented demand for support services</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/carers-wa-unprecedented-demand-support-services/106328164</link><description>An organisation that helps people caring for vulnerable family members in WA is experiencing unprecedented demand, with services unable to keep up with the community's needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec18c3068cc8e2883c0431ac89a4d61c</guid></item><item><title>How Perth paedophile Jason William Forbes hid in plain sight in suburban Baldivis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/jason-william-forbes-paedophile-hid-in-plain-sight-in-balidivis/106332628</link><description>"A regular sort of bloke" is how one of Jason Forbes's neighbours described the 39-year-old electrician — but behind the walls of his unassuming home in Perth's suburbs, he was hiding a dark secret.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dd2b32c45fd3aa306f9b3c95567d560</guid></item><item><title>Future of Port Hedland's West End uncertain after buyback scheme ends</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/port-hedland-buyback-ends-leaving-uncertain-future/106050394</link><description>As Port Hedland's controversial dust buyback scheme winds up, Pilbara Ports quietly walks away from major plans to build a training facility and accommodation, with development plans for the area still uncertain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3587d18364662f59c0d70ef1c4dbc441</guid></item><item><title>Pam Bondi clashes with members of Congress in Epstein files hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/pam-bondi-clashes-with-democrats-in-epstein-files-hearing-/106334174</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6510296d77021dd1e0afb1ac521cc4fd</guid></item><item><title>Multiple people rescued in Alice Springs as town inundated with floodwater</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/nt-alice-springs-flooding-wet-weather-emergency-rain/106334186</link><description>Northern Territory emergency services have rescued multiple people isolated by flooding in Alice Springs, after storms caused a dramatic rise in river levels overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f0111c3d67d09aaf04530f675a2283b</guid></item><item><title>Dispute over West Bank football pitch sparks international campaign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/west-bank-football-pitch-at-the-centre-of-a-dispute/106325786</link><description>A campaign to save a West Bank football pitch from demolition has gone global. The sport's most powerful bodies, as well as social media influencers, have intervened to pressure Israeli authorities to reconsider its destruction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">833c5b5cb80156058addeda78d62d0e6</guid></item><item><title>Protesters gather in Melbourne's CBD as Israeli President Isaac Herzog concludes visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/vic-israeli-president-isaac-herzog-melbourne-visit/106331776</link><description>A large crowd is protesting in Melbourne's CBD as Israeli President Isaac Herzog's concludes his visit to the city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3395870f42eb8d78eea57318fb57f23</guid></item><item><title>The Temper Trap is back with new music for the first time in almost a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/the-temper-trap-is-back-with-new-music-for-the/106329462</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a46bbedd13456562e870f6d91c694033</guid></item><item><title>South Africa beats Afghanistan at Twenty20 World Cup after two super overs at Narendra Modi Stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/south-africa-afghanistan-t20-world-cup-double-super-over/106334290</link><description>South Africa wins the most dramatic T20 World Cup group stage clash with Afghanistan, featuring two super overs and countless twists of fortune.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb1593268b4f75b9895b6ade64f0c231</guid></item><item><title>The cast of Crime 101 on the role of art during difficult times</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/the-cast-of-crime-101-on-the-role-/106331142</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c237341f82b2d4c6ecab5a082398fc0e</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Lindsey Vonn has successful surgery as Vladyslav Heraskevych wears his banned helmet — quick hits from day five</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/winter-olympics-2026-day-five-quick-hits-vonn-helmet/106334002</link><description>A Ukrainian athlete is refusing to back down over a controversial helmet featuring the dead, Lindsey Vonn has a third surgery, and maple syrup has powered Ryan Cochran-Siegle to another medal. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">881eb2ab6d01f7591d27959795e07f03</guid></item><item><title>FBI combs desert terrain for clues in Nancy Guthrie's disappearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/fbi-search-for-nancy-guthrie-continues-suspect-released/106334272</link><description>The man detained for questioning in the investigation into the disappearance of a US TV show host's mother has been released and the search continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98abca4b75add9ecbb225412ab313ec8</guid></item><item><title>Declining birth rates in southern right whales alarm researchers in new study</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/climate-change-driving-down-southern-right-whale-calving-numbers/106332214</link><description>New research on the birth rates of southern right whales – once touted as a global conservation success story – has revealed an alarming decline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5d80284251a8c0cd3713b5fe505730a</guid></item><item><title>Greens call for parliamentary inquiry into paedophile former Tasmanian police officer Paul Reynolds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/tasmanian-greens-paul-reynolds-parliamentary-inquiry-call/106332474</link><description>The Greens will push for Tasmania's parliament to scrutinise how police handled child abuse allegations against former officer Paul Reynolds, and why it was decided to give him a full police funeral.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f7f501ebb062cec9e3826f249c2421e</guid></item><item><title>Muslim leader urges public apology over police 'manhandling' at Sydney protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/muslims-nsw-police-public-apology-sydney-protest-cronulla/106333996</link><description>The Lebanese Muslim Association's secretary says the community's relationship with police could be fractured following the Sydney protest despite spending "nearly 20 years repairing" the damage caused by the Cronulla Riot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d02612f12f38a0ec4573ea3b1e9dc4e</guid></item><item><title>Mackay MP who crossed floor to oppose LNP ban on abortion debate defends actions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/nigel-dalton-crosses-floor-abortion-debate/106334698</link><description>Mackay MP Nigel Dalton crossed the floor on Tuesday to vote with Katter's Australian Party to end a parliamentary ban on abortion debate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7af1877d708465b9f166d5233952c8b6</guid></item><item><title>Public DNA databases lead to arrest over historical NSW sexual assault cases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/dna-technology-leads-to-arrest-nsw-sexual-assault-cold-cases/106334110</link><description>A 77-year-old man is arrested in connection with a string of alleged sexual assaults in NSW dating back to the 1990s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">957f7d3970b9923c7d95cd14199fbfad</guid></item><item><title>Albemarle's lithium refinery in WA's South West placed on care and maintenance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/albemarle-kemerton-lithium-refinery-shut-down/106334822</link><description>A multi-billion-dollar lithium refinery in WA's South West has been shut down, affecting about 275 workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5062fb4ce50ee697f9ff892aa55a778c</guid></item><item><title>What young people think of One Nation's rising popularity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/what-young-people-think-of-one-nation/106330036</link><description>Recent opinion polls have found that, for the first time, One Nation is the second-most popular party with voters, overtaking the Coalition. So what do teenagers think of One Nation and do they still trust the major parties?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf4dfc3768ab9cb8e02d5cdd6d73aba9</guid></item><item><title>Scotty James and Valentino Guseli raise their level at 'unbelievable' snowboard halfpipe qualifier at Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/scotty-james-valentino-guseli-snowboard-halfpipe-qualification/106333268</link><description>Scotty James is the man to beat in the snowboard halfpipe at the 2026 Winter Olympics, but a stunning qualifying competition proves that the final is going to be on another level entirely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84595f7c496f7dbad48fe23b81679130</guid></item><item><title>UK police to decide on Andrew Mounbatten-Windsor Epstein trade document investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-police-epstein-files-investigation/106334742</link><description>British police say they are "making progress as quickly as possible" on whether to launch a full investigation into allegations that Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor shared confidential trade documents with late financier and sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70f896e77bb48c2fb240d5bc44cccee3</guid></item><item><title>Three arrested by CFMEU corruption taskforce as premier insists she took appropriate action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/three-arrested-taskforce-hawk-cfmeu-corruption-investigation/106334256</link><description>The arrests were made hours before Premier Jacinta Allan faced reporters over separate allegations detailed in a new report that $15 billion in taxpayer dollars had made its way into the hands of criminals who had infiltrated the union.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc02ad89e79207293943a68d6da5adee</guid></item><item><title>Chris Minns has cracked down on protests. Will it pay off?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/chris-minns-protest-laws-herzog-visit-police/106331440</link><description>By expanding police powers and allowing bans on authorised public assemblies the Minns government has made restricting protest a defining feature of its first term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">527083f33675311c91fad837565911cc</guid></item><item><title>Video shows Guildford shooting victim pleading for help from neighbours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/guilford-shooting-video-shows-victim-plea-for-help/106335532</link><description>Vision shows the moment a bleeding man shot in Sydney's south-west overnight begs for help in a neighbour's back yard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b41f498015908cf46ca9f5559c3f42e2</guid></item><item><title>5,000 cannabis plants seized on rural NSW property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/5-000-cannabis-plants-seized-on-rural-nsw-property/106334568</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51853416fd6d3685a6d065d7635bcf34</guid></item><item><title>Four people charged after alleged discovery of thousands of cannabis plants in NSW Riverina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/alleged-cannabis-plant-seizure-nsw-riverina-property/106334240</link><description>Police allege the four people charged were cultivating a large-scale cannabis farm in the Riverina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc722b2f2ad68bab10683a6dbc9f2acf</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 6</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-matt-graham/106330602</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e7755738441e4486f4c3fbb99fe3561</guid></item><item><title>Plotters, kingmakers and dark horses — the Liberals vying for control</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/the-liberals-vying-for-control-of-party/106335554</link><description>Parliament House has entered the spill zone, where politics is at its most primal. Here are the Liberals jostling for control of their much-reduced party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01251844a95201cce2e0e2a131bfd5f3</guid></item><item><title>Reo Te Whetu Marama Marsh pleads guilty to murdering Mary Benedito on Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/marybenedito-murder-former-partner-pleads-guilty-southport/106335664</link><description>The 25-year-old mother was found unresponsive in a Southport apartment in 2021 and later died of her injuries in hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41675660826075c3b3cef1da1d9a7876</guid></item><item><title>Warrnambool pub fined $150k for numerous gambling regulation breaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/warrnambool-pub-fined-150000-for-gambling-regulation-breaches/106334576</link><description>The breaches included three instances of failing to interact with a patron showing signs of distress that may have related to gambling harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d00408e0652d27652cac54ce09ebfb21</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian man Corey Chugg found alive four days after going missing in bushland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/corey-chugg-found-after-being-missing-for-four-days/106336412</link><description>The 32-year-old man went into a bushland with a friend to collect firewood on Sunday. Police say he has been found alive at the bottom of a steep incline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5572cc953ef79133e4c891baf00fb4d7</guid></item><item><title>Labor releases audio of Liberal MP backtracking on $495 million cost of living policy at industry event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/labor-releases-audio-of-liberal-backtrack/106334676</link><description>South Australia's Treasurer says the Liberal Party has secretly dumped its major $495 million policy less than six weeks out from the state election, with the Opposition arguing it has to wind back Labor's tax due to state budget blowouts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41c94a52edb47ae2f974cc0fddf1c2cb</guid></item><item><title>Electronic monitoring bill strengthening bail laws passes Qld parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/electronic-monitoring-bill-passes-qld-parliament/106335736</link><description>Magistrates will now be able to order children as young as 10 to wear electronic monitoring devices as a bail condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d62157adacf18c5a2ad5fd577c7e2ed0</guid></item><item><title>Camels dying from dehydration descend on APY Lands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/apy-lands-feral-camels-dying-drought-sa/106321572</link><description>Large mobs of camels wreak havoc in remote Indigenous communities as they desperately search for water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c807cb91079deb6ab0c14e1cb642ee2</guid></item><item><title>James Van Der Beek was synonymous with his character. How he embraced it with humour will be his legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/james-van-der-beek-dawsons-creek-character-legacy/106335718</link><description>James Van Der Beek's death prompts wide-ranging tributes from co-stars and friends who have praised his kindness and humour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a76d007b4e1dd749503740e00c13fea9</guid></item><item><title>RBA governor accused by senator of 'gaslighting' Australians on economy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/rba-governor-accused-of-gaslighting-australians-on-economy/106335332</link><description>Reserve Bank governor Michele Bullock fires back at Nationals senator Matt Canavan after he accused her of "gaslighting" Australians over the state of the Australian economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3d3abbc8ab57a6e74180c9d88ef4dae</guid></item><item><title>Ex-police officer Kritan Kutti jailed for arson and possession of bestiality videos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/former-nsw-police-officer-kritan-kutti-jailed/106329584</link><description>A former NSW police officer is jailed for multiple offences, including arson and possession of bestiality videos, while stationed at a rural border post.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b60e70d23fd8c282aad6b8a419d10ebc</guid></item><item><title>Bowls Queensland maintains silence over rumoured Coorparoo Bowls Club sell-off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/bowls-queensland-silent-over-coorparoo-sell-off-rumours/106336482</link><description>Bowls Queensland has repeatedly refused to comment on its plans for the site, despite pressure from all three levels of government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">732e520d2b302f3478ce4be23560a529</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: 'Pindemonium' sweeps Milano Cortina as collectors go treasure hunting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/pindemonium-sweeps-winter-olympics-milano-cortina/106336996</link><description>For Olympic pin hunters, Milano Cortina 2026 is proving to be a thrilling treasure hunt, one that is taking them to corners of the world they may never have otherwise visited.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">133f5a34145c7cffb3fff053a69b8dff</guid></item><item><title>Man faces Mackay court accused of buying boat for drug smuggling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/man-accused-buying-boat-facilitate-import-illegal-drugs/106336250</link><description>Police allege the owner of a recently set up fishing company purchased a vessel with illicit funds to facilitate the importation of illegal drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a0b73226052d169923a9a7b5bfd9b8e</guid></item><item><title>Support firms for Angus Taylor to win Liberal leadership, though Ley expected to achieve 'good result'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/angus-taylor-liberal-leadership-support-firms/106334120</link><description>Support is firming for Angus Taylor to topple Opposition Leader Sussan Ley, though her supporters still expect her to achieve a "good result".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ec143f5904383374cfda9bd081918e1</guid></item><item><title>Mother of autistic man starved to death in Gold Coast hospital 'satisfied' with damning investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/ombudsman-investigation-robina-hospital-death/106334338</link><description>Queensland’s health watchdog finds Stewart Kelly's 2022 hospital death was the result of systemic failures in care, particularly around responding to his complex needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f21ac0cb928bb63b34bd2332709076bd</guid></item><item><title>Chocolate recipes to share some love with the people in your life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/valentines-day-recipes-love-chocolate/106325802</link><description>Whether you are into Valentine's Day or not, these chocolate recipes are perfect for sharing some love.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4882faeefbbf9e3310ba059823c6008</guid></item><item><title>NT coroner hands down findings into death of infamous murderer Martin Leach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/nt-coroner-findings-into-death-of-murderer-rapist-martin-leach/106333540</link><description>An inquest into the 2024 death of double murderer Martin Leach raises questions about whether prisoners have a right to end-of-life care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1343d6662df13df32315e87290cc3466</guid></item><item><title>Julian Assange's brother backs exiled former ASIO spy Marcus amid Bondi Beach gunman radicalisation claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/julian-assange-s-brother-supporting-former-spy-living-in-exile/106334144</link><description>Former undercover agent Marcus says he shared intelligence with ASIO about Bondi gunmen Naveed and Sajid Akram's alleged terrorism associations as far back as 2019.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d342528c0b8c306cae08cb9c3c5a0d35</guid></item><item><title>Liberals' leadership machinations dominate the political week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/liberals-leadership-spill-angus-taylor-sussan-ley/106325872</link><description>The Liberals have spent the week embroiled in leadership woes as the party braces for a spill on Friday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">874320a6b150dbbf66b077e9b0f5d9b5</guid></item><item><title>Ballarat man pleads guilty to taking almost 200 'upskirt' images in public places</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/ballarat-man-derek-grima-pleads-guilty-to-upskirting-offences/106337058</link><description>A court hears a man took "upskirting" images of unwitting women and girls in shopping centres and his workplace, in Melbourne, Geelong and Ballarat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33712309d1614f6803be7f6621987692</guid></item><item><title>Gas exploration seismic testing project rejected in south-west Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/regia-3d-mss-project-seismic-testing-rejected-gas-exploration/106334294</link><description>A controversial seismic testing proposal off Victoria's south-west coast has been rejected in a "rare" move from the offshore regulator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f07ea3447a079671409f13da47906a8b</guid></item><item><title>Two Chinese nationals accused of foreign interference granted bail in ACT Magistrates Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/act-two-chinese-nationals-accused-foreign-interference-bail/106335336</link><description>Police allege the two Chinese nationals, who are charged with reckless foreign interference for alleged spying on the Canberra branch of a Buddhist association, are linked to a woman arrested on the same charge last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8ffcbf499d3b6e411f85857ee4a6971</guid></item><item><title>Severe thunderstorm warnings issued for much of south-east Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/thunderstorms-severe-weather-warnings-south-east-queensland/106337566</link><description>Severe thunderstorms are likely to produce heavy rainfall that may lead to flash flooding across parts of south-east Queensland this afternoon, according to the weather bureau.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0e82342c3647b805eed1dc7a1817a34</guid></item><item><title>Fatal Queensland house fire inquiry hears father was 'pretty abusive'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/queensland-fatal-house-fire-inquiry/106336740</link><description>The mother of a young boy killed in a house fire in 2017 has given emotional evidence at an inquest into his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e821f83fd67d3541967e14a7c326eb70</guid></item><item><title>New video shows 76-year-old protester wrestled to the ground by police.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/james-ricketson-arrest/106337664</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1ede9ce3f2f74e240d6e269b334c672</guid></item><item><title>New video shows violent arrest of Australian filmmaker James Ricketson at Sydney's anti-Herzog protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/video-shows-arrest-filmmaker-james-ricketson-sydney-protest/106337470</link><description>New video obtained by ABC NEWS Verify shows in vivid detail the arrest of a 76-year-old man, who was later released without charge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e8b85f342914cc4a1db8e8f827b072c</guid></item><item><title>Barbeques Galore enters receivership as debt burns into bottom line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/barbeques-galore-enters-receivership/106337962</link><description>Barbeques Galore has plunged into receivership, leaving question marks for its nearly 100 stores that employ about 500 staff.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69523934e505732dbc33d0c34030742d</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106337290</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d261cc973fdb20ab56fe51470b7d321c</guid></item></channel></rss>