<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 05:15:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Australian production company Matchbox Pictures to be closed by Universal International Studios</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/matchbox-pictures-closed-universal-international-studios/106355260</link><description>Matchbox Pictures, the local production house behind Dog Park, The Survivors and Secret City, will be closed by its international parent company, Universal International Studios.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78b9d935e059c11895c3efac8807b716</guid></item><item><title>Addin Fonua-Blake and Briton Nikora embrace chance to play State of Origin following eligibility changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/addin-fonua-blake-briton-nikora-state-of-origin/106355576</link><description>Cronulla duo Briton Nikora and Addin Fonua-Blake have both praised the rule changes that will give the pair a chance at State of Origin football they thought had long passed them by.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ec581ac1f034662bed78ff674c00b7</guid></item><item><title>Private health premiums to rise at fastest rate in almost a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/private-health-premiums-increase/106355550</link><description>Private health insurance premiums will rise at their fastest rate in almost a decade, after the federal government approved a 4.41 per cent average increase from April.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cf53e80cc9f8f5821a0c50d3aa7dd87</guid></item><item><title>Police drop charges against WIM Resource employee accused of falsifying documents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/wim-resource-murray-wilson-fraud-charges-dropped/106355362</link><description>Victoria Police has dropped all charges against WIM Resource employee Murray Wilson, who worked on the controversial Avonbank Mineral Sands Project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e46ef3f04400c724cf57f4b12383ce25</guid></item><item><title>Mother of former Manly player Keith Titmuss breaks silence on lawsuit against NRL club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/keith-titmuss-mother-speaks-on-manly-sea-eagles-lawsuit/106354504</link><description>The mother of Manly player Keith Titmuss, who died of exertional heat stroke following a 2020 Sea Eagles training session, breaks her silence on her family's multi-million-dollar lawsuit against the NRL club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0be5af7a65024f5d1249c96c36ab639d</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested after fatal Merrylands stabbing escaped care 10 days before attack, health authorities say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/man-arrested-after-merrylands-stabbing-escaped-hospital-care/106356218</link><description>A man arrested after a fatal stabbing in Merrylands escaped from mental health care while being transferred between hospitals more than a week ago, health authorities say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac37a20a68838d5f1d8ead99df730433</guid></item><item><title>Father whose son died in house fire accuses lawyer at coronial inquiry of 'degrading him'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/qld-fatal-fire-inquest-father-outburst/106354862</link><description>The father, in an emotional outburst, told the inquest he had spent thousands of dollars on psychiatric and hypnotherapy appointments so he could move on from the tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2817eed5da4210d086772b41a3286cb6</guid></item><item><title>Sydney’s great fatberg hiding in the sewers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/sydney-s-great-fatberg-hiding-in-the-sewers/106355414</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d86c2192d0e5b5504b2ff2bec1bd22ef</guid></item><item><title>ABC to move Adelaide office to new Tapangka site in CBD, alongside arts organisations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/abc-adelaide-to-move-to-new-cbd-arts-hub/106355280</link><description>The ABC has announced a new location for its Adelaide operations, moving to a new arts and media hub alongside other government arts organisation in the CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">304f07af147679233a1ce91d82d122b7</guid></item><item><title>Grammy-winning songwriter and hitmaker Billy Steinberg dies aged 75</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/grammy-winning-songwriter-billy-steinberg-dies-aged-75/106356348</link><description>Award-winning US songwriter Billy Steinberg, who wrote several top hit songs including Madonna's Like a Virgin, died on Monday aged 75, according to media reports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb0f5e86348cae84a5923360286fcd40</guid></item><item><title>Aussie teen forced to wait for Olympic final as heavy snow wreaks havoc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-day-11-live-blog/106354466</link><description>Australia's Ally Hickman has to wait another day for the women's snowboard slopestyle final, as a snowstorm hits Livigno and causes scheduling delays.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0610df31fc2a456d285c9d60f0eeb066</guid></item><item><title>Jesse Jackson, civil rights leader and US presidential hopeful, dead at 84</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/civil-rghts-leader-jesse-jackson-dies-age-84/106356528</link><description>The two-time Democratic presidential hopeful remembered for powerful speeches died peacefully surrounded by loved ones, his family said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bef1e4b64b56ce290b7d00444b297818</guid></item><item><title>Australia knocked out of T20 World Cup with one game left to play</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/australia-knocked-out-of-t20-world-cup/106356754</link><description>Australia can no longer catch up with Zimbabwe after it was awarded a point from a rained out match with Ireland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dfa50a4be411761518915d4c45e5985</guid></item><item><title>Richard Roxburgh, Damon Herriman and Toby Schmitz star in 'wickedly funny' play Art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/art-the-play-richard-roxburgh-damon-herriman-toby-schmitz/106051888</link><description>In the 1994 French play Art, Serge spends 160,000 euros on an all-white painting, horrifying his friend Marc. It might just wreck their decades-long friendship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf94795c60e3d3af64640f380e98e6b3</guid></item><item><title>Millionaire Gary Stevenson's dire warning for Australian property market losing the 'fair go'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/economist-gary-stevenson-warns-australia-losing-the-fair-go/106342536</link><description>British economist Gary Stevenson is on a speaking tour, warning Australia will follow the path of the UK with "poverty exploding" unless politicians deal with inequality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f588e11282bda2e3e28ac0a5b4d7af5d</guid></item><item><title>HungryPanda riders say Chinese police intimidating families in China over Sydney protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/hungrypanda-riders-chinese-police-threats-sydney-australia/106353996</link><description>Riders embroiled in a dispute over pay and conditions with food delivery company HungryPanda in Sydney say Chinese police have asserted pressure back home to stop them protesting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00b78e0a081535d928622de443de63b8</guid></item><item><title>Private health insurance customers stung by exclusions after downgrading from gold policies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/private-health-patients-discover-exclusions-downgrade-policy/106325324</link><description>Australians are increasingly downgrading their health cover, with 360,000 people leaving gold policies since 2020. But some have been left out of pocket for surgeries they thought they were covered for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4543069212aa1935d9d011728be77184</guid></item><item><title>Aerials delay is not unusual, as snow causes chaos at Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/aerials-delays-2026-winter-olympics/106356762</link><description>Delays are nothing new in skiing events, with weather and light a constant battle for event organisers. However, the Australian aerials team has an unusual method to handle the disruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f49e711941aae6ee00c9b528308bb80f</guid></item><item><title>Long-term solution to repeated Waterfall Way landslips on the horizon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/long-term-solution-repeated-waterfall-way-landslides/106353438</link><description>The NSW government hopes to reopen a key east-west transport route by April, as a long-term solution to frequent landslips in the area is explored.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93a127abafb503c04ed7b234a9aa7f0e</guid></item><item><title>Owners win right to demolish Lis Escop house in Rockhampton after appeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/owners-win-appeal-to-demolish-162-year-old-rockhampton-home/106341768</link><description>A couple has won the right to demolish a 162-year-old building in a Queensland city scattered with heritage-listed properties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2e33910bc6ae9d2b7fa35586dc25a14</guid></item><item><title>Hindmarsh Island bridge dispute told through Ngarrindjeri women's art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/ngarrindjeri-women-retell-hindmarsh-island-bridge-story/106282804</link><description>In the 1990s, a group of Indigenous women were accused of fabricating claims of sacred sites to stop the construction of a bridge south of Adelaide. It was a decision that has impacted a community for decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c8df9f180475c2f0cfe199f0433a284</guid></item><item><title>Disenfranchised Farrer voters turn out in droves to consider One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/one-nation-farrer-federal-by-election/106354342</link><description>This southern New South Wales town of Gerogery is typically dead on a Monday night, but that all changed when One Nation came to town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfeec7877eeface1749af84fb416ce74</guid></item><item><title>Living across the river from Nyrstar zinc smelter has Jan doing what she can to lower lead risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/living-across-from-nyrstar-hobart-zinc-smelter/106355866</link><description>Jan Twomey bought a house on Hobart's eastern shore just over a year ago, knowing full well it was across from a zinc smelter. But news of high levels of lead detected in dust samples has her concerned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f9c7a6c4056b671696fc0a27e2861ea</guid></item><item><title>OCD is often misunderstood. Elena wants you to know what it feels like</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/elena-ocd-heywire-quiz/106254504</link><description>Elena wants people with OCD to know they're not alone. But how well do Australians understand the condition?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c381c4562a28f911f49f436b138ce17d</guid></item><item><title>Matildas expected to name Mary Fowler in Asian Cup squad, injured Charli Grant set to miss out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/matildas-set-to-gamble-on-fowler-fitness-in-asian-cup-squad/106357060</link><description>Mary Fowler is expected to be named in Australia's Women's Asian Cup squad on Thursday despite having played limited minutes in her return from an ACL injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3411cba4c526944d5b5fb418a7a5f2db</guid></item><item><title>Telstra accused of environmental breaches in culturally-significant area in SA national park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/telstra-investigated-environmental-breach-south-australia-site/106349226</link><description>Sources say the actions will likely affect Aboriginal communities and that the investigation was not shared with the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b5f492e4ab694c6050d7c2fadc97f21</guid></item><item><title>Test results show high levels of lead dust around Hobart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/lead-dust-risk-nyrstar-smelter-in-hobart/106357116</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00dd140169e0498d91069943911894da</guid></item><item><title>Space industry firm Terram Astra launches with plans for outback Northern Territory, South Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/nt-new-outback-space-project-alice-springs-terram-astra/106352872</link><description>A new company sets its sights on the Australian outback, with bold ambitions of creating a high-tech hub capable of communicating with outer space.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cfd735ac65a201f73b2d4a1425fc3ff</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Jürgen Klopp makes Milano Cortina Games cameo, ice hockey fight ban labelled a 'joke' — quick hits from day 11</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-day-11-quick-hits/106356448</link><description>Football manager Jürgen Klopp makes an appearance at the Milano Cortina Games, while French ice hockey players are unhappy about the ban handed to a teammate for fighting. Here are the quick hits from day 11.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9e6fc860b11cec670fa7d512e4c8727</guid></item><item><title>Riverland wine grape growers want to rezone land for housing to exit industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/housing-plan-riverland-wine-grape-crisis-rezoning-land-sa/106243944</link><description>The wine grape industry in South Australia's Riverland continues to face unprecedented levels of uncertainty, as growers look to exit the industry and turn their land into residential housing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b952a8705ecf3fd902de2cb20e0489c</guid></item><item><title>Parkes Shire Council formally opposes controversial waste incinerator</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/parkes-shire-council-objects-to-waste-plant-/106353452</link><description>The Parkes Shire Council has formally objected to controversial plans to dispose of some of Sydney's red-bin rubbish on the edge of its biggest town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d99d0f29b19f948bbe7a21bfd5e94e4</guid></item><item><title>Daly River flood evacuees threatened with edged weapon in incident outside Darwin evacuation centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/nt-daly-river-flooding-foskey-evacuation-centre-weapon-incident/106354738</link><description>As Daly River flood evacuees near their second full week in Darwin, residents staying at the showgrounds say they feel scared after a group was threatened with an edged weapon on Monday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">442adf31e6390d8dc213bea3d8ab2463</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Writers' Festival announces Randa Abdel-Fattah for 2026 program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/randa-abdel-fattah-to-feature-at-sydney-writers-festival/106357178</link><description>Sydney Writers' Festival has defended featuring Randa Abdel-Fattah on its 2026 program, saying it is "not in the business of cancelling or censoring writers".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27fd50a9ce304983c79c05fe33b13137</guid></item><item><title>Pauline Hanson issues partial apology for suggesting there are no 'good' Muslims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/pauline-hanson-partially-apologises-for-muslim-remarks/106357130</link><description>The One Nation leader qualified her earlier remarks, which had been met with condemnation, while reiterating calls for tougher vetting processes for Muslim migrants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef8666bfdfbfd0c8dffd9a0c82b5b3cd</guid></item><item><title>Actor Shia LaBeouf arrested for allegedly hitting two men at Mardi Gras in New Orleans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/shia-labeouf-arrested-for-alleged-fight-mardi-gras-new-orleans/106357346</link><description>The actor allegedly hit a man multiple times with closed fists and allegedly punched another man in the nose.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f284d1a63429f4a42321d1db2ea5e20</guid></item><item><title>Matt Wright moved to Darwin Correctional Centre's Complex Behaviour Unit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/matt-wright-darwin-correctional-centre-complex-behaviour-unit/106354836</link><description>Matt Wright, the star of Netflix's Outback Wrangler, has been separated from the general prison population at the Darwin Correctional Centre where most inmates contend with overcrowding and extreme heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7f14cd488223e95b2a17f131826724c</guid></item><item><title>Foo Fighters announce 2026 Australian stadium tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/foo-fighters-to-tour-australia-2026-dave-grohl-special-guests/106357718</link><description>American rock superstars Foo Fighters will return to Australia for a run of stadium shows before the year is out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a1855fdd5149c72de22208ce0af24ae</guid></item><item><title>Real Madrid star Vinícius Júnior says Benfica's Gianluca Prestianni racially abused him in Champions League match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/champions-league-racism-vinicius-junior-real-madrid-benfica/106357730</link><description>Real Madrid forward Vinícius Júnior accuses an opponent of racially abusing him during a Champions League game against Benfica, leading to the game being halted for nearly 10 minutes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">659589228e0656b84af72920641782c0</guid></item><item><title>Australia's most successful Winter Olympics coach Peter McNiel and how his moguls team led the Milano Cortina gold rush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/australia-winter-olympics-coach-peter-mcniel-moguls/106356920</link><description>With a background in mathematics and an enviable attention to detail, it would be tempting to think of Australian ski coach Peter McNiel as moguls' answer to Moneyball. The truth is far more detailed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">525992813f56d82643171c38d6db94ad</guid></item><item><title>Police release man arrested over Galiwin'ku stabbing death without charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/nt-man-released-without-charge-after-fatal-galiwinku-stabbing/106357704</link><description>Police say a 19-year-old man arrested over the stabbing death of another man, 27, on Elcho Island on Saturday has been released without charge "pending further investigations".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a506da9a67db14560688134793469b6f</guid></item><item><title>Police charge man and woman with cocaine and cannabis offences at Airlie Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/police-charge-man-and-woman-with-drug-offences-at-airlie-beach/106358094</link><description>Two people have been charged after police allegedly found drugs, utensils and cash at an Airlie Beach property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01f78ae7b2f5026f3965a4198f2c5b45</guid></item><item><title>As Donald Trump's first Board of Peace meeting approaches, Indonesians are watching their own president closely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/donald-trump-first-meeting-board-of-peace-indonesian-president/106348628</link><description>Ahead of the inaugural meeting of US President Donald Trump's Board of Peace, charged with leading the way forward in Gaza, Indonesian President Prabowo Subianto faces perhaps his most significant foreign policy test yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d30635e040376ea60c805df9793c8cb</guid></item><item><title>Is it ever a good idea to stay together for the kids?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/should-you-ever-stay-together-for-the-kids/106281890</link><description>When a relationships breaks down, sometimes we think staying in the familiar discomfort is less scary — and even protective — for our kids. But is it ever a good idea to stay in an unhappy relationship for the sake of the children?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbe4bbc74caa9ba1918949fae6630fe1</guid></item><item><title>Legends slam Australia's 'not surprising' T20 World Cup crash out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/aussie-t20-world-cup-eliminated-shock-loss/106359106</link><description>For the first time since 2009, Australia won't advance from the group stage of a cricket World Cup and some of the game's greatest ever players are demanding answers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbd3f4835d2882acc4aa5f3b0c0d541b</guid></item><item><title>Launceston Council scraps 4-day work week plan after backlash from business sector</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/launceston-council-scraps-4-day-work-week-after-backlash/106358434</link><description>A Tasmanian council's move to introduce a four-day work week, in part to attract and retain staff, has been abandoned after pushback by a business lobby group and what has been described as "unacceptable hostility" towards staff on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a5c0f5a516d42058b0f4ea6fedf631a</guid></item><item><title>James Slipper set to play 200th Super Rugby match as ACT Brumbies travel to face Crusaders in Christchurch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/james-slipper-set-to-play-200th-super-rugby-match/106359004</link><description>James Slipper will become the first Australian player to reach the 200-game milestone in Super Rugby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">666672c36683f7dfca20fa7cad0c1916</guid></item><item><title>Potential rugby development in Sydney's Hills district sparks stoush with protesters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/residents-turn-to-blocking-fred-caterson-development/106357890</link><description>Protesters say they will block the council from developing sporting fields for the use of an elite club rugby at a reserve in the city's north-west, as a court challenge to the project is due to be heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86383eb37a77ebed5bc01816183f967b</guid></item><item><title>Chalmers suggests ex-RBA governor's spending critique is due to personal vendetta</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/chalmers-dismisses-criticism-from-philip-lowe/106359398</link><description>Treasurer Jim Chalmers says Philip Lowe was critical of the government over spending because it did not re-appoint him as RBA governor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4578c9f616d6026ee0f378a69efa25e</guid></item><item><title>Mazda, Nissan, Hyundai and Subaru face multi-million-dollar penalties under NVES</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/new-vehicle-efficiency-standard-results-mazda-nissan-penalties/106358770</link><description>Major car brands are staring down the barrel of multi-million-dollar penalties for exceeding their emissions, the first results of the federal government's climate laws for new vehicles have revealed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45198840bd21329442d531c79bcbff0d</guid></item><item><title>Planned nurse strike rescheduled at Lyell McEwin Hospital amid pay dispute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/nurses-strike-rescheduled-at-lyell-mcewin-hospital/106357820</link><description>The South Australian government says plans from Lyell McEwin Hospital nurses to strike tomorrow have been postponed, amid an unresolved industrial dispute over pay and conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ffbe0d18fbda24b0ebc0a4110aec457</guid></item><item><title>Jesse Jackson helped lay the groundwork for Barack Obama and kept the fight for justice in the public eye</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/jesse-jackson-groundwork-for-americas-first-black-president/106359248</link><description>Reverend Jesse Jackson, who died on Tuesday aged 84, leaves behind a towering legacy in politics and the fight for justice in the United States and abroad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0665d46428bd50fafd1d8f2ab4989a0</guid></item><item><title>Alcoa hit with record fine for unlawfully clearing WA jarrah forests for bauxite mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/alcoa-fined-for-clearing-jarrah-forest-for-bauxite-mine/106359988</link><description>US mining giant Alcoa is forced to pay $55 million after unlawfully clearing parts of a Western Australian native forest to mine bauxite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f74bb47c6f321183a916fc154005c8ee</guid></item><item><title>Former Coles manager admits 'human error' over Shapes 'Down Down' pricing in federal court showdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/coles-accc-discounts-federal-court/106358474</link><description>A former Coles manager has given evidence in the federal court on day three of a bombshell case between the consumer watchdog and supermarket giant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fac3387b11a41f3cb04ca5d82d1e043</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Macarthur FC captain Ulises Dávila fined $11k over A-League card fixing saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/ex-a-league-captain-ulises-d%C3%A1vila-fined-over-betting-scandal/106358086</link><description>Former Macarthur FC captain Ulises Dávila avoids jail time over his involvement in a card fixing scandal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d649323fcbad3f77ec947285f3251da</guid></item><item><title>Blue Bush Floodway enjoyed by all.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/blue-bush-floodway-enjoyed-by-all/106360146</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbd2f162df0e8fed005d6a35a8340a73</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106359046</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">077e4b34cad227fccef803151960b1af</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 12</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide/106357404</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5927607c6b226a4fc3cd81eec0fa5c61</guid></item><item><title>Queensland man accused of offering $730 to adopt and abuse overseas children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/qld-man-refused-bail-over-alleged-child-sex-procurement-plot/106360740</link><description>A Queensland man accused of offering to pay more than $700 to adopt children overseas so he could have sex with them is refused bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0adc407b09567e623482d48b0cf6af66</guid></item><item><title>Ex-cop granted bail over alleged stalking following neighbour dispute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/ex-cop-granted-bail-over-alleged-stalking-charges/106359998</link><description>A former Queensland police officer accused of allegedly wearing a balaclava and Easter bonnet to harass and intimidate a neighbouring family has been granted bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aea69af313928f8cdfdf95d42f0e5112</guid></item><item><title>Man fined $32,000 for poaching rare snakes from Far North Queensland rainforest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/man-fined-for-poaching-rare-snakes/106360544</link><description>The court heard Clinton Spiteri was with two others when he visited a rainforest in the Cape York area to steal eight snakes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e054b8dba8caac08516c2d5f4789e82</guid></item><item><title>More delays for Winter Olympics as 'severe' weather approaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/winter-olympics-day-12-live-blog/106358928</link><description>Milano Cortina organisers have been forced to postpone the men's aerials event, featuring Australian Reilly Flanagan, due to another forecast of inclement weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1afa317592e146df44942abefc37c8a4</guid></item><item><title>Police accused of being slow to respond to alleged homemade bomb at Perth Invasion Day rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/sisonke-picked-up-ied-thrown-at-perth-invasion-day-rally/106360508</link><description>When Sisonke picked up a device that looked like a glass jar in Perth on Australia Day, she had a sense of foreboding so she took it to police. She says they took some time to act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4484d2c8c44530667bc645d156bdc3b</guid></item><item><title>Driver charged over Camden fatal crash escaped Cumberland Hospital mental health care before incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/cumberland-hospital-patient-absconded-before-camden-fatal-crash/106361010</link><description>A driver charged over a double-fatal crash used a staff pass to escape hospital the day before an alleged Sydney stabber fled the same mental health facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9b460c845ba44fdb8e18d6fdf3752c5</guid></item><item><title>Tackling 'blatant' fake discounting, restoring consumer trust among ACCC's priorities for 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/accc-outlines-priorities-for-2026-including-fake-discounting/106359994</link><description>ACCC chair Gina Cass-Gottlieb outlines the consumer watchdog's priorities for 2026, including targeting "blatant" fake discounting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2937ff2740ca14e3dac8a4082576d74e</guid></item><item><title>Danielle Scott wins silver medal in women's aerials event at 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/winter-olympics-dani-scott-silver-womens-aerials/106361098</link><description>Danielle Scott ends a 12-year drought for Australia by winning the silver medal in the women's aerials final at the Milano Cortina Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3820d5e835f545e590e5477cd6c61b06</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic pioneer John King Davis's grave was unmarked – until now</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/unmarked-grave-of-antarctic-pioneer-john-king-davis-found/106357712</link><description>Captain John King Davis was one of Australia's greatest Antarctic explorers, but for decades, his final resting place was an unmarked grave in Melbourne. Today, that will change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f55c0796c4ce772d58aac0922060d57</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian EPA drops plan to implement tighter lead controls after pushback from Nyrstar smelter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/epa-folds-after-nyrstar-pushback-on-tougher-lead-emissions/106352924</link><description>Three years ago, Tasmania's environment watchdog proposed to tighten lead emission limits from Hobart's zinc smelter to bring the state into line with national standards — but after pushback from the operator, that plan was dropped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8b8d1991b39bb3d2dd77b421c60cd3b</guid></item><item><title>Mary Fowler named in Matildas Women's Asian Cup squad, Sam Kerr to captain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/matildas-womens-asian-cup-squad-mary-fowler-return-sam-kerr/106358720</link><description>Considered the Matildas' X-factor, Mary Fowler has been named in the Women's Asian Cup squad, just 10 months after sustaining an ACL injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94e1148a75a920a6b5eef99a0cdf14d1</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, February 19: Britpop, beats and a lust for life on Trainspotting's deathless soundtrack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/trainspotting-soundtrack-30th-anniversary-danny-boyle-britpop/106354570</link><description>Most films are lucky to get just one needle-drop moment embedded in the Zeitgeist. Trainspotting boasted several.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ab3fc2c71c82699927e06d1a58d6cf7</guid></item><item><title>Quiz: Which books are these literary quotes from?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/famous-book-quotes-quiz/106321984</link><description>Are you happiest with your nose in a book? Did you spend summer reading at the beach? This quiz is for you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93263cc459c19ed242af066f07f52020</guid></item><item><title>Government spending is creeping up and threatening Australia’s 'low-debt' status</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/government-spending-threatening-australias-low-debt-status/105579046</link><description>Australia will cease to be a low-debt country and be more vulnerable in a future crisis without a combination of spending restraint and tax reform, a new report has warned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13ac01b1668865c59fb5bf518f92a919</guid></item><item><title>Senate committee features climate disinformation, the Atlas Network, and Dr Karl's clash with One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/climate-disinformation-senate-committee-dr-karl-atlas-network/106350002</link><description>The scourge of AI-slopaganda, viral disinformation campaigns and online attacks against individuals and institutions is going to get far worse before it gets better, if the latest public hearings on the topic are any indication.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc806ab7e06e7cc45d048d4f225dbed0</guid></item><item><title>Trump official says US did not censor Colbert interview but is probing The View</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/fcc-confirms-investigation-into-the-view/106361394</link><description>The confirmation of a probe into the daytime talk show came after it interviewed the same Democratic candidate whose interview with Stephen Colbert was allegedly barred from airing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00896e420fd548e96575bb0b6c4b91f3</guid></item><item><title>Perth couple Jonathan and Amy Carr-Knox locked in international surrogacy battle to bring home daughter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/battle-bring-home-sophie-after-surrogacy-red-tape-argentina/106126626</link><description>Jonathan and Amy had a child via surrogacy in Argentina. They have been stuck there for 12 months, unable to bring their daughter home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e1192412c2820ccafbe31fa94aa760c</guid></item><item><title>Danielle Scott's Winter Olympic silver ends years of pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/danielle-scott-aerials-silver-medal-2026-winter-olympics/106361322</link><description>In this most tension-filled Winter Olympic sport, it's no wonder tears are a by-product of both success and failure. Thankfully for Dani Scott, this time she was crying tears of pure joy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e5d5a3ecb08453f6f6bb9cdeaccc263</guid></item><item><title>Renewable energy company abandons native title court application over Darwin solar farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/darwin-solar-farm-court-application-abandoned/106357534</link><description>A renewable energy company planning to build a solar farm near Darwin withdraws a court application that traditional owners argued would "erase" their rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16119d56006ff2c8aae6209ef2b53cf7</guid></item><item><title>Could SA Liberal leader Ashton Hurn lose her seat at the next election?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/could-ashton-hurn-lose-her-seat-at-the-next-sa-election/106357818</link><description>It's an almost unthinkable scenario, but the fact it's even being discussed shows the extent of the Liberal Party's predicament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9786f949730f20ebd11b7fd76ff59c7f</guid></item><item><title>Advocates call for more accessible cool spaces for people with heat regulation impairments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/heat-regulation-impairments-urban-planning-disabilities-sa/106348980</link><description>With heatwave events set to be more frequent across the country, researchers say thermoregulation must be part of urban planning to avoid risking the lives of people with heat regulation impairments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">216a8c869b4587c68f7909785495ccb2</guid></item><item><title>Cherbourg turns to emerging technology while it waits for $26m water treatment plant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/cherbourg-uses-new-atmospheric-water-generation-technology/106359278</link><description>Just three hours from Brisbane, the residents of Cherbourg need to boil the town water to make it safe to drink. Delays to a new water treatment plant have driven them to use emerging technology that creates clean water from thin air.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">266c61156c671a486ddd0d7e7b72d819</guid></item><item><title>Fiji's former prime minister Frank Bainimarama charged with inciting mutiny</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/former-fiji-prime-minister-bainimarama-arrested-charged-mutiny/106360516</link><description>Long-serving Fiji prime minister Frank Bainimarama and a former police commissioner will face court on Tuesday on charges of mutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfb056a8d72b38a8175534edc2ea18aa</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Dog invades cross-country skiing, Americans get engaged as Ally Hickman feels the pain — day 12 quick hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/winter-olympics-day-12-quick-hits/106360904</link><description>A pair of US athletes announce their engagement as Ally Hickman's medal bid turns sour and a dog steals the show at the cross-country skiing. Here are the quick hits from day 12 at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd59fe51c584fb48b6564fd085361a09</guid></item><item><title>Moyne Shire Council never wanted Port Fairy's pool, yet it paid $3.4m for it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/port-fairy-pool-moyne-shire-cost-belfast-aquatics/106345296</link><description>A Victorian community group promised its local shire a new pool would not cost it money once it was built. In less than three months, the promise was broken.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8cfb04cc8a00decf70f2adc47081828</guid></item><item><title>Outback families hope for change amid review into Queensland Patient Travel Subsidy Scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/travel-subsidy-scheme-review-outback-queensland-patients/106358404</link><description>The cost of living is hurting outback residents who need to travel for medical treatment. They say government subsidies need to increase as the price of everything continues to rise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d837333d6979b3e02127123d5a34593</guid></item><item><title>James and Sophie among West Australians keen to give back as regional doctors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/kalgoorlie-students-following-dreams-medical-career/106325718</link><description>After graduating six years apart at the same high school in Kalgoorlie, both James Gent and Sophie Barton are following their dream of becoming a doctor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74f984707ff32b96a738d83a30123435</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Channel Nine reporter Danika Mason apologises after viral Today show cross</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/winter-olympics-2026-danika-mason-channel-nine-live-cross/106361740</link><description>Danika Mason has apologised for letting her standards slip during a live cross to the Today show from the Winter Olympics in Milano Cortina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">587053632e396210a542b81ba13dccca</guid></item><item><title>Mark Zuckerberg tells court Meta no longer designs apps to maximise screen time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/meta-ceo-mark-zuckerberg-trial-over-youth-social-media-addiction/106361496</link><description>The Meta chief executive's comments were made in a landmark trial over youth social media addiction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0f5700c9189cbb596e9bc5000e1c747</guid></item><item><title>Home and businesses raided as Darwin NDIA employee arrested for alleged $5m NDIS fraud</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/darwin-ndia-employee-arrested-for-alleged-5m-ndis-fraud/106361742</link><description>A 47-year-old Darwin public servant has been arrested and charged for allegedly defrauding $5 million from the National Disability Insurance Scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08c4965dbddd6b1045f2d272a06f8834</guid></item><item><title>Midwest farmers want Defence action on explosive risk after fire at Depot Hill wildflower reserve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/farmers-want-answers-midwest-bushfire-explosive-risk/106332262</link><description>Residents are calling for clarity and action over the risk of unexploded WWII ordnance after a popular wildflower reserve was torched in WA's Midwest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af835f318aa5ac64f28c3077c486b11b</guid></item><item><title>From crime heists to a BDSM love story, here's what's in cinemas this month</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/what-to-watch-movies-february-pillion-crime-101/106352928</link><description>Australians will also finally be able to catch Sirât and The Voice of Hind Rajab, two movies that will be vying for Best International Film at the Academy Awards next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8040a86763a5a4d748d6c02c57f6603a</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane's Lang Park concert cap almost doubles under new trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/qld-lang-park-suncorp-concert-limit-to-almost-double/106360994</link><description>A one-year trial will see the number of concerts at Brisbane's Lang Park almost double from 12 to 21 per year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e40403a7bf49eabd7e064b1ff94cddfd</guid></item><item><title>How exclusion orders could ban Australian citizens from returning home indefinitely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/australian-citizens-banned-returning-overseas-exclusion-orders/106361634</link><description>One of the Australian women being held in a Syrian refugee camp has been barred from returning home after being given a temporary exclusion order — but the ban may not be as temporary as the name implies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b69ea4e5ccbec5d9f3ed7794e281795c</guid></item><item><title>Lakemba Mosque calls for more security after third threatening letter as Ramadan begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/lakemba-mosque-third-threatening-letter/106361678</link><description>Another threatening letter has been sent to Lakemba Mosque in Sydney's west, the third in recent weeks just hours before the start of Ramadan on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e08c365e2757731d8a0052e8d565fb82</guid></item><item><title>SA secures Australian MotoGP, world-first street circuit announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/sa-secures-motogp-world-first-street-circuit-announced/106361722</link><description>The South Australian government has confirmed the Australian MotoGP will move to Adelaide from 2027, bringing with it huge economic benefits, but the opposition and Greens say the state has other priorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a957e6c008c2cd348424eaa2acecad49</guid></item><item><title>The Kyneton women's football team's story was always about more than just one club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/kyneton-womens-football-story-widespread-issue/106338680</link><description>The women's team from Kyneton's 15-month public and bitter saga suggests it is the canary in the coal mine of a widespread issue for women's players across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af213a5a4c0ac76bfd7fb9926ae5b4ef</guid></item><item><title>Unemployment rate remains at 4.1pc in January, leading to talk of another rate rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/unemployment-rate-australia-january-2026-steady/106362428</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate remained at 4.1 per cent in January, with 17,800 more employed people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3deb22f01e8aa72f8fccc75f74faf25b</guid></item><item><title>Canberra bar declared a crime scene as police seize 'clearly satirical' posters under new Commonwealth hate laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/canberra-bar-declared-crime-scene-displaying-posters/106361644</link><description>Police have seized five posters on display in the window of a Canberra bar, declaring a "crime scene" while they investigate the artworks under new Commonwealth hate laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28f4acd2c8de3673dff101dd5a9f181e</guid></item><item><title>Feed and water supplies dry up in NSW as drought tightens grip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/drought-tightens-grip-nsw-feed-water-supplies-dry-up/106360686</link><description>Over this season's hot and dry summer in New South Wales, farmer Ryan Staniforth has spent much of his time carting water to keep his sheep alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46db9976c248632ce753eccaa9b15e80</guid></item><item><title>BlueScope remains in race for Whyalla steelworks as analyst warns of market concentration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/bluescope-and-foreign-bidders-race-to-buy-whyalla-steelworks-sa/106358600</link><description>Twelve months since the Whyalla steelworks was forced into administration, the sale process has entered its final stages, with the number of interested buyers narrowing from a field of 70 to five. One of those already owns Australia's largest steelworks in Port Kembla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4978ed303afd5ee0b5a590f6ec370084</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Pickering on his ADHD, satire and the 'ludicrous' Trump era</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/charlie-pickering-the-weekly-interview/106307588</link><description>Political satire occasionally comes at a price, but Charlie Pickering still believes the right joke at the right time can have a huge impact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7c1acd1c8fd008196d50eecb9154256</guid></item><item><title>The heartwarming tribute to injured aerials star Laura Peel at the Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/heartwarming-aerials-tribute-laura-peel/106361392</link><description>This Winter Olympics aerials competition saw plenty of Aussies achieve lifetime goals, but they never forgot the one person who was missing — injured champion Laura Peel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">837dd8955b1207595385711ea5af7ba8</guid></item><item><title>Wayne Gardner disappointed Victoria won't host Australian MotoGP</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/former-motogp-champion-disappointed/106363350</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">431dc933aa3e70b73ec6f2262d8685f3</guid></item><item><title>Labor opposition propose five-day kindergarten for Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/tas-labor-announces-five-day-kinder-policy/106362388</link><description>Tasmania's state opposition unveils a policy to extend kindergarten to five days a week in an effort to tackle the state's underperforming education system, but the government says Labor is "light on details".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20d131e8503e551f43bd2fd1d742e601</guid></item><item><title>Premier Chris Minns questions what went wrong amid Cumberland Hospital patient escapes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/nsw-premier-chris-minns-concerned-by-cumberland-hospital-escapes/106362938</link><description>NSW Premier Chris Minns says it is "deeply distressing" that two mental health patients who escaped from the same Sydney hospital within 24 hours went on to allegedly kill three people between them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40a75e6cfb2d8eb4e72c618a140267a6</guid></item><item><title>Alcoa's environmental record 'disappointing' says WA premier after $55m payment for unlawful jarrah forest clearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/alcoa-environment-record-disappointing-says-roger-cook/106363128</link><description>Roger Cook criticises Alcoa's environmental record for being "not at the level we expect", after the US mining giant agreed to pay $55 million for clearing a native jarrah forest in WA's south without approval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">297fe700fe6b245c2b7d9210aafd3c92</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide Ice Arena charged after patrons hospitalised for alleged carbon monoxide exposure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/sa-ice-arena-charged-after-alleged-carbon-monoxide-exposure/106363482</link><description>Safework SA has launched criminal proceedings against the Adelaide Ice Arena, after hockey players and spectators were allegedly exposed to "significant levels" of carbon monoxide more than two years ago, leading to more than 40 hospitalisations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1882f6204d7aad9203d031ed3ba13514</guid></item><item><title>Heavy rain through north Queensland leads to multiple floodwater rescues and Bruce Highway closures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/queensland-rain-bruce-highway-closure-mount-isa-rescues/106362844</link><description>Heavy rainfall across north Queensland has led to multiple rescues and the closure of several sections of the Bruce Highway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f93257abf07c3acbc49599880adb87</guid></item><item><title>Sydney businessman compiled reports for what he allegedly believed was Chinese intelligence, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/sydney-businessman-alexander-csergo-foreign-interference-trial/106363262</link><description>A LinkedIn introduction led to Australian businessman Alexander Csergo compiling reports for two people he believed worked for a Chinese intelligence agency in exchange for cash, a jury has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">651f82d577914adb4455f34dffd493c5</guid></item><item><title>In her memoir, Gisèle Pelicot reveals the secret love behind France's most infamous rape trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/secret-boyfriend-who-stood-beside-gis%C3%A8le-pelicot/106357080</link><description>The world knows Gisèle Pelicot as the woman who waived anonymity during France's most infamous rape trial. But in her new memoir she reveals an unexpected story — the boyfriend she kept hidden and the love that helped her face an open courtroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f0faacac57b0eb7bcc67090ad05c423</guid></item><item><title>North Qld Anglican diocese given green light to sell properties to pay compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/north-queensland-anglican-diocese-to-sell-properties/106361784</link><description>A successful Supreme Court application will allow the church to sell assets to help fund its commitments to victims of historical child abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dafc4035f9ff254859cbe8ab50d8accb</guid></item><item><title>Rugby fans furious over 2027 Rugby World Cup ticket website crashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/rugby-world-cup-tickets-website-crash/106363344</link><description>Rugby fans from around the world are furious after failing to get tickets to the 2027 Men's World Cup due technical glitches and website crashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4827688c1be1b5c4bd7a18a7c04671b5</guid></item><item><title>For salty South Australians, motorsport revenge is oh so sweet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/for-salty-south-australians-motorsport-revenge-is-oh-so-sweet/106363660</link><description>The last Grand Prix in Adelaide was held in 1995 before its move across the border to Victoria. Now, Adelaide has poached the MotoGP — but will it be enough to appease resentful SA Formula One fans?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ffda5df5fc99fb91a7d77ce30ebe2be</guid></item><item><title>Hate laws put free speech at risk, constitutional expert tells NSW extremism inquiry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/concerns-laws-targeting-antisemitism-risk-free-speech/106363916</link><description>An influx of federal and state laws trying to curb hateful rhetoric after a wave of antisemitic attacks are risking free speech and could anger the public, a constitutional law expert warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ec2ab33e6214d10bc2d82b96c8df256</guid></item><item><title>Free RSV flu vaccine for aged care residents to be rolled out in WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/free-rsv-flu-vaccine-for-wa-aged-care-residents/106363530</link><description>After a horror flu season last year, free RSV vaccinations are being rolled out for the first time for older Western Australians living in residential aged care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fe0ef7aa592c15d4a4bc95474ee48a7</guid></item><item><title>Canberra schoolboys face drug-affected driver who struck them outside St Edmund's College</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/court-hears-st-eddies-victim-struck-stolen-car-drug-driver/106364166</link><description>Tayler Hazell is facing his victims in a sentencing hearing in the ACT Supreme Court. He struck two students in Canberra in a stolen car while high on drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a88ee09264511c3bc4d69c943a39cbf1</guid></item><item><title>Hanson digs her heels in, Taylor goes on tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/pauline-hanson-barnaby-joyce-angus-taylor-anthony-albanese/106349216</link><description>This week, the new opposition leader revealed his shadow cabinet while Pauline Hanson spun through a cycle she knows well.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ea3a4f2179a8b0064925ee07ccfca6c</guid></item><item><title>Vegetable scraps to be turned into bioenergy by Scenic Rim farm as part of $291 million project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/qld-kalfresh-bioenergy-scenic-rim/106363982</link><description>A new $291 million project set to turn farm scraps to energy has begun construction in Queensland's Scenic Rim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db61a8e13ba17ab198287e56aca27dc2</guid></item><item><title>What is Skimo? The sport preparing to steal the show at the Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/skimo-debut-winter-olympic-games/106361848</link><description>Skimo, or ski mountaineering, is coming to the 2026 Winter Olympics. But what is the sport and why is it so exciting?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cc7441c0ae245bfcfcc6c6051609c64</guid></item><item><title>Court hears statement murdered woman Irma Palasics made after harrowing assault a year earlier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/act-irma-palasics-trial-hears-statement-from-prior-burglary/106361986</link><description>A statement made by murdered woman Irma Palasics after a burglary at her home a year prior is read to the ACT Supreme Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0c56923a5ad0aebab9da439119af986</guid></item><item><title>Racing NSW disqualifies stablehand and owner Brian Carey over racehorse death in Maryborough</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/brian-carey-city-limits-racing-nsw-racehorse-maryborough/106362914</link><description>Registered owner and stablehand Brian Carey is disqualified after being found guilty by Racing NSW of failing to ensure his racehorse, City Limits, had sufficient food and water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89c623d6aac3515dcfe6d5527459d333</guid></item><item><title>Salmon farm antibiotics found in native Tasmanian species kilometres away</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/salmon-farm-antibiotics-found-in-native-species/106363462</link><description>An antibiotic used by the Tasmanian salmon farming industry is detected in native species more than 10km away from the closest fish operation using it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a05dff63808936e6ea4c1dbd47b42ed5</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of 'controlling' the lives of Venezuelan youth group granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/bail-granted-over-alleged-youth-group-servitude/106363616</link><description>An alleged religious leader accused of "controlling every aspect" of the lives of a Venezuelan youth group has been granted release on strict home detention conditions by a South Australian court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91bc9f195f669d568f2a90e1fe9c2a44</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 13</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide/106361600</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b82fce97399d532a4a35eed6ae6a0ea9</guid></item><item><title>Collingwood apologises after asking elderly members for donations via their wills</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/collingwood-magpies-afl-will-elderly-members-donate/106364978</link><description>The Magpies have come under fire after a letter campaign asking elderly members to amend their wills to donate to the AFL club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f43cc50e873d456431eb853f09b69899</guid></item><item><title>Coles manager moved product onto 'Down Down' promotion days after price hike to be more competitive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/coles-accc-federal-court-dog-food-down-down-pricing/106358664</link><description>A second Coles manager has been grilled in the federal court over whether rushing a product onto a "Down Down" promotion could have broken internal guidelines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41ca3a7b1fd4851df375d2220574fd44</guid></item><item><title>South Korea's ex-president Yoon Suk Yeol sentenced to life in prison over insurrection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/south-korea-president-yoon-suk-yeol-sentenced-insurrection-guilt/106363456</link><description>Former South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol is sentenced to life in prison on charges of rebellion for his attempt to put the country under military rule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8145bfdf54ebbed599a2b489a9edabf6</guid></item><item><title>Rottnest Channel Swim organisers weigh cancellation as 55 kph winds forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/rottnest-channel-swim-threatened-cancellation-rough-seas/106363432</link><description>As thousands of people prepare to tackle Western Australia's iconic Rottnest Island Swim, rough weather is threatening to grind it to a halt just 48 hours before it begins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a39a33fd7de283d8a2e3ed71fb9cf4e</guid></item><item><title>Greg Lynn applies for bail as retrial for High Country camper murder looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/greg-lynn-applies-for-bail-court/106365580</link><description>The former Jetstar pilot awaits a retrial for the murder of Carol Clay, after his 2024 conviction was quashed in December.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77a388716f1e874a2b4c47724de2d0e3</guid></item><item><title>American star completes comeback with figure skating gold after 'retiring' at 16</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-live-blog-day-13/106363160</link><description>Alysa Liu becomes the first American woman to win singles figure skating gold in 24 years, completing her comeback after retiring in 2022 when she was only 16 years old.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfe1fb096a25edbb2543b23f098e496e</guid></item><item><title>Employees of Albany lolly shop fined for illegal tobacco sales say they were never paid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/illegal-tobacco-fines-albany-lolly-shop/106364808</link><description>"Vulnerable" staff at a smoke shop disguised as a candy store in Albany say they were never paid by the shop's mystery operators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">504a81865723b70dcc8bc16fa3cc618b</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/thursday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/106364470</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4c5b51e530a659b7487c6517551d5d1</guid></item><item><title>Have Australian researchers found the secret to treating sepsis?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/have-australian-researchers-found-the-secret-to-treating-sepsis-/106365350</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca3d947de4df531dbc1b85968457a16a</guid></item><item><title>Abandoned Antarctic base is now a pollution threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/abandoned-antarctic-base-is-now-a-pollution-threat-/106365360</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49846b03030ffc2b913431f02159b7f8</guid></item><item><title>Michael Brian Becton sentenced to more than 24 years in jail for child sex offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/man-sentenced-to-24-years-in-jail-over-child-sex-offences/106365380</link><description>Michael Brian Becton, 33, is handed a 24-and-a-half year prison term after pleading guilty to 77 child sexual offences against children and babies. WARNING: This story contains details that some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">388c384c47b78f4a85d064f1750a1efd</guid></item><item><title>Former prince returns home as police investigation continues — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-epstein-police/106365802</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor has returned to his Sandringham home after being arrested and questioned on suspicion of misconduct in public office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5fc074cadfc2697a563fee6e91b29af</guid></item><item><title>What we know about ex-prince Andrew's arrest on suspicion of misconduct in public office</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/what-we-know-about-former-prince-andrew-arrest/106365894</link><description>Police are searching two addresses in the UK, including Royal Lodge on the Windsor Estate where the former prince lived until last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8039d5e6abc316002657b559e90ee456</guid></item><item><title>Ally Hickman showed her grit at 2026 Winter Olympics after heavy fall on second run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/ally-hickman-crash-snowboard-slopestyle-2026-winter-olympics/106366350</link><description>In a Winter Olympics beset by both glory and injury, Ally Hickman's heavy fall in the snowboard slopestyle could have turned a happy day into another disappointing one. Instead, the young Aussie showed her grit to get back up and go again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a129ccb67369e26da08c0952f439ed6</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump suggests decision on Iran likely within 10 to 15 days</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/trump-indicates-iran-decision-likely-in-ten-days/106366370</link><description>Speaking at the inaugural "Board of Peace" meeting in Washington DC, the US president warns "bad things" will happen if a "meaningful deal" isn't reached in nuclear talks with Iran.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c17e84308d8d7bf043e1328663cd0215</guid></item><item><title>Former premier joins community calls for speed reduction at 'dangerous' fatal intersection in Newham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/community-calls-for-speed-reduction-newham-intersection-victoria/106364280</link><description>A community in central Victoria is calling for a 20 kph speed limit reduction at a "terribly dangerous" intersection after four major accidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d28bf645384eca294d072c5b45849511</guid></item><item><title>Man On The Run: How Paul McCartney rebuilt his life after The Beatles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/paul-mccartney-documentary-man-on-the-run-review/106364370</link><description>Morgan Neville's new documentary is a fascinating portrait of an artist rebuilding himself while the world watches on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f4da03f75ed84529ea3aaf5400af393</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: Museum robberies, the Lunar New Year and a new shadow cabinet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/weekly-news-quiz-february-20/106362896</link><description>It has been a huge week in news. Did you catch these stories?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa766aab7e5861a7bbb39277f470de89</guid></item><item><title>Sisters Lisa and Rachael Maza reunite on stage for the world premiere of Black Light</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/lisa-rachael-maza-sisters-black-light-malthouse-theatre/106357630</link><description>The former head of Indigenous theatre company Ilbijerri teams up with her sister Lisa for the world premiere of Black Light, which tells the story of three generations of Blak women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1799e84905988608fb42c35ca34a445</guid></item><item><title>Calls for protection of Tasmania's penguins amid reports of birds 'handled by the neck'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/people-interacting-with-tasmanian-penguins-and-harming-them/106361614</link><description>Each summer, tourists flock to Tasmanian beaches to marvel at penguins, but for some, admiring the birds from afar is not enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a8bc422a73f9012a025e072732b4fbb</guid></item><item><title>Police guarding former prince Andrew's residence in Sandringham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/police-guarding-former-prince-andrew-s-residence-in-sandringham/106366520</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">230140cfa446b0397fb1807d140d3ab6</guid></item><item><title>Police say 'hope is fading' in hunt for kidnapped Sydney grandfather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/chris-baghsarian-kidnapping-dural-update/106366514</link><description>Police believe they have found a "stronghold" used by the kidnappers of Chris Baghsarian in Dural as the search for the 85-year-old continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc8967c1b1d6ddfb449c5911301dc1f2</guid></item><item><title>Grace Tame event in Bendigo to proceed despite pressure to cancel appearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/grace-tame-international-womens-day-event-bendigo/106361838</link><description>An International Women's Day event in Bendigo featuring former Australian of the Year Grace Tame will go ahead despite calls for it to be cancelled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad432cd5670825e9b24157e6726d05dc</guid></item><item><title>Georgia Voll top scores as Australia beats India in second Twenty20 by 19 runs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/georgia-voll-following-alyssa-healy-footsteps-in-india-t20/106366526</link><description>The retirement of Alyssa Healy leaves a big hole at the top of the order, but Georgia Voll looks capable of stepping in after a career-best outing in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74487880f457828fe8e726b872f23c9d</guid></item><item><title>As electric car prices fall, will affordability win over drivers?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/cart-electric-vehicles-becoming-more-affordable/106348534</link><description>The price tag of EVs has been a barrier to uptake. As cheaper models hit the market, will more drivers go electric?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8e8609bc047b4700deb6c7a5c8c5aa4</guid></item><item><title>The 2026 South Australia election is here — Have your say about what matters to you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/your-say-sa/106310300</link><description>We want to know what issues matter most to you and what you want us to find out ahead of the March 21, SA election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8775ae3583b363e14b02f155e2e28dce</guid></item><item><title>Full list of 11 Australian women with ISIS links trying to leave Syria revealed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/eleven-australian-isis-brides-trying-to-leave-syria-named/106362024</link><description>The ABC can reveal the names of the 11 women connected to former Islamic State fighters in Syria who attempted to journey home to Australia this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b55cf419212aa7070f0842155fe39b42</guid></item><item><title>Voters divided as Barnaby Joyce considers contesting New England for One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/new-england-divided-over-barnaby-joyce/106353714</link><description>One Nation MP Barnaby Joyce says he might recontest his seat of New England as a candidate for One Nation if the party needs him to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8216e2cb0110f0bcd4db9bab70757914</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's arrest could end monarchy's 'never complain, never explain' mentality</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrest-a-problem-for-monarchy/106365934</link><description>British royals have lived by the adage "never complain, never explain", but these days, many of their subjects are demanding answers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69ce80bb0d80419516702662a1c32494</guid></item><item><title>Youth justice experts warn over-policing of residential care children is 'manufacturing criminals'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/over-policing-residential-care-children-fast-tracking-criminals/106352902</link><description>Experts say over-policing and South Australia's youth criminal justice system is helping turn children in residential care into criminals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18308ad8258e1668e4b639d5c38e6dcf</guid></item><item><title>Study to test whether a new helmet will significantly reduce risk of concussion in football players</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/helmet-studied-to-see-if-it-reduces-concussion-risk-footballers/106358372</link><description>A lot of research has gone in to treating concussions, but now scientists are testing a new helmet to see if it can prevent them before they happen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f22fb72db16b8951d854fc6dc06f4c17</guid></item><item><title>Can Angus Taylor get beyond slogans to craft a sound immigration policy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/angus-taylor-immigration-pauline-hanson/106349268</link><description>The rifts in Australia's social cohesion can be seen in the blow-up over the so-called ISIS brides and their children, who want to come to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81483ff7c63fdba169c22b024c766cea</guid></item><item><title>Prominent arts lawyer labels Commonwealth hate speech laws 'problematic' for artists, democracies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/shock-police-seized-canberra-posters-under-hate-laws/106364938</link><description>Police are assessing posters seized from a Canberra venue under new Commonwealth hate speech laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad3305e3701237d24a77287e3248bc39</guid></item><item><title>Wild horse art on birth certificates is 'hypocritical', says brumby welfare group</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/brumby-birth-certificate-art-outrage/106363854</link><description>A limited-edition birth certificate released to mark the Chinese Year of the Horse is being labelled "hypocritical" as a cull of wild horses continues in the NSW high country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">036d3db4d54a10ba8cdd2c50a1ae692e</guid></item><item><title>Car driving Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor leaves UK police station.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-released-after-being-in-custody/106366694</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5d1b414c5b63a2abd8afd19a7fb4208</guid></item><item><title>Amyl and the Sniffers singer in escalating legal battle with photographer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/amy-taylor-amyl-and-the-sniffers-court-cases-copyright/106361084</link><description>What began as a photo shoot with champagne, ice cream and humorous glamour shots of Amy Taylor, singer from punk band Amyl and the Sniffers, has escalated into a legal fight over copyright, the US Constitution and an application for a restraining order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2eecb7daec40c63d6dec04c319e48120</guid></item><item><title>Coalition willing to help stop passports for IS-linked women— as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/federal-politics-live-albanese-taylor-labor-coalition/106363700</link><description>Angus Taylor says the Coalition is willing to help the government strengthen legislation so women with ties to Islamic State are not issued Australian passports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e73f6a4c21f2ed041db318fdf5bfddfe</guid></item><item><title>Investigation finds cave diver Gary Gibson died after being separated from dive buddies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/gary-gibson-cave-diver-death-report/106363634</link><description>Australia's peak cave diving body rules out malfunctioning equipment as a factor in the death of a man while diving in SA's Tank Cave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06d1bf34074bc49aeae30b6eee34d569</guid></item><item><title>More rainfall expected for parts of northern Queensland after wet week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/more-rainfall-forecast-for-northern-qld/106362726</link><description>A risk for further heavy rainfall and thunderstorms is possible in northern parts of the state today and into the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e9add29fa1f01a82340402c2e1aad56</guid></item><item><title>First NT women's prison opens in Alice Springs with focus on rehabilitation to break 'cycle of reoffending'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/first-nt-womens-prison-opens-in-alice-springs/106357580</link><description>Thirty-five female prisoners have moved into the Northern Territory's first women's prison, near Alice Springs, with more expected in the coming months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b13e3f1982f1c6fef53a91ff356eabb1</guid></item><item><title>Live: Major US fund's credit squeeze could 'blow up'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-friday-20-february/106366740</link><description>Shares in US asset manager Blue Owl have fallen sharply after it announced it was having challenges meeting investors' cash demands. Follow the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8cfa058595f0f84f2b91273acd73f15</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says Andrew's arrest is a 'shame' for Royal family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/donald-trump-says-andrew-s-arrest-is-a-shame-for-royal-family-/106366752</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3ac836173af3ee6429afa5d754a1fc1</guid></item><item><title>Pilbara housing company looks to modular houses as solution to Australia's shortage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/pilbara-housing-company-seeks-modular-houses-for-rent/106354430</link><description>Amid warnings regional housing shortages will deepen, the Pilbara city of Karratha in northern Western Australia is looking to modular homes as a cost-effective and quicker fix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">328dfb8704255c3f3b1711173a91cda9</guid></item><item><title>Ingham abuzz as recovering sugar town prepares to host Tones And I concert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/ingham-buzzing-ahead-of-tones-and-i-concert/106357352</link><description>A dedicated community campaign results in the Australian singer performing a one-off, almost sold-out show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54a2843af718594604b8837c663e03da</guid></item><item><title>Sam Altman and Dario Amodei refuse to hold hands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/sam-altman-and-dario-amodei-refuse-to-hold-hands/106366810</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28360275abe5f689dc70a72962b98b0f</guid></item><item><title>Bill Gates pulls out of India AI summit amid Epstein files scrutiny</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/bill-gates-pulls-out-of-india-ai-summit-amid-epstein-scrutiny/106366684</link><description>Microsoft co-founder Bill Gates pulls out of his keynote address at India's AI Impact Summit hours before it was scheduled to take place.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46985f074b03fc243b85c6e6a2c7f890</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor released under investigation after almost 10 hours in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrested-misconduct-in-public-office/106366200</link><description>The former Duke of York has been released under investigation by British police, as officers continue to search his former Windsor home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94a6bbd07a298ae5c28f71caf5061d5c</guid></item><item><title>Bangarra Dance Theatre wins Golden Lion at international dance festival Venice Danza 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/bangarra-dance-theatre-golden-lion-venice-biennale/106366904</link><description>Indigenous dance company Bangarra Dance Theatre has become the first company and first First Nations performers to receive the Golden Lion at Venice Danza, the international festival of contemporary dance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1e2f7d948461775c920779a3628e602</guid></item><item><title>'Dying' NASA satellite leaves Australia's north waiting hours for latest fire information</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/dying-satellite-delays-nafi-fire-detections/106353398</link><description>A NASA satellite used to detect bushfires in real time across two thirds of Australia is "dying" and it could be months before a replacement is online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">816ad33b117b9b0c1f1a67a375fa58e4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump hosts first 'Board of Peace' meeting with new pledges for Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/donald-trump-hosts-first-board-of-peace-meeting/106366982</link><description>A group of nations will provide billions of dollars and thousands of troops to rebuild Gaza, according to pledges made at the inaugural meeting of Donald Trump's "Board of Peace".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de8507029b17ae7487ff35961e9fef5d</guid></item><item><title>Canadian skier Cassie Sharpe's horrific crash in the halfpipe reminds us of Winter Olympics dangers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/cassie-sharpe-canadian-freeski-halfpipe-crash/106366818</link><description>As Cassie Sharpe lay motionless on the base of the Livigno halfpipe, the excruciating tension reminded us all that winter Olympians are only ever seconds from disaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca8a04bde9604f081e69e3f402a12a68</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: JD Vance laments Eileen Gu's choice and Scotty James channels Wolf of Wall Street — day 13 quick hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/winter-olympics-day-13-quick-hits-eileen-gu-jd-vance/106365688</link><description>Scotty James says he is not done, while Sweden claims the entire curling world is "against us". Here are the quick hits from day 13 at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a9ff45d94aa4dfae8c06d942bbc0bcd</guid></item><item><title>Fiji, Palau and Tuvalu set to show world leaders climate change impact ahead of COP31</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/pacific-nations-set-to-host-world-leaders-on-climate-change/106366110</link><description>Fiji, Palau and Tuvalu look set to host world leaders and climate change ministers in the lead-up to COP31 in a bid to encourage larger countries to accelerate cuts to emissions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efb0153cc3ad4a4f839fc3664ed151a9</guid></item><item><title>Is it OK to feed Australia's wild birds?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/is-it-ok-to-feed-australias-wild-birds/106349168</link><description>Many of us love interacting with and feeding wild birds, but experts say giving them the wrong types of food can do more harm than good.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eec910366a2f5aeb070b335682010295</guid></item><item><title>NT hit-and-run driver Jake Danby's sentence extended on appeal, now to serve two years in home detention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/jake-danby-sentence-extended-on-appeal-2-years-home-detention/106366800</link><description>The sentence of NT hit-and-run driver Jake Danby has been extended on appeal, meaning he will serve two years in home detention. Danby hit two pedestrians with his car in June 2024, killing one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f57345975c6d0ea9d3ea8d0e24b086a</guid></item><item><title>Australian exporters could face windfall if Trump tariffs ruled unlawful by US Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/australian-exporters-windfall-over-trump-tariffs-court-ruling/106363368</link><description>Modelling by consulting firm EY Australia shows Australian exporters would be owed more than $1.4 billion in refunds collectively if the US tariffs are struck down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7de8009fd822c72acadb5cc05ff6a69</guid></item><item><title>NT cattle sector backs draft buffel grass plan as environmental and Aboriginal groups say it favours industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/buffel-grass-weed-draft-plan-groups-say-it-favours-industry/106309368</link><description>Cattle producers support the NT's draft buffel grass weed management plan, but it has attracted criticism from traditional owners and environmental groups.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f63e14c6d52852a5e04560d27f31045b</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos lose World Club Challenge to Hull KR 30-24</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/brisbane-broncos-lose-world-club-challenge-to-hull-kr/106367354</link><description>After pulling off three straight comebacks to win the NRL premiership, the Brisbane Broncos fall just short of another miracle against Hull KR in the World Club Challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">226460c361ffc36183702882e85cf411</guid></item><item><title>Indra Brown's Winter Olympics medal contention doesn't remove the reality of school homework</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/indra-brown-qualifies-2026-winter-olympics-halfpipe/106366490</link><description>Sixteen-year-old Indra Brown came into the Winter Olympics as one of the top medal contenders in freeski halfpipe — a status elevated since she finished fourth in qualification — but it still doesn't get her out of maths homework.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c99296c009f79f41a37a2c64a4d0bb1</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide University internal emails reveal research accreditation issue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/adelaide-university-experienced-accreditation-issue/106362188</link><description>The newly merged Adelaide University has experienced an accreditation and compliance issue for human research projects, only receiving "conditional" accreditation as opposed to full approval from a federal body late last week with further documentation still required.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1074dc2ea71a4632f0d18d991206f2e</guid></item><item><title>David James Pye found guilty of murdering former Rebels boss Nick Martin after recruiting sniper</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/david-pye-guilty-orchestrating-assassination-nick-martin-sniper/106365638</link><description>Bikie David Pye is convicted of murder after he paid a trained sniper to assassinate his former friend and ex-Rebels boss Nick Martin in front of horrified onlookers at a drag racing event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbf544938badafba7fef8c6ab33f86a3</guid></item><item><title>Commercial fishing licence buybacks recommended in latest harmful algal bloom report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/sa-parliament-report-into-harmful-algal-bloom-handed-down/106363850</link><description>Fishing licence buybacks and long-term restocking plans are some of the recommendations in the latest report into South Australia's harmful algal bloom, which has been labelled as "vanilla" by one scientist turned political candidate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d3a00e55feef726ec2f63dce3afd3b3</guid></item><item><title>Timeline of key moments leading to former prince Andrew's arrest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrest-timeline-explained/106366940</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor has for years faced allegations over his contact with Jeffrey Epstein. These key moments led to his arrest on suspicion of misconduct in public office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a2f46ab3e75e5fbccb701232eb54201</guid></item><item><title>Eric Dane, star of Grey's Anatomy and Euphoria, dies aged 53</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/eric-dane-star-of-greys-anatomy-and-euphoria-dies/106188556</link><description>The star was best known for his role as Dr Mark Sloan in long-running medical drama Grey's Anatomy, and as the patriarch of the Jacobs family in teen hit Euphoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38f5c65f82f5e42103bcfbd84e4e18ea</guid></item><item><title>WA councils could make laws to stop cats roaming under proposed state legislation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/wa-councils-could-soon-have-power-to-stop-cats-roaming/106365476</link><description>The WA government announces plans to give local councils the power to require cats to be contained to owners' properties, to protect native birds and other wildlife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9304ac0385f2634a77bf6bab016498b8</guid></item><item><title>The Board of Peace meant to rebuild Gaza may well end up as another monument to Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/donald-trump-gaza-board-of-peace-speech-leaves-questions/106367958</link><description>Unless the Board of Peace begins to focus and genuinely tries to make the world a better place, this may well prove to be yet another monument to Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19b5df8e6b47a6791635a631e37275ff</guid></item><item><title>Cameron William Leslie Clark, accused of Easts Leagues Club stabbing, appears in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/easts-leagues-club-stabbing-accused-appears-in-court/106366762</link><description>Cameron William Leslie Clark is accused of repeatedly stabbing a 20-year-old female employee of the Easts Leagues Club in Coorparoo last Thursday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96ec27e06b17fd9990fde151bd53e7a1</guid></item><item><title>Complainant in former Liberal MP Rory Amon's sexual assault trial addresses court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/former-nsw-mp-rory-amon-opening-address-trial/106368066</link><description>The complainant in the sexual assault trial of former Liberal MP Rory Amon has told a court of the alleged incidents that took place when he was 13.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47ab61a84a81d5d6cbe195e43a350ef1</guid></item><item><title>Eileen Gu says JD Vance is 'sweet' for saying she should be competing for US at 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/eileen-gu-jd-vance-us-china-row/106367168</link><description>Eileen Gu says she is flattered that JD Vance thinks she should be competing for the US, but feels his comments are driven by an anti-China bias from Washington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d89980fb1e4f346814c87b1cd907a8d</guid></item><item><title>Racist hate mail sent to politicians bears hallmarks of Lakemba Mosque letters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/racist-hate-mail-politicians-hallmarks-of-lakemba-mosque-letters/106367872</link><description>The ABC can reveal two of the threatening, hate-filled letters sent to Lakemba Mosque this month bear close resemblance to similar racist letters sent to multiple politicians since 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6e986afd5bf4027ac11562bd322c9fa</guid></item><item><title>Launceston council approve six-storey City Mission social housing project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/win-for-city-mission-launceston-community-precinct-project/106368388</link><description>Almost 50 new social and affordable homes will be built in Tasmania's north following a green light from council, despite some concern about parking and "anti-social behaviour".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5600bd55175547422ae8d4140aa441f3</guid></item><item><title>What to watch, read and listen to this weekend: Eternity, "Wuthering Heights" and new Meg Mac</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/what-to-watch-read-and-listen-to-this-weekend/106348892</link><description>From a cursed vagina to a classic retold, there's plenty of culture to dig into this weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de104c63d006fce83127b9a4e083d6bd</guid></item><item><title>Senior Constable Stuart Parsonage charged with illegal surveillance by WA Police sex crime division</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/wa-police-officer-court-computer-crime-surveillance-charges/106365724</link><description>Geraldton Senior Constable Stuart Parsonage has been charged with the illegal installation of a surveillance device and unlawful use of a computer by WA sex crime detectives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ef0a162b68b5d35ea9dcd87f112ee98</guid></item><item><title>Parents speak at sentencing hearing for Christopher Turner over fatal gas mix-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/christopher-turner-gas-pipe-mix-up-hospital-victim-impacts/106367440</link><description>The parents of two babies given nitrous oxide in a fatal gas mix-up at a Sydney hospital almost a decade ago express their pain and trauma at the sentencing hearing for the man responsible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e2ecb02a7ac2a45488be9175b75450f</guid></item><item><title>Mercedes F1 boss Toto Wolff defends team over engine drama ahead of Australian Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/mercedes-f1-boss-toto-wolff-calls-rivals-over-engine-saga/106368722</link><description>Mercedes boss Toto Wolff has accused rival Formula 1 manufacturers of ganging up against his team to put pressure on the governing FIA to change the engine rules, but says it will make no difference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf062a44fa8f20ae64da57f3e573fc38</guid></item><item><title>Coroner delivers findings into James Tsindos's death from allergic reaction to delivery meal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/coroner-delivers-james-tsindos-nut-allergy-findings/106367040</link><description>A Victorian coroner hands down her findings into the death of a teenager who suffered a severe allergic reaction to a delivery meal — but it's unclear if more urgent treatment would have saved his life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebac18c8be8e4bab52fd1a3ef61d1b64</guid></item><item><title>Kyra Wheatley ready to ride the chaos and speed of ski cross at Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/kyra-wheatley-ski-cross-speed-chaos-winter-olympics/106366406</link><description>The speed and chaos of ski cross is what attracted Kyra Wheatley to the sport, and to realise a dream 12 years in the making of competing at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1a4056e5ff034ff263b9864448b4429</guid></item><item><title>NT Police search for inmate Clinton Daylight freed from Darwin jail by mistake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/clinton-daylight-prisoner-mistakenly-released-nt-darwin-/106368724</link><description>A search is underway for a 52-year-old prisoner who was mistakenly released from the Darwin Correctional Centre two days ago due to an "administration error" by prison staff.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb7561cc42cd18328fd7c0670fcd32eb</guid></item></channel></rss>