<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:06:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ex-Tropical Cyclone Mitchell brings damage and rain to farmers in WA's south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/strong-winds-wreak-havoc-on-farm-properties-wheatbelt-region/106329960</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says a weather system influenced by ex-Tropical Cyclone Mitchell delivered storms to the Great Southern and central Wheatbelt this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe2f4307942ad8b54d9b5037e79ee1e6</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide's own a medal contender for US in women's double luge at Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/winter-olympics-chevonne-forgan-womens-doubles-luge-adelaide/106331288</link><description>The driest state in the driest country of the world might seem the unlikeliest of places for a star in the Winter Olympics sport of luge to emerge, but Chevonne Forgan will be a medal contender tonight — albeit for Team USA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8190dc66c1226686cb38afb044c221c4</guid></item><item><title>Supersized fatberg clogging Sydney sewer blamed for mysterious debris balls on beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/supersized-fatberg-clogging-sydney-sewer-debris-balls/106309658</link><description>The debris balls that have washed up on NSW beaches in recent years are likely to continue as Sydney Water admits a massive fatberg it cannot reach is clogging sewers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e47536114404d9c787ba564b5b869472</guid></item><item><title>Mum of motorcyclist fatally hit by car tells court of 'immeasurable' devastation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/victim-impact-statement-after-motorcyclist-killed-in-crash/106331510</link><description>A grieving mother whose 21-year-old son died after he was struck by a car while riding his motorcycle south of Adelaide tells a court of her devastation and issues a plea to drivers to "check, double check and check again" for bikes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd9c850d55ea31fc30c7fe349201dec0</guid></item><item><title>Ex-student tells court alleged abuse by Matriculation College teacher led to theft and 'warped' relationships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/hobart-matriculation-college-former-student-gives-evidence-rape/106332498</link><description>A woman suing her former teacher has told a court that the alleged abuse impacted her future relationships and "warped" her professional boundaries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa634835bf36571a04b2a810f331b12b</guid></item><item><title>NSW soccer coach Tullio 'Tony' Giacomo Cigana jailed over child abuse material</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/nsw-soccer-coach-jailed-over-child-abuse-material/106332804</link><description>A once well-regarded soccer coach has been handed a 12 month jail sentence for possessing child abuse material, after a Sydney court heard he has been disowned by family members.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46189d96dae7bf43bc8498eec2003538</guid></item><item><title>New video sheds light on beginning of altercation between police officers and Town Hall protester</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/-white-shirt-man-town-hall-protests-punched-new-video/106332094</link><description>A new video filmed by a bystander and shared with ABC NEWS Verify shows the full minute before two police officers began punching a protester, shedding light on the beginning of the altercation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4fecc044fc46d6003450c9200ac8eba</guid></item><item><title>Bondi: Path to Terror</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/bondi-path-to-terror-four-corners/106332752</link><description>Four Corners is the home of Australian investigative journalism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3e3ec0c11f67bf60a856adfabe308d3</guid></item><item><title>Israeli President Isaac Herzog welcomes 'new beginning' in meeting with Anthony Albanese</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/protesters-rally-as-mps-skip-question-time-for-herzog-visit/106331226</link><description>Israeli President Isaac Herzog meets with the prime minister at Parliament House in Canberra, saying his visit to Australia has been "very emotional".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">579de49026fcdc60f86649be3a4bb35f</guid></item><item><title>Australian dollar reaches '40-year high' against Japan's yen, as cheap holidays fuel tourism surge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/australian-dollar-japanese-yen-currency-exchange-rate-tourism/106332346</link><description>Australia's exchange rate with Japan has grown increasingly favourable to tourists, which have surged to record numbers and topped more than one million visitors in 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7abbc35d9096aae897d046e36ccf9990</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds treated for e-bike injuries in 2025 at Sydney St Vincent Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/ebike-injuries-double-at-sydney-hospital/106332460</link><description>More than 200 people were treated for e-bike related injuries at a single Sydney hospital last year, with one medical professor describing the trend as an "epidemic".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51176d07eca703bb7654923149b12871</guid></item><item><title>RBA deputy governor defends central bank from critics, wonders if Australia is more inflation-prone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/rba-deputy-governor-says-rba-not-criticise-government-policy/106331502</link><description>RBA deputy governor Andrew Hauser says central banks should not criticise normal government spending choices, but he wonders if Australia's economy is more inflation-prone because it is so finely balanced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f806f14f928362b28b219b82a640327b</guid></item><item><title>Australian fans miss out on World Cup tickets as prices skyrocket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/world-cup-ticket-prices-aussie-fans-miss-out/106332736</link><description>A host of Australian fans will be denied the chance to watch the Socceroos World Cup campaign amid accusations of price gouging by FIFA as tickets to the tournament soar to astronomical prices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cb80105f0eeb0984e8c6d7afad7d449</guid></item><item><title>Labor tries again on super taxes, but yet to secure Greens support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/labor-tries-again-on-super-taxes/106331524</link><description>A second attempt to raise taxes on high super balances has been presented to parliament, but will require the support of the Greens to secure Senate passage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a466ab31df35bf825a2dc9c0feee1d03</guid></item><item><title>US bars Palau senate president and former Marshall Islands mayor over alleged corruption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/us-bars-palau-marshall-islands-officials-for-alleged-corruption/106329288</link><description>A senior Palau politician rejects accusations from the United States Department of State that he accepted bribes from "government, business, and criminal interests from China".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4c5d3311f093881fd48b21aa27d5d56</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106332300</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b1ea351c35c93ca1ce9d6966ef4ae9d</guid></item><item><title>Kane Dallow sentenced to two years in prison on fraud and other charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/tasmanian-man-kane-dallow-jailed-for-28-offences/106227598</link><description>A Tasmanian man who impersonated the Launceston Magistrates Court has been convicted on 28 crimes relating to fraud, forgery and perverting justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a46ce2b2cf467d06b9f88e5ba53d770b</guid></item><item><title>Chinese flotilla sailed to edge of Australia's waters, ADF chief reveals at Senate estimates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/chinese-flotilla-edge-australian-exclusive-economic-zone/106333020</link><description>Under questioning in Senate estimates, the chief of the Australian Defence Force reveals that a Chinese flotilla sailed within seven nautical miles of Australia's 200 nautical mile exclusive economic zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54162e69e9611e52a37af7ad332cce70</guid></item><item><title>NSW Parliament backs Cheryl Grimmer's family after 56-year quest for justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/cheryl-grimmer-parliament-motion-buckingham/106332722</link><description>Decades after three-year-old Cheryl Grimmer vanished from Fairy Meadow Beach, NSW MPs move to support her family's fight for justice, as Jeremy Buckingham directly addressed the alleged perpetrator under parliamentary privilege.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9f2d8b7e5889008ddc973077711f317</guid></item><item><title>Surveillance devices captured accused talking about alleged murder of Geoffrey McLean, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/court-hears-evidence-over-alleged-murder-of-geoffrey-mclean/106333170</link><description>An SA Supreme Court trial hears listening devices captured alleged murderer Mark Murphy admitting to his role in killing Geoffrey McLean in 2022. Warning: This story contains details that some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dee7af032cb8fec1ac1248900b766e93</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor resigns from front bench ahead of expected leadership challenge to Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/angus-taylor-resigns-from-frontbench-sussan-ley-leadership/106332492</link><description>Angus Taylor says the Liberals are at their weakest point since the party was formed as he announces his resignation from the front bench.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">719ec35aae82fd4ae16e34d338c37aa1</guid></item><item><title>Parents association fined after allowing alleged sexual offender to keep working at care centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/cranbrook-state-primary-school-parents-association-fined/106333024</link><description>A North Queensland parents association is fined $50,000 for failures in handling allegations of sexual abuse at an after school care service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6337111b808dadf036441dc7b286623c</guid></item><item><title>Olympic great impressed by Aussies as James and Guseli reach halfpipe final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/winter-olympics-2026-live-jakara-anthony-scotty-james/106329908</link><description>Australian Scotty James starts his quest for a third Olympic medal, qualifying in first place with a phenomenal run in snowboard halfpipe qualifying at the Milano Cortina Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bde28b9ffb03fa5cbe8c29b66aac219b</guid></item><item><title>Audio of Austin Appelbee's incredible Triple Zero call after marathon swim to save family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/audio-of-austin-appelbee-s-incredible-triple-zero-call-after-mar/106333512</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a07e12a8516d493dc30141c630813b8</guid></item><item><title>Australia cruises to victory over Ireland in T20 World Cup opener</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/cricket-t20-world-cup-australia-ireland-blog-scores-stats/106330266</link><description>Australia beats Ireland by 67 runs to win its first game at the T20 World Cup, after captain Mitch Marsh was a late out due to testicular bleeding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f10653e8e126254d5fa9b92b8b0d7bf</guid></item><item><title>Channel Nine says Warren Tredrea has now paid costs over long-running legal battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/channel-nine-says-warren-tredrea-has-paid-legal-costs/106333410</link><description>Channel Nine has confirmed it has received legal costs from former AFL player and sports presenter Warren Tredrea, who was ordered to pay $149,000 to his ex-employer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f2d55f17d07ae474e5568f1f5fecbde</guid></item><item><title>PM condemns 'white supremacy ideology' behind alleged Invasion Day terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/prime-minister-closing-the-gap-speech/106332998</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has condemned the "racism and hatred" and "white supremacy ideology" behind the alleged terrorist attack on the Invasion Day rally in Borloo/Perth last month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e3643c30243d9459a9602b299a97cc4</guid></item><item><title>Britney Spears sells rights to music catalogue in reported $281m deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/britney-sells-rights-music-catalogue-primary-wave/106333696</link><description>Spears is the latest music star to sell the rights to their work, a decade after the release of her ninth and last studio album.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46d37ff06c7881b67f6362f876d81145</guid></item><item><title>Jakara Anthony misses medals at 2026 Winter Olympic Games in Milano Cortina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/jakara-anthony-2026-winter-olympics-moguls-final-wilson/106333690</link><description>The Australian spectators in Livigno are stunned as defending champion Jakara Anthony crashes out of contention in the women's moguls final at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a060f999a428f2c8f193deb043d835a1</guid></item><item><title>Xi Jinping says China's army has undergone 'revolutionary tempering' in corruption crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/xi-jinping-acknowledges-army-corruption-crackdown/106333834</link><description>Xi Jinping's comments were the first public admission of issues in China's armed forces since an investigation was launched into senior members of the body that overseas the country's military.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c77d72b3b87ccaf57b6cca7a5238b8a</guid></item><item><title>Jakara Anthony may not have won Winter Olympics moguls gold, but winning is not always measured in medals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/jakara-anthony-2026-winter-olympics-moguls/106333208</link><description>Disaster stared Jakara Anthony in the face and meted out the cruellest of injustices as she missed out on a moguls medal at the 2026 Winter Olympic Games. But her response showed us the character that should make Australia proud regardless.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e7220da0752d7dbb33f88021143e2b1</guid></item><item><title>The identities linked to corruption at the CFMEU, according to Queensland's Commission of Inquiry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/cfmeu-inquiry-report-corruption/106333306</link><description>Members of bikie gangs, convicted murderers and violent criminals are among more than 25 people who allegedly benefited from or are linked to corrupt behaviour at the CFMEU, according to a report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79526cb09b14525015408b39b1c1b5b4</guid></item><item><title>Crack found in new $786m Bridgewater Bridge, RTI documents reveal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/concrete-cracks-in-bridgewater-bridge-rti-documents-reveal/106326476</link><description>Days before the official opening, the Tasmanian government's largest-ever infrastructure project hit a hurdle, with a large crack picked up in one of the Bridgewater Bridge's piers detected and fixed, documents show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dedb596ad7690da3fa77fd190349acb0</guid></item><item><title>Kath &amp; Kim is back on ABC iview. Test your Fountain Lakes fan credentials with our quiz. It's noice, it's different, it's _____</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/kath-and-kim-quiz/106286470</link><description>It's an Aussie classic, but do you know who delivered these iconic lines in Kath &amp; Kim? Put down your cardonnay and footy franks and show us what you've got.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b67dba22afc919812a6491878f676fa7</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor is moving to challenge Sussan Ley — but not on his terms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/angus-taylor-sussan-ley-leadership-timing-not-wanted/106331132</link><description>Angus Taylor was holidaying in Europe when his colleagues began manoeuvring to topple Sussan Ley. A leadership spill this week wasn't what he or Sussan Ley wanted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32d6f00ceb18364ee804ea3ff647cbdf</guid></item><item><title>Transparency concerns as Bougainville's Panguna mine that sparked civil war on path to reopen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/bougainville-signs-secretive-deal-to-reopen-panguna-mine/106331778</link><description>The Autonomous Bougainville Government signs a secretive deal to reopen the huge Panguna gold and copper mine that sparked a catastrophic civil war three decades ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7a5ff00e0503cc102c30c6e22dae858</guid></item><item><title>Australia's toxic legacy at Wilkes Station in Antarctica</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/wilkes-station-in-antarctica-a-toxic-legacy/106281888</link><description>The ABC has been given rare access to an abandoned Australian base in Antarctica that continues to pose a threat to the environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86fbd4ded36d272a381c32bb0d71bd55</guid></item><item><title>Old Bureau of Meteorology website still getting thousands of clicks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/old-bom-website-drawing-traffic-months-after-new-page-launch/106326812</link><description>The new BOM website is still drawing criticism, with 400,000 users turning to the old site, despite $1.15 million in recent updates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6571b8e0e99bb64c79240519d9e09619</guid></item><item><title>Australia Diamonds defeat Jamaica 80-33 in third netball Test to claim 3-0 series win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/australia-diamonds-defeat-jamaica-80-33-in-third-test/106333890</link><description>Coach Stacey Marinkovich believes a refreshed Diamonds squad has found its "identity" ahead of attempting to become the first Australian netball team to defend Commonwealth Games gold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">572f0f2c0fcd545047cd50c575ce4950</guid></item><item><title>Shoalhaven Council loses control over leadership appointments after Andrew Constance hire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/andrew-constance-shoalhaven-council-preformance-improvement/106329850</link><description>The NSW government is set to take control of senior leadership recruitment at Shoalhaven City Council, amid probity concerns regarding the hiring of former Liberal minister Andrew Constance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bdaa91ffe7f73c9cc7024178f88a0bc</guid></item><item><title>A look at the ballistic missile program Iran refuses to negotiate on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/iran-ballistic-missile-program-weapons-us-talks-trump/106307798</link><description>Iran has spent decades building the largest and most diverse ballistic missile stockpile in the Middle East and is refusing US demands to put limits on the weapons program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43b81c86e32420037a6e9d60aa99108f</guid></item><item><title>Animal abuse charge takes one year as RSPCA prosecutions in Queensland drastically decline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/queensland-rspca-drop-in-prosecutions-animal-cruelty/106277220</link><description>A man has been charged with animal cruelty a year after neighbours first made a complaint to the RSPCA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cd8515cd059d1ed39c4f1b8f6e3e75d</guid></item><item><title>Baker Boy talks new album Djandjay, Riverboats festival and family legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/baker-boy-djandjay-album-riverboats-festival-racism-fresh-prince/106321578</link><description>The Yolŋu artist known as the Fresh Prince of Arnhem Land is the king of feel-good bilingual bangers. But heavy is the crown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a7e4fe54da381b9b3169df148ff7976</guid></item><item><title>James Van Der Beek, star of Dawson's Creek, dies aged 48 after colorectal cancer diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/james-van-der-beek-dawsons-creek-star-obituary/105821848</link><description>The American actor was best known for his starring role as Dawson Leery in Dawson's Creek from 1998 to 2003.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0a7efc4b90b9a094e5d4af5773abbca</guid></item><item><title>Canada school shooter 18-year-old Jesse Van Rootselaar acted alone, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/canadian-shooter-identified-in-school-attack/106333992</link><description>Police identify the person who carried out a school massacre in a remote Canadian community as an 18-year-old woman with mental health issues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3aa7b080fb4f452119e946dd95e8524</guid></item><item><title>Severe weather warning issued for heavy rain across south-east Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/qld-south-east-temperatures-peak-heatwave-rainfall-storms/106331426</link><description>A severe weather warning has been issued for south-east Queensland after a day of scorching heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d556db13a5bfa50ba00c3ef5b2711b11</guid></item><item><title>Liberal frontbench resignations snowball as Ley backer resigns — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/federal-politics-live-blog-sussan-ley/106333952</link><description>Angus Taylor has confirmed he will challenge Opposition Leader Sussan Ley for the leadership at the meeting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c870442734b3073dc8ba7593b59edcb</guid></item><item><title>Pam Bondi grilled over Epstein files as survivors express fury over redactions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/pam-bondi-faces-congress-questions-over-epstein-files/106329688</link><description>US Attorney-General Pam Bondi faces furious questions over the censorship of names in the Epstein files at a heated hearing before a committee of Congress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f6370664d2895327e9152794883f228</guid></item><item><title>Australians feel divided as Albanese asks to 'turn the temperature down'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/social-cohesion-anthony-albanese-isaac-herzog/106294752</link><description>Most Australians want greater social cohesion here, even if they don't see much of it right now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa28ba119db2dd3922f89dee680cc738</guid></item><item><title>Darwin traditional owners feel 'bulldozed' by ambitious solar farm company's approach to consultation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/darwin-traditional-owners-bulldozed-solar-farm-legal-case/106325986</link><description>A renewable energy company planning to build a solar farm near Darwin is seeking a court ruling that no native title claim exists at the proposed site.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3568f961affbc4c6c592ec5ca4aea80</guid></item><item><title>Carers WA struggling to cope with unprecedented demand for support services</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/carers-wa-unprecedented-demand-support-services/106328164</link><description>An organisation that helps people caring for vulnerable family members in WA is experiencing unprecedented demand, with services unable to keep up with the community's needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec18c3068cc8e2883c0431ac89a4d61c</guid></item><item><title>How Perth paedophile Jason William Forbes hid in plain sight in suburban Baldivis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/jason-william-forbes-paedophile-hid-in-plain-sight-in-balidivis/106332628</link><description>"A regular sort of bloke" is how one of Jason Forbes's neighbours described the 39-year-old electrician — but behind the walls of his unassuming home in Perth's suburbs, he was hiding a dark secret.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dd2b32c45fd3aa306f9b3c95567d560</guid></item><item><title>Future of Port Hedland's West End uncertain after buyback scheme ends</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/port-hedland-buyback-ends-leaving-uncertain-future/106050394</link><description>As Port Hedland's controversial dust buyback scheme winds up, Pilbara Ports quietly walks away from major plans to build a training facility and accommodation, with development plans for the area still uncertain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3587d18364662f59c0d70ef1c4dbc441</guid></item><item><title>Authorities warn Alice Springs flash flooding threat isn't over, more Central Australian rain predicted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/nt-alice-springs-flooding-wet-weather-emergency-rain/106334186</link><description>Authorities are warning Alice Springs could face further flooding overnight, with forecasts of more wet weather posing a threat to slowly receding water levels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f0111c3d67d09aaf04530f675a2283b</guid></item><item><title>Dispute over West Bank football pitch sparks international campaign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/west-bank-football-pitch-at-the-centre-of-a-dispute/106325786</link><description>A campaign to save a West Bank football pitch from demolition has gone global. The sport's most powerful bodies, as well as social media influencers, have intervened to pressure Israeli authorities to reconsider its destruction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">833c5b5cb80156058addeda78d62d0e6</guid></item><item><title>Protesters march through Melbourne's CBD as Israeli President Isaac Herzog concludes visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/vic-israeli-president-isaac-herzog-melbourne-visit/106331776</link><description>Thousands of people have marched through Melbourne's CBD in protest as Israeli President Isaac Herzog's visit to the Australia winds up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3395870f42eb8d78eea57318fb57f23</guid></item><item><title>South Africa beats Afghanistan at Twenty20 World Cup after two super overs at Narendra Modi Stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/south-africa-afghanistan-t20-world-cup-double-super-over/106334290</link><description>South Africa wins the most dramatic T20 World Cup group stage clash with Afghanistan, featuring two super overs and countless twists of fortune.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb1593268b4f75b9895b6ade64f0c231</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Lindsey Vonn has successful surgery as Vladyslav Heraskevych wears his banned helmet — quick hits from day five</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/winter-olympics-2026-day-five-quick-hits-vonn-helmet/106334002</link><description>A Ukrainian athlete is refusing to back down over a controversial helmet featuring the dead, Lindsey Vonn has a third surgery, and maple syrup has powered Ryan Cochran-Siegle to another medal. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">881eb2ab6d01f7591d27959795e07f03</guid></item><item><title>FBI combs desert terrain for clues in Nancy Guthrie's disappearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/fbi-search-for-nancy-guthrie-continues-suspect-released/106334272</link><description>The man detained for questioning in the investigation into the disappearance of a US TV show host's mother has been released and the search continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98abca4b75add9ecbb225412ab313ec8</guid></item><item><title>Declining birth rates in southern right whales alarm researchers in new study</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/climate-change-driving-down-southern-right-whale-calving-numbers/106332214</link><description>New research on the birth rates of southern right whales – once touted as a global conservation success story – has revealed an alarming decline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5d80284251a8c0cd3713b5fe505730a</guid></item><item><title>Mackay MP who crossed floor to oppose LNP ban on abortion debate defends actions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/nigel-dalton-crosses-floor-abortion-debate/106334698</link><description>Mackay MP Nigel Dalton crossed the floor on Tuesday to vote with Katter's Australian Party to end a parliamentary ban on abortion debate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7af1877d708465b9f166d5233952c8b6</guid></item><item><title>Public DNA databases lead to arrest over historical NSW sexual assault cases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/dna-technology-leads-to-arrest-nsw-sexual-assault-cold-cases/106334110</link><description>A 77-year-old man is arrested in connection with a string of alleged sexual assaults in NSW dating back to the 1990s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">957f7d3970b9923c7d95cd14199fbfad</guid></item><item><title>Albemarle's lithium refinery in WA's South West placed on care and maintenance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/albemarle-kemerton-lithium-refinery-shut-down/106334822</link><description>A multi-billion-dollar lithium refinery in WA's South West has been shut down, affecting about 275 workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5062fb4ce50ee697f9ff892aa55a778c</guid></item><item><title>Scotty James and Valentino Guseli raise their level at 'unbelievable' snowboard halfpipe qualifier at Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/scotty-james-valentino-guseli-snowboard-halfpipe-qualification/106333268</link><description>Scotty James is the man to beat in the snowboard halfpipe at the 2026 Winter Olympics, but a stunning qualifying competition proves that the final is going to be on another level entirely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84595f7c496f7dbad48fe23b81679130</guid></item><item><title>UK police to decide on Andrew Mounbatten-Windsor Epstein trade document investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-police-epstein-files-investigation/106334742</link><description>British police say they are "making progress as quickly as possible" on whether to launch a full investigation into allegations that Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor shared confidential trade documents with late financier and sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70f896e77bb48c2fb240d5bc44cccee3</guid></item><item><title>Three arrested by CFMEU corruption taskforce as premier insists she took appropriate action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/three-arrested-taskforce-hawk-cfmeu-corruption-investigation/106334256</link><description>The arrests were made hours before Premier Jacinta Allan faced reporters over separate allegations detailed in a new report that $15 billion in taxpayer dollars had made its way into the hands of criminals who had infiltrated the union.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc02ad89e79207293943a68d6da5adee</guid></item><item><title>Chris Minns has cracked down on protests. Will it pay off?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/chris-minns-protest-laws-herzog-visit-police/106331440</link><description>By expanding police powers and allowing bans on authorised public assemblies the Minns government has made restricting protest a defining feature of its first term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">527083f33675311c91fad837565911cc</guid></item><item><title>Video shows Guildford shooting victim pleading for help from neighbours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/guilford-shooting-video-shows-victim-plea-for-help/106335532</link><description>Vision shows the moment a bleeding man shot in Sydney's south-west overnight begs for help in a neighbour's back yard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b41f498015908cf46ca9f5559c3f42e2</guid></item><item><title>Four people charged after alleged discovery of thousands of cannabis plants in NSW Riverina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/alleged-cannabis-plant-seizure-nsw-riverina-property/106334240</link><description>Police allege the four people charged were cultivating a large-scale cannabis farm in the Riverina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc722b2f2ad68bab10683a6dbc9f2acf</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 6</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-matt-graham/106330602</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e7755738441e4486f4c3fbb99fe3561</guid></item><item><title>Plotters, kingmakers and dark horses — the Liberals vying for control</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/the-liberals-vying-for-control-of-party/106335554</link><description>Parliament House has entered the spill zone, where politics is at its most primal. Here are the Liberals jostling for control of their much-reduced party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01251844a95201cce2e0e2a131bfd5f3</guid></item><item><title>Reo Te Whetu Marama Marsh pleads guilty to murdering Mary Benedito on Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/marybenedito-murder-former-partner-pleads-guilty-southport/106335664</link><description>The 25-year-old mother was found unresponsive in a Southport apartment in 2021 and later died of her injuries in hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41675660826075c3b3cef1da1d9a7876</guid></item><item><title>Warrnambool pub fined $150k for numerous gambling regulation breaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/warrnambool-pub-fined-150000-for-gambling-regulation-breaches/106334576</link><description>The breaches included three instances of failing to interact with a patron showing signs of distress that may have related to gambling harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d00408e0652d27652cac54ce09ebfb21</guid></item><item><title>Labor releases audio of Liberal MP backtracking on $495 million cost of living policy at industry event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/labor-releases-audio-of-liberal-backtrack/106334676</link><description>South Australia's Treasurer says the Liberal Party has secretly dumped its major $495 million policy less than six weeks out from the state election, with the Opposition arguing it has to wind back Labor's tax due to state budget blowouts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41c94a52edb47ae2f974cc0fddf1c2cb</guid></item><item><title>Electronic monitoring bill strengthening bail laws passes Qld parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/electronic-monitoring-bill-passes-qld-parliament/106335736</link><description>Magistrates will now be able to order children as young as 10 to wear electronic monitoring devices as a bail condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d62157adacf18c5a2ad5fd577c7e2ed0</guid></item><item><title>Camels dying from dehydration descend on APY Lands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/apy-lands-feral-camels-dying-drought-sa/106321572</link><description>Large mobs of camels wreak havoc in remote Indigenous communities as they desperately search for water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c807cb91079deb6ab0c14e1cb642ee2</guid></item><item><title>James Van Der Beek was synonymous with his character. How he embraced it with humour will be his legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/james-van-der-beek-dawsons-creek-character-legacy/106335718</link><description>James Van Der Beek's death prompts wide-ranging tributes from co-stars and friends who have praised his kindness and humour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a76d007b4e1dd749503740e00c13fea9</guid></item><item><title>RBA governor accused by senator of 'gaslighting' Australians on economy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/rba-governor-accused-of-gaslighting-australians-on-economy/106335332</link><description>Reserve Bank governor Michele Bullock fires back at Nationals senator Matt Canavan after he accused her of "gaslighting" Australians over the state of the Australian economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3d3abbc8ab57a6e74180c9d88ef4dae</guid></item><item><title>Ex-police officer Kritan Kutti jailed for arson and possession of bestiality videos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/former-nsw-police-officer-kritan-kutti-jailed/106329584</link><description>A former NSW police officer is jailed for multiple offences, including arson and possession of bestiality videos, while stationed at a rural border post.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b60e70d23fd8c282aad6b8a419d10ebc</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: 'Pindemonium' sweeps Milano Cortina as collectors go treasure hunting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/pindemonium-sweeps-winter-olympics-milano-cortina/106336996</link><description>For Olympic pin hunters, Milano Cortina 2026 is proving to be a thrilling treasure hunt, one that is taking them to corners of the world they may never have otherwise visited.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">133f5a34145c7cffb3fff053a69b8dff</guid></item><item><title>Man faces Mackay court accused of buying boat for drug smuggling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/man-accused-buying-boat-facilitate-import-illegal-drugs/106336250</link><description>Police allege the owner of a recently set up fishing company purchased a vessel with illicit funds to facilitate the importation of illegal drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a0b73226052d169923a9a7b5bfd9b8e</guid></item><item><title>Support firms for Angus Taylor to win Liberal leadership, though Ley expected to achieve 'good result'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/angus-taylor-liberal-leadership-support-firms/106334120</link><description>Support is firming for Angus Taylor to topple Opposition Leader Sussan Ley, though her supporters still expect her to achieve a "good result".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ec143f5904383374cfda9bd081918e1</guid></item><item><title>Mother of autistic man starved to death in Gold Coast hospital 'satisfied' with damning investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/ombudsman-investigation-robina-hospital-death/106334338</link><description>Queensland’s health watchdog finds Stewart Kelly's 2022 hospital death was the result of systemic failures in care, particularly around responding to his complex needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f21ac0cb928bb63b34bd2332709076bd</guid></item><item><title>Chocolate recipes to share some love with the people in your life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/valentines-day-recipes-love-chocolate/106325802</link><description>Whether you are into Valentine's Day or not, these chocolate recipes are perfect for sharing some love.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4882faeefbbf9e3310ba059823c6008</guid></item><item><title>NT coroner hands down findings into death of infamous murderer Martin Leach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/nt-coroner-findings-into-death-of-murderer-rapist-martin-leach/106333540</link><description>An inquest into the 2024 death of double murderer Martin Leach raises questions about whether prisoners have a right to end-of-life care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1343d6662df13df32315e87290cc3466</guid></item><item><title>Liberals' leadership machinations dominate the political week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/liberals-leadership-spill-angus-taylor-sussan-ley/106325872</link><description>The Liberals have spent the week embroiled in leadership woes as the party braces for a spill on Friday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">874320a6b150dbbf66b077e9b0f5d9b5</guid></item><item><title>Ballarat man pleads guilty to taking almost 200 'upskirt' images in public places</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/ballarat-man-derek-grima-pleads-guilty-to-upskirting-offences/106337058</link><description>A court hears a man took "upskirting" images of unwitting women and girls in shopping centres and his workplace, in Melbourne, Geelong and Ballarat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33712309d1614f6803be7f6621987692</guid></item><item><title>Gas exploration seismic testing project rejected in south-west Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/regia-3d-mss-project-seismic-testing-rejected-gas-exploration/106334294</link><description>A controversial seismic testing proposal off Victoria's south-west coast has been rejected in a "rare" move from the offshore regulator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f07ea3447a079671409f13da47906a8b</guid></item><item><title>Two Chinese nationals accused of foreign interference granted bail in ACT Magistrates Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/act-two-chinese-nationals-accused-foreign-interference-bail/106335336</link><description>Police allege the two Chinese nationals, who are charged with reckless foreign interference for alleged spying on the Canberra branch of a Buddhist association, are linked to a woman arrested on the same charge last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8ffcbf499d3b6e411f85857ee4a6971</guid></item><item><title>Severe thunderstorm, heavy rainfall warnings issued for Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/thunderstorms-severe-weather-warnings-south-east-queensland/106337566</link><description>Severe thunderstorms are likely to produce heavy rainfall that may lead to flash flooding across parts of Queensland tonight, according to the weather bureau.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0e82342c3647b805eed1dc7a1817a34</guid></item><item><title>Fatal Queensland house fire inquiry hears father was 'pretty abusive'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/queensland-fatal-house-fire-inquiry/106336740</link><description>The mother of a young boy killed in a house fire in 2017 has given emotional evidence at an inquest into his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e821f83fd67d3541967e14a7c326eb70</guid></item><item><title>New video shows violent arrest of Australian filmmaker James Ricketson at Sydney's anti-Herzog protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/video-shows-arrest-filmmaker-james-ricketson-sydney-protest/106337470</link><description>New video obtained by ABC NEWS Verify shows in vivid detail the arrest of a 76-year-old man, who was later released without charge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e8b85f342914cc4a1db8e8f827b072c</guid></item><item><title>Barbeques Galore enters receivership as debt burns into bottom line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/barbeques-galore-enters-receivership/106337962</link><description>Barbeques Galore has plunged into receivership, leaving question marks for nearly 100 stores that employ about 500 staff.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69523934e505732dbc33d0c34030742d</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106337290</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d261cc973fdb20ab56fe51470b7d321c</guid></item><item><title>Cars submerged, trees torn down, roads inundated: Alice Springs flooding in pictures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/nt-alice-springs-flooding-in-pictures-floodwaters-damage/106336102</link><description>Overnight thunderstorms left Central Australian rivers inundated on Thursday, with rapidly rising floodwaters submerging cars, ripping up trees and leaving multiple people stranded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e025807245504400521b8ef8f7040fd1</guid></item><item><title>Toowoomba Hospital maternity unit to implement recommendations for workplace culture overhaul</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/toowoomba-hospital-maternity-unit-workplace-culture-findings/106338238</link><description>Staff at the Toowoomba Hospital maternity unit will be implementing recommended changes to their workplace culture following an independent review.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fffb7e8031442fc89790d85b110ac64c</guid></item><item><title>Teen bounces back from nasty crash to snatch gold from American great</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/winter-olympics-2026-live-milano-cortina-cooper-woods/106338490</link><description>Two-time Winter Olympic champion Chloe Kim is pipped for first place by 17-year-old Gaon Choi late in the women's snowboard halfpipe final at the Milano Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77fd8c878e9a3a73529932cf9fb473c2</guid></item><item><title>Children prescribed puberty blockers without proper assessment at Cairns health service, review finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/qld-puberty-blockers-cairns-health-service/106336756</link><description>The review of the Cairns paediatric gender health service found that children as young as 12 were given puberty blockers inconsistently and without formal consent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">239aa031616658a4122734a07b49c2df</guid></item><item><title>Father finds family's bones in rubble of Gaza house destroyed in air strikes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/gaza-father-searches-for-family-bones-in-house-rubble/106335798</link><description>Mahmoud Hammad believes he has found his family's remains in the rubble of his house, which was destroyed more than two years ago in air strikes, killing his pregnant wife and their five children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c72e878a5950523e5fef0914825cd59a</guid></item><item><title>Nightcliff by-election set for March 7, Greens and Labor announce candidates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/nt-nightcliff-byelection-candidates-greens-labor-kat-mcnamara/106335938</link><description>The Greens and Labor have announced their candidates for the Nightcliff by-election, set for March 7, after the resignation of Greens MLA Kat McNamara earlier this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bb26b69187d156e3509e605e9c38389</guid></item><item><title>IOC disqualifies Ukrainian skeleton racer Vladyslav Heraskevych over helmet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/olympics-ukrainian-vladyslav-heraskevych-disqualified-helmet/106338586</link><description>Vladyslav Heraskevych is disqualified over his customised helmet featuring the faces of Ukrainian athletes and coaches killed in the Russia-Ukraine war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fccc878b54f516f48ad6edf96316efba</guid></item><item><title>Cooper Woods wins Australia's first gold of 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/cooper-woods-wins-winter-olympic-gold-moguls/106338772</link><description>Cooper Woods has stunned the moguls field to win a maiden career title at the 2026 Winter Olympic Games at Milano Cortina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b63e0dd3c0b2886d37f6baecb4e90bc</guid></item><item><title>Multiple people stabbed outside Coorparoo's Easts Leagues Club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/multiple-people-stabbed-easts-leagues-club-disturbance/106338794</link><description>A 33-year-old man has been arrested after the incident at Coorparoo's Easts Leagues Club on Thursday evening, which left two people in hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c59f0508e5e2d8715e345b2d4079ca1</guid></item><item><title>Cooper Woods welcomed to the Winter Olympic 'gold medal club' by Alisa Camplin-Warner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/cooper-woods-gold-medal-club-alisa-camplin/106338996</link><description>Only seven Australian athletes have ever felt the weight of a Winter Olympic gold medal being hung around their necks. And one of the first, Alisa Camplin-Warner, was thrilled to welcome the most recent, Cooper Woods, to the club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00bcbc79601b776b4d7b20f266d65169</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's border tsar Tom Homan announces ICE withdrawal from Minnesota</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/ice-withdrawal-minnesota-homan-trump-tsar/106339228</link><description>An immigration crackdown in the Midwestern state has been marred by protests and public anger after the shooting of two US citizens by federal agents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebad345af8d5ae5ca9b449aeb32b47bb</guid></item><item><title>Liberal Party poised to dump first female federal leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/liberal-party-poised-to-dump-first-female-leader/106338452</link><description>The Liberal Party is poised to dump its first federal female leader, with Sussan Ley's supporters acknowledging her rival, Angus Taylor, is in the "ascendancy".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6149b17b767527046bc7170e8b43226a</guid></item><item><title>3,100 aged care patients stranded in hospitals as states again press Commonwealth for action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/aged-care-hospital-funding-bed-block/106336820</link><description>With the ink still wet on a new hospital deal, state and territory health ministers will today use a meeting with their federal counterpart to call for urgent action on stranded patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db2af93a0e38f039ffeb1e1ccf5f3042</guid></item><item><title>Water utility 'confident' Hobart drinking water is antibiotic-free after salmon disease outbreak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/salmon-disease-outbreak-antibiotics-river-derwent/106330724</link><description>Tasmania's water provider says there is no risk of antibiotics entering Hobart's water supply, following Huon Aquaculture's use of oxytetracycline in the River Derwent to treat a disease outbreak.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1dee99594bcccdd9569ae25d5806d21</guid></item><item><title>Men face drug cultivation charges after $10 million cannabis bust in Victoria's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/men-face-commercial-drug-cultivation-charges-after-cannabis-bust/106338128</link><description>Police allege a drug bust in Victoria's north-west has uncovered 10 large grow houses cultivating $10 million worth of illegal cannabis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7d9fee7539b4a4ea68bd8031cfeac2b</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: A leadership spill, a ghost barge and mysterious balls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/weekly-news-quiz-february-13/106336680</link><description>Have you been paying attention to the headlines this week? Test yourself here.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8661fd8f3afb21c5f2bd8d2ebafdb227</guid></item><item><title>Italy wins first T20 Cricket World Cup match as Australian-born players shine in 10-wicket win over Nepal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/italy-wins-first-t20-cricket-world-cup-match/106339406</link><description>Sydney-born brothers Justin and Anthony Mosca have guided T20 World Cup debutants Italy to their first win in the tournament, as their unbeaten half-centuries secured a dominant 10-wicket victory over Nepal on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3c6d0fe17105b65b0990f4c481c3845</guid></item><item><title>Cooper Woods, Australia's unexpected Winter Olympic champion, finds his purpose</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/cooper-woods-australias-unexpected-champion-winter-olympics/106339106</link><description>Cooper Woods came into the 2026 Winter Olympic Games ranked 22nd in the World Cup rankings in moguls. But in finding his purpose, he roared to a glorious gold medal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ca54a379cdb065db55986946103d8e3</guid></item><item><title>How the Liberals' first female leader found herself here</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/sussan-ley-liberals-leadership-spill/106325896</link><description>Sussan Ley has had much less than a year to try to prove herself. So how did the Liberals' first female leader find herself on the canvas so quickly and dramatically?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a78c7472c31dc86785a72568b3e7375</guid></item><item><title>ASX boss to depart as another controversy unfolds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/asx-boss-to-depart-as-another-controversy-unfolds/106336322</link><description>A decade of technology failures, unplanned outages, management upheaval, irate investors and the torching of hundreds of millions of dollars has left the ASX's reputation in shreds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d1cb6399c00e87f8a119dacdf9976aa</guid></item><item><title>Epstein victims stand up during House Judiciary Committee hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/epstein-victims-stand-up-during-house-judiciary-committee/106336132</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9715195d155fadad84500e2798d0720</guid></item><item><title>Epstein survivor says release of files was 're-traumatising' and falls short of transparency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/epstein-survivor-says-release-of-files-retraumatising/106317616</link><description>Lisa Phillips says the publication of the "Epstein" files was meant to deliver long-promised transparency but has instead exposed victims, deepened trauma and continued to shield powerful men.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">702d35e388b86c7214a684bca057a62f</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor is the new leader of the Liberal Party. Who is he?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/who-is-liberal-party-leader-hopeful-angus-taylor/105268090</link><description>After months of speculation, Liberals hope Angus Taylor can bring the Liberals back from what many in the party fear is the edge of obscurity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da8415b8432271ddc8217b42ad3a877c</guid></item><item><title>Economist Bruce Preston appointed to RBA Board</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/economist-bruce-preston-appointed-to-rba-board/106337708</link><description>The economics professor is the second academic economist added to the board since a review recommended boosting its expertise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c0edb3495c53e1eb1dd6f353acd5bef</guid></item><item><title>The Christchurch terrorist changed New Zealand, now he is testing its legal system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/christchurch-terrorst-testing-nz-legal-system/106336320</link><description>It may be months before New Zealand finds out if the Christchurch terrorist will be granted an application to have his guilty pleas vacated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ffbd3cb1612c1e71fa5e4924f4f9071</guid></item><item><title>Lake Cargelligo residents live in fear as Julian Ingram clocks up three weeks on the run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/lake-cargelligo-struggles-as-julian-ingram-search-continues/106329894</link><description>As alleged triple-murderer Julian Ingram notches up three weeks on the run, residents in the small town are struggling to heal from shootings that rocked the community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dddd0fec0d64e1564639a60814b2225</guid></item><item><title>More than 100 Stolen Generations survivors gather for apology anniversary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/largest-gathering-of-stolen-generations-survivors-for-apology/106322950</link><description>More than 100 Stolen Generations survivors have gathered in Canberra for the apology anniversary. The government is pledging new money to help them heal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c81bef72da28cb61fb66cddb9bf13666</guid></item><item><title>Marine biologists fight to save endangered seagrass species in Sydney Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/science-key-to-saving-endangered-seagrass-population/106337120</link><description>A centuries-old nautical technique is being redesigned within a small Sydney cove in a bid to save a tiny remnant population of a dying species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c23125b58cdf591c3340528784e5fcd</guid></item><item><title>Intense rainfall risk for south-east Queensland as weather system drenches Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/intense-rainfall-south-east-qld-wet-condtions-queensland/106331410</link><description>South-east Queensland is being told to brace for an intense soaking from today with up to 150 millimetres to fall in some coastal areas and rainfall all weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">554feef4458ed64818b6a117e26a1463</guid></item><item><title>The 'farm-fluencers' taking agriculture online to bridge the rural divide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/farmer-influencers-sharing-rural-lives-online-content-creators/106326048</link><description>Farmers and agricultural workers are taking to social media to educate a new audience while building a community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed4626a80b6a8b07114590acfaf1a595</guid></item><item><title>Cost-of-living crisis sees more young women neglecting health and basic needs, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/young-women-cost-of-living-crisis-basic-needs/106300314</link><description>A study from Deakin University has found many young women admit skipping meals or forgoing medical attention to save money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5cd45054bcabb5c8fa618e72defa4a5</guid></item><item><title>Openly gay men in elite sport are rare, leaving women to lead the way for queer inclusion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/queer-lgbtiqa-inclusion-womens-sport-anneli-maley-wnbl-pride-cup/106149906</link><description>While high profile instances of homophobia in elite men's sport continue, leading female athletes are hoping to help create more inclusive spaces for all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70321d6613ab8607cbaea120ca706e88</guid></item><item><title>Four charged after $10 million cannabis crop busted in Victoria's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/four-charged-after-10-million-cannabis-crop-busted-/106339512</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b696f2667e1fc6727a09310d1c0869ee</guid></item><item><title>Consumers back call for country-of-origin labels on timber sold in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/calls-for-timber-wood-product-country-origin-labels/106335698</link><description>Consumer advocates and the wood products industry say it is time the origin of timber was made clear, as imports grow year-on-year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e45cbaa92971f939d0856d9c106483b</guid></item><item><title>What a 566yo coolabah tree in the Gwydir Wetlands could tell us about climate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/gwydir-wetlands-566-year-old-coolabah-tree-climate-history/106325412</link><description>New research shows some of the coolabahs and river red gums in the Gwydir Wetlands, New South Wales are hundreds of years old, and hold important climate history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a88c850ac8f236466b63627c9ffafc9e</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley to quit politics after losing spill, setting up by-election — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/federal-politics-live-blog-liberal-spill/106339480</link><description>Sussan Ley announces she will quit the parliament after losing her leadership to Angus Taylor, setting up a by-election in her seat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e54c956be73e4b8996ca621b91910220</guid></item><item><title>Kim Jong Un set to pick daughter Kim Ju Ae to lead North Korea, South Korean intelligence says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/kim-jong-un-to-pick-kim-ju-ae-as-next-leader-south-korea-says/106339110</link><description>South Korea's spy agency says that Kim Jong Un is set to choose his daughter as his heir, extending his family's rule into a fourth generation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37569486a4575609470e58b928b30b7e</guid></item><item><title>Max Verstappen critical of new Formula 1 cars as preseason testing continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/max-verstappen-critical-of-new-formula-1-cars/106339508</link><description>Four-time Formula 1 world champion Max Verstappen says the 2026 cars are "not so fun", claiming the increasing energy management demands on drivers are "just not Formula 1".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">950bfbf36871e9c9d62401075e1fd446</guid></item><item><title>NT Australian of the Year Felix Ho volunteers thousands of hours to the community each year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/nt-australian-of-year-dr-felix-ho-thousands-of-volunteer-hours/106329556</link><description>Finding time to volunteer can be a stretch for most people, but for Darwin doctor Felix Ho, who volunteers thousands of hours every year, it's his "full-time hobby".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b99c4561a769bc93eea33549024a298</guid></item><item><title>Share market tumbles on 'traditional Friday 13 meltdown' — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/asx-markets-business-live-news-feb-13-2026/106339608</link><description>Market analysts have blamed a share market sell-off on an increasing trend that is resulting in heavy stock selling as investors fear a meltdown on Wall Street's last day of trade for the week. Look back on the day's business developments in our blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18fef90dc73d15c4a2fdb264a54d455d</guid></item><item><title>Thai raid finds Cambodian scam centre had personal details of 300 Australians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/australians-targeted-by-cambodian-scam-compound/106335866</link><description>Australia's National Anti-Scam Centre says documents seized in a raid on a Cambodian scam compound contained the phone numbers, names and addresses of 300 Australians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08f7a75e42a1578ec6ae98632dc8210b</guid></item><item><title>Why do some regional councils charge for car parking in country towns, while others don't?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/paid-parking-council-in-victoria-parking-meters-fines-cost/106314960</link><description>Parking meters have been ripped out in some country towns, while in others, motorists are still being slugged, and retailers are feeling the pinch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bee258382b42dba9b9634ad0cdab2b36</guid></item><item><title>From new life to grief, Ella Macens's music for the Melbourne Symphony Orchestra is rooted in love</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/music-by-australian-ella-macens-premiered-by-melbourne-symphony/106323262</link><description>After experiencing the Bondi terror attack in December, this composer's new music grew to encompass love's power to heal us from hate and harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bbfdad77654f3b7445bd689a1085326</guid></item><item><title>The key factor that will define your NRL team's chances in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/2026-nrl-season-preview-key-stats/106334724</link><description>With the preseason challenge well underway and the season-opening matches in Las Vegas on the horizon, find out the key numbers that will make or break your team's NRL chances for 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdbd63c61f95bb7099a8f344adfd200e</guid></item><item><title>Raymond Reddington blamed wife Sharon Fulton's disappearance on serial killers David and Catherine Birnie, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/raymond-reddington-blamed-serial-killer-birnies-for-missing-wife/106336720</link><description>Notorious Perth serial killers David and Catherine Birnie could not be ruled out as suspects in the alleged murder of a woman who vanished the same year they killed four young women, the detective who arrested them says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2bbe9165743f94c76dde41edb99743d</guid></item><item><title>Trump repeals power to fight climate change, axes vehicle emissions rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/trump-revokes-basis-of-us-climate-regulation-ends-vehicle-emissi/106339598</link><description>President Donald Trump's administration has revoked a scientific determination that has been the central basis for US action to fight climate change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14587c3b8bd37c5943c0d33c136fd2f9</guid></item><item><title>Keen to declutter this year? Here's how to start</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/simple-ways-to-start-decluttering-at-home/106300708</link><description>Experts say you don't need to pull out the entire contents of a cupboard, beginning with one bag is best.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a8e041b72c037976f8eb5cb64a4f2a3</guid></item><item><title>Albemarle lithium refinery closure gives WA government a critical minerals reality check</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/kemerton-lithium-closure-wa-processing-challenges/106336122</link><description>It was once hoped WA would be in the "box seat" to process critical minerals like lithium. So why are processors like Albemarle pulling the pin?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebccfda86e0d4862543de2b4952b4ff5</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Breezy Johnson gets engaged at the Games, Snoop Dogg shows plenty of support — quick hits from day six</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/sport-winter-olympics-quick-hits-day-six/106339098</link><description>Breezy Johnson's pain of crashing was washed away by the euphoria of love, while Snoop Dogg showed his support with a magnificent snow jacket. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59bf59903ae0317ba477a60054f1e33f</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor becomes Liberal leader after defeating Sussan Ley 34–17</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/angus-taylor-becomes-liberal-leader/106339798</link><description>Sussan Ley, the first female leader of the Liberal Party, is set to quit politics after losing a leadership vote today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fa7d372d6cff076b3d6fe902ba524d0</guid></item><item><title>Former Tottenham manager Ange Postecoglou says Spurs 'not a big club' in wake of Thomas Frank sacking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/former-tottenham-manager-ange-postecoglou-on-club-issues/106339490</link><description>Tottenham Hotspur are "not a big club" because of their policy in the transfer market, former manager Ange Postecoglou has said in the wake of the London club's sacking of head coach Thomas Frank on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ce56a4955c12cf141f86e6540834b3a</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with stalking Israeli President Isaac Herzog during Sydney visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/man-allegedly-stalked-israeli-president-isaac-herzog-sydney/106339786</link><description>Police also allege the 45-year-old man stopped outside a school at Bondi Junction and filmed a security guard while using offensive language.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff670e1d1d3c662da8553512a71dae6c</guid></item><item><title>Cooper Woods' mum reacts after stunning gold medal win in Men’'s Moguls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/cooper-woods-mum-reacts-after-stunning-gold-medal-win-/106339924</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9330246f2d9b13f2b20e5765e9270dc4</guid></item><item><title>Future uncertain for 150-year-old mansion on SA's Limestone Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/struan-house-future-uncertain-amid-research-centre-rebuild/106323358</link><description>Since a government department moved out, the historic Struan House has sat empty, with no set plans for its future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6c247ec0e3848af955a61e405c1cfba</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 medal tally: Cooper Woods puts Australia ahead of Canada and China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-medal-tally/106339814</link><description>Cooper Woods's moguls gold puts Australia ahead of powerhouses Canada and China on the official Winter Olympics medal tally, despite having fewer medals overall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7c36716af86ea21ffeeaac5f7b3ef61</guid></item><item><title>Norway's former PM, Thorbjoern Jagland, accused of aggravated corruption over Epstein links</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/norway-former-prime-minister-ties-with-jeffrey-epstein/106339852</link><description>The files indicate that Thorbjoern Jagland and Jeffrey Epstein's assistants made detailed plans in 2014 for the politician to visit the American in Palm Beach, Florida.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3b70dba55d4ba770182042e51ba2176</guid></item><item><title>Albany Woollen Mills' 101 years celebrated via shared love of blankets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/albany-woollen-mill-in-albany-celebrates-101-years/106322356</link><description>Established in 1925, Western Australia's first and only woollen mill transformed raw wool into fabric and blankets, becoming a cornerstone of Albany's industry before closing in 2002.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebfd4b3313c5a634d2a8d4ee911573eb</guid></item><item><title>Record-breaking heatwave leaves some flower farmers without Valentine's Day blooms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/flower-farmers-heatwave-victoria-losses-valentines-day/106329998</link><description>A record heatwave has destroyed a Mallee flower farm's Valentine's Day blooms, leaving its owner devastated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7db6c60336395b1e9aea3e528a183bc7</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Australian snowboard cross riders struggle after Cam Bolton's injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/winter-olympics-snowboard-cross-emotional-toll-cam-bolton/106338726</link><description>Cam Bolton's broken neck hangs heavily over the Australian snowboard cross team, with his late replacement Jimmy Johnstone vowing his appearance was "all for him".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">108a118275afba78a9d56fcdc5b77bdd</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs woman survives 12-hour flood ordeal on Todd River</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/alice-springs-todd-river-flood-rescue/106338710</link><description>When her mother was swept into the flooding Todd River this week, Alice Springs woman Latarne Wayne went in after her.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a0d92e3f4e0d139f91767b2f3eb420c</guid></item><item><title>Law Enforcement Conduct Commission announces investigation into police actions during Sydney protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/lecc-investigates-town-hall-protest-response/106340598</link><description>The Law Enforcement Conduct Commission says it will investigate the police response to the demonstration at Town Hall against Israeli President Isaac Herzog's visit on Monday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19f86deb588b5858f9b56b0f2e73a2bb</guid></item><item><title>Mystery barge washed up in Torres Strait seen 'struggling' off Bali by retired Australian skipper</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/mystery-barge-seen-struggling-off-bali/106338134</link><description>One of the last known people to have seen a foreign-owned barge at sea before it washed up on a remote Australian island says it was being towed by a boat not suited to the job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b9d38d5664c1c4b6f3f15a0cd9533bb</guid></item><item><title>It took 80 years for a woman to become Liberal leader, and 9 months to ditch her</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/sussan-ley-s-time-as-liberal-leader/106045934</link><description>Sussan Ley vowed to be a different opposition leader, one who consulted widely and listened to her broad church. But it left many wondering what, if anything, she stood for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05d0ee7f0ef658ce063e5a98c8024ae7</guid></item><item><title>Alexander Repin sentenced over murder of Rex Upton in Lismore in 2023</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/alexander-repin-sentence-for-murder-of-rex-upton-in-lismore/106333078</link><description>Alexander Repin had been out of jail for four days when he consumed alcohol and drugs, then murdered an 89-year-old man in Lismore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ceb2ecf386262e6e04d6055c5dac1ba4</guid></item><item><title>Organisations branch out to help men's mental health in regional NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/organisations-branch-out-help-mens-mental-health-rural-nsw/106332542</link><description>Keith Cowen was alone on his farm in regional NSW when he had a heart attack. It made him realise how much he needed mates around him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f33d23d5d6f337a5fe04f7b32b849b2f</guid></item><item><title>Detonated homemade explosive found on oval in south Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/police-information-detonated-homemade-explosive-found-canberra/106340128</link><description>Police have issued a call-out for information after a homemade bomb exploded on an oval in Canberra's south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78659dd92f1ed11830c1aa0c09d5c01c</guid></item><item><title>FBI raises reward to $US100,000 in suspected abduction of Savannah Guthrie's mother</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/fbi-raises-reward-releases-new-images-for-nancy-guthrie/106340336</link><description>The FBI increases its reward and releases new images as part of its investigation into the suspected abduction of US television host Savannah Guthrie's mother, Nancy, from her southern Arizona home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5acb6c395de1e1de01a4284c80b5a013</guid></item><item><title>Ley leaves Taylor an immediate electoral test with Farrer by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/farrer-byelection-sussan-ley-angus-taylor/106341236</link><description>Within two hours of being elected Liberal leader, Angus Taylor has already been delivered his first big electoral test, and it has come from the woman he deposed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a9957d8828440921d19f5f6180a2356</guid></item><item><title>Adolescence writer Jack Thorne on his new TV adaptation of castaway novel Lord of the Flies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/lord-of-the-flies-tv-show-jack-thorne-adolescence/106295874</link><description>After winning an Emmy for writing Adolescence, Jack Thorne's latest project, a TV adaptation of Lord of the Flies, also sits at the intersection of vulnerability, masculinity and violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd85640874e64ee279c21abb06ec290e</guid></item><item><title>Bangladesh Nationalist Party wins nation's first election since gen Z-led uprising toppled Sheikh Hasina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/bangladesh-nationalist-party-wins-first-election-since-uprising/106338732</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party has won a landmark parliamentary election, according to local TV stations, securing a resounding mandate in a pivotal vote.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cecba2d45ea708381aa812a501c1d47</guid></item><item><title>Katie Holmes pays tribute to Dawson's Creek co-star James Van Der Beek in handwritten letter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/katie-holmes-pays-tribute-to-james-van-der-beek/106340686</link><description>In a handwritten letter posted to social media, actor Katie Holmes has paid tribute to her Dawson's Creek co-star James Van Der Beek, who has died. He was 48.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a28511573104b49c927e99586c21dea6</guid></item><item><title>Scotty James's snowboard halfpipe gold medal hopes in judges' hands at Milano Cortina Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/snowboard-halfpipe-judging-2026-winter-olympics/106333290</link><description>Scotty James is about to face the biggest competition of his life — so what will he need to do to impress those who will decide his Olympic fate?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e9a8c5e104a8050ed2a66b0efe0a3e1</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 7</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-scotty-james/106334738</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e106df780eab1c0c626be93f3649ca6</guid></item><item><title>AFL Origin 2026: Are footy fans still keen on interstate football?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/afl-origin-2026-history-of-interstate-football-state-of-origin/106341464</link><description>After a break of more than a quarter of a century, AFL State of Origin returns in Perth tomorrow with a battle between two proud football states, Western Australia and Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ac0aaab0d5f3f7f1e75b164d08b3c0e</guid></item><item><title>What to know about the Year of the Horse and Lunar New Year celebrations in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/how-lunar-new-year-of-the-horse-is-celebrated-in-australia/106295942</link><description>The Year of the Horse is here and 2026 is a rare "Red Horse" year. Find out what it means, which zodiac animal you are, and how Lunar New Year is celebrated across Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3a175856e4652c5d58d63f6eaaa7e9b</guid></item><item><title>Christopher Mark Jordan, accused of murdering Shyanne-Lee Tatnell, expected to stand trial in September</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/christopher-mark-jordan-shyanne-lee-tatnell-murder-trial/106341902</link><description>A man who has pleaded not guilty to murdering a 14-year-old girl could stand trial as early as September, the Supreme Court in Launceston has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c23cd702f5245c6f78b30b18f7dcff6e</guid></item><item><title>Cooper Woods's hometown celebrates his Milano Cortina Winter Olympics gold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/cooper-woods-gold-medalist-pambula-beach-celebration/106340524</link><description>The 25-year-old moguls champion may have heard the cheers from Pambula as he won gold at the Milano Cortina Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c04820bb3d914ee7ec63fb292abb263</guid></item><item><title>Bald Archy satirical art prize highlights political victories, a murder trial and protest movements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/bald-archy-prize-reveals-politics-crime-and-bob-irwin/106340644</link><description>From the trial of Erin Patterson to the landslide election victory, 2025 is pilloried in this year's satirical art prize, the Bald Archy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e360d2786aee3a4fd31acfa42d11981</guid></item><item><title>Maugean skate's endangered status not changing, Environment Minister Murray Watt says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/maugean-skate-endangered-listing-not-changing-murray-watt-says/106342278</link><description>Environment Minister Murray Watt says his decision to keep the status of a rare Tasmanian skate species as endangered rather than change it to critically endangered is based on scientific advice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e900785b0c8d8f08f1f99a4eaf01e576</guid></item><item><title>Kitchen hand charged with attempted murder, stalking over alleged stabbing at Brisbane leagues club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/stabbing-charge-easts-leagues-club-coorparoo/106341498</link><description>Cameron William Leslie Clark, 33, remains in hospital after the alleged incident at Easts Leagues Club in the inner-city Brisbane suburb of Coorparoo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55690bfd7d349d8f65709a25ca26e37d</guid></item><item><title>Drug vessel MV Raider heading towards Sydney after being stripped of cocaine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/drug-vessel-mv-raider-sydney-bound-after-cocaine-seized/106337382</link><description>A ship caught carrying five tonnes of cocaine is making its way towards Sydney after being stripped of its cargo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62c02ce422ef3bc47452cda0114ef3d5</guid></item><item><title>Detective Inspector Donna Hoffmeier talks about a homemade explosive device found detonated in south Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/detonated-homemade-explosive-found-on-oval-in-south-canberra/106342084</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">818d0aa6cc06c931938555e4dfaf1fa5</guid></item><item><title>Flower industry peak body pushes for country of origin labelling amid Valentine's Day rush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/flower-industry-peak-body-seeks-country-of-origin-labelling/106340602</link><description>Millions of red roses will fly off florists' shelves this weekend, but the flower industry says there is not much to tell customers where the flowers are from.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85ad6e4fc8075f48a7b72dcf0b7c7234</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley to quit politics after losing Liberal leadership spill.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/sussan-ley-quits-politics-after-losing-leadership-spill-/106341296</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">489da7b06a51dd2c888d653c7a1a0ef8</guid></item><item><title>To survive, Angus Taylor's Liberals must now get over their self-obsession</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/angus-taylor-liberal-leadership-change-self-obsession/106339870</link><description>By its new leader Angus Taylor's own admission, the Liberal Party is running out of time to pull out of the nosedive that has it heading towards oblivion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6deaa2b7ef412fd41ea270749ef71894</guid></item><item><title>Rain map southeast Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/rain-anim-130226/106342574</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c993d4824ab3b7c5e80cef69c39ca03</guid></item><item><title>Heaviest outback rain in 15 years tracks east to flood Queensland and northern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/rain-storms-for-queensland-chance-of-flooding/106342492</link><description>This rare desert drenching is the result of an intrusion of very humid tropical air — an air mass — which is now over Queensland, where it will stall for several days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f824db6bcc6bd869039d56a5148b4d4</guid></item><item><title>Sunshine Coast environmentalists outraged by Comiskey Group Coochin Creek site approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/environmentalists-oppose-comiskey-group-coochin-creek-sites/106342062</link><description>The Queensland government has approved a massive music festival and event site despite environmentalists saying it's "disgraceful" to put tourism before sustainability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">513c3220a4dbf0da3778dbee7016daee</guid></item><item><title>Mining camp supposed to be cash cow for WA council but huge debts took it to brink of collapse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/shire-of-coolgardie-sale-kambalda-mining-camp-bluebush-village/106331572</link><description>A controversial mining camp that cost the Shire of Coolgardie $24.8 million to build and led to accusations of "gross financial mismanagement" could be sold to one of Australia's biggest gold miners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89bca277218ba8072e40a924e302b8bc</guid></item><item><title>Australia in danger of World Cup elimination after 'unbelievable' loss to Zimbabwe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/cricket-australia-zimbabwe-t20-world-cup-live-blog-scores/106327068</link><description>Australia's hopes of advancing out of Group B are dealt an almighty blow as Zimbabwe claims one of the biggest upset wins in T20 World Cup history in Colombo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">476ca6531e7d6c07f466b52971129dba</guid></item><item><title>How do you find modern dating? Share your highs and lows with us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/audience-callout-modern-dating-love-stories/106287262</link><description>Whether you've shed tears of joy, sadness or even laughter in the process, we want to hear it all — but keep it under 150 words.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e85c8d73dd7cdf15e05f480eb2c663e8</guid></item><item><title>Support for all-ages performances among changes proposed for NSW's live music scene</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/changes-proposed-for-nsw-live-music-industry/106342426</link><description>The state government introduces what it describes as a "world first" bill to support the live music scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f2148b3c35f403dc6e9467efc37b781</guid></item><item><title>US man linked to Wieambilla shooting sentenced to three years' prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/donald-day-wieambilla-shooting-sentence/106342394</link><description>A US-based conspiracy theorist with links to the Wieambilla shooters is handed a three-year sentence for firearms offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8af3d279107fa5b0e7ef4c045a515afb</guid></item><item><title>Out of 38,000 people fined for non-voting in NT local government elections just 3 per cent have paid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/-38-000-fined-for-non-voting-in-the-nt-3-per-cent-have-paid/106342158</link><description>Just 3 per cent of voters fined for not voting in last year’s Northern Territory local government elections have paid the penalty. Debate is growing over whether the system is working — or unfair to voters in remote areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7e516b49aab0aa22c5101d34c71fe0d</guid></item><item><title>Tim Picton's accused killer Brodie Dewar says Labor identity made unwanted advances on cousin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/tim-picton-accused-killer-brodie-dewar-paramount-nightclub-/106340252</link><description>A man who allegedly killed Tim Picton in a one-punch attack outside a Perth nightclub claims the Labor identity had repeatedly approached his female cousin before being escorted out of the venue because he was intoxicated, a Perth court hears.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83536e93561ec71286007899af12d406</guid></item><item><title>Cigarette lighter prompts gun scare near Hyde Park girls' school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/man-charged-after-gun-scare-at-unley/106343012</link><description>A man spotted with what was initially believed to be a gun near a shopping centre in Adelaide's inner south will face court charged with the assault of an emergency worker, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f43dda364f12294fc1353efd83feafc2</guid></item><item><title>Teenager hit by a car at Narre Warren in Melbourne's south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/child-hit-by-car-narre-warren-melbourne/106343388</link><description>A 16-year-old has life-threatening injuries after he was hit on Pound Road about 4:30pm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdd7c102c6863731086e30e72d10cc28</guid></item><item><title>Sydney children's author Oliver Phommavanh jailed for sending sexually explicit messages to minors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/childrens-author-oliver-phommavanh-jailed-for-grooming-minors/106342160</link><description>Oliver Phommavanh is sentenced to six-and-a-half years in prison with a non-parole period of four years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c59431758c6b35c4dc27a1b4299ab7a8</guid></item><item><title>Woman dead, son in coma as detectives probe alleged Albany homicide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/albany-homicide-investigation-development/106341380</link><description>Detectives say the son of a 69-year-old woman found dead in Albany is being treated as a suspect in her alleged homicide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">933fd95c373fdcefd3f51e619f7879ca</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106342580</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76c17c42326e19ea7822ebf9dbd9ff19</guid></item><item><title>US aircraft carrier redeployed from Caribbean to Middle East as Iran tensions rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/us-aircraft-carrier-carribbean-middle-east-iran/106342830</link><description>The United States will send the USS Gerald R. Ford aircraft carrier to the Middle East amid escalating tensions with Iran, according to US media outlets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dba89bbc4532bd10a2663ca44423e737</guid></item><item><title>Tony Abbott says Australia is Judaeo-Christian but warns Angus Taylor about being One Nation-lite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/tony-abbott-on-angus-taylor-one-nation-immigration-assimilation/106342458</link><description>As Angus Taylor takes the Liberal leadership via a spill motion, a former leader with plenty of experience offers up some advice on dealing with One Nation and immigration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b9b39f5ae9e1a7e6d5811e0c79cc190</guid></item><item><title>Live: Aussie snowboarders show promise, Ukrainian faces CAS hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/winter-olympics-2026-live-milano-cortina-scotty-james/106340876</link><description>Mia Clift and Josie Baff move straight into the round of 32 in the women's snowboard cross at the Milano Cortina Winter Olympics. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4daa0023116b48b35965b2688e4f5173</guid></item><item><title>Coroner finds police tactic not the cause of Toowoomba Indigenous man's death in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/steven-nixon-mckellar-coronial-findings-death-in-custody/106343656</link><description>A Queensland coroner finds the cause of Indigenous man Steven Nixon-McKellar's death during an arrest was "multi-factorial".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7cece3525e620fdc4a4921898494d2a</guid></item><item><title>Former prime minister Tony Abbott warns Angus Taylor about being 'One Nation-lite'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/tony-abbott-warns-angus-taylor-one-nation-lite-liberal-party/106343090</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e7dd9602586555d72eb9cd128a70678</guid></item><item><title>Japan seizes Chinese fishing boat, arrests captain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/japan-seizes-chinese-fishing-boat-amid-dispute-between-countries/106343816</link><description>Japanese authorities have seized a Chinese fishing vessel for the first time since 2022 and it comes against the backdrop of a major diplomatic dispute between the countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12e5c1d093edb0d8ed45d30eaa119cd8</guid></item></channel></rss>