<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 19:42:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hobart's Macquarie Point stadium debate weighs 'expert' advice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/hobart-macquarie-point-stadium-debate/105865012</link><description>Tasmania's minister responsible for the proposed $1.13 billion Macquarie Point stadium, Eric Abetz, says there are many "expert" views, but ultimately the government will decide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb634d41fd45254375e1e37438c6811d</guid></item><item><title>Strava is suing Garmin for patent infringement. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/why-is-strava-suing-garmin/105865392</link><description>Fitness app Strava and sports watchmaker Garmin usually go hand-in-hand, but the two fitness tech leaders are now in competition in a US lawsuit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">405e53404a636a1e020301726d45cc2f</guid></item><item><title>Stephen Miller has said Donald Trump has plenary authority but what does that actually mean?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/stephen-miller-donald-trump-plenary-authority/105865430</link><description>A Trump administration official faces criticism after allegedly claiming US President Donald Trump has "plenary authority" while on a live interview with CNN.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7749a6fbb7a76dc4181cbe4a0e3a80c7</guid></item><item><title>Do dishwashers release microplastics when you wash plastic containers and kitchenware?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/do-dishwashers-release-microplastics-wash-plastic-containers/105860862</link><description>If you're worried about microplastics, is it safe to wash plastic containers and other utensils in the dishwasher, given the use of heat and detergents? We asked two experts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fd5611f6ea7fae53cd7f7e02afd0135</guid></item><item><title>Jon Stevens releases new album Shimmer, announces tour on 64th birthday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/jon-stevens-new-album-shimmer-announces-tour-on-64th-birthday/105867096</link><description>From teen idol to rock great, Jon Stevens has fronted legendary bands Noiseworks and INXS. He has chosen his 64th birthday to release a new album and announce a tour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afdcebd18dbb3b1f571e9a4bc92e8758</guid></item><item><title>City of Melbourne set to vote on security camera overhaul, surveillance powers for staff</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/melbourne-city-council-cctv-security-network-proposed-expansion/105864992</link><description>The City of Melbourne is set to vote on a new plan that would see more privately owned CCTV cameras feeding into the city's security network and staff able to access the footage to investigate local law breaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e651efd7aa333e63fda95c9803c5fcae</guid></item><item><title>Australia's parliament is likely to grow for the first time in 40 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/parliament-increase-fixed-terms-senate-estimates/105865534</link><description>Australia's parliament is likely to get larger as the government canvasses possibilities for expanding the number of MPs and introducing fixed or four-year terms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47e1e744d90a2df3ebb85c40bc9c207c</guid></item><item><title>Algal bloom chief asked about 'disaster' declaration as inquiry told of thousands of marine deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/algal-bloom-parliamentary-inquiry-told-of-marine-death-tolls/105866214</link><description>The SA government has never formally requested that the Commonwealth declare the algal bloom a "national disaster", a senior bureaucrat has told a parliamentary inquiry — despite a state minister "advocating" for such a response three months ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">daf6411ce251563c25ae83ac3c0acbde</guid></item><item><title>Grieving Canberra dog owner warns of deadly blue-green algae but testing shows no increased risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/warning-blue-green-algae-lake-ginninderra-toxic-dog-dead/105865256</link><description>Toxic algae is sometimes detected in Canberra's waterways, where a dog died after swimming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf133c39e7536cf2d8235f23b13118b4</guid></item><item><title>With pressure from China to last, more metals facilities could put their hands up for a bailout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/metals-facility-bailout-china-price-pressure/105865170</link><description>The bailout of another metals facility — this time in Queensland — is unlikely to be the last, with pressures on the sector driven by China to keep up for years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">178a81a316c523f3b3497386fb31f5cf</guid></item><item><title>Free the galah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/free-the-galah/105868508</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4b372f0ce14e38305c4153b37c2cf38</guid></item><item><title>Mates channel MacGyver in rescue of galah trapped in power pole in WA's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/macgyver-style-rescue-of-galah-in-wa-north-goes-viral/105865732</link><description>A lifetime sailor says his experience problem-solving with limited resources helped figure out how to rescue a galah trapped in an 8-metre-tall power pole.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1c6d99ab2227d23bfdd561aeeaec0e4</guid></item><item><title>Labor backbencher calls for action to stop countries onselling Australian gas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/ed-husic-gas-reserve-stop-foreign-onselling/105868522</link><description>Ed Husic calls for stronger action to prevent foreign countries that buy Australian gas from onselling it to other countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42f93ef61706ee720ac19d9c1c2ebe2a</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar's military uses paraglider to bomb festival and anti-junta protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/dozens-killed-in-myanmar-military-strike-on-festival/105868620</link><description>People were gathering for the festival and an anti-junta demonstration when bombs killed at least 20 people and injured dozens more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be1cd3bf5f119b10691e3900edf734f0</guid></item><item><title>Beth Mooney, Alana King save Australia from Women's Cricket World Cup upset loss to Pakistan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/womens-cricket-world-cup-live-australia-pakistan-scores/105865554</link><description>Beth Mooney's century and a classy unbeaten 51 from Alana King saves Australia from a stunning upset loss to Pakistan at the Cricket World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68de1642a2a5924a00441e4e4b57ef52</guid></item><item><title>Trio of scientists awarded Nobel Prize in Chemistry for 'development of metal-organic frameworks'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/nobel-prize-in-chemistry-announced/105868538</link><description>Scientists Susumu Kitagawa, Richard Robson and Omar Yaghi receive the 2025 Nobel Prize in Chemistry "for the development of metal-organic frameworks", the award-giving body announces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f15011661bf2d10170a38ea0db800969</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds put foot down to beat South Africa in 67-40 victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/netball-second-test-australia-diamonds-south-africa/105866192</link><description>Australia flew out of the blocks to take a 2-0 lead in the series and extend their unbeaten record against South Africa to an extraordinary 48 wins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0427a680bc32ada296a05841db9a59e</guid></item><item><title>Former FBI director James Comey pleads not guilty in Congress case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/fbi-james-comey-pleads-not-guilty/105868956</link><description>The guilty plea follows an extraordinary chain of events that saw Mr Trump publicly implore Attorney General Pam Bondi to take action against Mr Comey and other perceived adversaries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fd328797f1f1abe6fed7f0fe675ae4b</guid></item><item><title>Jonathan Rinderknecht arrested and charged with deliberately lighting Pacific Palisades blaze in Los Angeles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/man-arrested-charged-lighting-los-angeles-pacific-palisades-fire/105869026</link><description>Police arrested and charged Jonathan Rinderknecht over the fire this week, which was the most destructive in Los Angeles's history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92369c05e25867d8eac4db63d06ae393</guid></item><item><title>Can we still trust Australia's sunscreens?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/sunscreen-spf-factor-labelling-tga/105866434</link><description>Summer is just around the corner, and many Australians are confused right now about which sunscreens they can trust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a36a8730c1869e4f7b2ec19d264243d0</guid></item><item><title>Optus wears blame but government needs to explain how it handled early advice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/optus-triple-zero-communications-anika-wells-senate-estimates/105830532</link><description>The government is determined to avoid wearing any blame for Optus' failure but also needs to be transparent about how it handled early advice from the telco.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98d8487976bf0f469413f350d685cb67</guid></item><item><title>Older Australians struggling to find work before hitting the pension age</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/struggle-to-find-work-before-hitting-pension-age/105866550</link><description>In the three years that 65-year-old Kerry Forrest has been applying for positions, she has faced repeated rejection. She thinks it is time employers consider older workers more favourably.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d07133eca0875d7bd02bcb35fe05a6b4</guid></item><item><title>In voice notes from Gaza, Majeda chronicles her family's displacement and despair</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/the-journey-of-displacement-from-gaza-city/105776430</link><description>The war in Gaza may be ending soon, but those displaced by Israel's bombardment and invasion know their suffering is far from over.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89f402e8df29b0f402e5e387289edcf1</guid></item><item><title>Australia's energy transition in flux amid struggle to build major transmission arteries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/australia-energy-transition-hampered-by-power-lines/105838808</link><description>Touted as a model for the energy transition, a "quick and easy" high-voltage powerline project linking South Australia directly to New South Wales is running dramatically over time and over budget.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3919f7987267766fce355906093f6bda</guid></item><item><title>University wrongly accuses students of using artificial intelligence to cheat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/artificial-intelligence-cheating-australian-catholic-university/105863524</link><description>An Australian university has accused thousands of its students of cheating with artificial intelligence. The problem? Many have done nothing wrong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9aa7eccad194fe36c313cc265ad306a3</guid></item><item><title>Third narco sub found in Solomon Islands, as cocaine and meth trafficking comes to the Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/narco-sub-cocaine-meth-solomon-islands-pacific/105865658</link><description>Cousins Reubenson and Martin Fugui found a 'Made in Colombia' narco sub in Solomon Islands over the weekend — the third such vessel found in the country's waters over the past year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ccb8717f57ba48e14b4a6f2a33a4d8f</guid></item><item><title>Police cordon off scene of deadly Riverstone shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/police-cordon-off-scene-of-deadly-riverstone-shooting/105869112</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59ac7f5147cd34ad3f89d2d34fd454ad</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government urged to take stronger action on conservation as number of threatened species rises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/calls-for-stronger-action-queensland-great-barrier-reef-species/105867412</link><description>The Queensland Conservation Council (QCC) has called out the LNP government for "not taking the environment seriously" with the number of flora and fauna species under threat on the rise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b70dd89997ce7aa2dc6d03f773c448ec</guid></item><item><title>Domain rental report for September quarter shows rent for houses stable across combined capital cities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/domain-rental-report-september-quarter-2025/105868398</link><description>Domain's September quarterly report shows house rents across the country's combined capitals have remained stable for five consecutive quarters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4195ce266d53f9e8b7b3108d8b6860ff</guid></item><item><title>Powerlifting champion aged 82 and ready to represent Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/powerlifting-champion-aged-82-and-ready-to/105868692</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e86a029c85c4645e6a5b1179ad310de</guid></item><item><title>Man who turned to weightlifting for health now headed to powerlifting world championships at 82</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/powerlifting-champion-aged-82-and-ready-to-represent-australia/105868066</link><description>Ravi Sood turned to the gym to help build muscle before a knee replacement. It has changed his life and led him to the World Masters Powerlifting Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37b1b80b2e0569777da0ad8458a97675</guid></item><item><title>Murray Watt nears deal with Coalition to finally overhaul environment laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/watt-coalition-near-deal-epbc-environment-laws/105865472</link><description>Environment Minister Murray Watt will sit down with his Liberal counterpart Angie Bell today, with quiet optimism in both parties that a deal might soon be struck to finally rewrite Australia's "broken" and outdated environment laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">826e7cc6dd7537e0557ff29d46425beb</guid></item><item><title>Infant's death in illegal Robinvale childcare centre among sector's secret failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/nanicha-singchart-childcare-death-among-dozens-of-vic-incidents/105863798</link><description>The death of a 15-week-old baby in an unlicensed home day care in Victoria’s north-west is among more than two dozen disturbing childcare incidents recorded in government documents unearthed by the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c4247f6a5ffdf24ec78c48a9f742fcd</guid></item><item><title>Advocates say First Nations children's commissioner must have power to make change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/snaicc-conference-first-nations-childrens-commissioner/105865612</link><description>Governments have been unable to reduce the rates of First Nations children in out-of-care and youth detention. Advocates say the new children's commissioner needs the power to hold them to account.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8fcc6e4952034663250399e1ab743fd</guid></item><item><title>Family donates $1.7 million to transform dementia care at aged care facility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/family-donation-to-reshape-dementia-care-in-stawell/105865792</link><description>An aged care facility in western Victoria receives an "unprecedented" donation that will allow it to enhance the lives of residents living with dementia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c79206d096282f78f6a33d3d4655ea3f</guid></item><item><title>Hereditary fructose intolerance group to raise awareness about often-misdiagnosed condition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/hereditary-fructose-intolerance-support-group/105762986</link><description>A Queensland woman is on a mission to raise awareness about hereditary fructose intolerance, after having to wait until age 45 to understand why so many foods make her sick.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f0f08453e32ae97dac0be23d422ac74</guid></item><item><title>Endometriosis sufferers battling to manage pain as system struggles to cope</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/endometriosis-sufferers-struggle-pain-mental-health/105811172</link><description>Women suffering from the chronic pain associated with endometriosis have called for more government investment into understanding the condition, with an expert warning the mental effects can be just as debilitating as the physical symptoms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efee30effa42b7415297303fa8cdabb8</guid></item><item><title>Suspected 'narco sub' found in Solomon Islands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/suspected-narco-sub-found-in-solomon-islands/105869286</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc050cfc0ed616541e007bf00d592ff7</guid></item><item><title>Coalition ramps up criticism of communications minister over Optus outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/coalition-ramps-up-criticism-of-communications/105869292</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82d4d56f9195b141e329d0005e044f6d</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, day four recap: St Kilda causes a stir by aborting Leek Aleer deal after adding Liam Ryan, Max Heath joins Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/afl-trade-period-day-four-live-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca/105868314</link><description>St Kilda officially adds Liam Ryan in a trade with West Coast as the AFL world continues to react to the Saints' stunning decision to pull out of a move for Leek Aleer. Here's how day four of the AFL trade period panned out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61352215a3672db81129ef51e60bb9ea</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur wins 50th tennis match for 2025, reaching Shanghai Masters clash with Daniil Medvedev</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/alex-de-minaur-wins-50th-match-of-2025-at-shanghai-masters/105869206</link><description>Alex de Minaur wins 50 matches in a season for the first time in his career as he reaches the quarterfinals at the Shanghai Masters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f318b33e8803f18a1248bbeb3fc659a</guid></item><item><title>AC Milan star Adrien Rabiot says plan to play Serie A match in Perth is 'truly absurd'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/ac-milan-in-perth-plan-criticised-by-star-player-rabiot/105869346</link><description>AC Milan midfielder Adrien Rabiot hits out at plans to play a game in Perth, earning a rebuke from the Serie A chief executive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b67cb7b2da39989b0184ef8b981ebc78</guid></item><item><title>Measles warning issued in WA's Pilbara as confirmed cases rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/measles-cases-from-unknown-source-climbing-in-wa/105867168</link><description>Health authorities say they are not able to trace WA's latest measles cases to a source, meaning they cannot tell how far the virus has spread.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e5094457d4a2fdecf3cadb2c8f3f399</guid></item><item><title>Beast of War is the indie shark movie that bit off a lot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/beast-of-war-kiah-roache-turner-mark-coles-smith/105857098</link><description>Mystery Road star Mark Coles Smith and his Beast of War director Kiah Roache-Turner on taking a chomp out of WWII soldiers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c11e53d16ff74618f42da0430ef3787b</guid></item><item><title>Self-taught child drummer makes rock band debut with The Living End</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/child-drummer-plays-with-the-living-end-wanderer-festival/105861302</link><description>It was a dream come true when 12-year-old Noah Pope was pulled from the crowd to perform with The Living End.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">344b9fa1c598bc226869e34d887a6ff5</guid></item><item><title>Trump says Israel Gaza war ceasefire deal is 'very close', Rubio more cautious</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/trump-says-deal-to-end-israel-gaza-war-is-very-close/105869362</link><description>Donald Trump is handed a note from Marco Rubio during White House talks saying: "We're very close to a deal in the Middle East."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee742bc1a3df383a7ab9cff87ff3c6ec</guid></item><item><title>Dolly Parton responds to concerns about her health, says she is not dying</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/dolly-parton-reassures-fans-after-health-concerns/105869280</link><description>Dolly Parton has taken to social media to hose down speculation about her health after a comment from her sister sent fans into a tailspin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9cf814360dff4a14df6f80136217574</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr returns to Champions League in Chelsea's draw with Twente Enschede</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/sam-kerr-returns-to-champions-league-football/105869372</link><description>Australian striker Sam Kerr makes another appearance for Chelsea off the bench, getting 23 minutes of playing time but unable to break a 1-1 deadlock with their Dutch opponent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8be88f2cf245467da33d855cd83d496a</guid></item><item><title>Israel and Hamas agree to first phase of peace plan, Donald Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/israel-hamas-agree-first-phase-peace-plan/105356144</link><description>US President Donald Trump says Israel and the militant group Hamas have accepted the first phase of a peace plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57611618e3e61827cbf9c31d5a43d060</guid></item><item><title>Gaza updates: Israelis and Palestinians celebrate agreement on first phase of peace proposal — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/israel-and-hamas-agree-to-gaza-peace-proposal/105356146</link><description>US President Donald Trump says Israel and the militant group Hamas have signed off on the first phase of a Gaza peace proposal that would see a pause in fighting and the release of at least some hostages and prisoners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e786618afe3994238f153a2d53cf775</guid></item><item><title>Argentina-Puerto Rico football friendly moved from Chicago amid immigration crack down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/argentina-puerto-rico-game-moved-over-national-guard-in-chicago/105869564</link><description>An Argentine Football Association executive confirms an upcoming football match against Puerto Rico is moving from Chicago due to the National Guard being called in to quell immigration protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35a5e12e2ec1b8bc2ccbf801832e994b</guid></item><item><title>RFS firefighter seriously injured by falling tree at Coutts Crossing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/firefighter-injured-by-falling-tree-at-coutts-crossing/105869728</link><description>A volunteer firefighter is hospitalised with head and neck injuries after being hit by a falling tree on a fireground on the NSW north coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">654deebe092f5cd200812102adee8fc4</guid></item><item><title>Fertiliser plant uncertainty puts Mount Isa Copper Smelter future in doubt despite bailout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/dyno-nobel-fertiliser-plant-impact-on-mount-isa-copper-smelter/105869194</link><description>Mining giant Glencore's government bailout was touted as its outback smelter's saving grace, but uncertainty about a fertiliser plant it relies on could still see it cease production before 2028.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42624d0211cf45c084e8456b48de4067</guid></item><item><title>Albany's tiny art gallery joins growing global community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/tiny-art-gallery-albany-global-movement/105857528</link><description>A new tiny art gallery on WA's south coast adds to a growing global movement of community verge-side offerings that range from puzzles to seed exchange.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbdc3d5da80b26f3c016522a14117d79</guid></item><item><title>Israel and Hamas have reached an agreement. What does this mean for the Gaza peace plan?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/israel-and-hamas-gaza-peace-plan-hostage-deal-explainer/105870194</link><description>All of the living Israeli hostages in Gaza could be released as soon as next week under the first phase of a peace plan led by the United States — but the full details are yet to be released. Here is what we know so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8da3d97ca5dce024309cb5991f9e3f7c</guid></item><item><title>UN to slash quarter of peacekeepers in nine operations globally due to lack of funds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/un-slash-peace-keeping-force/105870788</link><description>That would amount to between 13,000 and 14,000 troops and police removed from their nine operations around the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1c7789b92595e9ac432e52bc0b9a5ae</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins's injury recovery continues ahead of Ashes, Mitchell Starc confident he can perform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/pat-cummins-backed-by-mitchell-starc-in-ashes-tests/105865832</link><description>Australia captain Pat Cummins is in serious doubt for the Ashes and has almost been ruled out of appearing in the first Test as he continues his recovery from a back injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3777906494e600c595b49e6589350fb9</guid></item><item><title>Israel hostage families celebrate at prospect of ceasefire deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/israel-hostage-families-celebrate-at-prospect-of/105873348</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2486901dc1371454b4b06a59c5e1a792</guid></item><item><title>Gaza emergency doctor evacuated, reunites with husband Dr Mo in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/gaza-dr-mo-nour-reunite-perth-australia/105858548</link><description>Mohammed Mustafa and Nour Dalloul got married while bombs exploded around them. Now their war-torn love, forged in the emergency rooms of a Gazan hospital, has found a home in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7558a8e49bfdc55a3cdbe724d3d74777</guid></item><item><title>Bell Bay Aluminium delivers 'unsettling news' to staff ahead of power deal expiry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/bell-bay-aluminium-delivers-unsettling-news-to-staff-/105869370</link><description>Bell Bay Aluminium has told staff the company faces a "significant risk" after negotiations for a new power deal stalled, jeopardising its future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6a799ca0ee5a9a7a0516228a1102673</guid></item><item><title>How reading romance has helped keep the spark alive for this couple</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/romance-books-a-doorway-into-improved-sexual-intimacy/105734524</link><description>After 10 years of marriage and two kids, Joseph Heath and wife Laura are still in the "honeymoon phase". He says romance novels are a large part of why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e4147b61abe9cc6aa8f9a59e8b43f57</guid></item><item><title>Jane Fonda joins other stars to revive a group that emerged during Hollywood's anti-communist panic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/jane-fonda-free-speech-committee-first-amendment/105869756</link><description>The original group was formed in October 1947 at a time when the US government worried that there were communists in Hollywood who were putting left-wing propaganda into the movies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4aee10a373c8419c317734657120521</guid></item><item><title>Tony Burke suddenly keen to answer questions about Islamic State relatives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/tony-burke-andrew-hastie-anthony-albanese/105858462</link><description>This week in Canberra, Tony Burke finally answered questions about the return of Islamic State relatives, Senate estimates turned into an episode of Utopia, and Andrew Hastie quit the frontbench.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c1650235972fc3a8c1d9de82b0cc008</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanians urged to prepare for wind gusts of up to 125kph</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/tasmanians-urged-to-make-preparations-for-damaging-wind-gusts/105869730</link><description>Residents on the north and west coast of Tasmania are being warned to secure loose items around their homes ahead of wind gusts of up to 125 kilometres per hour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd3f34d6777160f9f308d5b13e5847cf</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroo Island visitor details 'extraordinary moment of timing' family came across shark attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/kangaroo-island-shark-attack-witness-extraordinary-moment/105873108</link><description>A man who witnessed the "extraordinary" moment a surfer was bitten by a shark chasing a seal offshore Kangaroo Island has spoken to the ABC after his footage circulated online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d0e5cadb01ecb795fa49f3d163b5f24</guid></item><item><title>First look inside the Sydney Fish Market, with opening date yet to be confirmed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/sydney-fish-market-fist-look/105869460</link><description>The NSW government is expecting construction for the long-awaited Sydney Fish Market development to be completed by next month, but an opening date for the $700 million project is yet to be announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca1a9ee73ddfb5826bb72526f304f43d</guid></item><item><title>Israel and Hamas's first-phase peace plan agreement is monumental but the end of the war is far from certain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/question-marks-on-israel-hamas-peace-agreement-details/105870198</link><description>The announcement that Israel and Hamas have agreed to phase one of a peace deal in Gaza is significant. But despite the celebrations, the end of the war is still far from certain, writes Matthew Doran.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9b24489302e1fcdf06a4b33cf35d476</guid></item><item><title>Netball fights for recognition amid influx of women's sports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/netball-fights-for-recognition-amid-influx-of-womens-sports/105869454</link><description>Netball Australia is taking elite-level netball to regional communities, hoping to showcase the sport's global impact and inspire the next generation of athletes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c29340636422638897d13e7c3376d3f</guid></item><item><title>How drought inspired Goondiwindi's thriving art movement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/goondiwindi-lanescape-sculpture-trail-festival/105867942</link><description>Goondiwindi's Lanescape art collective transforms the Queensland border town into an open-air gallery featuring large steel sculptures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dff5c0bac15384a50569b46b3772841</guid></item><item><title>Mixed feelings among Israelis after news of hostage return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/mixed-feelings-among-israelis-after-the-news-of/105874048</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acca73ee358b7512c5568ad88027636a</guid></item><item><title>Israelis celebrate deal announcement with US flags and Trump costume</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/israelis-celebrate-deal-announcement-with-us-flags/105874066</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f21f0df054032c8c96db83af9221f070</guid></item><item><title>Mitch Brown was thrust into the spotlight after coming out. He wants to use it to 'call people in,' not out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/mitch-brown-hate-after-speaking-out-on-queer-issues/105862948</link><description>After coming out, Mitch Brown became an unofficial spokesperson for queer issues in the AFL. While that experience has been overwhelmingly positive, it's also come with an onslaught of hate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e05331597384262a651057a5ba1156ec</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne boosts Ashes hopes with One-Day Cup century for Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/ashes-australia-england-marnus-century-in-one-day-cup/105873938</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne's case for a men's Ashes call-up continues to build after he scored a second century in the space of a week and third of the domestic summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">362174f44227618140154caed43afb5a</guid></item><item><title>Future of pokies boss hangs in balance after US gaming licence troubles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/future-of-pokie-boss-hangs-in-balance-after-us-licence-troubles/105458416</link><description>An Australian pokie machine giant says it is reviewing its chief executive's future after a US gaming regulator spurned his licence application. It comes months after the ABC revealed he was the subject of a corruption investigation in Austria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae656b170969f4c342d640a338150205</guid></item><item><title>Competition watchdog approves Elders' $475m acquisition of agribusiness rival Delta</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/elders-delta-acquisition-approved-by-accc-competition-watchdog/105869652</link><description>The consumer watchdog has given the go-ahead for Elders to acquire its competitor, Delta, but it must sell six Delta stores in WA to improve competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dda21e910c76f2e0fe579ad341f4b7a</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm grants Nelson Asofa-Solomona immediate release from NRL contract</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/nrl-melbourne-storm-nelson-asofa-solomona-contract-release/105874194</link><description>Melbourne will clear Nelson Asofa-Solomona's salary from its cap after the powerful front-rower was granted a release from the final two years of his deal with the club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b68459e3d2d56c43d3bea81b42409d1</guid></item><item><title>Nebal Farsakh from the Palestinian Red Crescent Society</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/nebal-farsakh-from-the-palestinian-red-crescent/105874528</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5511df97ae5517725e062407713610f0</guid></item><item><title>Thursday's Finance news with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/thursdays-finance-news-with-daniel-ziffer/105875676</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfc1a0f4a149ab3f13a46d956339861b</guid></item><item><title>Deloitte caught out using AI in report for federal government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/deloitte-caught-out-using-ai-in-report-for-federal/105874634</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73a40e241a39295c35b76e8f87cb1de6</guid></item><item><title>Questions over Optus's priorities during the triple-0 crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/questions-over-optuss-priorities-during-the-triple/105874638</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a04cae1697cfd7c08bf89286d042e1f1</guid></item><item><title>The first phase of a Gaza peace deal has been agreed upon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/the-first-phase-of-a-gaza-peace-deal-has-been/105874648</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">973bb4b43edd06a3e9acc285af85cd38</guid></item><item><title>Sharren Haskel on Trump's role in negotiating peace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/sharren-haskel-on-trumps-role-in-negotiating-peace/105874654</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6186c4e1a6509812f15dd71a08a007a0</guid></item><item><title>László Krasznahorkai awarded Nobel Prize in Literature for 'visionary' work that 'reaffirms the power of art'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/l%C3%A1szl%C3%B3-krasznahorkai-nobel-prize-in-literature-2025/105874554</link><description>László Krasznahorkai has been awarded the Nobel Prize in Literature, one of the world's most prestigious writing awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcaabf1e799e51426d25d8a82300fd8f</guid></item><item><title>Ruby Hunter, Shellie Morris and Missy Higgins among recipients at Australian Women in Music Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/australian-women-music-awards-winners-2025/105818332</link><description>The Australian Women in Music Awards recognised contributions across the music sector, from artists, to photographers, journalists, filmmakers, and leaders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6a9fa96fc27f3c059d502ac8fe237a0</guid></item><item><title>Europe Commission President Ursula von der Leyen survives no-confidence votes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/ursula-von-der-leyen-no-confidence-vote/105874816</link><description>The European Commission president has faced criticism from the left and right after striking a tariff deal with the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38f9eb683dff13f9b08da77359695e43</guid></item><item><title>China further limits the export of rare earth materials and products</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/china-rare-earth-exports-limited-further/105874886</link><description>The issue has been a key sticking point in the trade war between Beijing and Washington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5225fa84dc406f960ab2eba29fe1bd5</guid></item><item><title>Jail term increased for man who appealed Gisele Pelicot rape conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/man-appealing-pelicot-rape-conviction-has-jail-sentence-increase/105875152</link><description>Husamettin Dogan, 44, was the only one to have maintained his appeal after the first trial last year of 51 men, including Gisele Pelicot's husband, in the case of mass sexual abuse that shocked France and the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6b4306b2ebdced96d1b3c168eab3648</guid></item><item><title>Google is abruptly changing the game for journalism — again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/google-meta-ai-journalism-future-rug-pull/105866774</link><description>The launch of 'AI Mode' ushers in a future where news sites are kept alive to train AI chatbots for a US tech company.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c1035f383510c24ed89699e014ac496</guid></item><item><title>Gaza updates: US sending 200 troops to Israel to help monitor peace deal — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/israel-hamas-peace-deal-agreement/105874592</link><description>The Israeli cabinet has approved a framework for the release of hostages, according to Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eaca924593267cbefdf218bdd353e087</guid></item><item><title>Vladimir Putin is fearful the return of his convict army could destabilise Russian society, sources say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/russia-braces-for-return-of-convict-army-post-ukraine-war/105812936</link><description>The Russian president views the prospect of an army returning en masse as a potential risk he wants carefully managed to avoid destabilising society, three sources close to the Kremlin said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63589d280dfa3d97b98a39b22696cc63</guid></item><item><title>First Guardian super trustee Diversa 'ticked off' investments, says former financial adviser Ferras Merhi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/first-guardian-shield-super-trustees-diversa-and-equity-trustees/105833840</link><description>A former financial adviser involved in placing thousands of clients into the First Guardian Master Fund says he was given clearance by superannuation trustee Diversa to do so after the trustee initially flagged compliance concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e63548bd7baad68bd71fdff6112324db</guid></item><item><title>Ceasefire announcement met with joy and some scepticism in Israel and Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/ceasefire-announcement-met-joy-scepticism-israel-gaza/105859468</link><description>The announcement of an agreement to phase one of a ceasefire deal between Israel and Hamas brings great joy to many people in Israel and Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6287b88a3d91d9e217c0620510ac952</guid></item><item><title>World leaders praise Donald Trump for achieving 'first phase' of Gaza deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/world-leaders-praise-donald-trump-for-achieving-peace/105875278</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c9daa1e8a2d22ed6ead229d96bd45f4</guid></item><item><title>Trump says hostages to be released early next week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/trump-lays-out-hostage-release-timeline-/105875328</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85cb50918805dc29769a5fd4b26752a5</guid></item><item><title>Paul Brereton 'consulted' for ADF watchdog 11 times while head of NACC, Senate estimates hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/paul-brereton-adf-inspector-general-nacc-11-times/105874846</link><description>Paul Brereton and Labor politicians had previously stated he had stepped away from the body and resigned as assistant inspector-general of the ADF prior to taking on the top integrity job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">535f0ebc70ece92f9915dc1d92a41b2e</guid></item><item><title>Sick sea turtle rescued from algal bloom recovering at Adelaide Zoo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/sick-turtle-rescue-algal-bloom-south-australia/105870382</link><description>A walker says Adelaide Zoo's care for an injured sea turtle he rescued from Moana beach is a small sign of hope amid the destruction of South Australia's algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b126a2a5ee8a3c2fa5ccdc27936d7e9</guid></item><item><title>Will the Liberals hold firm in the fight over freedom of information?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/freedom-of-information-foi-liberals-transparency/105858416</link><description>Crossbenchers are joining forces to condemn the government's FOI bill, calling for its withdrawal and an independent inquiry. Will the Coalition stand for transparency?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d4f97d3849ac29bf5f057276b05c41a</guid></item><item><title>The US sees Pacific Islands as 'tip of the spear', but locals fear becoming China's 'bullseye'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/united-states-military-presence-pacific-guam-palau/105861216</link><description>The United States is spending billions of dollars muscling up across its Pacific Island military outposts, but locals fear their peaceful islands will become a target.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b686686c787aed163ffe21d540cdc7e</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: A viral gaffe, supermoon shots and vintage cars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/weekly-news-quiz-october-10/105870640</link><description>It's that time of the week again. Test your news knowledge to see how much you remember for the week that was.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da11acf65c144e83aee90cade0e96945</guid></item><item><title>Legally-blind skier Georgia Gunew vying for winter Paralympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/paralympic-blind-skier-georgia-gunew-winter-paralympic-training/105833758</link><description>It takes a combination of precision and bravery to ski down the snowy mountains. Georgia Gunew does it all with limited vision, her guide and a "pop-star" style headset.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b5a4aa51a32cd517cfc754812b5fed9</guid></item><item><title>Coal-fired power stations to operate in Queensland until least 2046 as energy road map unveiled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/queensland-government-to-establish-400m-energy-fund/105874318</link><description>The five-year plan lays out what role coal, gas, wind, solar, pumped hydro and battery storage will play over the long-term in Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98cea3b3afe6b8fefd1c007967742783</guid></item><item><title>Beyond Blue survey finds loneliness has deeper impact on some Australians' mental health than financial hardship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/beyond-blue-survey-loneliness-deeper-impact-financial-hardship/105870174</link><description>A new national report by Beyond Blue has revealed loneliness and social isolation has reached new heights, with 46 per cent of respondents listing it as a bigger mental health stressor than financial hardship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1a340ced02484f41a772729fdfd0f33</guid></item><item><title>Why Alliyah is identifying themselves as a victim-survivor — and the power this act holds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/alliyah-identifying-as-abuse-victim-survivor/105865908</link><description>Alliyah's decision to talk about their abuse was a brave act that exposed the red flags that weren't caught along the way — and they hope it helps others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef3b7c86d2e08ce64793b8a13d322eee</guid></item><item><title>Inside the NSW government chat group as the Sydney Harbour Bridge pro-Palestinian march unfolded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/inside-the-nsw-government-chat-group-as-the-sydney-harbour/105867960</link><description>Documents obtained by the ABC reveal internal discussions within the NSW government did not align with the external NSW Police messaging that the march could have been "catastrophic".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1105269e8ef2e54edc7c23640078465</guid></item><item><title>Advocates mixed on plans to bolster undercover police powers to share child abuse material</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/afp-police-powers-child-abuse-material-mixed-response/105869926</link><description>The spread of child abuse material in Australia has come under renewed focus following high-profile incidents of childcare workers abusing toddlers, and a push by the Coalition to introduce mandatory minimum prison sentences for child exploitation offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41ecfaa5a41a9f0d75b44fd9cf4a4991</guid></item><item><title>Global pilot shortage could mean more delays after push to raise retirement age</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/grounding-pilots-age-65-international-flights/105869998</link><description>A bid to raise the retirement age for pilots has been grounded, with some experts warning the decision could worsen flight delays, cause cancellations and increase airfares.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">383777dcff769f6cbd9f7d1b3a76f6aa</guid></item><item><title>London Police release video of criminals snatching phones</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/london-police-release-video-of-criminals-snatching-phones/105866060</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3ae84eb8a819fcf3620bff589243c76</guid></item><item><title>London Police finds bags with metal objects and cash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/london-police-finds-bags-with-metal-objects-and-cash/105865986</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ef0ff3b9b7516d46a97c033ba9c5dba</guid></item><item><title>London is the world's 'phone theft capital', but one Aussie decides to fight back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/london-phone-theft-capital-australian-fights-back/105864288</link><description>Emma Van Der Hoek had only just moved to London from Sydney when her phone was stolen. She was inspired to do something about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">649c2e51f2ebf2e278643bc49e375f4f</guid></item><item><title>London Police release video of moment of phone snatching</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/london-police-release-video-of-moment-of-phone-snatching/105866150</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71cced497b842eeaebf5ef7608b8d36e</guid></item><item><title>Man returns to boxing after sepsis forces partial amputations of his arms and legs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/man-returns-to-boxing-after-quadruple-amputation/105802512</link><description>Adam Smith became "fixated" on returning to the gym after sepsis forced the partial amputation of his arms and legs. Now he can press 365 kilograms and get back into boxing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afd4bacb212ecb09e96e14340d62c3aa</guid></item><item><title>South Africa defeat India by three wickets in Women's Cricket World Cup at Visakhapatnam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/south-africa-defeat-india-womens-cricket-world-cup/105868672</link><description>South Africa defeats co-hosts India by three wickets in the group stage of the Women's Cricket World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">344af34c876b9d1fd805b45a4e937c11</guid></item><item><title>New statistics show Victoria's most dangerous roads are in regional areas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/victoria-most-dangerous-roads-are-regional/105858040</link><description>In regional Victoria, potholes are not being fixed and major rural road projects have stalled, despite the loss of life from accidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f21ea12d59704621728578e03da03e8b</guid></item><item><title>'Sigh of relief': Israelis react to first phase of Gaza peace deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/israelis-react-to-first-phase-of-gaza-peace-deal/105875508</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a72956b4e25dac4a7e00cc28a8997bbe</guid></item><item><title>Israelis gather at Hostage Square in Tel Aviv to celebrate peace deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/israelis-gather-at-hostage-square-in-tel-aviv-/105875500</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c4bf2b01c2bd8a637ef9f0a6752b489</guid></item><item><title>The NT's first Alice Springs-based police commissioner has a rocky road ahead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/new-nt-police-commissioner-martin-dole-challenges-ahead/105872198</link><description>Martin Dole has been a Northern Territory police officer for nearly 30 years — but as the new commissioner, his most challenging role now lies ahead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62a4fe70a93c35ff3bf4d9dd3e6e2dbc</guid></item><item><title>Two dead on private property in Tasmania after tree falls in wild winds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/tasmania-wild-weather-two-dead-in-tree-fall/105875332</link><description>Two people have died after a tree fell on them on a rural property in Tasmania's north-west, amid severe winds and wet weather, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">762b5ecc8c7afc01f1284936da8823ae</guid></item><item><title>RBA governor Michele Bullock fronts Senate hearing, ASX ends the week lower — As it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/asx-markets-business-live-news-10-oct/105875398</link><description>Michele Bullock says either shoppers or merchants will have to pay more under the central bank's proposed debit and credit card changes. The ASX closed lower after oil and gold prices retreated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7b054430694d7b28c309ac6d16c7891</guid></item><item><title>Rain causes crashes during first Bathurst 1000 practice sessions on Mount Panorama</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/bathurst-1000-mount-panorama-supercars-practice-thursday/105875440</link><description>Supercars heavyweights Triple Eight lead the charge into the Bathurst 1000 with one eye on the trophy and another on the weather forecast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c73e68997f4588b80602c150f382881a</guid></item><item><title>What the State of WA’s appeal of Dion Barber’s $2.8 million compensation win could mean for abuse survivors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/-dion-barber-abuse-compensation-appeal-to-set-legal-precedent/105873760</link><description>Less than a decade after the door opened for victims of historic child sexual abuse to seek justice in WA, abuse survivors could be at risk of having that door shut again, writes Cason Ho.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09b69bd78ea93e7d62f375821a7ebad0</guid></item><item><title>Hamas is trusting Trump as his 'eternal peace' in Gaza turns into a shaky ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/analysis-trump-eternal-peace-in-gaza-turns-into-shaky-ceasefire/105874742</link><description>With Israel and Hamas not sticking to Donald Trump's proposed "20-point plan", the deal to bring "eternal peace" in the Middle East looks more like a temporary ceasefire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e597e0e0fb47c628dfaca2d504bc30d</guid></item><item><title>Letitia James, NY attorney general and Donald Trump foe, indicted for bank fraud</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/letitia-james-ny-attorney-general-trump-foe-indicted-bank-fraud/105875568</link><description>New York Attorney General Letitia James, a longtime foe of US President Donald Trump, is indicted for bank fraud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7794029ca8b380e949956f97889ca8f</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, day five recap: Geelong opens Charlie Curnow bidding as Sydney looms, Ben Ainsworth and Campbell Chesser join Blues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/afl-trade-period-day-five-live-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca/105875584</link><description>The chase for Carlton star Charlie Curnow heated up on day five of the AFL trade period, with Geelong seeing an offer rejected as Sydney prepared its bid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1af08ce39a4f267630c93fa4dbf8386</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic advances to Shanghai Masters semifinals, qualifier Valentin Vacherot continues fairytale run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/novak-djokovic-advances-to-semifinals-of-shanghai-masters/105875540</link><description>Fourth seed Novak Djokovic battled past a spirited Zizou Bergs 6-3 7-5 on Thursday to reach the Shanghai Masters semifinals for a 10th time, setting up a clash with surprise package and world number 204 Valentin Vacherot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">745b0675e4a5c74aaa50698faa310769</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia urges respect for its sovereignty after Australia-PNG defence treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/indonesia-responded-pukpuk-defence-agreement-australia-png/105869738</link><description>The landmark agreement commits both countries to "meet the common danger" in the event of an armed attack on either. With that, questions have been raised about Australia's role if the conflict in West Papua escalates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d73f53cf0f068b144851c0c5f4cd706</guid></item><item><title>When is the Nobel Peace Prize awarded? Who decides the winner?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/how-does-the-nobel-peace-prize-work/105870196</link><description>As we wait for the announcement tonight, let's unpack how the awards work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89cda7e751d1afa2530d6153ece46b77</guid></item><item><title>Israeli government approves phase one of Gaza ceasefire and hostage deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/israel-government-approves-gaza-ceasefire-deal-first-phase/105874642</link><description>The Israeli government has approved Gaza's ceasefire and hostage deal, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's office said early on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba82c5f54c63b4cb4cce011d677a0e9f</guid></item><item><title>Australia's dark matter experiment construction nears completion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/the-global-race-to-detect-dark-matter-stawell-lab-sabre/105861050</link><description>Deep underground in an old gold mine in regional Victoria, scientists enter a worldwide race to understand the composition of dark matter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20bdfc9fdb6ec2c681a7dae294b644ed</guid></item><item><title>Netanyahu and US envoys address media after Cabinet meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/netanyahu-and-us-envoys-address-media-after/105875886</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8569563443ad443504dd0b9d6b3b25a5</guid></item><item><title>Industrial businesses to ramp-up noise monitoring over humming noise in Sydney's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/epa-closes-in-on-businesses-over-disturbing-humming-noise-sydney/105870234</link><description>The NSW environmental watchdog has acted on complaints by residents in Sydney's north-west who have been kept awake at night by a disturbing humming noise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c7f8ce47ec86c2e6609ce33551985d2</guid></item><item><title>Several Australian Gaza flotilla activists home after being detained by Israel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/flotilla-activists-detained-by-israel-arrive-home/105875740</link><description>Australians who were on the Global Sumud Flotilla, a fleet of ships intercepted by Israel's navy off Gaza last week, are met by supporters upon their arrival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23ee2234ee1455b66ebd1f3782bcd5a3</guid></item><item><title>Principals' power to ban aggressive parents from school grounds to extend to social media behaviour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/safety-protections-parents-schools-aggressive-parents-review/105875552</link><description>Principals in Victoria already have the power to ban aggressive or violent parents from school grounds, but the state government is looking to apply the power to parents' behaviour on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cfdbdd1cc62140ca01e0eeea675488e</guid></item><item><title>Federal government investigates PFAS spread in Rockhampton amid concern for property prices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/pfas-contamination-rockhampton-airport-concerns-for-properties/105830932</link><description>Christine Stasch was planning to sell her family farm and retire further north. Now, she is fighting for compensation after discovering PFAS contamination on her property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8211dd335880fe3781624b719dbbcd7a</guid></item><item><title>Michael James Vella, 57, charged with murder after alleged assault victim dies in Hervey Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/man-charged-with-murder-hervey-bay-death/105875836</link><description>Police have charged a 57-year-old man with murder over the death of a 40-year-old man in a coastal Queensland town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3cf8dd6d1ded4f8e4ecfb0b79200508</guid></item><item><title>Hollywood icon Paul Feig to take audiences behind-the-scenes of Bridesmaids at SXSW Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/paul-feig-to-go-behind-the-scenes-at-sxsw-sydney/105876010</link><description>Hollywood director Paul Feig has a special strategy that's served him well when it comes to making popular movies and television shows that stand the test of time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bbf931ff2574bffc35e9ba72be36763</guid></item><item><title>Public health alert for nitazenes issued after person dies in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/queensland-records-death-from-synthetic-opioid/105875620</link><description>Queensland Health issues a public health alert warning nitazenes have been detected in tablets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74030fde7f87fd50b0bcb255243ada39</guid></item><item><title>Cairns faces prospect of water restrictions at wettest time of year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/cairns-facing-water-restrictions-wettest-time-year/105874192</link><description>Cairns residents are urged to cut down on their water use as multiple infrastructure failures put the city at risk of water shortfalls heading into summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f3a138386a7fabdb54be0b3faf38c82</guid></item><item><title>PM says there's 'nothing unusual' in Treasury meeting on contentious superannuation tax proposal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/albanese-plays-down-treasury-request-superannuation-tax/105875570</link><description>Anthony Albanese says his request for Treasury to examine a controversial proposal to lift taxes on some superannuation balances is "nothing unusual", rejecting claims he is planning to rewrite it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe7afdcdf15f814487b7881f7653bc89</guid></item><item><title>Matildas confirm return of Sam Kerr to squad for England and Wales friendlies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/matildas-confirm-return-of-sam-kerr/105875916</link><description>Sam Kerr is back in the Matildas squad for the first time since late 2023, ahead of friendlies against Wales and England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5aeea9e4dce40106f87d459df2eade18</guid></item><item><title>Judge dismisses Drake's lawsuit over Kendrick Lamar diss track Not Like Us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/judge-dismisses-drake-lawsuit-kendrick-lamar-not-like-us/105876144</link><description>The judge says a reasonable listener could not have concluded that Not Like Us was conveying objective facts about Drake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f5f53f791e2466fdbe508fd95f87668</guid></item><item><title>Working dog makes championship comeback after leg amputation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/cheese-the-champion-three-legged-dog-comeback/105833270</link><description>Cheese was on track to be a champion when an accident cut his working dog trial career short. A year on from a leg amputation, the border collie is back in the yards and the winner's circle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30087740aaa42038b8fd192bd39249e7</guid></item><item><title>Two dead after magnitude-7.4 Philippines earthquake sparks tsunami warnings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/magnitude-7-4-earthquake-strikes-philippines-tsunami-warning/105877252</link><description>The quake hit in the Mindanao region at a depth of 62 kilometres below ground level and could cause hazardous tsunami waves along coasts within 300km of the epicentre, seismology authorities say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0203a68b6ef5ddf44b4d1ebd08c9622e</guid></item><item><title>RBA governor Michele Bullock says First Home Guarantee could lead to riskier loans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/rba-governor-michele-bullock-senate-grilling-property-price-rise/105873716</link><description>RBA Governor Michele Bullock says the federal government's First Home Guarantee scheme could see some Australians taking out riskier loans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38ef789309a652d1ddba94eab70c3783</guid></item><item><title>David Pocock reinvited to parliament sports club after prime minister weighs in</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/david-pocock-parliament-sports-club-gambling-lobby-sponsorship/105876446</link><description>The former star Wallabies player turned independent senator was kicked out of the social sports club after raising concerns about its links to the gambling industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd97cdeba6a6b1da2db09b46e5826137</guid></item><item><title>Family of ducks cross busy freeway causing six-car crash. (Supplied: Main Roads)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/family-of-ducks-cross-busy-freeway-causing-six-car/105877780</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d14a050539151d14194d0eb2bd5c6a8</guid></item><item><title>Family of ducks crossing Perth's Kwinana Freeway cause six-car peak-hour pile up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/ducks-crossing-kwinana-freeway-cause-pile-up-/105877568</link><description>Six cars are caught in a pile-up as a family of ducks attempts to cross busy Kwinana Freeway during the morning peak hour in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">100e64d032ae73d4bbcb6e6cc6e89b2b</guid></item><item><title>Vladimir Putin says Russian air defences were to blame for Azerbaijani jetliner crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/azerbaijani-plane-crash-russian-air-defences-to-blame-putin-says/105876934</link><description>The Russian president makes his first public admission of responsibility for the crash, in an effort to improve relations with Azerbaijan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">397860cc5db8e0d72e7856342cddcf24</guid></item><item><title>Australia 'still optimistic' Pat Cummins will play first Ashes Test against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/ashes-australia-england-pat-cummins-first-test/105877424</link><description>With the opening men's Ashes Test six weeks away, Australia coach Andrew McDonald is not willing to rule out Pat Cummins taking the field in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1447a7d5df1ddcc1e1d81f8972e49486</guid></item><item><title>Patients may not see benefits of $8.5 billlion bulk billing boost for four years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/bulk-billing-incentive-boost-may-not-flow-for-years/105877228</link><description>Patients may not see the benefits of higher bulk billing for years, and average-out-of-pocket costs are expected to rise, the health department has conceded — despite $8.5 billion being tipped into the GP subsidy scheme from November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59bcd666888fb324634b523eb9d30802</guid></item><item><title>Sydney rock oysters to be grown at Lakes Entrance on the Gippsland Lakes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/victorians-could-soon-enjoy-homegrown-sydney-rock-oysters/105876316</link><description>Victoria could have its own Sydney rock oyster industry after a trial in the state's east yielded positive results.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c3ab285fc280a71bdaa80e9d36de7f0</guid></item><item><title>Can you ever throw out a previous home owner or renter's mail?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/can-you-ever-throw-out-someone-elses-mail/105837974</link><description>Even years after moving in, you might still be receiving someone else’s bills and letters. Here’s what can you do about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bad6b718ab042dcb408f6ce3edd8d58c</guid></item><item><title>Donna Nelson drops attempts to overturn Japan drug smuggling conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/donna-nelson-abandons-japan-drug-smuggling-appeal/105877124</link><description>A Perth grandmother duped into becoming a drug mule in an elaborate love scam abandons her final line of appeal on drug importing charges in Japan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">206f27669cbf42ca05647fc2575cb5ab</guid></item><item><title>From the ARIAs to the AFL we can’t stop watching Yolngu musician Baker Boy ‘sonically evolve’</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/from-the-arias-to-the-afl-we-can%E2%80%99t-stop-watching/105878300</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">948cea2d583b3e2fe2864eccd6f41805</guid></item><item><title>David Sharaz served bankruptcy papers by former WA Senator Linda Reynolds after defamation win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/linda-reynolds-brittany-higgins-david-sharaz-bankruptcy-served/105878088</link><description>Brittany Higgins's husband David Sharaz is served bankruptcy papers by former Senator Linda Reynolds, as she tries to recover damages awarded to her by a Perth court for defamation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1256d5d93c57b054c08e985d405d0b7f</guid></item><item><title>Former Olympic basketballer Danny Morseu 'disappointed' retrial abandoned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/olympic-basketballer-danny-morseu-charges-dropped/105877170</link><description>Danny Morseu's conviction has been wiped but he says he will struggle to find a job, a home, and a source of income after Queensland's Director of Public Prosecutions decided not to pursue a retrial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">225218dcd9709b51e823ef5322977d84</guid></item><item><title>Powerful 7.4 magnitude earthquake strikes off southern Philippines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/powerful-magnitude-earthquake-strikes-off/105878332</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6aec7234ad17e83390993f0a8a6233c0</guid></item><item><title>More Indian cough syrups recalled after 19 children die by poisoning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/more-indian-cough-syrups-recalled-19-children-die/105876056</link><description>The World Health Organisation flags the risk of unregulated export of poisoned Indian cough syrup after 19 deaths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a27bbb9499a2201c6fc01b2dd90f3af9</guid></item><item><title>From the ARIAs to the AFL we can’t stop watching Baker Boy ‘sonically evolve’</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/baker-boy-on-his-new-album-djandjay/105877714</link><description>Yolngu musician Baker Boy talks to News Breakfast about channelling difficult emotions after the Voice referendum to create his new album.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc45ee40f241673075215ef795b126c3</guid></item><item><title>LIV's financial losses do not deter SA premier from $50m golf course</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/liv-golf-losses-will-not-impact-sa-golf-course-plan-premier-says/105877386</link><description>Premier Peter Malinauskas has rejected suggestions his government's North Adelaide golf course redevelopment is a risky investment with LIV Golf losing hundreds of millions a year, as he revealed where the Saudi-backed tournament will be hosted in 2027.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a665172221b8b91d065521a8b05f783</guid></item><item><title>Taylor Swift breaks Adele's record for most album sales in first week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/taylor-swift-breaks-record-for-most-album-sales-in-first-week/105877320</link><description>The star's 12th album's sales success has come despite the mixed reception it received from critics and fans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e75dd58b18405de92bc999a70707258</guid></item><item><title>Court throws out man's attempt to charge government officials using archaic practice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/port-augusta-council-charged-with-350-common-law-offences/105876884</link><description>A Port Augusta resident's attempt to charge several government officials and his local council with more than 350 criminal offences using an archaic concept of common law is tossed out by court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cedce768bfdc9cc5e2a3e9c63942deb0</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos wary of Canada ahead of international friendly in Montreal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/international-friendly-socceroos-vs-canada/105878752</link><description>In the build-up to Saturday's match in Montreal, Socceroos coach Tony Popovic feels Canada has given his squad the ultimate compliment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8f0c47995749d6a1c13b42cea53e946</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged with Mark Akers's murder after body found on roadside</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/woman-charged-with-murder-after-body-found-beside-newell-highway/105878820</link><description>Mark Akers was travelling to Melbourne from Brisbane before his body was found on the side of the Newell Highway near Jerilderie in June.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df7e846a4faf7fa7b1a2af7bf2364d2a</guid></item><item><title>State government urged to reject Comiskey Group's Coochin Fields music festival site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/qld-regs-coalition-opposes-coochin-creek-development/105875640</link><description>A coalition of Sunshine Coast community groups is calling on the state government to scrap a major music festival development because of ecological concerns raised by the State Assessment and Referrals Agency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0539c64bdbb5c4af23a9fcf63d332535</guid></item><item><title>Elderly man hit by truck at Canberra tip dies later in hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/canberra-man-killed-by-truck-at-tip-dies-later-in-hospital/105878718</link><description>ACT police say the man was hit by the truck and knocked into the rubbish collection area, suffering fatal injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfe3c4d1dbf5c5d5304e88fc5f3650ba</guid></item><item><title>Sydney University staff outburst at Jewish students</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/sydney-university-staff-outburst-at-jewish-students/105879074</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c440d41d5121b0c5d8e4b066126f87fc</guid></item><item><title>University of Sydney staff member suspended over verbal outburst against Jewish students</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/sydney-uni-staffer-suspended-for-verbal-outburst-jewish-students/105876266</link><description>Video shows the group of Jewish students being verbally abused and intimidated by the University of Sydney female staff member, before she was moved along by security.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b85d33232fb84eed61c49d8bdba0f0b9</guid></item><item><title>Correspondent Matthew Doran at Hostage Square in Tel Aviv</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/correspondent-matthew-doran-at-hostage-square-in/105879334</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e83cef0757bfdd6b6e0f297912844fe</guid></item><item><title>Australians travelling to Europe warned of long delays at airports after new entry rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/border-rules-change-europe-schengen-zone-security/105877556</link><description>Facial scans and fingerprinting will replace passport stamps across 29 countries in the Schengen Zone from October 12.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74bdcf2255b838d3cd2899c4e4240842</guid></item><item><title>Brodie Kostecki sets qualifying record to snare Bathurst 1000 provisional pole</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/bathurst-1000-qualifying-brodie-kostecki-sets-record/105879396</link><description>Brodie Kostecki looks a strong chance to become the third driver to claim three consecutive Bathurst 1000 poles after going fastest in Friday's qualifying session.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7507b3e62b65366d3ca4a6fdabe8fb7</guid></item><item><title>Protecting rock art from wasp nests in Central Australia's Trephina Gorge with chopsticks and brushes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/rock-art-cleaning-at-trephina-gorge/105867252</link><description>Rock art has significant cultural importance to traditional owners, and is a highlight for visitors who make the hike to see it. These Ltyentye Apurte Rangers are working to help keep them protected from wasp nests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e32adeeb4bd3293608b4c2b5f2f9468a</guid></item><item><title>FBI 'seizes and destroys' website linked to hackers threatening to release Qantas customers' data</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/article-qantas-data-breach-website-seizure/105879120</link><description>The seizure comes less than 24 hours before a deadline set by the hackers for around 40 global firms to pay a ransom to prevent the release of sensitive information is due to end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a8c7ec78afba1c7dcd39ff71f28b500</guid></item><item><title>Hoop pine may set record as Australia's tallest rainforest tree</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/hoop-pine-discovery-might-be-tallest-rainforest-tree/105876058</link><description>Researchers mapping millions of trees as part of a climate change study think they have found Australia's tallest rainforest tree.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5b9000e787551f9b2e1e6206dd33c0d</guid></item><item><title>Coalition frontbencher tries to reframe immigration policy debate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/paul-scarr-reframes-immigration-policy-debate/105878470</link><description>Shadow Immigration Minister Paul Scarr has called for a "measured and considered" debate over migration levels after incendiary comments by members of the party's right flank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">009be0aa615f933c89b4f08de8b7d5ef</guid></item><item><title>Japan's ruling coalition splits, throwing Takaichi's PM bid into doubt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/japan-ruling-coalition-komeito-party-splits-sanae-takaichi/105879610</link><description>Japan's Komeito party on Friday said it would quit its coalition with the Liberal Democratic Party (LDP). Its departure could trigger an unwinding of the so-called "Takaichi trade", which had been driven by investor optimism around fiscal stimulus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c099a37d396da198c4abec6237491ab</guid></item><item><title>SA government 'cautiously optimistic' about toxic algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/sa-government-cautiously-optimistic-about-toxic-algal-bloom-/105879314</link><description>SA government officials say there are some positive signs around the toxic algal bloom crisis as it continues to affect the state's metropolitan beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff7f4f2252b7d9c923a41ed25ffcc4d9</guid></item><item><title>Girl's remains identified years after devastating 2011 Japan tsunami and earthquake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/girls-remains-found-years-after-2011-japan-tsunami-earthquake/105879644</link><description>Human remains found in Japan's north-east have been identified as those of a six-year-old girl missing since the massive earthquake and tsunami of 2011.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">052b029d612ed933656d7769990dd38b</guid></item><item><title>Latest finance news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/latest-finance-news/105879480</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83b3f6cc6c027d4ba22acdae17f46292</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan opposition leader María Corina Machado awarded Nobel Peace Prize</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/nobel-peace-prize-awarded-mar%C3%ADa-corina-machado/105879576</link><description>The Venezuelan opposition leader is awarded the prize for "her tireless work promoting democratic rights" in the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e08335f42623c0315e2e8fa011581819</guid></item><item><title>Ceasefire begins but IDF to remain in Gaza Strip until Hamas disarms, Netanyahu says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/ceasefire-in-gaza-starts/105879726</link><description>The Israel Defense Forces announces a ceasefire has begun, but Benjamin Netanyahu says Israeli forces will remain in Gaza to pressure Hamas until it disarms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e522f39f337f20a791e2d552f3cf9189</guid></item><item><title>Japan's decorated trucks facing extinction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/japans-decorate-trucks-facing-extinction/105876222</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">978f4b2e9949dfe33839423942f03ad5</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump didn't receive the Nobel Peace Prize. Experts say he had 'no chance' of winning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/donald-trump-no-chance-at-winning-peace-prize/105878636</link><description>Donald Trump has not been awarded the Nobel Peace Prize, and, despite his persistent claim that he "deserves the prize", experts are not at all surprised he didn't win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31bc4dedbf7891cb8dc5dbbf015e19e1</guid></item><item><title>Western Bulldogs extend Essendon's losing streak with 57 point thrashing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/western-bulldogs-thrash-essendon/105879214</link><description>The Western Bulldogs have kept their faint AFLW finals hopes alive with a commanding 57 point drubbing of Essendon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac92bfe6e1f2c52e8561d9563d00cbb4</guid></item><item><title>Top stories from ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/top-stories-from-abc-news/105879860</link><description>Listen to ABC News interviews and commentary and analysis from radio programs like AM, PM and The World Today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a7ef31125cf99a7e937df8cdafc91fc</guid></item><item><title>International Criminal Court rejects Rodrigo Duterte's bid for release from detention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/icc-rejects-rodrigo-duterte-bid-to-be-released-from-detention/105879846</link><description>Former Philippine President Rodrigo Duterte must remain behind bars while awaiting trial, judges at the ICC have ruled, saying he might use his freedom to interfere with the legal process and suggesting he was a flight risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ec05a77bae27bbba4cacc40494c16dd</guid></item><item><title>Melania Trump has 'open' line of communication with Vladimir Putin on Ukrainian children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/melania-trump-has-open-line-with-putin-on-ukranian-children/105880086</link><description>The US first lady tells reporters at the White House that eight children have been reunited with their families in the last 24 hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5180e9c2497ade32c5102ddf6efd2d88</guid></item><item><title>Liberals find brief lull in internal hostilities for a passable week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/coalition-andrew-hastie-tony-pasin-anika-wells-chris-bowen/105858494</link><description>If there was some internal call within the Liberals to show some discipline after the last few weeks, it worked at a basic level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98db697ba6641fa4f18bac1f61add805</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump threatens 'massive' tariffs on China after Beijing restricts rare earths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/trump-new-china-massive-tariffs-threat/105880136</link><description>The US President takes to Truth Social to say he sees "no reason" to meet Xi Jinping after Beijing's "hostile" move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c593e331aa58e6e28231bfbe40174ca6</guid></item><item><title>framesTOP</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/framestop/105856882</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30de636d30e4bd6976e66450dc9d08c4</guid></item><item><title>frame bombing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/frame-bombing/105871194</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c74d0a26af894303b7eaf512d9898fb2</guid></item><item><title>Satellite vision over Tel el-Hawa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/map/105858584</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b772a7e28ddf1babadab1a7ccf4bde8</guid></item><item><title>nour_frame</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/nour-frame/105872850</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">882a1e5360860b5f20be3161e2b2ad2f</guid></item><item><title>Life was never easy for Nour in Gaza.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/frame1/105856134</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1447cd93a949aa66d70ab2c331b2de3c</guid></item><item><title>frame3</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/frame3/105856202</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85f025edbada8b4a2f732cd355a81719</guid></item><item><title>return_home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/return-home/105873088</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8f9e15c347686ca87601f59314c724c</guid></item><item><title>Memories from the rubble</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/verify-tracking-the-destruction-of-a-neighbourhood-in-gaza/105814932</link><description>When 25-year-old Nour imagines herself back home in Gaza City, she remembers the things that made her smile. Now that's all gone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef31548e58d9f19f9724991b39be12c6</guid></item><item><title>Older borrowers taking out later-in-life loans risk post-retirement mortgage pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/housing-prices-older-borrowers-risk-mortgage-debt-in-retirement/105867244</link><description>Property analysts, brokers and banks report more borrowers are taking on big housing debts in their late 40s and 50s and, potentially, a retirement still saddled with mortgage repayments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cea624f58afd0c1f6bdfb886c7aaa758</guid></item><item><title>Japan's decorated trucks face 'extinction' but fans and truckies are trying to bring them back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/japan-culture-of-dekotora-decorated-trucks-under-threat/105862672</link><description>The dekotora, large decorated trucks covered in colour and bright lights, were once a common sight across Japan. Now they are fighting for survival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eb195808234a2a8b67b318263d22ece</guid></item><item><title>Las Vegas licence hearing turns nightmare for boss of Australian pokies giant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/las-vegas-licence-withdrawn-australian-pokies-boss/105878214</link><description>Regulators in the world's most influential gaming jurisdiction have dismissed a licence bid by the boss of Australia's Ainsworth Game Technology, branding him "arrogant", "misleading" and lacking in "emotional intelligence".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c92d4ad80838c1474d9c5146b5c7914</guid></item><item><title>Queensland plan to extend life of coal-fired power stations sends 'mixed messages'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/queensland-coal-fired-power-stations-energy-plan/105879574</link><description>Communities across Queensland have welcomed plans to keep coal and gas burning across the state, though some warn a lack of future planning could undermine short-term benefits.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa49ed8303cabfa57e2ba899e8da02ed</guid></item></channel></rss>