<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 18:04:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Letter sent to Lakemba Mosque threatening violence on Australia Day investigated by police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/nsw-australia-day-mosque-threat-police-investigation/106260802</link><description>The note, seen by the ABC, incited violence against several groups, including Middle Eastern communities, Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islanders and a number of political figures from Labor, the Greens and "socialists" were also singled out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40a93d7c9c85c5131545560539c3e2e1</guid></item><item><title>US officials tout 'New Gaza' plans filled with shiny luxury skyscrapers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/us-touts-new-gaza-filled-with-luxury-real-estate/106261524</link><description>US officials have presented their vision for a "New Gaza" that would turn the shattered Palestinian territory into a glitzy resort of skyscrapers by the sea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">332468f105e8f38eeb197372324b59be</guid></item><item><title>Track temperatures as heatwave sweeps across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/temperatures-heatwave-tracker-australia-day/106261904</link><description>Use our tracker to keep an eye on temperatures as a heatwave moves across much of the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e57e1f2214ee021677fa9f1ede08fbdd</guid></item><item><title>Who is the Neo-Nazi who was booed at Hobart's March for Australia rally?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/who-is-neo-nazi-nsn-member-at-hobart-march-for-australia/106243774</link><description>With the organisers of March for Australia rallies saying they "are in no way concerned by the presence" of members of the National Socialist Network, the ABC can confirm a Tasmanian man whose words were too extreme for many in the Hobart crowd is believed to be a leader within the state's Neo-Nazi movement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dd9e1cf44e49a7d888aa48587dc3692</guid></item><item><title>Labor identity Tim Picton remembered at Perth Stadium memorial service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/tim-picton-memorial-service/106255116</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is among political figures and business leaders who travel across the country to pay their respects to Mr Picton.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5d7055f3334cbd3e08a1546f091c39f</guid></item><item><title>Federal Court finds extended Victoria Police stop-and-search declaration was unlawful and invalid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/federal-court-police-designated-area-designation-unlawful/106262240</link><description>The Federal Court has found a Victoria Police move to give officers greater powers in Melbourne's CBD for six months was invalid and unlawful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff906739ce6790b737ba6a47ae4879b9</guid></item><item><title>What is a landslide, how do they happen and where are they most common?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/how-landslides-happen-and-where-they-are-most-common/106261240</link><description>Two people have died after a landslide hit their home in New Zealand and authorities are searching for several others feared dead in another slip nearby. Here's how landslides occur, the warning signs and where they are most common.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">851733bbedf99ceab4b1c59174b2194c</guid></item><item><title>How to attract native wildlife and birds to your garden</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/how-to-attract-native-wildlife-and-birds-to-your-garden/106042150</link><description>There are simple things we can all do to encourage more native wildlife to our gardens, backyards, balconies and shared spaces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a86ce4b9695adc5a6d1286749a33f7cf</guid></item><item><title>Video of bull shark washed up on Brisbane River bank sparks debate over AI technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/qld-bull-shark-brisbane-river-ai-speculation/106261868</link><description>A video posted to social media of a bull shark washed up in the Brisbane River went viral and prompted speculation that it was AI-generated, but experts say it appears to be legitimate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79cee32b8f5ede448241764cbe5b102e</guid></item><item><title>Former Broome pub manager jailed for six years over rape of staff member</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/broome-pub-manager-stewart-burchell-sentenced/106037710</link><description>Stewart Patrick Burchell is jailed for six years, found guilty by jury trial of raping a staff member and indecently assaulting several others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfd31eca85588a6872ef20bdd2788feb</guid></item><item><title>Bail accommodation facility for women opens in Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/bail-accommodation-facility-for-women-opens-in-alice-springs/106257182</link><description>There are hopes the Salvation Army-run facility will keep women safe and help them reintegrate into the community while easing pressure on the prison system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9c1101d12ec87a4bb68bf62658eebdb</guid></item><item><title>Lake Cargelligo residents in shock after three people shot dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/lake-cargelligo-urged-indoors-a-neighbours-recall-gunshots/106260708</link><description>Residents of a remote NSW town of just 1,500 residents have expressed shock at a deadly shooting spree where three people were shot dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d8d66d4d35e438eccff0c1e13a7f7fa</guid></item><item><title>UK government says new passport rules designed with national security in mind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/uk-government-says-new-passport-rules-improve-national-security/106263628</link><description>The requirement for dual British citizens to have a valid UK passport while entering the country would help prevent the arrival of people who present a threat, Australia's British High Commission says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43f832a9617243fb7df73acd79487d61</guid></item><item><title>Friday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/friday-finance-with-david-chau-230126/106263986</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34ec08ab02b049799d6e47323e23bab7</guid></item><item><title>Fatigue a concern as massive fires continue to burn across southern WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/wa-bushfire-update-wandering-boddington/106263020</link><description>DFES says there have been no confirmed property losses as the battle to contain fires near Boddington and Wandering continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65513a7670758f54ef3746e5ebf3161a</guid></item><item><title>Yulia Putintseva taunts Zeynep Sönmez's Australian Open supporters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/australian-open-yulia-putintseva-zeynep-sonmez-crowd/106263414</link><description>Kazakhstan's Yulia Putintseva happily plays the role of villain following her three-set win over Zeynep Sönmez at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97bc78ebf825d2b6a958edc49355cb10</guid></item><item><title>Japanese PM Sanae Takaichi dissolves parliament after only three months in office, setting up snap election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/japan-prime-minister-dissolves-parliament-after-3-months-office/106263926</link><description>Japan's prime minister, Sanae Takaichi, has dissolved the lower house of parliament, paving the way for a snap election on February 8.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7af2f321d4a3c3f3d0dfbbc805f880f</guid></item><item><title>To Lam wins second term to rule Vietnam through 2030</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/vietnam-to-lam-reelected-second-term-rule-2030/106263924</link><description>Vietnam's leader To Lam has been re-appointed as head of the ruling Communist Party for the next five years, and pledges to turbocharge growth in the export-reliant nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9955cc5f187fbcce22b63cc8db6f3dcd</guid></item><item><title>Lawyers call for Australian investigation into Israeli President Isaac Herzog amid genocide allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/calls-to-probe-israeli-president-isaac-herzog-australia-visit/106263374</link><description>The Australian Centre for International Justice has formally requested a police investigation into Israel's president for alleged incitement to genocide. He is expected to visit to Australia next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79c6b12747235201bc8fcc9a866d9ce4</guid></item><item><title>West Coast Eagles player Tyler Brockman charged with assault after Geraldton fracas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/afl-tyler-brockman-charged-over-geraldton-fight/106264146</link><description>West Coast Eagles player Tyler Brockman is charged with causing grievous bodily harm following an incident in Geraldton in late December.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ec2577e804e9db4e400b95d5de33a53</guid></item><item><title>Drowning most likely cause of death of Canadian backpacker Piper James on K'gari, coroner says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/canadian-teen-piper-james-likely-died-from-drowning-on-kgari/106256020</link><description>A preliminary report from the Coroners Court of Queensland finds that while Piper James was bitten by dingoes before she died on K'gari, drowning is the most likely cause of death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12168408beb719f457f5902194785958</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith delivers again as Sixers down Hurricanes to cruise into BBL decider</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/steve-smith-fires-sydney-sixers-into-bbl-final/106264300</link><description>Steve Smith top scores for the fifth time in as many innings as the Sixers down the Hurricanes to book a place in Sunday's BBL decider in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e348c53fcfa7f88f916aeae4be93ff8</guid></item><item><title>UK PM Keir Starmer demands Donald Trump apologise for 'appalling' claim NATO troops swerved front line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/european-veterans-outraged-over-trump-nato-troops-comments/106264332</link><description>Donald Trump criticised NATO during a Fox News interview on Thursday, saying the US had "never needed" the alliance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38f721a042e64bd07408956226a8a2b0</guid></item><item><title>Ukrainian, Russian and US officials meet for first trilateral talks to end war in Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/ukraine-russia-us-meeting-in-abu-dhabi-peace-deal/106264648</link><description>The Abu Dhabi talks mark the first known trilateral meeting between the countries since Moscow launched its invasion of Ukraine more than four years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58eba80797f636c2f7db6241a46e665a</guid></item><item><title>Hottest 100 quiz: How well do you remember past countdowns?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/hottest-100-history-quiz-triple-j/106237066</link><description>While you wait to hear who is number one this year, test your memory of past Hottest 100 countdowns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">355a47b8d47ae7693d3035362c3c91a4</guid></item><item><title>As Russia's war intensifies Europe is exploring military and economic independence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/davos-donald-trump-zelenskyy-russia-war-technology/106252046</link><description>As the world's elite gathered in Davos, European leaders confronted a reality in which they might need to defend themselves, and potentially against, the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">777407f3d912131f903aabe2a0e5650c</guid></item><item><title>From ultimatum to implosion: How the Coalition went its separate ways</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/how-the-coalition-split-played-out/106263654</link><description>Dissecting the implosion of the Coalition and figuring out what comes next has become a full-time vocation for the newly emancipated Liberals and Nationals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f29b55a2c0c1f764650c346e4ccff7cd</guid></item><item><title>US copied Iran's Shahed drones — now they are deployed in the Middle East</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/us-copy-replica-iran-shahed-kamikaze-attack-drone-strikes-trump/106232818</link><description>The US copied Iran's Shahed 136 drone. Now, as Donald Trump threatens military action against the regime, analysts say the US could soon use Iran's weapons technology against it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea93691d3fd263480d17ca56f198efa1</guid></item><item><title>Prince Harry takes on the Daily Mail in High Court privacy showdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/prince-harry-duke-sussex-daily-mail-court-case-principle-anger/106261250</link><description>The Duke of Sussex takes on the publisher he believes poisoned his childhood, his marriage, and his peace of mind in a legal battle driven by anger as well as principle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0734b45ec2433eaff1d6c9115bfcbc11</guid></item><item><title>Search for Julian Ingram enters third day following Lake Cargelligo shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/lake-cargelligo-search-resumes-for-gunman-julian-ingram/106262074</link><description>A gunman accused of killing three people and seriously injuring another in New South Wales' Central West may be receiving help to evade authorities, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be92b25778e6ce54592c9759ee196224</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Luana forms into category one system off Kimberley coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/tropical-cyclone-luana-forms-off-kimberley-coast/106257746</link><description>Residents in WA's West Kimberley are being warned to prepare for days of wild weather, with a tropical cyclone forming up off the region's coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25fb2f9c9cb6af9ec15007da7b412fc9</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur driven to prove doubters wrong as Australian Open campaign continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/australian-open-tennis-alex-de-minaur-frances-tiafoe/106264260</link><description>Alex de Minaur is back in familiar territory, on the cusp of the Australian Open quarterfinals, but he is adamant he can make a deeper run at Melbourne Park than his previous appearances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f65a72004cb1c174e578be2ecb878b9b</guid></item><item><title>Australia smash Sri Lanka by nine wickets to stay unbeaten at Under-19s Cricket World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/australia-u19s-result-will-byron-sri-lanka/106264830</link><description>Australia have continued their dominant run through the Under-19s Cricket World Cup with Will Byrom's 5-14 leading the way in a nine-wicket win over Sri Lanka in their final group match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d9de7093079101b37bad476ef784e63</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur's wedding confession and Yulia Putintseva plays the villain — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/australian-open-2026-day-six-quick-hits-putintseva/106261160</link><description>Alex de Minaur has some thoughts on his upcoming wedding with Katie Boulter, while Yulia Putintseva plays the villain on day six. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89847952f8857b2a9bac637c4dd83daa</guid></item><item><title>Crews prepare iconic landmarks in Wonnangatta Valley ahead of total fire ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/wonnangatta-dargo-fire-high-country-landmarks-protection/105802954</link><description>A number of historic landmarks across Victoria's east have been given protective cover in case a nearby bushfire breaks containment lines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa61137659ad34170b48a7d0be70bdb7</guid></item><item><title>Australian Neo-Nazis use symbols that may evade hate speech laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/verify-neo-nazi-symbols-explainer/106258068</link><description>Viking symbols and a Norwegian jacket have now become synonymous with Australia's Neo-Nazi groups, but what do they mean?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f2701670a0fb89f719abd3c6cfdc0f4</guid></item><item><title>Track temperatures as heatwave sweeps across continent over Australia Day weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/temperatures-heatwave-tracker-australia-day/106263796</link><description>Use our tracker to keep an eye on temperatures as a heatwave moves across much of the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d78fc3dc49dc4e45663bc0aa841072a</guid></item><item><title>Inside Minnesota, Reverend Ashley Horan is helping people steer clear of ICE agents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/leading-the-fight-against-ice-in-minnesota/106248564</link><description>Reverend Ashley Horan lives one block from where Renee Good was shot and killed and by ICE agents. She and her neighbours have been tracking ICE's movements around Minneapolis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e946a892ab913ccf34bcadc83d433d0f</guid></item><item><title>Worst crown-of-thorns starfish outbreak in decades emerging on Great Barrier Reef</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/crown-of-thorns-starfish-outbreak-great-barrier-reef/106252468</link><description>Scientists are rushing to contain an emerging outbreak of coral-eating crown-of-thorns starfish on the Great Barrier Reef, warning it could be one of the worst in 60 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd5b86f1137da7bacc6ec43d7b35523a</guid></item><item><title>SA heatwave leads to total fire bans, catastrophic conditions and Tour Down Under changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/sa-heatwave-saturday-total-fire-bans-catastrophic-conditions/106262450</link><description>South Australia's hottest weather in six years creates dangerous bushfire conditions, which the head of the Country Fire Service says are "as serious as it gets".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3c13d73d888acbf298fb2981f3b0728</guid></item><item><title>Triggering a heatwave takes more than just temperature — as Australia braces for another</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/what-makes-heatwave-in-australia-explained/105893650</link><description>Yet another major heatwave is sweeping across south-eastern Australia. But what actually triggers the warning? Spoiler alert: hitting 40C is not enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30b4e1477044b893bcbb4f31df0a73b8</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave and fire warnings across south-east Australia as tropical cyclone hits WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/heatwave-south-east-australia-tropical-cyclone-wa/106261940</link><description>Parts of south-east Australia are enduring severe heatwaves with fire warnings in place over the long weekend, as the Bureau of Meteorology issues a tropical cyclone warning for Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29b281821a69a1c26a74706b3f280a03</guid></item><item><title>Ross River Virus cases quadruple in South Australia in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/ross-river-virus-cases-quadruple-in-south-australia-in-2025/106206394</link><description>There were more than four times the number of Ross River Virus cases in South Australia in 2025 compared to 2024, prompting a new public health awareness campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">700c70d9ba7d34701e727a4888e57afe</guid></item><item><title>How a tank of zebrafish helped two children born with a rare genetic variant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/zebrafish-research-helps-children-with-rare-genetic-variants/106243868</link><description>With a tank of zebrafish, Queensland researcher Jean Giacomotto was able to test a never-before seen genetic variant affecting two babies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4739baaea5242ec7f686f3813e4bb7e1</guid></item><item><title>Police search for woman after man stabbed at North Wonthaggi, south-east of Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/vic-police-search-for-woman-who-stabbed-a-man-at-north-wonthaggi/106264870</link><description>Police are searching for a woman after a man suffered serious injuries in a stabbing at North Wonthaggi in the early hours of Saturday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0d9ca5567c1a5f377db00d6721ea245</guid></item><item><title>Future of Canberra's Black Mountain Tower in limbo as Ngunnawal cultural site plans stall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/black-mountain-tower-indigenous-cultural-site-stalled/106263224</link><description>Custodians say they have been excluded from talks between Telstra and the ACT government about plans to develop the iconic tower into a Ngunnawal cultural site.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0308dda5f51e68e7f5117a2dda31603a</guid></item><item><title>Gen Z led the revolution in Bangladesh — can they win the election?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/bangladesh-election-gen-z-revolution-will-they-win/106204040</link><description>After toppling Sheikh Hasina, Bangladesh's newest political party faces its first election next month, testing a newly formed alliance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69dbde527d8d7c5e03110e8208a21381</guid></item><item><title>Calls to make financial literacy mandatory in schools amid concerns young people don't have basic financial knowledge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/calls-to-make-financial-literacy-mandatory-in-schools/106257050</link><description>In an increasingly complex financial world of buy-now-pay-later schemes, scams, and social media marketing, there are renewed calls for financial literacy to become a mandatory part of the school curriculum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb69d2654022ceb896b6dcfc6823c932</guid></item><item><title>Quick and easy pasta with a zesty, no-cook salsa sauce - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/summer-pasta-with-no-cook-salsa-sauce/106254654</link><description>Salsa is not just for tacos. It's the perfect summer pasta sauce and makes the most of juicy summer tomatoes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1362255da12c15379673ce7cc421c41</guid></item><item><title>Chalamet getting fresh for an Oscar, or is his campaign a bit (ping) pongy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/marty-supreme-review-timothee-chalamet/106254190</link><description>Director Josh Safdie's debut solo film has been garnering accolades left and right, but it isn't quite lead actor Timothée Chalamet's finest work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d8ce71feb87facc97229d5e74b415d7</guid></item><item><title>Play to start earlier at Australian Open as Melbourne braces for a heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/heatwave-australian-open-explainer/106261014</link><description>Play will start earlier on Saturday, with temperatures in Melbourne set to reach 40 degrees Celsius.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fffa174362da9d8d3d2f45a84643da37</guid></item><item><title>Authorities confirm body of French diver missing in Antarctica has been found</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/body-of-missing-french-diver-found-antarctica/106264908</link><description>The body of a French diver who went missing in Antarctica earlier this month has been found after an extensive multinational search, the French Polar Institute says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f03398e847d740cb2226b003776f0d9</guid></item><item><title>Aussie Inglis progresses as Osaka announces shock late withdrawal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/australian-open-2026-live-sinner-djokovic-osaka-inglis/106264358</link><description>Naomi Osaka withdraws from her match against Maddison Inglis shortly before it was due to be played, putting the Australian into the fourth round.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b366d250003b9ec32168a906e200075</guid></item><item><title>FBI releases video of former Olympic snowboarder Ryan Wedding's arrest.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/former-canadian-olympic-snowboarder-ryan-wedding-arrested-by-fbi/106265004</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">437ad517148a36324b6a0188aad66c32</guid></item><item><title>David Connolly's appointment as NT administrator sees a cultural rift widen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/david-connolly-nt-administrator-appointment-cultural-rift-widens/106263574</link><description>The man picked for one of the Northern Territory's most lucrative jobs — which comes with a manor overlooking Darwin Harbour — has drawn controversy before even walking through the gates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a09173cee118657952ceab3bb7d5423</guid></item><item><title>WA government hopes new Perth Film Studios can become epicentre of Australia's screen industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/perth-film-studios-government-and-industry-hopes-for-success/106259442</link><description>Perth's new film studio is almost ready to receive its first production. There’s just one problem – no one has signed up yet. Is that a sign of things to come from a facility the government has sunk millions into?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39e220c614ab3816b31923e158ff07f5</guid></item><item><title>Olivia Dean takes out the #1 spot on the triple j Hottest 100 of 2025 — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/triple-j-hottest-100-2025-live-updates/106256428</link><description>After millions of votes from Australia and around the world, British artist Olivia Dean has topped the triple j Hottest 100 of 2025 with her song, Man I Need.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b1235c93fa1b3b0beabeb92cc471b08</guid></item><item><title>John Williamson takes his final bow at the Tamworth Country Music Festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/john-williamson-last-tamworth-country-music-festival-performance/106260430</link><description>Aussie music legend John Williamson will take the Tamworth Country Music Festival stage for the last time as he steps into retirement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76021075858529b46df379e68b918807</guid></item><item><title>Plume of smoke rises after house fire in Portsea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/plume-of-smoke-rises-after-house-fire-in-portsea/106265082</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">986a243dc4e8c093491f74249d552489</guid></item><item><title>Scientists fear 30pc of critically endangered western ground parrot's habitat lost in bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/endangered-parrot-habitat-destroyed-by-fire/106253522</link><description>Experts estimate 11,000 hectares of core habitat for the critically endangered parrot has been lost to a recent fire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f62310fe6ae66e2033707fb8f3cb0a3f</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos receive major boost as Jackson Irvine returns from injury for St Pauli</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/jackson-irvine-returns-for-st-pauli/106265074</link><description>In welcome news for Socceroos boss Tony Popovic, key Australian midfielder Jackson Irvine has made an early return from injury for St Pauli in the Bundesliga.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">853c1fc9f4dd19feb631e0ba0d3226d2</guid></item><item><title>Inside the program getting more First Nations people into fire and rescue squads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/getting-more-first-nations-people-into-fire-and-rescue/106174194</link><description>For First Nations recruits the path to firefighting is demanding, competitive and often deeply personal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f19bb0c87e87116c9a2998740d63e11c</guid></item><item><title>Fortescue breaks ground on Pilbara's first wind farm in move to decarbonise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/fortescue-begins-construction-on-pilbaras-first-wind-farm/106245178</link><description>A mining company in Western Australia's Pilbara region is one step closer to decarbonising its iron ore production after starting construction on the region's first wind farm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5760d1f6700c62fb3199b3a3d87dbc2f</guid></item><item><title>The Limestone Coast's Little Blue Lake drawing visitors over summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/visitors-flock-to-little-blue-lake-mount-gambier/106206022</link><description>While its younger brother gets much of the shine, the Little Blue Lake is a unique and ancient spectacle in SA's south east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">913f2c4f8d1e642033ae9741fed05184</guid></item><item><title>A generation of activists like Grace Oo are taking up arms against Myanmar's military</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/taking-up-arms-against-myanmar-military/106252216</link><description>As Myanmar's military junta seeks international legitimacy through elections, its brutal repression of the pro-democracy movement is radicalising a new generation of activists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72a427ab5a1dcc938b3234c3d5fc1407</guid></item><item><title>How much power does China really have in the Arctic amid Trump's Greenland claims?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/how-much-power-does-china-really-have-in-the-arctic/106257590</link><description>Donald Trump says the US needs to control Greenland to fight a security threat from China. But does Beijing really have that much power in the region?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97be12ab6ffe8414d1b3bae90eae88d9</guid></item><item><title>US looks to South Korea to take 'primary responsibility' in monitoring Kim Jong Un and North Korea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/pentagon-north-korea-kim-jong-un-threat-usa-looks-to-south-korea/106265180</link><description>The United States says it intends to play a "more limited" role in deterring nuclear-powered North Korea, shifting the burden of responsibility onto South Korea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d75a773c638178ae047d145130dba1fa</guid></item><item><title>Nico Antic, 12yo boy attacked by shark at Sydney beach, dies in hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/sydney-12yo-shark-attack-victim-nico-antic-dies-in-hospital/106249554</link><description>Nico Antic, the 12-year-old boy who suffered serious leg injuries after being bitten by a shark in Sydney's east has died in hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">474853b08513b0a0e52bb924383d3a16</guid></item><item><title>Piper James 'felt so free' on K'gari beach where her body was found</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/piper-james-family-plan-to-return-her-home-to-canada/106265238</link><description>Piper James loved to start her days on K'gari by swimming alone at sunrise. Now her family is planning her final journey home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af4e580ae0cd3a17f831c15dc351d070</guid></item><item><title>Seven dead, 82 missing in Indonesia landslide, agency says, with search and rescue efforts ramped up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/indonesia-landslide-west-bandung-west-java-province/106265558</link><description>The landslide was reported in the West Bandung region of Indonesia's West Java province, according to the nation's agency spokesperson Abdul Muhari.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83eec2673f3c329c50e7714442880bbe</guid></item><item><title>Corpse flower Smellanie at Adelaide Botanic Garden is blooming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/adelaide-botanic-garden-corpse-flower-is-blooming/106265134</link><description>Cheese, fermented cabbage, roadkill – these are how some people have described the smell emitting from a corpse flower that has finally bloomed at the Adelaide Botanic Garden.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63d8e365c23135287ab9f84703b095af</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open matches suspended due to extreme heat at Melbourne Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/australian-open-tennis-extreme-heat-play-suspended-melbourne/106265530</link><description>Extreme heat protocols kick into gear at Melbourne Park, as the stifling weather conditions wreak havoc with the Australian Open tournament's schedule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e3c348c3155bcfa535fe5ebb441d66a</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire threatens communities in Victoria's south-west as temperatures soar across the state</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/victoria-heat-bushfire-total-fire-ban-otways-warnings/106263672</link><description>A bushfire threatens communities in south-western Victoria after it escapes control lines on Saturday afternoon, as a heatwave continues to scorch the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">228dbf6d94ac42e98a4ce61cf87a25a5</guid></item><item><title>Reports of power outage in parts of Derby as Tropical Cyclone Luana continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/tropical-cyclone-luana-landfall-kimberley/106265140</link><description>Tropical Cyclone Luana edges closer to the Kimberley town of Derby as a category one system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15e65308b1282b1903c0a762c6831687</guid></item><item><title>Jannik Sinner admits he got lucky after surviving Australian Open scare against Eliot Spizzirri</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/australian-open-jannik-sinner-eliot-spizzirri-extreme-heat-rules/106265666</link><description>Had the Australian Open's extreme heat protocols not taken effect, Janik Sinner wonders if he would still be in the tournament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c7186386f575c662a856857fb38637a</guid></item><item><title>Hottest 100 of 2025 - featuring Playlunch, Olivia Dean, Tame Impala and RAYE</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/triple-j-hottest-100-top-ten/106265932</link><description>It's that time again, triple j has counted down the year's Hottest 100 songs as voted by the public, celebrating all the incredible music that soundtracked our lives in 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdc1d7983a23a4037df77daa00502580</guid></item><item><title>Travel-weary Sydney Sixers aim to turn tables on Perth Scorchers in BBL decider</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/sport-bbl-final-preview/106265930</link><description>After a taxing, cross-continental travel journey to Sunday's BBL decider, the Sydney Sixers are set for one final push against the all-conquering Scorchers at Perth Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54b24a18247b60ff4917de5291fb9523</guid></item><item><title>Naomi Osaka withdraws from Australian Open as Maddison Inglis reaches fourth round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/australian-open-naomi-osaka-pulls-out-maddison-inglis/106265922</link><description>Naomi Osaka pulls the pin on her Australian Open campaign, handing Maddison Inglis her first appearance in the fourth round at a major.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fb7807b2427603f13b3317ad60da70f</guid></item><item><title>US-brokered peace talks end without deal as Russia continues Ukraine attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/russia-attacks-ukraine-amid-peace-talks-with-united-states/106266046</link><description>Russian attacks on Ukraine have killed at least one person and wounded 31, as negotiators from both countries and the US met for a second day of peace talks. The meetings ended without a deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aaa528e12dd3aacdb1cad8a2cc6919ce</guid></item><item><title>Golden Guitar success for Kasey Chambers and Shane Nicholson with The Divorce Song</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/golden-guitar-award-winners-2026-tamworth-country-music-festival/106265498</link><description>Kasey Chambers wins three Golden Guitars in Tamworth, including Single and Song of the Year for a track she penned with ex-husband Shane Nicholson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38596e03b2ac284a1d0fbebfa8f9c827</guid></item><item><title>After a horror week of shark attacks, how do we sift facts from fear?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/horror-week-shark-bites-attack-nsw-facts-fears-risk/106260980</link><description>As a devoted ocean swimmer, I've learned to accept the risk of exploring an ocean that is not my natural habitat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">375df3f5296337c1503d72c1ff87ef64</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, January 25: How Nirvana saved the first Big Day Out in 1992</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/first-big-out-sydney-nirvana-violent-femmes-ken-west-podcast/106250404</link><description>How the first Big Day Out in 1992 turned a risky idea into a landmark moment in Australian music history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7592856fccfe81735e675eb6afd24a6c</guid></item><item><title>Great Aussie home ownership dream aging as banks see more first-time buyers above 40</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/great-australian-dream-aging-as-more-first-home-buyers-over-40/106206552</link><description>The average age of purchasing your first home is increasing as economists say politicians continue to favour the current home owner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad7adf47ca28bc202aad76dbf5c08aa5</guid></item><item><title>Nine self-harm hospitalisations in 12 months after new NT youth justice centre opened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/nt-youth-detention-foi-self-harm-sexual-assault-vandalism/106180656</link><description>Nine youths ended up in hospital after self-harming at Darwin's new $130 million detention centre in the 12 months after it opened, documents released to the ABC under Freedom of Information laws have revealed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1507602bcbebeefc7c1248b80539fa27</guid></item><item><title>From truth-telling to closing the gap, First Nations leaders outline their priorities in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/truth-telling-closing-the-gap-indigenous-affairs-agenda-2026/106260862</link><description>Ahead of the national debate around Indigenous rights and recognition this January 26, the ABC has spoken to First Nations leaders about what they think are the top priorities for Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c23e331bbf8ea07539a3839ef19cbf4</guid></item><item><title>Liberals wait on Hastie-Taylor decision before challenging Sussan Ley's leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/liberals-hastie-taylor-likely-challengers-sussan-ley-leadership/106265762</link><description>Liberal leadership aspirants Andrew Hastie and Angus Taylor are being urged to "sort out" which of them will challenge Sussan Ley for the party's top job before a spill is called.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38227caeb5c6b1e6f7f67ca03bde848a</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic shows his love-hate relationship with Australian tennis fans is like no other</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/novak-djokovic-relationship-aus-open-fans-analysis/106266018</link><description>Novak Djokovic shows once again that his relationship with Australian tennis fans is as complicated as it gets, turning a routine win into a full-blown drama.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0eb61ac860fa8a8e4d8546a429594486</guid></item><item><title>Stan Wawrinka says goodbye with a beer as Jannik Sinner is saved by the sun — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/australian-open-day-seven-quick-hits/106264454</link><description>Stan Wawrinka bowed out from the Australian Open with a tear in his eye and a beer in his hand, while a grumpy Novak Djokovic set an incredible new benchmark. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29c23ec47dd1cef86a3e862e9a472167</guid></item><item><title>Former state care kid calls for fundamental change to fix 'broken' residential care system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/state-care-children-say-system-is-broken-south-australia/106090498</link><description>Residential care is often a last resort for society's most vulnerable children, but being raised by a "system" can leave both physical and emotional scars. It's why those who have gone through it are asking for their voices to be included to reform it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f11503bf6b8a54ccd1a7e5d6836ec3d2</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Will this be the week you nail it? Nah, probably not</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/105682622</link><description>I applaud your repeated attempts to do well at this quiz. Will your desperation pay off?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89fec54edfa9225fdb7d508e1fcc26f6</guid></item><item><title>Australia warned recovering Chinese tourism market may cool in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/tourism-chinese-travel-to-australia-may-cool-in-2026/106253542</link><description>Chinese visitor numbers have increased but are still below pre-pandemic levels, with economists warning ongoing economic uncertainty in China could dampen long-haul travel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ec5f9e3768658cee9097b8de01f520b</guid></item><item><title>Australia Day event Aus Lights on the River cancelled in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/adelaide-australia-day-community-event-cancelled/106265304</link><description>An annual Australia Day event in the Adelaide CBD has been cancelled ahead of potentially the hottest day in six years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeb35a757efe5d8eba2b29ea078269e0</guid></item><item><title>Sydney volunteers break barriers to music, sports events for disability community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/people-with-disability-find-connection-at-gig-buddies-sydney/106237060</link><description>For some, going to a music gig or sporting event alone can be daunting, but a Sydney volunteer program is empowering people with a disability to get out of their comfort zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39bdd1743bb1b0f4d8ecef293ff9d7de</guid></item><item><title>Out-of-control bushfire in Victoria's Otways grows as state faces record temperatures on Tuesday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/victorian-otways-fire-threatens-communities-heatwave/106265690</link><description>An out-of-control bushfire has threatened communities in Victoria's Otways, as heatwave conditions continue in some parts of the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29cf4c2db076445131cac9cd5f11c931</guid></item><item><title>New residents purchase real estate in Barcaldine, attracted by affordable prices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/buying-real-estate-barcaldine-western-queensland/106258330</link><description>From retirees to first home buyers, people are making the most of affordable housing in this outback town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4c2b2111eba794338928c407d7f3966</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Tropical Cyclone Luana downgraded to tropical low after impacting Dampier Peninsula</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/tropical-cyclone-luana-brings-destructive-winds/106265736</link><description>Ex-Tropical Cyclone Luana is downgraded to a tropical low as it continues inland after crossing the northern WA coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cc55225bb75a2d4f30a63e20c1c02af</guid></item><item><title>Mother shares tribute to 15-year-old Max trapped under Mount Maunganui landslide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/nz-landslide-victims-unlikely-to-survive-police-say/106265934</link><description>After two days of holding out hope despite all the odds, the local police superintendent had the heart-wrenching job of announcing that no-one trapped by the landslide at Mount Maunganui could have survived.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16cc801b4de5cb7aa92580629fad34c1</guid></item><item><title>Former Japanese PM Shinzo Abe's killer motivated by 'disgust' at links to Unification Church</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/shinzo-abe-killer-tetsuya-yamagami/106254108</link><description>The man who killed former Japanese prime minister Shinzo Abe thought it was his life's mission to destroy a controversial church.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9f13f005150aef71c839b8510ff63fd</guid></item><item><title>Rod Laver’s father built him a backyard tennis court 80 years ago. Now locals are battling to save it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/rod-laver-arena-rockhampton-tennis-courts/106261184</link><description>Like Donald Bradman’s tank stand, the backyard tennis court of Rod Laver’s youth has survived against the odds, but it is yet to be heritage listed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">425a1b86dfad8a1d856e4d776e79ef2e</guid></item><item><title>Searching for Celine: How YouTube filmmaker Rob Parsons helped the search for missing tourist Celine Cremer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/filmmaker-rob-parsons-celine-cremer-search/106242088</link><description>Rob Parsons amassed a following on YouTube for his videos of remote gold panning and mineral fossicking. Now, his attention is on the search for missing Belgian tourist Celine Cremer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">521a8c9e5bde3fa9d8b039d08914de68</guid></item><item><title>Kondoli Dreaming brings Ramindjeri and Ngarrindjeri knowledge to firefighting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/kondoli-dreaming-ramindjeri-ngarrindjeri-firefighting/106219126</link><description>A new fire response vehicle in South Australia's Fleurieu Peninsula has been named after a Dreaming story about a powerful whale man that explores the creation of fire, paying homage to tens of thousands of years of local fire management knowledge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1656ac7a8e7fb47c7bac7e67f6c125a0</guid></item><item><title>Iranian protesters chant for a 'revolution' after years of economic chaos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/iranians-chant-for-a-revolution-amid-economic-chaos-corruption/106262220</link><description>Decades of economic mismanagement and government corruption have widened wealth gaps in Iran, leaving ordinary Iranians calling for a revolution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44fd911d05e4d5c5c0c324b5c4c5510c</guid></item><item><title>How moving overseas changed my shopping habits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/shopping-habits-fashion-moving-overseas/105996352</link><description>Amid all the adventure and growth, I've noticed a surprisingly quiet shift I didn't expect: my relationship with shopping.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">246193d66753b2f67119b594a2a8704e</guid></item><item><title>People involved in Runt movie grappling with how to feel after author Craig Silvey charged</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/york-told-to-stay-positive-after-author-craig-silvey-charged/106256812</link><description>As one of Australia's most renowned authors faces child exploitation material charges, the town where one of his children's books was turned into a motion picture is grappling with the news.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cda3d8a5cb21aaa32a1fe451153b02da</guid></item><item><title>PM says Trump's insult to troops 'not acceptable', as he names Greg Moriarty next ambassador to the US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/greg-moriarty-us-ambassador-rudd/106266786</link><description>Defence department boss Greg Moriarty is named the next ambassador to the United States, as Prime Minister Anthony Albanese criticises the US president's claim that allied troops did not serve on the front lines of Afghanistan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55e8297fd9a084b4a7a18aecf5e07fec</guid></item><item><title>Bangladesh officially withdraws from T20 World Cup as Scotland wins last-minute call-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/scotland-replaces-bangladesh-at-t20-world-cup/106266812</link><description>After weeks of uncertainty, Bangladesh officially withdraws from next month's T20 World Cup due to security concerns, with Scotland called in for the tournament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">189c2faf107b43cfcc1cfdbb76f2c8a7</guid></item><item><title>De Minaur demolishes Bublik to storm into quarterfinal date with Alcaraz</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/australian-open-live-blog-day-eight-results-updates/106266662</link><description>Alex de Minaur obliterates Alexander Bublik in straight sets on Rod Laver Arena, after superstars Aryna Sabalenka and Carlos Alcaraz progressed through to the last eight of the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c3cbe72f16d8fda6572d88173ef6672</guid></item><item><title>Why easing demand for illegal cigarettes will be a win-win situation for WA government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/illegal-cigarette-demand-challenge-for-wa-government/106259170</link><description>Much has been made of how the WA government is trying to stop the supply of illegal cigarettes, but its more difficult challenge is what can be done to ease demand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4455e7789896347bde7302557b8254ff</guid></item><item><title>British dual citizen shares concerns about middleman websites overcharging for passport renewals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/british-passport-fallout-overcharging-middleman/106253650</link><description>As many British-Australian dual nationals grapple with new entry requirements, experts warn of exploitative and middleman websites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97e43718b529a76c13b69c77406b3330</guid></item><item><title>Health warning issued as Melbourne blanketed in smoke from Otways fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/melbourne-blanketed-in-smoke-as-bushfires-burn-in-otways/106266832</link><description>A health warning was issued to Melbourne residents as the city was covered in smoke from a bushfire burning in the Otways, in Victoria's south-west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0db367855914aaa45c945e0cb361fc1</guid></item><item><title>Chinese military's top general investigated for 'suspected serious violations of discipline' as purge targets officials</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/china-military-investigation-zhang-youxia/106266914</link><description>Rumours of a probe swirled last week after military officials Zhang Youxia and Liu Zhenli appeared to miss a meeting chaired by Xi Jinping.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">075ca0d4ae3f70b3ad9a48ecfa4e825a</guid></item><item><title>Sharn Davidson is living with Tourette syndrome and uses dinosaurs to educate others about differences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/sharn-davidson-tourette-syndrome-dinosaur-roar/105083252</link><description>Sharn has two dinosaurs inside her — one is called Kevin and the other Terry. Here's how she handles it when they roar unexpectedly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26a520c7ef67da8b2820dcfa0758bc48</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump praises UK troops as 'brave' warriors after widespread condemnation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/donald-trump-praises-uk-troops-as-brave-warriors/106266908</link><description>The US President has praised British soldiers, after remarks he made earlier this week about NATO troops in Afghanistan were described as "insulting and appalling" by the UK's Prime Minister Keir Starmer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b3bfe0fe5b80ccb5fab58a7fdb9e6a1</guid></item><item><title>Queensland family trades cattle breeding for steak searing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/queensland-family-trades-cattle-breeding-for-steak-searing/106176382</link><description>A Queensland family is trading decades of purebred cattle breeding for life in the kitchen, selling off 20 years of stud work to focus on a new paddock-to-plate restaurant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62a203869abe7b45e4ae4900c04b308c</guid></item><item><title>Police confirm possible sighting of Julian Ingram in Mount Hope after Lake Cargelligo shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/julian-ingram-possible-sighting-at-mt-hope/106266998</link><description>A large-scale search is underway in the Mount Hope district after a possible sighting of the alleged triple murderer overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ccfd0fa14b664d8eddeabb588e0be60</guid></item><item><title>US snowstorm triggers thousands of flight cancellations and power outages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/us-winter-storm-power-outages-thousands-of-flight-cancellations/106267082</link><description>A monster snowstorm is moving across the US, cancelling thousands of flights, knocking out power and snarling major roadways with ice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49bd6af08f652cf14dd4efe6af6657fc</guid></item><item><title>K'gari dingoes involved in death of Canadian backpacker Piper James euthanased</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/dingoes-involved-in-k-gari-backpacker-death-euthanised/106267322</link><description>Queensland government officials euthanase six dingoes involved in the death of a Canadian backpacker on K'gari, with more to be put down in the coming days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bfa49a34602f1d4686b9473f49d9482</guid></item><item><title>Trump’s geopolitics undermines AI focus at World Economic Forum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/trump-s-geopolitics-undermines-ai-focus-at-world-economic-forum-/106267360</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edded62c7bc80e01e99e3d7e672c6f4d</guid></item><item><title>Last-ditch push to land hospital and NDIS funding deal, as states fight back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/national-cabinet-hospital-ndis-funding-deal/106267184</link><description>The Commonwealth will try to force a deal on hospital funding at a National Cabinet meeting this week, after months of stalled negotiations with angry state leaders, who say the federal government is not contributing its fair share.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e26818d1805e43aae7af031c7316554</guid></item><item><title>New era dawns in Australian cricket as Big Bash generation steps up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/next-generation-players-new-era-australian-cricket/106265608</link><description>While Australian punters and pundits alike have been wringing their hands over an aging national cricket squad, the next generation has been quietly getting to work, proving they are ready to fill the shoes of retiring stars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dcd7bde6122f635acf8eab9ebf5ff13</guid></item><item><title>Bull shark tagging and extra drones for NSW beaches following attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/sydney-bull-shark-tagging-program-and-extra-drones-nsw-beaches/106266896</link><description>NSW coast and Sydney Harbour beachgoers can expect to see more drones in the sky after a $4.2 million investment into the state's shark management program in the wake of four shark attacks, including one fatal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">240ff0417da03ec80d9714660ffe00bd</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open favourite Aryna Sabalenka's simple approach to being world number one</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/australian-open-aryna-sabalenka-wins-fourth-round/106267374</link><description>As another Australian Open title beckons, Aryna Sabalenka reveals why she has not changed since topping the world rankings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23b5005766c8500ce2314a50d9cd23d5</guid></item><item><title>Scotty James wins fifth-straight X-Games superpipe gold ahead of Milano Cortina Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/scotty-james-wins-x-games-gold/106267420</link><description>Scotty James has matched snowboard legend Shaun White by claiming his eighth superpipe gold medal at the X-Games Aspen 2026, making him a sure favourite for Olympic gold in Milano Cortina next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ebcd8f21f4b4607fa1cf0da6c09d841</guid></item><item><title>Foo Fighters and Beaconsfield trapped miner reunite at Launceston concert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/foo-fighters-concert-launceston/106267426</link><description>Foo Fighters frontman Dave Grohl says it was a "profound moment" when a pair of miners requested the rock band's music to lift their spirits while trapped underground in 2006.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78956d31425276f2bc52f431584836d6</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroo takes out Tour Down Under peloton, Jay Vine claims overall victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/kangaroo-crashes-into-tour-down-under-peloton-as-jay-vine-wins/106267096</link><description>Jay Vine was taken out by a pair of kangaroos and lost yet another teammate to injury, but was still able to hang on and claim a second career Tour Down Under victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b78e63a5ece1034f2c7fe54cfd3e8da</guid></item><item><title>A second person has been shot dead by federal agents in Minneapolis. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/explainer-here-s-what-we-know-about-the-minneapolis-shooting/106267266</link><description>The death of 37-year-old US citizen Alex Pretti has prompted a fierce political debate and further protests in an already tense city. This is what we know about the situation so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fb0f6f0f4a69d84a400ec03d5050a7e</guid></item><item><title>Police at Mount Hope after possible sighting of Julian Ingram</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/police-at-mount-hope-after-possible-sighting-of-julian-ingram/106267806</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">528eb11903cb6d5353149cbf4ce74d45</guid></item><item><title>Tens of thousands of cigarettes and vapes seized in illicit tobacco crackdown in South West WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/illicit-tobacco-crackdown-in-southwest-wa/106267262</link><description>Tens of thousands of cigarettes and vapes, and almost $90,000 cash, has been seized during a week-long crackdown on illicit tobacco in WA's South West.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21c66596d26ba93c8b1fdeb004174b8c</guid></item><item><title>Police seize illicit tobacco products in WA's south-west.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/police-seize-illicit-tobacco-products-in-wa-south-west-/106267450</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b916a97ee76d6a6a40d8ba9e69815546</guid></item><item><title>Police search for missing 12-year-old boy at Venus Bay in Victoria's east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/missing-12yo-boy-venus-bay-victoria-gippsland-coast-search/106267850</link><description>Police and the community have mounted a search for 12-year-old Danny, who was last seen swimming at a beach in Venus Bay on Sunday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a0462944dd56b6809f5d577cf656dd9</guid></item><item><title>English veteran stars in Scorchers' record-extending sixth BBL title</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/scorchers-claim-sixth-bbl-title-against-sixers/106265840</link><description>The Perth Scorchers have easily accounted for a meek Sydney Sixers in the BBL final, cruising to a six-wicket triumph at a raucous Perth Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5025b1b0b5907ebcef2b0060df278c66</guid></item><item><title>Space industry trailblazer named Australian of the Year 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/australian-of-the-year-awards-2026/106267536</link><description>Katherine Bennell-Pegg has been named 2026 Australian of the Year for making history as the first Australian to qualify as an astronaut under the nation's space program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5ae7678f581697b07ccbb5311d87c21</guid></item><item><title>Sole survivor of Lake Cargelligo shooting opens up on the moment violence erupted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/lake-cargelligo-shooting-survivor-kaleb-macqueen-speaks/106265692</link><description>Nineteen-year-old Kaleb Macqueen was working on his car in the quiet NSW outback town of Lake Cargelligo last Thursday when violence erupted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe99dfe1797ad4944b4d36c256b7d244</guid></item><item><title>2026 Local Hero Frank Mitchell accepts honour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/2026-local-hero-frank-mitchell-accepts-honour-/106267998</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa57d4b1175e95962f9620cee559b61a</guid></item><item><title>Australia Day Honours List 2026: Meet some of the people inspiring the nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/2026-australia-day-honours-list/106258634</link><description>From champion athletes to those working to help our most vulnerable, the 2026 Australia Day Honours List showcases the very best of the nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53711307a01f4f50a4d1a89d08fb4c85</guid></item><item><title>Keynes's Bancor idea needs revisiting in wake of Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/trump-us-dollar-keynes-bretton-woods-economy/106260832</link><description>In the wake of Trump, the world will now have to revisit the conference that set up the "rules-based world order".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7c25cf0ec124d612617b099b383281e</guid></item><item><title>Could you be working on unrealistic life goals?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/new-year-resolutions-goals/106205930</link><description>Experts say knowing when to abandon or change your goals may be just as important as persistence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c841c5034c35496ea3d633e43cfb4f78</guid></item><item><title>From pod people to nuclear fallout, these Adelaidians tried to predict the future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/if-youre-listening-future-predictions-adelaide-history-radio/106256170</link><description>I had been trawling absent-mindedly through the ABC's internal digital archive in a vague search for inspiration and clicked on this file called "Letters to the Unborn" at random.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bfd3f88573bacef459b1e6b47f8a536</guid></item><item><title>Moderate Liberals 'rock solid' behind Sussan Ley amid leadership whispers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/moderate-liberals-rock-solid-ley-leadership-challenge/106267314</link><description>While conservatives Angus Taylor and Andrew Hastie canvass support to challenge for the Liberal leadership, moderates say there is no mood for turning on Sussan Ley — meaning a spill would likely result in another divided vote.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4547a8c3ecfa14684aa1c6bc509f1108</guid></item><item><title>Temperatures to exceed 40C in several parts of the country on Australia Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/heatwave-conditions-across-australia/106267024</link><description>Record-breaking temperatures above 40 degrees Celsius will be experienced in several parts of Australia from today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2891a8b3db5398f59346c0c3af167c71</guid></item><item><title>ICE agents urged to leave Minneapolis after second fatal shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/minneapolis-ice-alex-pretti-shooting-democrats/106268614</link><description>It is the second death in Minneapolis linked to the Trump administration's immigration crackdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab6560f86f0f89e752804a6486f8e203</guid></item><item><title>Support services on alert as Adelaide possibly facing its hottest Australia Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/adelaide-set-to-record-its-hottest-australia-day/106267032</link><description>South Australians are being advised to stay aware of the impacts of a "significant heatwave", as Adelaide prepares to swelter through what could be its hottest Australia Day on record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74f316f840e7f92370bf05d0c1e83b00</guid></item><item><title>Australia Day honour for former South Australian premier Steven Marshall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/australia-day-honour-for-former-sa-premier-steven-marshall/106261028</link><description>The former South Australian premier joins other state leaders from the COVID era in being recognised with an Order of Australia award.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">865ee3202ac00542159d7fd1596cc931</guid></item><item><title>Learner Tien's bloody nose, Iva Jovic arrives and Carlos Alcaraz's debt to Novak Djokovic — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/australian-open-day-eight-quick-hits/106266898</link><description>On a day of blowout wins, Learner Tien could only be slowed by his own nosebleed and Iva Jovic proved she is a superstar of the future. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb6a9fa258019dca4ae99cd121f2c775</guid></item><item><title>After years of playing nice, Alex de Minaur is done being polite ahead of Australian Open quarterfinal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/alex-de-minaur-quarterfinal-analysis-australian-open/106268074</link><description>After years of playing nice, Alex de Minaur is done hearing all the noise, and has put himself in position to reach somewhere he's never been.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0e2ebf7b2ccce634fb7fa49bcc4c6f4</guid></item><item><title>ShareSorted properties still up for rent despite being deemed 'not habitable' by NSW tribunal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/sharesorted-homes-up-for-rent-despite-not-habitable-ncat-ruling/106135310</link><description>Furnished accommodation company ShareSorted was found in breach of its obligations related to at least two properties, but a lack of regulation allows them to continue to operate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1981056d7f7accd23a055f10377e429</guid></item><item><title>The Five Islands Nature Reserve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/five-islands-nature-reserve/106236356</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24a9cc2d24c644bcdf337442a3f0084a</guid></item><item><title>Explorers Bass and Flinders named five Illawarra islands after themselves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/history-of-five-islands-nature-reserve-in-nsw-illawarra-region/106050352</link><description>Home to migratory sea birds, seals and penguins, the history of Wollongong's five islands goes back well beyond Bass and Flinders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cec7a4643668a99c73476143199ed7da</guid></item><item><title>How the Atlas Network is shaping your life, even if you've never heard of it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/atlas-network-mont-pelerin-society-neoliberal-think-tanks/105700628</link><description>A constant battle of ideas reshapes the world we live in, and few groups have been more successful in winning the war than the little-known Atlas Network.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcb2727fd9deb13d65cbf3f3d2f53c5b</guid></item><item><title>What does the rise of digital devices and decline of handwriting mean for how we live and learn?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/handwriting-decline-education-digital-devices-learning/106231320</link><description>Most of the learning done in schools these days is digital, but experts say handwriting still plays an important role in the development of thinking, learning, and fine motor skills.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60411952bcc5094f0f843cdb52eae8a1</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane temperatures tops 35 degrees as Cairns and Townsville face soaking rain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/brisbane-set-for-hottest-australia-day-so-far-this-century/106267764</link><description>South-east Queensland is sweating through its hottest Australia Day so far this century, with Brisbane recording its highest maximum temperature since 1998.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d92e7e61df648d974c73da3f400d83a</guid></item><item><title>Removal of old Bridgewater Bridge marks 'sad point' for Tasmania's rail history, advocates say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/rail-over-the-derwent-a-distant-memory-as-final-pieces-removed/106266736</link><description>As the old Bridgewater Bridge is removed piece by piece, so too is the opportunity for passenger and heritage rail connections to some of southern Tasmania's fastest-growing residential areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2b7e5faee23993aaeead0793357a691</guid></item><item><title>National Film and Sound Archive's restoration of Mount Gambier edition of Life in Australia film given new life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/nfsa-restoration-of-mount-gambier-life-in-australia/106117106</link><description>The National Film and Sound Archive has released 4K restorations of the 1960s film series Life in Australia, commissioned by the Department of Immigration to attract new migrants to regional Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0789eafc1911f3c373a782c2d4e79a85</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open influencers are changing the grand slam's look, feel and experience for tennis fans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/influencers-changing-australian-open-2026/106267980</link><description>Many long-time tennis fans have levelled some frustration at the influx of influencers who have descended on Melbourne Park, as they battle long lines, overcrowding and increased ticket prices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">520e9b00005ea7d3747e3629063eb37e</guid></item><item><title>Rescuers recover more bodies but dozens still missing after landslide in Indonesia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/indonesia-searches-missing-people-after-landslide-west-java/106268804</link><description>Dozens of people remain missing — many feared buried under mud, rocks and uprooted trees — after a landslide on Indonesia's main island of Java.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97858d33ece740f3ecd89ae46379f1ec</guid></item><item><title>More than 1,100 properties under evacuation warnings for Otways fire before extreme weather hits on Tuesday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/vic-otways-fire-not-contained/106267634</link><description>Residents from more than 1,100 properties near Victoria's Otways bushfire have been asked to evacuate before sunset ahead of extreme fire conditions on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eed566faf191248092e1ba55a5cef3b5</guid></item><item><title>Videos of Minneapolis shooting appear to contradict Trump administration's claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/minneapolis-videos-shooting-alex-pretti/106268710</link><description>Multiple videos emerge of nurse Alex Pretti being pepper-sprayed, wrestled to the ground and then shot. The Trump administration says Mr Pretti was an armed man provoking violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7054555d5864a5578b11fb92f474b1ca</guid></item><item><title>Anthony is Boddington's 'underground' carer for orphaned joeys despite the licensing hurdles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/underground-kangaroo-carer-boddington-wa/106196684</link><description>Roofus is one of many orphaned kangaroos taken under the wing of unofficial wildlife carers, a vocation one Boddington local found in his adolescence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1350c8559124997d9923faaa40ac7192</guid></item><item><title>Track temperatures live as Australia Day heatwave hits multiple states</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/temperatures-heatwave-tracker-australia-day/106268950</link><description>Use our tracker to keep an eye on temperatures as a heatwave moves across much of the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0273417c88d9ee5f3829bfe77e24139</guid></item><item><title>Manhunt for Julian Ingram enters fifth day after Lake Cargelligo shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/lake-cargelligo-manhunt-police-mount-hope-nsw/106268762</link><description>A pregnant woman who was one of three people shot dead in a suspected domestic violence attack in a remote NSW town has been remembered as a gentle and kind person.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">372f09e5e168bf33c6d7f77b4192f95c</guid></item><item><title>Mercedes Cove coastal retreat home destroyed by Tropical Cyclone Luana</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/roof-ripped-off-mercedes-cove-home-by-tropical-cyclone-luana/106267822</link><description>A family's home in WA's far north was "all but destroyed" by Tropical Cyclone Luana. The system, now a tropical low, is tracking inland across the Kimberley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3beb611968a702c639ce1e469724a5a3</guid></item><item><title>All top six seeds make quarterfinals for first time in the Open Era</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/australian-open-2026-live-jannik-sinner-maddison-inglis-swiatek/106268840</link><description>The 2026 Australian Open will be the first grand slam that all top six seeds in the men's and women's singles have reached the quarterfinals in the Open Era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41d1412692588185302d718d13f0421b</guid></item><item><title>Two men dead after drowning in Never Never River north of Bellingen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/two-men-dead-bellingen-drowning/106269014</link><description>Two men have drowned and another remains in a stable condition in hospital after a mishap in a river on the New South Wales Mid North Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cc48ed752f1b52f104bdd42a01fa475</guid></item><item><title>18-year-old tennis player Iva Jović ready to face Australian Open favourite Aryna Sabalenka</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/australian-open-tennis-iva-jovic-aryna-sabalenka/106269176</link><description>Iva Jović refuses to be intimidated about facing two-time Australian Open champion Aryna Sabalenka in the quarterfinals at Melbourne Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a31e99569c9a387cdd1467265ea308ad</guid></item><item><title>What is life like in Delhi, one of the world's most polluted cities?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/delhi-india-air-pollution-residents-struggle-breathing/106085882</link><description>Poor air quality in Delhi has impacted nearly all aspects of life with residents saying they have lost many of the "simple joys" such as opening a window or going for a walk outside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">085920628afd6fe5b51edf17d431eec4</guid></item><item><title>Parents of missing Queensland man Jack McLennan hopeful after meeting with police minister</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/missing-man-jack-mclennan-queensland-police-minister-meeting/106269360</link><description>The parents of missing Jack McLennan say they have drawn some comfort from a meeting with Queensland Police Minister Dan Purdie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1041d64f6e35fa28848910e083b6790</guid></item><item><title>At least ten dead as winter storm grips much of US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/snow-sleet-and-freezing-rain-cause-havoc-across-united-states/106268992</link><description>A massive winter storm across much of the US, spreading from Texas all the way to New England, affects powerlines, traffic and air travel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff05096c102beeb1d6df6bf0b2348590</guid></item><item><title>Witness footage shows lead-up to deadly shooting of Alex Pretti</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/witness-footage-shows-lead-up-to-deadly-shooting-of-alex-pretti/106269508</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e81702de55c7ddbcf5b8bca6c3e4398</guid></item><item><title>Video showing lead-up to Minneapolis shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/minneapolis-shooting/106269558</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">055d5b778d17f6253872b7411f94f576</guid></item><item><title>US citizens are becoming collateral damage in Donald Trump's quest to deport immigrants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/us-citizens-collateral-damage-in-trump-s-immigration-crackdown/106269166</link><description>Minneapolis has become the flashpoint of an aggressive immigration enforcement operation ordered by the Trump administration and pitched as a campaign against undocumented criminals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92f5c0d64fad223fd8349ad33fa967af</guid></item><item><title>Potential explosive device thrown into crowd at Perth Invasion Day rally, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/invasion-day-rallies-australia-january-26-australia-day/106267560</link><description>Police say they are investigating whether a device thrown into an Invasion Day rally crowd in Perth contained explosives, in addition to ball bearings and screws found inside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bad110f23151b55de241e4f1394db5bc</guid></item><item><title>Australia Day 2026 marked by citizenship ceremonies, traditional dances, fun runs and heatwave conditions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/australia-day-celebrations-across-country-community-events/106268794</link><description>Communities across the country are marking Australia Day with citizenship ceremonies, traditional dances, smoking ceremonies and fun runs, as the prime minister calls for "unity not division" during a speech in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89a297ebf30dbceba064bdca817744b6</guid></item><item><title>Ferry carrying more than 300 people sinks in southern Philippines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/rescue-efforts-after-ferry-sinks-in-southern-philippines/106269480</link><description>Rescuers are searching for missing passengers and at least 18 are dead, after a ferry with more than 300 people onboard sunk in the southern Philippines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04fa2aa0ec3caa62769f614d6169748b</guid></item><item><title>Police arrest man as part of investigation into alleged sexual assault at Yeppen Lagoon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/rockhampton-police-investigate-alleged-sexual-assault/106269804</link><description>Police have taken a 27-year-old man into custody as part of their investigations after a woman was allegedly attacked on a popular walkway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e99697e3dba98f26345668a9a99c8a4f</guid></item><item><title>Gold's record run rolls on with prices surging past $US5,000 as investors seek safety</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/gold-record-run-continues-price-surges-past-us-5000/106269850</link><description>Gold surges to a record high above $US5,000 an ounce, extending a historic rally as investors pile into the safe-haven asset amid rising geopolitical tensions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23bbc0ce16bea8c51eb3c1035a7cf312</guid></item><item><title>'Dog in driver's seat' of ute on Tasmanian beach sparks call for witnesses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/dog-in-driver-seat-of-ute-on-tasmanian-beach/106270074</link><description>Reports of a "dog in the driver's seat" of a ute driving on a Tasmanian beach have prompted police to ask for witnesses to come forward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64bd480c793c2afb08c97fdec71c00ce</guid></item><item><title>Call for public information following home invasion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/call-for-public-information-following-home-invasion/106269446</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">626519a86fbf008159136f2e73459c63</guid></item><item><title>Police appeal for information after 54-year-old woman assaulted in Sale home invasion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/sale-ross-street-home-invasion-woman-assaulted-police/106123750</link><description>Wellington Crime Investigation detectives turn to the public for help as they continue to investigate a 2025 home invasion where they allege three men broke in and assaulted a woman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db32c2e589adaee9c0ec93a59c6659fb</guid></item><item><title>Timothée Chalamet on 'unlearning' everything he knew as an actor for Marty Supreme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/timoth%C3%A9e-chalamet-on-unlearning-everything-he-knew-as-an-actor/106260386</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cf70ceb9d86f4ab10ee3df3bebf900c</guid></item><item><title>Australian of the Year Katherine Bennell-Pegg reflects on space, STEM and the launch pad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/australian-of-the-year-katherine-bennell-pegg-on-space-and-stem/106269082</link><description>The 2026 Australian of the Year — astronaut and space engineer Katherine Bennell-Pegg — is a strong advocate for STEM education, but fears too much talent is being left on the "launch pad".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edeb680b7a28ff90b1a912dad59944d3</guid></item><item><title>Super Bowl LX match-up confirmed with Seattle Seahawks to play New England Patriots</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/super-bowl-lx-match-up-seattle-new-england/106270308</link><description>New England survived a Denver blizzard and Seattle outlasted Los Angeles in an offensive shootout to set up a bumper clash for Super Bowl LX.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20a9d6c817e8de413b597b7526531cbc</guid></item><item><title>Animated movie Imagine invited 150 Indigenous kids to collaborate with stars like Taika Waititi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/imagine-movie-jack-manning-bancroft-aime-indigenous-mentoring/106256658</link><description>The beautifully animated, crowdsourced movie Imagine introduces a wealth of Indigenous knowledge to audiences in the funniest way possible and hopes to generate real change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84f5433c25ed7356c9db4fefe25232b8</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners heartbroken over decision to cull K'gari dingoes involved in Piper James's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/traditional-owners-heartbroken-at-decision-to-cull-kgari-dingoes/106269824</link><description>The Queensland government euthanises six dingoes involved in Piper James's death on K'gari, and is expected to cull more in the coming days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45eaa987e1113e0f5ecce3f19a4a2ad1</guid></item><item><title>Australia Day heat record for Adelaide, as mercury hits 49C in Ceduna</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/adelaide-records-australia-day-heat-record/106270456</link><description>As Adelaide sets a new record for its hottest Australia Day, other parts of SA are enduring conditions that are even more sweltering, with the mercury climbing above 49C in Ceduna.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d0724e16a5e1fce8b2130181191edf8</guid></item><item><title>Madison Keys's world hasn't ended now her Australian Open defence is over</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/australian-open-madison-keys-jessica-pegula-fourth-round/106270864</link><description>There were no tears or tantrums once Madison Keys left Rod Laver Arena, knowing her Australian Open title defence had come to an end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9d96112d66d107dbf2ddad031e238d4</guid></item><item><title>Quick and easy burger recipes for stress-free summer dinners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/quick-and-easy-burger-recipes-for-stress-free-summer-dinners/106136826</link><description>From chargrilled beef patties and beer-battered fish to vegetarian parmigiana and cheeseburger tray bake, we have burgers to suit all tastes and diets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80df8dd571c7b72bbde93a28fde82e65</guid></item><item><title>Call for memorial to Beaumont children, 60 years after they disappeared</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/beaumont-children-missing-60-years-today-memorial/106269224</link><description>Politician Frank Pangallo is calling for a permanent memorial to be installed at an Adelaide beach to acknowledge the disappearance of the Beaumont children in 1966.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d98522fb95c1cd0c87faa382485d057</guid></item><item><title>Anti-immigration rallies take place in major cities across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/march-for-australia-anti-immigration-rally/106269414</link><description>A 31-year-old has been arrested and charged by police for allegedly using hate speech "aligned with Neo-Nazi ideology" at an open mic session at the anti-immigration rally.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1452902136948eb178a2f7ab8c819b0</guid></item><item><title>Worst heatwave in decades sending temperatures close to 50C over south-east Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/south-east-australia-weather-hit-close-to-50c-worst-heatwave/106270302</link><description>A record heatwave across south-east Australia will peak during the coming days, leading to extreme fire danger and temperatures close to 50 degrees Celsius in multiple states.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c04b7f382ab317c08fced4431d4891d</guid></item><item><title>Police confirm human remains found in north Queensland those of missing man Jayden Penno-Tompsett</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/jayden-penno-tompsett-remains-confirmed-north-queensland/105919904</link><description>Human remains found in north Queensland belong to a missing New South Wales man last seen eight years ago, according to police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7df045b9c4b25556bf901030951af32d</guid></item><item><title>Travellers stranded at Nullarbor roadhouses as bushfire shuts Eyre Highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/eyre-highway-closed-bushfire-travellers-stranded/106270912</link><description>A fire near Caiguna has blocked the major road link between Western Australia and the east coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fa28955bc0da7c8801fe5f2ad91544b</guid></item><item><title>Confusion and chaos at Perth Invasion Day rally as police respond to security threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/confusion-and-chaos-at-perth-invasion-day-rally/106271484</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f9d8b4224d36417234c30dd0ada6a0f</guid></item><item><title>Man dies after confrontation with police officers in Kalgoorlie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/south-kalgoorlie-death-in-custody-police-investigation/106271730</link><description>A 43-year-old man has died after an incident involving WA Police officers in South Kalgoorlie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5aab0c4b8db9531438d22ab1be5f0959</guid></item><item><title>Gunmen open fire at soccer field in central Mexico, killing 11</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/mexico-shooting-soccer-field-salamanca/106271736</link><description>Authorities say gunmen opened fire in the city of Salamanca, killing at least 11 people and wounding 12 at the end of a soccer match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1154ce725b04adfda7cea06aae17974d</guid></item><item><title>Government agency deliberately broke law for years, federal watchdog finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/services-australia-knowingly-broke-law-for-years/106261814</link><description>Services Australia has known it was not fully complying with new child support laws since 2019, according to a scathing report released by the Commonwealth Ombudsman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fd0aefb325b79e1cc94de522aa7f401</guid></item><item><title>Remains of last Israeli hostage in Gaza, Ran Gvili, have been found, Benjamin Netanyahu says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/remains-of-last-israeli-hostage-in-gaza-ran-gvili-found/106271998</link><description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu confirmed that the remains of 24-year-old Ran Gvili had been found and identified.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97407c51a7fd92648efee5a60e2b745e</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump sends 'border czar' Tom Homan to Minnesota after shooting of nurse Alex Pretti</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/republicans-express-shock-over-minneapolis-shooting/106271792</link><description>An American citizen, Alex Pretti, was shot by federal agents during a continuing Trump administration immigration crackdown in the city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c571686af181bc1dd64b85b1fde3edb</guid></item><item><title>Indonesian marines among at least 42 people missing in Indonesian landslide in West Java province</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/west-java-landslide-buries-indonesian-marines/106271942</link><description>The search is ongoing for survivors after the pre-dawn landslide on the slopes of Mount Burangrang in West Java province killed at least two dozen people at the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bdefc869b094b335a8c3d865a144fda</guid></item><item><title>Private jet crashes as major winter storm kills 13 across US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/deaths-reported-as-winter-storm-barrels-across-us/106271804</link><description>Almost 200 million Americans are under cold weather alerts as snow, sleet and freezing rain affects swathes of the country from Texas to New England, with temperatures set to fall dangerously low this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd6cd8de90e3824c4046645c9905dc2a</guid></item><item><title>Russia, Ukraine and US plan further trilateral talks on ending war</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/major-challenges-ukraine-russia-kremlin/106272110</link><description>Volodymyr Zelenskyy said discussions between envoys from Ukraine, Russia and the US in Abu Dhabi last week aimed at ending Moscow's invasion left some political issues unresolved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f43e81e7388e85393beb91099c9153c2</guid></item></channel></rss>