<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 11:21:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Central Coast Mariners star Annalise Rasmussen signs with Italian powerhouse Juventus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/annalise-rasmussen-central-coast-mariners-signs-with-juventus/106300846</link><description>A-League leading goal scorer Annalise Rasmussen leaves the competition immediately to join Italian powerhouse Juventus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5824f89d8ddce116ae033a1edcb9862</guid></item><item><title>Son of Norway's crown princess tells rape trial sex was consensual</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/son-norway-crown-princess/106302292</link><description>Marius Borg Høiby pleads not guilty to four counts of rape and one of domestic violence but guilty to a count of offensive sexual behaviour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">402ea0fa721a64c5ff0edc7185b3003e</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of parents seek support as children cannot go to school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/school-cant-parents-seek-support/106298400</link><description>Thousands of Australian parents are struggling with children who cannot go to school. A new podcast and e-book have been released to help support them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb507a88382b90baa4d0ff18ae33cd3e</guid></item><item><title>What could the government do to help battle inflation?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/what-could-the-government-do-to-help-battle-inflation/106301894</link><description>The federal government has a variety of options available if it wants to do more to stave off inflation, but none are popular.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39726803731460e09844b959e8b4513c</guid></item><item><title>Elite women athletes finding ways to work smarter, to help sporting and professional careers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/elite-women-athletes-work-careers-performance-chloe-dalton/106284886</link><description>The sport-work-life balance is a struggle faced by many female athletes, but many are finding meaningful ways to diversify their income to secure their future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6fe2599cc430201f4c2313ceeb5ba38</guid></item><item><title>How to know if you're experiencing PTSD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/how-to-know-if-you-are-experiencing-ptsd-symptoms/106287082</link><description>Louise was experiencing nightmares for five years before being diagnosed with post-traumatic stress disorder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93d1325bb199373e4f1bf9b01b5f6fff</guid></item><item><title>Boost for development of low-emissions alternatives to glass wine bottles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/low-emission-alternatives-to-wine-glass-bottles-australia/106272524</link><description>The federal government provides $2 million towards developing low-emissions alternatives to glass wine bottles using materials like seaweed and plant sugar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf150fa9f741923d5e2f222d98ce87cf</guid></item><item><title>What the Epstein files tell us about Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's 'car crash' 2019 interview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/epstein-files-shed-more-light-on-mountbatten-windsor-interview/106302294</link><description>Documents released last week have shed more light on what the former prince might have been lying about in that fateful sit-down with the BBC's flagship current affairs program, Newsnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6779dc32f34e97d931db509a2116209a</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Ferguson offered Jeffrey Epstein woman with 'great body' after his release from prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/sarah-ferguson-emails-to-jeffrey-epstein-revealed/106302466</link><description>Emails contained in the Epstein files show former British royal Sarah Ferguson told the convicted child sex offender she knew a "single" woman with a "great body" he should meet, weeks after his 2009 release from prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8216f6d90bb222bab0daa5d9f345c016</guid></item><item><title>Up to 100,000 dead fish found on bank of Lake Menindee</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/fish-kill-on-sunset-strip-shores-near-menindee/106302904</link><description>Residents of a far west New South Wales community found tens of thousands of dead fish on the banks of Lake Menindee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cb838985300290e2945ea85c41c9eb9</guid></item><item><title>Demons defender Steven May misses AFL pre-season training</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/demons-defender-may-misses-afl-pre-season-training/106304280</link><description>Melbourne Demons veteran Steven May was not at training for his club on Wednesday, just six weeks out from the start of the 2026 AFL season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59f8902d785b99ba4c5c2cd0b16a3148</guid></item><item><title>Art exhibitions to see this summer, from Ron Mueck to Hobart Current and Olafur Eliasson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/art-exhibitions-ron-mueck-hobart-current-olafur-eliasson/106295866</link><description>From Aussie expat Ron Mueck's hyper-realistic sculptures and Icelandic Danish artist Olafur Eliasson's thought-provoking installations to the best contemporary artists in Tasmania, here are three exhibitions to see.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">298caa8ff84eba3f4959fca7878c20aa</guid></item><item><title>Ban on sand flathead fishing in south-eastern Tasmania amid severe decline in numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/fishing-ban-for-southern-tasmania-on-depleted-sand-flathead/106302974</link><description>Populations of sand flathead have "severely declined" in Tasmanian waters, prompting the government to close a fishery in the state's south-east to recreational anglers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edf2da94922d88069d46b2a4b63def7b</guid></item><item><title>Northern Territory mum wrangles Humpty Doo crocodile near Arnhem Highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/nt-mum-helps-wrangle-crocodile-humpty-doo-bottle-shop-arnhem-hwy/106303792</link><description>Melody Wehipeihana was dropping her kids off at school when she pulled over to see what a crowd had gathered to look at in a puddle outside a Northern Territory pub.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3391dee89a5e7c013bfaf9e4aeb786b7</guid></item><item><title>Humpty Doo locals help relocate crocodile from side of highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/humpty-doo-locals-help-relocate-crocodile-from-side-of-highway/106304366</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3e0a3ff3c023e3ab1ba031de41c6426</guid></item><item><title>Banned tennis player Thomas Fancutt makes comeback after IV vitamin breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/banned-tennis-player-thomas-fancutt-makes-comeback/106303088</link><description>Thomas Fancutt has made his return to professional tennis after receiving a 10-month ban for a vitamin and magnesium infusion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42fc7b5264f3284f619a1da6e7afddf2</guid></item><item><title>Why these women took marriage sabbaticals — and how it went</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/women-on-taking-a-break-from-their-marriage/106281918</link><description>Do you ever feel like taking a break from your marriage? Three women share how a marriage sabbatical changed their relationship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a22d596cb89a89bdce7261b2f8056448</guid></item><item><title>Olympic sports face 'difficult conversations' before Brisbane 2032 as IOC president confirms reforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/fit-for-the-future-olympic-games-brisbane-2032-sports-difficult/106302676</link><description>Brisbane Olympic organisers say they do not know what events will be at the 2032 Games, as IOC president Kirsty Coventry says her reforms will result in "difficult conversations" with established sports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6c1204787ebdd74db7210cdf5703b95</guid></item><item><title>Daly River residents being evacuated to Darwin ahead of predicted major flooding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/emergency-evacuation-for-daly-river-ahead-of-major-flooding/106305594</link><description>About 450 people are being evacuated from the remote Northern Territory town of Daly River, ahead of expected flood levels of more than 14 metres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">752a5659cbfe3bb88bfb57771236b4cc</guid></item><item><title>Ex-prince Andrew leaves Windsor home as British police investigate latest Epstein revelations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-moves-out-of-windsor/106306600</link><description>British police are investigating Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor after new files suggest Jeffrey Epstein arranged for a woman to have sex with the former prince at his home at the Royal Lodge in 2010.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96c031baea93110fb38b3d9532c422c4</guid></item><item><title>Australia announces Jakara Anthony, Matt Graham as 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics flag bearers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/australia-announces-2026-winter-olympics-flag-bearers/106306688</link><description>Jakara Anthony and Matt Graham have been named as flag bearers for the 2026 Winter Olympic Games in Milano Cortina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dd17f2d42429c1b56d68a37e9849f4c</guid></item><item><title>Marius Borg Høiby, son of Norwegian crown princess, denies rape charges in testimony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/hoiby-norwegian-prince-testimony-cries-rape-trial/106306936</link><description>Marius Borg Høiby is pleading not guilty to the most serious charges of rape and domestic violence but admits some lesser charges, including driving too fast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4ce7b016f8b79d715372aa5e208ab27</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics quiz: How well are you prepared for the Games?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/winter-olympics-quiz/106289820</link><description>The Winter Olympics gets underway in Milan Cortina this week — but how much do you know about the Winter Olympics? Test yourself in our fiendish quiz.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f80031d3dc4b6049fe0ed85b109e119b</guid></item><item><title>Report points to exploitation, Medicare and visa concerns in Pacific islander jobs scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/palm-scheme-report-calls-for-change/106298514</link><description>Changing jobs is a basic right for most people, but it is not so simple for Pacific Australia Labour Mobility workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f21909b4c4949bb2d5b3a261ebd665c</guid></item><item><title>Fears SA's endangered glossy black-cockatoo eggs will 'cook' in nesting boxes during heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/kangaroo-island-glossy-black-cockatoos-heatwaves/106273812</link><description>South Australia's population of a unique subspecies of glossy black-cockatoos is heavily dependent on artificial nesting boxes. That could pose a problem during extreme heat conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92c894ea4f73cd62977ed5ac13ed4426</guid></item><item><title>Grandmother removed from Toowoomba birth suite by security</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/grandmother-removed-from-toowoomba-birth-suite-by-security/106301414</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82f83e6cb6359c2e1b990d90449f47f9</guid></item><item><title>Central Queensland conservation group wants to see more transparency on coal mine water releases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/call-for-more-information-on-coal-mine-water-release/106288312</link><description>There were 55 water releases from the region's coal mines in the month of January into the largest catchment draining to the Great Barrier Reef.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ff8693894a0a260e74954e81d5136b2</guid></item><item><title>New resource connects people with organisations on front lines of bushfire relief effort</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/resource-connecting-people-with-frontline-bushfire-relief-orgs/106273490</link><description>A new online resource aims to make it easier for people to contribute to bushfire relief efforts across Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd36f19dbab5f9df4c883c9b96a27f9f</guid></item><item><title>Police executing drug raid find deadly snakes, crocodile in alleged makeshift zoo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/police-discover-snakes-crocodile-during-kempsey-drug-raid/106307800</link><description>More than 50 reptiles, including a 1.3-metre crocodile, have been seized after police discovered an alleged makeshift zoo during a drug raid on the NSW Mid North Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">192a2b9248295d31e2166b2cd7d961e9</guid></item><item><title>State of Origin 2027 in New Zealand hailed as a boost for rugby league by Kiwi great</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/state-of-origin-2027-in-new-zealand-boost-says-kiwi/106308612</link><description>The NRL's reported landmark move to host a State of Origin match in New Zealand is hailed as "sensational" by Kiwi legend Gary Freeman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">159d849e4617ffdb86ae3e8b97588b9a</guid></item><item><title>Invasion Day bomb declared terror act, as accused's 'pro-white ideology' probed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/perth-invasion-day-rally-attempted-bombing-terrorist-act/106303806</link><description>The attempted bombing of an Invasion Day rally in Perth's CBD last week is declared a terrorist attack by authorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bc486c32a0f3eb6459afa4f7641f5a9</guid></item><item><title>Strict caps on bottled water extraction urged for World Heritage-listed Springbrook</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/water-extraction-caps-at-world-heritage-springbrook/106304388</link><description>A long-awaited study warns that the extraction of bottled water from the World Heritage-listed Springbrook area poses a potential risk to the ancient Gondwana rainforests and should be strictly limited.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19d076e599ae81db17a9effaa24af962</guid></item><item><title>AFL integrity unit looking into why police visited Melbourne Demons player Steven May</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/afl-integrity-unit-looking-into-why-police-visited-steven-may/106309028</link><description>Melbourne veteran Steven May is being investigated by the AFL integrity unit, as the premiership defender stays away from Demons training.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c42c8d49e23a155f085f14d82937f7e5</guid></item><item><title>Albanese, Ley condemn alleged act of terror targeting Indigenous protesters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/albanese-ley-condemn-alleged-invasion-rally-terror-act/106309170</link><description>The prime minister and opposition leader have both condemned the alleged attempted bombing of an Invasion Day rally more than a week ago, after police revealed it was being prosecuted as a terror incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5627852046870a17972ecd39ceb5004e</guid></item><item><title>How capital gains tax changes could impact you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/how-capital-gains-tax-changes-could-impact-you/106309066</link><description>According to a well-sourced leak, changes to capital gains tax discounts could form the centrepiece of the next federal budget in May. And while the government has downplayed the idea, it has not been ruled out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">566800855cbc95596fa22fe075eeef0e</guid></item><item><title>Coroner recommends Ambulance Victoria guideline review following nut allergy death of Max McKenzie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/anaphylaxis-death-nut-allergy-max-mckenzie-box-hill-hospital/106307284</link><description>The coroner could not definitively rule that the anaphylaxis death of 15-year-old Max McKenzie was preventable, despite identifying delays in the teen's medical treatment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7fb96224de8dfd3ac5b2522e7071ec1</guid></item><item><title>Thursday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106309854</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ac2a52ba0b6ad6ce9ccec04590edbb7</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Junction inquest saw recommendation for supported housing for homeless, some are already benefitting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/bondi-junction-stabbing-inquest-habilis-mental-health-housing/106309484</link><description>An inquest into the Bondi Junction stabbing has recommended that the NSW government support long-term accommodation for homeless people experiencing mental health issues. It's a model that is already finding success.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a81fc4ebb5907745acfeae2e974efbeb</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds defeat Jamaica in first netball Test match in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/diamonds-defeat-jamaica-in-adelaide/106311692</link><description>The Diamonds made a flying start with the initial six goals in a comprehensive 72-41 victory at the Adelaide Entertainment Centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be741f4d1fb677fd340efe1016d77511</guid></item><item><title>New study reveals how stressful footy fandom can be</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/study-reveals-how-stressful-footy-fandom-is/106310960</link><description>A new study reveals how much high-stakes sporting events can get the heart pumping by strapping trackers to over 200 German football fans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c31f01f9ec961ff01d3df42c41faafef</guid></item><item><title>Valentino Guseli gets snowboard big air wildcard, leaps into final at Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/val-guseli-snowboard-big-air-milano-cortina-winter-olympics/106312046</link><description>Valentino Guseli only found out he had been added to the big air field a couple of hours before the competition start after a rival's injury, but still found a way to make it to the final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84ec8404886766b47120ef6c552e418d</guid></item><item><title>Epstein files reveal the men who looked away after women had spoken up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/jeffrey-epstein-files-allegations-melinda-gates/106308164</link><description>The millions of pages of documents related to the late convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein have shone a light on how many influential men were ready to disregard the experiences of countless women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40d57aedebb5b5169d68dfe86d5517cc</guid></item><item><title>Today in history, February 6: The Manchester United team that perished in the Munich air disaster of 1958</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/manchester-united-munich-air-disaster-1958/106183032</link><description>On a snowy February afternoon in 1958, the football team that many were calling the greatest that Britain had ever produced stopped to refuel at Munich Airport. The plane would never take off, and the Flowers of Manchester would take years to bloom again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd269141d3e84cd66d24a4d4ebf71ed8</guid></item><item><title>Former attorney-general Mark Dreyfus warned anti-corruption chief to 'manage' or 'avoid' conflicts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/mark-dreyfus-warned-anti-corruption-chief-to-avoid-conflicts/106311478</link><description>A letter from Mark Dreyfus to Paul Brereton provides new insight into the expectations set for the inaugural chief of the anti-corruption watchdog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e67d41ae94005c162be09aa4254b2e2</guid></item><item><title>Effect of capital gains tax changes on housing affordability likely depends on design</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/would-higher-property-taxes-mean-lower-house-prices/106311582</link><description>Labor has not ruled out changes to the capital gains tax discount but wants any tax changes to improve housing affordability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8837e3812457a3afcc82335b9e69139a</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: When does it start, how to watch and who is competing in which sports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/winter-olympics-milano-cortina-2026-when-where/106188146</link><description>Australia is tipped for enormous success over the next couple of weeks so now might be a good time to clue yourself up. Here's everything you need to know about the 2026 Winter Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a93b24614f2e1ae879ffc8503e731c6</guid></item><item><title>An ex-jihadi and terror experts agree on one thing about extremism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/bondi-terror-attack-radicalisation-islamic-state-group/106300484</link><description>As police probe what led to the deadliest terror attack on Australian soil in December, radicalisation researchers and a former Islamic State group supporter have shed light on how people are recruited.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5cd14c9f76f47554b7f5454f0088c8a</guid></item><item><title>World Anti-Doping Agency bosses 'will look at' claims of penis enlargement in ski jumping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/wada-will-investigate-ski-jumper-penis-enlargement-allegations/106311706</link><description>The World Anti-Doping Agency will investigate bizarre claims in German newspaper Bild that ski jumpers are injecting substances into their penises to aid aerodynamics — and other stories from the Winter Olympics a day out from the opening ceremony.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84586ef0f66b1f30261a833dd26efe85</guid></item><item><title>US hopes to challenge China's critical minerals dominance with new trading bloc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/us-pitches-new-critical-minerals-trading-bloc/106309202</link><description>The US is urging dozens of countries to follow Australia's lead and sign on to a plan to stop relying on China for the critical minerals used in modern technology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4c34d4de059770202fdc288ddc3883b</guid></item><item><title>What Israel's President Isaac Herzog has said about Gaza, and why he won't be arrested in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/herzog-will-be-aware-controversy-wont-be-arrested-in-australia/106311734</link><description>When Israel's president lands in Australia this weekend, he can expect an official red carpet treatment. But he will be all too aware of the controversy his visit is generating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ffdecd9e59cf515e239536238754ac7</guid></item><item><title>ATO debt continues to drive record level of calls to small business financial helpline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/debts-to-ato-drive-record-level-of-financial-helpline-calls/106308516</link><description>Financial counsellors say small businesses struggling to pay debts owed to the tax office are driving calls to Australia's Small Business Debt Helpline higher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5e7106c0d32cd232b4538e4271760e1</guid></item><item><title>Late NSW tradie Brett Mckay connected with thousands by sharing cancer battle online</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/brett-mckay-legacy-after-sharing-cancer-battle-via-social-media/106295230</link><description>When NSW tradie Brett Mckay started sharing videos of his cancer journey with his mates on social media, he did not expect thousands of strangers to come along for the ride.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b28afc999a5809b20a0a7c420ae28ce2</guid></item><item><title>Voters in David Littleproud's seat of Maranoa weigh in amid Coalition split, One Nation surge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/david-littleproud-seat-of-maranoa-weigh-coalition-split/106305146</link><description>As One Nation announces its plan to open an office in Longreach, the ABC speaks to voters in David Littleproud's electorate to get their thoughts on the Nationals leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78476b785e998ff817539d1db814fbeb</guid></item><item><title>Nationals counter Ley's offer with two-week frontbench exile — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/federal-politics-live/106310298</link><description>The Nationals have proposed spending another two weeks in exile from the frontbench rather than address the Liberals' non-negotiable conditions for a Coalition reunion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6336bed62f747957f082b887d6fdb45f</guid></item><item><title>Georgia Voll helps Royal Challengers Bengaluru win Indian Women's Premier League</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/royal-challengers-bengaluru-win-indian-women-premier-league/106312236</link><description>Royal Challengers Bengaluru pulled off the biggest successful chase in the Women's Premier League to win their second title in the Indian franchise-based T20 league.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e308434821166760b39b511e513be5cf</guid></item><item><title>Pharmacy apologises after customers given wrong medicines, scripts in Broome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/pharmacy-customers-detail-wrong-medicines-and-scripts-in-broome/106308810</link><description>More than a dozen customers have come forward over concerns two Broome chemists have handed out the wrong medications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f538e97e2b860296b05ed825dc97371</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Jewish leader wants stronger crackdown on symbols, flags, and slogans in wake of Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/qld-jewish-board-of-deputies-bondi-attack-antisemitism/106310388</link><description>Queensland Jewish Board of Deputies president Jason Steinberg has called on the state government to ramp up anti-hate laws in the wake of last year's Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">657fe1e021667e15565d5bcf8e958757</guid></item><item><title>Louvre releases photos of squashed crown abandoned by jewel heist gang</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/louvre-heist-empress-eugenie-crown-to-be-restored/106312526</link><description>The thieves who robbed the famed Paris museum last October dropped the diamond and emerald-studded crown as they escaped, leaving it crushed and broken.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80c91de186b4aa4f509ce7c72582cf12</guid></item><item><title>Beyond the Songs Inside: After the applause</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/beyond-the-songs-inside-documentary/106032528</link><description>Creative prison programs are celebrated for their ability to heal and transform incarcerated people. But are they enough to break the cycle?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">522012622427958b8365731ca8a4abfe</guid></item><item><title>Questions raised over $93 million investment in WA school with 30 per cent attendance rate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/roebourne-school-low-attendance-lands-93-million-rebuild/106232702</link><description>By the end of 2026 the WA government and Woodside will have spent over $93 million on Roebourne District High School and its 141 enrolled students. But last year only one in four upper school students attended.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cdd919ebf3696cf88d426b1371b09e7</guid></item><item><title>French authorities sink tonnes of cocaine bound for Australia, then release suspects</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/french-authorities-sink-five-tonnes-of-cocaine/106307438</link><description>French authorities intercept a ship carrying five tonnes of cocaine bound for Australia, before releasing the vessel and its crew.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9429ea7a44b7fd6eb152b561ab54a17</guid></item><item><title>Australia's surging expectations at the Winter Olympics come thanks to Geoff Henke's strident advocacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/winter-olympics-success-for-australia-geoff-henke-revolution/106302018</link><description>Australia is hoping Milano Cortina 2026 will be its most successful Winter Olympics in history. The reason for Australia's winter sports surge has its roots in a 70-year-old snubbing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">864e05b9f59b0989d860aae75009df3d</guid></item><item><title>RecipeTin Eats' Nagi Maehashi is normalising taking time off for pets. Here's why that matters.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/recipetineats-nagi-maehashi-time-off-work-care-for-dog-dozer/106313752</link><description>Experts say our pets have become such an important part of our lives that it's important to take a step back from responsibilities, if possible, when they are sick or dying.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9cbd7b56d7377cd2c066ce8db744bca</guid></item><item><title>Man faces court charged with possessing extremist material after phone search at Brisbane Airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/extremist-material-charge-after-phone-search-brisbane-airport/106315576</link><description>Police allege a 25-year-old man intercepted at Brisbane International Airport had violent extremist material on his phone, after an investigation into an alleged Nazi flag delivery to the man.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">507bf1b576bc371496a5d69577c3b4b6</guid></item><item><title>Bullock says government spending not sole factor pushing inflation higher as political fight heats up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/rba-governor-refuses-to-blame-government-for-rising-inflation/106313266</link><description>RBA governor Michele Bullock has refused to blame the Albanese government for rising inflation, as a political fight breaks out in the wake of the bank's rate hike.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c98b12981d05c59ed145353062642772</guid></item><item><title>Josh Hazlewood out of T20 World Cup with injury in another blow to Australia's hopes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/josh-hazlewood-out-of-t20-world-cup-injury-australia/106315684</link><description>Josh Hazlewood is ruled out of Australia's T20 World Cup campaign as he continues to recover from the injuries which kept him from playing in the summer's Ashes series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc2eaa2ecdfd92d77e913bc4aef7b367</guid></item><item><title>Patrol boats out of action in Cairns shipyards as foreign fishers reach Australian shores</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/patrol-boats-out-of-water-amid-illegal-foreign-fishing-influx/106309428</link><description>A "continuous" influx of illegal foreign fishing boats in Queensland waters coincides with at least two of the nation's fleet of patrol boats being out of commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4161f0b872e22c9609c84a3991e94649</guid></item><item><title>Why it took police nine days to declare the Invasion Day attempted bomb attack in Perth terrorism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/process-to-declare-invasion-day-alleged-attack-terrorism-/106314916</link><description>When a homemade fragment bomb was allegedly thrown into a crowd on January 26, it took nine days for it to be declared an act of terrorism. The WA police commissioner explains why, as Indigenous leaders raise concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3aa7ffedfadafcc72701809222cd8964</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Snook, The Newsreader and Bring Her Back triumph at AACTA Awards — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/aacta-awards-2026-live-blog-winners-sarah-snook-celeste-barber/106295178</link><description>Australia's answer to the Oscars — the AACTAs — lit up the Gold Coast tonight, with horror Bring Her Back and The Narrow Road to the Deep North dominating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">473742d5b25ca33648f2c7c0647748d5</guid></item><item><title>Friday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106316284</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">442d545004b23100d0c522b6883e3f48</guid></item><item><title>Pentagon reportedly asked to probe SpaceX for potential Chinese ownership seen as a 'national security threat'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/pentagon-asked-to-probe-spacex-chinese-ownership/106311868</link><description>Chinese investment in Elon Musk's company SpaceX has been cited as a "national security threat", according to senators Elizabeth Warren and Andy Kim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a14c66ba0a91388f5002547f0fc8165b</guid></item><item><title>Evidence concludes in inquest into psychiatric patient's death at Alice Springs Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/kumanjayi-brogus-inquest-nt-alice-springs-hospital-death/106309452</link><description>A coronial inquest has heard that the death of a 34-year-old mother who was repeatedly sedated during a schizophrenic episode was "entirely preventable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e37e11908baa219401597f522da46fe7</guid></item><item><title>AACTA 2026 winners list: Gory horror wins best film, Jacob Elordi drama dominates TV</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/aactas-winners-list-jacob-elordi-key-moments/106315590</link><description>Directors Danny and Michael Philippou clean up at the 2026 AACTA awards, taking home 10 statues for their chilling horror film Bring Her Back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">180771fbc8035cfdbeeb3540d53fab91</guid></item><item><title>TC Mitchell set to become severe category 3 system off WA's Pilbara coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/wa-pilbara-warnings-cyclone-mitchell/106314534</link><description>Residents along WA's Pilbara coast have been warned to prepare to shelter as Cyclone Mitchell builds into a severe category 3 system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b97a227aadadcc4688c45e3310259768</guid></item><item><title>Daisy Thomas, competing without an ACL, suffers heavy crash at Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/daisy-thomas-acl-milano-cortina-2026-winter-olympics/106316542</link><description>Australian freestyle skier Daisy Thomas, who is competing at the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games without an ACL, suffers a heavy fall in slopestyle training and has withdrawn from the event to focus on big air.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f025e657abeae9134b373e8a2e58473</guid></item><item><title>US accuses China of secret nuclear testing as Washington calls for Beijing to be part of new arms deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/us-accuses-china-of-secret-nuclear-testing/106316826</link><description>The claim comes as the US calls for China to be involved in a new deal limiting the use of nuclear weapons, after the New START deal expired this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cb9e860548f8785bbe0b55a630e419e</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's invitation to Herzog is a shift in his approach to Israel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/isaac-herzog-visit-australia/106294858</link><description>Unravelling the threads of antisemitism and anti-Israeli sentiment will require both more political courage and more community tolerance than we have seen to date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0a6a89c96284aff250024f0220ea9d0</guid></item><item><title>'Another world is possible': Calls for unity at Winter Olympics opening</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/winter-olympics-opening-ceremony-live-blog/106305458</link><description>The 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics are here, launched in an historic opening ceremony held in a number of Italian locations simultaneously.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0991b17313ac249b3564bdd43d3536aa</guid></item><item><title>Former ambassador Ian Kemish writes about Europe's 'forgotten' war in debut novel Two Islands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/ian-kemish-ambassador-book-two-islands-balkan-war/106309626</link><description>Former ambassador Ian Kemish draws on his 25-year diplomatic career in his debut novel, Two Islands, set against the backdrop of the Balkan War.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05ef96597ffb663c7a85cc4469dd35e3</guid></item><item><title>Elders say truth-telling 'critical' to combatting racism after alleged terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/perth-first-nations-elders-call-for-truth-healing-and-justice/106314644</link><description>For Noongar Elders, the alleged attack on Boorloo/Perth is viewed against the background of a long history of violence. They are calling for a truth-telling commission to heal deep scars and help to combat racism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5a4e6692d897a27ad96d0fecbf58894</guid></item><item><title>ICC T20 World Cup: Everything you need to know and who to support as a neutral cricket fan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/cricket-t20-world-cup-ultimate-guide-who-to-support/106307782</link><description>As another T20 World Cup sneaks up on us, here's everything you need to know about the tournament, including a guide on how to pick which team to support, depending on your needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">244273c35ff46c6ce067b4171a530bce</guid></item><item><title>Vaibhav Sooryavanshi, India's 14-year-old batting prodigy, breaks records in Under-19 World Cup final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/vaibhav-sooryavanshi-india-14yo-world-cup-final/106316944</link><description>The 14-year-old prodigy Vaibhav Sooryavanshi breaks Alyssa Healy's record with the highest score ever in a World Cup final to power India to the global under-19 crown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9a291c39d2bac1693c6f902371b6cd0</guid></item><item><title>Meringandan collector sells vintage tractors, trucks, machines on Queensland farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/meringandan-collector-sells-vintage-tractors-trucks-machines-qld/106305032</link><description>As the last man standing, 78-year-old cattleman Mervyn has parted with his collection of tractors and utes, pledging his estate to charity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">467219dc24b07990a0bbb37f1d3c6d41</guid></item><item><title>Epstein files reaffirm even a conviction doesn't taint 'good bloke' status</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/jeffrey-epstein-good-character-reference/106307992</link><description>The rich and powerful were all too happy to stay connected to Jeffrey Epstein until it became the less convenient option.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ccb9e603f7a0840f1ddee0df072a838</guid></item><item><title>Australian athletes to watch at the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/aussies-to-watch-milano-cortina-winter-olympic-games-2026/106273742</link><description>Australia is taking its strongest ever team to the Winter Olympics in 2026, with a number of genuine medal chances. Here's a handful of the stars you need to pay attention to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bd59a489c46987c65b9466b27e8d05c</guid></item><item><title>Easy homemade granola that will last you weeks - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/easy-chunky-granola-with-nuts-and-seeds/105442842</link><description>When it comes to batch cooking, don't forget breakfast. This granola can make mornings easier and will last weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a385d3e380c821e791d0def365c56e1</guid></item><item><title>A 2026 Winter Olympics opening ceremony message of harmony and peace, rammed into a world of division</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/winter-olympics-2026-opening-ceremony-chilly-global-outlook/106316092</link><description>As the Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics Opening ceremony pleads a message of peace, the world outside the Olympic bubble burns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55c5f67fe73425a4675fe57a1c27a807</guid></item><item><title>Why 13yo Austin Appelbee's story of survival resonated so strongly across the globe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/austin-appelbee-quindalup-rescue-global-phenomenon/106306482</link><description>The remarkable story of Austin Appelbee's marathon swim for help went around the world, so why did it spark such an emotional reaction?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df0506ffba50ac7075d62dfa75270cd6</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 1, Saturday, February 7</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-day-one/106287722</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46c776b730057ca497c0c6b947cce9df</guid></item><item><title>Accused militant in deadly 2012 Benghazi attack on US compound taken into custody in United States</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/libyan-zubayar-al-bakoush-arrested-extradited-america/106317146</link><description>Zubayar Al-Bakoush, 58, has been wanted by the United States for more than a decade for his alleged role in the attack, which killed four Americans, including the US ambassador to Libya.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da4c915a8eb2989c66aa09d8ca9da2bc</guid></item><item><title>The Mark of Cain lead singer on a lifetime masking the truth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/the-mark-of-cain-lead-singer-josie-scott-transgender/106315830</link><description>The lead singer of legendary Adelaide rockers The Mark of Cain this week announced she was transgender, but it comes after nearly 60 years of hiding the truth from everyone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f38fc9591c45b6185b51090540bed25</guid></item><item><title>US prosecutors seek 46-month sentence for conspiracy theorist linked to Wieambilla killers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/wieambilla-shooting-daniel-day-sentencing/106317202</link><description>US prosecutors are seeking a sentence of almost four years for a conspiracy theorist linked to the trio behind the Wieambilla shooting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecaaafab7f7a654e969eb656226771fd</guid></item><item><title>Thailand election stakes are high as progressives mount new challenge against establishment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/thailand-election-stakes-high-as-progressives-mount-challenge/106312802</link><description>As Thailand prepares to head to the polls, voters remain wary that in their version of democracy, the party they vote for is not always the one that takes power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0569a9a2b0e10f4a080427f63b37d5b2</guid></item><item><title>What you need to know about skiing in Japan and how to keep yourself safe on the slopes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/how-to-keep-safe-skiing-and-snowboarding-in-japan/106310604</link><description>Australians flock to Japan each year to take advantage of its unique and plentiful snow, but it's not just the travel costs that are mounting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17215f0a9c755ba21ee9e86b1e92d22c</guid></item><item><title>Luigi Mangione speaks out against prospect of back-to-back trials over Brian Thompson's killing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/luigi-mangione-speaks-out-against-dual-state-and-federal-trials/106317270</link><description>Accused killer has spoken out in court against the prospect of back-to-back trials over the shooting of UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson, telling a judge "it's the same trial twice".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">390fec098a01b2229cd8a97c02e0ad2d</guid></item><item><title>Mayor of flood-hit Daly region accuses governments of inaction over long-term planning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/nt-long-term-flood-planning-victoria-daly-river-mayor/106317292</link><description>The Northern Territory and federal governments are being accused of failing to plan long term to protect Indigenous communities in the Victoria Daly region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86a569a8f6ddd8608406b0f482e4a898</guid></item><item><title>Latest Epstein files documents reveal links to multiple monarchies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/epstein-files-rock-global-monarchies/106316380</link><description>The latest release of the so-called Epstein files has revealed the convicted child sex offender was in contact with members of — and people close to — monarchies across Europe and the Middle East.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96f0f632ab3802486dbc61abcadd585b</guid></item><item><title>Why Wests Tigers hopeful Pat Herbert jumped off an excavator and into an NRL pre-season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/pat-herbert-nrl-wests-tigers-train-and-trial/106317620</link><description>After three years away from first grade, Pat Herbert was ready to get on with the rest of his life but a call from Wests Tigers got him off the job site and into an NRL pre-season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">916a7b8e20ff292d6a9e4fe1704fad62</guid></item><item><title>Aussie snowboarder Guseli finishes outside medals at Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/winter-olympics-day-one-live-blog-updates-guseli/106317886</link><description>Australia's Valentino Guseli falls short of reaching the podium in the men's snowboard big air final on day one of the Milano Cortino Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bcc9d97fc427e3a730c60850a929116</guid></item><item><title>If you could learn your baby's genetic disease risk at birth, would you?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/map-genome-dna-genetic-disease-newborn-screen/106305482</link><description>From rare cancers caught early to dementia foretold decades in advance, newborn genomic testing raises an unsettling question: Just because we can know, should we?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10b515034a68a9bbb421fb5da7cbb002</guid></item><item><title>How the Liberals will justify Sussan Ley's ousting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/sussan-ley-liberals-coalition-leadership-spill-angus-taylor/106295860</link><description>A permission structure has been crafted for Liberals to ditch the first woman to lead the federal party room before she has even had a year in the role.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bc84b8c3a351135cabe86c86fa06316</guid></item><item><title>Xavier Rudd on visiting Echuca, playing solo, and the spiritual being that follows him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/xavier-rudd-riverboats-tour-live-shows-solo/106299686</link><description>Xavier Rudd performs solo these days, but he carries a spirit with him wherever he goes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">524cef1858a02519f4777fc1222fcba8</guid></item><item><title>$203 million crackdown on dodgy doctors and advocates targeting veterans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/crackdown-on-doctors-advocates-targeting-veterans-fraud/106309512</link><description>Fraudsters taking advantage of people with disability now appear to be targeting veterans, prompting a $200 million crackdown by the federal government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7588808674a2c5aeb4db08c4ad599984</guid></item><item><title>After the uprising, Bangladesh returns to the ballot with its wounds still open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/bangladesh-returns-to-the-ballot-with-its-wounds-still-open/106296274</link><description>Bangladesh is heading back to the ballot box in what is being billed as its first free and fair election in more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8836801d915258a766ff8ef0bd45738e</guid></item><item><title>How Super Bowl half-time moments became flashpoints from the 'wardrobe malfunction' to caged kids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/super-bowl-half-time-show-janet-jackson-justin-timberlake/106307184</link><description>For a show that lasts roughly 13 minutes, the Super Bowl half-time performance has fuelled decades of conversation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5ff29a641957847844fbaf70655c0c1</guid></item><item><title>Australia's men and women unbeaten in Perth Sevens to set up semifinal opportunities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/australias-men-and-women-make-perfect-start-to-perth-sevens/106318568</link><description>Australia makes a hot start to the Rugby Sevens in Perth, with both the men's and women's teams going unbeaten in securing semifinal berths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efaad4c55d2717b9f28329c308b9b6f7</guid></item><item><title>As the West wakes up to the reality of the Epstein class, China plans a global reserve currency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/renminbi-global-reserve-currency/106317290</link><description>As the West reacts to the revelations in the latest batch of Epstein files, China has plans for the renminbi to become a global reserve currency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aacbcca5799241d0cad7000111351276</guid></item><item><title>United States send India a T20 World Cup scare before Suryakumar Yadav settles hosts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/india-survives-massive-scare-from-minnow-us-in-t20-world-cup/106318592</link><description>India is briefly left reeling at 6-67 against an underdog United States team, but captain Suryakumar Yadav helps the hosts avoid a horror start at the T20 World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b4cfa036b792e7378042063ed8c7311</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 day one quick hits: Mariah Carey accused of lip-syncing, Eileen Gu channels inner 'nerd'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/winter-olympics-2026-day-one-quick-hits/106318022</link><description>A Finnish skier makes a questionable fashion choice on the slopes, while Mariah Carey faces claims she was lip-syncing at the opening ceremony. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdbe8b25341547e8aee34f10f9adff31</guid></item><item><title>Seasonal Australian produce to make the most of in February</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/february-seasonal-fruit-and-veg/106308194</link><description>From grapes to red capsicum, here's how to prioritise some of this season's best fruit and veg.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5184a825d458dccc2d1d1b5d79ff1709</guid></item><item><title>Lee Lovell calls for expansion to victim of crime assistance as Queensland government makes almost $500 million in payments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/qld-victim-of-crime-payments-500-million-lee-lovell/106314616</link><description>The ABC can reveal the state government has paid almost $500 million to tens of thousands of victims of crime over the past three financial years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa487ea4337837a8f2fdf2b866171337</guid></item><item><title>How a Canberra-based refugee fled the Maduro regime along with millions of other Venezuelans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/act-how-a-venezuelan-fled-the-maduro-regime/106313290</link><description>Josh Madrid was arrested for attending a pro-democracy protest in Venezuela. 24 hours later, he fled his homeland, fearing he would be killed by the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d635939cd740a309d45cc1fc12ccddb7</guid></item><item><title>Coalition reunited after last-minute deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/deal-done-to-bring-coalition-back-together/102760848</link><description>The Liberals and Nationals have reached a breakthrough deal to reunite the Coalition after 11th-hour talks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03d631d89d350d9986b7badfae6006de</guid></item><item><title>Valentino Guseli missed out on a bonus 2026 Winter Olympics medal, but won something even more important</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/valentino-guseli-2026-winter-olympics-big-air-snowboard/106318724</link><description>It was 18 months ago that Valentino Guseli blew out his ACL attempting a backside 1800 at the Beijing big air. At the Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics snowboard big air final, he put that ghost to rest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6cb85fcb30e9b60ce1daa388c5f7d61</guid></item><item><title>3 Doors Down frontman Brad Arnold dies after stage four cancer battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/3-doors-down-frontman-brad-arnold-dies/106318798</link><description>Brad Arnold, a founder and the lead singer of American rock band 3 Doors Down, dies nine months after revealing he had kidney cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cbbceb57b53ce8d7ad340e98b862894</guid></item><item><title>Train delays in Italy during Winter Olympics opening weekend after damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/winter-olympics-italy-railway-sabotage-allegations/106318876</link><description>Police are investigating three incidents of damage on lines around Bologna, and have not ruled out a potential link to the Milan Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54f40c4b9d300363d1667f309b32f0dd</guid></item><item><title>Jim Chalmers says next federal budget will focus on lifting economy's 'speed limit'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/may-federal-budget-to-focus-on-lifting-speed-limit-on-economy/105435282</link><description>Treasurer Jim Chalmers says the federal government's budget in May will focus on productivity, spending restraint and tax reform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da4b1c57606aca371fd50217191fb699</guid></item><item><title>Equine photography in demand in Australian performance horse industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/equine-photography-in-demand-in-performance-horse-industry/106298426</link><description>From leaf blowers to dance moves, photographers use every trick they can think of to get the perfect shot for the biggest performance-horse sale in the southern hemisphere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22805fcce898863bfe3fedf070b53d08</guid></item><item><title>Palestine Action Group takes court action against extra police powers ahead of protests against Israeli president's Sydney visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/palestine-action-group-to-challenge-police-powers-herzog-visit/106319078</link><description>The Palestine Action Group lodged submissions late on Sunday afternoon, arguing the declaration was "draconian" and imposed rules unsuitable for protest activity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d620aa168abe72abd53aa441463941cb</guid></item><item><title>Payne Haas quits Brisbane to sign three-year deal with South Sydney Rabbitohs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/payne-haas-signs-with-south-sydney-for-2027/106319316</link><description>South Sydney have pulled off one of the biggest recruitment moves in NRL history after signing Brisbane enforcer Payne Haas to a three-year contract from 2027.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4006492fb182ade2ddeeb67451c5ec53</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian government says illegal tobacco sales crackdown will deliver some of the 'toughest' laws in the country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/tasmanian-illegal-tobacco-vapes-crackdown/106318886</link><description>The Tasmanian government announces increased penalties for those caught selling illegal tobacco products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abb1e0b80c97bfdd83a60a814abd6175</guid></item><item><title>In the Australian outback, we're listening for nuclear tests. What we hear matters more than ever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/australian-outback-nuclear-tests-listening-warramunga-facility/106307478</link><description>As the New START treaty curbing the US and Russian nuclear weapons programs expires, the work we do here in the red centre has become more important than ever before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0e5b08cded46dedfceb1992d9d6b4b6</guid></item><item><title>WA photographers reminisce about bygone Goldfields era as gold's price surges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/photographers-remember-bygone-era-wa-gold-prospecting/106299710</link><description>In 1989, two photographers travelled from Fremantle to Western Australia's Goldfields to capture the end of a gold mining era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83d7ae07fe11c173f4fe0efc06d5eacf</guid></item><item><title>Two Australians reach big air final after tense qualifying runs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/winter-olympics-day-two-live-blog-updates/106319558</link><description>Olympic medallist Tess Coady and fellow Australian Meila Stalker reach the snowboard big air final, after a dramatic day where American superstar Lindsey Vonn crashes in women's downhill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eabe2255ae86c9fbbf5b0a4f952c27ac</guid></item><item><title>Grandmother Bishnu Kumari Gurung killed as car ploughs into Perth home, family pays tribute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/bishnu-kumari-gurung-himali-killed-rivervale-house-crash/106319748</link><description>The family of a grandmother who died sleeping in bed when a car crashed into a Perth home pays tribute to her in an emotional press conference, after a man is charged with manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2de2519b4d66efba2a889f992fe3603d</guid></item><item><title>Lindsey Vonn's horror crash at the 2026 Winter Olympic Games was always on the cards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/lindsey-vonn-2026-winter-olympic-games-horror-downhill-crash/106319806</link><description>Lindsey Vonn's shocking downhill crash at the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games was always a possibility given the American was competing just nine days after rupturing her ACL. But it was never going to stop her from trying.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3298a9e82bd89310260dbbb7b476aef6</guid></item><item><title>Man extradited from Dubai to Moscow over top Russian general's shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/russian-general-shooting-dubai-moscow-extradition/106319910</link><description>Lieutenant General Vladimir Alexeyev is the deputy head of Russia's vast GRU military intelligence service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a718dd9de19d878789e384eddfec8f8</guid></item><item><title>Coalition's rushed reunification does not solve their respective branding problems</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/coalition-reunification-liberals-nationals-sussan-ley/106304664</link><description>The Coalition has reunited, but the new agreement does not address underlying party tensions nor the surging fragmentation of the right.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4015c0b9e86f13b0cbf1a5cc8413b8c5</guid></item><item><title>One Nation capitalises on anti-immigration sentiment in a housing crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/one-nation-pauline-hanson-housing-crisis-immigration/106304670</link><description>Pauline Hanson might not have any substantive policies, but her rhetoric about reducing migration is clearly finding an audience.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23968ca9459afcd8c2cf60c2582e68d7</guid></item><item><title>Telstra mobile tower sparks backlash in St Helens despite poor phone coverage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/st-helens-locals-concerns-about-telstra-phone-tower/106308180</link><description>It's known for fishing boats, a pristine coast, a skyline without a high-rise in sight — and notoriously patchy phone reception. So, a new phone tower would be welcome, you'd think.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53ab70f898080072416904e0da0192b7</guid></item><item><title>The Tasmania Devils start selling memberships later this month — how will they work?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/tasmania-devils-membership-reserved-seating-how-will-it-work/106315102</link><description>The Tasmania Devils will start signing up members later this month, but there's some confusion about what is required to secure a seat for AFL games in 2028. Here's how it will work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb0c918108d8e59c0b88b8f5e5d450ae</guid></item><item><title>Five simple steps to saving cash (while still having a life)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/finance-tips-saving-money-new-year/106303046</link><description>Saving money is not about beating yourself up. It's also not about depriving yourself of all sources of joy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59b760f5e77d65279a49b68106aa5c6d</guid></item><item><title>This week in history quiz, February 9: How well do you know the past?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/this-week-in-history-quiz/106276538</link><description>Groundhog Day, an audacious art theft and a new chief mouser: how well do you remember these events?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34b2c03bbdcecbeecdee865a592b0059</guid></item><item><title>Young people could get massive pay boost in 'totemic' wage case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/millions-of-young-people-could-get-massive-pay-boost-in-totemic/106101186</link><description>"I'm paying adult fuel with still a child's wage," says Ben Walker, one of the almost half a million young people who could see a huge boost to their wage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c8ac9ab718a2220257ac5a49545a466</guid></item><item><title>UK prime minister's chief of staff Morgan McSweeney quits amid Epstein fallout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/morgan-mcsweeney-resigns-epstein-mandelson/106320216</link><description>Sir Keir Starmer's leadership is under threat after revelations that one of his former US ambassadors had close ties with Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cee5f2015f6214e64864f3870d049084</guid></item><item><title>Japan PM Sanae Takaichi leads coalition to landslide election victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/japan-election-sanae-takaichi-landslide-victory/106320228</link><description>Sanae Takaichi's Liberal Democratic Party and its coalition partner are expected to hold upwards of two-thirds of the seats in Japan's lower house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fb71b428c5bbf7507c7f3ce7b77658c</guid></item><item><title>$740m veterans plan to fund social 'rehabilitation' and psychedelic treatments for PTSD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/veterans-funding-social-rehabilitation-mdma-ptsd/106309994</link><description>A $740 million program will expand support for veterans and include funding for social activities such as yoga and language classes, with new treatment including MDMA and psilocybin for the worst forms of PTSD also funded for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fae87a317eaabd51c41fe0364bba0f6b</guid></item><item><title>Ghislaine Maxwell to testify before US Congress as Epstein files reveal more about her role</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/epstein-files-spotlight-maxwells-role/106313368</link><description>This week, Ghislaine Maxwell could be a very unwelcome distraction for Donald Trump as she appears before one of America's top political institutions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d78d90e2cb3b37efeeb57864347d1e6</guid></item><item><title>Thailand PM Anutin Charnvirakul confident of forming government after election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/thailand-election-result-anutin-results/106320270</link><description>South-East Asia's second-largest economy went to the polls on Sunday in a tight race between conservatives aligned with the military and the monarchy, and progressive elements represented by the reform-driven People's Party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea445c2de3e44242cdf9e5b0f4e49cf0</guid></item><item><title>Investors driving up regional house prices with some buying sight unseen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/regional-housing-investors-driving-up-prices/106298600</link><description>Local buyers are facing stiff competition from outside investors, with regional house price rises tipped to continue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">580552bc67817077cc0f778f4d6c40d8</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Diamonds smash Jamaica again to seal three-game series in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/all-too-easy-for-the-diamonds-in-sealing-series-win-over-jamaica/106320414</link><description>Kate Moloney celebrates her 50-game milestone in style as the Australian Diamonds post a 32-goal victory over an understrength Jamaica in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17c58aaad7fd1ed71acafd10afe3d217</guid></item><item><title>Why Payne Haas's move from Brisbane to South Sydney changes the game for two NRL giants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/payne-haas-brisbane-broncos-south-sydney-nrl/106319624</link><description>Payne Haas's decision to leave Brisbane for South Sydney in 2027 didn't just shock the rugby league world, it transformed the futures of two of rugby league's most powerful clubs in an instant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3870c2c914c0402e56a618be411dd7e9</guid></item><item><title>Japanese prime minister confirms sweeping election win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/japanese-prime-minister-confirms-sweeping-election-win-/106320386</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">384bb30f1e8e2c1d75e666b3ce5bab10</guid></item><item><title>Businessman and bad gambler Sam Kanjo linked to Australia's biggest illegal tobacco fine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/sam-kanjo-linked-to-australias-biggest-illegal-tobacco-fine/106286014</link><description>He's been declared bankrupt repeatedly, and was a gambling addict. Now he's linked to a $1.5 million fine for illegal tobacco.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f50f644637f1f8f64249db0e52537e9</guid></item><item><title>Australia's women beaten by New Zealand in Perth Sevens final, but men claim bronze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/aussie-women-settle-for-perth-sevens-silver-new-zealand/106320454</link><description>The Australian women are forced to settle for silver at the Perth Sevens, while the Aussie men claim bronze in thrilling fashion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23861d2dad88948210d071dce4f97e17</guid></item><item><title>Bullying surges in ACT public schools as parents, teachers speak out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/bullying-reports-rise-in-act-public-schools/106269450</link><description>Reports of bullying in ACT public schools have risen sharply in four years. Parents and teachers say children are paying the price, and the system is not coping.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7cda36cd7ac7cd9196735a6516e4323</guid></item><item><title>ASX jumps 1.9 per cent in $60b rally, another Optus exec sacked — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-january-09/106319466</link><description>The ASX has recouped the losses of last week with a broad-based $60 billion rally.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1e7915364d79ad3062ddde2e4b76baa</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout opts out of Commonwealth Games as he seeks to follow in Usain Bolt's footsteps</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/gout-gout-out-commonwealth-games-usain-bolt/106320530</link><description>Sprint sensation Gout Gout pulls out of the Glasgow Commonwealth Games in a major blow to the Australian team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a577baa77f3c2a9c5823e922dfd5551</guid></item><item><title>Israeli President Isaac Herzog tells Sydney event antisemitism has been 'festering' in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/nsw-sydney-israeli-president-isaac-herzog-lands-bondi-attack/106320482</link><description>Isaac Herzog was invited by the governor-general and prime minister to join the Jewish community grieving the loss of life in the December 14 massacre of mostly Jewish Australians at a Hanukkah event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8477437267014ce2c5d1873b72d0a6d</guid></item><item><title>As AFL prepares to reboot State of Origin, there are hopes it can capture the imagination of a new generation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/afl-state-of-origin-game-does-it-have-place-in-modern-footy/105781418</link><description>The AFL is about to reboot the State of Origin concept, with the clash between Western Australia and Victoria at Perth Stadium next Saturday — on Valentine's Day — set to show if there's any love left for the idea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c46379064496246d0108e4942b1d209</guid></item><item><title>Explain the Internet: Why Wuthering Heights is one of the year's most controversial adaptations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/wuthering-heights-controversy-emerald-fennell-jacob-elordi/106305404</link><description>Days away from the release of Emerald Fennell's highly anticipated adaptation of Emily Brontë's classic novel, critics and fans alike are still fighting about text fidelity in the comments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51691c38c09e7e812fe2f8ae70e9ae0d</guid></item><item><title>Deua River Valley and Cobargo still rebuilding six years after Black Summer bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/cobargo-deua-river-still-rebuilding-after-black-summer-bushfires/106273804</link><description>Residents who lived through the 2019-20 bushfires on the NSW South Coast say this summer's fires triggered traumatic memories, and highlighted the recovery and resilience projects that remain unfinished.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75a6395d574e8ce915a53455bd5abe17</guid></item><item><title>Liberals despair at prospect of 'non-existence' and weigh leadership change after catastrophic Newspoll</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/liberals-despair-after-disastrous-poll-weigh-sussan-ley-spill/106320642</link><description>Sussan Ley could face a challenge to her leadership from Angus Taylor this week after a disastrous opinion poll showed the Coalition parties falling further behind One Nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d6794b583bc82ebb66b82a29f4dee89</guid></item><item><title>Aussie stars as Seahawks use ferocious defence to claim Super Bowl win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/super-bowl-lx-live-blog-seahawks-vs-patriots-bad-bunny/106320762</link><description>The Seattle Seahawks overawe the New England Patriots in Super Bowl LX as punter Michael Dickson becomes the second ever Australian NFL champion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fad6557763c143875756ac2daf86b7c</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Lindsey Vonn breaks her leg, Breezy Johnson breaks her gold medal — quick hits from day two</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/winter-olympics-2026-day-two-quick-hits-lindsey-vonn/106319962</link><description>US great Lindsey Vonn breaks her leg, and her compatriot breaks her gold medal as Tess Coady sneaks through to the final after a nervous wait on the bubble. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">271eb82bfbfbeb3c22aa7602ccb93659</guid></item><item><title>Cyclists slam 'nightmare' shared path at new Sydney Fish Market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/cyclists-slam-shared-path-at-new-sydney-fish-market/106307556</link><description>The decision to put a shared bike path in front of the new Sydney Fish Market is causing a clash between commuter cyclists and visitors to the site, riders say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53e99d860ab88303dcd0b2c2dabf0a99</guid></item><item><title>Live: Protesters clash with police in Sydney amid chants of 'we will march'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/isaac-herzog-to-visit-israel-president-bondi-attacks/106320994</link><description>Thousands of people have gathered across Australia to protest the visit of Israeli President Isaac Herzog. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0cf37da38773a17a6f3be276ce40f06</guid></item><item><title>Backyard pods won't fix the housing crisis but they signal a shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/backyard-pods-wont-fix-the-housing-crisis/106314472</link><description>Australia's biggest hardware retailer has started selling tiny homes. Are backyard pods the answer to a national housing crisis?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dd2b8a3992ec554b10d8b236bba7c64</guid></item><item><title>Iran sentences Nobel Peace Prize winner Narges Mohammadi to six more years in prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/nobel-peace-laureate-narges-mohammadi-sentenced-iran/106314130</link><description>Women's rights activist Narges Mohammadi is sentenced to a further six years in jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a361ee5a20a3e359c2b25fbca523621</guid></item><item><title>Broome North Primary School students swelter through wet season with broken air conditioning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/broome-school-air-conditioning-issues/106314502</link><description>Classroom temperatures at Broome North Primary School in the Kimberley are reportedly pushing 30 degrees, with long-reported air conditioning breakdowns yet to be fixed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e74e6078bd7ccad5c759b5dfabc6f7a</guid></item><item><title>Laura Tingle says Herzog visit links Israel's actions with antisemitism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/laura-tingle-says-herzog-visit-links-israel-s-actions/106321346</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5abb16cc18541b821c47d76abcaa06b4</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 3, Monday, February 9</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-holly-harris-jason-chan/106307460</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b8f3992831865843a3ea28399b9cf1f</guid></item><item><title>HESTA CEO Debby Blakey resigns after superannuation administration outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/hesta-superannuation-ceo-debby-blakey-resigns/106321478</link><description>HESTA's boss is calling it quits after 11 years in the role. Her exit follows an outage that left members unable to access their accounts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2aa4f7459e81fc5b96c6dfeaeae7d5b</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Lindsey Vonn hailed as 'idol' by downhill rivals after Milano Cortina crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/winter-olympics-rivals-pay-credit-to-lindsey-vonn/106320254</link><description>Lindsey Vonn's 2026 Winter Olympic Games ended in disaster, but her teammates and rivals have heaped praise on the three-time Olympic medallist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d1e30943c1086fc7cce481c2af84273</guid></item><item><title>Jon Kudelka, Walkley-winning Tasmanian cartoonist, dies from brain cancer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/jon-kudelka-tasmanian-cartoonist-dies/106321714</link><description>Award-winning Tasmanian cartoonist Jon Kudelka dies after being diagnosed with brain cancer in 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b64794da6dd1ff79a97006ebfd7d1f1b</guid></item><item><title>Christchurch terrorist gives testimony in NZ appeal court as he attempts to vacate guilty pleas over 2019 attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/christchurch-terrorist-in-court-of-appeal/106320628</link><description>The convicted Christchurch terrorist and murderer is giving testimony in the New Zealand Court of Appeal as he seeks to vacate his guilty pleas over his 2019 attack on two mosques.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7059761925b534c1c89ac119dab5a9e9</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong media mogul Jimmy Lai sentenced to 20 years in landmark case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/hong-kong-media-mogul-jimmy-lai-sentenced-to-20-years-jail/106321070</link><description>Jimmy Lai, one of Hong Kong's most outspoken critics of China, has learned his fate after being sentenced this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03525059e67690dbcf8a35c0db81456f</guid></item><item><title>Independent inquiry launched into NACC chief's handling of defence ties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/independent-inquiry-launched-into-nacc-chief-defence-ties/106320954</link><description>The body responsible for holding the federal integrity watchdog to account will formally investigate it for agency maladministration and its chief, Paul Brereton, for officer misconduct.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9eb72c36c774cffcae6b73bcb70d699</guid></item><item><title>Mitchell Freeway head-on crash in Butler leaves two dead after ute driven on wrong side of road</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/two-people-dead-after-mitchell-freeway-butler-head-on-crash/106321408</link><description>A 56-year-old-woman and a 24-year-old man are dead after a head-on collision involving a utility that was being driven on the wrong side of the Mitchell Freeway in Perth's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">366c71a2ba852d44551f4bb42a51335e</guid></item><item><title>Five simple, tasty vegetarian recipes that are perfect for meat-free Mondays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/five-simple-tasty-vegetarian-recipes-for-meat-free-monday/106309846</link><description>Looking to add some more vegetarian dishes to your weekly rotation? We have you covered with these five recipes that are perfect for meat-free Mondays.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8ccc6ae83e7b914cda93001f414be5d</guid></item><item><title>Queensland coroner hears father showed no concern for children caught in fatal house fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/fatal-queensland-house-fire-inquest/106322354</link><description>An inquest has started probing a fatal house fire, with a coroner tasked with trying to determine what sparked it and whether either parent may have been involved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78710984851c5b1a448311680b813808</guid></item><item><title>NFL Super Bowl LX quick hits: Mack Hollins dresses as a prisoner, Bad Bunny hosts a wedding and Michael Dickson's punts help Seattle Seahawks win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/nfl-super-bowl-lx-quick-hits-mack-hollins-bad-bunny-/106321254</link><description>The most important match of the NFL season crowns a champion, but also provides eye-catching moments on and off the field. Here are five quick hits from Super Bowl LX.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1dd04beb634bf19744e31966ae73569</guid></item><item><title>Dimitri D'Elio, Kylie Stott jailed for Christmas Eve killing of Charlie Gander in Bunbartha, Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/charlie-gander-dimitri-delio-murder-manslaughter-sentence/106320770</link><description>Charlie Gander’s body was found in a burnt-out car on a country road on Christmas Eve, 2022. Today, two people were sentenced to a combined 36 years in prison over his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d3f8fc30d2257d50cb749a40e84e872</guid></item><item><title>Family rallies to save pets left behind in Daly River flood evacuation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/family-creates-makeshift-animal-shelter-daly-river-flooding-nt/106319036</link><description>When hundreds of people evacuated the Daly River community due to flooding, most had to leave their pets behind. But a nearby family swung into action to help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a64bdce8d15fa7b49eb8035ac084d64d</guid></item><item><title>Bad Bunny's Super Bowl half-time show features surprise guests Lady Gaga and Ricky Martin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/bad-bunny-super-bowl-half-time-show-lady-gaga-ricky-martin/106321192</link><description>Global superstar Bad Bunny performs at the Super Bowl LX, sharing the stage with surprise guests Lady Gaga and Ricky Martin, while a couple weds on stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">991a08560eae442223c0026326bb6a2b</guid></item><item><title>Ben Batterham receives payout from NSW government for wrongful prosecution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/ben-batterham-gets-payout-from-state-for-wrongful-prosecution/106322122</link><description>A Newcastle man will receive a confidential payout from the NSW government for wrongful prosecution by police for an alleged home invasion murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6c1ff78372dd9ba63fb088e5a78ed5e</guid></item><item><title>SpaceX to build 'self-growing city' on Moon, Elon Musk says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/spacex-building-lunar-self-gowing-city-moon-elon-musk/106322472</link><description>Billionaire chief executive says the company will shift its focus from Mars and the project could be achieved within 10 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60090cd3e2417da1cd2217d495e8de23</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos captain Adam Reynolds announces retirement at end of NRL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/brisbane-broncos-captain-adam-reynolds-announces-nrl-retirement/106322932</link><description>Adam Reynolds will finish his stellar career at the end of the season after fulfilling his Broncos mission to perfection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">169322d9299a44e0989b53593be68e74</guid></item><item><title>Palestine Action Group loses court challenge to extra police powers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/palestine-action-group-loses-extra-police-powers-legal-battle/106320780</link><description>A Supreme Court challenge was launched by Palestine Action Group on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75d84690f8d9c2aec306eebd3c63f75c</guid></item><item><title>New gun ownership laws announced by Queensland Premier David Crisafulli</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/queensland-gun-laws-premier-bondi-response/106322868</link><description>The laws aim to crack down on rising gun crime and include tougher penalties for drive-by shootings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9e0505970320f994bd598f7cdc457d3</guid></item><item><title>Inside Minnesotan homes these people are hiding from ICE and living in fear for their children and parents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/inside-minnesota-familes-at-risk-from-ice-arrest-speak-out/106322022</link><description>What was once a hindrance is now "a paranoia like I've never known before", one Minnesotan man says, as his family hides from immigration agents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b02e0fe5c465309c1c3d7f4d3c6850a</guid></item><item><title>Daly River expected to surpass major flood level before reaching peak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/nt-daly-river-expected-to-reach-major-flood-level-today/106320860</link><description>Flooding at the Daly River community is expected to surpass the major flood level late Monday, with a peak of 14.1 metres expected by Tuesday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee956724ec301301f81352410e8d51f8</guid></item><item><title>Heavy rain in central Australia causes celebration and concern</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/heavy-rain-central-australia-causes-celebration-concern/106321708</link><description>Rain across central Australia has been welcomed at cattle stations, but flooding and road damage have cut off some remote communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f942437247ff1b6fcb96ff6e4bb6f47c</guid></item><item><title>Crocodile wrangler Matt Wright fined $10k for landing helicopter in backyard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/nt-outback-wranger-matt-wright-fined-landing-helicopter-backyard/106321446</link><description>The Netflix star, who is currently behind bars on unrelated charges, pleaded guilty to a single count for landing his chopper and taking off in the backyard of his former home in Darwin's rural area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a84969dedee4c7c55505ce6e58c62f1d</guid></item><item><title>Widespread protests against Israeli President Issac Herzog's visit to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/crowds-protest-israeli-president-isaac-herzog-in-australia/106321716</link><description>Thousands of people attend protests against Israeli President Isaac Herzog's visit to Australia in the wake of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf9c9e3b1bab97471914ed882c6b5903</guid></item><item><title>Heavy police presence at Sydney Town Hall as protesters gather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/heavy-police-presence-at-sydney-town-hall-as-protesters-gather/106323658</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6890622b1f36b1d8373ef68a68fcec15</guid></item><item><title>Another Optus tech 'issue' affects hundreds of thousands of customers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/optus-tech-issue-affects-customers-no-service/106323474</link><description>Optus says an issue is affecting mobile services for some customers, who are seeing "no service" or "SOS" on their device.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47d7fc7e21afa43e3c80749b4b4950a2</guid></item><item><title>Families of Laos methanol poisoning victims say they've been left in the dark on investigations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/laos-methanol-poisoining-bianca-jones-holly-morton-bowles/106321336</link><description>The families of Bianca Jones and Holly Morton-Bowles say they have been left in the dark following the 2024 poisoning deaths of their daughters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2580145a0bf20f8945a54bc153c8c054</guid></item><item><title>Sanae Takaichi's stomping victory will have profound consequences for Australia and the Asia-Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/japanese-pm-sanae-takaichi-s-election-victory/106323082</link><description>A stomping victory by the ruling coalition government of Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi has opened the way for a major geo-strategic realignment in the Asia-Pacific region, with big implications for Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65ca2c9fe328e0e0981fb58f90e534b5</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106323636</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">968ecebb9b9600345e1566ed32833449</guid></item><item><title>Protesters gather at Flinders Street Station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/protesters-gather-at-flinders-street-station/106323806</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">267a877d67f741c07ea235e2ab8c954b</guid></item><item><title>ASIO was told about Bondi shooter's terrorist links years before attack, former spy claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/bondi-shooting-spy-claims-told-asio-terror-links-four-corners/106306092</link><description>The former undercover agent spied on the Akrams when he infiltrated a Sydney IS terror cell for Australia's intelligence agency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38e7d75b35ff2d3c4a5b6be5b9bb9d73</guid></item><item><title>'Massive' Indonesian ghost barge washes up on tiny Torres Strait island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/mystery-indonesian-ghost-barge-washed-up-in-torres-strait/106323116</link><description>The barge drifted into Australian waters from Indonesia after breaking from its moorings during bad weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08b39ef063e5e2f00075ab3cf9dbea37</guid></item><item><title>Live: Freestyle skiing, snowboarding and Australian ice dance duo in action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/winter-olympics-day-two-live-blog-updates/106322542</link><description>Holly Harris and Jason Chan will become the first Aussies in 12 years to represent the country in ice dancing, while Tess Coady and Meila Stalker will compete in the big air final. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ab5c808eefcaa38bad83f2aee6e5fb7</guid></item><item><title>Shaun Dunk asks to be 'locked up' 15 days before alleged stabbing murder, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/shaun-dunk-asks-to-be-locked-up-weeks-before-alleged-murder/106323324</link><description>Fifteen days before he allegedly killed a woman and attempted to kill another, Shaun Michael Dunk asked to be taken into custody so he would not be a danger to anyone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">776a71d9c1219b80be2c49f508bed9c7</guid></item><item><title>Police and protesters clash at Sydney's Town Hall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/police-and-protesters-clash-at-sydney-s-town-hall-/106323954</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d617c31f1bfdae141ee155484c6f77c1</guid></item><item><title>Prince William and Kate say they are 'deeply concerned' about Epstein files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/prince-william-kate-epstein-deeply-concerned-statement/106323984</link><description>The Prince and Princess of Wales say their thoughts remain focused on the victims of the late sex offender Jeffrey Epstein, in their first statement on the issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d612c2a641317f685b27655f77ed980a</guid></item><item><title>Queensland health minister orders review of Toowoomba Hospital maternity unit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/toowoomba-hospital-maternity-unit-audit/106323798</link><description>Announcement comes after a woman reveals her support person was prevented from entering the birth suite while she was in labour by Toowoomba Hospital security.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99b063ed21a492a5f313bd8e1046e624</guid></item><item><title>Maritime safety regulator investigating luxury Carnival cruise ship after whistleblower concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/amsa-investigating-carnival-cruise-ship-exploitation-claims/106323754</link><description>The maritime union says crew members of a luxury Carnival cruise ship allege they are being made to sleep in crowded rooms, lack access to safe free drinking water, and that some are earning as little as $2.50 an hour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aac8562047e40499a73214ddcb3bb039</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth files defence against Linda Reynolds legal action in federal court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/commonwealth-files-defence-against-linda-reynolds-legal-action/106324034</link><description>The Commonwealth files its defence against former senator Linda Reynolds, who is suing the government and its lawyers over a $2.4 million payout it made to Brittany Higgins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">868917d636420ea166ce9e95e7cd1d3f</guid></item></channel></rss>