<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 22:56:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Community comes together to send Christmas cards to South Australian prisoners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/christmas-cards-spread-joy-to-adelaide-prisoners/106115156</link><description>Two Adelaide women have made it their mission to collect 2,000 Christmas cards for prisoners who'll spend this year's festive season behind bars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd31a6d423d4a5998190a2c09d0c385c</guid></item><item><title>Gaza named deadliest place for journalists in 2025 RSF report on dangers facing media globally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/gaza-named-deadliest-place-for-journalists-in-2025/106123004</link><description>Gaza has been named the deadliest place in the world to work as a journalist by French-based press freedom advocates Reporters Without Borders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5f9ba03199b188b75b459b67a38bd69</guid></item><item><title>Widespread rain across NSW to reduce threat of bushfires leading up to Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/widespread-rain-forecast-for-nsw-a-relief-for-bushfire-threats/106121526</link><description>The most widespread rain in three months will develop across New South Wales during the coming days, reducing the threat of bushfires in the lead-up to Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49da9ef067c2ff0b09f499e9525d7e9f</guid></item><item><title>Abuse survivors say Centrelink's 'couple rule' puts women in danger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/couple-rule-centrelink-income-test-concerns/106100196</link><description>Financial and domestic abuse survivors say the way Centrelink assesses benefit payments for people in a relationship makes it harder for women to leave dangerous relationships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df9ee2f41264eeace457f874b59e068c</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police charge 19yo over alleged grenade, gunfire attack at Tallawong home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/man-charged-over-grenade-gunfire-attack-tallawong-home/106123066</link><description>A 19-year-old is expected to front court on Wednesday after been charged over the alleged shooting at a Tallawong home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f35db945aa17061eea479523aebef76</guid></item><item><title>Scorchers take aim at Sixers ahead of WBBL semifinal after eliminating Stars in knockout final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/cricket-wbbl-scorchers-aim-at-sixers-after-beating-stars-final/106123136</link><description>The Perth Scorchers keep their WBBL title hopes alive with a win over the Stars in a knockout final, as youngster Chloe Ainsworth shows her credentials on the big stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68ef51afed024ed6a33a6d8c3ab91f31</guid></item><item><title>Taronga Zoo to 'rewild' cleared farmland in northern NSW with native Australian animals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/taronga-zoo-to-rewild-cleared-farmland-with-native-animals/106121552</link><description>Taronga Zoo has successfully bred native Australian animals for years — but it now has a vision on how to re-establish their populations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6c2a1e5a637e00e6fe97b1cdfef3359</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal group left without legal recourse without federal human rights act</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/wunna-nyiyaparli-title-fight-human-rights-act/106036872</link><description>Legal experts say Australia is lagging in its human rights approach and should adopt a federal human rights act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd168af02397f759e879efd42ef0044c</guid></item><item><title>Ten-year-old snake bite survivor gives back to community through cow sale</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/10-year-old-snake-bite-survivor-giving-back-to-community/106114456</link><description>This 10-year-old is selling her family's cows to help raise funds for those who rescued her when she suffered a potentially deadly snake bite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c8898cb976b32ba6705953d32764ac0</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Albanese says social media ban biggest 'cultural change' Australia has faced — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/federal-politics-live-blog-december-10/106120662</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese says Australia's social media ban will change lives as Australia takes "back control" from social media companies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1ff720287ed0c2f11b929cfb5ed3724</guid></item><item><title>Markets live: ASX falls and Wall Street cautious ahead of likely US rate cut decision — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/asx-markets-business-live-news/106123228</link><description>The Australian share market has fallen slightly on a mostly flat day, following a cautious performance on Wall Street as the US Federal Reserve decides whether to cut interest rates. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">549bc1efccb37c60046b791c696abee0</guid></item><item><title>US judge approves release of grand jury documents against Ghislaine Maxwell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/us-judge-approves-release-of-documents-against-ghislaine-maxwell/106123122</link><description>The judge grants the Justice Department's request under a new law requiring the release of files related to Jeffrey Epstein and Ghislaine Maxwell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">debcadced8c2241d8734bcafbc24d8e9</guid></item><item><title>Why is Elon Musk fighting with the European Union over social media platform X?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/elon-musk-fighting-with-european-union-over-x/106117886</link><description>The latest target of Elon Musk's ire is the European Union, which he has called a "bureaucratic monster" that "should be abolished". So, what's going on?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ead87207d43858d0d334a7337c9b1679</guid></item><item><title>UN Working Group on Arbitrary Detention denied visits to NT prisons, meetings with government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/nt-un-denied-visit-to-prisons-clp-finocchiaro-government-jails/106121438</link><description>The number of people in custody has surged dramatically in the Northern Territory since the government passed sweeping bail and justice reforms in 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd957cf18cc79ea1e7c54bbb336f059c</guid></item><item><title>Mayhem at Brisbane Lady Gaga concert as long queues blamed on 'technical issues'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/fans-report-waiting-hours-to-get-into-brisbane-lady-gaga-concert/106122524</link><description>The stadium says "technical issues" identified during a sound check meant the gates did not open until 50 minutes later than scheduled, which caused long queues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b49b600c553349c4191db9c0fcf5ad5f</guid></item><item><title>South Africa dismissed for its lowest ever T20 score as India sends ominous message to rivals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/cricket-south-africa-lowest-t20-score-india-world-cup-rematch/106123238</link><description>The rematch of last year's T20 World Cup final is dominated by India as South Africa is dismissed for just 74 runs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e17db46b43fe455f0053c869e6f32bb</guid></item><item><title>Report finds 'shockingly low' government spend on preventing child removals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/snaicc-family-matters-report-calls-for-investment-in-prevention/106114764</link><description>Only 15.6 per cent of national child protection funding goes towards family support services aimed at keeping families intact, a report has found. Advocates are urging the government to "invest in families, not crisis".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1544693c4556d3b47c92547a3625a01</guid></item><item><title>'Integrity' of environmental approvals questioned in WA government's attempt to balance nature and industry in new laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/state-development-laws-wa-analysis/106119780</link><description>As WA's state development laws make their way through parliament, critics are worried about environmental approvals and concentration of power, but the government insists the changes mean more transparency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a2c6a5a4c2925cd9dd74ff67db7c18e</guid></item><item><title>Pet cam captures bull and horse sneaking into home of NT politician Andrew Mackay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/dogs-let-bull-and-horse-to-enter-nt-politicians-home/106118568</link><description>An NT resident tells of discovering he had unexpected guests in his home, after his dogs were filmed nudging open a door and letting inside a pet bull and horse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9537621f3ff0b957105d2fb27fec790d</guid></item><item><title>Volunteer WA firefighter with rare and aggressive cancer calls for compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/volunteer-firefighter-fighting-cancer-calls-for-compensation/106054572</link><description>Matthew Petch says firefighters like him are being left behind by an outdated compensation scheme and a lack of health screening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cdcb02a9468eb0fac75e6784d411e21</guid></item><item><title>Hannah Wilson has quit medicinal cannabis but has been relentlessly targeted by advertisements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/how-cannabis-companies-exploit-australias-legal-loopholes/106074556</link><description>Hannah Wilson says she found it shockingly easy to obtain a medicinal cannabis prescription, despite her history of schizophrenic psychosis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed85e20d31c6a635d841a3adababa780</guid></item><item><title>Formal complaint filed to FIFA over Gianni Infantino's peace prize awarded to US president Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/complaint-filed-to-fifa-over-peace-prize-awarded-to-donald-trump/106123358</link><description>A human rights organisation files an official complaint to FIFA over its peace prize awarded to US President Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e14bd5d331879d3b0f8004d5d410ade9</guid></item><item><title>Unknown number of homes and buildings destroyed in Capertee Valley bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/capertee-bushfire-homes-destroyed/106123214</link><description>An unknown number of unoccupied homes and buildings have been destroyed in a bushfire burning in NSW's Capertee Valley near Lithgow. A high fire danger warning remains in place with conditions expected to get worse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1e4c1d47fa5d6c932a8b7894dcb532e</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian ministers access $45,000 in free NBL and AFL tickets in a year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/tas-gift-registry-for-politicians-published/106119614</link><description>Tasmanian government ministers have accessed more than $21,000 of free tickets to Tasmania JackJumpers games in the past 12 months, available as part of an agreement with the basketball club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ea0ae056c66fbc39dd6bff1d95c87c2</guid></item><item><title>Rare brain illness could not stop Milly from making country netball history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/milly-brock-tongala-netball-encephalitis/106098456</link><description>A rare brain illness left Milly Brock unable to walk or speak, but eight months later, she was back leading her regional netball club on grand final day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">821bba383f0020f9d6f99b0b9a15f322</guid></item><item><title>Sydney lawyer Sylvan Singh charged with alleged attempts to import drugs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/sydney-lawyer-sylvan-singh-charged-shooting-drug-importation/106123490</link><description>Solicitor Sylvan Singh, 26, is granted bail after being charged with four counts of attempting to import a commercial quantity of drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4d90537381dcbf1049bd12e1e2ea7b7</guid></item><item><title>In Data Dreams: Art and AI at the MCA, 10 artists explore the impact of AI on contemporary life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/data-dreams-art-and-ai-mca-sydney-christopher-kulendran-thomas/106115358</link><description>Can you tell what's real and what's fake online? Data Dreams: Art and AI at the MCA, featuring a Kim Kardashian deepfake, looks at the impact of AI on everyday life</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6da8bd58bdbf5d37f5aac827b55e6a1</guid></item><item><title>Union votes for correctional officers to continue strike, leaving prisoners in SA locked down indefinitely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/sa-prisons-remain-locked-down-indefinitely/106123454</link><description>The union representing correctional officers has voted to strike indefinitely, while officers who monitor 1,500 people on home detention will stop work for 24 hours</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de83151db4cfaac739301d3b4df83317</guid></item><item><title>Dancing gorilla wins Comedy Wildlife Photo Awards 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/wildlife-comedy-photo-awards-winners-2025/106123480</link><description>The winning images pair talented nature photography with humour that often relies on capturing a moment at just the right time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50aafd52b8ccb489374be2add3c97440</guid></item><item><title>Wells says 'gut reaction' to travel claims fair but she has 'upheld' rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/anika-wells-gut-reaction-travel-expense-rules/106118512</link><description>Communications and Sports Minister Anika Wells accepts her taxpayer-funded travel claims have prompted a "gut reaction" in people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b44d2a73090ecce02214e2201b1dfe7e</guid></item><item><title>Man found 'hiding underwater' after Beenleigh fatal shooting charged with murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/qld-man-charged-with-murder-after-beenleigh-fatal-shooting/106124016</link><description>Police have charged 22-year-old Paul Tagirara over a fatal shooting in Beenleigh, south of Brisbane, earlier this month which claimed the life of a 35-year-old man.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">029ce655ad188b4cbebcc8652fb489d7</guid></item><item><title>Testing on supermarket imported honey finds some is not all honey</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/testing-finds-some-imported-honey-not-honey/106119344</link><description>Australian beekeepers are funding their own investigation into the authenticity of imported honey, with tests showing other products are being added.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a452fb7b1b2545a83a7b102f3a342b2</guid></item><item><title>Crucial koala corridors are dwindling in Sydney's south-west, conservationists warn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/koala-corridors-under-threat-in-sydney-conservationists-warn/106099774</link><description>Key wildlife links between two of Sydney's major rivers are under threat from land clearing for housing, according to a koala conservation group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f91af6ff105daa364b7ab66152f69f9a</guid></item><item><title>Mother whose son died after deliberately-lit house fire in Sydney says 'life is precious'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/arthur-haines-house-fire-manslaughter-mother-victim-impact/106124786</link><description>The mother of a teenager who was killed in a deliberately-lit house fire has told a Sydney court her son taught her "life is so precious" and she longed to be with him again for the rest of her days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db28f1e4f8b6f53849fe0a5cbf6f9a1c</guid></item><item><title>AI to be trialled at Royal Perth Hospital in bid to reduce pressure on WA health system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/wa-health-system-turns-to-ai-in-bid-to-free-up-doctors-nurses/106124964</link><description>A trial of artificial intelligence at Royal Perth Hospital is announced in an attempt to help health workers focus on patient care, as new data reveals WA's emergency departments are among the most stretched in the nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">916420c5a5be3e9614bebad33b7e6ec3</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste remembers Indonesian invasion 50 years after military assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/timor-leste-invasion-indonesia-anniversary/106118850</link><description>Survivors still have clear memories of the invasion by Indonesia, as Timor-Leste this week commemorates the beginning of a brutal 24-year occupation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb2d22cb023e1625be40a01636cd7005</guid></item><item><title>Taliban arrests young men in Afghanistan for Peaky Blinders dress-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/taliban-arrests-afghan-men-for-peaky-blinders-dress-up/106119104</link><description>Morality police in Afghanistan detain several influencers who have gone viral for dressing up as 1920s gangsters in the style of BBC series Peaky Blinders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b60e2a3095ffcf14564a6d30d3f6b72f</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne nutrition influencer died from postpartum haemorrhage after freebirth, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/stacey-warnecke-free-birth-death-coroner-investigates/106124514</link><description>A coroner's court has heard Melbourne nutrition influencer Stacey Warnecke died from a postpartum haemorrhage following a freebirth in September.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5cfcb104032fdb91e4e566b5242f6c8</guid></item><item><title>Four more teenagers charged over stabbing at Ellenbrook Secondary College</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/ellenbrook-school-stabbing-three-more-teenagers-charged/106125770</link><description>A 10th teenager is charged over an alleged premeditated gang attack at Ellenbrook Secondary College on Monday that left a student with stab wounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3bdb120f5abcc8527b2d16b44b6ac22</guid></item><item><title>From peacekeeping in Timor-Leste to PTSD in Afghanistan: The beauty and terror of being an official war artist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/being-an-official-war-artist/106074572</link><description>Australia has been sending artists to the frontline since World War I, with more than 50 local artists taking part since then. But what's it actually like to head into war armed with a paintbrush?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0869c324d87322e512f070bec50429fd</guid></item><item><title>To-do list, travel plans found during Luigi Mangione arrest revealed in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/to-do-list-travel-plans-luigi-mangione-arrest-court/106125418</link><description>A to-do list and travel plans shed light on the steps the 27-year-old may have taken — or planned to take — to avoid capture after UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson's killing last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc92e74ed867d6535763e8a1031721ea</guid></item><item><title>Alex Volkanovski hoses down retirement rumours ahead of first UFC title defence on Australian soil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/alex-volkanovski-ufc-325-diego-lopes-fight/106125956</link><description>Alex Volkanovski hoses down retirement rumours ahead of his first hometown fight in almost a decade with Australia's greatest ever UFC fighter aiming for another lengthy run defending the featherweight title.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75fbbb1fadea9b7e6985f043af6c40aa</guid></item><item><title>WA opposition blames police staffing levels for slow response to Boulder ambulance emergency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/wa-opposition-blames-police-numbers-for-slow-ambulance-response/106119620</link><description>The WA Liberals say a slow police response to a violent incident involving St John Ambulance officers in the Goldfields is due to understaffing but the claim has been rejected by the police minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89a501a2552c0abb67b6dad738e4d227</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's bushfire danger arrived suddenly. Here's how to prepare</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/tasmania-bushfire-preparation-explainer-what-to-do/106125742</link><description>Tasmania's bushfire season has suddenly arrived, with two catastrophes within days of each other. Here is how to prepare if one comes your way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b16253a54f55c77704f587d31bb4f7d</guid></item><item><title>Children as young as 10 could be fitted with ankle monitors under proposed Queensland laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/queensland-proposed-laws-crime-children-ankle-monitors/106126136</link><description>The legislation removes the requirement for either the child, or their parent or guardian, to consent to wearing the device.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5f1ff9a7a6110c8e573a7b919ca2410</guid></item><item><title>Defence briefs Pacific nations on China's naval flotilla but 'final destination' unknown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/australia-briefs-pacific-nations-chinese-navy-flotilla/106125002</link><description>Australian Defence officials have been briefing Pacific nations about the formidable capabilities and weaponry of a Chinese naval flotilla in the region, which the ADF is continuing to monitor closely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db439db52988340f905c0e260d1bb3ff</guid></item><item><title>Halls Creek man arrested after allegedly selling $45k worth of alcohol in dry WA communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/halls-creek-alcohol-sly-grogging-money-laundering-charge/106126488</link><description>The man allegedly bought large quantities of beer, champagne and rum in Darwin before selling it in WA's Kimberley region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2051a7f7ce917ea09a9f94d88ea4d89</guid></item><item><title>Victim statements redacted in 2014 fatal SA freeway crash court hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/south-eastern-freeway-fatal-crash-victim-impact-statements/106126356</link><description>The daughters of a man who died in a truck crash at the bottom of the South-Eastern Freeway in 2014 have their heavily redacted victim impact statements read aloud in court, more than 11 years after their father died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1dc19e37a9e8742d452e5c79fcaebad</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of men march against domestic violence in Alice Springs on Human Rights Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/hundreds-of-men-march-against-domestic-violence-alice-springs-/106126534</link><description>Up to 300 men — and a similar number of women — have taken part in the annual Ingkintja Men's March Against Domestic Violence under the slogan End the silence! Stop the violence! in Alice Springs, coinciding with the International Human Rights Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afb9de3eaad61b077c62d7b9feab54d1</guid></item><item><title>Age verification errors see some under-16s retain access to banned social media platforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/social-media-ban-day-one-teen-access/106126706</link><description>It's day one of the social media ban, but dozens of parents have told the ABC their children have already been able to get around the restrictions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24031d86565b1c6820fd19fd4b8bb05b</guid></item><item><title>New order banning supply of NSW North Coast green prawns a 'death knell' for industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/five-year-ban-on-nsw-raw-prawn-supply-due-to-white-spot-disease/106123412</link><description>White spot disease in prawns has led the NSW government to issue a new, five-year control order which will ban the sale of green prawns caught in affected waters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49297718e7446a4d6c754181c2e15c1d</guid></item><item><title>New crocodile management plan draws mixed response in north Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/north-queenslanders-split-over-new-crocodile-management-plan/106125448</link><description>The new management plan sees the expansion of crocodile removal zones across north and far north Queensland. Some say it will not increase safety without better community education.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d527c03e914a223eb5eb665d7dd0aa2</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106127258</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e85aeff20efe1d71f9c55706e4551a44</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne expect to land former number one AFLW draft pick Kristie-Lee Weston-Turner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/north-melbourne-aflw-former-number-one-pick/106127740</link><description>North Melbourne have been unable to trade for Kristie-Lee Weston-Turner but the two-time defending AFLW premiers are still confident they'll secure the former number one draft pick.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ea6b8b1cac99bb7b87d916611cd573f</guid></item><item><title>Climate crisis is threatening disabled Australians' access to nature</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/climate-crisis-access-to-nature-disability/106116294</link><description>From bushfires and decreasing air quality to flooding and erosion, climate change is threatening our relationship with nature, and people with disability are being disproportionately impacted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e6030aecdfc7bd4bfb090bffc4c8061</guid></item><item><title>Inquest into toddler's septic tank death sparks calls for improved maintenance in remote NT public housing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/septic-tank-death-kumanjayi-fly-public-housing-coronial-inquest/106118886</link><description>Aboriginal housing advocates are calling for urgent improvements to the way remote public housing is maintained in the Northern Territory, after the coroner found the death of a toddler who fell into a backyard septic tank could have been prevented.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">caec77585ea2e595da2a95f4e9e2f192</guid></item><item><title>Australia records highest number of Indigenous deaths in custody since 1979</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/largest-number-of-indigenous-deaths-in-custody-since-1979/106121828</link><description>Australia has recorded the highest number of Indigenous deaths in custody since 1979. Experts say over-incarceration remains a national crisis and prisons are neglecting the physical and mental health of vulnerable people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beaf475b8b27faa178ef96c69cf1409b</guid></item><item><title>Marco Rubio orders US State Department to revert to Times New Roman font, calling Calibri adoption 'wasteful'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/us-state-department-reverts-times-new-roman-font/106127732</link><description>In a leaked internal cable, Secretary of State Marco Rubio calls the department's decision to adopt Calibri in 2023 a "wasteful" diversity move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f98705a0075c776b00b9cb6290441f9</guid></item><item><title>US backs Japan in dispute with China over radar incident as tensions escalate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/us-backs-japan-in-dispute-with-china-over-radar-incident/106128020</link><description>China and Japan have given differing accounts of the incident, which was a major escalation in tensions between the two nations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f7c862084fd730289846293bc733530</guid></item><item><title>Nearly 200 children conceived from sperm donor with increased cancer risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/children-conceived-from-sperm-with-cancer-risk/106128026</link><description>Between 2006 and 2022, the man's sperm was sold to 67 clinics in 14 countries, whereas 99 children were fathered by the donor in Denmark alone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cd952c66ea268a278bb59c7d05297ca</guid></item><item><title>US plans to order foreign tourists, including Australians, to disclose social media histories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/white-house-plans-social-media-requirement-visa-exempt-countries/106128022</link><description>Applicants would also have to submit phone numbers, email addresses, personal details of family members and biometric information under the plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91b5c6ed58ba5307414ebb7f60b53bb4</guid></item><item><title>Half a million people flee Thailand–Cambodia border conflict as Trump moves to intervene again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/half-a-million-people-flee-thailand-cambodia-border-conflict/106128158</link><description>Thailand has rejected Donald Trump's plan to call both sides to achieve peace, with half a million people forced to flee the fighting along the border.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2187d0404028679ddc4bb7ef75216c4e</guid></item><item><title>Sophie Kinsella, author of the best-selling Shopaholic novels, dies at 55</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/sophie-kinsella-author-of-shopaholic-book-series-dies-aged-55/106128174</link><description>Kinsella, who also published under her real name, Madeleine Wickham, announced in April 2024 that she had been diagnosed in late 2022 with glioblastoma, an aggressive form of brain cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5df3ad8902d66540f2d3c6b1a47afb4</guid></item><item><title>Democracies must fight for freedom, Nobel Peace Prize laureate Machado says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/democracies-must-fight-for-freedom-nobel-peace-prize-machado/106128196</link><description>Democracies must be prepared to fight for freedom in order to survive, Nobel Peace Prize laureate and Venezuelan opposition leader María Corina Machado says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a802fb115dd97304b5ad35f3a4d04cf9</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 11: How a van full of armed men and millions of dollars inspired Goodfellas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/today-in-history-december-11-lufthansa-heist/106116722</link><description>It has been almost 50 years since armed men burst into the Lufthansa cargo terminal at New York's John F Kennedy International Airport and got away with stealing millions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa60e0fd4333897c002bc02951aff74a</guid></item><item><title>Landmark case aims to force betting agencies to return gambled stolen millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/case-seeks-to-recover-gambled-stolen-millions-from-bookmakers/106127214</link><description>A landmark legal case against three of Australia's biggest online betting agencies has been filed in the Federal Court, aimed at recovering millions of dollars' worth of stolen money that was gambled away and kept by corporate bookmakers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdbffe5eb41d9639002ebac899132190</guid></item><item><title>Nationals MP's high family travel bill highlights generous rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/nationals-mps-high-family-travel-bill-highlights-generous-rules/106126842</link><description>Calls for politicians' family travel entitlements to be tightened are growing, as analysis shows one Nationals MP was allowed to charge taxpayers more than $80,000 to fly his spouse to and from Canberra 27 times in two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7e02c292ccefc5d6bca00c1bf777cbb</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's bushfires may be an indication of what's to come this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/tasmania-summer-bushfire-drivers-and-outlook-bom/106126762</link><description>Just days into summer, Tasmania is battling bushfires and their presence can be linked back to a rare spike in temperatures above Antarctica back in September.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc7f21634c642fd281ef2a19b45bb506</guid></item><item><title>Why Ashton Hurn may, or may not, succeed as SA Liberal leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/ashton-hurn-vs-peter-malinauskas-election/106115114</link><description>Ashton Hurn now has the job she said she didn't want. Could she be the leader the South Australian Liberal Party needs?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09d86e9573dbb3d47b5534e04b272ccf</guid></item><item><title>Third time is the charm as long-running soap opera Neighbours wraps up, again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/tv-neighbours-ends-again/106127164</link><description>After more than 40 years on air, the final credits will roll on the iconic soap Neighbours — again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9294b4c1ba5afc18d168fbb6beb71c5a</guid></item><item><title>NSW government acquires two outback stations to convert into national parks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/corinya-and-tasman-stations-to-be-converted-into-national-parks/106125500</link><description>Two outback stations 800 kilometres west of Sydney are purchased by the state government in an effort to protect the environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e08563b4690939a2d3bb0a924a889be</guid></item><item><title>Australia's education system 'highly segregated' says former minister Susan Close</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/susan-close-on-socio-economic-divide-in-schools/106126084</link><description>South Australia's former deputy premier Susan Close has called out what she describes as "extreme" socio-economic segregation in Australian schools.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0a681652a4d06ad13dadca8a80d4be4</guid></item><item><title>Australia's grand social media experiment is finally live. Teens say nothing has changed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/social-media-ban-under-16s-day-one/106120020</link><description>After a year of waiting, Australia's world-leading laws to block kids from accessing social media are officially enacted. But the teens they're meant to impact say not much has actually changed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">605110735879eabae4a76f4e3ea6f4d8</guid></item><item><title>Fears of 'another Cronulla riot' 20 years on from violence at beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/fears-of-another-cronulla-riot-20-years-on-from-sydney-fights/106120526</link><description>Two decades on from the racially-fuelled brawls at Cronulla, experts warn something similar could happen amid anti-immigration rhetoric.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">530eb8b1f8a7882b31e610972e8f7881</guid></item><item><title>Households now need six-figure income to comfortably rent in any capital city</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/qld-rental-prices-data-six-figure-income/106126784</link><description>The average income needed to comfortably rent a median-priced home in any Australian capital city is now more than $112,000, according to new analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0f4eb594289999d4b1f9675bab6d71c</guid></item><item><title>National Library of Australia reveals its treasures with exhibition showcasing books from throughout history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/national-library-australia-exhibition-reveals-treasures/106126192</link><description>The NLA has more than 10 million items, but they are all in storage. Now a new exhibition reveals a selection of its hidden treasures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">225fb88ccc28e7fd81c2aa21f6d60d91</guid></item><item><title>US Republicans and Democrats push for Australian-style kids' social media ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/us-republicans-democrats-praise-australias-u16-social-media-ban/106128242</link><description>As Australians under 16 lose their social media accounts, influential Republicans and Democrats are pushing the US Congress to consider a similar ban for children under 13.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">203e1f6da89e43fe3b2617333f18dddd</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka adamant 'Battle of the Sexes' clash against Nick Kyrgios will help women's tennis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/tennis-aryna-sabalenka-nick-kyrgios-defend-polarising-match/106128302</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka is adamant her upcoming clash against Nick Kyrgios will not prove to be a gimmick that damages women's tennis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4923bb3d0bc8d79da189a795d6da956</guid></item><item><title>Cabinet ministers debate whether gas reservation plan can cut power prices as hoped</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/gas-reservation-power-price-fears/106125184</link><description>A long-awaited scheme to force east coast energy giants to set aside gas for Australian use is being finalised in down-to-the-wire negotiations between half a dozen cabinet ministers grappling with concerns it may not lower prices as much as hoped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">863c406b91f7e9e36fe01e9992b3f2b5</guid></item><item><title>National Anti-Corruption Commission chief updates official declaration of interests to disclose defence link</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/nacc-chief-updates-official-declaration/106126738</link><description>National Anti-Corruption Commission chief Paul Brereton formally discloses his consulting work for the defence watchdog after the ABC reveals the links.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d086faaba53f92740d46dcb677157195</guid></item><item><title>'Zombie-proof' EV ad tops complaints list as social media cases rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/the-most-complained-about-ads-of-2025/106105394</link><description>As more businesses look to do their own advertising, audience complaints for social media ads are growing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3859fe975c24dd1d54d1615daa78299f</guid></item><item><title>RBA interest rate hike expectations on the rise after mixed jobs report — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/asx-markets-business-live-news-dec-11-2025/106128346</link><description>Market pricing for a February rate hike is on the up after the unemployment rate remained steady at 4.3 per cent, while fewer people have been in work or looking for a job. Meanwhile, APRA is taking action against super giant HESTA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6528d38e5edbcfd547a1f22d0a1824a8</guid></item><item><title>Seasonal conditions lead to supersized strawberries in Australian stores</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/supersized-large-stawberries-in-australia/106120026</link><description>Seasonal conditions are leading to big berries this summer, with the fruit on the larger side in some regions because of a wetter spring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f94adb5d206a0c79c684f67387fce243</guid></item><item><title>US seizes oil tanker off coast of Venezuela, Donald Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/us-seizes-oil-tanker-off-coast-of-venezuela/106128382</link><description>US President Donald Trump says the tanker is "the largest one ever seized".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df8042715ed4912de309799be119c949</guid></item><item><title>Murray River water thieves hit with $558,000 fine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/david-littore-jindalee-road-wines-water-theft/106124764</link><description>Jindalee Road Wines and its former manager have been penalised $558,000 for illegally tapping into an irrigation pipeline and stealing water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d3c35e88314dc643b4f56233b142cd3</guid></item><item><title>From stacking supermarkets to 'chairman of everything', David Gonski exits uni leadership job</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/education-figure-david-gonski-retires-interview-on-education/106124520</link><description>Best known for his review into schools funding, David Gonski feels optimistic about the future of education in Australia, despite the growing challenges posed by AI and funding pressures on universities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fca3e751b522dce04afc6baf6012d4b</guid></item><item><title>Federal Court hears bid from Regis Resources to overturn protection order that stopped McPhillamys Gold Mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/regis-resources-bid-overturn-nsw-gold-mine-protection-order/106123596</link><description>Regis Resources argues the federal environment department was "uncritical" in accepting evidence about a First Nations Dreaming story that led to its proposed gold project being halted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d92a43c5ba9086c9d1d582cb8395d195</guid></item><item><title>Tiwi Islands become 700,000-hectare Indigenous Protected Area under federal agreement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/nt-tiwi-islands-becomes-indigenous-protected-area-ipa/106126788</link><description>The agreement with the federal government sees the Tiwi Islands included in Australia's national parks and reserves system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15956b1a0b81e5bb1868c3a086c4fabd</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Coalition accuses PM of 'running away from responsibility' on expenses controversy — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/federal-politics-live-blog-dec-11/106126114</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese again defends the communication minister's use of travel entitlements but says he understands why it is controversial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd5612836fa73e3193d9c776552b48c5</guid></item><item><title>Why WA's housing crisis is proving a roadblock to easing family and domestic violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/wa-housing-crisis-is-a-roadblock-to-dv-victims/106127682</link><description>The WA government is talking up its efforts to stamp out domestic and family violence, but there is one fundamental roadblock to alleviating the situation for women in crisis, and that is the state's housing crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38986bea311fba1f1a8a0a102c475fc2</guid></item><item><title>Greg Lynn's murder conviction set aside, new trial ordered — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/live-blog-greg-lynn-high-country-appeal-court/106124374</link><description>Greg Lynn has had his conviction for the murder of Carol Clay set aside by Victoria's Court of Appeal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">713e7fef41c022b28587f1909512686e</guid></item><item><title>Egypt and Iran complain to FIFA over potential LGBTQ+ pride match at World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/football-egypt-iran-complain-fifa-over-world-cup-pride-match/106128348</link><description>Iran and Egypt's group stage clash at next year's FIFA World Cup in Seattle is set to be a celebration of LGBTQ+ pride, and both federations are not happy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9067be37645d23b6f582902d41be1550</guid></item><item><title>Mount Isa inquest into the three-year disappearance of Tallis Ahfat concludes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/tallis-ahfat-disappearance-inquest-mount-isa/106095296</link><description>The inquest into a man missing in Queensland's north-west for the past three years has heard CCTV footage at a drug dealer's home from the night of the disappearance had been erased.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adbbd9fc64b7accb35521613a32df6c9</guid></item><item><title>Threat eases from Stieglitz bushfire near St Helens on Tasmania's east coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/tasmania-st-helens-stieglitz-fire-threat-eases-road-reopening/106128334</link><description>Firefighters have reopened access for residents of a bushfire-struck community on Tasmania's east coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">771055f203fc1c8421dd97504bd5a741</guid></item><item><title>Man attempted to abduct child outside Hobart Domain playground, police investigate white van</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/child-approached-by-stanger-in-hobart-domain-area/106128418</link><description>A man wearing a medical mask, sunglasses and bandages attempted to usher a primary school child into his van near a Hobart playground, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">552d115d07b322728d04acd45e20ede3</guid></item><item><title>Half Big Brother, half late-night talk show: The WNBA stars revolutionising sports media</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/wnba-studbudz-natisha-hiedeman-courtney-williams-sport-marketing/106090546</link><description>The WNBA's 'StudBudz' are using live streaming to build a brand and community, while providing lessons in marketing women's sports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cd56cfc0c9fbc505e1e9c6f24777a14</guid></item><item><title>Greg Lynn's murder conviction for death of High Country camper Carol Clay quashed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/greg-lynn-appeal-decision-high-country-camper/106128570</link><description>Former Jetstar pilot Greg Lynn has had his conviction for the murder of retiree Carol Clay overturned by Victoria's Court of Appeal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50db3535022f96b757cf6a5962cf132c</guid></item><item><title>Nicole Kidman to co-chair Met Gala with Beyoncé, Venus Williams and Anna Wintour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/nicole-kidman-beyonce-venus-williams-chair-met-gala/106128614</link><description>The museum also announced a gala host committee, chaired by designer Anthony Vaccarello and filmmaker Zoë Kravitz.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eac6c7a5126cc2aca138e618c40905d8</guid></item><item><title>AUKUS ministers meet in Washington as Hegseth praises Australia for 'stepping up'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/aukus-submarine-project-on-track-richard-marles-says/106128670</link><description>The defence minister insists the AUKUS program is on track to provide Australia with nuclear-powered submarines in the next decade — despite the delays plaguing shipbuilding programs in both the US and the UK.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d156d1724b200e852ed8945aec05c7cc</guid></item><item><title>Greg Lynn arrives at court for appeal decision</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/greg-lynn-arrives-at-court-for-appeal-decision/106128928</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">684b5ba1950dc8f14c30fe8960826a92</guid></item><item><title>Walter Sofronoff loses appeal against finding he engaged in corrupt conduct during inquiry into Bruce Lehrmann's prosecution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/walter-sofronoff-loses-appeal-against-corruption-finding/106126878</link><description>The man who led the inquiry into the criminal prosecution of Bruce Lehrmann loses his appeal to have serious corruption findings against him overturned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d23e60051e9d89e5f5b4b02e819cf382</guid></item><item><title>US authorities seize Venezuela oil tanker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/us-authorities-seize-venezuela-oil-tanker/106128742</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a31913eac113556360db67ab47e0eaf7</guid></item><item><title>Michigan fires football coach Sherrone Moore over 'inappropriate relationship' with staffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/michigan-football-coach-sherrone-moore-fired-staffer-scandal/106128866</link><description>Sherrone Moore's rollercoaster tenure with Michigan comes to an end midway through its second season as the college shows zero tolerance for his actions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cfba8bc214c7876a27b4b7b804d381f</guid></item><item><title>SA courts close amid escalating dispute over correctional services pay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/courts-close-amid-escalating-pay-dispute-over-prison-staff-pay/106128312</link><description>Strike action involving prison officers has again escalated, forcing the closure of SA's major courts and causing disruptions to case hearings, which will now be rescheduled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7ca7e18e36096f2c902a696849898e8</guid></item><item><title>Superannuation giant HESTA hit with extra licence restrictions as APRA raises governance, risk concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/super-fund-hesta-hit-with-extra-conditions-apra-governance-risk/106128664</link><description>APRA says the fallout of HESTA's planned outage led to a "severe, prolonged disruption" that caused direct harm to some of its 1.1 million members, in a damning assessment of the fund.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35554f5c84bc7088fdb2609c8d5613dc</guid></item><item><title>Collingwood employee resigns after alcohol-fuelled incident at Alice Springs training camp</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/afl-collingwood-employee-resigns-alcohol-fuelled-incident/106128612</link><description>A Collingwood employee hands in his resignation following an incident on an interstate trip that required an investigation by the club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21f893a5d3a036c1e738cb694cfb4f8b</guid></item><item><title>ACCC opposes sale of RAC WA's insurance arm to Sydney-based IAG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/accc-opposes-sale-of-racwa-to-sydney-company-iag/106128754</link><description>The Australian Competition and Consumer Commission finds IAG's proposed acquisition of RAC WA would "eliminate the significant competition" between the two major insurance companies and likely result in higher premiums.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3690b642d2949473d2562499f335689</guid></item><item><title>Australia's unemployment rate remains at 4.3 per cent, but underemployment surges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/australia-unemployment-rate-november-2025/106129300</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate holds steady at 4.3 per cent in November, but the underemployment rate jumps to 12-month high.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1516dc0d7c467b531207223b29f02c64</guid></item><item><title>This Grand Designs Australia house cost $320k to build. Here's how its owners pulled it off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/grand-designs-cheap-house-320k-how-couple-did-it/106102674</link><description>Bespoke architectural builds on small budgets may seem like an impossible housing dream, but James and Rita managed to turn their vision into a reality — without breaking the bank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1959b70829d84196ecd189375f3325da</guid></item><item><title>Bureau of Meteorology makes major changes to $96.5m website after refresh backlash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/weather-bureau-updates-new-website-after-critisicm/106128956</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology has updated the rain radar, temperature information and warning displays on its new website in response to public feedback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b3801ebd5ac3764a1b79ef836e78a63</guid></item><item><title>Four French nationals charged with stealing $10 million in luxury items from Canberra home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/french-nationals-charged-burglary-10-million-canberra-home/106129586</link><description>Police allege the men travelled to Australia to rob a Canberra home, stealing distinctive, luxury items.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c55d53a719157d8ddc067fdceb438799</guid></item><item><title>Iceland becomes fifth country to boycott Eurovision 2026 over Israeli participation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/iceland-not-participating-in-eurovison-2026/106128592</link><description>Iceland has joined Ireland, the Netherlands, Spain and Slovenia in boycotting the competition in protest against Israel's participation in the song contest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">202f76c005b4117588c215f1ac71821b</guid></item><item><title>AC Milan Serie A Perth soccer game in serious doubt amid FIFA roadblock</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/ac-milan-serie-a-perth-soccer-game-in-trouble-rita-saffioti-fifa/106129592</link><description>Plans to host seven-time European champions AC Milan in Perth for an Italian league game are in trouble, with growing concerns soccer's global governing body will not sign off on the event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4f29263e2e479f6c6974d076a7c091f</guid></item><item><title>Council investigates mould, food safety complaints at Civeo Coppabella mining camp</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/isaac-council-investigates-complaints-civeo-coppabella/106128686</link><description>Isaac Regional Council says it is looking into multiple claims about a fly-in, fly-out camp capable of housing more than 3,000 workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0189961ee7be0b9ce9b6da5155f87a8</guid></item><item><title>Sentence handed to Darwin fatal hit-and-run driver Jake Danby 'shocked public consciousness', appeal hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/darwin-hit-and-run-driver-jake-danby-prosecution-appeal-reserved/106124686</link><description>The NT Court of Criminal Appeal has heard an appeal against the sentence for a 24-year-old driver who avoided a jail sentence after hitting two Aboriginal pedestrians with his vehicle, killing one, and then boasting about it over text.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4025212876e9275aa51fea604bffd7c</guid></item><item><title>PM distances himself from politician spending rules amid Anika Wells controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/pm-distances-himself-from-politician-spending-rules-anika-wells/106130760</link><description>Pressed on whether his government should review the rules that allow politicians to fly their families around the country in business class, the prime minister says his focus is on the social media ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">daea64309046e0955b2f7c7122665131</guid></item><item><title>States lash Commonwealth's revised public hospital funding offer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/albanese-offers-extra-funding-for-public-hospitals/106130754</link><description>The prime minister wrote to states and territories this week, upping the Commonwealth's offer for public hospital funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81a7feea6b061580a3e2b8c23982ed32</guid></item><item><title>The Golden Spurtle takes audiences into the heart of the World Porridge Making Championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/the-golden-spurtle-porridge-making-championship-documentary/106118710</link><description>Every year, the Scottish town of Carrbridge hosts a porridge competition. Its contestants and chieftain are larger than life and celebrated in the new Aussie documentary The Golden Spurtle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12ad0434302f24dc80fd695083ecdc14</guid></item><item><title>The two Navy officers breaking ground, heading towards Winter Paralympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/navy-officers-breaking-ground-towards-winter-paralympics/106126742</link><description>It has been 20 years since Australia sent a biathlete to the Winter Paralympics, but two serving Navy personnel are hoping to change this.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51d23b79d9fb3944846f47d09d70d0b7</guid></item><item><title>Coalition agrees to sweeping changes to NSW workers' compensation scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/workers-compensation-scheme-changes-coalition-kellie-sloane/106129434</link><description>NSW Opposition Leader Kellie Sloane says changes to the state's workers' compensation scheme are an important "reset".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7bc0b41a8aaabca09dc7bc682b92037</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic science and logistics given $208m federal funding boost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/antarctic-science-and-logistics-given-208-million-funding-boost/106130794</link><description>The federal government has announced more than $200 million in additional funding over the next seven years for Antarctic science and logistics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec45dc9da2fbe532cb1d7bb4cc378f8f</guid></item><item><title>Blackwater massage therapist Donovan Webb charged with additional sexual assault offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/blackwater-masseuse-donovan-webb-charged-with-sexual-assault/106130814</link><description>Blackwater massage therapist Donovan Webb has been charged with a further 40 counts of sexual assault alleged to have taken place during massage therapy sessions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b56008589ec5c4d75baa46e402c8563</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested for alleged murder of father-of-two Chris Robertson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/lonsdale-alleged-murder-arrest/106131440</link><description>Police have arrested a 30-year-old man for the alleged murder of Adelaide father-of-two Chris Robertson, who was found dead in a Lonsdale workshop in September.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc8679b4efb2bc0c83388052adeecb88</guid></item><item><title>Australian hooker Harry Grant awarded rugby league Golden Boot for 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/harry-grant-golden-boot-australia-dylan-brown/106131732</link><description>New Zealand's Dylan Brown seemed a certainty to claim the Golden Boot as rugby league's best international player for 2025 but the Kiwi five-eighth has missed out in a stunning twist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6805ac76cd4379fd23324a09498cabc3</guid></item><item><title>Sixth person charged with murder over stabbing of Gordon Kessey in Bega</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/shoalhaven-man-tehata-hapuku-charged-over-alleged-bega-murder/106129076</link><description>Tehata Hapuku has been named as the sixth person charged over the fatal stabbing of Nowra man Gordon Kessey near a park in Bega on the NSW far south coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99605fc1b80669384300cfdf48c1dade</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government moves to lift ban on political donations from property developers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/political-donations-qld-property-developers/106130862</link><description>The attorney-general said the proposed laws would level the political playing field, labelling the ban as a "gerrymander" by the former Labor government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c49306a158c5f48a15cc52eee8051bcc</guid></item><item><title>SA algal bloom testing shows positive signs ahead of peak summer temperatures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/positive-signs-amid-algal-bloom-monitoring/106131392</link><description>Authorities say the "best signs" in a "long time" have been observed in the latest round of monitoring of the state's algal bloom crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f43189df2fdae26a1fc3f1a9c4713c41</guid></item><item><title>China's huge trade surplus shows Trump failed to tame Beijing's export juggernaut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/china-trade-surplus-tariffs-beijing-donald-trump-global-economy/106130778</link><description>China's record breaking one trillion-dollar trade surplus shows Trump's tariffs have done little to tame Beijing's export juggernaut. In fact, they might have turbocharged it instead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52ab115a4db0a42fa89da402d0849146</guid></item><item><title>Victorian government's gas exploration plans in Gippsland and the Otways anger environmental groups</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/gas-exploration-licences-approved-gippsland-otways/106123740</link><description>The Victorian government calls for tenders after it approved exploration licenses for two new gas projects in the Otway and Gippsland basins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a8e29e48fdff55891113a238cdd226b</guid></item><item><title>Ex-NRL star Jarryd Hayne applies to have civil damages case by rape accuser dismissed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/hayne-moves-to-have-damages-case-dismissed/106128674</link><description>Lawyers for the former NRL star seek to have a civil damages lawsuit against him dismissed, citing delays in the Supreme Court civil case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0daa8fc3220ba577df3b9bc01cb0e0c7</guid></item><item><title>Adult content creator Bonnie Blue will be banned from Bali after studio raid involving 14 Australians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/bonnie-blue-banned-from-bali-after-raid-involving-australians/106120234</link><description>A high-profile British adult content creator will be banned from Bali for 10 years after police raided a "studio" on the island, in which 14 Australians were found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6b2aaebe86e88750b533b6a36c94a3a</guid></item><item><title>Two bushfires downgraded from emergency warnings in Bullsbrook and Kenwick in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/kenwick-wattle-grove-maddington-beckenham-bushfire/106132334</link><description>Fires in the city's north-east and south-east are downgraded to watch and act levels, while lives and homes remain possibly under threat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">601d34af889bff85be5f7ef21eb19da6</guid></item><item><title>Nobel laureate Machado greets fans from Oslo hotel balcony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/nobel-laureate-machado-greets-fans-from-oslo-hotel-balcony/106130710</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">722736a5b3a37a4df552bc50e657a84b</guid></item><item><title>Nobel Peace Prize laureate Maria Machado emerges from hiding to greet cheering crowds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/maria-machado-greets-cheering-crowds-in-oslo-norway/106130560</link><description>Venezuelan opposition leader and Nobel Peace Prize laureate Maria Corina Machado, who has been living in hiding in fear for her safety, appears in public for the first time in almost a year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d948e536d1de01c54ccdd3e8398609d8</guid></item><item><title>Father of Michael Purse relieved as murderer Mark-Bry Leedham loses appeal against conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/mark-bry-leedham-loses-appeal-michael-purse-murder-conviction/106130792</link><description>Jeffrey Purse says a court's decision to dismiss an appeal by his son's killer offers "some justice" for his family, as the search for Michael Purse's remains continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b43e768ff2079d2c84974b4f3f6f53e0</guid></item><item><title>Tom Silvagni revealed as man from high-profile Victorian family convicted of rape</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/tom-silvagni-identified-as-man-found-guilty-of-rape/106129488</link><description>Tom Silvagni, the son of Carlton Football Club great Stephen Silvagni, can now be identified as the man last week found guilty of raping a woman in 2024, after a court lifted a restriction on publishing his name.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">751f404865b43c78142d4e1039955304</guid></item><item><title>Six-ingredient rocky road is perfect for last-minute Christmas prep - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/easy-milk-chocolate-rocky-road-with-pretzels-peanuts-licorice/105748720</link><description>This milk chocolate rocky road is easy to make. It creates 12 large slices, perfect for gifting or dessert if you're bringing a plate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cdd96d64ada5a866ca3dab538b13228</guid></item><item><title>From the ABC archive: Floating the dollar in 1983</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/1983-abc-story-about-floating-the-dollar/106132424</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0c79ced60a9d989743e210c69787706</guid></item><item><title>Detective Acting Inspector Mark Battye</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/detective-acting-inspector-mark-battye/106132420</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f88044c38510d98192c2a11560b004a1</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man jailed for raping customer in mall art shop where he worked</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/act-man-jailed-raping-customer-in-mall-art-shop-where-he-worked/106132062</link><description>A judge says the former art shop worker had a "complete disconnect between perception and reality" as she jails him for rape.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a6dfcbc5458a63075a7496e6150061e</guid></item><item><title>Motherhood and sport 'can co-exist': AOC offers cash incentives for Olympian mums</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/motherhood-and-sport-can-co-exist-olympic-funding-alyce-wood/106130494</link><description>The Australian Olympic Committee hopes to keep more athletes in sport by offering cash incentives for women who return after having children, and tens of thousands of dollars for retiring Olympians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3f91d46921c6acb74f8b555d5e5839e</guid></item><item><title>Former Yipirinya School principal Gavin Morris handed suspended sentence for physically assaulting students</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/former-yipirinya-school-principal-gavin-morris-sentenced-court/106113598</link><description>Gavin Morris, the former principal of Yipirinya School in Alice Springs, has received an 18-month suspended sentence for the aggravated assault of four students.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed9cca541322c7eb50be7e0fc268c095</guid></item><item><title>Court of Appeal details reasons behind quashing of Greg Lynn's murder conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/greg-lynn-court-of-appeal-conviction-quashed-reasons/106130172</link><description>The Victorian Court of Appeal ruled to overturn the former Jetstar pilot's murder conviction and ordered a new trial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4feb166e29ac3ddb831134d97c603aaf</guid></item><item><title>Barry O'Farrell expected to return as Wests Tigers chairman 10 days after shock sacking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/barry-ofarrell-wests-tigers-chairman-return-ceo/106132934</link><description>The boardroom dramas at Wests Tigers take another turn with Barry O'Farrell and multiple other ousted independent directors expected to return to the club at the NRL's demand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f582a4d420f02eb4105d1d3ed8715d1b</guid></item><item><title>Milenko 'Gobesan' Snjegota found guilty but not criminally responsible of father's backyard murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/milenko-gobesan-snjegota-guilty-not-criminally-reponsible/106128748</link><description>An Illawarra man living with diagnosed schizophrenia has been found guilty but not criminally responsible for murdering his father in February 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ec00fae072f2ba5c970d040263a91cd</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106132750</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12df59ada546783e55ba420b144dc6d4</guid></item><item><title>NACC chief Brereton's claim recusal 'unnecessary' openly disputed by his deputies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/brereton-nacc-deputies-dispute-recusal-unnecessary/106131710</link><description>The National Anti-Corruption Commission's chief personally drafted lines in a media release saying his recusal from defence cases was "unnecessary". His deputies have publicly disagreed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cae8f4ef1ed66eddb7c09281bb69cf2c</guid></item><item><title>Lawyers defend Tanya Plibersek's part protection of McPhillamys mine site from development</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/court-hears-sensitive-dreaming-story-halted-mcphillamys-mine/106129606</link><description>Lawyers for former federal environment minister Tanya Plibersek have defended the Commonwealth's acceptance of the Blue Banded Bee Dreaming to protect part of a gold mine site from development.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65830e06d72c3debf4dc2c4804e44158</guid></item><item><title>Regulator 'disappointed' over Tasmanian salmon industry's antibiotic plan, emails show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/tas-regulator-salmon-company-at-odds-over-antibiotic-rollout/106133156</link><description>A salmon company gave Tasmanian authorities a week's notice before it planned to start using a new antibiotic in the state's waterways to combat a disease outbreak, sparking a strong rebuke from the industry regulator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe49df76809cdcb291c6661fc8992caf</guid></item><item><title>Bookkeeper Karen Anne Webb given suspended sentence for stealing $163,000 from Mount Barker employer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/karen-anne-webb-sentenced-for-stealing-from-employer/106132974</link><description>The Albany Magistrates Court heard the woman had transferred the money to her personal account in smaller amounts over 15 months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69865e92af02c368349853cf8c668824</guid></item><item><title>Luke Anthony Shaw given 23-year prison sentence for 2022 murder of David Wayne Jenkins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/george-town-tasmania-sentencing-for-david-wayne-jenkins-murder/106130696</link><description>A northern Tasmanian man has been sentenced to more than two decades in prison for the "unnecessary and pointless" 2022 stabbing death of another man.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d3317e4e8196e13a39f53ab2f7dd61c</guid></item><item><title>Gas company Beetaloo Energy clears final hurdle for fracking in the Beetaloo Basin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/beetaloo-energy-australia-final-investment-decision/106131964</link><description>Major global oil and gas companies are expressing "serious interest" in the Beetaloo Basin for the first time, one analyst says, now that Beetaloo Energy has reached a final investment decision and committed to developing its fracking project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8f88b833f4900ab198fa1aad2f73766</guid></item><item><title>Living seawalls bringing life back into harbours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/living-seawalls-bringing-life-back-into-harbours-/106132946</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0f91ef051c3f6e980bd8c742b12c6fd</guid></item><item><title>More than 3,000 aged care patients stuck in hospital beds, new national figures show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/aged-care-patients-stuck-in-hospital-beds/106123998</link><description>State health ministers will today enter their final meeting of the year with their federal counterpart armed with figures showing a 25 per cent increase in just three months of aged care patients stranded in hospitals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c03287d6958c33610fb0a30c5858954</guid></item><item><title>NATO chief Mark Rutte tells allies: 'We are Russia's next target'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/nato-chief-warns-allies-they-are-russia-s-next-target/106133866</link><description>Mark Rutte said Moscow could be ready to use military force against NATO in five years, adding Europe should be prepared for war comparable to what "our grandparents and great-grandparents endured".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">321984e9b2339427483c5b69928b0aea</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar army bombs hospital in Rakhine state killing at least 31 people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/myanmar-junta-bombs-hospital-in-rakhine-state-killing-31-people/106133832</link><description>The latest strike reportedly killed multiple members of the same family and a months-old infant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2ad33947bedae1ccd83360aaeba6e5a</guid></item><item><title>TIME magazine names 'The Architects of AI' as 2025 Person of the Year, confirming leak to betting markets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/time-person-of-the-year-2025-announcement-ai-architects/106133986</link><description>The magazine cites the tremendous technological advances made by the artificial intelligence industry over the past year in bringing on the age of "thinking machines".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abeef511c965985fc244ffdf6bc99599</guid></item><item><title>Alleged co-owners of Goa nightclub Birch by Romeo Lane detained in Thailand following fire that killed 25 people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/brothers-detained-in-thailand-after-deadly-goa-nightclub-fire/106134092</link><description>The blaze killed 25 people, with authorities arresting six other people in the case so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b06cd0c0e475e73175c7102ebe16889e</guid></item><item><title>Amnesty International report finds Hamas committed crimes against humanity with October 7 attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/amnesty-report-accuses-hamas-of-crimes-against-humanity/106133834</link><description>Amnesty's investigation finds Hamas's crimes against humanity included murder, extermination, imprisonment, torture, rape and other inhumane acts, including during its time holding more than 250 people hostage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dd2a0d4486d2093112de32eb07b2b26</guid></item><item><title>US judge orders Kilmar Abrego Garcia be released from ICE detention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/judge-orders-kilmar-abrego-garcia-be-released-from-ice-detention/106134200</link><description>The case has become a key test of Donald Trump's immigration crackdown after Mr Abrego Garcia was wrongfully deported to El Salvador.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54bf47c698d7e5cc880af69b94f5470f</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy proposes Ukrainian referendum on disputed territory as Donald Trump tires of meetings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/zelenskyy-says-ukraine-has-sent-us-updated-peace-plan/106134242</link><description>Ukraine has proposed a vote on disputed territory in an updated version of the US-led peace plan to end Russia's war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f670657a0ebc12999b3675ea4bff480</guid></item><item><title>Trump's oil tanker seizure raises questions about potential Venezuela blockade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/venezuela-donald-trump-foreign-policy-oil-tanker-seizure/106130650</link><description>Donald Trump's assertions on foreign policy since his return to the White House have literally stretched from one end of the Western Hemisphere to the other.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d842a6a85a3696c7316e477f68d4ab6</guid></item><item><title>Greg Lynn successfully appealed his Victorian High Country murder conviction. What happens now?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/greg-lynn-appeal-carol-clay-what-happens-next/106131408</link><description>Prosecutors in Greg Lynn's Victorian High Country murder trial are preparing for a second trial after the Court of Appeal quashed his conviction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08ac50b5ee2f5e1dfb6dcf2aa44c96ac</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 12: Australian dollar floated amid financial chaos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/today-in-history-december-12-floating-the-dollar/106131892</link><description>It was a pivotal moment in the nation's history, forever changing the way we were governed and the way in which we interacted with the rest of the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd71ceb4b77b3d734f62bf79dd415dcc</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: A furious bidding war, hilarious animals and the Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/abc-weekly-news-quiz-december-12/106130344</link><description>A lot happened in news this week. Did you take it all in?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4dd53cfd5d33ac909f25c3dd0896913</guid></item><item><title>NSW guidelines proposed to prevent hospitals from refusing abortion care based on personal beliefs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/document-reveals-plan-to-limit-blocking-of-abortions/106091562</link><description>Hospital managers and executives in NSW will be barred from blocking abortions because of moral and religious views, according to a document obtained by the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3d3062cf75f3a97bc05383490ea6084</guid></item><item><title>After opposing the Coalition's 'robo' NDIS reforms, Labor accused of going down similar path</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/ican-ndis-planning-system-creating-deja-vu/106116170</link><description>The finer details of a new NDIS planning system are yet to be finalised, but it's already drawing comparisons to failed Coalition-era reforms, write Nas Campanella and Evan Young.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c59b3bf4ebdd059df618b5e2606e4e58</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Racing Club under fire as members allege conflicts of interest and governance failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/brisbane-racing-club-members-allege-conflicts-of-interest/106132016</link><description>Members of Queensland's richest horse racing club are demanding answers after they discovered its former chairman struck a lucrative deal with the developer of its luxury residential precinct while he had oversight of the $850 million project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2322f470081bf0736f0df8942416368d</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's social media ban is bold reform, but it will take years to judge its real success</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/teen-social-media-ban-albanese-government-david-coleman/106129676</link><description>Parents will thank the government for giving them more agency in dealing with the social media issue but kids aren't voters and it is hard to see the issue deciding votes either way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ba9b0802fb9c08f9a407ad1c8f7fc8c</guid></item><item><title>Bendigo Writers Festival council report recommends one-year hiatus amid reputational damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/bendigo-writers-festival-council-report-recommends-one-year-off/106130278</link><description>Council officers recommend a one-year hiatus for the Bendigo Writers Festival to work on repairing the reputation of the event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">306011983281fc9bdfa5556f1412eaf9</guid></item><item><title>Labor tries to end Ashton Hurn's 'honeymoon' early</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/ashton-hurn-state-election-honeymoon/106131140</link><description>Only days after taking her party's top job, Liberal leader Ashton Hurn is under pressure on a key election promise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd3b1f568f6ebc41c5f0a0db8e74e9db</guid></item><item><title>Bathurst mother Emma Mason's advocacy for social media ban piques interests of global leaders and media</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/emma-mason-reflects-on-tilly-legacy-social-media-ban-australia/106116832</link><description>Bathurst mother and lawyer Emma Mason's advocacy for Australia's social media ban has always been in honour of her late daughter, Tilly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">365bf04a741bb8fe7551d2415fe34461</guid></item><item><title>Grieving families call for tougher penalties as NSW road toll surges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/new-south-wales-road-deaths-on-the-rise/106100696</link><description>Renee Ernst's world fell apart when her husband Troy was killed in a crash on his way home from work. She says consequences for dangerous driving need to be harsher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be8e2b1ca169562f91ce86782900e2fc</guid></item><item><title>Calls for vending machines in hospitals after women denied period products</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/women-denied-period-products-in-hospital/106121588</link><description>When Samantha Bruce got her period in hospital she wasn't able to get a pad or tampon. She says the response left her feeling "small and dehumanised".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8843f9f4fe4254b5fb036f3785f37d54</guid></item><item><title>How schools of excellence are changing the future of girls rugby league in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/qld-rugby-league-girls-school-of-excellence/106125352</link><description>A growing rugby league excellence program is helping change the future of Queensland girls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b310cf7908a68687ea21ed87a25ad3e8</guid></item><item><title>Families grapple with results of review into systemic failings that enabled paedophile Ashley Paul Griffith</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/ashley-paul-griffith-queensland-victims-damning-report/106130100</link><description>Ashley Paul Griffith was sentenced to life in prison last year for sexually abusing 69 girls at childcare centres in Brisbane and Italy over a two-decade period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26200706f31fab61f953fadfa2252f66</guid></item><item><title>Landlords eligible for $3,500 rebates for putting rooftop solar on rentals under Queensland scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/queensland-landlord-renters-rooftop-solar-scheme-rebates/106131208</link><description>The $26 million pre-election commitment from the LNP is estimated by the government to save 6,500 households around $700 on energy bills, with applications opening on Friday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2f9d58591b92e12f616cee8f282142b</guid></item><item><title>How 'snakeheads' are redirecting illegal migration from China toward Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/chinese-nationals-walking-the-routes-to-australia-boat-explained/106124082</link><description>Recent boat arrivals in Western Australia offer a glimpse into how routes through South-East Asia, particularly Indonesia, are being used to reach Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96570f64d21f4ef9f4cbcb03f5bb70d6</guid></item><item><title>Why the football Dylan Brown showed for New Zealand can make his record-breaking move to Newcastle pay off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/dylan-brown-golden-boot-newcastle-knights-contract/106126952</link><description>The football Dylan Brown played for New Zealand should have won him the Golden Boot but it could also be the key to his record-breaking move to Newcastle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b66459bac729932c38199a2ed35baba1</guid></item><item><title>Australian rare earth processing plant to be ready for use in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/rare-earth-processing-facility-mining-south-australia/106123882</link><description>The processing market is dominated by China, but Australia is building its capabilities in an attempt to boost the domestic industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76cd3cd1ea5800ec9707c1a72f6776cd</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: Mid-year budget update to show $12b spending blowout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/federal-politics-live-blog-dec-12/106134352</link><description>The treasurer and finance minister will need to find room for more than $12 billion in extra costs for "unavoidable" spending in the mid-year budget update. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e473ad0ef6aac29b4fbaefd35a9388e1</guid></item><item><title>Police Commissioner Grant Stevens appointed to Adelaide Football Club board</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/police-commissioner-grant-stevens-joins-adelaide-crows-board/106133692</link><description>South Australia's top cop has taken on an extra role, joining the Adelaide Football Club's board of directors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09e93f9c48e604eb3ccb6fcdbd02e0c3</guid></item><item><title>Trusted Mildura accountant facing longer prison sentence after defrauding clients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/trusted-mildura-accountant-philip-shugg-facing-longer-sentence/106129286</link><description>Philip Shugg, a prominent accountant from Victoria's north-west, is facing an even lengthier prison sentence after pleading guilty to defrauding his clients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57faad4e4c13ed7944513432f6053354</guid></item><item><title>NSW prison watchdog calls to shut parts of Sydney's Long Bay Jail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/watchdog-calls-to-close-some-of-dilapidated-long-bay-jail-sydney/106128352</link><description>The NSW's prisons watchdog has deemed parts of Long Bay Jail "unsafe" and "dilapidated" and "incapable of providing safe and humane" conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c789cbea02fb9a68a6d27b444474f422</guid></item><item><title>Perth Scorchers into WBBL final as Beth Mooney continues sparkling form to down Sydney Sixers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/cricket-beth-mooney-stars-scorchers-into-wbbl-final/106134414</link><description>Sydney Sixers keeper Alyssa Healy misses a glorious chance to dismiss Beth Mooney, and the Aussie left-hander makes her pay big-time with a sparkling innings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f23135c1ee0b7703fe9b9e8aea71299</guid></item><item><title>$10 million Oasis Townsville veterans support hub folds after $1 million loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/oasis-townsville-veterans-support-hub-folds-/106103390</link><description>Questions are being asked why a $10 million "flagship" veterans support hub has had to close, just four years after it opened in Townsville.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6be05c3d900ad7a326e19ea22c8fd33</guid></item><item><title>Markets live update: ASX poised to rally as Dow jumps, tech stocks slump as Oracle sparks AI fears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/asx-markets-business-live-news-dec-12/106134504</link><description>The ASX could post a weekly gain, after the Dow rallied on Wall St amid a rotation out of tech stocks. A slump for cloud firm Oracle reignited fears about whether huge AI-related spending would pay off. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22dd22fa432152c61a1dc4190fa94df3</guid></item><item><title>Celebrity crocodile wrangler Matt Wright is expected to be sentenced today. Here's what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/nt-celebrity-crocodile-wrangler-matt-wright-sentencing-court/106127054</link><description>Celebrity crocodile wrangler Matt Wright was earlier this year found guilty on two counts of attempting to pervert the course of justice. Today, the court will consider his sentence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cec0f59c2a7bffda4e319243789e89dc</guid></item><item><title>Independent wholesaler cautiously welcomes review into outback food subsidy scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/outback-food-subsidy-scheme-review-cautiously-welcomed/106090748</link><description>A wholesaler hopes a review of a controversial outback food subsidy scheme will be independent and transparent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec8ea28f6aa649b62bc6717d5ff7ee0c</guid></item><item><title>Fans bid another farewell to beloved TV show Neighbours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/fans-bid-farewell-to-australian-tv-show-neighbours/106132748</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0467cbdd56671a5b7a813d7e7caf594b</guid></item><item><title>After 40 years of plot twists and drama, Neighbours wraps up for the last time — again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/neighbours-finale-recap/106133684</link><description>Relive the highlights, such as they were, in the final episode of Neighbours, which went to air last night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66d77596370f9dcb56e3473c4c20e070</guid></item><item><title>Demersal fishing ban leaves industry 'drowning' as mental health concerns rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/fishing-industry-drowning-in-emotional-toll-of-dermersal-ban/106109302</link><description>WA fishers are raising concerns about a lack of mental health support as the commercial industry comes to terms with a ban on demersal fishing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">780356866a5457fda1599f1fb8e408ed</guid></item><item><title>Suspect in Charlie Kirk killing, Tyler Robinson, makes first in-court appearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/suspect-in-charlie-kirk-killing-tyler-first-in-court-appearance/106134566</link><description>Lawyers for Tyler Robinson, the man accused of killing conservative activist Charlie Kirk, have sought to limit media access to ensure a fair trial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">910a1b27c6f6893a54d60ca24ee94a2e</guid></item><item><title>US preparing to intercept more ships carrying Venezuelan oil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/us-ready-to-seize-ships-venezuelan-oil-tankers/106134498</link><description>The US is undertaking a large-scale military build-up in the southern Caribbean to increase pressure on Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro, and is planning to intercept more ships, according to sources.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3988de499dfa17007965f95e974b24e4</guid></item><item><title>FIFA World Cup ticket prices leave fans fuming and claiming 'monumental betrayal'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/football-fifa-world-cup-ticket-prices-fans-monumental-betrayal/106134502</link><description>A fans organisation lashes out at "extortionate" prices for tickets at next year's FIFA World Cup despite claims from the footballing body that the tournament would be affordable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c4f63a7a6a402c846bff82d5660abb8</guid></item><item><title>Record-breaking crocodile Cassius taxidermied for Green Island exhibit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/world-record-crocodile-cassius-taxidermied-new-exhibit/106131178</link><description>The world's largest crocodile in captivity until its death last year is going on display in Far North Queensland, as more findings are revealed about its cause of death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">733169fd9a429b9ff1e0b26e8fc099d4</guid></item><item><title>Grattai, south of Mudgee, was hit by a hailstorm on Thursday afternoon.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/hail-storm-hits-mudgee-region/106134668</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd773c1d317bc4364c8b5c4d3e25b1c3</guid></item><item><title>Hailstorm batters western NSW as homes destroyed in bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/storm-fire-cause-damage-nsw/106134570</link><description>Hailstorms have damaged homes in parts of western NSW as the cost of nearby bushfires continues to mount.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07dafe09ecc5e0e93c29e90d78c2a495</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne's West Gate Tunnel 'ready to take cars from Sunday'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/vic-west-gate-tunnel-ready-to-open/106134682</link><description>After being plagued by cost blowouts and delays, Melbourne's West Gate Tunnel will be ready to take motor vehicles from Sunday, say multiple sources.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">892c381d9f9b85832ba1460d984863e3</guid></item><item><title>Community rallies around family of farmer Mark Mudie after bushfire death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/community-support-wa-farmer-family-after-bushfire-death/106130238</link><description>In the wake of the tragic loss of farmer Mark Mudie while fighting a bushfire, the community has rallied to help his family finish harvesting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29225b57eeac8a3e9bddf250890cea9b</guid></item></channel></rss>