<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 14:04:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Concerns over abortion, vasectomies, IVF, gender-affirming care access as Catholic organisation Calvary buys Hobart Private</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/hobart-private-hospital-sale-calvary-abortion-concerns/106177108</link><description>The operator of the Hobart Private Hospital has agreed to sell the facility to Catholic healthcare provider Calvary, leading to concerns about access to surgical abortions, vasectomies and some other legal procedures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5430d43a7cde42fec16d598dafd02f8d</guid></item><item><title>England skipper Ben Stokes defends his team as Jofra Archer ruled out of Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/england-boxing-day-ben-stokes-noosa/106177474</link><description>England's disastrous Ashes tour has received another blow with Jofra Archer ruled out of the remaining two Tests while skipper Ben Stokes has dug in to defend his beleaguered team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d30958882c35c298deebc595e0fbf384</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs veteran Geoffrey Shaw remembered as tireless advocate for Aboriginal rights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/vietnam-veteran-land-rights-champion-geoffrey-shaw-remembered/106177422</link><description>Alice Springs war veteran Geoffrey Shaw OAM has been remembered as a tireless advocate for Indigenous rights in Central Australia, who leaves a legacy of courage and service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9eadafd0e8f634cc10d6af15eb22c34</guid></item><item><title>Bomb-making list, firearms, extremist flags seized from Perth man accused of backing Bondi attackers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/bondi-attack-supporter-charged-in-perth-raid/106177710</link><description>Police found a bomb-making shopping list when they searched the home of a man who allegedly posted on social media that he supported the gunmen behind the Bondi terror attack, a Perth court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36521dccd8b218e73f0e8c2c3deeac09</guid></item><item><title>Even in the markets, it's beginning to look like Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/finance-report-241225/106177792</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b4f9300c7f3d9aad335a7ab323c356c</guid></item><item><title>US and Ukraine reach consensus on key issues to end war with Russia but territorial disputes remain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/us-ukraine-reach-consensus-on-key-issues-to-end-war/106178118</link><description>President Volodymyr Zelenskyy has said that Ukraine has reached consensus with the US on key issues to end the war with Russia but sensitive issues around territorial control, along with the management of a nuclear power plant, still remain unresolved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05c4eb8bd99fe5b814901714a1641ea9</guid></item><item><title>Christmas quiz: How well do you know traditional Christmas carols?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/christmas-songs-quiz-traditional-carols/106133808</link><description>Do you know your Merry Gentlemen from you Three Kings? Your Dancers from your Prancers?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">824d802373eed7060a62552b3ca0c026</guid></item><item><title>Rental Family offers connection in an increasingly polarised world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/brendan-fraser-rental-family-hikari/106156660</link><description>Academy Award-winner Brendan Fraser speaks to ABC News about his new film and why human connection is the antidote to an increasingly polarised world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64796142ed39b4c48912a9c0e0b1a59d</guid></item><item><title>Gaza's remaining Christians mark Christmas with subdued celebrations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/gaza-remaining-christians-mark-christmas-subdued-celebrations/106177982</link><description>The small number of Christians remaining in Gaza have marked Christmas early with subdued celebrations in the shadow of ongoing conflict and occupation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eda5898dfa737111276df19f9aee72c4</guid></item><item><title>How political divides are putting more pressure on Australian couples</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/political-differences-pressure-australian-couples/106048876</link><description>More Australian relationships are struggling because of political divides. But experts say this does not have to be the end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfdae25d8b39d3f18ef6996ee10d6146</guid></item><item><title>What you need to know before you buy lab-grown versus natural diamonds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/what-to-know-about-laboratory-grown-and-natural-diamonds/106167962</link><description>Diamonds are generally considered a luxury asset that holds its value, but the emergence of laboratory-grown diamonds in the jewellery industry over recent years could challenge that belief.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24202eae3fcc5aaa1137df26f99527c9</guid></item><item><title>Second-hand shopping is a sustainable alternative, but could it be fuelling consumption?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/qld-second-hand-shopping-thrifting-consumption-apps/106173026</link><description>The rising popularity of second-hand and vintage fashion has been viewed as an opportunity to reduce fast fashion consumption; however, Australia remains one of the world's highest waste producers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71947152529f5c6dfc7368acdb22a6f8</guid></item><item><title>She readies for a 23rd Sydney to Hobart as the crew honours late owner Peter Rodgers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/sydney-to-hobart-she-peter-rodgers-memorial-race/106056430</link><description>A fellowship of sailors will embark on She's 23rd Sydney to Hobart campaign. As they do they will honour one of the most resilient boats in the race's history and remember late owner Peter Rodgers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e98f67c47d1cb8aba16c38df8cad139f</guid></item><item><title>Aged care centre confronts racism, improves staff retention with cultural celebrations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/aged-care-centre-starts-cultural-celebrations-to-address-racism/106085844</link><description>In 2024 a nurse reported racist abuse from some residents and family members. A year later, instances of abuse have plummeted and staff say it is because of a new program promoting respect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">106bbaf745444b130937df055a3765c6</guid></item><item><title>White House orders US forces to focus on 'quarantine' of Venezuelan oil, official says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/us-forces-to-quarantine-venezuelan-oil-as-un-condemns-aggression/106178276</link><description>The White House has ordered US military forces to focus almost exclusively on enforcing the "quarantine" of Venezuelan oil, a US official says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29c3a7ae3d0bfc2c7ac85c07e2b281fc</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Grant expected to remain category one system as it passes Cocos (Keeling) Islands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/tropical-cyclone-grant-impacts-cocos-islands-christmas-day/106178056</link><description>Tropical Cyclone Grant is expected to remain a category one system as it passes just to the north of the Cocos (Keeling) Islands off the West Australian coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ee3c8641c0d4437378e06a43346d1a2</guid></item><item><title>Australia's 'outback fashion capital' promotes healing through fashion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/fitzroy-crossing-fashion-event-helps-to-heal-community/106037952</link><description>Almost three years ago, a region in Western Australia's far north was devastated by once-in-a-century floods. Now fashion is stepping in, to heal scars and promote confidence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e3fc90c6543ea536adf803f980f1417</guid></item><item><title>Analogue camera technicians with decades of experience retiring amid boom in film photography</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/future-of-film-as-camera-repairers-retire/106012478</link><description>As film photography surges in popularity among younger generations, technicians who repair analogue cameras are retiring, raising concerns it will become a dying art.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f2260136cba1cb406538e0cd51e9a96</guid></item><item><title>Why is there a massive camera in this tiny outback town?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/why-is-there-a-massive-camera-in-this-tiny-outback-town-/106178014</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ad7e44111139ee42ee84852115b69d6</guid></item><item><title>Nick Bolkus, long-time Labor senator and Hawke-Keating-era minister, dies aged 75</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/nick-bolkus-obituary/106178484</link><description>Nick Bolkus, the long-time Labor senator who played an influential role in shaping Australia's migration policy under prime minister Paul Keating, has died aged 75.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2580267b3575e4e215ac342a2ffa5f6a</guid></item><item><title>Public assemblies banned for 14 days across Sydney as police enforce new powers under protest laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/public-assemblies-banned-14-days-in-sydney-under-new-protest-law/106178406</link><description>The NSW Police Commissioner, Mal Lanyon, has activated new powers prescribed under changes to NSW protest laws sparked by the terrorist attack at Bondi Beach on December 14.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0ffae786ed4d39fb5070328bf4f1a2a</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Australia leaves out a spinner in all-pace bowling attack for MCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/australia-boxing-day-test-12-man-squad/106178630</link><description>With up to 10mm of grass on the MCG pitch, Australia has opted for a bold and historic option and left out offspinner Todd Murphy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa9a9b3b335c8c7dde4f63a8f42f6ad8</guid></item><item><title>'Scandinavian sleep method' could help your bad sleep</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/scandinavian-sleep-method-hot-cold-doona-temperature/106171152</link><description>This arrangement allows couples to continue sleeping together while meeting each person's individual needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd2b759a8a0d6dd541f517639ef58108</guid></item><item><title>Multiple bushfires threaten homes north and south of Perth, triggering power outages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/christmas-day-boddington-bushfire-emergency/106178756</link><description>Several bushfires burning north and south of Perth have caused major power blackouts, including the entire town of Margaret River.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02cd42472ece8c0d5742158fbddf1ee2</guid></item><item><title>Police make emergency declaration after partial crane collapse on the Gold Coast on Christmas Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/qld-crane-collapse-gold-coast-christmas-day/106178834</link><description>Storms hit south-east Queensland on Christmas Day afternoon, knocking out power to thousands of homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">554a17c52ea5b34c83e1e5244c87a2a7</guid></item><item><title>Pope Leo decries conditions in Gaza during Christmas Day speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/pope-leo-decries-conditions-in-gaza-christmas-speech/106178920</link><description>During his Urbi et Orbi (city and world) speech on Christmas Day, Pope Leo XIV has called for an end to all wars and for people to think about the conditions in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1023451f4ca1f78f346c0e2c228d714b</guid></item><item><title>The marathon mums competing in the Olympics and breaking records postpartum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/marathon-mums-competing-olympics-breaking-records-postpartum/106158638</link><description>For decades, pregnancy was seen as an "injury" that could end a career. But now, determination and growing industry support are seeing marathon-running mothers reach new heights after giving birth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">911ad6e201fbaac1ec3430b377f3fe12</guid></item><item><title>From Spongebob to Orwell: Here's your guide to Boxing Day movies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/what-to-watch-boxing-day-cinemas/106170510</link><description>The soaring mercury has you craving the cool, dark sanctuary of the cinema. But what to see? The art-house awards-season hopeful? The psychological book adaptation? The one with the big snake?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0067604e8d12d4c660cec1c700395679</guid></item><item><title>Gamba grass risks star attractions in NT's beloved Litchfield National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/nt-national-park-under-threat-from-invasive-gamba-grass-weed/106167898</link><description>Much-loved by locals and bringing in more than 250,000 visitors a year, Litchfield National Park has become one of the Northern Territory's star attractions. But it's under threat from a near-invisible invader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b403c062bde0be6fd104443d00f5983e</guid></item><item><title>How to track Sydney to Hobart yacht race 2025 and other questions answered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/sydney-hobart-yacht-race-2025-how-to-watch-explainer/106165964</link><description>Black sails, a tiny cannon, no prize money — everything you need to know about the Sydney to Hobart yacht race, as the 80th edition takes place.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93cb21fc77a0e2af01d8a8b4e6258273</guid></item><item><title>Shield and First Guardian raise the question, who pays when super funds collapse?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/first-guardian-investors-dealt-another-devastating-blow/106145496</link><description>Thousands of First Guardian investors were dealt another devastating blow when it was revealed just $1.6 million had been recovered from the almost $450 million invested in the collapsed fund. Who will end up paying investors back their lost retirement savings?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61ee5120fe363a2c94729fb05ef29323</guid></item><item><title>Monitoring cameras help determine Adélie penguin colony size</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/adelie-penguins-timelapse/106157940</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87708cd86d3a08507b2e7ec75b9abd83</guid></item><item><title>Scientists on 'high alert' as bird flu threat looms over Australian Antarctic Territory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/bird-flu-threat-looms-over-australian-antarctic-territory/106171164</link><description>Preparations are underway for the arrival of the deadly H5 strain of bird flu in the Australian Antarctic Territory, as scientists gather baseline population data so they can measure potential deaths among wildlife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e7609304214a3894f11e91309f5811f</guid></item><item><title>Women and girls coming to the crease in more numbers at regional Victorian cricket clubs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/country-womens-cricket-victoria-batswomen-bowlers/105904124</link><description>More women of all ages are signing up to play cricket in regional Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7db42b0b2843ee1230ad3286d1379a35</guid></item><item><title>Entertainer Kamahl, now 91, reflects on life, career spanning 70 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/kamahl-entertainer-reflects-on-life-70-year-career-racism/106132732</link><description>At 91, Malaysian-born Australian entertainment legend Kamahl reflects on his life and career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b946d4eaecacc1a82baa773ab3a7fab2</guid></item><item><title>The best classical music and jazz stories of 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/best-classical-music-and-jazz-stories-2025/106176460</link><description>From homegrown heroes to visiting legends, here are Australia's favourite classical music and jazz stories this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e20a46b15fc67a0c56dc741372cd716d</guid></item><item><title>Boxing Day Test more than just cricket for descendant of Australia's First XI Aboriginal team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/boxing-day-test-medal-presenter-honours-aboriginal-cricket-team/106137822</link><description>They travelled on horse and cart and were smuggled on a boat for three months to England, the story of the First XI Aboriginal cricket team is being remembered as a descendant presents the Boxing Day medal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b50808a74cf8fa3304dee6cab90223c8</guid></item><item><title>Cricket cartoons illustrate a match to rival the Ashes played by prisoners of war during WWII</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/substitute-ashes-world-war-2-prisoners-of-war/106169886</link><description>As Australia and England clash in The Ashes cricket series, Australian War Memorial historians have uncovered two diaries that recount a cricket series played behind barbed wire in prisoner of war camps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbbcb825611802eb1f7caa6a303768cd</guid></item><item><title>Hoop dreams come true as first Indigenous basketball team heads to USA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/indigenous-basketball-team-heads-to-usa/106158408</link><description>School attendance was just as important as a jump shot for the scouts picking a First Nations team to take part in a prestigious US basketball competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d34d1da0da81d4b5ea855db9d5a3d0b9</guid></item><item><title>Why Australian Open organisers will be torn on offering Nick Kyrgios a wildcard berth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/nick-kyrgios-australian-open-wildcard-update/106179426</link><description>Nick Kyrgios remains one of Australian tennis' biggest names, but, according to Mark Philippoussis, there are clear pros and cons to offering him a wildcard berth for the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db1b5fc77ce0878c8ec246e2f1b02586</guid></item><item><title>New virtual fencing laws could promise safer bushfire response by allowing farmers to move stock remotely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/virtual-fencing-could-help-in-bushfire-response/106170506</link><description>New technology allowing livestock to be remotely moved via electronic collars has been legalised in SA. Industry says virtual fencing has the potential to save animals and even human lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">192897585527f4b7df9b5fd155d53c37</guid></item><item><title>Endangered malleefowl chick saved from fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/endangered-malleefowl-chick-saved-from-fire/106177074</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b90ce9d521644bc3b0b15c52ef61269</guid></item><item><title>Endangered malleefowl chick saved in 2,000-hectare fire at Wyperfeld National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/malleefowl-chick-saved-wyperfeld-national-park-bushfire/106176370</link><description>An endangered malleefowl chick has been saved from a 2,000-hectare bushfire in a regional Victorian national park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddefccd7a2b1c56365c12e2baad72bb7</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Australia all out for 152 on Boxing Day Test, England bowled out for 110 in reply on day one at the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/live-updates-ashes-boxing-day-test-australia-vs-england-day-one/106179504</link><description>Australia lead England by 42 runs on a wild Boxing Day after 20 wickets fall on the first day at the MCG. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c303409339583878a217bf5cfe4bcd88</guid></item><item><title>Driving near Kakadu wetlands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/driving-near-kakadu-wetlands/105848610</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44a6b4f95afbb0fa7eee54fb5a7f017c</guid></item><item><title>King tide at Nightcliff beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/king-tide-at-nightcliff-beach/105848020</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18f6764d3b52708bd856985f15fa3f13</guid></item><item><title>Dead trees in Tommy Cutt creek</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/dead-trees-in-tommy-cutt-creek/105848200</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a02e7b174f7540e1f7c00b2fcb96175</guid></item><item><title>Panning shot over Kakadu National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/panning-shot-over-kakadu-national-park/106179456</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eeb462767c44fbab555df86f304749f4</guid></item><item><title>When can you get a refund or exchange under Australian law?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/what-are-the-return-and-exchange-rights-in-australia/106078512</link><description>It can feel awkward asking for a refund or to exchange an item if you’re not sure what you’re entitled to. We’ve broken it down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2723be7871092c53be9590ed79e4005</guid></item><item><title>Türkiye detains 115 alleged Islamic State members 'planning attacks during Christmas'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/turkiye-detains-115-alleged-is-members/106179536</link><description>Istanbul's prosecutor general says intelligence picked up on plans for potential Islamic State attacks during the end-of-year holiday period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f836656caae2c1112d7b73e0c41506e0</guid></item><item><title>Vladimir Putin critic and pro-war activist sentenced to six years in prison by Russian court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/russian-court-sentences-war-activist-and-putin-critic-to-prison/106179590</link><description>Sergei Udaltsov, the leader of the Left Front movement that opposes President Vladimir Putin, was arrested last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f46694fd12b3eb7d27f87246e14db092</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump launches US strikes against Islamic State militants in Nigeria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/donald-trump-ordered-strikes-against-islamic-state-nigeria/106179626</link><description>Donald Trump says he ordered a "powerful and deadly strike against ISIS terrorist scum" for targeting Christians at levels not seen for years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e78e946ebf1f357d5108534304674ddc</guid></item><item><title>Revellers swarm Coogee Beach for Christmas Day celebrations after Bronte Beach off-limits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/nsw-christmas-cleanup-at-coogee-beach/106179370</link><description>As thousands of revellers spend Boxing Day recovering, Randwick City Council staff worked through the night to remove 20 tonnes of rubbish following a wild pop-up Christmas Day dance party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd1eb32a6dbb9b663390c3bdee8ebf93</guid></item><item><title>Tim Wilson desires to one day lead the federal Liberal Party</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/tim-wilson-liberal-party-politics-now-the-interview/106162420</link><description>In a broad ranging interview for the Politics Now podcast, Liberal MP Tim Wilson speaks about what the Liberal Party should be fighting for and why he would one day like to be its leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0109c7585acd76bdfd34229961e7858a</guid></item><item><title>Fishing facilities lacking despite high boat ownership in Karratha</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/karratha-boating-fishing-lack-of-toilets-filleting-facilities/106093260</link><description>Female fishers say the lack of toilet facilities at Karratha boat ramps does not cater for the increasing number of women on the water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef18396e1b505919d63f589ce903e197</guid></item><item><title>Boddington gold mine infrastructure damaged by bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/boddington-fire-western-australia-christmas-fires/106179544</link><description>The bushfire has burnt through more than 4,000 hectares.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e98a4c122f6d614247d735cd5c74867d</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast exclusion zone displacing tourists will continue until Tuesday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/damaged-crane-gold-coast-80-tourists-evacuated/106179414</link><description>Holiday-makers spent Christmas night in temporary accommodation after a crane damaged in a Gold Coast storm caused authorities to evacuate several streets around Southport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0e6df85ea6ebde13f9f577d928f21f5</guid></item><item><title>2025 Sydney to Hobart Yacht Race: Day one of the 80th edition of the blue water classic, as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/sydney-to-hobart-yacht-race-live-blog/106179718</link><description>Master Lock Comanche takes over from LawConnect late on day one of the Sydney to Hobart, as tough conditions take their toll on the fleet, forcing a number of retirements. Look back at the action in our blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a51b09c950062dc669c8df81130ac30e</guid></item><item><title>Shopper stampedes are a thing of the past, but Boxing Day sales are still a big driver of spending</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/shoppers-hit-boxing-day-sales/106179634</link><description>The Australian Retailers Association is predicting a 4 per cent rise in spending in the Boxing Day sales, despite tough economic conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1fccd889508af2afe87117790536d76</guid></item><item><title>Teenager charged over Nazi salutes granted bail after spending Christmas Day in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/teen-zachery-hook-charged-nazi-salutes-canberra/106179974</link><description>An 18-year-old Canberra man accused of performing Nazi salutes in public and spreading extremist propaganda has been released on strict bail conditions after spending Christmas Day in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e82e1ecbbb5eea6afa21d1c319e3b449</guid></item><item><title>Poland intercepts Russian plane over Baltic, reports airspace breaches from Belarus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/poland-intercepts-russian-plane-over-baltic/106179994</link><description>Poland has warned several incidents regarding airspace during the holiday season may signal a provocation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e6bb0e0fce20217418dbbc6e3e3d1dd</guid></item><item><title>US Department of Defense releases missile launch video after northwest Nigeria operation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/us-missile-launch-video-nigeria/106180096</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05859f74ae3122414840f1530da6383c</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with assaulting pregnant woman, firing at police in Christmas Eve stand-off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/canberra-man-charged-firing-gun-police-whitlam/106179976</link><description>A 39-year-old man has been remanded in custody after police allege he fired multiple shots at officers during a Christmas Eve incident in Canberra's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a30589cbe907ba80131c1057fc542f0</guid></item><item><title>Paddleboarders rescued after drifting from Portarlington to Wyndham Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/victoria-family-rescued-christmas-day-paddelboard-mishap/106179858</link><description>Police say two holidaymakers are lucky to be alive after being rescued from the cold waters of Port Phillip, south-west of Melbourne, on Christmas Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50da2ebb51bc40fb017ee61ba1c7f634</guid></item><item><title>Japan okays record defence budget amid rising tensions with China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/japan-approves-record-defence-spending-china-tensions/106180112</link><description>Japan's cabinet approves a record defence budget plan aiming to fortify its strike-back capability and coastal defence amid rising regional tensions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">226514049ef3fb20b15245e7b63db459</guid></item><item><title>Sydney to Hobart pays tribute to Bondi victims with petals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/sydney-to-hobart-boat-tributes-bondi-victims-with-petals-/106180276</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1eb26c06a311d6aa9fafe2681d251de5</guid></item><item><title>Kazuaki Ono's photo exhibition Southern Crust melds Australian scenery with our bakery culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/southern-crust-bakery-photography-exhibition/106169972</link><description>Kazuaki Ono wanted to entice people from Japan to visit Australia by showing we have as much to offer with our food culture as we do with our iconic scenery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92d7b7dca9079219e2846df04f166a65</guid></item><item><title>The best documentaries to binge in the weird week after Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/best-docos-to-binge-over-christmas-summer/106022170</link><description>Summer is here and so are those long leisurely days of nothing following Christmas. Here are five documentaries that will help you while away the time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e551aa5c5e8b609e0c5d9d9e10e9bab2</guid></item><item><title>Harry Brook's on the attack, Cameron Green runs himself out and Josh Tongue cashes in — quick hits from Boxing Day at the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/ashes-test-england-australia-quick-hits-harry-brook-cam-green/106179806</link><description>A record crowd for cricket at the MCG saw another fast-forward day of Ashes action as calamitous run outs and wild Bazball batting took centre stage. Here are the quick hits from the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75bc2f7fccf9d4a6d699188d9e20e531</guid></item><item><title>Australia's batting headaches masked again by dismal English failure on wild Ashes Boxing Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/cowardly-english-batting-spares-australia-s-boxing-day-blushes/106180182</link><description>Australia's batting order is unsettled, unbalanced and out of form, but it matters little as England throws in the towel and considers the challenge of a Boxing Day Ashes Test all too hard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">187ff36f0baab20891ef104286fac289</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy plans to meet with Trump as peace plan with Russia inches closer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/volodymyr-zelenskyy-donald-trump-meeting-peace-plan-russia/106180632</link><description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy says he is planning to meet with US President Donald Trump on Sunday to search for ways to end the war with Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c94842f6bc240f2c1f589fba07963d6d</guid></item><item><title>Today in history, December 27: Benazir Bhutto assasinated at election rally by teenage militant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/today-history-december-27-benazir-bhutto-assasination-pakistan/106165790</link><description>During the tense campaign for her third term as prime minister of Pakistan, Benazir Bhutto survived one attempt on her life before she was shot dead by a teenage suicide bomber on December 27, 2007. She helped to build a political dynasty that continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">493a29be57b003ed7d2fcd17f5ab5bf9</guid></item><item><title>Family unearths story of Australian cricket's 'girl Bradman' Hazel Pritchard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/cricket-hazel-pritchard-girl-bradman-women-cricket-test-1937/106100096</link><description>There was no central catalogue for the scattered histories of women's cricket. That may be about to change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75fa9e9dfca84c469dc8ce1a5f7d1c67</guid></item><item><title>The 'Epstein Files' reveal how Ghislaine Maxwell helped pull young girls into a paedophile's web</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/epstein-files-victim-grooming/106179662</link><description>The arts camp was prestigious, and "Jane" had travelled almost 2,500 kilometres to attend. As she sat by herself on a bench between classes, a man and a woman approached her.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a45298537181d5d1a679e98cdd53ae08</guid></item><item><title>England's soft underbelly exposed again as 20 Boxing Day wickets put MCG pitch in firing line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/england-batting-criticised-mcg-pitch-20-wickets-boxing-day/106180560</link><description>England's batters once again fall flat on their faces in the face of tricky conditions at the MCG for the Boxing Day Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8066d2349a2bd017297819914f562f0f</guid></item><item><title>A quick guide to the best fabrics and fibres for summer and their sustainability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/what-fibres-and-fabrics-to-wear-in-summer/105981546</link><description>What our clothes are made of can make a big difference when it comes to keeping cool, but not all fabrics are created equal. Here is what to look for — and avoid — during the warmer months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dc31cbc8f4af5932b93e4fb5b030ee6</guid></item><item><title>25 years on, the search continues for stars of the Sydney Olympics' closing ceremony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/sydney-olympics-kewpie-doll-search/106169888</link><description>For Trevor Harvey, honouring a departed mate meant one thing — finding a 6-metre-tall Kewpie doll from the Sydney Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2db87d7aa3f1086c01d0693d98b03505</guid></item><item><title>Sydney to Hobart race crews doing it tough in challenging conditions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/sydney-to-hobart-yacht-race-day-two/106180992</link><description>Crews are battling sea sickness and tough conditions as teams head for the finish in the 2025 Sydney to Hobart yacht race.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0256d5474c3476a9c0ba3461c1ee630d</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal community tension in Victoria's north amid health board division</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/aboriginal-community-tension-mallee-board-division/106170928</link><description>An annual meeting to elect a new board at Mallee District Aboriginal Services has led to divisions among members and incoming board members as the chair announces elections will be re-run.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f068d39e8567f078e563191fa53cb96</guid></item><item><title>When green energy threatens what it is meant to save</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/nelson-wetlands-green-energy-boom-planning-protections/106097868</link><description>In a tiny town near the Victoria–South Australia border, a proposed wind farm near a protected wetland is posing a big question for Australia's planning regulators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cce00efa3282f14d1cb581e60a16068</guid></item><item><title>BBL title-holders Hobart Hurricanes beat Perth Scorchers but lose Tim David to hamstring injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/tim-david-injures-hamstring-as-hurricanes-beat-scorchers/106181008</link><description>Hobart's title defence suffers a huge blow after star batter Tim David injures his hamstring in his team's four-wicket win over the Scorchers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83ac28695423a38f74cc26978038bce4</guid></item><item><title>The best vantage points and everything else you need to know about Sydney's New Year's Eve fireworks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/where-to-watch-the-new-years-eve-fireworks-in-sydney-2025/106175504</link><description>Sydney's New Year's Eve celebrations will this year pay tribute to the victims of the Bondi terror attack, with events to feature a heavy police presence. Here is everything you need to know to plan your night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf93969efada38d9bce589ed6247600b</guid></item><item><title>South Australian playwright pays tribute to late partner in new production</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/anthony-nocera-log-boy-play/106095628</link><description>An upcoming South Australian playwright was writing a horror, comedy show about the prospect of losing a much older partner, then it happened to him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">459b7018fcf05da5cd1894814562d377</guid></item><item><title>Australian medical history – the heart donor who still walks the earth 20 years later</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/qld-domino-transplant-lucinda-simpson-cystic-fibrosis/106127132</link><description>Lucinda is a member of an exclusive club — living heart donors, and is the only woman to have a baby after a heart-lung-liver transplant</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fdc746668c7434580fe039bc48bbe9f</guid></item><item><title>13 long reads to catch up on for your summer holiday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/long-reads-2025-virginia-trioli/106175224</link><description>Here we've gathered a bunch of other things to read while you're relaxing over summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96a03c3f95f56c5d4532a4ecf3388352</guid></item><item><title>Ladybirds set loose at Australian Parliament House in Canberra over summer to take out pests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/ladybugs-released-at-canberra-parliament-house/106160100</link><description>When politicians and most staff are away for the summer holidays, a ravenous group of fly-in workers descend on Parliament House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d0fc288cf443c20ee792420a6420b93</guid></item><item><title>175-year-old Nor' West Bend Station reopened to public after decades of restoration work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/175-year-old-nor-west-bend-station-reopened-to-public/106028646</link><description>History is being brought back to life at a former pastoral station that has seen drought, boom and bust over the course of its 175 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8940f35a06954e50ec7e7c189ecb994a</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: England wins first Test in Australia in 5,468 days after two-day MCG match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/ashes-boxing-day-test-live-australia-england-day-two/106181180</link><description>England survives a nervy run chase to win its first Test match on Australian soil since 2011 in a manic two-day encounter in Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bf833f810194620176aaebe677ed1b4</guid></item><item><title>Mosque blast during Friday noon prayers kills eight in Syria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/mosque-blast-during-friday-noon-prayers-kills-eight-in-syria/106181170</link><description>The attack has been claimed by the ultra-conservative Sunni group Saraya Ansar al-Sunnah, which was also responsible for a Damascus church bombing in June.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4f4106013b1c8b4b610fbfa10b3cbb7</guid></item><item><title>Trio of retirees from Dongara win award for community rubbish collection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/dongara-roadside-relics-group-collecting-litter-wins-award/106154988</link><description>Armed with gloves, bags, buckets and tongs, a trio of passionate rubbish removalists have picked up an award in this regional Western Australia town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfadfe96068151ef0ee3f0fa86954cde</guid></item><item><title>Storm Hunter returns for the Australian summer targeting a top doubles ranking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/storm-warning-aussie-wants-to-regain-world-number-one-status/106181154</link><description>Popular Australian Storm Hunter is back from injury and adamant she can return to the form that made her the world's top-ranked doubles player.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd5d5e8783ea370e7a17bcad44a8bacc</guid></item><item><title>Australians are drinking less, but one cohort won't give up the booze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/australians-drinking-less-older-taking-bigger-health-risks/105371018</link><description>Health-conscious Australians may be thinking twice about having that first or second beer, but not all of us are getting the message when it comes to alcohol and risky drinking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fd92f06e70a0c7e12bc8de8191b8249</guid></item><item><title>These volunteer firefighters keep communities safe. Here's why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/volunteer-firefighters-risk-their-lives-to-keep-communities-safe/106139496</link><description>Volunteer firefighters put their lives on the line for their community, despite facing extreme situations, heightened health risks and constant exposure to traumatic events.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e5df5e52758b691d4ab28b9ed0d45a1</guid></item><item><title>China hits US defence firms with sanctions over arms sales to Taiwan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/china-sanctions-us-defence-firms-over-arms-sales-taiwan/106181220</link><description>China urged the US to "stop the dangerous moves of arming Taiwan" after its multi-billion-dollar sale of weapons last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33227ba851bab9d9f659aabc61e30a14</guid></item><item><title>Ukrainian capital Kyiv under Russian attack, officials say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/ukrainian-capital-kyiv-under-russian-attack-officials-say/106181284</link><description>Explosions have been heard, air defences are in operation and the military is on alert for impending missile attacks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4965b085c5fd94c37f6cd1db355ea66f</guid></item><item><title>How a tsunami in Sri Lanka sparked a push to prevent drowning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/sri-lanka-tsunami-solutions-to-drownings-waterways/106173020</link><description>What began as tsunami relief, has become something more powerful — teaching children not to fear the water that surrounds them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e4eb5c147fe58006ee735956f6a75f7</guid></item><item><title>Thailand and Cambodia agree to ceasefire, ending weeks of clashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/thailand-and-cambodia-agree-to-ceasefire-/106181650</link><description>The ceasefire will take effect on Saturday at noon local time, in a conflict which has displaced more than half a million people on both sides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3865afc2e60cb84e441f304589306cc</guid></item><item><title>Urban water restrictions likely across Victoria as dam levels drop and dry summer predicted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/urban-water-restrictions-likely-across-victoria-dam-levels-drop/106181336</link><description>Victoria's water storage levels have dropped to 61 per cent capacity after most of the state recorded below average rainfall in 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">802ede04d18fcccb9d3a0a58674a6485</guid></item><item><title>Robots, AI and 'smart tourism' will change how we travel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/tourist-new-technology-ai-travel-smart-tourism/105956560</link><description>Will new technology lead to streamlined service and stress-free travel, or will it fundamentally change tourism and tourist destinations?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6265082f5c6968dacc7e1d1fd35c0efb</guid></item><item><title>Residents return home as threat level downgraded for Boddington fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/residents-return-home-after-boddington-fire/106181310</link><description>Residents have begun returning to their homes after a bushfire burning south-east of Perth forced them to flee on Christmas Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38d7667979dbb4c735e54fcc93462d7a</guid></item><item><title>Hobart family reunited with dog nearly four years after it disappeared from home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/tasmanian-family-reunited-with-missing-dog-found-living-wild/106181610</link><description>A blurry photo on social media has led to a Hobart family reuniting with their missing dog nearly four years after it vanished from their home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a92c519decdd8e65e93256421933dd9b</guid></item><item><title>Gus Atkinson injured and Marnus Labuschagne struggles again as Bazball pays off for England — five quick hits from day two of the Boxing Day Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/ashes-boxing-day-two-quick-hits-atkinson-bazball-wins/106181258</link><description>Bazball finally has its day in the Aussie sun as England's audacious tactics pay off despite another hit to its pace stocks. Here are the quick hits from day two at the MCG.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ea1ecf2308c1e2b3b75e519e61af7b8</guid></item><item><title>Australia belted, England vindicated and Test cricket wounded in MCG Ashes Test farce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/australia-belted-england-vindicated-test-cricket-wounded-mcg/106181362</link><description>As England deservedly celebrates a long-awaited Test win in Australia, everyone else involved counts the cost of a farcical and damaging two-day disaster at the MCG.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b8c1e011213e214665690d118a882bc</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Calls for MCG Boxing Day Test pitch to be rated 'poor' as England and Australia batting criticised</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/boxing-day-ashes-test-ends-inside-two-days/106181452</link><description>After the first Test of the Ashes series sensationally ended in just two days, Cricket Australia hoped it wouldn't see that again for a century. It's happened again five weeks later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bef5f9857484c314cb5ce8fecde9597f</guid></item><item><title>Russian drones, missiles pound Ukraine ahead of Zelenskyy-Trump meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/russian-strikes-pound-ukraine-ahead-of-zelenskyy-trump-meeting/106181990</link><description>Russia has attacked Ukraine with hundreds of missiles and drones ahead of what President Volodymyr Zelenskyy said would be a crucial meeting with Donald Trump to work out a deal to end nearly four years of war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0ac272b1e62ea83e94bba00d6fc8eee</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz tournament: Think you are good at quizzes? I dare you to try these 50 questions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/hard-quiz-tournament-weekly-trivia/106130622</link><description>Looking to settle who is the smartest in your family? Challenge them to a Hard Quiz tournament: five rounds, 50 questions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcd07256f1bb8166d44f0919bc31e28f</guid></item><item><title>Today in History: Top-secret Manhattan Project quietly approved</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/manhattan-project-roosevelt-nuclear-bomb-oppenheimer-japan/106174568</link><description>On December 28, 1942, a US president formally approved an investment in the top-secret project to create nuclear weapons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b97d3cfa3d0bc0fb02cbfcc70b2cd52</guid></item><item><title>Steroid use is 'exploding' — but there are no clinical guidelines on how to quit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/steroid-use-increase-quit-guidelines-australia/106043898</link><description>A rising number of Australians are using steroids. But one expert says a lack of knowledge and widespread stigma make it tough to get clinical support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c5f65de8977165f59203d14fa8e06ac</guid></item><item><title>Parents in China use AI technology to monitor children's homework</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/parents-in-china-using-ai-monitor-children-homework-social-media/106176546</link><description>AI is becoming a regular presence at homework time in many Chinese households. Experts say where families draw the line matters more than the technology itself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7ba3d6cc4fd5d41e9f23b056dc5c3ab</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: How the internet reacted to England winning the Boxing Day Test in two days</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/how-the-internet-reacted-to-englands-boxing-day-ashes-test-win/106179786</link><description>The English swashed their buckles and came out on top in a Boxing Day Test that was played in fast-forward. Here's how the internet reacted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f25b29f0ff7539560bcb11f144f4fbd7</guid></item><item><title>More than a quarter of Sydney to Hobart fleet retires as leaders head down Tasmania's east coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/sydney-to-hobart-yacht-race-retirements-rough-conditions/106181970</link><description>Crews have been battling challenging conditions, damage and sea sickness as the leading yachts are expected to arrive in Hobart later today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05c650c16301bfe04ba6f9a8c2a071d9</guid></item><item><title>Cyber attacks that occurred this year and how you can protect your data</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/cyber-attacks-2025-and-ways-to-protect-your-data/106113950</link><description>More than 500 data breaches were reported in Australia over the first half of 2025 alone, but there are some ways you can minimise your risk of being caught up in one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6598bb0502d89389e7d5e5b3034648f</guid></item><item><title>How the teen social media ban is impacting Australia’s multicultural communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/teens-stay-connected-to-overseas-family-post-social-media-ban/106177038</link><description>Sydney teenager Ilia Kyrychenko was relieved to delete his accounts after the social media ban, but the change is making it more difficult to connect with his loved ones in Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a741447e2137a617d80fba502cade1e</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Heat beats Adelaide Strikers by seven runs, thanks to debutant Tom Balkin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/heat-call-on-lightning-fast-debutant-in-rollicking-bbl-win/106182342</link><description>Injury to Shaheen Afridi leaves debutant Tom Balkin to bowl the final over, and the 21-year-old delivers to help Brisbane Heat to a seven-run BBL win over Adelaide Strikers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf24169f767377c226a5fad18d15e2da</guid></item><item><title>Local Government Inspectorate closed years-long Hepburn Hub investigation without finishing report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/local-government-inspectorate-rex-theatre-hepburn-hub-probe/106038890</link><description>The integrity agency tasked with keeping the local government sector in check is under fire after an ABC investigation raised questions over whether it was properly empowered to carry out its core functions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de5d8811badcc83af3f6fddc72df7cf1</guid></item><item><title>Experts say climate change bigger threat to biodiversity than renewable energy projects</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/renewable-energy-impacts-kentbruck-wind-farm/106157018</link><description>As the green energy boom gathers pace, experts say climate change is a bigger threat to biodiversity than wind farms and other renewables projects.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e664a3bfdc63f8077cf844a68acce4f</guid></item><item><title>What was on summer reading lists 100 years ago, in 1925?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/summer-reading-list-1925-human-experience-time-travel/106172974</link><description>There are books from authors that would become household names — F. Scott Fitzgerald and A.A Milne among them — and books that are now banned in some countries. But what can we learn from what people were reading in 1925?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d08c1d2e3ba6ff50a847933c46b8cd8a</guid></item><item><title>Mentors gave me confidence to navigate life with a disability. Now I'm giving back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/mentors-gave-me-confidence-to-navigate-life-with-a-disability/106169450</link><description>Other people with lived experience of blindness gave ABC reporter Nas Campanella the confidence to navigate life. Her mentee, Lily, is enjoying similar benefits.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f2710fbd235d36e292f977452d42c6</guid></item><item><title>Dingo management should be 'non-lethal', traditional owners say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/non-lethal-dingo-management-push-by-traditional-owners/105807306</link><description>When Sonya sees a black-and-tan dingo, she feels a connection to family and Country, but many landholders see them as livestock-killing pests. Can graziers and dingoes co-exist?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dbd93a43b5a77e1ac9c73c36cabab5e</guid></item><item><title>A rescued dingo puppy explores its new surroundings.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/a-dingo-puppy-walks-awkwardly-across-some-grass/106127112</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1548d921911e3b45201eeeaee566b96</guid></item><item><title>Weatherald, Labuschagne, Green under Ashes selection pressure after MCG loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/australias-shaky-batters-face-scg-selection-scrutiny/106182432</link><description>Jake Weatherald, Marnus Labuschagne and Cameron Green all face selection pressure following double failures in Australia's jarring loss at the MCG.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50bc3003c4bc68d8bf3b70a89abf98a5</guid></item><item><title>A career for all ages: Meet the truckies keeping Australia on the road</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/truck-driver-hangs-up-keys-after-six-decades-on-the-road/106146694</link><description>At 83, truck driver Terry Bairstow says he would not change a thing after spending six decades behind the wheel carting grain and sheep.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d377650bf8f1a32fa4c0812bd7846a6a</guid></item><item><title>What to know about the Islamic State militants targeted by US air strikes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/trump-us-air-strikes-is-militants-nigeria/106181242</link><description>With US President Donald Trump hinting at plans for further strikes on IS militants in Nigeria, here's a rundown on what you need to know about the conflict.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">409b97b5b2a7281b8083c6c8490f3f06</guid></item><item><title>Hands-on memories spark connection for dementia residents at western NSW aged care home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/adult-activity-board-for-dementia-patients/106173414</link><description>Creating meaningful, sensory activities for people living with dementia can be challenging, particularly when many traditional options feel more suited to children than adults with a lifetime of lived experience behind them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a77900a93309dfceb04ffb9fbaf8f904</guid></item><item><title>Man charged for allegedly displaying hate symbol tattoos at Newcastle beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/man-charged-for-allegedly-displaying-antisemitic-tattoos/106182526</link><description>A man has been charged for allegedly displaying what police have called "hate symbol" tattoos at a beach in Newcastle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f53322ab0acd29d0350f0c5924bc74bc</guid></item><item><title>Rockingham's leap to major AUKUS defence hub leaves some locals trepidatious</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/rockingham-locals-worried-about-impact-of-aukus-defence-hub/106153364</link><description>Rockingham in Perth's south is fast becoming a crucial part of the AUKUS nuclear submarine deal, with promises of a big boost in jobs and infrastructure — but it's also leaving residents afraid for their lives and lifestyle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ebc36485eb2bb6c367b21f80c2942a0</guid></item><item><title>From soapboxes to social media: Two artists shaping Queensland's bush art scene</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/artists-shaping-queensland-s-bush-art-scene/106175014</link><description>Marion Moore is 101. Zarabella Bambling is 23. Despite their differences, both women have just celebrated the same major achievement as bush artists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">427d241e1ba0b484ea9d0a3fced806c4</guid></item><item><title>Former Australian fast bowler Brett Lee inducted into the Australian Cricket Hall of Fame</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/aussie-speedster-brett-lee-given-hall-of-fame-nod/106182682</link><description>Renowned for his express pace, former fast bowler Brett Lee is the latest inductee into the Australian Cricket Hall of Fame.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40162193553c6a743c9d53320dcd5be1</guid></item><item><title>The case of the Guayaquil Four places scrutiny on Ecuador's security crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/guayaquil-four-sentence-lays-bare-racism-and-security-in-ecuador/106173084</link><description>In the weeks before Christmas, four boys under 16 left home to play a game of soccer. Their forced disappearance at the hands of Ecuador's military has been labelled a national "turning point".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49b1ef624f5f479dd3ab2d8593a6c9e2</guid></item><item><title>Spanish soccer coach missing after tourist boat sinks in Indonesia's Komodo National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/spanish-soccer-coach-missing-after-boat-sank-komodo-park/106182542</link><description>The Labuan Bajo port authority attributes the sinking to high waves of up to three metres, but rescuers say they are "determined" to find survivors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5441712670751126c6e63aca3be00d2</guid></item><item><title>'Grumpy' seal disrupts Blairgowrie boat race on Victoria's Mornington Peninsula</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/grumpy-seal-blairgowrie-petersville-regatta/106182708</link><description>A wild seal dubbed "Grumpy" causes some commotion at an annual boat race on the Mornington Peninsula, outside Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">083e2941bae98fafdb7d5202d1fe7c23</guid></item><item><title>MCG curator Matt Page admits Boxing Day Test pitch 'favoured the bowlers too much'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/mcc-boss-defends-curator-after-two-day-ashes-test/106182802</link><description>MCC boss Stuart Fox staunchly defends chief curator Matt Page after a wild Boxing Day Test finishes within two days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1acfc9a80c189932f3941f9cf9cb33be</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with assaulting Labor identity Tim Picton granted bail in Perth court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/tim-picton-family-statement-alleged-northbridge-assault/106182738</link><description>A 20-year-old man is granted bail after allegedly assaulting Tim Picton, a prominent Labor Party identity — an attack police prosecutors say may leave him permanently disabled, if he survives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">582a30d244334d7fc711737f77e529db</guid></item><item><title>Coral Adventurer runs aground off Papua New Guinea with 120 people onboard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/cruise-ship-coral-adventurer-runs-aground-off-papua-new-guinea/106182788</link><description>The Coral Adventurer has run aground off the coast of Papua New Guinea with more than 120 people aboard, two months after the death of a passenger allegedly left behind on a Great Barrier Reef island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6567446a57129047ac675b525e0e1c3</guid></item><item><title>SA independent MP Nick McBride charged with assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/sa-independent-mp-nick-mcbride-charged/106182668</link><description>Police say they responded to reports of a domestic assault at a home in South Australia's south-east on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc915b603692b5192afe65dd47c0b132</guid></item><item><title>Extreme fire conditions forecast for South Australia on Monday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/sa-fire-season-extreme-danger-warning/106182676</link><description>Authorities are warning people to be prepared as hot and windy conditions sweep across the state in what the CFS says will be a "challenging day" for firefighters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">316a25463dd2f2187a498f42603be372</guid></item><item><title>Taiwan's cunning tax compliance makes most shopping receipts a ticket in a lottery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/taiwan-receipt-lottery-win-money-from-shopping/106140828</link><description>Most shopping receipts in Taiwan are also tickets for a lottery run every second month by the government to increase tax compliance, and there are some big prizes up for grabs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25f5e0a517eb8eafa70303f39fc1010c</guid></item><item><title>Comanche takes out line honours in 2025 Sydney to Hobart Yacht Race — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/live-blog-sydney-to-hobart-yacht-race-tracking-the-finish/106182756</link><description>Master Lock Comanche claims line honours in the 80th edition of the gruelling Sydney to Hobart yacht race, with a stunning daylight hours finish, making up for retiring early in last year's race.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">338d82dc7e18ccdd20b895f471a22571</guid></item><item><title>Comanche wins Sydney to Hobart line honours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/comanche-wins-sydney-to-hobart-line-honours/106183250</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a72afefec57b8ae17123abe534199049</guid></item><item><title>Brigitte Bardot, iconic French actor, sex symbol and animal rights campaigner, dies aged 91</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/brigitte-bardot-dies-age-91/102626484</link><description>The French actor and singer was a screen siren of the 1950s and 1960s who in later life became a prominent animal rights campaigner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a8bea482f12114393ea501ba0b3a9a0</guid></item><item><title>Brigitte Bardot was the world's 'sex kitten'. Her nonchalance was all French</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/brigitte-bardot-sex-symbol-fashion-darling-and-french-icon/105927998</link><description>Few epitomised French chic like Brigitte Bardot, the doe-eyed beauty whose sensuality rocked a post-war world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60d23ab3a781560aba2c74662576b8d4</guid></item><item><title>Families of Bondi victims call for federal royal commission</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/bondi-beach-victim-families-call-for-federal-royal-comission/106183188</link><description>Loved ones of those killed and injured in the Bondi Beach attack say rising antisemitism requires a "powerful national response", piling pressure on Anthony Albanese for a royal commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6fc9a1e1906617a1395c8773838364e</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios defeats Aryna Sabalenka in latest 'battle of the sexes'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/nick-kyrgios-aryna-sabalenka-battle-of-the-sexes-live-blog/106182808</link><description>Australia's Nick Kyrgios defeated women's world number one Aryna Sabalenka in the latest "battle of the sexes". The Aussie, who has fallen outside the ATP top 600 after barely playing for three years, won 6-3, 6-3.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">190b8c7e84e5d376abc1085871d67f15</guid></item><item><title>A growing number of older women surfers are showing age is just a state of mind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/older-women-surfing-trends/105867538</link><description>When Katie Pahlow turned 60, she decided to finally bite the bullet and book herself in for some surf lessons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7393da40072bb0d63dcf47898161a0db</guid></item><item><title>This week in history quiz, December 29: How well do you remember this week in history?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/this-week-in-history-quiz-december-29/106174918</link><description>Test your knowledge with questions about Shane Warne, Frank Sinatra and Australia's first stamp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">896dd0819b196cdd114099a694a97a41</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Larcombe's journey back to the top of the paraclimbing world after devastating injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/sarah-larcombe-paraclimbing-injury-arapiles-world-championships/106018328</link><description>When Sarah Larcombe fell off Mount Arapiles in February, she thought she just sprained her ankle. What followed was months of ups and downs ending in a stunning world championships result.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f086b176ddcd0acf46baf29b3420471</guid></item><item><title>Aid agencies fear lifesaving program banned in Gaza under new Israeli requirements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/aid-agencies-fear-lifesaving-program-blockage-into-gaza-/106181964</link><description>The Israeli government has introduced new rules for aid organisations, including that they must not engage in any activities or criticism which "delegitimise" the state of Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd0ed41a1ad1defc29299a64e4369121</guid></item><item><title>Inside Big Ben, a London icon that's been ringing since 1859</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/inside-big-ben-the-bell-ringing-in-new-years-day/106172402</link><description>It's among the world's most photographed landmarks, a symbol of the United Kingdom and an engineering marvel. And for London's Big Ben the most important night of the year is fast approaching.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fb7606f57e5c6ab58277e445e0284f5</guid></item><item><title>Furious customers slam ASIC for ignoring Zone RV whistleblower complaints before collapse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/furious-customers-asic-whistleblower-zone-rv-caravan-collapse/106169334</link><description>Anger is growing after revelations the corporate watchdog failed to investigate allegations against luxury caravan manufacturer Zone RV.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c22815f3508ce96be6e70f36ef42f7d3</guid></item><item><title>Australia's driver courtesy wave dying out, say truckies, but experiment proves wave still alive on back roads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/australian-drivers-truckies-courtesy-wave/106152822</link><description>For generations, the courtesy wave has been etched into the Australian culture, but is it on the verge of dying?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab1044fced53244ab59b2127f9073c74</guid></item><item><title>Overall winner yet to be decided as Sydney to Hobart yacht race enters fourth day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/sydney-to-hobart-yacht-race-enters-day-four/106183294</link><description>The yacht race has entered the fourth day, after Master Lock Comanche claimed line honours late on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4cba130833aabf1a653c8633a657a2a</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy says progress made on peace deal, but Donald Trump says 'thorny issues' remain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/trump-meets-zelenskyy-to-discuss-ukraine-peace-plan/106183658</link><description>Volodymyr Zelenskyy says a security guarantee between Ukraine and the US as part of a peace deal is "100 per cent agreed", while Donald Trump says there are still one or two "thorny issues" to finalise in the deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06163790a274f36391c30a19988e561a</guid></item><item><title>Concerns medical weight-loss treatments are being advertised to vulnerable eating disorder patients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/juniper-telehealth-concerns-weight-loss-treatment-glp1/106114626</link><description>Eating disorder bodies are raising concerns about weight-loss treatments being prescribed by telehealth companies, one of which ran a Black Friday sale to promote its services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d11ae8b27f1bc3eef0a9dee97b0a2f</guid></item><item><title>Young women join Country Women's Association Sydney branch in droves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/country-womens-association-cwa-in-sydney-young-women-joining/105941208</link><description>More young women are joining the Country Women's Association's city branches, with a passion for jams and scones along with social connection and purpose.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67607c13646f850e0435fa1c89495c0d</guid></item><item><title>Dad and his boys stranded in outback after intense rain cuts roads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/northern-and-western-queensland-brace-for-flooding/106183228</link><description>Intense rainfall across the north and west of Queensland is forecast to cause widespread flooding and damaging winds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">388080b10ccb39a9e28e29aca2db93f8</guid></item><item><title>Voter turnout lower than expected in Myanmar's first election since 2020</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/voter-turnout-low-myanmar-first-election-2020/106183648</link><description>Myanmar's election has been widely dismissed as a sham by many governments and human rights activists who have said the military will use proxy candidates to legitimise their rule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d51e58cecc72915c62d1db7781e09955</guid></item><item><title>Travis Head happy to see out Ashes as Australian opener before working out future role</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/australias-travis-head-not-fazed-on-opening-role-in-future/106183666</link><description>Australia star Travis Head says he is not precious about continuing to open the batting beyond this Ashes and will bat wherever the coaches tell him to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">922094f96e3a457a294c7309ef6a65a5</guid></item><item><title>AI powered 2025's economy to record highs. So why are only robots smiling?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/end-of-year-economics-analysis-wrap/106176480</link><description>This year saw economies survive tariff shocks and markets burst through record highs, but it doesn't feel like a party because so many people aren't invited.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6da1698c0a40d26aaf7b2833b7f573d8</guid></item><item><title>Deadly varroa mite threatens half of Canberra’s beehives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/act-varroa-mite-wipe-out-half-bees-two-years/106148658</link><description>A fast-spreading parasite is expected to devastate local bee colonies over the next two years, affecting commercial and backyard crops.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8efde471e61f47b153c0556497f33df6</guid></item><item><title>LGBTQIA+ focused boxing class combatting loneliness amid warnings about social isolation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/lgbtqia-boxing-class-tackling-loneliness/106034550</link><description>One in three adults experience social isolation in what experts say is a "dangerous" issue in society. One suburban boxing group is working to tackle the issue, focused on the LGBTQIA+ community more at risk of loneliness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be1b7e6c38093ce747c6d1f9fa059918</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Hayley upgraded to category two system, as northern WA residents told to prepare</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/cyclone-hayley-forms-off-wa-coast-broome-in-watch-zone/106182876</link><description>Residents in WA's north are on alert following the formation of Tropical Cyclone Hayley off the coast overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf432452bba2d586f8686b2bbf83b502</guid></item><item><title>Wet season's arrival prompts moves to shore up food security in Far North Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/flooded-roads-cause-food-insecurity-in-far-north-queensland/106176990</link><description>Earlier this year, a once-in-a-century flood devastated Ingham and cut the main supply route between Cairns and Townsville. Now, as intense rainfall once again triggers multiple warnings and floods roads across northern Queensland, communities are taking steps to prevent another food shortage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9171d9c772b41bbf73794cbd198be777</guid></item><item><title>How vintage black-and-white films are making a splash back in colour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/revitalising-vintage-films/105721412</link><description>Would those classic black-and-white films be the same if viewed in full colour?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">920bdb4c48f10f5d070dc6a984c533b4</guid></item><item><title>Australian rowers targetting Los Angeles Olympics after breakthrough medal in coastal beach sprints</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/quiet-confidence-aussie-rowers-who-shocked-the-world/106183784</link><description>After claiming Australia's first world championship medal in rowing coastal beach sprints, these athletes are turning their attention towards the LA Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7248c9d35428b3a9488993e8a3850876</guid></item><item><title>Victorian master builder transforms Warrnambool house into castle for his son</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/builder-transforms-warrnambool-home-into-castle-for-son/106176624</link><description>They say "a man's home is his castle," but one builder from south-west Victoria has taken that literally when creating a dream home for his son.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">695b846b83e8f11dbad0909f3c891cba</guid></item><item><title>Mexico train crash kills passengers in country's south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/passengers-dead-after-mexico-train-derails/106184194</link><description>Another five people are in a critical condition after the Interoceanic Train detailed in the southern state of Oaxana.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd8463a4b35c27f32cbc759da4ac54a6</guid></item><item><title>New search for missing woman Trisha Graf near Andamooka</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/new-search-for-missing-woman-trisha-graf-near-andamooka/106184188</link><description>Police say they have "grave concerns" for a woman who has not been seen for more than two weeks in outback South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">511e0cecf82c3bbde044a019f19a62e6</guid></item><item><title>NSW government sets up hub to assist those impacted by Bondi Beach terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/nsw-government-announces-bondi-hub-for-impacted-locals-re-attack/106184248</link><description>The Bondi Hub will be open to the community and those directly or indirectly impacted by the December 14 shooting at the Chanukah by the Sea event at Bondi Beach, where 15 people were killed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38290ea192f47497f85499cb84648cb0</guid></item><item><title>Australia coach Andrew McDonald says Usman Khawaja will play the final Ashes Test amid retirement speculation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/khawaja-guaranteed-for-scg-future-unclear-after-that/106184310</link><description>Usman Khawaja will play in the Ashes finale at the SCG, but Australian coach Andrew McDonald remains in the dark about the 39-year-old's future beyond that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d906fedef83a721543a674e8516f4cb</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese announces terms for Richardson review of Bondi terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/bondi-breaking-announcement/106184434</link><description>The PM says a former head of ASIO will assess whether multiple security and law agencies worked as effectively as they should have before the attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78790121282cd6631c15dcb53f6684a5</guid></item><item><title>'Air experience' student killed in crash during Tasmanian glider's launch phase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/tas-glider-crash-was-during-launch-phase/106184430</link><description>A woman in her 50s was taking an "air experience" flight along with an instructor when they crashed during the take-off towing phase, as her husband watched.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c28fa551df0aa23d40ff1ed707008819</guid></item><item><title>NT police arrest woman for allegedly stealing from patients in Alice Springs Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/elderly-theft-alice-springs-hospital/106184326</link><description>A 30-year-old woman faces court after allegedly stealing from multiple elderly patients recovering from surgery in Alice Springs Hospital over an extended period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dadea0f3cdc0d06e06262cda42d00b4</guid></item><item><title>Coolongolook Rural Fire Service volunteers 'gutted' after robbery during fire season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/coolongolook-rfs-robbery/106184106</link><description>The volunteers discovered the theft when they arrived at the Coolongolook RFS shed to attend a car crash. Thieves stole hoses, breathing masks, radios and chainsaws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffcd8748790754acacd5a3346ef0c2ae</guid></item><item><title>Wu-Tang Clan's RZA reflects on the legendary hip-hop group's place in history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/wu-tang-clan-s-rza-on-being-in-one-of-/106176230</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02631ae97147b460167ea17ab6059f4d</guid></item><item><title>Jack Black and Paul Rudd reveal their surprise encounters while filming in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/jack-black-and-paul-rudd-reveal-their-surprise-encounters/106176344</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78f06ed9562be7ef672b8b8d52f86060</guid></item><item><title>University of Melbourne vice-chancellor Emma Johnston dies from cancer complications, aged 52</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/melbourne-university-vice-chancellor-science-death-emma-johnston/106184576</link><description>University of Melbourne vice-chancellor Emma Johnston has died from complications associated with cancer, aged 52.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3b872989d89b67b4add1cf5e0065fa9</guid></item><item><title>England's pace bowling stocks stripped bare with Gus Atkinson out of SCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/gus-atkinson-england-ruled-out-scg-test/106184680</link><description>England's pace bowling stocks will be stretched to their absolute limit for the final Ashes Test with Gus Atkinson ruled out with a hamstring injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22aefbd0e149e9e30254a8f87eca7bee</guid></item><item><title>Bondi hero recounts how he disarmed one of the gunmen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/bondi-hero-recounts-how-he-disarmed-one-of-the-gunmen/106184738</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e27bf827203d6933c058dfc0d1f0dc34</guid></item><item><title>Ahmed Al Ahmed recounts how he disarmed one of the gunmen in Bondi Beach terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/bondi-hero-ahmed-al-ahmed-recounts-story-of-wrestling-gunman/106183900</link><description>Father-of-two Ahmed Al Ahmed, who risked his life to disarm one of the Bondi gunmen during a terrorist attack, says he feels sorry for the 15 people who were killed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6a49f3b62dec473e7ffccc0ed4079a2</guid></item><item><title>The right way to stack your dishwasher and the verdict on rinsing beforehand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/the-verdict-on-rinsing-dishes-before-stacking-the-dishwasher/106022382</link><description>Rinsing can actually send a message to your dishwasher that your plate doesn't need as much washing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b16a5e33ffb32c5a75404f38ecdbd73d</guid></item><item><title>Celebrating New Year's Eve in Melbourne? Here's how and where to bring in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/how-to-celebrate-new-years-eve-in-melbourne/106183938</link><description>Half a million people are expected in the CBD as Melbourne farewells 2025 and ushers in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a16b07aac66c36c7a236913dce6ccff6</guid></item><item><title>Swan Hill tobacco shop rammed in failed firebomb attempt as tobacco wars continue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/tobacco-shop-rammed-failed-firebomb-attempt-after-note-left/106184112</link><description>A tobacco shop is rammed with a vehicle weeks after receiving a shakedown note demanding the owner "contact the commission".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac7192d468ef920243fe742bbbb7643e</guid></item><item><title>Stranded passengers to fly home from PNG after failed efforts to free Coral Adventurer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/coral-adventurer-cruise-passengers-to-fly-home-from-png/106184296</link><description>Passengers on the Australian cruise ship stranded off the coast of Papua New Guinea will be flown out of the country after efforts to refloat the vessel failed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f76911ebbee1286772ba5bf89ef00380</guid></item><item><title>South Australian MP Nick McBride to remain in custody for next seven days</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/nick-mcbride-remains-in-custody/106183758</link><description>South Australian independent MP Nick McBride will spend the next week in custody, after being arrested and charged over the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23cfb7d551970cb59aa18a5b3f9cb66b</guid></item><item><title>China launches military exercise warning against Taiwan independence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/china-taiwan-military-exercise-independence/106184600</link><description>China has moved its military to surround Taiwan warning against its independence. But Beijing's action has been condemned by Taiwan calling for regional peace and de-escalation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37ecc5e002b8f8f0e07100aae2ff9ccb</guid></item><item><title>'Punishing seaway' pushes Sydney to Hobart sailors to their limits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/rough-weather-dominates-sydney-hobart/106185046</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2843da3c2fe97b7a7c62151897e764ac</guid></item><item><title>Sydney to Hobart competitors tell of 'horrendous' conditions during 2025 race ordeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/2025-sydney-to-hobart-competitors-endure-rough-seas/106184046</link><description>Those now safely onshore after finishing the 2025 Sydney to Hobart tell of "horrendous" conditions, resulting in injuries, broken boats and seasickness — even among experienced crew members.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3d61d78845f12e1a58903944ac9f4eb</guid></item><item><title>Prosecutors wrap up bribery investigation into South Korea's former first lady</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/kim-keon-hee-bribery-accusations/106184962</link><description>Kim Keon Hee, the wife of disgraced ex-president Yoon Suk Yeol, is alleged to have accepted lavish bribes including fine art, jewellery and designer handbags, and to have meddled in state affairs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b0d782413b3369dcb0aae4239acdf2c</guid></item><item><title>Kempsey community marks 10 years since death in custody of David Dungay Jr</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/david-dungay-jr-death-anniversary-rally/106183046</link><description>A decade after his death in a Sydney prison, David Dungay Jr's family hold with a memorial rally calling for change to a corrections system they say still fails to protect Indigenous people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bdd7f9e29a766e460ae327c8d02e857</guid></item><item><title>Man fights for life after sustaining critical burns in Cairns unit fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/police-investigate-cairns-unit-fire/106185198</link><description>A man has sustained life-threatening burns after a unit complex went up in flames in Cairns. Police continue to investigate the cause of the fire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1beadf70728318c89cec79bf2f8bef00</guid></item><item><title>Slow TV for kids: Relax and unwind with low-stimulation shows on ABC iview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/low-stimulation-kids-tv-shows-stream-iview-abckids/106024290</link><description>Looking for screen-time options that won't leave your kids overstimulated? 'Slow TV' shows, with their soothing visuals and soundtracks, could be the answer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">428e608956327dc581fd5e961f4708a4</guid></item><item><title>Boat fire at Bonnie Doon leaves two men with serious injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/bonnie-doon-boat-fire-serious-injuries/106185204</link><description>Emergency services were on Monday called to a Lake Eildon boat ramp where two men had sustained serious injuries in a fire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">508a76c7c859dceb430d8f948f8b254c</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Sydney Test a golden opportunity for Cameron Green to belatedly shine in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/ashes-cameron-green-home-test-struggles/106185032</link><description>He has already proven his quality away from home, but heading into the final Test of the Ashes summer, Cameron Green remains in search of his breakthrough moment in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58a0cbd79c3cf2c39cce515515f91558</guid></item><item><title>Legal loophole in Queensland's double jeopardy law closed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/dna-double-jeopardy-cases-qld-law-changes/106184178</link><description>Last-minute amendments to Queensland's double jeopardy laws could allow for the retrial of botched DNA cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1ca9a578ce596f77c5d8a343e7e5f45</guid></item><item><title>Australia is considered a "lifeboat" region for some threatened rhino ray species, but the numbers worldwide are grim.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/rhino-ray-numbers-northern-territory-indonesia-extinction/106185030</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a7a7eaa5ae38567db7ecf4dd704011b</guid></item><item><title>Man faces court over alleged Boxing Day murder in remote NT community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/greg-shaun-williams-faces-court-over-alleged-boxing-day-murder/106185286</link><description>A 39-year-old man appears in court charged with the stabbing murder of a man in a remote Northern Territory community north of Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5478d4449ea06d23f01082c453ddfd97</guid></item><item><title>Dozens of shark heads dumped outside WA Fisheries minister's office as demersal fishing ban looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/shark-heads-dumped-outside-jackie-jarvis-office-fisheries/106184674</link><description>Hundreds of kilograms of shark heads have been left dumped outside the WA Fisheries minister's office in Margaret River, just three days before a permanent commercial demersal fishing ban comes into effect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52da2612172243bdd59c8424d34d39b0</guid></item><item><title>Menorah to light up Sydney Harbour Bridge on New Year's Eve after open letter from Jewish creatives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/nsw-nye-sydney-changes-after-jewish-creatives-open-letter/106185368</link><description>More than 30 Jewish-Australian creatives wrote to Lord Mayor Clover Moore on Monday morning, urging for a "Jewish-specific symbol" to commemorate the victims of the Bondi Beach terror attacks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00b316968710e16f09894837bc2fc7ee</guid></item><item><title>ICC gives MCG pitch 'unsatisfactory' rating as two-day Test fallout continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/mcg-boxing-day-test-pitch-icc-verdict-unsatisfactory/106185382</link><description>The ICC has handed down their verdict on the controversial MCG pitch which led to this year's Boxing Day Test wrapping up after just two days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3eb403942ca3ba789e82b7d7f5975ab9</guid></item><item><title>Thailand accuses Cambodia of breaching ceasefire deal after 250 drones flown over border</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/thailand-accuses-cambodia-of-breaching-ceasefire-deal/106185620</link><description>Bangkok has accused Phnom Penh of violating the peace deal that was struck on Saturday, after it claimed some 250 drones had been flown over the disputed border region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7147b1fd623dc9f4c30fa238964acc9a</guid></item></channel></rss>