<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 23:39:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Midnight Oil fans rally to keep Rob Hirst's drum kit 'in public hands' at charity auction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/midnight-oil-fans-secure-rob-hirsts-drum-kit-at-charity-auction/105887566</link><description>Midnight Oil drummer Rob Hirst auctions off the kit, which he has had since 1979, saying he can no longer play it because of his battle with pancreatic cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4b1a250f2c50ae072e79e344e2dc5fa</guid></item><item><title>Plans for national art gallery in Alice Springs scrapped after government rift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/nt-aboriginal-and-torres-strait-islander-art-alice-springs/105887842</link><description>The Northern Territory government scraps controversial plans to build the Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Art Gallery of Australia in Alice Springs after nine years of back and forth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">218dcceb9a72a6805cd42afc69e27584</guid></item><item><title>Search underway in icy conditions for bushwalker Daryl Fong in Tasmania's Mt Field National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/bushwalker-missing-in-mt-field-national-park-tasmania/105887818</link><description>A search is underway for a Tasmanian man in Mount Field National Park in challenging, snowy conditions after his last contact on Sunday morning said he would seek shelter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc1077490070d9be093a67a29c0fcfa7</guid></item><item><title>When to share the news of a pregnancy with your employer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/when-to-share-the-news-of-a-pregnancy-with-your-employer/105865350</link><description>Experts on the rules around when you need to inform your employer if you’re planning to take parental leave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdd7ceffb7b18af44c36f8079e6d9e03</guid></item><item><title>Former Collingwood coach Nathan Buckley to join Geelong as assistant coach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/nathan-buckley-moves-back-into-coaching-with-surprise-cats-role/105889810</link><description>Nathan Buckley takes a surprise assistant coaching job as the Collingwood legend awaits on a likely offer to lead Tasmania's inaugural AFL team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fd3d52a338ea52e945304cb458dc004</guid></item><item><title>Almost 130 people dead or missing in Mexico floods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/dozens-dead-after-torrential-rains-lash-mexico/105889300</link><description>The death toll from flooding in Mexico's central region has risen to 64, with another 65 people missing, according to the Mexican government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8015efd23b16e6fafd30e13d802aae13</guid></item><item><title>Eugowra flood inquest hears evidence of a 'day of hell'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/eugowra-flood-inquest-day-two-hears-of-inland-tsunami/105887756</link><description>A Eugowra resident tells an inquest into deadly flooding how she put her six-day-old granddaughter in a roof cavity after a wave of water hit the Central West town, killing two people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d6a5ec2b5dd8ff9a04b9d8f7c7f8998</guid></item><item><title>Bridget Archer announces funding for Hobart Clinic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/bridget-archer-announces-funding-for-hobart-clinic/105890098</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb1b30d865a9a239f2642a4dd843222b</guid></item><item><title>Roblox 'taken to task' but may not be included in social media ban, says eSafety commissioner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/esafety-commissioner-social-media-ban-roblox/105889222</link><description>Australia's eSafety commissioner says her team has "taken Roblox to task" over its risk of exposing children to harm but warned the online gaming platform may not be included in the upcoming social media ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db4b3f6eea6b606948efa08757097591</guid></item><item><title>Suggestion AFLW being used as a 'trial run' for new rules causes frustration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/frustration-as-aflw-used-as-trial-run-for-new-rules-for-afl-mens/105889756</link><description>Collingwood's Tarni White says it feels as though the women's competition is being used as a trial run for new rules before they are implemented into the men's league.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22b2ee856b6c7691dbc3cfbefcc9b672</guid></item><item><title>Victory in Socceroos' friendly against United States could ease World Cup draw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/socceroos-friendly-against-us-could-impact-world-cup-draw/105890480</link><description>The Socceroos' friendly against the United States is a positive step in their World Cup preparation, while a positive result could also influence their tournament draw.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">818fc0fb7ab727bff2ff2f14d8091448</guid></item><item><title>Police officer had 'high likelihood of PTSD' at time of death, inquest told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/inquest-into-death-of-sa-police-officer-benjamin-warren/105887870</link><description>A coronial inquest will explore whether the 2022 death of SA Police Senior Constable Benjamin Edward Warren could have been prevented if his mental health issues had been identified.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd13e8e347a708108fd3eddb6aa8ea74</guid></item><item><title>WA's flu season exceeds 30,000 cases as authorities blame low vaccination rates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/wa-flu-season-worst-ever-poor-vaccination-rates/105891252</link><description>Western Australia records its worst flu season on record, with more than 30,000 influenza cases reported this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f1f2484096733debed58e21c7b6682</guid></item><item><title>Abducted by Hamas, Noa never lost hope she would see her 'soulmate' again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/noa-argamani-avinatan-or-hamas-hostages-freed/105890692</link><description>Noa and Avinatan's abduction from a music festival became an enduring illustration of the horrors endured by Israelis on October 7. Now safely in each other's arms, a chapter has closed on a harrowing two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e795ebb238cdbebca7f0fd0bfe11d9d4</guid></item><item><title>Concerns teenagers in regional West Australia face further isolation as social media ban looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/regional-teens-left-lonely/105888190</link><description>Advocates are concerned rural and remote children will experience compounding challenges with the looming social media ban for people under 16.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1170b18fc2aa14fb4b4494d3cfed0a2f</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105891880</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">653774c141b651a45c0a8cb8f098cded</guid></item><item><title>Senior conservative James Paterson cautions Liberal Party against splitting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/james-paterson-urges-liberals-not-to-break-up-farage-teal/105888150</link><description>In a major address to his party, James Paterson says "marginal" voices agitating for the Liberal party to split must be kept on the sidelines, cautioning it would spell "disaster".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b19c93195b4681ddf79b775907477599</guid></item><item><title>Five takeaways from the ABC's Your Say: The Digital Dilemma forum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/abc-your-say-the-digital-dilemma-key-takeaways/105890184</link><description>An emotional plea to the country, concerns about privacy and how Australia's social media ban will actually work. These are the key takeaways from the ABC's Your Say: The Digital Dilemma forum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de6e80e7d191490fa6fdf7119bf8ab6e</guid></item><item><title>Victorian councils call on state government to strengthen trial aimed at preventing gambling harm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/gambling-harm-prevention-trial-yourplay-card-criticism/105865050</link><description>Victorian councils taking part in a trial of account-based play at pokies venues say they're disappointed with the state government's handling of the scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7908f4da03b11575b3818fb735f838e</guid></item><item><title>An embarrassing backflip by Chalmers on super or a strategic shift?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/was-chalmers-taught-a-lesson-in-his-fight-over-superannuation/105891400</link><description>After two years of refusing to reshape his superannuation shake-up, the treasurer abandons the idea of taxing unrealised gains while agreeing to index a key tax threshold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81f26bfccf07023bc6ed3051fab482c2</guid></item><item><title>Forensic imaging revealing hidden layers under Sidney Nolan's Ned Kelly paintings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/act-revealing-hidden-layers-of-sidney-nolan-ned-kelly-paintings/105889294</link><description>Hidden figures and inscriptions are being discovered beneath some of Australia's most famous paintings as conservators use infrared technology to reveal details in Sidney Nolan's Ned Kelly series, unseen since the artist's own time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">571022a8dd0d719c04c7924d5d111407</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos coach Kevin Walters pledges no Queensland bias in Ashes series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/nrl-kangaroos-england-australia-ashes-tests/105892660</link><description>Reece Walsh has built a compelling case for selection in the Kangaroos' starting line-up to face England, but coach Kevin Walters says he will not show favouritism towards the Maroons contingent in his squad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbaa2f074a49fcbe600576d71e6b56e2</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's fashion industry fears TasTAFE course cuts will impact creative pathways</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/tasmanian-young-fashion-designers-career-pathways/105887772</link><description>Under planned government cuts to vocational training in Tasmania, young aspiring creatives are worried about a loss of opportunity in their home state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82f5f9f78478f10675a08b7502145bd5</guid></item><item><title>Grammy-winning R&amp;B singer D'Angelo dies of cancer aged 51</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/grammy-winning-singer-dangelo-dies-aged-51/105892638</link><description>The Untitled (How Does It Feel) singer died after a long struggle with cancer, his family said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b3f3f79c82f23a9810f81db1f015302</guid></item><item><title>Regional developers cash in on the global gaming industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/regional-gaming-business-growth-pilbara-red-dog-studios/105790186</link><description>Better known for its gas and iron ore, the Pilbara hopes to add gaming to its list of local exports as internet access and technology improve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7464b0f15ce63829b17d4f0b08d239f8</guid></item><item><title>Dying mother loses life insurance after failing to declare UTI tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/dying-mother-loses-life-insurance-after-failing-to/105891944</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3a16fd23e92a2762fe66d3e28645c0c</guid></item><item><title>Failure to declare tests after urinary tract infection sees cancer patient's insurance voided</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/terminally-ill-woman-life-insurance-voided-over-paperwork/105872718</link><description>A terminal cancer patient is told her failure to declare a UTI has voided her insurance policies, leaving her struggling to pay her mortgage and care for her children in her final days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fdc30419a0a448c3301e9d5575cd819</guid></item><item><title>Power outage knocks out Victoria's triple-0 dispatch software for several hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/software-failure-power-outage-affects-victoria-triple-0-response/105892758</link><description>Victoria's triple-0 dispatch software fails due to a power outage, forcing operators to take notes with pen and paper.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29d074bfc5b78adf04bcc060ad451cc5</guid></item><item><title>Prosthetics clients of Jack McDonald question what legal rights they have for compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/clients-of-artificial-eye-maker-jack-mcdonald-want-refund/105888342</link><description>A prosthetics provider has left Australians thousands of dollars out of pocket, some having to cope with ill-fitting or wrong-coloured fingers and eyes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58fd38cac408e72900a888d7ae781834</guid></item><item><title>Regional Victorian farmers left high and dry as decent spring rain fails to arrive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/farmers-cutting-crops-for-hay-as-decent-spring-rain-doesnt-come/105884166</link><description>Some Victorian farmers are cutting crops for hay as the drought continues to bite in the nation's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">509574dcbec28aaf0b1eb34f8aa69ab5</guid></item><item><title>Illawarrra Academy of Sport holds open testing day for aspiring young athletes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/illawarrra-academy-of-sport-pen-testing-day-young-athletes/105878204</link><description>Young athletes wanting to be the next Emma McKeon or Jessica Hull have been put through high-performance testing to see if they have what it takes to be a professional.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15a018213f26351372e484eeb90ad629</guid></item><item><title>Japan makes history as Brazil records 'unacceptable' 3-2 loss in international friendly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/japan-beats-brazil-in-football-international-friendly/105893036</link><description>For the first time in 14 meetings, Japan defeats Brazil 3-2 in their international friendly at a sold-out Tokyo Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6454207cf8d9709c6caca8495b04511c</guid></item><item><title>Queensland health minister knew of hospital failures before going on leave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/queensland-health-minister-knew-about-caboolture-/105890580</link><description>Queensland's health minister has revealed he knew about failures at Caboolture Hospital involving the death of a patient after delays to medical scan results, before he went on holiday when the issue later became public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12969694309920e5fabdb01232ea2a22</guid></item><item><title>WA's Coolgardie council avoids suspension, with residents expressing frustration and relief over the saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/coolgardie-to-dig-itself-out-of-debt/105881252</link><description>Coolgardie Shire leaders hope to rebuild trust among ratepayers after the local government minister announced the WA state government would not suspend the council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77b218585453033539c537af21793f7f</guid></item><item><title>England thrashes Latvia 5-0 to qualify for World Cup finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/football-england-thrashes-latvia-to-reach-world-cup-finals/105893278</link><description>Unbeaten in its qualifying matches, England reaches next year's World Cup finals following a dominant 5-0 defeat of Latvia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">776384400073f9c24dc5ed3d14d31475</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of Victorians are graduating as paramedics, but have to go interstate for jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/paramedic-student-glut-no-jobs-ambulance-victoria/105874740</link><description>For regional paramedicine graduates, finding a job, let alone one in your hometown, is a challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87a5961a74a7b4d6e63a1037bd6466b2</guid></item><item><title>Gaps in cyberbullying reporting leave parents feeling lost, struggling to find answers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/cyberbullying-reporting-gaps-leave-parents-children-helpless/105864800</link><description>Parents and carers are frustrated by what they say is a lack of support when trying to report several Instagram accounts targeting children under the age of 17 over the school holidays.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86168b6389493c5ee569ccfbc8f2dbdb</guid></item><item><title>Randa Abdel-Fattah reveals how the Israel-Gaza war shaped her new book Discipline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/randa-abdel-fattah-palestinian-author-new-book-discipline/105865540</link><description>Randa Abdel-Fattah explores the experience of Palestinian Australians in Discipline, her first book for adults.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5256627cfb3d5e9fd11c695daf718ec</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos lose 2-1 to USA in international friendly, ending Tony Popovic's unbeaten start</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/live-updates-usa-socceroos-international-friendly-fifa-world-cup/105884330</link><description>The Socceroos suffer defeat for the first time under Tony Popovic, falling to a 2-1 defeat against the USA in Colorado.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ce54438a6647fef94dd054d64e53f08</guid></item><item><title>US strike on alleged drug boat off Venezuela kills six, Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/us-strike-on-alleged-drug-boat-off-venezuela-kills-six/105893308</link><description>It is the fifth deadly strike in the Caribbean amid the Trump administration's crackdown on alleged drug traffickers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c1e71f90039f55cf158db7a0c7d28d9</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump posts video of US strikes on alleged drug trafficking boat off coast of Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/donald-trump-posts-video-of-us-strikes-on-alleged/105893326</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7821ad1026d9a5f2396b0de54e5b73f6</guid></item><item><title>The US has dropped out of the top 10 most powerful passports — but where does Australia rank?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/united-states-passport-drops-out-of-top-10-most-powerful/105893408</link><description>The US passport has fallen to 12th place, a five-spot decline from its previous ranking, tying with Malaysia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">210460eb5dcbc50a34d606ea70c1a796</guid></item><item><title>Powerhouse misses opportunity to get Melbourne-bound drums of Sydney's Midnight Oil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/sydneys-powerhouse-missed-out-on-midnight-oil-drums-hirst/105894330</link><description>Midnight Oil are Sydney rock royalty, but the drum kit that stuck with the band for more than 40 years is heading to a Melbourne music museum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77d8f6e30d82e4cfddfe3d8643cf4ad8</guid></item><item><title>Conjoined boys born in PNG bound for Australia for medical treatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/png-conjoined-twins-braun-hospital-medical-treatment-sydney/105888942</link><description>The boys, who are only the second known case of conjoined twins born in PNG, are expected to come to Australia for medical treatment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">602984aa1a6e648bd1700a79bdd0ced0</guid></item><item><title>Australian seamer Megan Schutt looks to delay retirement until 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/full-trophy-cabinet-part-of-schutt-s-cricket-retirement-dream/105894742</link><description>Megan Schutt had once planned to walk away after the ODI Women's World Cup, but the veteran seamer is now considering playing into 2026 for Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f84bc367da9d0232000fcadc14ce9b90</guid></item><item><title>ARLC says NRL players face 10-year ban for joining rebel leagues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/nrl-players-face-10-year-ban-for-joining-rebel-leagues/105894992</link><description>The Australian Rugby League Commission has announced a 10-year ban for any NRL player who agrees to join a football competition it does not recognise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddb37f0928e43c1b5bbf5bd94cff1dfa</guid></item><item><title>Hamas fighters execute alleged collaborators in Gaza. ABC NEWS Verify has chosen not to show the executions due to their graphic nature.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/hamas-fighters-execute-alleged-collaborators-in/105893348</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d75241605dfda6cf26081e293c37b7c</guid></item><item><title>Hamas executes 'collaborators and lawbreakers' in graphic scenes in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/abc-news-verify-hamas-executions-gaza-city/105893350</link><description>Masked gunmen have carried out "extrajudicial executions" in the streets of Gaza City as an expert claims the terror group is trying to regain control of the destroyed enclave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">011b7d02b9a4606194657179c44c731f</guid></item><item><title>Michael J Fox talks about life with Parkinson's disease</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/michael-j-fox-talks-about-death-and-parkinsons-disease/105894044</link><description>The Back to the Future star has been candid about life with the degenerative neurological condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb8da2122b00a39bed22e5f831e89528</guid></item><item><title>SES critical of weather bureau, Eugowra flood inquest told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/eugowra-coronial-inquest-told-of-ses-tension/105893086</link><description>The third day of an inquest into two deaths during the 2022 Eugowra flood hears of concerns raised within the SES about the accuracy of weather bureau warnings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba050b5f18ce69c303a9e8769c5bf7fb</guid></item><item><title>NSW bowler Sean Abbott subbed out of Sheffield Shield game after splitting webbing on hand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/abbott-splits-webbing-on-hand-in-latest-australian-bowling-blow/105895908</link><description>Sean Abbott becomes the latest Test hopeful to suffer an injury, ruled out of NSW's Sheffield Shield match after splitting the webbing on his bowling hand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63204e72e5ad62a8ea02127575bba291</guid></item><item><title>Three Australian men accused of killing Zivan Radmanovic in Bali could face death penalty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/three-australian-men-could-face-death-penalty-bali/105896428</link><description>Indonesian police allege Zivan Radmanovic was killed when two Australian men stormed the villa, shooting him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4bb686a2307e1685b9fddd02d399650</guid></item><item><title>Boat approaches southern right whales off Albany coast in WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/boat-approaches-southern-right-whale-and-calf-wa/105893974</link><description>The latest close encounter with a protected whale species has renewed calls for the public to give the animals space.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d402bafad752b1c94a1343f0154bcac</guid></item><item><title>Residents in WA's north urged to prepare for cyclone season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/bom-retires-cyclone-outlook-for-northern-wa/105894634</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says it will no longer publish a cyclone outlook for WA's north, saying it was less reliable due to a changing climate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53781b9b19159607ee69607086ea9579</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105896606</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5de03d8a271e83312ef111c5e775f4b8</guid></item><item><title>One of four bodies handed over by Hamas does not match any hostage, Israel says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-15/body-returned-to-israel-not-a-hostage-israel-says/105897000</link><description>The Israeli military says one of four bodies handed over by Hamas on Tuesday night, local time, is not that of an Israeli hostage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f337f67d18c93c55e85db0501d33d7d5</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan and Afghanistan agree to temporary ceasefire after deadly violence along border</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/pakistan-afghanistan-fighting-temporary-ceasefire-conflict/105897208</link><description>A 48-hour ceasefire has been decided between the Pakistan government and the Afghan Taliban regime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c0608cfefe376793ed0f1726baceedd</guid></item><item><title>Fresh new faces campaigning to make a difference in Melbourne's north as part of youth council</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/hume-council-youth-elections/105895026</link><description>Melbourne's Hume Council will see the city's first-ever democratically elected youth mayor take office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">495c6511513593a8edc13e076cfdb0e4</guid></item><item><title>Calvary Health Care questioned over Launceston private hospital's future after infrastructure failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/calvary-health-care-private-hospital-launceston-tasmania/105885816</link><description>Tasmanian healthcare experts are calling for assurances about the future of a private hospital in Launceston in the wake of a costly infrastructure failure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41f8500ececa20b4fc5acfda9bbdbc9e</guid></item><item><title>Singapore, 'so dependent on external demand', braces for tariff hit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/singapore-economy-business-fallout-donald-trump-tariffs/105893038</link><description>Businesses in Singapore — one of the most trade-exposed economies in the world — have been watching the fallout from Donald Trump's 'Liberation Day' tariffs with apprehension.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f30cb84dd7e9868667ba93e4670d3a2</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period quick hits: Zach Merrett's agent fumes, clubs feud over Callum Ah Chee deal and Charlie Curnow gets his move</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/afl-trade-period-deadline-day-quick-hits-merrett-curnow/105897020</link><description>The AFL trade period's deadline day delivered more drama than ever — with a manager blowing up and a Hawks star suggesting Essendon is 'Alcatraz' on a social media post.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30e7d7c3c3877a4e5422e185ff4a2a02</guid></item><item><title>US wants to make rare earth deals with Australia but without China involved, expert says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/us-is-open-to-make-rare-earth-deals-with-australia/105895128</link><description>As rare earths re-emerge as a central battleground in the US-China trade war, Australian companies are already striking deals to supply America. A policy expert says talks at the White House next week could secure a national agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93a0c2c00f2f1e07783629d538ec8b4e</guid></item><item><title>Fifty years since the Balibo Five murders, families are still seeking justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/balibo-five-murders-50-years-indonesia-australia-timor-leste/105884316</link><description>On the 50th anniversary of the Balibo Five murders, families are still grieving the loss of their loved ones and remain committed to holding those responsible accountable for their actions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1314ae8328046a527aba9120658d2d1d</guid></item><item><title>Dead koala found after sighting of the endangered animal halted ACT suburb's construction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/act-dead-koala-found-as-new-suburb-development-on-hold/105896808</link><description>The construction of new homes in Canberra's north remains on hold after a koala was spotted. Now, a dead koala has been found nearby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">662b333c24de695d37cbf543e12d606a</guid></item><item><title>Council wants to ban artificial grass on nature strips over microplastics and PFAS concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/queanbeyan-council-artifical-grass-ban/105894880</link><description>Queanbeyan-Palerang Regional Council says microplastics and chemicals from artificial lawns can contaminate stormwater.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71e3ec87868e10161c78257d051b006d</guid></item><item><title>Bundaberg and Maryborough grapple with anti-social behaviour in town centres</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/queensland-towns-grapple-with-anti-social-behaviour/105890248</link><description>Arriving at their local park for a morning walk, Lili Jacobsen was pulling her pram out of the car when a woman approached her, talking about the devil and demanding money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41ea3f514aee424f129616008b60678b</guid></item><item><title>Nikon Small World photomicroscopy competition's top 15 images of 2025 capture our tiniest signs of life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/nikon-small-world-photomicrography-competition-2025-winners/105880892</link><description>Extreme close-ups of rice weevil, pollen in a spider's web and a geometer moth laying eggs are among this year's Nikon Small World competition entries from thousands of scientists and artists across the globe. Here are the judges' favourites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">422146c134220b9daaeb85e97181786b</guid></item><item><title>Soldier killed in vehicle rollover during army training in north Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/army-soldier-killed-in-vehicle-rollover-while-training/105897572</link><description>The Department of Defence says an Australian soldier has died after a single-vehicle rollover during training at the Australian Army's Townsville Field Training Area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9064921280d2988c8f1986804181b2f4</guid></item><item><title>Cost of 'best practice' on emissions at leaking Darwin gas plant an 'intolerable risk' for Santos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/santos-darwin-lng-emissions-best-practice-intolerable-risk/105819802</link><description>Santos's Darwin gas plant is set for a new lease of life despite a major methane leak. The company told federal officials the risk it could be forced to meet best practice on carbon emissions was "intolerable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4185616f1eb4420fa8e0bb9f51a7a95</guid></item><item><title>Replica of destroyed Juukan Gorge being built five years after Rio Tinto blast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/juukan-gorge-rock-shelter-recreated-models-virtual-reality/105889276</link><description>A full-scale replica of the Juukan Gorge rock shelter, destroyed by mining company Rio Tinto, will be built over the remains of the original in Western Australia's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17d49eeea6ddb3bcb9585027b4d633f3</guid></item><item><title>$5 milk and $90 rent increases: The NT's rising cost of living pushing families into housing stress</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/nt-cost-of-living-report-rising-rents-fuel-prices-housing-stress/105895916</link><description>Kerrie Matthews has been forced to sell personal items to afford life-saving diabetes equipment, and with skyrocketing bills she is putting her house on the market and leaving the Northern Territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6003c03876e99fd949a9e637f3665cce</guid></item><item><title>Prestigious Australian wine labels feeling the pinch as Chinese buy and drink less</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/premium-wine-penfolds-reports-china-sales-slump/105887474</link><description>Cheaper bulk wine has been struggling in the market, but now even prestigious labels like Penfolds are feeling the pinch off the back of changing drinking habits and a reported crackdown on lavish banquets for civil servants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">824a7cb7547f583c912f4b33ffcad31d</guid></item><item><title>Pentagon journalists exit en masse over new reporting restrictions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/pentagon-press-corps-leaves-in-protest-over-reporting-rules/105892258</link><description>Journalists working at the Pentagon had been asked to sign a pledge to refrain from reporting information not authorised for release by the US Department of War.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55cc5a0ac437d8e13ddd34e87c58ee4e</guid></item><item><title>Country GP crushed by vintage tractor in Denmark issues safety warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/safety-warning-after-country-gp-crushed-by-heritage-tractor/105885980</link><description>What started as a routine day of chores for a country GP and his son became a life-or-death situation after he was crushed by a vintage tractor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc4c053f90131636fe18b998de8dcf1f</guid></item><item><title>Four-time Olympic champion Ariarne Titmus announces retirement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/swimming-ariarne-titmus-announces-retirement/105898036</link><description>Ariarne Titmus draws the curtain on a decorated career, in which she won eight medals across two Olympic Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b20c3d209eb66b297a235d75ac8ea914</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Auditor-General lays out government's 'slow' and 'burdensome' response to 2022 floods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/auditor-general-lays-out-slow-reponse-to-2022-floods/105895512</link><description>A Victorian Auditor-General's report says state government agencies need to be quicker at providing relief and recovery when responding to natural disasters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b0605c3712edfcb20f02a29fd0c8fc4</guid></item><item><title>Madura Plains sheep station hits the market as wool and lamb prices soar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/historic-madura-plains-for-sale-wa-sheep-station/105894986</link><description>One of Australia's largest sheep stations is listed for sale as wool and lamb prices soar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdf5cb0f5e7c6d4612908253b324ec0b</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill man who ran 27 marathons in 29 days finishes with fractured hip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/broken-hill-man-ran-to-newcastle-with-broken-femur/105866122</link><description>Mitch McKenny is unlikely to run again after spending four weeks running from Broken Hill to Newcastle, including the last 380 kilometres with severe pain in his hip.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de6f9d09fba1260c22272a56efcf4fa3</guid></item><item><title>Australia's unemployment rate jumps to 4.5pc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/australia-unemployment-rate-rises-september-2025/105898244</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate jumped to 4.5 per cent in September, up from 4.3 per cent in August.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">944d983f4c3e591e79c311c6deea0d20</guid></item><item><title>Kingston residents rally to save 130yo oak tree from transmission project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/campaign-to-save-algerian-oak-kingston-western-renewables-link/105885046</link><description>Residents are getting creative in their fight to save a "magnificent" 130-year-old Algerian oak tree from being felled for a controversial transmission line project in western Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f54bb8b9ecab1e3d0af3c172dfd77c73</guid></item><item><title>Female shearer sets world record by shearing 500 merino lambs in one day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/shearer-sets-womens-record-shearing-500-merino-lambs-in-a-day/105897736</link><description>Nikki Lyons's clippers started humming at 6am. Twelve hours later, she was a world record holder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d962c3ee2503118469de3426af4a2f</guid></item><item><title>Remains of missing Victorian woman Lucinda Miller discovered in police search</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/lucinda-miller-items-found-neerim-south-gippsland/105895350</link><description>New information from a member of the local community has led police to human remains in bushland in Victoria's east believed to be missing woman Lucinda Miller.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ff902b644302bf25e73309688f89cf5</guid></item><item><title>Ariarne Titmus's retirement ends years of sacrifice and allows her to at last savour her greatness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/ariarne-titmus-retirement-a-career-of-sacrifice-and-greatness/105898280</link><description>Ariarne Titmus has given her life to a dream. As she sets off on her next adventures, she can be in no doubt that her years of sacrifice and devotion were worth it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ace92f301f8bbd380cf4ea10e08f291</guid></item><item><title>Consumer groups, regulator concern as number of Australians accessing super to fix health surges again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/concern-over-accessing-super-for-medical-care-rises/105876384</link><description>Australians were allowed to withdraw $1.37 billion from their superannuation accounts for medical costs last financial year, in another jump from previous years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc6ab38204feeb436342c69f39e8b1a1</guid></item><item><title>First Nations artists warn against AI 'double colonisation' as Meta uses work for training</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/first-nations-creatives-warn-against-ai-double-colonisation/105889290</link><description>The rapid development of AI is testing the effectiveness of the Copyright Act, with creative and media industries calling for better protections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fc2ae378cfa0f6d485867eb2b770985</guid></item><item><title>Trump confirms the CIA is conducting covert operations inside Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/trump-confirms-cia-conducting-covert-venezuela-operations/105899100</link><description>Donald Trump says he authorised the CIA operation in part to stop the flow of "drugs coming in from Venezuela".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e085079c4af6fbf7e7281c139d73b6c8</guid></item><item><title>Endangered regent honeyeaters released in Hunter breeding effort</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/critically-endangered-regent-honeyeaters-released-hunter-valley/105897506</link><description>Dozens of regent honeyeaters have been released in woodlands in the NSW Hunter Valley in an effort to boost the critically endangered population.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">383b1b3969cfdfce4abe0f4f51474d27</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar's president Andry Rajoelina rose to power off youth discontent and was taken down by it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/madagascar-explainer-andry-rajoelina-president-ousted/105898028</link><description>Former DJ Andry Rajoelina was the world's youngest head of state when he came to power in Madagascar in a 2009 coup. The military and youth movement were pivotal in his rise — and fall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18df5036d8670e01811282249766d2e5</guid></item><item><title>Review: After the Hunt has noble ambitions but misses the mark</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/after-the-hunt-julia-roberts-review/105876254</link><description>The ingredients are all here — public scandal, duelling divas and unearthed secrets — but Luca Guadagnino's provocative drama misses the mark.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f67b806ed73e7ac77c9e5486230066b3</guid></item><item><title>Albanese dismisses lobby concerns, Chalmers takes one for the team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/anthony-albanese-jim-chalmers-good-oppositions/105884222</link><description>This week, the PM was not wasting any time on "this" issue, and the treasurer took one for the team as Brett Worthington signs off with his final political wrap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8caaca04017f6e10ef0a87a9a892f94f</guid></item><item><title>Coroner expresses 'horror' at lack of infrastructure upgrades after 2022 Eugowra flood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/eugowra-inquest-day-four/105898058</link><description>A coroner has expressed "horror" at the lack of modern river gauge infrastructure around the NSW inland community of Eugowra three years after it was smashed by record-breaking floods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfabe5218f015faa669d4da3b163dd62</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government approves Arrow Energy gas plant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/darling-downs-arrow-energy-gas-plant-approval/105900018</link><description>The Queensland government's recent approval of a major coal seam gas-processing facility three kilometres from a farming family's home has left them feeling "extremely disappointed".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cfb1f65a2244ef0e91ff8d80b92092e</guid></item><item><title>Former Ballarat dentist Ian Lomax suspended after alleged Neo-Nazi ties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/former-ballarat-dentist-suspended-after-alleged-neo-nazi-ties/105876992</link><description>Dental board suspends practitioner, who was allegedly photographed at a Neo-Nazi rally, while it investigates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">318fe292d66345273a778b72f5f069a7</guid></item><item><title>The Hobart Clinic rescue hinges on Monday shareholder meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/hobart-clinic-rescue-hinges-on-monday-meeting/105893386</link><description>Despite the offer of a $2 million lifeline to keep a private mental health clinic in Hobart open, last-minute wobbles could yet scupper the rescue bid, as the clinic's shareholders prepare to meet on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bc39e20ce0caab5b58da7fe6590d2ae</guid></item><item><title>Mark Haines inquest hears differing opinions from detectives on teen's mysterious death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/mark-haines-inquest-hears-from-detectives-and-homicide-squad/105887822</link><description>Thirty seven years after his death, police still cannot agree on how 17-year-old Mark Haines came to be found on train tracks near Tamworth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f08356610886575aa5a825b2c6af363e</guid></item><item><title>Teddy Swims tells SXSW Sydney he uses AI when making music, but warns of its dangers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/teddy-swims-tells-sxsw-sydney-he-uses-ai-in-music/105897908</link><description>Grammy-nominated music artist Teddy Swims says AI is a "beautiful tool" when it comes to composing music. Swims was in conversation at SXSW Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dcc839da82c48def79030a917173b7e</guid></item><item><title>Ariarne Titmus's greatest races, from Olympic golds, world records and surprise silvers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/ariarne-titmus-a-swimming-legend-races/105899372</link><description>The races that made Ariarne Titmus an Australian legend, from her maiden world championships appearance to her perfect Paris farewell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db607ccb521dd952dfad409a01b1c02e</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian and Jewish communities in Australia watch on with caution over Gaza peace plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/palestinian-jewish-people-australia-react-to-gaza-peace-plan/105896464</link><description>Samer Tarazi is one of thousands with strong ties to the Middle East region, watching from afar to see what the US-led peace plan means for the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">404b4d3c975048899e4387620de98f34</guid></item><item><title>Diane Keaton's family releases cause of death, urging tributes to homelessness services and animal shelters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/diane-keaton-cause-of-death-released/105898904</link><description>The actor's family says the 79-year-old died of pneumonia, expressing gratitude for the "extraordinary messages of love and support" received following news of her passing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ad4d9062c3fd28201c61a47954bccd0</guid></item><item><title>Release of Virginia Giuffre's memoir renews sex allegations against Prince Andrew</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/virginia-giuffre-book-prince-andrew-allegations-jeffrey-epstein/105898044</link><description>Extracts from Virginia Giuffre's posthumously released memoir have further intensified the recently renewed scrutiny on Prince Andrew.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40e21158edb995f36869ca565b0e2b53</guid></item><item><title>Cohealth's closure of three Melbourne GP clinics to affect 12,500 patients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/melbourne-cohealth-gp-clinics-closing/105897006</link><description>Inner-city Melbourne community health service cohealth will be shuttering its GP services at the end of the year, citing escalating costs and aging infrastructure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">206d1831d09920250b9663ff89ae7f92</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/thursday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/105900826</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39251dff22abd93c574816fddff415b9</guid></item><item><title>National Gallery will host APY artwork exhibition after paintings cleared of improper interference</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/act-apy-indigenous-art-interference-national-gallery-exhibition/105901272</link><description>The National Gallery will host an exhibition of art from the Aṉangu Pitjantjatjara Yankunytjatjara Lands three years after a video appearing to show a non-Aboriginal assistant helping to paint an artwork led to it being postponed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f256cd75d8dd22a070a0b023a2212e2</guid></item><item><title>Tasma Walton and Robbie Arnott share $100,000 ARA Historical Novel Prize</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/tasma-walton-robbie-arnott-ara-historical-novel-prize-2025/105886334</link><description>Robbie Arnott's Dusk about twins hunting a puma in Tasmania, and Tasma Walton's I Am Nannertgarrook about an Aboriginal woman kidnapped and sold into slavery, have tied to win the ARA Historical Novel Prize.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36563ad06ad055a6eaead4a3f8596a89</guid></item><item><title>Government unveils a plan to combat South Australian algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/plan-to-combat-sa-algal-bloom/105900918</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb673ff2efdfdb07d4b825046c407370</guid></item><item><title>French PM Sebastien Lecornu survives no-confidence votes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-16/french-pm-sebastien-lecornu-survives-no-confidence-votes/105901916</link><description>Despite the reprieve, the motions underscore the fragility of President Emmanuel Macron's administration midway through his final term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef9eb69bc5c812ba483714c1ea1b2bea</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says Narendra Modi has pledged that India will stop buying Russian oil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/donald-trump-says-india-will-stop-buying-russian-oil/105901976</link><description>The US president says his Indian counterpart has made the pledge, as pressure continues to mount over the purchases that fund Moscow's war in Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfa3d657832c0a2a078b14f16d2fc9e8</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump and Vladimir Putin to discuss Ukraine war at Budapest summit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/donald-trump-vladimir-putin-to-meet-again/105902260</link><description>Donald Trump and Vladimir Putin will meet face-to-face in Hungary to discuss ending Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine, the US president announces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87e82ba667b74fbf2ab5298f72f1c729</guid></item><item><title>Calls for Australia to follow England's ban on supermarket junk food specials</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/calls-for-australia-to-follow-england-ban-on-junk-food-specials/105807974</link><description>Research finding supermarkets continue to offer discounts and multi-buy deals on junk food more frequently than healthy food prompts calls for Australia to follow England's lead and ban "buy one, get one free" deals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edbe2cd8f08f8c2fc9c6395f9edf30b7</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian journalist Shadi Abu Sido reunites with his family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/palestinian-journalist-shadi-abu-sido-reunites-with-his-family/105900342</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4444ed700101dc4a34dd62cee2419b5</guid></item><item><title>More Palestinian prisoners allege mistreatment in Israeli prison system after being reunited with their families</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/palestinian-prisoners-allege-mistreatment-in-israel/105895592</link><description>Shadi Abu Sido spent 18 months in Israeli detention believing that his entire family had been killed in Gaza. Then he was reunited with his wife and children in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c31a6cc30147c611bd4bfc23280a0c4</guid></item><item><title>Oil leaking from WW2 shipwreck the Rio de Janeiro Maru in Chuuk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/oil-leaking-from-ww2-shipwreck-the-rio-de-janeiro-maru-in-chuuk/105889748</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2be0837ab0fb4ac0467e1f6078adc4e</guid></item><item><title>WWII shipwrecks a 'ticking time bomb' for Federated States of Micronesia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/war-relics-threat-for-federated-states-of-micronesia/105884710</link><description>The Federated States of Micronesia's biggest tourism asset has become one of its largest threats, with as much as 22 million litres of oil from World War II shipwrecks slowly leaking into the ocean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5a5e22c5b7f81e23acf8feb4ae870bd</guid></item><item><title>'Dangerously low' funding to Tasmanian arts sector creating reputational damage, minister warned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/tasmanian-arts-industry-highly-vulnerable-low-funding-investment/105899498</link><description>"Dangerously low" arts sector funding has rendered the Tasmanian industry "highly vulnerable", with funding stagnant since 2016-17, the state government has conceded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a29de7c4d5bc252c9a785dea93220878</guid></item><item><title>Jim Chalmers and Tony Burke are in a long race for prime position</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/jim-chalmers-tony-burke-leadership/105884226</link><description>There is general agreement in Labor that Jim Chalmers is the government's best communicator. But insiders watching this race know Tony Burke is the master tactician.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93f58dc170f3f37c70cca03a69e3a6f5</guid></item><item><title>Expanded search for Gus ends as missing persons advocate speaks out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/renewed-search-for-missing-boy-gus-continues-in-sa-outback/105900448</link><description>SA Police and ADF personnel have concluded a four-day renewed search for four-year-old Gus, as a missing persons advocate speaks out about the emotional impact of such cases on all families who have experienced the disappearance of a loved one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a97a1bed1323118fc2f898d318dc3426</guid></item><item><title>Drunken motorcyclist crashes with daughter riding as passenger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/drunken-motorcyclist-crashes-with-daughter-passenger/105898498</link><description>A Mildura father-of-six avoids jail after drunkenly crashing his motorbike while carrying his young daughter as a passenger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b7dbbdb3b9ed775f287c7490a9599c8</guid></item><item><title>Warnings for explicit deepfakes, 'image-based abuse' amid rise of AI technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/sydney-school-students-explicit-ai-images-investigation-police/105901372</link><description>A senior academic has warned a Sydney school caught up in an investigation into digitally altered explicit images of female students is just "another shocking iteration" of gendered violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9bb776a70b24518b0d2a82348f1046f</guid></item><item><title>ASX slips as gold price surges to new record above $US4,300 — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/asx-markets-business-live-news-date-year/105902438</link><description>The Australian share market falls after a downbeat session on Wall Street, weighed down by a sell-off across US regional bank stocks. Gold jumped to a new record high, above $US4,300 an ounce, as investors flocked to safe haven assets amid US-China trade tensions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c45f9ed11d3fac698ab6fe04be5606</guid></item><item><title>BHP vs China Inc: What the iron ore dispute says about Australia's present and future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/what-bhp-china-iron-ore-dispute-means-to-australia/105901692</link><description>The resolution of negotiations between Australian mining giant BHP and China's state-backed iron ore buyer China Mineral Resources Group could reshape not just the resources industry, but also international trade flows, global markets, and the relationship between China and the West.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f17745151acc39e0b5f38368c4928c68</guid></item><item><title>Lucy Derbyshire hunting first Coolangatta Gold win, enters Iron Series as defending champion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/lucy-derbyshire-hunting-first-coolangatta-gold-win-iron-series/105806790</link><description>Lucy Derbyshire enters this year's Iron Series as the defending champion and has set her sights on winning the Coolangatta Gold for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59032c6abfd46454ff5e9b348f7ebe8b</guid></item><item><title>From cult web series to cinema: Nirvanna the Band the Show the Movie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/nirvanna-the-band-the-show-the-movie/105898756</link><description>Canada's cult web series heads to the big screen, after creators Matt Johnson and Jay McCarrol were told they could make any movie they liked after their success with BlackBerry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcab9960bf8462cac061bee2cf98745a</guid></item><item><title>New research shows impact of lead poisoning on ancient humans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/new-research-shows-impact-lead-poisoning-ancient-humans/105899188</link><description>A new study claims lead might be the reason why Homo sapiens came to dominate the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12aa86f8c8828a99bbdb6054ea89c8c1</guid></item><item><title>Dangerous flammable cladding still not removed from dozens of NSW high-rise apartment buildings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/government-yet-to-fix-cladding-on-dozens-of-apartments-re-scheme/105900296</link><description>Dozens of high-rise apartment buildings across the state are still covered in flammable cladding as the NSW government's scheme has failed to fix them on schedule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">900570fd41fc7cafb3f056a176d7d52c</guid></item><item><title>How a 15yo autistic boy tinkering in his bedroom triggered WA's biggest ever data breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/joshua-unwittingly-triggered-major-wa-health-data-breach-autism/105455250</link><description>Joshua's "passion project" with a radio scanner led to one of WA's most significant public health data breaches. His story highlights the challenges confronting autistic people caught up in the legal system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13c71de037de480416dd879b9c6eab51</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government seeks private market interest to develop riverside precinct in South Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/qld-riverfront-precinct-south-brisbane-private-sector/105902488</link><description>The government says construction could begin from March 2027 and has suggested the site could feature over 4,000 homes, as well as "event lawns" and promenades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71e510b6fa92de09ab4aec4b9b044d41</guid></item><item><title>NicheLiving customers continue to find defects</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/nicheliving-customers-continue-to-find-defects/105899574</link><description>Nicheliving customer Kathy Ellis thought her three-year nightmare was finally over in July, only to discover defective plumbing work in her new house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c827db340a1c42daeb836818d1a1c034</guid></item><item><title>Woman stabbed in Melbourne's CBD in broad daylight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/woman-stabbed-in-melbourne-s-cbd-in-broad-daylight/105902728</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d3d70526290bba71783eacb1628cb9c</guid></item><item><title>Ace Frehley, founding member of rock group KISS, dies at 74</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/ace-frehley-guitarist-kiss-dies-aged-74/105902920</link><description>The original lead guitarist of the glam rock band captivated audiences with his elaborate makeup and smoke-filled guitar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70f68f5def708160810eec0ad80e8354</guid></item><item><title>Australian swimming star Ariarne Titmus says she lost 'fire in the belly' before shock retirement call</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/swimming-ariarne-titmus-retirement-press-conference/105902788</link><description>Ariarne Titmus has spoken publicly for the first time after abruptly retiring from professional swimming at just 25, revealing the reasons behind her decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce4208efcf5ba5f558acc40ad5edc802</guid></item><item><title>SA Education Department fined after teen fell from school playground swing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/sa-education-department-fined-playground-swing-fall/105900366</link><description>South Australia's Education Department has been fined $225,000 after a student at a special school fell from a swing which had not had a comprehensive safety inspection for eight years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cdc7ec760bf1e318791fcad162c615f</guid></item><item><title>Defence in talks to support Gaza peace plan but Australia says no request yet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/defence-in-talks-with-us-to-support-gaza-peace-plan/105902742</link><description>Australia's defence force has had discussions with the Unted States to provide support for its Gaza peace plan but the government says no formal request has been made yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd80619b996f35eb17de143a6b7e07dc</guid></item><item><title>Virtual emergency department a lifeline for patients in regional areas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/virtual-emergency-department-option-for-patients-remote-areas/105371852</link><description>A virtual emergency room app created during the pandemic could help bridge healthcare gaps in regional Victoria. But more patients need to dial-in and use the resource.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cce3e05039289d83c6bdbae0a5d4e7b</guid></item><item><title>Bears kill record number of people in Japan amid scores of attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/record-number-of-bear-attacks-in-japan/105902770</link><description>At least seven people have been killed by bears in the country since April and many more have been injured as the hungry animals venture into human territory to find food.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41b4b93bb120166534952debb22263e8</guid></item><item><title>US dangled threat of Tomahawks for Ukraine, then Russia called to negotiate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/us-tomahawk-long-range-missiles-supply-ukraine-russia-talks/105884192</link><description>US President Donald Trump threatened to send Tomahawk missiles to Ukraine if Russia did not return to peace talks, but analysts say the long-range weapons are not the game-changer they are made out to be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab37297fc9b45cbc08d59856d14f85f4</guid></item><item><title>Venezuela says US strike on suspected drug vessel 'extrajudicial executions'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/new-usa-strike-on-venezuelan-drugs-boat-leaves-survivors/105903128</link><description>A US strike against a suspected Venezuelan drug-smuggling vessel has left multiple survivors, as Venezuela's ambassador to the United Nations condemned the strikes as a "series of assassinations".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a3ad366e7e0f7f78fc016c52b612098</guid></item><item><title>'No doubt' Anthony Albanese and Donald Trump will discuss critical minerals: Chalmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/albanese-trump-chalmers-critical-minerals-deal/105903392</link><description>Anthony Albanese will "no doubt" use a meeting with Donald Trump next week to discuss critical minerals, the treasurer says as he dismisses a call for Australia to "decouple" with China over rare earth materials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fe4351ff10e966c7a84c8e260555fa8</guid></item><item><title>Missing man Troy Milne found alive in bushland more than two hours from campsite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/missing-man-found-troy-milne-fire-gippsland/105904026</link><description>A man who was missing in Victoria's east for more than a week is recovering in hospital after being found in bushland when he started a fire to draw attention to his location.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c75d2afbeefc32496c0ab94cbb90f22</guid></item><item><title>WA's insolvent Griffin Coal ramps up operations as taxpayer bailout deadline looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/insolvent-wa-griffin-coal-ramps-up-operations/105901120</link><description>The receiver of a WA coal mine says it is ramping up operations in a final attempt to trade out of insolvency before millions of dollars in taxpayer support dries up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2e888ffc914c66fe0fec7316e9144da</guid></item><item><title>Pet-friendly flights are taking off in Australia. Here's what to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/pet-friendly-flights-what-to-know/105903876</link><description>The first pet-friendly commercial flights have taken off in Australia this week. Here's what you need to know about the new service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4379a2d55c184d75fb0dbc167127d3db</guid></item><item><title>Australia Test batter Nic Maddinson reveals testicular cancer diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/australia-test-batter-nic-maddinson-testicular-cancer-diagnosis/105905220</link><description>Former Australia batter Nic Maddinson has revealed he underwent chemotherapy for testicular cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7f603e8cc45b625885d16071d38bc7a</guid></item><item><title>Ways to increase safety on a first date and red flags to watch for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/red-flags-on-first-date-safety-tips/105805388</link><description>Both people involved in a date are responsible for creating a safe environment, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f5f2638f6ee24d2f8b7347e8441dce8</guid></item><item><title>Endemic frog and gecko species identified on Dauan Island in Torres Strait</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/frog-gecko-species-found-dauan-torres-strait/105790146</link><description>Two new frog species and a banded-patterned gecko are believed to have sheltered among the boulders of Dauan, in the Torres Strait, for millions of years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02d7af04ef02838cbdfc93bff8ff13f8</guid></item><item><title>WA farmers and caravaners defend Australia's growing love affair with US-style utes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/big-cars-us-style-trucks-tax/105901678</link><description>As American-style utes gain popularity across the country, there are calls for owners to face higher taxes for their "big cars, causing big problems".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">184ba6d7bde7a359132586201a8b0e76</guid></item><item><title>Inquest hears of grief, trauma from families of Eugowra locals after record-breaking 2022 flood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/eugowra-inquest-day-five/105902498</link><description>Families speak of loss, trauma on final day of the coronial inquest into the deaths of Les Vugec and Diane Smith.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dcae5aba593220ee08189da0bc90ff1</guid></item><item><title>Video of attempted strip search that breached Aboriginal woman's human rights made public</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/video-of-attempted-strip-search-canberra-jail-released-court/105904704</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3fd11c0749eadaff81abffecd47f378</guid></item><item><title>Video released of moments leading up to strip search that breached Aboriginal woman's human rights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/julianne-williams-strip-search-canberra-jail-video-release-court/105905888</link><description>The ACT Supreme Court has made public confronting video showing the moments leading up to a strip search that violated an Aboriginal woman’s human rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdcb7325932b405b24aab30e15587062</guid></item><item><title>Wayne Swan steps down as Labor president urging party to focus on membership boost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/wayne-swan-labor-president-leaves-role-politics/105905064</link><description>Labor party president Wayne Swan will step down next July and has warned the ALP must boost membership if it is to survive into the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75e127f2e28c7f78ce730de287d98398</guid></item><item><title>Wittenoom asbestos contamination prompts legal threat from Banjima traditional owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/wittenoom-asbestos-litigation-documentary/105886444</link><description>After decades of disconnection, the traditional owners of Wittenoom say they are prepared to take legal action to ensure the area is properly remediated so they can return to country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">713ee52afb0c4689f99c025841f00428</guid></item><item><title>Deepfake image-based abuse happening at least once a week in schools, eSafety data shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/deepfake-image-based-abuse-doubles-across-australia/105905152</link><description>The latest data revealed by Australia's eSafety Commissioner comes just days after reports that digitally altered explicit images of female students from a Sydney high school were shared online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd27dfbd0ff0516ec2e07457a0070394</guid></item><item><title>Friday the pelican captured and washed after three-week chase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/friday-the-pelican-captured-and-washed-after-three-week-chase/105906028</link><description>Friday the pelican evaded capture for weeks. But a long-overdue bath is for her own good.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08e29ab2dd99920f8f64165e8034ff2b</guid></item><item><title>Grimmer family sets parliamentary privilege deadline for cold case identity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/cheryl-grimmer-brothers-set-deadline-parliamentary-privilege/105904330</link><description>A brother of three-year-old Cheryl Grimmer, who vanished in 1970, has given the man who confessed to her killing a deadline to come forward or be named.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f15982335786071048424d142871b2b9</guid></item><item><title>Minjee Lee shoots six-under second round at LPGA BMW Ladies Championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/minjee-lee-six-under-second-round-bmw-ladies-championship/105905080</link><description>In-form Minjee Lee has made a big move, powering once again into contention for a 12th LPGA Tour title.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9bdb1a02a6e1386ecfc1a9f73571f5f</guid></item><item><title>Chinese national charged with foreign interference granted bail despite concerns she could flee country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/act-chinese-national-charged-foreign-interference-granted-bail/105906106</link><description>A woman accused of covertly gathering information for the Chinese government has been granted bail in Canberra, despite police warning she could try to flee the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f8a82b873c67ac845e029c6fb5fd2f1</guid></item><item><title>Scott Boland bowls Victoria to Sheffield Shield victory over NSW, ahead of Ashes against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/scott-boland-bowls-victoria-to-sheffield-shield-victory-over-nsw/105905076</link><description>Scott Boland has produced a man-of-the-match performance, bowling Victoria to a 38-run win over New South Wales in their Sheffield Shield clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">729329d9bae119b36c0706d109492cf3</guid></item><item><title>Former Japanese prime minister Tomiichi Murayama, famous for WWII apology, dies aged 101</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/ex-japan-prime-minister-tomiichi-murayama-dies-aged-101/105906158</link><description>Known for his landmark apology for Japan's World War II aggression and the phrases "deep remorse" and "heartfelt apology", Tomiichi Murayama has died at a hospital in Oita City.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03b35ac069e03d3037f52ba5261468f2</guid></item><item><title>Phillip Island lap record smashed by Marco Bezzecchi in MotoGP practice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/phillip-island-lap-record-smashed-in-motogp-practice/105906416</link><description>In a stunning performance in perfect conditions on Friday, Marco Bezzecchi became the first MotoGP rider to go under 1.27 at the regional Victorian track.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0275f5ccce1401f0389a378f2f04709c</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar military leader Michael Randrianirina sworn in as president after coup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/madagascar-new-president-sworn-in-after-military-coup/105906334</link><description>An army colonel who seized power in a military coup has been sworn in as Madagascar's new leader, after a sudden power grab that ousted the president and sent him fleeing from the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96dcc3f3b1832b7f3704ff8662f60934</guid></item><item><title>Premier David Crisafulli apologises for 'poor choice' comment about Melbourne stabbing attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/qld-premier-david-crisafulli-melbourne-stabbing-comment-apology/105906370</link><description>David Crisafulli apologises for a remark about crime, made on the same day footage emerges of a random stabbing attack in Melbourne's CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cfc9ef57f9baede516fe09e6c82b709</guid></item><item><title>Australia Diamonds defeat New Zealand Silver Ferns 69-52 in game one of Constellation Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/australia-diamonds-defeat-new-zealand-silver-ferns-69-52/105905070</link><description>Australia has stormed to a commanding win in the first Test of the Constellation Cup series, defeating New Zealand 69-52.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f36860ee433d3f4861c1144ddc36164e</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's Trump meeting comes amid global geopolitical circus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/gaza-ceasefire-deal-donald-trump-anthony-albanese-trade-tariff/105884238</link><description>All signs suggest Anthony Albanese will be sticking with Plan A in his meeting with the US president on Tuesday, rather than becoming a prop for the bigger global circus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7369e04e283103228bfcf69dddc12dd2</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew giving up his royal titles and honours after speaking with King Charles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/prince-andrew-to-give-up-royal-titles-and-honours/105907098</link><description>King Charles's brother has come under significant pressure after being linked to the late convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein and his ties to China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b88d507f6b73a3388229f325fd5168e</guid></item><item><title>Creating deepfakes has never been easier, so what should parents do?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/creating-deepfakes-is-easy-what-should-parents-do/105902982</link><description>Some parents may feel distressed and ill-equipped to tackle the issue of image-based abuse and deepfakes. This is what to watch out for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">136e26003e31a95432cd2b1c4b32704d</guid></item><item><title>Video appears to show March for Australia organiser coordinating with Neo-Nazi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/march-for-australia-organiser-coordinates-with-neo-nazi/105902754</link><description>A previously unreported video has emerged appearing to show a key March for Australia organiser coordinating with a Neo-Nazi at the first rally in Sydney in August, ABC NEWS Verify has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc104ef4e2d70260f456bb05e05b9a6c</guid></item><item><title>Administrative Review Tribunal swamped by surging demand, more than 100 members short</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/administrative-review-tribunal-overwhelmed-surging-demand/105893728</link><description>The Administrative Review Tribunal was set up to resolve issues with its predecessor, but has struggled with staffing and long wait times over its first year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fd2f156e95340a969daa8b6003273f1</guid></item><item><title>Benjamin Netanyahu's name prompted boos in Israel but is it a signal he has lost favour?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/benjamin-netanyahu-popularity-in-israel-in-spotlight/105903240</link><description>As the dust settles on the ceasefire and hostage exchange deal, the question arises as to whether the partial resolution could deliver Benjamin Netanyahu a bounce in the polls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3cc3003b8b28e951e730e5aa18bbb1f</guid></item><item><title>Wall Street sell-off could mean hip-pocket relief for millions of Australians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/insurance-companies-caught-in-global-sector-sell-off/105906164</link><description>Australia's big insurance companies were sold off heavily on the share market on Friday after a wave of anxiety hit the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e35eee1242809cb384df7776dc560ebc</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's family reportedly made hundreds of millions from crypto after White House return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/how-trump-family-profits-from-cryptocurrencies/105445400</link><description>US President Donald Trump and his family have reportedly amassed hundreds of millions of dollars from cryptocurrencies. Here is what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d405316e27218a44724818a9f9ff772a</guid></item><item><title>China expels top-ranking military leaders from Communist Party</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/china-expels-top-military-leaders-amid-corruption-charges/105907114</link><description>He Weidong, China's second-most-senior general, and navy admiral Miao Hua, the military's former top political officer, have been accused of "serious duty-related crimes involving an extremely large amount of money".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bbf6aaab1e32a9d0d9c40a249845d46</guid></item><item><title>Fire authorities warn of 'above average' fire season as NSW starts to warm up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/nsw-above-average-fire-season-bushfire-risk-weather/105900120</link><description>Fire authorities warn of above average fire season in NSW despite previous modelling showing a wet summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52eaca3898c563789480ae66f0c7a43f</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy offers Donald Trump Ukrainian drones in exchange for US Tomahawks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/donald-trump-volodymyr-zelenskyy-meet-after-vladimir-putin-call/105907092</link><description>The Ukrainian president offers the US thousands of military drones in exchange for American Tomahawk missiles, but Donald Trump says he wants to end the war "without thinking about Tomahawks".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c7ba4e71bbd1cb098a9e72ec1aa1c48</guid></item><item><title>Water testing in the Murweh Shire returns negative for dangerous amoeba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/murweh-mayor-charleville-hospital-negative-water-testing-amoeba/105899494</link><description>South-west Queensland residents are questioning the detection of a dangerous amoeba at Queensland Health sites after all follow-up tests were negative.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f732b4b65ef2c9618812d9b472a6ce26</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of Victorian Neighbourhood Houses in jeopardy as funding shortfall bites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/victoria-neighbourhood-houses-at-risk-of-closing/105870034</link><description>Vulnerable people reliant on the support of Neighbourhood Houses to live plead for increased funding from the Victorian government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83c27da72dc2d6134240cd243fdf2cf9</guid></item><item><title>Brad Battin under pressure as Liberal MPs weigh up second leadership spill in less than 12 months</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/brad-battin-victorian-liberal-leader-analysis/105904104</link><description>The Victorian Liberals could be headed for their third leader in less than 12 months, with MPs internally dissatisfied with the performance of current leader Brad Battin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c7498fe9c9833ab207d978dc7164bb6</guid></item><item><title>Is the transfer of Australia's best young soccer players a good thing?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/soccer-a-league-player-transfers/105893566</link><description>Are A-League soccer fans right to be frustrated when its best young players are sold off, or should they accept it is a 'selling' league?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0e06963459d7a95465fff2d57464f52</guid></item><item><title>As the Australian op shop turns 100, the legacy of Lady Millie Tallis lives on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/lady-millie-tallis-australian-op-shop-100-year-anniversary/105901846</link><description>One hundred years ago, showgirl-turned-philanthropist Millie Tallis spent weeks preparing for a major second-hand goods fundraiser in Melbourne, giving rise to the Australian op shop.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92ea4c4664694717607b7fd6c4bd9662</guid></item><item><title>Young people with chronic pain feel 'unheard', misunderstood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/young-people-living-with-chronic-pain/105898314</link><description>Chronic pain affects one in five Australian children. Two young people who experience it want more people to understand their conditions and better support for all children in pain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">946486ae5287caf11084ac18ee24e69e</guid></item><item><title>Renewed search for Gus concludes without answers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/sa-renewed-search-for-gus-finishes-long-read/105903652</link><description>When police announced a new search for a missing four-year-old earlier this week, it came with a renewed hope for answers. But the latest search came to an end on Friday with crews finding no sign of little Gus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a9c245450519d0f9b810a9b73bb0806</guid></item><item><title>Trump 'risking full-fledged war' against Venezuela as US military action escalates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/trump-risking-war-in-venezuela-as-military-action-escalates/105905370</link><description>The US military has launched six strikes on Venezuelan vessels the Trump administration claims were involved in drugs trafficking, and some are warning the intervention is threatening to spark an all-out war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b073ef6c9e14d9494c974248c3a4de84</guid></item><item><title>Protesters clash with police as Bangladesh's political parties agree to pathway for reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/protesters-clash-with-police-in-bangladesh-over-political-reform/105907038</link><description>Tear gas and stun grenades were used to disperse hundreds of protesters who were calling for more provisions for those who helped oust the former government of Sheikh Hasina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">487bc6155e85e21b8f55d26aa4aa70b8</guid></item><item><title>Lack of housing in remote NT community Borroloola forcing families off country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/borroloola-housing-lack-forcing-families-leave-country/105895586</link><description>Remote NT residents are calling on the government to fund new housing in the Gulf community of Borroloola, fearing limited access to appropriate homes has forced families to move off country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df22bcf01f5fa2c70abd461d204c6d03</guid></item><item><title>Former Trump adviser John Bolton pleads not guilty to sharing classified information</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/john-bolton-pleads-not-guilty-to-sharing-classified-information/105906928</link><description>John Bolton has become one of Donald Trump's most vocal critics after he was ousted from the US president's administration during his first term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8908cf93af441dee92e8c2b344ce9896</guid></item><item><title>Australians encouraged to have conversations about end-of-life care as new online tool launched</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/conversations-about-final-stage-life-difficult-necessary/105887826</link><description>Many people struggle to approach the subject of death with family, and what kind of care they want to receive in their final months or years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e2d16068fa0d5972ee65aa901f8b06c</guid></item><item><title>James Duckworth returns to ATP Tour semifinal four years after his last</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/james-duckworth-atp-tour-astana-open-semi-final/105907190</link><description>Four years since he last reached an ATP tournament semifinal in Kazakhstan, Australian James Duckworth is back in the last four at the Almaty Open</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dceb858841c1c847c349b2a7432508b3</guid></item><item><title>Locals swarm when air freight carrying fresh food arrives on the island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/locals-swarm-when-air-freight-carrying-fresh-food-arrives/105896242</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">874c9e4756d74a99a787d3dd04623436</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Island wants more tourists but luggage is often left behind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/christmas-island-travellers-luggage-regularly-left-behind/105778992</link><description>On Christmas Island, locals are not surprised if tourists' checked baggage does not arrive with them. Fragile supply chains on the remote Indian Ocean island are a part of life in this unique community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf635fd57a7aedc3288c6869b3851e6d</guid></item><item><title>Lifesavers trial AI cameras to detect emergencies and improve rock fishing safety.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/lifesavers-trial-ai-cameras-for-rock-fishers/105906074</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bff700008ea2018a273611322df951a9</guid></item><item><title>AI tech takes on one of NSW's deadliest rock fishing spots</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/ai-camera-trial-rock-fishing-safety-nsw/105902900</link><description>Surf Life Saving NSW is testing artificial intelligence cameras at Kiama Blowhole to detect when fishers are swept into the water and alert rescuers within seconds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">151eddbf0d62e8e7f4aeb5cec27a435d</guid></item><item><title>Body of another Israeli hostage handed over by Hamas in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/israeli-hostage-body-to-be-handed-over-by-hamas/105907214</link><description>Israel says it has received nine of 28 bodies held in Gaza, and Hamas says it needs heavy machinery and excavating equipment to speed up the process of locating bodies buried under rubble.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6621b61c6b91adb3b38b0164580c669e</guid></item><item><title>West End residents are concerned about development plans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/west-end-development-flooding/105905096</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2cafba25a8b629fd4d6001d3b7b9a3d</guid></item><item><title>The face of Brisbane is changing — but should thousands of homes be developed in a flood zone?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/visy-montague-road-riverfront-precinct-thousands-of-homes-floods/105904030</link><description>Plans to build a riverfront precinct in a flood-prone area of Brisbane have urban planners and locals wary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d506b00fbc8d45eff04ef30c465454e6</guid></item><item><title>Pakistani soldiers killed by suicide bomb near Afghanistan border</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/suicide-bomb-attack-kills-soldiers-in-pakistan/105906932</link><description>The attack on a military base near the Afghanistan border comes as Taliban and Pakistani officials say a peace deal has been extended.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a43f6b1a97e689f439e7e9bc7a686da6</guid></item><item><title>The Australian Poweroos in action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/australian-poweroos-players-in-action/105901628</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">deb4849821415c6624227c5fcb52ce21</guid></item><item><title>Tool's Maynard James Keenan on touring Australia, making wine and martial arts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/tool-australia-tour-2025-maynard-james-keenan-interview/105865706</link><description>The alt-metal band's frontman is a world-class multi-tasker. He tells us how he balances it all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">501350518724f7dcac6393cd0c095da6</guid></item><item><title>Western Australia starts harvesting what could be a record-breaking grain crop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/western-australia-harvest-record-grain-crop-expected/105900332</link><description>Farmers in Western Australia have begun harvesting a grain crop that could set a new record. It is a different story on the other side of the Nullabor though.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a84a87f36461e65b587de7b1fd2f66c6</guid></item><item><title>Greek-inspired lamb kebabs with olive potatoes baked in the oven - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/easy-oven-baked-lamb-kebabs-with-olive-potatoes/105291672</link><description>The lamb is fuss-free and full of flavour. No barbecue needed — the oven takes care of everything.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97732d3bb23552f5f8a4e4e0fa75a14b</guid></item><item><title>From a Springsteen biopic to a doggy horror: here are the movies out in October</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/october-movie-wrap-what-to-watch/105893300</link><description>From the highly anticipated Bruce Springsteen biopic to a horror movie from the viewpoint of the family pup, here are the films filling up cinemas in October.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f217a9477d3de1211d4744ae2ba19bd8</guid></item><item><title>WNBL's new leadership committed to the 'long-haul' as season tips off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/wnbl-new-season-new-ownership-jennie-sager/105905322</link><description>After years of financial struggles and lack of exposure, players are hoping the WNBL's new owners will resurrect the league, and head office is promising it is in it for the long haul.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df22f2c2efc0ef8bb2a17cfbc2129b4f</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne's record-setting AFLW winning streak is clear in the numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/north-melbourne-setting-aflw-standards/105905842</link><description>Having developed the program layer by layer since joining the AFLW in 2019, North Melbourne's disciplined, professional style of footy is forcing the rest of the league to rise to their level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3f69ec228f1094f89b081dd9d305cb5</guid></item><item><title>Cool weather prescribed burn on WA's south coast should be expanded, environmental group says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/call-to-expand-cool-weather-burns-to-protect-the-environment/105896512</link><description>The success of a small, autumn prescribed burn on WA's south coast has prompted calls to replace the regular program to reduce environmental damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">164585befee231bbcfbedee418ccc7bd</guid></item></channel></rss>